tickets for Berliner on sale there's
more exhibits upstairs shout out to ice
fire for being our title sponsor what
what after party tonight at nine o'clock
at the Ritz Arts Hotel uh if you don't
have a ticket if it wasn't in your
packet and you want to buy a ticket it's
like 200 Euros you can talk to Jesse
about it and now our next panel this
will be in English by the way uh so if
you need to go get a translator set you
can get one out there but here we go the
founder we're so happy we're so lucky to
have her here she's an amazing person
the founder of MJ Universe let's hear it
for Lisa hog
[Applause]
[Music]
hello everybody and welcome to our
speakers also and uh to our panel on
evolving cannabis policy within the
European Union
um
so today ICBC is bringing to you guys
he's a business and corporate lawyer in
Germany since 2003. he is very familiar
with the interconnectivity between
National and European regulations
especially with regard to Consumer
Protection product safety and emerging
new cannabis products he has a legal
blog that is very worth reading is kind
of minusbiz dot legal and he's also one
of the major consultants for CBD
companies and medicinal companies in
Germany and hopefully very soon also for
recreational companies then we have
found this panel Carla parisha from
zubalona Carla is based in California
she's focused on cross-border corporate
transaction and Regulatory matters often
in relation to Europe and also Latin
America she's been representing cannabis
companies for most of her legal career
she has graduated at University
pampufawa it's a very famous university
in Spain and she works in Spanish and
Portuguese and is originally here from
Barcelona
um then we have foreign Rockaway here
he's CEO and managing attorney at
Rockaway Law Group he's the founder and
managing director there and they're
located in California and Oregon as well
as the Rockaway group as swissvine he's
professionally involved in the Cannabis
industry since 2004 has studied in
Germany also and he's
participated in numerous cases related
to cannabis for mediations and
arbitrations
and then we also have Here Andrew
bonello from relief Malta he's the
president he's active since 2019 and has
worked tirelessly to represent the voice
of cannabis consumers in Malta so let's
have a quick one Welcome to our
panelists
[Applause]
and then let's get started right away
Kai let's start with you maybe it's the
most pressing question is happening at
the moment what is happening in Germany
so would you give us a late a latest
update on the legalization efforts in
Germany where do we stand right now and
what is to be expected over the next
couple of months for sure
so as you all know we had Federal
elections in September 21 in Germany and
we had a new government a traffic light
Coalition Social Democratic party the
liberal party and the greens and they
agreed in November 21 on legalization of
a cannabis so the the plan is to
distribute cannabis
licensed cannabis and licensed stores to
adults
since now with one and a half years ago
there nothing really much happened
but now the decisive month will be the
March 2023 so we're expecting the draft
of the new government of the government
in March presented by the Ministry of
Health probably at the end of March
maybe there will be a leak like last
time with this Keystone with this key
Point paper and then
we see also we will also see the plan of
the German government how to roll out
these draft and how this can work we
have lots of international legal issues
starting with a single convention to EU
law and
mainly the last one and a half years we
spent discussions on how to how to
tackle this how to handle this and
that's the reason why it was so slowly
but now we're expecting that we will see
two different kind of of drafts so the
the first step of legalization will be
decolonization homegrown and Collective
home growth
um and the plan is to
get this draft at the end of March to
transfer to brunestar then it comes to
Brunswick within the normal procedures
the first hearing second hearing third
hearing and then it will be agreed on
before the summer break of of the
bundestag in June July so that's the
plan if that happens
decriminalization and town grow will be
allowed with immediate effect from June
or July this year on the complicated
thing is the commercial route to
establish a commercial route which is
the declared goal of the government
which means that you have cultivation
license cultivation license shops and
yeah
real business like we see in Canada and
in in the US
and that's tricky because there are lots
of illegal issues going along with that
because Imports big question right now
the German government assumes that now
Imports are possible to Germany so every
single gram has to be cultivated in
Germany because the EU has the only
authority to agree on international
trade agreements uh and if we can't find
a way to to deal with that we can't even
have a trade within the EU right now
because of these EU framework decisions
um but they're working behind the scenes
so almost every many EU member states
like Czech Republic Spain Portugal and
Malta Luxembourg Netherlands Germany
they all want to go a different route in
terms of cannabis policy and they're
working behind the scenes and there's an
initiative to change these uh these EU
framework decisions and to amend the
Schengen uh so that at least the EU
member states can can trade cannabis
among them if they want to and they can
legalize cannabis on a certain
legal basis and not being afraid of the
you commission to start infringement
procedure procedures or stuff like that
so that will also be explained by the
health Ministry uh however you confirm
are you complying legalization can be
rolled out in Germany in March and we're
expecting a federal Supreme Court
decision also in March
before the Easter break on the general
legality of the Cannabis prohibition if
the Cannabis prohibition is legal and
complying with the constitution on the
grounds of the freedom of person I think
the two of our Constitution and article
3 the principle of equality equality why
is cannabis treating more treated more
strictly more stricter than alcohol and
these are the big developments in
Germany in March 2023 will be decisive
thank you um okay maybe we'll stay with
you you just said that there's a lot of
like contracts that have to be
considered in that regard in Germany
we're also talking about the
interpretation declaration or the
interpretation solution can you maybe
tell the audience a little bit about
that
yeah sure so there is the 1961 single
convention on aquatic Dux saying that
the trade of cannabis is only allowed
for scientific and medical purposes
and this is an international treaty
almost every country in the world is a
member of this treaty
um and so we have to deal somehow with
that Germany is in principle very
friendly to international law Germany
wants to comply with these rules and
there are different routes you can go
like Uruguay that takes a Firm Stance on
human rights
legalizing a cannabis allowing trade
with cannabis is on the grounds of Human
Rights because they had lots of crimes
and and victims and people suffering
from the ban of prohibition Canada did
sort of something else something nothing
you know don't know the mixture of Human
Rights and health protection and the
German government is now saying we
interpretate we inter we do an
interpretation of these single
convention and we say to legalize is
better health protection than to
prohibit to go on to prohibit cannabis
and that's how we interpret it and this
is in line with the singular convention
because the single function was made up
for the health protection for the
protection of your of the of the people
that's basically it there are so many
legal problems everything is disputed if
there is an Intercity possible
retroactivity
etc etc you can't find your way out
with a single convention and you can
just take a Firm Stance on human rights
like Uruguay or on health protection and
it's in the the singular convention will
never be changed in the in the near
future so think of States like Russia or
or China putting CBD in Hong Kong on the
list of prohibited substances so that's
the way but we of the the more delicate
issues of course the EU the framework
decision to find the solution to allow
International Trade within the EU to
find the ways that every EU member State
can legalize on firm legally grounds
yeah
so let's stay with the single convention
for a bit America has been one of the
main driving forces uh to bring this
contractual framework into place does
the single convention play a role at all
in the U.S and is the U.S maybe also in
the Second Step considering to
um legalize cannabis also on a national
level or is it going to stay Fair um is
it going to stay on the state level I
would say probably no to both I don't
think that the US is really concerned
about the single conventions treaty in
terms of domestic policy or with respect
to like violating international law if
domestic laws were to change it's just
not I don't think a part of the
considerations or the conversation or
the political dialogue yet it is ironic
obviously that the U.S essentially
imposed this on the rest of the world
and is ambivalent about the impact of
you know that obligation domestically in
terms of federal legalization there is
kind of perennial conversation about it
but uh I'm I'm a little cynical at this
point I just don't think that it's
likely to happen I think that uh you
know the Biden had his his chance uh
when he had control over both houses or
the Democrats rather had control over
both houses of Congress and now that um
the House Representatives is uh in
control uh with the Republican party I
just think it's very unlikely that
there'll be legislation that makes it
through Congress to legalize cannabis
um in the in the near terms so I think
there's going to have to be you know in
terms of just the sequencing another
election where there's the the party in
power for Congress and the president
that supports legalization which at this
point and historically the Republicans
are just not in favor of that
um so I think probably what the future
is going to look like for the us as much
of How It's looked um so far which is
sort of this piecemeal approach
different states essentially being the
laboratory of ideas and trying to enact
their own policies that have some
commonalities but are fairly disjointed
which is really problematic actually
because you know kind of similar to how
it is at least described with how Kai
described with the EU is there's no real
common denominator for policy in the U.S
other than prohibition so basically the
U.S policy federally is that cannabis is
the same as heroin whereas when we're
talking about California where I am you
know medical use has been legal since
legalization was enacted by the voters
in 2016
and so you know you can go to a lot of
different parts of the state access
cannabis legally obviously not treated
like heroin but the federal government
still has it as a schedule and
controlled substance so it's somewhat of
a schizophrenic approach I think both
with respect to international law and
domestically
thank you Andrew let's go over to you
what's the status on cannabis
legalization in Malta and say if I were
on holiday there could I just go and
visit a social club and get some
cannabis well it's early days obviously
Malta is on the tip of everyone's tongue
at the moment because it has the most
Progressive law in Europe
um but if you actually look at what the
law is saying you'll find out that it's
nowhere near legalized it is closer to
some some sort of decriminalization
would say maybe a partial
decriminalization and what we have in
the law is we can grow up to four plants
without being criminalized
and we can have seven grams of cannabis
possession out in public
you can expunge your criminal records
and also there is the biggest part of
the law which would be the issuing of
licenses to open
um what were meant to be Social Clubs
but unfortunately you know along the
line you know there's a lot of politics
involved and prime ministers fall and
you get a new one ministers change and
the topic goes from one Ministry to
another and Gets Lost in Translation
with no Handover I don't know if this is
in all politics but unfortunately it's
what happened in Malta so we don't
really have a model which is going to be
either social and there's going to be no
Club so they've decided to call them
associations which is going to be based
more on a dispensary system so
um you you have to be obviously a member
of this club where you can go and
acquire your cannabis and take it home
but you know licenses have just been
issued now like literally last week and
so applications basically but still
those people that applied don't even
know what the final license fee is going
to be so it's kind of
um being rolled out and being formed as
they go along and I'm happy to say that
my organization is involved obviously as
much as possible to try and shape policy
to make sure that it's um just an
effective policy
yeah that's super interesting I mean
it's in general very important to be
involved in the discussion some of the
rules don't make are made with you and
not for you
um so color let's move over to you some
homegrown and Social Clubs do they play
or did they play a role during the
legalization efforts in U.S states and
what would you recommend to lawmakers
under the debate in Europe on this
so uh canopy Social Clubs actually have
existed in the United States for a while
in the 1920s they were called teapots
and they were bars where people went and
listened to jazz music and and small
cannabis and they disappeared after
cannabis became illegal but they they
have a player role definitely and
um uh we see that there is a path toward
legalization and and we're kind of
position clubs and homegrown cannabis is
generally part of this regularization in
the 1973 that's how we started in the
United States with Oregon
followed by California and Alaska and
Colorado and one very important thing to
keep me in mind after so many years of
bad propaganda in cannabis is
responsible use and this canopy Social
Clubs promote these responsible use
where people have a place to go and and
consume cannabis in a social setting and
the the states in the United States that
have legalized cannabis but have not
regulated these social clubs are somehow
handicapped because you can you can
purchase cannabis but you don't have a
place to to go and smoke it and
uh
what what we've seen for example in
States like California you you where
where the the canopy social groups have
been regulated is that you can go and
you can the dispensary licensees allow
you to also consume cannabis there there
are different approaches for example in
New York it's more of a of a separate uh
the same way as alcohol Works kind of
where you have you can go purchase uh
cannabis uh like a liquor store you
cannot consume it there but you can
purchase it and consume it at home or
you have the the the the retail license
where you can go and and purchase
cannabis but you cannot so the retail
license would be like the liquor store
and then you have the consumption
license where you can go and consummate
there and New York is actually issuing
the first licenses this summer New
Jersey also has
um included just past some regulations
on kind of a social clubs and and
homeroom cannabis and I think for from
the European lawmakers which we should
keep in mind that legalization should
have
in mind that the safety and quality of
the products it should definitely
include uh what I was mentioning about
responsible use and it should recognize
the benefits of cannabis such as
reducing uh um the burden on law
enforcement and reducing the criminal
activities
that's very true
um Kai decriminalization and Collective
home growth are caliber Social Clubs as
a possible Plan B has been discussed is
this compatible with EU law and scheng
and a queen and framework decision
okay as I mentioned before you
everything is disputed but this is in
the most justifiable justifiable way out
of this
decriminalization yes this is a
article 3 of the framework decision is
talking about personal consumption but
think about cannabis Social Clubs in
Hamburg Frankfurt Hanover Berlin a
thousand members 5 000 members imagine
what a growth this would be the plan is
that you can legally grow three plants
three flowering plants at one time and
so you have the
the the plants in the early stages and
uh as soon as they turn into a flower
ring you have to get rid of one or you
have to have a better management of this
but if you delegate this weight right to
a canopy Social Club so uh you have 10
000 members then you can have three
flower three thousand flowering plants
at one time
if that is compatible with with EU log
with these provision in article three of
the framework decision
you know so but it's anytime we talk
about cannabis legally on a global
illegally and globally uh you you will
never get a clear way a clear regulation
without any justify
arguments and and some some
circumvention routes in augmentation
that is like it is and but the Social
Democratic party is very much in favor
of the Cannabis Social Club
because they think you have you can
exercise a social control
within the association with the members
and they want to really promote that and
give a clear legal framework for that so
that you can really have a huge
numbers a huge associations and
I think this is a good way to go so for
first start for for Germany and it it's
possible to to to realize that really
after the decision in bonus attack and
I'm really looking much looking forward
to that yeah maybe also to mention the
associations are an important thing in
Germany anyways we have like Association
for ducks hound breeders bowling clubs
and whatever so we have a lot of
associations also for patients for
example so it's an important role in
Germany I mean and look in the scene
here in Barcelona is how many social
clubs hundreds over 100 and they have a
cultural event
program you have bands you have DJing
you can come together share your
experience share your grow experience I
think that's perfect for stock
uh Carla let's go back to you
um the Social Clubs in Spain what's your
opinion on that and how well do you
think are those regulated
well so cannabis Social Clubs in Spain
uh operate under a legal limbo the
international single convention on
narcotic trucks was ratified by Spain in
1966 and it prohibits the
production the public possession the
trafficking and the use of cannabis so
the stipulation on public possession is
where everything comes around here so
um the the
private possession consumption in Canada
in in Spain is basically decriminalized
so
um the canopy Social Clubs here work a
little bit like the Netherlands Social
Club so the difference that they are not
open to the public so it's like a
member-only club you have to to be a
member it's it's a member invite only
type of Club so generally you can only
join the clubs viewer if you're invited
by another existing member and it's an
area where where people go and pay a
membership fee the membership it doesn't
go towards the purchase of cannabis
because the the cannabis clubs are
non-profit organizations so they can
have a commercial purpose so
um the membership fee that you pay is
basically towards the grow of the blend
and the maintenance of the social club
itself and other places most of the
clubs are here in Catalonia they're uh
quite a number of clubs also in El Pais
Vasco and here in Catalonia they are
somehow regulated so there are certain
um factors that need to be followed from
a perspective of of Public Health and
and the amount of calories that can be
sold to an individual within a period of
time
um but other places where the social
clubs are not um regulated under local
law
um there are concerns over potential
criminal activities that that take place
in these Social Clubs because of the
potential High revenues that they can
generate and the low chance of being
prosecuted
um so I mean Spain should definitely
take steps towards uh regulating the
Social Clubs in a in a more complete way
because currently they're just operating
under a gray area
um Andrew let's go back to you so we
heard this discussion also with EU law
single convention
um is there a position in Malta on that
and are there any statement on human
rights as in the case of Uruguay for
example or on Better Health protection
is this an important driver yes I mean
there is not an official position from
Malta but they have been to the incb
um the The Ambassador in Vienna has
actually spoken to the incb and of
course the the human rights obligation
is being used a lot together with Health
and Social Justice which is where the
Cannabis Social Club model fits in
perfectly because it's a decriminalized
system and you are basically flying
under the radar of the the single
convention so no no rules are really
being broken
and it's an easy way to go forward and
you can understand that Malta obviously
isn't going to go going to you know
um go for complete legalization like
maybe Germany has more muscle to be able
to do that and challenge so I can
understand that most of being a smaller
country has decided obviously wanted to
reform with the new government that came
in in 2013 there was a strong urge um to
actually make this reform
um but obviously they you know when you
look at the rules and regulations you
realize what you really can and where
the big challenges are and the big
challenges we know is basically that
commercial sale which is prohibited so
you know when you have a Social Club
model which is sort of built by the
community for the community offering a
safe space and obviously also a perfect
space to introduce harm reduction
measures this obviously fits in with the
human rights obligation as well so this
is pretty much acceptable and so that's
the route we we we're taking and when it
comes to
um speaking with the EU and it's
important to keep dialogue open
um explain to them exactly what we're
doing we have an agency which is um
called The Authority for the responsible
use of cannabis which has been set up
and is in the in the process of
employing more people
um and and getting the framework
together so the you know the European
commission knows exactly what is going
on there's there's open dialogue and so
far we haven't had any problems so is it
a plan B for Germany I mean I I think so
because at the end of the day it's it's
a safe route
um it's one which I know the Grassroots
movement and actual consumers would be
happy with
um but and then obviously you know
commercialization is something that you
can't avoid this is something that's
going to come in but we truly truly
believe especially my organization my
organization believes that we should be
building from the bottom up and once we
do that then industry can come in and
and play together with the community so
that way
um you leave no cracks in the in the
foundation of building a new framework
so the social shops are step one and the
commercialization potentially a second
step well commercialization is
inevitable and it's something that has
to happen but I think it's important
that one country doesn't go It Alone
when trying to challenge this I think
that if if the like-minded countries can
get together and and have a solid
proposal I think it will make much more
sense and be easier to move forward that
way yeah
um Joe you've been doing this for a very
very long time so um what would you
recommend to EU member states who want
to legalize or regulate cannabis adult
use cannabis in regard to the experience
you made in the US
lots of stuff
um so
we've we made a lot of mistakes in in
the U.S particularly in California and I
would say that sort of the over
commercialization is a problem uh we saw
after legalization just this sort of
hyper
um
hyperactive capitalization of companies
that were not mature enough to take on
the money the businesses didn't really
have a model to be able to responsibly
use that investment money there was
there's just a lot of examples of
companies getting you know 50 million
dollars a hundred million dollars and
squandering it
um and I think a lot of people in
California in particular would feel that
the model that existed under the medical
laws from about 2004 until 2017 when
legalization was implemented is superior
to the legalization model and that's the
model that we had basically these
collectives and cooperatives that
qualified patients that time could
collectively associate to cultivate
medical cannabis and provide that to the
qualified patient members same as what
Kai was describing with Germany we could
aggregate the number of plants per
patient and get to a larger number of
plans to be produced and then provided
to those patients and also through a
non-profit model for all of the flaws
that that model had
it worked it was successful for a long
period of time and Legacy cannabis
industry operators were able to be
successful for 10 years 15 years under
that model and then legalization
happened because so much money went into
it and there was so much hype and the
regulations were just unsettled the laws
were unsettled federal law as we just
discussed is not helpful
all of that stuff sort of conspired
together to make legalization really
challenging to implement in California
and that's just sort of one state out of
50 states and so you know when you look
at at most parts of America almost
nowhere can you have on-site social
consumption almost entirely what the
model is is like off sale uh retail
where you can go and purchase it and
then consume it essentially only in your
home and usually only if you own your
home because a lot of rental leases have
conditions like non-smoking rules as a
part of that lease and so then you have
a situation where people can consume
cannabis at their home or in public
which is generally prohibited a lot of
people consume in their cars which is
obviously not a good idea and also
prohibited so I think actually the
Germany Plan B maybe should be plan A
you know the the legalization of having
a model of more of a sort of
pharmaceutical base model a monopoly
type model is I don't think going to be
as beneficial as something that is more
Grassroots more bottom up more focused
on the people and the organizations that
have been a part of legalization from
the beginning and to rely on them and
their expertise their knowledge to carry
forward
um so um Jessica step in here and I see
the problem when you have these two
Roots so you have to Social Club model
and a commercial route you have to
protect the commercial route and you
have to make sure that these Social Club
idea is really restrained to to a
community to a social club to the
members and the members taking it
seriously and it's not it can't be that
the social clubs are in fact commercial
businesses just taking the restricted
the the
um the um the easier rules for for for
operating because the commercial would
have to be licensed there will have to
be invests in retail stores and Retail
structures in and you have to really
really separate that and you have to
control that as well so the Cannabis
Social Club must be a social model and
not a hidden business model
um those two things can exist in
parallel they're not mutually exclusive
and I think the social club model is a
good backstop against the sort of
full-fledged
um capitalistic approach uh that I think
has really been problematic uh for Los
Angeles which is in particular which is
maybe the largest cannabis Market in the
world
um has utterly failed to implement
legalization on on every level and it's
a huge disappointment for the industry
it's a huge disappointment I know for me
personally
um and I think
um you know different countries within
the EU can do a much better job than
we've done domestically in the U.S if
they they learn from our our lessons and
they kind of move the policy forward in
a way that um I think it really should
be
thank you um so maybe one last uh final
question before we move on to the
audience for all of you um maybe one
quick sentence statement what should
division look like for the EU and Global
cannabis legalization
um a robust system which makes global
trade possible
foreign
I'd say create a system that is uh on
parity with how alcohol is regulated so
if you have a model in in your country
where you can freely buy it and consume
it whatever those age limits are just
adopt that same model to cannabis it
works with alcohol it can work with
cannabis and you don't have to create an
entirely new and weird and separate
model just for cannabis it really
doesn't need to be like that and that's
something I think that if that was
implemented in the U.S we would have a
far better cannabis system of
regulations and laws than we do
currently kind of um I think it should
be seen from a perspective of safety
Public Health social equity and research
and Innovation from a public health
perspective what I mentioned about
responsible use is very important to
promote responsible use from a safety
perspective I think there should be
robust testing requirements to make sure
the products that we bring to the market
are are safe and of high quality
the communities of color and low-income
communities have been negatively
impacted and disproportionately impacted
by the uh but by prohibition so I think
that this community should have access
to the benefits of a legal cannabis
market and there should be constant
research and Innovation to make sure we
we have a quality cannabis based
products in the market and there should
definitely be an international
perspective on on the legalization
I think the EU needs to take a good hard
look at the criminalization that is
still happening in different countries
and look at the statistics and see how
many people's lives are getting ruined
at the moment for simple possession
cultivation or consumption
um and I realized that prohibition is
doing obviously more damage than the
plant itself so once once they take a
good hard look at the figures and the
statistics then they they can realize
that obviously we have to move some to
some sort of Reform with
decriminalization I feel being the first
step that's very important in Germany we
have over 200
000 criminal cases prosecuted for
personal consumption so thank you to the
panelists open the floor for questions
um we just have six minutes left so I
can only take one or two
hi thank you uh very much for a very
informative and engaging uh panel uh
actually Carla just started to touch on
this at the end of the subject and and
one of the interesting contrasts between
uh the U.S and Europe is that uh the
consumption lounges came as sort of a a
secondary proposal to the commercial uh
regulations uh whereas here it seems
like the consumption lounges are more
the foot in the door uh to commercial
legalization uh the problem is that I
see is that well I mean I guess the
opportunity uh that with the consumption
Lounge is coming later is licensing
around consumption lounges licensing
around deliveries and the relatively low
barriers to entry associated with those
made them a very attractive licenses for
social Equity applicants and I I don't
see is it cute a problem in Europe
around social equity and the impact of
the War on Drugs to disproportionately
impacted communities but it is an issue
in Europe as well so if these
consumption lounges are sort of the the
foot in the door for the larger
commercial interests uh how do you see
the evolution of cannabis policy within
Europe in embracing uh the the Legacy
market and those communities that have
been disproportionately impacted by
prohibition thank you
well I think
um
it's it's important to to to
do something similar to what was done in
the United States I think that the
social Equity licenses were were uh uh
the intention was a very good intention
um the problem that has happened is that
a lot of investors have basically
um taken over these licenses and the
social Equity applicants have been uh
put in in a second stage uh so so the
intention was good I think it's
important to give special license to
these to these um uh applicants but it
should be done in a way to to protect to
protect their interests because it
hasn't been done
um the way it was intended in the United
States I don't know if Joe you have a
different opinion
uh well so I I agree
um completely that we need to take care
of the communities that have been the
most harmed from the War on Drugs in the
United States it's a very problematic
and troubled history with respect to
communities of color in particular and
how those communities have been impacted
by prohibition and disproportionate
incarcer and all those things the
problem with how we've dealt with social
Equity is that we really haven't ignored
the benefits of legalization to those
communities all we've done with our
programs is given basically a better
spot in line to the the permits that are
issued at a municipal level
so what that means is to Carla's Point
uh there is you know companies that are
forced like in the LA social Equity
program they're forced uh to have a
social Equity component to their
application in order to be able to to
get a local permit which is prerequisite
to a state license and that's how one
becomes legal uh but those relationships
are very exploitative and what ends up
happening is the social Equity applicant
ends up not being benefited from that
relationship they're just used from that
relationship
so I think should happen is looking at
more of a community benefit model where
instead of just giving preferential
treatment to you know someone's ability
to get a permit first that ultimately
doesn't matter what matters is that the
communities that are underprivileged
that are underserved that are just
inadequately represented in basically
all ways they get access to benefits
that come from Cannabis even if they
don't consume cannabis uh you know writ
large to individuals in those
communities where we have tax dollars
for example derived from Cannabis to
fund social programs for communities
that need them that's the solution I
think not just getting preferential
treatment online and that's a big big
reason why a lot of like the the bigger
metropolitan areas in the U.S and in
California particular have really failed
with their local permitting is they're
focused on on this really just
inadequate model of trying to help
social Equity communities and programs
pounds in a way that doesn't actually
help them the benefits may be driven to
communities not preferential treatment
in one permit application for one
applicant who ends up getting exploited
by the investors oftentimes in that
company yeah thank you for saying that
it's very important and I think it's a
good last word if you have any questions
to the panelists you can find them
outside later and address that directly
and then we're done here and thank you
everybody for listening to our panel
thank you let's hear it again
very informative thank you such a lot of
Heavy Hitters too you guys are all so
amazing we appreciate you thank you it's
the kind of talent we get here at the
international cannabis business
conference