so good afternoon OCBC oh that's lame
good afternoon Oh CBC show Alex how
awesome this is give him a little bit of
love I want to briefly introduce the
folks on this panel and then allow each
of them a moment to tell you why you
should care about what they have to say
we have some amazing expertise up here
to not just talk about what you need to
do but importantly what not to do and so
in order to my right and your left we
have been sent do you Cole I practiced
do you Cole T the co-founder and CEO of
show companies please welcome if you
want to go ahead and give a minute can
you hear me yeah okay I'm the co-founder
of show companies I've been on the quest
build a family of brands both ancillary
and THC touching brands we started in
the industry about five years ago with
brand rasen tech products familiarized
to become one of the leaders in solvent
extraction equipment continued on to
garnish over a catalogue of over 4,000
celeb products CBD wellness we also
operate distribution company in the
state of California that manufactures
and distributes in the state of
California right on Thank You Vincent
next to Vincent we have mark slaw and he
is the founder and CEO of I comply mark
tell us about doc I comply thanks Dale
hi everyone my name is Mark swamp CEO
and founder of I comply were the oldest
cannabis compliance company in the world
surrounded back in 2011 been involved in
Colorado and some of the early
legislative stuff were based out of
Denver and we've helped over 200 clients
in probably 13 14 different national and
international markets were active in
about 10 different states what we do is
compliance management very similar to
what you'll see in any other heavily
regulated industry where that's
hospitals oil and gas pharmaceuticals
there is a world 2
this cannabis thing sometimes a
four-letter word known as compliance
which is important to be proactive
rather than reactive about so I'm here
to really share with you guys what that
experience looks like what it looks like
to unpack that buzzword of compliance
and really set up and manage
appropriately an operational compliance
infrastructure as a strategic
partnership for your businesses indeed
very true and next to you we have mr.
Rocco Petrelli
the chairman of the National cannabis
Risk Management Association Rocco
thanks very much the NCR MA we're
relatively new to the game we've been
around about 18 months and really active
for about 14 of those 18 but we're a
voice of our members and our members are
the owners and operators all along the
vertical who are just finding out in
many cases that good and effective risk
management is very key to success in any
business arena our message is very
simple our mission is to make our
members better and we're committed to
and in the process of creating a
pioneering and disruptive and very
innovative risk management platform
that's going to fit this non-traditional
industry like a glove
so we look look forward to bringing that
to our members and growing with this
industry Thank You Rocco next to you
Justin Botti a he is a partner at Gaelic
CPAs Justin yes so I'm a partner at a
CPA firm based in the hills of Southern
Oregon been doing business tax
accounting tax planning since 2006
self-employed and we do a lot in the
business advisory entity formations 280e
mitigation in terms of the cannabis
industry many of you are familiar with
280e and the complex that brings then as
well as we act kind of as a general
in terms of your accounting needs
payroll bookkeeping higher-level
accounting taxes tax planning so those
kind of things we find solutions for you
and that in that way I'm going to be
talking about the tax consequences of
strategic partnerships in this case
usually negative
Justin McCarthy on the end and our
hammer the Membership Director for C CIA
of which many of you are members thank
you for being here tell us a little more
about yourself Justin awesome yeah my
name is Justin McCarthy I was membership
director for except a couple of weeks
ago I'm now congratulations on can we
get a woohoo
amazing membership team now so I myself
but in short I've been with the
Association for five years now the
Association turns seven next month we do
a lot of the legislative and regulatory
working in Sacramento so working very
closely with state departments and
legislative officials in terms of
getting the situation we're in figured
out my side with the business
development obviously work on a lot of
our strategic partnerships offering you
know enhanced member discounts that our
members can take advantage of and giving
them the education that they need to
survive in the industry that it's
California right on thank you and thank
you for being here I think that we
realize that the success were relative
failures of each of our opportunities
our business often rests on who we
choose as a strategic partner and how we
go about forming that partnership I've
looked around a lot of folks are suing
each other and it seems to boil down to
two things who you chose as a partner
and what that contract looked like but
what is a partner that's a very broad
word broad term strategic partnership so
first I just want to explore with you
guys real quick because each of you come
from a different aspect of the industry
what types of strategic partnerships you
come across and what you're looking for
in those partnerships how do you vet
them I'll start here
so since we have a expansive catalog of
about 4,000 products some of them are
in-house and others are obviously with
partnerships so I deal with the partners
every single day my business is based on
dealing with true strategic partnerships
I can't operate my business without
partnerships after all so for me the
biggest thing in a strategic partnership
is sort of being like upfront and honest
in the beginning if you're looking to be
doing business for longevity to me if
anything you're hiding or leaving off
the table will be exposed in the long
run so I think if you're able to just
whatever makes you think you're hiding
something or you're uncomfortable I lay
it out because like it usually it's not
as big of a deal as you think and if you
lay it out in the beginning and you can
iron those details out and honestly
before you move forward it's easier at
that point rather than setting
expectations in a way that you're
leading someone on kind of and then
you're just asking for disaster at that
point and that's why someone's going to
sue you and that's why they're not gonna
have a conversation with you to fix
things because you led them on in in a
demeanor that wasn't honest at the end
of the day so I think for me the biggest
thing in strategic partnerships is being
upfront and laying it out on the line in
the beginning rather than trying to act
like you're something that you're not
yeah so be clear about what you're gonna
do but also be clear about what you're
not gonna do right up front yeah mark
yeah I know that's that's great
I mean without integrity nothing works
right so says the compliance guy how
many of you guys get more time in this
industry I didn't think so I always say
you don't get more time you get more
team for me that's what strategic
partnerships are all about there are
things that he's going to be good at and
loves to do that I'm not good at and
don't love to do but with more people
around me to basically supplement and
align vision the more can be done in a
way that actually works and so I'm a
firm believer that if you share the same
vision everything else is a conversation
for workability how do we achieve that
vision how do we set those goals how do
we make that happen so we have somebody
new that comes to us for example and
says hey I want to be taking my
compliance to the next level I know I
have gaps in it I know I could do better
that's sort of what we need to hear and
see and understand in any sort of
strategic partnership where I'm gonna
put my time forward so I'm not really
here to waste anybody's money or my time
right we don't get a lot more of that
but with strategic partnerships you
actually expand both of those things so
I like to thinking about it from that
perspective how do we put integrity in
place how do we set expectations at a
real honest upfront manner
absolutely but also how do we surround
ourselves with people that share our
same vision and are willing to put in
the work to respect each other and to
create something that's bigger than each
of you individually and I think that's
what strategic partnerships are all
about for me you're about to jump out of
your chair you want to go next
of course Rocco's always good for a
comment that's why I knew I could yes
well you know I'm navigating I quickly
went from the young guy in the room to
the old man in the cave and I'm still
trying to figure that out but you know
with with that 30-plus years in in
business comes a lot of wisdom and you
know I I'm about two years into cannabis
and risk management after about thirty
four years in automotive components
manufacturing where I did informed and
work with partnerships all over the
world so have a pretty good perspective
of what worked and what didn't and it
really comes down to a good partner is
going to believe your vision they're
going to share your mission and they're
gonna live your core values everything
else is secondary because I mean they're
I have been involved in situations where
there were technical reasons there were
Geographic reasons there were logistic
reasons to form these partnerships but
they were all trumped by particularly
the core values side so anybody that's
in the business starting the business
new in the business or been in the
business for some time if you don't have
a vision if you don't have a set mission
statement and if you don't have a set of
core values the trumps everything you do
in your business I suggest you get them
because those are really gonna form the
criteria for the partnerships that you
for going forward
Rocco that's so well said and I would
dare say that that applies to every
relationship in our life most of which
are strategic whether it be personal or
professional so well stated yeah
Justin so so without repeating that the
mark and Rocco definitely highlighted
you know businesses you it's difficult
to be successful in business if you
don't have partnerships you're going to
have partners external partnerships in
this industry it seems like it's almost
essential to have internal partnerships
as well many of you are looking for
investment many of you are investing so
many of you need knowledge many of you
need investment that's it's a it's a
tricky it can be a tricky combination
but but definitely choosing the right
individuals is absolutely with the right
skill sets is absolutely important
successful businesses have many
different leadership styles there's many
responsibilities and you need to have
those people that are sharing the
various skill sets and complementing one
another and sharing the same vision and
and subscribing to the values as well
Justin it's obviously hard to elaborate
off of what they talked about but for me
it's it's it's clear value add for our
members is this going to be a
partnership that benefits our membership
base and why and then you know so
finding those areas are obviously
important and then once you find those
areas find people that align you know
our mission statement is our guiding
principles for everything we do so if
we're partnering with people they don't
align with that that's when things tend
to get messy so really you know
partnering with people that you know
it's not necessarily just a win-win for
me and whoever the partner was but I
look for partners who were doing you
know
in their community you know having more
of a broad sort of benefit you know as a
non-profit trade association is
definitely something we look for yeah
this is you know strategic relationship
strategic partnerships are often a
little bit like love you fall in love
with what you think that person can do
for your business or what you think that
business can do for your business and we
all know fools rush in yeah you think oh
this is a great idea and we can build
this business together but then the
failure to clearly articulate whose role
is what and finding people that not only
complement but in some cases fill those
gaps that you actually are not good at
the same things and don't think alike
because that can strengthen your
business if the core values are the same
so as much as we can all talk about that
perfect relationship that we always seek
how do you triangulate that that
relationship is who they say they are if
what you said just resonated with me
because there was many years in our
company we were three offices
coast-to-coast we had 20 employees and a
lot of our strategy was well let's just
get people to realize how not compliant
they are and we would call and say do
you have these SOPs and you have this or
do you have that and what I didn't
realize was we weren't really putting
our core values out there to be shared
in a way that aligned and what we got
were a lot of people that reacted to
non-compliance right rather than finding
that three or five percent of the
industry the select few out there that
wanted to be proactive about compliance
management and be in a position where
they could be proud about their
compliance and say that we can stand by
it
then so that was a very expensive lesson
to learn that if you don't vet it out or
you're not a stand for the values that
you say you are in the world you're just
gonna attract the wrong thing instead
there's something to the integrity of
yourself to in finding out who to
partner with or who to vet and how you
work with them absolutely there you
don't always necessarily know why but
your subconscious does Rocco and much of
this responsibility really falls on the
show
of leadership you know as a leader it's
important to really strive for clarity
and alignment and and to force
situations that where those things can
be measured I mean I have like I said
have been around a long time and I have
what I fondly call Rocco's ten rules of
business and and one of them is what
gets what gets measured gets done so you
have to find a way to quantify but
before you can quantify again to get
back in front of that it's really the
clarity issue because you know you can't
just as the other panel members were
saying I mean you can't just say these
are my core values you have to quantify
those core values and you have to be
very clear and the best way to to show
people you're clear is is through
demonstration not through instruction so
that that's that's key and and set that
bar high set that you only get one shot
you only get one shot so when you get a
chance to set that bar set it high yeah
I don't know the answer as far as how to
vet people because it's oftentimes it
can be trial and error but having a very
good operating agreement up front
especially in a joint venture is
absolutely imperative you definitely
want to hire a lawyer don't don't do
anything off of LegalZoom or copying and
pasting a word template off the internet
when you're doing that because they're
they have the expertise to go through
all the what-ifs with you and then get
those written down in detail of how how
are we gonna handle this if this happens
and remember to hire slowly fire fast
yes fail quickly excellent advice and
you bring up an important point because
you know in in a marriage you take vows
and let's hope you're not bowing
something that you know you're not gonna
stick to but when you're entering into a
business you also have to make vows that
these are the things that I am going to
do in this partnership this is my
statement of work what I'm responsible
for I also strongly recommend that you
state what you in two
to fail at meaning this is what I'm not
gonna do because that's where the gaps
often fall is oh I thought you were
gonna do it you thought I was gonna do
it will screw you we're going to court
and that brings me to the prenup right
the exit strategy I found when entering
into strategic partnerships that
envisioning the exit is the best way to
get to the agreement where and how is
this going to either sell or dissolve or
achieve its goal whatever that it is and
then work backwards from there and I
love for some of you to speak to that -
how do you envision the exit strategy
with respect to your strategic
partnerships for me honestly in a lot of
our partnerships I think I scare away
some partnerships in the early on stage
because I go straight to that end stage
with people right away or at least
discuss it I said well what are we
talking about four five years down the
long 10 years down the line how long are
you online how long you committing to me
are you two years are you in this for
five years are you selling in two years
you need to ask those questions upfront
to really see what the partnership is
gonna be you might have one idea of
where this partnerships going and their
idea is a completely different thing and
you might start off and everything's
great but then where you're going or
it's different and that's a big problem
so I think like it's okay to scare
someone away because that just means
it's not going to work out so just be
straight again upfront and honest of
where you're going with things to let
people out you know and I like to take a
different slant and again it's not
always successful I'm not claiming that
it is but I like to what I call create
the Hotel California situation with
partnerships you know you can check out
anytime you like but you can never leave
it's it's it's truly you know I like to
make them perpetual because you should
always be looking for a reason that you
want your partner to stay and your
partner should always be giving you a
reason that they want to stay and vice
versa so so it's always about creating
value and and you know it when you get
into a partnership it's no longer all
about you so you have to spend a lot of
time and effort in the value
the value proposition if your partner as
well as you but you know I don't spend a
lot of time on predetermined action
strategies or termination clauses or
periods of time I'd like to spend the
time and effort on the evolution of a
partnership that'll that'll last or
outlast the business and I think there's
a combination of the two there that some
people can find success in did you want
to say something on the end jasmine yeah
definitely
just make sure that the relationship
that you have with your strategic
partner the alignment of the mission
statement that is with the business and
not the person because that we've all
seen in this industry people move around
often I've worked on partnerships with
somebody for three months and then give
them a call back and they're no longer
there so definitely making sure that you
know everything is clearly obviously but
yeah definitely make sure that the
partnership is with the actual business
and not just a contact that you have a
great point absolute great point yeah
because so many people form partnerships
because it's it's in part a personal
relationship with the player and then
when that player doesn't show up at the
play first base that day and then
they're stuck because they realize it
wasn't with the business especially in
this industry right now I mean people
are moving so fast we have to try to
keep our database clean and it's it's a
it's a full-time job almost just with
how much different movement is happening
so if I ever clean out my shoe boxes of
your business cards I have your entire
work histories I know you say the other
point is get to know veterans who know
people
because usually somebody knows somebody
in this industry and there's either
gonna be a reputation that's positive
and you can count on that person being
there in the future or there's one
that's maybe not so positive and I think
it's important to ask the peers that are
in respected leadership positions
whether you should be forming strategic
partners with certain people because
it's taken a sweat blood and tears to
build what we have as brands and
reputation which are things people can't
take away but they're also double-edged
swords that can easily cut you if you
hand somebody that in trust right and
they turn it against you or it's used in
a way that
that really is detrimental rather than
sort of adding value at all yeah and
remember I mean because I mean we're
doing it then at the NC RMA I mean our
risk management platform is is so broad
that the vast majority of the risk
management services that we're offering
are through service partners one thing
to keep clearly in mind I mean you spend
a lot of time and money and effort
creating and protecting your brand as
soon as you bring a service partner on
board that person has to or that company
has to have the same obligation because
they become part of your brand there's
no separation at that point you're my
service partner and you do something
wrong that reflects badly on the brand
of the NCR mayor whatever business we're
talking about and it takes a certain
level of commitment as a partner to be
able to say I'm gonna be here for you
and that and I tell people we for
example my company we we take that stand
integrity excellence leadership our core
values and we're not here to make a
one-time checkbox happen and say you're
compliant compliance is for example an
ongoing continual process of continued
improvement it's not something that just
magically happens overnight so that's
that's at least a year-long agreement
with with our clients if not 2 to 5
because if you're the front you own that
partnership I mean there's no there's no
sidestepping the fact well you know if
you act in in for my benefit with my
members and you don't perform that's
just like me not performing indeed and I
think it's important to as you look to
these strategic relationships that you
find alignment in that the goal helps
the people involved do better the
agreement itself the partnership the
relationship has to raise all ships or
one of the partners is always getting
screwed or doing more work or wanting to
find a way out or find a way around and
so some of the more successful
relationships I've seen aren't people
that even necessarily like each other
but they have aligned common goals and
they have
a similar work ethic that when one wins
the other one wins and I think that
those are some of the most successful
long-term relationships I'm curious
because we all can talk about what to do
I want to hear what not to do and you
started tiptoeing down into this not
only is this the more interesting and
juicy topic of conversation but at
Oaksterdam we're big fans of not just
setting you up for success but preparing
you for the worst there are a lot of
potholes on the road to legalization and
regulation and you're likely to step in
one so how do you become a better
[ __ ] detector and what made you a
better one what terrible things are you
hoping they don't accidentally do I
think it's a comes in to management
styles for me at least I'm very tight
loose tight I will set the expectations
up front and let people know exactly
what I need how I need it and what I'll
do for them in return then it's a game
of integrity right showing up with your
word and actually doing it because you
said you would but I also give that
freedom and space for another
conversation to happen for things to
happen for business to happen with the
commitment of just trust respect in
place right because you have to allow
for people to show up and for people to
lift you up instead of tear you down or
whatever else they could end up doing
and it's in that loose space that I
often find that I'm discerning most
whether or not this is going to be a
valuable strategic partner and at that
point you can then come back to that
tight on the other end of that tight
loose tight and hold them accountable
and my world accountability is love
that's how I want to make sure my
clients are gonna be successful right
because they have accountability
transparency and integrity in their
business so for me that's that's kind of
how we like to operate this baby will at
least create sort of a structure that we
can figure that out we can do that dance
and figure out whether or not that
strategic partner is going to be a waste
of each other's time and money and not
be successful and it's much easier to
break up at that point or if you really
can show up on the other end of that and
take responsibility
just say you know maybe this isn't the
right time but I want to be your friend
let's wait until certain things happen
yeah Justin you see a lot of strategic
partnerships within the CCIA and I'd
love to hear a little bit and then go to
Justin Bo ta right after my Justin's on
the end yeah I mean we touched on this a
little bit but seeing partnerships be
formed without the right documentation
is really really bad obviously when I
was new with this you know I formed a
partnership for an event with a person
the deliverables on both sides weren't
clear and the MOU slipped things like
that and then you know the whole program
whatever it is so obviously learned the
hard way that way and then just really
making sure yeah
that you know that their side of things
because you could be very clear with
what you want out of the partnership but
really making sure that you're clear on
what they want out of it to be able to
you know not just work for six months
but work for three to five years because
when it's very clear on both sides
people are I mean yeah you don't
necessarily have to like each other but
you're you're invested you know a little
bit deeper level than just a business
perspective when you truly care about
what you're doing and that that slips a
lot too so my experience as far as this
goes
often comes from the investor operator
relationship there's the the person with
the money and there's the person with
the knowledge and oftentimes the people
with the knowledge leave with the money
and the people with the money leave with
the knowledge I don't know if you've
heard that one before
so it's very important that as an
investor you stay active in the business
you you you get a you get a hold of the
bookkeeping maybe cloudbase book and
you're always staying diligent as far as
how the expenditures are going you want
to make sure that the policies and
procedures are going correct again
there's people with different skill sets
that should be being employed in
good a successful business there's the
people who do our systems oriented
there's the visionary there's the person
who deals with the employees and and is
it facilitates um you want all of those
things going well and as an investor you
want to stay involved in that to make
sure that your money is is being spent
properly and then the one thing that I
the big thing that I like to warn people
about especially from an investor
perspective is oftentimes this is
totally like kind of going off in a
different direction
but if you're considering buying a
business or you got a I'll always take
into consideration the tax ramifications
of that yeah because because like people
think that like maybe buying a
dispensary is a really great idea
because it looks profitable on a cash
flow but just wait until that - return
gets done it's really bad bad stuff yeah
before you enter into any relationship
with anyone or any entity there are
several tax organizations that you're
gonna want to double-check their history
because you could be getting into bed
with someone that did not understand
280e
and now you are marrying into their tax
liabilities Rocco you know another
another point when considering a
partnership because many times when when
we consider partners I mean we approach
it very much like we're hiring key
employees or hiring employees so so a
danger is i mean don't don't focus only
on the cognitive because i mean like
many of us guilty of it for years until
i discovered the true value of talent
optimization but like many of us you
know we when we hire somebody we we
interview them and we ask them the
technical questions and we look at their
resume we check their reverence
references and all the cognitive skills
are there but but the relationship
doesn't work out because of you know the
behavioral side and we don't take the
time and effort or implement the tools
that we need to properly evaluate the
the behavioral side I mean it's like you
know we're hired for what we know and
we're fired for who we are so it's
equally important from a
partner standpoint you need to
understand not only the the cognitive
skill set of your partnership but also
the behavior skill set because that's
where it goes south I mean how many
times has a partnership truly gone south
because the person or the company that
you partnered with didn't know what you
thought they know very seldom because
that's what we vet what we don't fit is
how they behave what's important how
they're motivated how they think how
dominant they are how they communicate
patience our impatience formality so
that's an area that I think we have to
spend much more time in in developing
partnerships that do become perpetual I
was just gonna say don't be fooled by by
perception and you should fact check
because sometimes you can lead into what
people are saying and want to believe it
and that want to believe leads you to
believe it rather than actually doing
your homework and taking out the books
and whatever factual evidence you need
to make the right choice well thank you
for that segue because I would add to
everything that you said educate
yourself you know do the homework to not
just know your business but their
business know just enough to know what
keeps them up at night what are their
goals and responsibilities in that
strategic partnership I try to explain
to folks well I'm just going into the
business of cannabis I'm just going to
be ancillary or just just just yes but
you have to know what the growers are
dealing with what the patient's are
dealing with in order to be truly the
best dispensary including your bottom
line so educating yourself on the entire
supply chain but also the rights and
responsibilities is this person a
fiduciary does this person have other
responsibilities that you need to be
aware of that might involve agencies
where they're forced into certain
behavior because that's what's required
of them that you might not understand or
expect as a Candace can a business owner
I'm curious what keeps you guys up at
night I'll start with you what keeps you
up at night over your strategic
partnerships
I guess they like keeps me up at night
is what like worrying about or keeps me
I worry about oh no I don't worry much I
sleep well I shouldn't have started with
you yeah who wants to answer that well
take a stab at it
so I got into this because I'm
passionate about what Candice cannabis
can do for people and in ending right
the war on drugs and sort of the world
of the advocacy side of things like you
did Dale back in the day right so
there's a much bigger thing than me even
involved here we just do the most boring
non sexy thing a marijuana called
compliance because it's a stand for
integrity and transparency and
professionalism in our industry so it
keeps me up at night is that we're in
this very unique in each position in
which we deal with the investor and the
white-collar sort of world of things and
I don't just mean that figuratively
they're mostly like rich white men and
then there's the other side of it which
is the cannabis industry where people
came from for a lot of years going
through the war on drugs and the war
against cannabis and I think what keeps
me up at night is trying to get those
two worlds to really understand and
speak the same language and be able to
communicate their sets of expectations
to each other so that their strategic
partnerships can work because we
actually need both for this thing to
become what it can become and so as a
compliance person I often think and
worry about sort of what can we do with
regard to social equity I said on
national cannabis industry associations
equity diversity inclusion committee
being half Brazilian myself doing a lot
of work in Latin America how can we
raise other countries up that have been
most impacted by the war on drugs so
some of these are what I'm looking for
strategic partners when it comes to
aligning values and what you're really
up to but also how can compliance become
the dictionary thesaurus the translator
between those two worlds and create that
level of accountability and integrity
that both sides need to be able to have
with a
and sometimes that's the only language
is the one written for attorneys by
attorneys that we then need to translate
throughout the rest of the organization
and get into place in a way that is
going to make those strategic partners
work right in that business grow I love
that you are reminding us all to be
thoughtful about who we look for to
partner that it sometimes takes a moment
longer to look a little harder to find a
veteran a person of color a woman I'm
married to a white guy I have two young
sons and a daughter
I hope one of them gets turns into a
rich white white guy someday but it's
about seeking out the not obvious
opportunities and often these are going
to be your best relationships for sure
Rocco you know strictly from a
professional and from a risk management
perspective what I find most challenging
in in tackling this you know this
elephant in the room is they're
different from other industries of which
I've played that many of us have played
that they're much more traditional
there's really two types of risk in
cannabis there and we were talking about
this in the green room there's the
internal risk which is the risk that is
truly inherent in owning and operating a
cannabis business but then much much and
if it was just simply left at that we'd
have the problem solved but but the real
problem comes in is is differentiating
and defining the external risk and
that's all the risk that is inflicted on
the cannabis business owner because
they've chosen cannabis as a way to make
a living and we need to you know from
from an association that focuses on risk
management we spend a lot of time
differentiating those and and believe me
the latter is is much more difficult in
terms of coming up with service partners
and solutions to to help our members
advance the ball thank you Justin yeah
what keeps me up at night is definitely
I want my clients to be successful and
it's it's the the bureaucratic
environment the compliance can by
environment sometimes it's almost like
you have to like break rules in order to
also follow rules at the same time I
think in California it's like ninety
ninety percent of businesses are out of
compliance right now one way or another
and I mean I can give you example like
banking right now is very difficult to
secure it's very expensive in my home
region of Southern Oregon there is no
THC banking available unless you want to
go to Salem which is quite north but
then the tax the federal government
requires that you pay certain taxes
electronically so how do you how do you
do that well maybe you get a personal a
bank account start commingling funds I'd
never recommend doing that but like how
do you answer to all of these things
it's very difficult and so you know
that's what keeps me up at night thank
you yeah for me I think empathy like
actually caring about the members
because when I'm forming strategic
partnerships it's to directly offer
services benefits to our entire
membership base so it's not just a
partnership of mine it's potentially a
partnership of all 500 businesses that
are involved so really doing your
homework and not forming a strategic
partnership that's gonna you know screw
over a dozen members and then it's gonna
be a sticky situation and our
credibility gets hit and everything like
that so it's a little bit different from
an association standpoint because our
partnerships are to facilitate
partnerships and when there's that
snowball effect if it's good that's
great if it's bad it could get messy
well and I'd like to circle back to
something that a couple of you touched
on which is that mission and
understanding not just your mission but
the mission of your strategic
partnerships that a mission is not just
something that you pay to etched on the
wall behind you that people like clock
in and clock out as they walk by and
ignore it and stop seeing it for years
and years your mission statement is
actually what you bounce all your
decisions off of does this make
it needs to be a living breathing
decision of this is how we do business
you may also have a vision statement
that helps you you know delineate a few
more things but at the end of the day
that's not just something that you write
down and put aside that is what you can
use to determine whether or not these
strategic relationships or partnerships
are beneficial to your core mission and
your core goals and for the school our
mission is to provide quality training
for the cannabis industry but at the end
of the day I bounce it off of three
things every time what's best for the
students what's best for the staff and
faculty and what's best for the school
in that order there might be something
that's amazing for the students and it
will destroy if it's gonna kill the
people that have to execute it it's not
a good deal because these are the folks
that you need to embrace and drive it
forward if those two things are there
but it's gonna break your bottom line
then maybe you need to bring in another
strategic relationship like an investor
or a CPA or some tax advice but if you
can figure out that core goal and then
bounce off do you measure up to who we
are who we say we are and what we say
we're trying to do I'd say 9/10 decide
right then and there if this is right or
not and now you know who to focus on and
that last thing I'm gonna say it again
decide what you're not gonna be any good
at this is one of the most valuable
lessons I am still trying to learn so
many shiny objects so many amazing
people and some of these shiny objects
are gold they are raw diamonds and some
is fool's gold
right so I'm not saying shiny objects
are bad but if you have a way to pan for
the gold that is your mission these are
your core values that helps you pan for
the gold just like you two know this can
be successful we can do this together
and it will be good for everybody with
that it is now for 25 I think we nailed
it folks
and I just genuinely want to thank the
audience everybody that was here for
participating in this thank you so much
for being part of our panel have a
beautiful afternoon yeah absolutely
we'll stick around
quite sure too