and now this panel
that we're going to discuss forming
strategic Partnerships and to lead this
panel the CEO and founder and introduce
the consultant for the New Holland group
let's hear for Jamie Pearson
[Applause]
[Music]
hello hello come on people oh we're not
gonna have photos okay
that's great
[Music]
this chair feels amazing
just so you know
it's comfortable oh wow it's nice it's
lovely
I love it
I like the color
I'm so happy you all stayed here
and waited to the very end and we'll see
all of you at the party and I want to
say thank you to the ICBC we're gonna
Dive Right In
we'll wait till all those people up
there get out
okay I'm kidding but yeah get out if
you're gonna talk bye okay
oh yes awesome oh wow it makes it easier
for everybody in the crowd if we sit in
front of our pictures right
okay so we're gonna do first is I'm
gonna have uh my esteemed panel
introduce themselves everybody here is
an expert in forming strategic
Partnerships and that's what we're here
to talk about but I'm gonna let them
introduce themselves and talk about who
they are and what they do
I'm George Terry I'm the Executive Vice
President of radsource Technologies we
are a photonic decontamination company
that works on making sure that there's a
clean supply of cannabis flour without
Gamma or e-beam
hi everybody my name is Pedro morenco I
come from Pharmacy company from Slovenia
we are producers and manufacturers of
premium cosmetic products and food
supplements I'm
we do a different a bit of different
approach because I'm passionate about
clean cosmetics and clean life so we
don't use anything toxic in our products
and
um
uh it's a pleasure to be here thank you
hello everyone thanks for sticking
around until the end of the day with us
um Brian passman Hunter Esquire we're an
executive Search firm we're Headhunters
we do human capital advisory we started
in 2017 to serve the Cannabis industry
uh we expanded into psychedelics in 2020
we recruit globally on any role in the
Cannabis or psychedelics ecosystem
primarily focused on Executive
leadership placement
hi everybody I'm Dr John my company
United science basically puts people
into the business of cannabis production
we do engineering we do we do equipment
we do technology
and we have been involved in tremendous
number of different partnering and JVS
and all kinds of things so really
excited to be on this panel and just
kind of talk about what's worked and
what hasn't
great
um I have to tell you just uh well I'll
introduce myself I'm Jamie Pearson
um as ungayo said I'm a consultant I do
Global consultancy now I was the CEO of
bang for those of you who know bang
chocolate I did that job for three years
after seven years of being in the
company I left and people have been
asking me to help them bring their
companies to Europe and my specific
Target this trip was finding some of the
bigger players that were wanting to do
deals around 50 to 200 million dollars
like the big players that are going to
come conquer this Market I came to find
you so if you're out there come find me
um and I think the reason that I've been
successful in the Cannabis industry is
that I believe 100 that we are not
competitors we are colleagues and when
people know each other and they connect
their networks that's when magic happens
so I'd like to start by asking George
I'm going to just go in order because
it's easier I'm linear it's just kind of
how my brain works
um
could you name a time that you've
formed a partnership that was really
beneficial to your company and were
there challenges in getting that
partnership formed and if so how did you
overcome them
sure so just recently we we form a
partnership with Belushi Farms oh hang
on one second
okay that was a panelist I was about to
go off on somebody out there
you get a pass everybody shut off your
phones please okay start over but that's
passman why does he get a pass
it wasn't passed when it was Dr John but
you gave Dr John a pass but that's
password fair enough okay you said the
energetic you have to be entertaining
all the day everyone's dying so recently
we just did a a partnership with Belushi
Farms so Jim Belushi does a show on on
um Discovery called growing Belushi and
they're doing a a a cannabis Rescue in
Illinois
we met him in MJ bizcon in Las Vegas
they had a problem with uh with uh the
flower was very dirty they were not
passing aspergillus cfu
um and we we have the the equipment that
can fix that so we formed this
partnership with them we worked with
them the obstacles to overcome are
mainly regulations within the state of
Illinois
um you know working together with them
uh understanding what their scope was
when our scope was what we could offer
but the bottom line is together we
formed a union that's going to be able
to help this failing Farm in Illinois
and so there's 10 vendors in there so
there's a lighting vendor that's
actually here as well
yeah fos and a couple other vendors that
are helping them out they have the
nutrient one they have one for hydration
but this is a really good strategic
um uh partnership that we have with
these guys because not only are we
helping them but they're helping us as
far as the image of the of
decontamination in general well I can
imagine it's a bad deal when you're
Belushi's Farm you're high profile and
then you have someone say your flower is
dirty nobody wants to hear that that can
really harm a company and then you
provide a solution that's where a
strategic partnership was a win-win and
that's the other thing I think win-win
is the key because even if you could
um get a home run but you make sure the
other side has the win that's when the
Partnerships last forever
so Petra same question uh great
Partnerships
um that you could name and then if
there's been a part an obstacle
um you know or when you have to vet
somebody talk to us about that well
um we were lucky to find a really good
partner from Portugal cannoli canoli is
the name of the company and
um it's funny how in every business it's
hard to find a
partner that has the same
goals that you do the mentality oriented
in the similar business eventually it's
all about the money but when it comes to
that there are so many steps to get
there and sometimes gut feeling is the
thing that gets you going and I think
if we still listen to that I think that
we're safe there
um
it's really a challenge to to do this
especially in cannabis business I think
um because a lot of people come into
this just because okay cannabis who see
the benefits and the prices go and we
will earn a lot of money and so on
and um there are a lot of people that
don't actually mean something
um but we we kind of got lucky and we're
really hoping to develop a really nice
strategic partnership with them and what
do they do exactly uh they do different
things they do medical cannabis
facilities now
but they have their connection and their
Distributors for
um
products that we make
so they make you make the product and
they distribute them in Europe yes and
how did you find them
actually they found me through ICBC
pitch that I had and on I was there for
that investment Global investment Forum
that I had uh three years ago I think it
was three years ago and
um we took a while it's I think every
partnership takes a while and you cannot
do anything through the night but
um we were picky too so we didn't go for
the first one who came and I think it's
really important who you choose to
represent you and to represent your
products and if someone does that it's
important that it stands
that it has the same principles that you
do you have you have
for sure some people want speed to
Market some people want price protection
whatever it is you want you've got to
find the right partner and the
corporation is really important so the
communication we can adjust to a lot of
things and we can
um for example we can
um
have someone uh
say how it goes in the different markets
and so on but I think it's really
important too that we
um for me as a brand
Ambassador as a brand presentation
presenter
that I need to be involved also in those
kind of business with strategic
Partnerships because it's eventually
it's
at the end of the day it's the brand
that sells so it must be important it's
really important who you choose and how
how they do it
Brian is a headhunter
and I'm thinking about
um when I was running bang and I was
using recruitment services to place
Executives naturally you're going to be
a strategic partner for me because I'm
going to tell you everything I need and
you got to go find that person
but I also found working with you that
partnership was different
because it was truly a partnership it
was not just here's the task go jump
through the hoop so talk to me about how
headhunters for companies can be
strategic Partners in ways that people
in the audience maybe aren't aware of
sure yeah and I agree with everything
you said earlier about
um
Partnerships coming through uh building
relationships getting to know each other
which is I think how all of our
strategic Partnerships came about like
we knew each other socially really well
before we started working together and
I've got loads of great stories from
consuming weird stuff on mountaintops
with people that became clients to uh
stories Galore we have a
fun I think real quick on my strategic
partnership story because I have a I
have a fun one
um again the the guys that run the
Canadian Securities Exchange are pretty
fun to hang out with
and they approached us at a gathering in
Miami Beach a year or two ago and asked
if we would mind being listed on their
website as a search partner and I said
wow what's that going to cost I don't
know thanks a lot and they said no no we
know you you place a lot of the people
that a lot of our clients need you would
actually be doing us a favor
if we can just refer someone to you
instead of trying to help them hire
their Chief accounting officer whomever
they needed
so obviously a big win for us we got a
lot of business from that and in a funny
way a win for them because they didn't
have to try to be recruiters so now
everyone wants to try to be a recruiter
as their Hobby
so having a good uh recruiter as a
strategic partner rather than a vendor
is a benefit to our clients and
companies that use recruiters in a
similar partnership way because they're
your eyes and ears out there they're
talking everyone in the industry they're
driving business your way our clients
get referrals from us all of the time I
I don't and I don't like to monetize
every introduction their success is our
success there's a reason my LinkedIn
pronoun is super connector I just love
making introductions and I think my
partner wishes I'd monetize more them
but I don't think I would have the
Goodwill that we have right this you
have to build up a lot of Goodwill
currency in your bank account in this
industry to keep the Partnerships huge
yeah it's huge yeah so uh yeah that's
that's all I have to say on that
okay so
um
I'm kind of a fan girl of Dr John he
doesn't know that but I just disclosed
it
um he's kind of a big deal it's it's
kind of funny
um he's doing a lot of pharmaceutical
work and I think that's going to be big
in Europe because I think where cannabis
in America in most of the states started
from medical cannabis
I think it's different though here where
the medical element of it really does
require eugmp
API you know actual pharmaceutical
ingredients have to be run through uh
pharmaceutical grade technology so my
question to you is you have these
companies in Europe and in the U.S that
are pharmaceutical companies that's what
you're working with right how do you how
do you help them get launched in
cannabis so we help them on many many
different levels and it's not just
products uh coming from us to them it is
or even services
for example we might connect a grower in
one region under gacp with a GMP
producer in Europe or we might connect a
a U.S investor that that wants to get
into the eugmp world with a
pharmaceutical company and a and a and a
grower we've done all of those
connections and sometimes we're involved
in the transaction sometimes it's just a
you know hey here we know this guy
you're looking for this this other guy
it seems to work it's it's
um it's kind of a a nice way to do that
and it allows them to grow their
business and we we get the social cred
and we also get the business credit in
the in the in the process of that
um and one of the things that we've
really been work working on is making
sure that you know the products that we
have are are applicable and to the
pharmaceutical world and um one example
of of uh you know a very good JV that we
just went through recently is a company
where uh we're using our technology
which is basically CO2 and we're using
that to create water-soluble uh products
for formulations which we weren't in
before but it's just like one step away
from what we do and it's using our
technology it was a Canadian company the
company is called isolate and rjv is
isolate USA JV and we're basically
providing them access to the market
access to Pharmaceuticals access to
Europe and European customers they're
actually operating in our facility
um and so it's been it's really great
and then they they brought they brought
you know tobacco companies to us and
with a bunch of tobacco money so it's
stuff that I never could have connected
myself but now we're creating all kinds
of apis based on uh you know nicotine
for example interesting right uh that
has nothing to do with cannabis but we
also do cannabis work and connecting
those people now with um with our
customers so
um I think that we we always look at
um you know JV Partners or a gent joint
venture partners with you know does it
fit strategically does it fulfill a need
in both of our portfolios
and it can we work work together do we
like each other you know that type of
stuff all of that's important do you
like single malt scotch or not you know
that type of thing if you want to see
their name come across your phone or
you're not like oh it's that guy right
oh not him again oh yeah so I get to
talk to them yes it doesn't work with
the rest of the team too and do the
cultures really work well together
um you know we when we do JV work
um you know we have uh basically the
teams get integrated and if their
culture doesn't match your culture uh
just in the way they work or that won't
work I mean that's the most fundamental
thing so there has to be a culture match
with that with a joint venture
Partnerships so I think culture is the
most important
First Fundamental piece if I was going
to give every one of you a piece of
advice because everyone loves
unsolicited advice
um it would be that you have to open
your mind
to the possibility of a connection I
really believe that if you think
everyone that comes at you as a
colleague and not a competitor and you
think because I think sometimes people
are like well that person's competitive
to me well you may be competitive in one
thing that you overlap and then if you
do become Partners you figure out you
either retain that peace do it yourself
but if you can figure out how to make
that person
uh their gaps fill your gaps you become
stronger but you have to be willing to
give up a little bit of something and
that might be control
um you know some of us have control
issues I don't know I don't have control
issues but some of us do anybody want to
add something
I think that the biggest thing is
understanding what your strength is and
where you exceed and and nobody's going
to do it by themselves all right
especially in this industry and in most
Industries so you've got to really
understand where you need the help and
it's got to be a symbiotic relationship
where you're going to help them they're
going to help you we do it with
Regulators I do it with some of the
states in the U.S we've got Consultants
that we work with as well uh it's what I
give you and what you give me and
sometimes you're going to give me more
sometimes I'm going to give you more but
at the end we're both going to be rising
and we're not going to be you have to be
generous and you have you have to be
willing to give more and be generous it
always pays you back we've had
competitors that we've we've worked with
competitors where we provide products
that they don't have actually for
Downstream processing
um and you know it works works well
um they're not afraid to help your
competitor no I've had calls with them
and yeah no we you talk in shows like
this are really great for meeting people
and you know it's on a it's on a
personal basis so but
and I love oh
I love what you're saying and that you
operate that way and how you answer the
other question it sounds like you're
you're You're Building uh ecosystems
within your strategic partner
communities which is important I just
wanted to
um also add that what is really great I
think one of the big overriding themes
of conversations I've had today hearing
about people that are setting up in
Europe is the idea of coopetition
which
um seems to be something that the
European cannabis Community is grasping
because it's so challenging here and
that has been missing a lot for the most
part outside aside from what you're
saying we're saying up here has been
missing in in the American cannabis
industry uh it's more like crabs in a
barrel and I think the co-op position
attitude everyone's taking here is
really really key it's
um and if if you're not afraid to refer
uh business and clients and whatnot
around it it it comes back it's just
again I'll I'll probably mention a dozen
more times just the whole Goodwill thing
it's a it's a big small community and
coopetition is where it's at
Petra no I just wanted to add something
with uh regarding the competition for us
for example the competition is a Target
customer
because they need products and I know
I'm the first one to know how bad it is
if you don't have a good product on the
market and I know their their needs so I
think to to know what you do best like
George said before is the key key
ingredient to to adjust to the
risky competition yeah I love that I
mean you're all basically saying the
same thing coopetition helping a
competitor knowing your strengths it's
basically being generous with your
spirit with your time in cannabis we
have to do that we all need help but
we're talking about it what I don't
think everybody realizes
is that these two gentlemen at the end
are doing a strategic partnership with
that microphone
right oh yeah so they're they're
actually doing it
that was a cute observation
okay I want to know if there's any
questions from the audience for our
group I don't know when does our panel
end
never it's good it's ongoing we're stuck
here I think it's when the drinks are
ready right I just want are we done at
five are we done at 5 15 do you know
oh you have a question
tour this is tour hamler of uh green
Nexus seed salt
when you get new opportunities
to work with people
[Music]
that's a great question okay so do you
have a process for evaluating new um
opportunities absolutely absolutely it
is absolutely disciplined okay because
first of all
um like like in my business we have we
can go in a hundred different directions
we could have you know ingredients
company from DuPont calling us you know
asking us to do something we have uh
like fermentation we have uh
fermentation companies we have um let's
say oil and gas companies no kidding uh
so when you have broad-based
Technologies you get and you do
broad-based marketing you're gonna get
in a a whole bunch of different uh types
of uh you know inquiries okay and and
requests so how do you sift through all
those to make a disciplined approach
well you really have to start first with
your strategy in mind you you must have
a company strategy and and your vision
for your company uh you you should have
that in a three-year goal uh what What's
our company going to look like you need
to describe what that looks like uh to
to your employees to your business
development people and then
um you need to have your company values
really well established so that you can
understand okay well maybe that doesn't
fit because that's not in our company
value oil and gas company comes to us
we're a sustainable company okay we you
know let them go do their with what
they're going to do okay the last thing
I would say is you really back in the
90s everybody was doing these strategy
Maps Okay and I think it's a really
great discipline it has allowed us to
follow a market strategy which is okay
we're going to invest in the Cannabis
Market that's an that's a market
strategy and then we tie that to a
product strategy with a strategy map
okay well here's the process here's what
it looks like at one step one step two
step three and we just look upstream and
downstream of that and Upstream Upstream
of where we're operating those are
potential Partnerships Downstream of
where we're operating those are
potential Partnerships because they um
they not only we can provide Channel but
if they're not Market stream or
Downstream then then they're out then
they're out yeah they yeah there's also
a triage committee on this
um and usually you have to have your
Executives involved in that okay are we
going to go after this Market or are we
not right you can't do everything and I
I tell you the truth that if you are
very focused in on uh success with one
single Market strategy it is a superior
strategy I mean it it just is so like
Market strategies are really great we
have lots of different products
everybody up here has lots of different
products
um you know I think you're right because
in the Cannabis industry we say it's
easy to get the something shiny syndrome
right because there's opportunity
everywhere right and if Chinese if
you're like constantly being distracted
by this that or the other thing if you
have one strategy and you do that one
thing and you do it really well that's a
good item for quarterly goals so the
other thing is we have a framework
process also that we run I mean we have
quarterly meetings with our with our top
staff okay and then also on r d r d is
where all this stuff comes in right and
you get all the great ideas every idea
goes on a list and we we process it and
according to uh according to a process
and uh and then you bump it up against
your values your part your strategy yes
all that the purpose of strategy is to
kill stuff you know that's the purpose
of strategy so you can kill it because
there's too many ideas there's too many
markets uh to go after there's too many
um different potential Partnerships
they're they're all over the place so
the question is which ones make the most
sense for your organization which ones
will fit with your organization and fill
in gaps and which where where the joint
venture will be profitable for both
entities and you know we don't I think
that I would say early in my career we
had a less disciplined way of doing JVS
and those are those are all gone all of
those JVS are gone they either didn't
work or they weren't you know Partners
weren't right or whatever focus focus is
the thing and and make sure you do a
process run the process because uh even
with a two-man company or a two lady
company or whatever even with a small
company you can you can follow a market
strategy and you can still say here's my
values here's my three-year goal and and
here's my big rocks that I'm going to be
working on and review those every
quarter so that you don't get off track
because you can destroy your business
pursuing a dream of someone else and you
don't want to do that
any other questions out there oh there's
one back there
please yes
is okay wait I'm coming with a
microphone here I come sorry
it was 420 you guys it's like the price
is right here come on down
thank you so my name is Umberto I'm from
Portugal working on uh mainly on the
hemp business but also on medical
cannabis my main question uh of so many
questions I would ask you all and by the
way thank you so much George Terry for
being probably one of the the only
representative of uh other genetic human
groups here I don't mean to to blame the
fact that uh what about ungayo yes but
especially today it looks like large
story we look alike yeah
so my main question is we've seen a lot
of movements lately uh it looks like
Colombia for example was being hauled
for so long oh no exportations clever
leaves broke that
and now we have South America
providing the Western the Northern
Western Hemisphere
also on the hemp side let me tell you
Zimbabwe is provided in providing to
Europe
uh very very cheap the question is I'm
formulating if you allow me he's selling
a lot of CBD African CBD to Europe now
for extractions so this show at least
suggests that in the near future all
these billionaire Investments that are
being being done in North America and in
Europe have their days count so what
strategies to adapt to a point where
cannabis is a commodity being
cheaply produced in the southern
hemisphere what's the strategy for the
companies here in the Northern Western
Hemisphere to that thank you
well from my perspective we're actually
we actually have a unit Columbia where
put units in Canada and we're now almost
GMP here in the EU
we've actually
uh contracted with consultants in the in
this area much like Jamie
um to bring us into this this uh this
area the key thing and and I said this
in Berlin is know your regulatory
landscape know what you what's required
of you of what you have to do and the
partners that you'll need to get you
there so when we first came in to the EU
at ICBC in Berlin two years ago we
didn't know anything got a consultant
that knew the market brought on
attorneys in Germany in Dusseldorf and
other Consultants brought in a
consultant in Canada that for us to get
IQ oqpq so that we were able to to do
the GMP process so we knew I knew we
weren't going to do it alone
um you have to understand what you're
what you need from those people and set
timelines for example you know
I said this is not going to be a
three-year process I want this to be a
one-year process it ended up being a
two-year process so set a timeline have
milestones and just involve other people
pick the right people it might cost you
some money
all right also
um we also have people that are in the
industry like uh Xavier you know the
um he's been excellent to us you know
he's he's connected us to a lot of the
people in this room and Maria and
um and some of the other people that are
very famous in this room in the Cannabis
world so events like this are very
important guys because you get to
network with people and you get to learn
about other people's business of what
their other hurdles are and what their
other strategies are and you get the
Intelligence on what's going on hey you
know malta's moving ahead of Germany
really
you know who's yeah that's where the
Consultants LeapFrog you
um they might cost you some money but
the time that you spend figuring it out
for yourself costs you the same money
but time is value I mean it's the the
compounding factor for a lot of that I
would say to answer your question
um I would mimic what George is saying
that you you need to know what all the
compliance things are so for example
when the German regulation the draft
regulations came out and they said they
were not allowing import
understanding why is that the draft
regulation and then
perhaps hiring a regulatory consultant
to go do some lobbying to get the law
changed so that you can get your product
in or find the work around maybe you get
your product into Portugal do the EU GMP
certified dance and then get that
product can go somewhere else there's
always a workaround if you find it but
you got to know what the rules are I I
would say that
you're right South America I have a
client that's a Colombian company that's
currently working in Switzerland they're
producing great cannabis so cheaply
but it isn't welcome right now
for a lot of reasons and some of that is
if you're in Germany and you're going to
have an industry and the EU is not going
to approve you because you can't cross
borders they're waiting for that EU
approval and that might be one of the
hurdles so right now Germans are saying
maybe we're not going to have border
crossing for rec but they will have it
for adult or for medical so it just
boils down to knowing what the rules are
yeah I think I would also begin with the
end I mean you you want to be in the
growing area you want to leverage maybe
some land that you have or uh you're
looking at the market saying wow this is
supposed to have a very high come on a
new growth rate okay so I want to be in
this market okay why don't you begin
with the end go go get your takeoffs go
go get the takeoff agreements go get the
contracts
um you know you know go do your business
development up front just make sure that
you have that uh you know that base
business if you rely on distribution
after the fact you you're way behind the
eight ball That's a classic mistake yeah
I'm gonna grow some weed it's going to
be great now I've got a bunch of weed
right okay what do I do with it that
doesn't work I mean it just doesn't your
your weed's gonna sit there for a year
and and it's not going to be sold so
what you need to do is is go do that
business development first you should be
hitting all the shows you should be on
the ultimate networker you should be you
know before you start growing anything
and you know a lot of people like oh how
do you find those people all right how
do I find that well okay LinkedIn is
awesome you guys everybody here has uh I
mean we're we're a LinkedIn Stars right
okay so go on LinkedIn and find and
start a conversation everything starts
with the conversation yep Petra yeah
it's the same with our business so when
you do a product you you firstly the the
main thing that you need to know is who
is your customer and customer and why
are you doing this for them and what are
you doing for them that is I think
that's really important to know and
we actually are lucky to have Slovenia
being so small so we have a 2 million
population to test right the things and
um it's really
interesting how some products don't do
that well on the market when you thought
that would be a hit or a bomb and this
will sell really well usually it's up
the opposite and it's nice to know where
where the where to go and to adjust
quickly
um because the time difference that
comes from one product to another
product is really important so
um when you place something on a market
you should always be ready to make
adjustment really fast and I think
that's the key one of the key things to
be successful in but not to create more
business too and it's a risky business
because we don't know what will happen
tomorrow with the regulations so it's
the it's the Catch-22 you need to be
ready to Pivot quickly yeah
um but that is expensive so you want to
you want to buy packaging at scale and
then you buy a hundred thousand boxes
ouch and then regulation changes
don't do that but at the same time yeah
you know you got to be ready you have to
predict some things that could happen
and you have to have deep enough Pockets
yeah to allow for things to not go right
A lot of times the regulations and
that's my big thing because that's all I
deal with is regulations between 50
states and however many countries is
they telepath and I'm not going to
figure it out sitting in Atlanta Georgia
or Fort Lauderdale that's where my
friends in the industry call me up and
they say hey did you hear what's going
on with these guys or hey did you hear
what's going on in Michigan or Colorado
or whatever
those are the kind of Partnerships those
are the kind of friendships you want to
make in Colombia you know what's going
on in Canada what's going on in the EU
these are the kind of events where you
can make those those uh those those
friendships so that you know hey I know
somebody who's in Canada or I know
somebody who's in Slovenia or I know
somebody who's in you know the U.S
um and and let me reach out to them and
see if they've heard anything well and I
always I can't tell you how many times
today I said to people don't assume I
know I would rather hear the same piece
of information 40 times than never hear
it because everyone's like oh Jamie
already knows that if you hear something
and you think
somebody needs to know it be a resource
share the information
I think that's important what time is it
and when do we end it is 5 16 and we end
at 5 15 but if there's one more question
one more question from the audience is
there one more oh why do you wait
Greg Dunaway Maple Creek Consulting what
can we do for you
as the industry scales up you're one of
the top Recruiters in the United States
what are the pivotal positions for
people in Europe that you see either
being filled poorly as companies scale
in the U.S or are difficult to place for
you
wow
um way to save the easy one
uh I mean so we we we do live in the
constant state of being called on to
fill the the difficult to fill roles
that's where I want to live I don't want
our clients to just feel like they have
to call us with everything uh you know
um and I don't know so I actually had
this conversation earlier with some
other people I don't know if the
European market is there yet but really
difficult to fill roles are head of
legal how to finance we do a lot of
those I don't it a lot of people here
told me that the market here is not
mature enough to eat a lot of that
hiring but those are really difficult to
fill roles I don't know if it'll be as
difficult in Europe as it's been in the
states for CFOs in particular because of
the current state of the industry with
Federal prohibition because that's a
really risky role you're asking someone
to take on a lot of risk and put their
name on a lot of signature on a lot of
things that maybe haven't been done
before are you filling them with the
infractional people uh not yet not yet
but we we do expect more of that to
happen and a lot of those uh
professionals are more and more and more
interested in fractional roles and
outside the U.S role and then are you
bringing Americans with that experience
over to Europe I look forward to it okay
good to know I think we're done here
um we appreciate you all being here and
if any of you need anything look at this
group they're amazing let's hear it all
again for a fantastic fan uh panelists
we thank you all for coming to the
international cannabis business
conference in Barcelona 2023 shout out
to the auditory de cornea shout out to
ispire for being our title sponsor shout
out to Spanish for having us over shout
out to all of you for coming to support
we'll see you at the after party tonight
at the Arts Hotel uh starts at nine
o'clock and we'll see you in Berlin my
name is thank you all so very much see
you later
thank you