we're doing good all right it's 3:00 uh
shout out who's been here all day raise
your hands you're G's I can't
believe you who just got here because
you were out all last night just me
great um I'm David DS I'm a senior
editor at Leaf Ley thanks for being here
for the ICBC panel on forming strategic
Partnerships I'm going to go ahead and
let our panelists introduce themselves
real fast go ahead take it away Desiree
hi everyone my name is desray and I'm an
intuitive and Behavioral transperson
psychoanalyst um I'm also a published
author on the crosscultural study of
depression the universality of it and
its
medicalization I am also the um vice
president and director of the human
resources with a transformative Wellness
Retreat and a
distributorship company
which is Health self and what we have
there are all ancient uh healing plants
we wearing a lot of hats out of San
Diego Des I do plenty Sunny take it away
yes thank you I'm Sony mut one of the
partners at cultivators from the
Netherlands we're active in grown
consultancy and cultivation cannabis
research and
education George hit it George tanv CE
of com com is a European BAS based
company uh for 25 years into the
fragrance and flavor the last 10 years
into cannabis developed proprietary
technology under the trademark of pure
five for extraction of cannabis at uh
ambient conditions full tping profile
and uh preserving all V vitalities of
the plant Comer's in like 40 50 states
in the US and going hard in Europe this
year
Nathan hi uh I'm Nathan Kroger I'm with
rad Source Technologies we are a medical
device company that has as of about
eight years ago expanded into the
Cannabis industry and our equipment is
used to sanitize cannabis flour
primarily so that um people can pass
microbial testing and reduce risk for
people who have compromised immune
systems really diverse set of panelists
but I think one thing that we can all
relate to is the idea of forming
Partnerships uh I wanted you raise your
hands if you ever been in a bad
partnership in business or in your
personal life in your life reflect on
those for a moment right now everyone
cackles I remember doing events with
some with a team and uh on one project
and you're like gosh I can't believe I
got into this boat we need to get to the
other side of the lake so I can get out
of this boat as soon as I can um to
start about um strategic Partnerships
Sunny cultivators is working uh as a
project manager on 12 um different
companies that have different parts of
growing as part of the world horta
center how did that project how did that
partnership come
together um there was a need for um
research in cultivation and together
makes it more affordable for everybody
so they asked us to help them setting
that up and bringing companies
together um is it just a lot of meetings
did you have to meet people and befriend
them and RN them to your side or yeah of
course that is a part of it but it's
really like uh all have the goal in um
creating new knowledge and sharing that
knowledge so we are still in the
cultivation of cannabis it's still a
young industry we all need to learn um a
lot still and making it more uh
professional one of the key things is
genetics so uh one of the partners is an
F1 uh CCH is a breeder with um F1 hybrid
seats which is completely new and that
could be a game changer so we want to be
up front with that and knowing what is
happening in that field Desiree you been
doing indigenous Partnerships strategic
alliances in South America can you take
us inside some of those experiences and
talk a little bit about how forming
Partnerships with indigenous communities
has been different than in some of the
like at a broader level with Western
worlds or with countries exactly
well being the president and of and
co-founder of the foundation for hum
kindness and compassion which is the
nonprofit company or Oran organization
that we have Alliance and we're forming
a strategic alliance with these
indigenous communities now the main
problem with that one is
because the each country they have their
own laws but the indigenous people also
have their own laws actually one of our
experiences is what we had with uh
Colombia one of the community there were
in yeah shout out Colombia right yeah I
think lcky is agreeing with me yeah yeah
and uh because of the laws that they
have which is so different from whatever
the FED I'd call it Federal Colombia one
yeah um it took our proposals at least
three years and within that it's still
like fighting within the community so
yeah we're really having a hard time
putting that together but at least in
some of the other indigenous communities
that we have like in Peru and in Mexico
and Jamaica at least with that one we
don't it's going slow it's really very
slow because of that reason but we're
it's GNA it's going to happen can you
just Google Colombian indigenous laws or
do you have to go there and be like what
are your laws own yes you got to go talk
to them yes yes what are those
conversations like oh it's did you go to
Colombia and like go yeah actually we
had one uh um big meeting and proposal
when we did our first proposal with the
NASA community of C Kaa uhhuh uh that's
in Colombia actually there's two
indigenous community that we have in
Colombia one is the Koji Community for
the uh Tanga and the Sierra Nevada
um so the three years one is the one
that's happening with the Cowan yeah you
know and you go in there everyone you
know the leader the women the leader of
the women are there too because I also
wanted to go and start Mental Health on
there because uh every time all of this
strategic um uh alliances that we have
with each indigenous communities we
really want to attend to their health
and not only you know not only just the
health but it we want to develop all the
businesses that they have that is fit
within that Community you been working
on this like new understanding of
cannabis trying to change mindsets
around the healthfulness of it do these
communities see it that way or are you
reorienting them I mean I imagine a lot
of Colombian communities have been
really impacted by the war is one of a
really good um thing that you brought up
up because this um with not only
Colombia but uh Peru Mexico and even the
Jamaican with the rust Safari in there
because we're also involved with some of
the rust tafari
Community they they are in they can they
use cannabis they grow cannabis anything
like that and they understand the
spiritual side of it right and that's
what I want people to understand you
know whether we use it medical or
recreational we have to understand we
have to be in relation and vibrating
together with the consciousness of that
plan yeah and they do understand that
and that is something that we want to
really bring the uh and change the
mindset of each and everyone George over
in Germany we're seeing
decriminalization and the beginning of
further medical
legalization um are you looking at
Germany are you looking for new
Partnerships in Germany how is your how
is your approach to this year and next
year going to
go yes everybody's are looking at the
new legislation in Germany this year
they decriminalize flour we expect by
the end of the year to allow extraction
that will bring a lot of business into
Germany because currently all the
products that come in Germany are either
extracted in Switzerland or all around
the world um absolutely this is going to
be the cracking point of the entire
Europe because because everybody's
looking after Germany and France as a
major leaders of the EU so that is
essential to see that
change uh who what do you need on the
team do you need anything to expand in
Germany well um if we talk about
Partnerships of course you first look at
the holes of your organization and try
to fill them with uh the resources that
you don't have usually Partnerships are
formed like if you read the main uh the
the books for Partnerships the uh that's
what it says but uh really what
partnership helps is to save money from
tax and from investment so these are the
major things of of uh building
Partnerships so yes we're going to be um
partnering with uh companies in Europe
to provide systems to start uh
extracting to start processing the best
way possible and that's going to be
Mutual effort of course yeah to minimize
the expense what types of Partnerships
are you looking
at well
there're different Partnerships let's
say marketing Partnerships they um marke
yeah that's one of the uh is better to
find a marketing partner in Germany to
be able to uh get to a German audience
uh there's um supply chain uh
partnership like uh usually as extractor
manufacturer we have
um pretty sophisticated process for
Manufacturing Systems so we uh we're
looking at a lot of sourcing of
components uh just not purchasing like
Valves and pumps are not Partnerships
it's uh sourcing but uh when we do uh
part of the system or integration that's
another um partnership going to be
looking for companies to install in
Germany which is uh installation
partnership so we going to be
looking eventually also at Financial
partnership so to finance the system for
the local market so there are a lot of
things that can help setting up a
vertical integration which I see uh in
Europe is very typical to um to
Outsource your Niche uh that you're not
too competent to somebody else to do you
uh to help you
with raise your hand if you're looking
for a part partner
today all right we got a couple Sav your
questions for the end huh um how have
you gone about building some of your
more fruitful Partnerships over the
years when you think back on um ones
that have worked how did they come
together what is what's the learnings
there wow well uh if you are successful
with your first partnership that means
that you're either lucky or destined to
do
it it's 90% uh set to fell your first
partnership because 90% yeah if you God
damn okay good that's why that didn't
work out because the thing that doesn't
tell you is you have to figure out the
people you partner with and to figure
out the people you partner with like
usually the books say Okay first uh you
you need to feel your uh you see what
you need to Source second you need to
find a partner third you write a
contract and fourth follow the contract
yeah that doesn't work unless your
partner it's um it's a person that can
keep parts of it it's dedicated it's
passion then there's no contract that
can save you yeah it's like temperament
it's like ethics it doesn't show up in a
RFP you have to go and see how
they treat the waiter it's like a
marriage it's a it's a it's worse than a
marriage it's way you spend way more
time talking to this cont yeah right uh
you're chuckling over there Nathan have
you experienced this
well we um as I mentioned we're a
medical device manufacturer so we have
equipment all over the world I
personally have been to Mongolia China
and installing equipment and when you
have a good partner things go well and
when you don't you show up and they
don't have the equipment there or you
they want you to pay him under the table
to get you know get certain things done
and that makes life really miserable so
you know I like the idea that George
says about luck but you know just having
to get on the ground and go talk to
those some of those people is the only
way to get it done sometimes yeah if uh
you guys I've never done one yet just go
hang out with the person you're going to
do it with for a while and you're going
to know really fast whether it's going
to be like a fit or not I feel like
Desiree you're chuckling but I mean
you're psych psych you have like a
psychology background can you um can you
drill down into this a little bit the
it's like there's this phrase that
Personnel is policy but the people are
the personnel and so the people end up
being the policy um yeah but can you
build on what they're
saying in what sense but um how do you
sus out whether someone's a good partner
like as a person oh well what are the
red flags you should well red flags is
um how do I say
that with a partner that's being see
it's it's the same with being in a
relationship it's like because it's
really true that being in a business
it's like being in a marriage you know
and it's like the same as if you're the
president or anything you um you treat
the country as a business as well so in
a business sense
itself if two people let's say the
relationship and that is the most
important thing in any in any part
whether you're in business whether
you're in relationship if you know that
there are
two you don't really agree on some
things then and if the other one really
cannot accept it's more of the
acceptance of what each other's got okay
versus the like versus of going rock
unmovable I don't like what you're
saying and I'll fight this is what I
want it has to be you've got to have
more of an open mind and it depends on
what sort of course of business that
you've got and the person that you're
dealing with because most of the people
don't want to go and you know um get new
informations even though it's okay this
is my belief now there's new information
that I have you know received now people
should be able to go and adjust that or
adopt it to whatever day or believe so
that at least it's a different way at
least you're opening your mind a little
bit to what the other person is saying H
instead of being really closed because
hey this is my belief I'm scking with it
yeah and I don't believe whatever you
say I think this is how we're going to
go do it this how we're going to put
where our money is and everything
so yes yeah do they have a goal
orientation are they about solving a
problem or do you have two members on
the team that are an Unstoppable Force
meaning an immovable object you ever
been on the teams with those two people
one guy's just bashing the other guy's
never L up and uh the phrase that came
to mind is like Styles make fights you
know um if two you could have two really
effective people but if they have
different styles of
operating then they're going to conflict
and the sorry someone's I was just to
add to that we um we had a group we were
working with in Brazil that I was
working with and we were getting along
fairly well and then we had a new person
came in and they had a very different
style so it wasn't very long after that
we had a different partnership with the
people in Brazil just because those were
the people that um got along with the
guy that we were working with that we
sent down there to to to set that up so
to your point I think a big part of it
isn't just similar goals but also has to
be similar personalities
um and one thing I would add is like and
maybe you guys can talk about this like
is there a way to go slow with
Partnerships can you break off a little
bit and do a little bit together and
then build so it's not like getting
married on the first date can anybody
talk about being more iterative with
forming strategic Partnerships have any
you guys ever gone slow or you guys just
paper it up it's all about financing if
you have 20 million you can do
everything vertical but if you have
200,000 you got to find somebody to fill
the
holes straight up
um how what are the main differences in
Partnerships structures in the US versus
the
EU okay so I started first in the EU we
started uh with cannabis in 2014 uh we
tried to do it ourself by doing the way
in us like we acquired a Farm Company
because we didn't work with this product
so we started to work with farming then
extraction you cannot design an
extraction system unless you work with
the plant so you have to figure it out
and we spent a lot in that
process well uh it was beneficial at GN
but what I saw uh as the differences
between the markets that in US everybody
wants to be vertical and usually
probably because it's much easier to get
to hard amount of money so they buy the
building they start to grow they then
they think about extraction then they
think how to make products then they
start marketing and this under roof
probably the best way to have most
margins but again what about if you
don't have the funding uh in Europe I
noticed that companies are specialized
in making products and they Source their
material so this is a partner that they
Source the materials from and there are
more than one like uh packaging uh
actives and base ingredients and stuff
like that so they sales partners that
they go to sales network that's a
partnership so in Europe is more open to
do uh their little niches and getting
Partnerships and that's kind of the
first way to look into a business is
like who do I work with to achieve that
structure uh Sunny you're nodding uh
have you seen this type of
heterogenity uh horizontal integration
less vertical in Europe like can you
build on what George is
saying with vertical integration you
mean um really going together um
working uh in Europe it sounds like
everyone's got a piece no one can do one
whole thing even at I think we are um in
Europe more used to really working
together with different uh companies um
than than in America it's like together
you know more than alone and that is
also why the Horticulture industry in
the Netherlands got so big because you
can also learn from your neighbor it's
your competitor but you together you
know more than alone and then that way
we yeah are still number one if you talk
about uh growing in green houses
Horticulture and that's also in the
Cannabis sometimes a bit frustrating
because everybody is so closed and don't
want to say anything how they are doing
what they are doing but I'm True
Believer that if you you talk with each
other you you get to know more details
and you can get a better product in the
end yeah how does the a partnership look
on paper uh what is a standard type of
agreement is there any standard type of
agreement
George I already mentioned that whatever
you put on paper may know have the power
to protect you at the end if your
partners are
not not honest and not right people but
usually you got to First Define like I
never do three-way agreements never
that's never I I would never do
three-way agreement it always needs to
be uh two um partner agreement then um
you have to clearly Define
responsibility of the first party
responsibility of the second party uh
confidentiality terms because if it's
not confidential it's not real
partnership your partner is to care
about your success your confidentiality
your passion needs to improve himself
continuously as you do improve yourself
so if you try to capture these things
into the agreement that's good at least
outline in the agreement as many
things as you can so both parties are at
least aware what page they are on yeah
and um you're going to see how it goes
through the signing process because the
you know when it goes through attorneys
is
the the point where then a lot of things
break because Partners you can see if a
partner is committed at that point yeah
I mean these all like sound like things
they tell you in relationship advice
like Define
responsibilities like have confidence
poity like commit to self-improvement
one member of the team can't be like
learning on du lingo and the other one
just playing video games all night and
day and then you don't really know what
you got until you got you get in a
pickle together and you have to get out
together or you see what people are made
of right
Desiree yes yeah agree yeah I concur
yeah that's it I got it I'm I'm I'm a
good relationship consultant um sunny
the world H Center is putting out
knowledge in the form of
Articles uh what are some recent
articles that you guys have have that
the fruits of the partnership so far and
then what do you want to do
next yeah what we bringing out is uh new
knowledge which we GED through uh
cultivation research and um new things
which will be coming up is um yeah new
strategies in growing how you can
influence the final content so how can
you influence choid levels stpine levels
in the final product what type of
strategies because you had mentioned
earlier that you were just published
some papers on screening there's three
types of screens now blocking solar
energy saving heat energy and then
blocking out light entirely for light
dep yep yeah those are uh certain
examples uh where you can look at how
can you in that way influence uh the
final ingredients in the the dry flour
in the end of course but yeah you can
also play with um irrigation fertilizers
um and seeing how you can affect plan
growth and development and the the
content of the final
flower can anyone talk about the law
side of it is there something you
shouldn't do if you're an American
coming over here and trying to do a
handshake deal to start a partnership
George uh have you ever run into like
what's the legal things to sort of think
about can you just do a contract like
you do in the United States and like
give someone percentage of the company
or those kind of Arrangements how are
the EU and the US different that
way well I've done anything between a
single page to 10 page agreements um
depends of the urgency depends of the
commitment usually this Agreements are
not to give percentages from the company
but to Define forms for JV that two
companies uh have equal responsibilities
in this
project
um I would say that that's uh even a
single page agreement can be powerful
enough to protect both sides yeah unless
everything is like everything needs to
be listed inside and everyone needs to
be on the same page what they have to do
in order to commit and full
fuel so um to add to that one of the
things I found is that people in general
are good people right everybody wants
best for their for their neighbor
relatively or in my experience um so
what what we found is that contracts
that are a little more in detail that
reduce potential amb ambiguity uh
increase the likelihood that you're
going to both be happy with the outcome
yeah that reminds me when the Catholic
priest pulls the young couple together
you really want to get married and they
like start ironing it out they make you
do a Consulting where you're like get
you guys get on the same page right
before you cuz like let's make sure
we're going to agree to split the money
right put go gos go in the same check-in
account like all the little the details
yeah if you don't have the details and
you go into it you both might be going
into a a relationship a partnership with
different expectations and when those
don't happen or when something
unexpected happens if you don't have a
way to handle it both parties could be
very unhappy and you could find yourself
you know in a legal Court trying to
figure figure things out which is not
good yeah I mean I'm we're going to
close here we got 10 minutes we're going
to take some questions um I wanted you
guys to go down the line and tell me
what Partners you're looking for next
you're looking for financing Partners
correct yeah so the biggest um um
prohibitor for us to expand into Europe
um technology Works Industry is
acceptance of it but it's financed our
equipment is not inexpensive um and so
if we're looking for people who are
willing to take on the Cannabis industry
uh to finance it we it took us a while
to find Partners in the United States
and they helped us grow significantly so
that's what we're looking for in Europe
as well George next partnership my
challenge all this years in the Cannabis
industry has been education uh I know
that when a product of ours gets in the
hand of customer we win always
um the problem for me so the partner
that I'll be looking for is going to be
a distribution partner okay distribution
partner that can talk the right language
that can have the right uh access to the
customer base so to distribute the
product yes okay so like that might be
like CBD extracts cannabis we
manufacture machines technology the the
tech cool sunny next partnership
actually we are just finalizing it and
uh a partner where we can do together
practical trainings on cannabis
cultivation practical training training
yeah yeah so really need doing the
cloning um the growing but also post
Harvest um we're just finalizing it and
um the website should be soon live that
uh we really promote that that LPS can
send us stuff to us in the Netherlands
they can be trained for a week or two
weeks so that they ready when they start
up their own
where in the Netherlands do we get to
learn in Amsterdam no no no the South
Desiree next partnership you're looking
for well the communities and the
families that we are involved with um
are mostly in the Cannabis industry so
they're in the growing and of course all
other un seery services like the um
clothing handicraft bio uh chemical uh
bio plastic Plastics bio
constructions and the most important
thing is these people are the
custodians of the traditional medicine
and what they wanted to do is to also
share it with us and in that sense
that's where we need economic um support
because we want to manifest I want we
want them to manifest their dreams
groovy um if anybody's got a question we
do we do have questions let's hear it
for David DS and Desiree and sunny and
George and Nathan already we're going to
start question for that audience the 3
pm crowd going strong first question is
over
here hello thank you for your time thank
you um uh sorry
the the um you guys touched on a lot of
hot to Forum Partners um within the
Cannabis sector were there different
or in your experience has there been
different partners say with ancillary
businesses or certain say ctiv our
processors or even dispensaries that you
would recommend or recommend shying away
from um I guess uh I'll give everybody
like 30 seconds answer because we're
going to wrap it up I would say look for
who's got co-signs like is someone
reputable have they been around to other
people coign them um they have a track
record of experience versus like an
unproven partner where they're saying
they're promising the world but they
don't have much to show for it yet
there's a reason why people with large
reputations might be more pricey to work
with than someone new for example in the
cultivation space on the breeder side um
it's Wild and Woolly right now and seeds
and so when I'm writing about seeds and
who's got good ones I look for who's
winning Awards who other Growers want to
work with um and that is like a proxy
for their quality like the
cosiness do anybody else got build on
that just gossip among your friends
that's my advice yeah right we have
another question over here I'm in the
back go for it I'll Stand okay hi
everyone I'm Stephanie pow I'm the
founder of emerald L recruitment we're
revolutionizing how Recruitment and HR
services are delivered to the Cannabis
space uh yes across the globe so here we
are my question is you know these days
there's a lot of people who are
consultants and fractional it's you know
the buzzword is fractional everything
these days it is a good solution but
what I see from my side is the
difference between a partner a true
partner and a consultant and so as
people are and there's so many
consultants wanting to actually be a
true partner to our clients and to
customers were serving you know what do
you see the big difference between
actually being a partner versus a
consultant and how has that been
successful with the companies you've
actually truly partnered
with I can answer that question
when you are partner into um let's say
manufacturing company uh you need to be
vested into the products that is
developed as example we work with number
of universities and we had uh
consultants in the beginning but they're
professors in University that help us to
develop our systems so they've been
awarded even after we start selling the
systems uh because they're Direct work
was uh appreciated and was uh in a
foundation uh with what we do so we
treated them as partners and as soon as
you're invested into this uh business
with your customer then you can become
partner but they also have to recognize
you for that and give you the credit and
and this is a long-term relationship
it's not like a year or two it's can be
20 years so as soon as this value is
built and created and improved every
year
this is a great way to create a
partnership fantastic uh we have one
more I'm back here I'm sitting down my
feet hurt here we oh I hear you thank
take those doggies hello everyone my
name is Luke Monroy I'm a fun of plan
purpose media filmmaker
Storyteller um I was very lucky to
interview people from the international
cannabis industry for the last 10 years
and hemp and I've seen people who knew
their why being very successful in
forming strategic Partnerships and I
would really like to know from you on
stage um what's your thought on knowing
your why and how this is helping you not
only form successful Partnerships but
being being successful in the long term
yeah so I can tell you from for our
company um it's about we're a life
science company the goal is to try and
improve health um so that's ultimately
what we're trying to do whether it's
with the Cannabis or with the cancer
research or with um vaccine production
or large scale insect Pest Control our
goal is to make the world better uh
easier for people to live in and and
help people be more healthy I mean
that's that's what our ultimate goal is
so that's for that's why we look for
partners who are trying to do the same
go George I cannot to it
so don't be emotional thanks passion and
emotions are two different things
passion helps you emotion harms you
everything is numbers in business
everything is numbers you have to be
sure you have the value that value has a
number and you has the return that you
expect to and do it with
passion yeah are we at
time yeah great well um this is such an
important topic I got eight and 11y old
boys they're forming strategic partners
for life right now making friends on the
yard it doesn't get any more basic than
this I mean these people will be with
them their lives and in the business
sense maybe it's not like that kind of
friendship but it's that kind of
long-term strategic relationship and so
it doesn't get any more foundational the
why is so important if you don't know a
a person's why their reasons for being
what what's motivating and what's
operating in them you don't know the
first thing about them and um so I hope
you take some of these lessons out in
there dig deep into the people you want
to work with make sure you're aligned
and then start small and build outward
from there uh make sure it's the right
fit don't don't get into something you
need to get out of later right everybody
exactly yeah I'm glad to hear it was 90%
fail rate for the first one though
thanks
George all right let's hear it again for
our panel that was
fantastic very enlightening I'm sure
they'd love to talk to you more in the
4A if you like this is the international
Canabis business conference barcalona