all right next panel the future of
Oregon cannabis
first lead off with kind of good news
the kind of big picture some things we
can all be proud of
first I want to mention when we first
legalized or first start working on
measure 91 to legalize cannabis here in
Oregon there were twelve thousand eight
hundred and eight Oregonians who were
arrested inside it for cannabis in 2012
and those are the latest stats when we
started the campaign last year using
those same statistics for people
arrested for cannabis where cannabis was
like the reason they were arrested that
was the most harmful thing they were
charged with that's down to 47 all right
so 47 people arrested inside of her
cannabis last year right and 16 adults
that's it 21 juvenile 16 adults so we
can be proud of that
ragazzi proud of the fact that Senator
Merkley mentioned in his video this
morning we have doubled what the state
projected tax revenue would bring in
they projected 40 million at the most
every year we're on pace to bring an 80
million every year so we doubled that
projection funding schools drug
treatment programs putting that money to
good use I think we could put it to
other good uses as well and we've
created I think Governor Brown projects
we have 19,000 or so cannabis jobs have
been created but we got more work to do
we need to take care of patients we need
to sell more cannabis both in-state and
out-of-state and dress some other issues
so let me introduce the panel at large
and then I kick it off first I have a
lot of experience working with all these
fellows they're all great people on the
far end
Sam Chapman director of new revenue
coalition Sam helped lead the effort any
whatever Sam thank you Sam I helped lead
the effort to legalize medical cannabis
dispensaries in the legislature and now
he's at the legislature leading the
effort to legalize cannabis cafes and
other similar businesses think about the
cannabis model for winery tours
distillery tours things like that to
bring more tourism to the state provide
more jobs for our industry next to him
Casey Houlihan Oregon retailers or
garita or the cannabis Association Casey
a worthless a measure 91 it's a great
job working with the legislature to
protect
the the the industry of the retailers
who are the point of contact with the
general public and in many ways they're
the ambassadors for the program next to
him Adam Smith with the craft cannabis
Alliance Adam works with mom-and-pops
and he is leading the charge with one
fix cannabis to make sure that Oregon is
ready when the time is right and I think
the time is now to start exporting
cannabis across state and international
lines and go and then one of our biggest
allies in the legislature Oregon Senator
Floyd Pierzynski all right and Sam it's
a once you take it away talk about what
we're working on with a new revenue
coalition and the reasons why we got to
legalize and regulate cannabis cafes and
other businesses here in Oregon
sure thanks Anthony again Sam Chapman
new revenue coalition if you want to
learn more about us and new revenue
coalition com
so we founded the new revenue coalition
because there needed to be an organized
pack of industry members along with
folks who are not in the cannabis
industry who may just be consumers or
social justice advocates or housing
advocates or equity advocates to really
reframe the issue and the current
problem that we have with our existing
model of legalization which that more or
less it is a privileged form of
legalization and that if you don't own
your own home there's likely no legal
place for you to consume your cannabis
so that's something that we're working
on addressing in this legislative
session we've got a bill into
Legislative Council right now that would
do a couple of things and really quickly
I just want to get a raise instead how
do you retailers are in the room
retailers production processing cool
this you stand to benefit from this bill
every single one of you stands to
benefit from this bill let me tell you
why the first and main core concept that
we're looking to do with this bill is to
exempt cannabis from the indoor Clean
Air Act for those of you who don't know
cannabis was added in 2015 and that
means that you can't consume cannabis
inside very straightforward now that
created again quite a few problems for
folks who don't own their own homes
especially if you're in any type of
government assisted housing there was a
law that was just passed federally that
all federal housing is now smoke-free
and so the current law
disproportionately affects people of low
economic status and people of color and
I think that we've really got an
opportunity to address this in the
upcoming session so what does the bill
do one it allows retailers to co-locate
a consumption venue at their premise two
it extends that same ability to
processors and producers if you want to
have a brewery or vineyard model at your
farm or processing facility we think you
should be able to do that just like the
wine and brewery industries three
delivery to hotels the current law does
not allow delivery to hotels we think
that that's something that should be
allowed if you're a tourist and you're
coming to town you should not have to
walk around the corner smoke in an alley
in a park or in your rented car those
are public safety issues in our opinion
and we think that those need to be
addressed with sensible solutions and
three cannabis temporary event licenses
again this is not reinventing the wheel
this we have this for liquor now the
language that we've used and put in the
bill that we have at the moment directly
reflects existing language for alcohol
temporary event licenses and so that is
the general concept of the bill and I
think that the really important thing
for people here to recognize is that
this is not a done deal
right this is actually the second and
maybe depending on how much context you
have a previous session second and a
half attempt at pushing this through the
legislature and let me give you a little
context and 2017 I helped author and ran
a bill
Senate bill 307 that sought to simply
create a space for people to consume at
retailers right now the folks that we
need to work with and that we at least
need to get to neutral our public health
and law enforcement and mainly Public
Health they have a lot of the same
reefer madness concerns that we have
heard for decades they also have some
legitimate concerns that we very much
need to address and I think that it's
really important that the industry knows
that in that there will be concessions
in these conversations right if I had it
my way you'd be able to buy cannabis and
alcohol consume it in the same place
right we're not there yet right so there
are incremental aspects of this
political process that we need to go
through in 2017 we took our first step
in that process so we had a bill that
would allow this to happen out retailers
we had three stakeholder group meetings
and in every meeting we compromised we
compromised we compromised and by the
third meeting the bill had been watered
down so much to where it just codified
existing law which and my non legal
opinion means if you're outside not on
an olcc licensed premise and you're not
in a view of the public you can consume
cannabis that was what Public Health
told us that they needed to go neutral
well it turns out they weren't very
genuine and telling us that because they
they still opposed our bill so we're
coming in with a very different strategy
for the 2019 session you know that's
politics right I do my best every day to
make sure that I don't take those things
personally that's part of the game and
we can play that game too
and I think that part of the new
strategy this time around is one you
know we're asking for everything we want
right everything that we deserve and we
understand that that may be a tall order
for some folks who may not quite
understand who we are and that we're
also normal people we just have a
different you know
choice two we choose a different way to
relax or we just you know we're not the
same exact people but we do believe that
it's something that we just deserve the
freedom to have so basically what we're
doing is we're gonna work with public
health and law enforcement we're
genuinely coming back to the table with
them we had a first what I believe to be
a very productive work group meeting and
you know I think that we've got a real
shot at getting this through the
building this session but it's not gonna
be done without two major things one a
well organized and well financed
lobbying effort and to a community
organizing bottom-up lobbying effort
this is not an issue that is going to
get passed just through top-down
lobbying this is going to require
constituents to be activated consumers
to talk to their representatives to set
up meetings and say I deserve a legal
place to consume this legal product and
if we're not if we can't do that this
will not pass it's that simple
and so if you live here in Oregon and
you are willing to contact your
representative send an email host a
house party volunteer in one way or
another if you've got a special skill I
want to hear from you because it's gonna
take all of us to get this done and it's
not just going to be the lobbyists in
the building it's gonna need to be the
people and the voters that let their kid
that let the representatives know that
they want this so the other aspect of
the strategy is if we are not able to
get something through the building this
session we're simply gonna go to the
ballot that ruffles a lot of folks
feathers to be honest but it's a card
that we have to keep in our back pocket
if folks that we are required to work
with in the building are not willing to
work with us that's fine there's another
avenue that we can go to and frankly
with 500 and
seventy-eight retailers in the state
most of which would stand to benefit in
one form or another from this bill we
think that those retailers Act there's
pretty great conduits to constituents to
consumers to voters and it's there's
plenty of campaign plans out there that
can show us how to utilize those
connectors to organize you know a
groundswell of constituent support the
legislature has never seen on a cannabis
issue like this before this can assume
this issue of consumer equity is one
that stands to mobilize consumers in
ways that you've never seen before and I
think that on top of the opportunities
that are presented in that type of
organizing model it also really is
something that you should consider as a
business decision if you're the cannabis
industry you already know your business
is politics and all politics are local
if you're not paying attention to local
politics you're probably not paying
attention to your business very much
right the same is to be said for this
issue and I think it's really important
that people understand that lobbying
isn't necessarily the most glorious
thing in the world but that's how you
get [ __ ] done and that's what we need
from everyone we need everyone to be
able to pitch in resources time
connections whatever you have I'd love
to hear from you and I'm not gonna have
a whole lot of time to hang out after
this I've got to leave town but I'll
give you my email right now in RC pack
at gmail.com NR CPAC at gmail.com I'm
happy to meet with anyone and everyone
if you want to endorse our campaign
we're happy to throw your logo up we'd
love to get a statement of support and
we'd love to work with you on figuring
out how to activate your constituent
base to help make cannabis consumption a
reality in Oregon in 2019 thank you
thanks
new revenue coalition comm check it out
in our CPAC at gmail.com Sam this one
quick question for you you mentioned in
a dream world you'd like to see cannabis
and alcohol served at the same
establishments will that same
establishment be able to have a chrome
as well who all went to the axe-throwing
last night the occ go to axe-throwing
last night all right I'm just saying
like if we can legally drink beer and
throw axes and just sign a waiver like
the safer alternative is smoking weed
and throwing axes so let's look all
right mister Adam Smith take us away on
why we need an export cannabis and how
we're gonna do it I'm from New York so I
talked fast and I only have a little bit
of time and a lot of stuff to go over so
try to stay with me I know it's early in
the morning my name is Adam Smith I'm
the founder and executive director of
the craft cannabis Alliance we are a
mission-driven
trade association representing companies
large and small that are majority Oregon
owned that have made a commitment to
sustainability ethical business and
employment practices positive community
engagement and ending the drug war I'm
not here to talk about the craft
cannabis Alliance today that's who we
are before I get into export I just want
to note something because I'm not sure
who will say this from the stage today
but the FBI numbers came out and Anthony
referenced the fact that we are only
we've only arrested 47 people last year
in Oregon for cannabis but nationwide
those numbers actually went up this past
year we arrested over 600,000 people
across the country so if you are in the
cannabis industry if you make your
living from the cannabis industry okay I
know in Oregon we're not making a ton of
money from the cannabis industry but if
we are we have our fingers on this pot
of gold on this bag of gold but the only
reason that's true is because we're
standing on a mountain of 80 years of
ruined lives and destroyed community and
we have a moral ethical cultural and
financial obligation to make sure that
we are funding ending the drug war writ
large not just
so may I suggest may I may I suggest if
you're looking for ways to do that may I
suggest students for sensible drug
policy normal the drug policy Alliance
Marijuana Policy Project whether that's
local or national think about being part
of the solution
now or again how we got here how many
people here do business in Oregon
alright awesome how many people here
would be in favor of being able to
export products out of Oregon excellent
we got a friendly crowd all right I'm
gonna stand up how did we leave the
photo all right
so how do we get here Oregon decided I
think it was a smart idea we decided to
legalize the industry we had here in
Oregon we actually ran a campaign called
go legal and the campaign was not about
bring your big multinational here buy up
a bunch of farms and set up shop the
campaign was that we had an industry
here have had an industry here for
generations and we wanted to make it
feasible for all of those folks that
have been participating to continue
participating on the legal side this was
a good instinct we legalized the
industry we had the state said come on
in and thousands of people did the
problem is it turned out the industry we
had was largely an export industry and
so folks got we had medical obviously
right but for generations we've been
we've been feeding the west coast has
been feeding the end of the nation's
cannabis desires and doing a wall and so
we roped in all of this product we said
go ahead everybody grow when we turned
around and you know with cheap and easy
licensing and boom we have a glut right
Billy Williams the US attorney here
calls it a problem I like to call it a
bounty right we have a bounty but if you
think things are bountiful now wait till
California gets their licensing on track
it's gonna be very bountiful on the west
coast right Oregon is an export state
and we have always been an export state
and that is how our and that is how this
will function going forward and that's
the future for Oregon so but what we
have right now is we have a number of
problems number one we have the problem
that we've had since the beginning of
prohibition which is we are exporting
like
not the second problem we have is that
we have producer counties that don't
have resources enough resources coming
in to enforce regulation and the third
problem is that we are on the brink of
an economic catastrophe in Oregon a
real-time economic crisis we have
hundreds of millions of dollars of local
capital that is on the verge of being
wiped out that that stands to be wiped
out over the next 12 to 24 months right
and this is not Nikes local capital or
Intel's local capital this is the local
capital of thousands of people who have
gone all in to be part of this legal
industry right and if this was any other
industry if we had this kind of local
capital and thousands of jobs at
imminent risk we would have political
leadership coming from everywhere
screaming at the federal government to
open up markets for our hazelnuts or
filbert's you know for a salmon for a
grass seed whatever it is but it's
cannabis so it's touchy but it's not
touchy right we are looking at we are in
the midst of a sea change nationally a
couple of months ago
New York's Governor Andrew Cuomo came
out and said you know it's not a matter
of if New York should legalize cannabis
it's how New York should legalize
cannabis right well right now under the
current system the way things are if New
York wants to legalize cannabis tomorrow
they would have to create from scratch a
production industry approximately four
to five times larger than Oregon's
production industry right that's not
that's not they're competitive and or
economically feasible right I mean you
can grow oranges in New York too if you
want right it's not a good business plan
right and so not saying that folks in
New York shouldn't grow but they should
grow if they believe they can be
competitive with West Coast cannabis
coming because West Coast cannabis is
going to come and it may take until it
you know it may take until federal
prohibition ends but that day is coming
and so let's we should we need to look
economically toward what is the future
of this industry so to fix all of those
problems right
so let me just go back wait the US
Attorney Billy Williams said this is out
of control
right there's diversion from the legal
market there is illicit growing there is
organized crime and you know and to some
extent that is not untrue right but it
has been such since the beginning
prohibition right prohibition didn't
work it doesn't work now the state is
not going to suddenly become able to
make prohibition work right so the
question is not showing an export or not
the question is how is Oregon going to
export is it going to export ad hoc
illegally unregulated in ways that make
everybody including the US attorney
unhappy or is it going to do this in a
way that is regulated going into states
that want it into license hands to go to
adults where we get revenues back that
is the only question so we have decided
that it is time to push that question
and we started we have started a
campaign called one fix cannabis where
one stands for Oregon needs export okay
and there's there is a and let me tell
you right up front our goal is to export
product legally from Oregon by the end
of 2020 we are we plan to send product
out of Oregon by the end of 2020 because
because if it takes four years to get to
export or five years then there's a
really good chance that eighty or ninety
percent of the local industry who here
will be no more right we have large
companies that have come in here and
they have every right to be here and
they're buying up farms and buying up
retail and buying up brands right and
they're not here because they think
they're gonna get rich selling cannabis
to Oregonians right you know it's not
too much hyperbole to say it's possible
that you know the last profitable dollar
has already been made selling cannabis
to Oregon eum's right they are here
because there is an Oregon brand of
cannabis and when those walls come down
we are gonna have a multi-billion dollar
export industry right but there's a
really good chance that if it takes too
long there's gonna be some small number
of large deep-pocketed companies that
have outlasted and bought out everybody
else who will only who will own the
Oregon brand globally and we will turn
around and have this multi-billion
dollar industry and we will say wow what
a shame we don't really have a
significant ownership stake here
now I have good friends that work for
some of these large companies and if we
took a snapshot of the Oregon industry
right now and that's how this went
forward with the mix that we have of
outside companies inside companies we
would ever help the ecosystem but we're
not trending in that direction and the
longer it takes us to open up new
markets the harder and harder it's going
to get for us
have an industry that is of Oregon and
make no mistake the reason that the
Oregon has a brand globally for a
cannabis is exactly because of that
artisan craft right industry that has
worked for generations to create the
best cannabis on the planet right and so
it is valuable to everyone for that to
survive so what are we doing I'm gonna
close this up what are we doing the one
fixed cannabis campaign it's a
three-step process the first thing we
absolutely have to do is we have to pass
a bill and Senate presents key I believe
is going to help us do that that is
going to allow us that are gonna make it
legal under state law de to approve
transfers for the governor's office
through all 62 approved transfers out of
state right now if cannabis became legal
tomorrow federally it would still be
illegal under Oregon law for us to
approve out-of-state transfers we need
to get that out of the way that doesn't
get product out of the state but it gets
them it gets the legislature out of the
way so that when the time comes we are
able to jump on that opportunity right
and and the other thing we need to
understand is that we don't the
situation the federal level is fluid
right it's not about waiting for the
federal government to legalize cannabis
we have never made an advance in
cannabis policy in the last 40 years
because the federal government decided
to make something legal and say here go
ahead do it never not once they have not
legalized medical yet we would still be
waiting
we can't wait right so what we need to
do is get the make it legal in Oregon we
need to pass this bill it is vital it's
a necessary first step that campaign to
pass the bill is also a platform to tell
this story nationally about the future
of the economics in cannabis and find
our partners around the state that are
going to lobby for their state to allow
import whether that's New York or New
Jersey or Nevada or Utah's medical
program or Oklahoma's medical program we
need to punch a hole in the wall we need
to make a transfer from Oregon's system
into another state's legal system that
the states approve and the federal
government let's happen once that
happens we are an entirely different
world and so we need to bring it right
up to the wine and look at the federal
government and force them to make a
decision are you going to enforce
against two state governors that have
decided they're ready to move
and that this is going to help clear up
the illicit market and that's what we
need to get okay and so I want to thank
by the way you hear from Casey we learn
from Orca there are partners in one fix
cannabis they're an amazing job we just
met with Sun growers guild down south
and they are joining they're going to
join the campaign I don't know if Pete
is here we had a terrific meeting I'm
really excited to work with those guys
we can't do this there is a sign on
letter ok when we go to the legislature
we ask for things like socially is the
first thing people are gonna ask is is
that you know where is the industry on
this we need to get a thousand license
holders on this sign on letter you go to
one fix cannabis org it takes you 30
seconds sign on to the letter really
important we need to be able to show is
it we need to be able to show that this
is something everybody wants then and
then we are gonna lobby when the
legislative session starts and we are
gonna get this done okay so I'm gonna
pass this on but please be part of both
of these things we need to bring people
into the state to show them the
incredible world-class level of our
cannabis and let them go home and spread
our fame and our brand and then we need
to be able to send it to them and get it
on their shelves whether it's a state
that's already legal or the next state
that becomes legal we can do this by
2020 and again it's up to you know the
industry to stand up together and I hope
you all thank you so much
Thank You Adam 1 fix cannabis org let's
make it happen all right Casey you're at
brother name is Casey Houlihan I'm the
executive director of the Oregon
retailers of cannabis Association we
represent over 350 cannabis businesses
in the industry across the state many of
them are retailers but we also have
producers and processors you name it
several of whom I believe are here today
yeah great yeah and if you're not a
member to talk to us after we'll be here
all day I'm gonna echo a lot of what you
just heard from both of these speakers
there's a lot that we're working on for
the upcoming legislative session in 2019
and it's going to be a unique session in
a couple of ways that I wanted to point
out this will be the first long session
that we've had in the legislature for
some time without a specific committee
dedicated to focusing on cannabis
related policy that does mean that we
are going to be competing with
traditional industries and other
interest groups at the Capitol for basic
bandwidth for room on you know committee
hearings and just to make sure that we
can get their time and attention for
this so a lot of what we're seeing is
the culmination of efforts from a lot of
the folks up here but they've been doing
for years at this point and that's
exactly the type of time frame that
we're typically looking at for getting
these substantive policy measures passed
it's years after years and so one of the
other reasons I'm very excited about
this upcoming session is that we've also
made more progress than ever before
we have more advocates and allies on our
side than ever before we've added more
legislators to the positive columns for
all three or all all two of these
legislation bills that these guys are
talking about as well as the others and
I'm going to mention here our number one
focus is Adam pointed out is also going
to be making sure that we can get a
reasonable export policy for this state
because as you all know we are wildly
saturated on the production side and the
biggest solution that we could possibly
have would be to get that to another
state that needs it we can get more
money into the pockets of the growers
here and actually I think at the capital
will probably start referring to that
bility or cannabis industry full
employment act of 2019 because there's
nothing else we could do to help the
jobs outlook in this state in this
industry
it's a Sam's point as well and this is
actually one of the other elements
that's going to be new we have more
forces and more groups that are
coalesced around a lot of these specific
issues and driving support for these
specific issues than we've seen
historically and it's a really effective
mechanism at adding support so that's
another area where especially when we're
talking about something very
controversial like social consumption
where clearly there have been some
stakeholders particularly the public
health advocates who have been very
obstinate in their opposition to this
this is another area where after years
of making small progress and getting
more allies on our side then I think
this is going to be the best chance
we've had yet to get this type of bill
through and it's really important that
we all get behind it and make sure that
we can show our support for those
lobbying efforts as well a couple of the
other things that I know that we've
discussed in past sessions and our
association is looking to bring back up
as well is actually a bill that was
introduced by Senator presents key in
2017 as I believe SB 301 at the time
which would have eliminated employment
discrimination for off-hours cannabis
use and this is an important one because
there's still a great deal of folks out
there who are concerned about losing
their job or employment or financial
security if they consume cannabis this
is another example of Sam pointed out of
privileged legalization so we think that
this is something that everybody should
be able to have access to nobody should
be punished or deprived of an economic
opportunity because they choose a safer
legal intoxicant in the state of Oregon
so this is an area where consumers can
really directly provide a lot of input
and carry quite a bit of the weight of
these measures we're trying to advocate
for in session Sam inappropriately
pointed out that a grassroots effort on
this can be extremely impactful to
legislators and especially on an area
like this where so many consumers
directly would be impacted by this type
of policy this is one where we
especially as retailers can reach out to
our consumers to make sure they
understand to advocate for their
interests and to talk to their state
representatives and their state senators
to make sure that they support these
bills as well
lastly I also wanted to talk about
another bill that we're working on to
vacate automatically passed cannabis
convictions for folks that had been
victimized by the prohibition on
cannabis in the war on drugs
historically there is a path right now
for getting those types of charges
expunged however it is fairly circuitous
it's fairly time-consuming and it's
relatively costly and as such many folks
have
taking advantage of it that could so
this is something that we would like to
have done at the state level in statutes
but it can happen automatically for
those past offenses and folks don't have
to jump through a series of Hoops to
have something stricken from the record
that shouldn't have been there in the
first place I also I wear two hats in
the industry I also worked with BDS
analytics which market research and data
firm so I do operate kind of at the
cross section of policy and data so
there was a couple things I wanted to
mention just in terms of consumer power
from the cannabis consumer perspective
there are so many lobbying groups right
now that happened nationally that work
nationally that are essentially consumer
organizations I think the NRA is one of
the most powerful typically that folks
think of and that's because gun sales
are massive thirty percent of Americans
currently report that they own firearm
and estimated right now between nine and
ten billion dollars in North American
gun sales
however in states that have legalized
ation policy consumer insight research
that we have done has shown that thirty
two percent of folks in those legal
states have consumed cannabis in the
last six months and in 2017 legal
cannabis sales were nine point seven
billion dollars in North America in
about four years they're anticipated to
go up to twenty four billion so we're
gonna be running circles around some of
the the biggest interest groups in the
country in terms of how many sales
they're bringing in relative to ours and
this is an area where you can vote with
your voice you can vote with your dollar
you can connect with your representative
but we are a seasoned constituency that
at this point needs to have our voice
heard and we need to finish the job of
legalization that we started four years
ago thank you Thank You Casey Casey
how can people Casey how can people find
you online Casey how can people find you
online to get involved we were at Oregon
cannabis retailers calm and we also have
a table right out there and chat with us
all day thank you
all right let's hear from our ally and
what for your perspective Senator
presence key from from inside the
legislative building all right thank you
so I think it's important to kind of
take a step back to look at where we
were and where we are today I think Adam
brought a very distinct point of the
diversion that we have back in 2015
after the measure 91 was passed in 14
that's when we had a supercommittee that
was opened up there are ten members five
senators and five representatives
was one of the vice chairs of the that
committee during that process it came
very clear that we needed to do certain
things to ensure that we weren't going
to have this glut of product on the
market we had testimony that told us
that we already had within the medical
program that had been in existence since
98 when it was passed and started
growing in 99 so about 14 years three to
five times as much product flour already
being grown in the state without even
going into the recreational system and
that was based on research that an
individual and OSU had done what we took
from that and what I took from that was
that we needed to have a bill that was
going to limit new production for
growers to limit new people coming in
out of state so basically a residency
requirement we had a bill that actually
was going to require a four-year
residency program so he could in fact
allow for the mom and pops throughout
this state that were the roots of this
program of what we're now benefiting
from to be able to transition into the
open market what we're going to also do
is not keep someone from coming into the
state but they were gonna get what would
be called a vertical license a license
that would allow them to grow for their
own need and use but they would not be
able to flood the market with their
flour or their extracts or any other
processing into the open market they'd
have to sell it through their own retail
that would self regulate them as to how
much they grew because they can only
sell it within their own retail outlet
or through their own processing we know
that that would limit the addition and
will allow for everyone else who are
Oregonians before we had this transition
coming in to actually have a place at
the table have an existing market and
actually be able to come in from being
on the outs and being in a regulated
industry now what we have seen since
then is is glut we know with what we're
dealing with and so in 2017 I did in
fact introduced a bill Senate bill 20
excuse me
and 42 so if you're interested in
looking at it you can go to the Oregon
legislators legislative website and you
go to the bills go to the sessions first
pick the 2017 session and then look up
SB 1042 what 10:42 called for was to
establish a a process for the governor
to be able to enter into compacts with
adjacent states that had met had
marijuana programs either medical and/or
recreational programs so here in Oregon
we now have adjacent states of
California Nevada and Washington this
would in fact allow for those who are in
the process of growing that want to be
able to get a return for their product
to actually be able to have it go across
state lines now what we've realized is
that through this drafting we needed to
have a mechanism that would keep it from
being exclusively regulated by the feds
and that is through ground
transportation it's my belief from
working with our legislative council
that we could in fact do that because
only air and marine meaning water
transportation it's exclusively
regulated by the feds
so unfortunately even though I got the
bill passed out of my Senate Judiciary
Committee it went to another committee
and the leadership chose not to move the
bill that bill will be reintroduced we
will be looking at potential
modifications and an adam says one of
the things that we want to be as an
exporting state this is my vision as
well because we have seen it we know it
will be there and the reality there's
little that any other states going to be
able to do to outdo our state and our
growers because they're so renowned as
to what they do do and with the success
that they've had in the medical
application so why would a state that
has no medical growing program want to
try to establish that program now
clearly they can do that if New York
wants to do that so be it but guess what
we know that we have a brand we know
that we have growers who have been able
to identify attributes of their their
strains to help individuals and medical
needs and as
heard from veterans in front of my
committee the bottom line is they want
to be able to function they want to be
part of society they want to be able to
take care of their families they can't
do on opiates but they can do it but
they have access to quality strains of
marijuana that actually will benefit
them so that's one of the things we want
to do and this is now taken off to
another step just this week I had
individuals coming in from California
who represents the rural counties who
are looking at 10:42 as how they can
actually start working on their side of
the state boundary to actually implement
that so we can see that so you may see
the first two states actually doing this
would between us in California but I
still want to have that opening for
everywhere else
meaning adjacent states the other
everywhere else I'm afraid that it's
going to take a piece of legislation on
the federal side I think it's very
doable because we have 29 plus states in
DC that are doing medical programs so I
think the first step that you're going
to see on the federal side will be a
laxing allowing for transfer of medical
marijuana between states that allow for
medical marijuana that will allow us to
go interstate commerce that will in fact
allow us to ship by air or by water to
other states that are not adjacent to us
and that's a key component that we need
to actually expand this out as Adam
would like to do and the other thing I
think that we need to do for diversion
and dealing with this is taking off the
20 pound limit for medical transfers
into the recreational system if we have
a problem and we've heard from Billy
Williams we've heard from others that it
is the outdoor growing in Southern
Oregon the place the birth spot for
medical production why don't we allow
them to get their product whatever
excess they have after they take care of
their patients into the system again if
you want to deal with diversion this is
the way to do it
so the last thing I want to bring up to
you is I think is something that we've
heard from some of the discussions this
morning and why it's so important we
need to ensure that we maintain the
continuity that we have today with the
growers from yesterday that are here now
in multiple generations we cannot let
them fall off the wayside because they
don't have the capital to compete I'm
looking for ways that we can do that and
I think there's a couple things that we
need to be stressing number one we need
to have research on the attributes of
metal coating applications that is
something that we have we have put in
place a research component and we do
have the Commission that's working on
this but I do think it's something that
we need to keep in mind we can't lose
track of this is one of those areas that
I think that we can have another license
under
LCC I've talked to them briefly they
haven't warmed up to it completely but
we could have a license that allows for
a rider for medical growers to actually
be able to file with the agency or a
particular agency could be Oregon Health
Authority the attributes of their
strains it's anecdotal I know it's not
backed by scientific research but until
the feds open that door we can't do that
but what we can do is we can continue to
establish what the different strains
that are being grown here what there
have been beneficial for and then we'll
have that in our back pocket when we
start seeing national research going
we'll be all ready D marking that market
I think the last thing that we need to
do in this area is see genetics this is
one of those areas that if you think
about for those who are in the room
think about the Graduate movie when
William Brooks said to Dustin Hoffman
just one word plastics but if that word
would have been cannabis what if that
word would have been in the application
of how you actually make your product
available and stronger for whatever the
needs
the market our sea genetics is where we
have as a state because of all the work
that has been done in historical
perspective if we can maintain that we
will be an exporting state of not only
product but seeds to other parts of the
world because everyone knows what the
brand we have here is what they want to
actually duplicate thank you all right
thank you gentlemen
I did want to make an announcement
because I have been told that we have
got the a/c the way that we got the AC
blasting so uh we're cooling it off in
here because it got a little hot they've
got time for one maybe two questions for
in Gaia if you can flag them down not
question for me but a question for the
panel oh I have a question I know that
Germany or rather Canada is exporting
medical cannabis to Germany and other
countries right now do you think Oregon
or some of these West Coast states could
get involved in international cannabis
exporting as well or you try to keep it
just on a national level on the
international market we keep we can beat
Canada are weeds way better there's no
doubt that we can but there are sisters
to remember as the Cascadia region we
want to be all-inclusive but the reality
is we are not going to be able to do
that until we have movement on the
federal side until they actually in this
as part of the interstate commerce and
when we talk about interstate commerce
we actually are talking not only
Interstate within the US but
internationally because once that
happens the doors open is Canada and
Germany has already shown us quick it's
like a group of questions but now I know
they don't have time forums but the main
part about it is as a very as a small
recreational grower that's gone through
all the hoops and spent all the money
and and we're the ones being hit the
hardest in this industry do you guys are
you looking at the implications of
allowing us to be cross bordering with
California which has so much money and
so much size and so much different
regulations I just see that that's going
to destroy our small growers including
also discussion on genetics genetics
should be open if genetics are protected
Monsanto type companies are going to
come in
take over so I think that I mean all you
guys up there are you guys thinking
about the small independent growers
we're in Oregon suffering right now with
an overabundance even the 20 pound
increase you're talking about allowing
more product that's that's not been
regulated into our very tightly over
populated in marketplace so just to just
do a Jarvan thank you just suggest a
piece of that in terms of opening
borders obviously if we can export your
opening borders for for product to come
in but at this moment it would not be a
really good business decision for almost
anyone to send cannabis in the Oregon
right I mean you can you can smuggle
cocaine into Bolivia if you want but it
loses a lot of its value when it gets
there right and so it's the same we're
in that by the time we get to a point
where somebody wants to send cannabis in
here for commercial reasons it'll mean
that we've stabilized our prices right
and so we need to get there first before
we worry about you know California
California and Oregon are both obviously
going to be export states to the extent
that we can work with each other to
break a hole in that wall and I met with
the same folks from California that
Senator presents came out with the rural
counties and they're really interested
in this if we can work together to do
that then we can set a precedent and we
can all get it out so let me also follow
up for the small recreational growers
you have a product I assume that you are
very proud of in the strains that you do
guess what the people on the other side
of the borders want that product because
it's it's been regulated it's been
tested and you've got quality product as
compared to someone else that's why I
think the small businesses will in fact
be able to compete here I actually think
it's the Lifeline as compared to having
this market flood by everyone now on the
genetics to me the part is very
important you're correct it needs to be
open what we don't want to see is the
mass farmer or whoever else come in here
and take control how else are we gonna
do that if we don't have our own
research happening here in ensuring that
we have that viability for our small
businesses and again once we have that
research out I'll just name out one
person Seth Crawford who gave us a lot
of testimony back in 2015 and 2016 he
and his brother have been working on
genetics outside on their farm and
outside
corvallis and they're into stuff that I
mean it's a well it's above my head
let's just say that and it's just
amazing of what they're looking at and
as we know how many canards padorin
marijuana that have not been researched
have not been identified and it seems
important to me that we have that type
of research being done sanctioned within
the state so we can have our state to be
a medical research as well as just a
seed generating research facility that
people come to Oregon to find out what's
best thank you let's hear it again for
Anthony the entire panel that was great
was in depth there's a lot of a lot of
stuff happening it's it's kind of