to discuss future scientific
Horizons that's the one that's the one
the one here to lead us in this panel
the one and only COO of the tman group
that's Chief organizational officer
right it's fancy fancy I looked it up
dang so prepared I didn't just want to
call you the coup the coup he's coup and
he's the coup let's hear it for Justin
TBE thank you and appreciate that very
much how's everybody doing today it's
been a good day feeling well all all
right let's hear a little noise
ICBC all right thank you I think this is
going to be a great way to uh wrap up
the day with a really interesting
subject I'm sure it's uh something
that's prominent for many people here
thinking about where are the horizons of
research where are they taking us the
panel uh that we have here of uh subject
matter experts have a lot of experience
to share there will be uh of course a
bit of emphasis on the pharmaceutical
industry is that's the nature of the
panel discussion here but we will be
venturing a little bit beyond just the
narrow scope pharmaceutical industry uh
so briefly um we have in order Francesco
bauno uh and Professor Christian urz uh
athanasia Conley and professor badar
radich and uh and forgive give me if I
aasia athanasia
yeah uh indeed so we'd like to just give
each of the panelists uh a brief moment
to introduce yourselves what your
background is here and then we'll start
to to dive into the subject uh you want
to start us off Franchesco sure hello
everyone uh Franchesco here from Italy
but I worked uh globally in North
America and around Europe and and
basically we're doing a lot of research
and uh in the pharmaceutical industry
and there's a lot of uh you know
developments in the last years going on
on you know the medical side but we
focus basically on more on the patient
perspective so we have a completely
different model than the pharmaceutical
standard one on the standardized product
just for the market and it's going to be
great to talk about this with the with
my colleagues
here Christan thank you very much uh
welcome everyone in the evening here and
the afternoon last session Christian
Oris I'm professor at humbold University
here in Berlin um and uh I'm not working
in the medical field I'm working as a
plant ecop physiologist in agriculture
Horticulture so my main focus is here on
uh on the production side um but we have
established um a lab we are working
since six years uh in beginning with CBD
uh plans now with uh the own University
in Germany with a THC license for
medical cannabis um on the production
part mainly um including uh uh tissue
culture lab uh including the the
chemical analysis but we are having
partners um uh established with a German
Center for Medical Health um with um
German Center for um psychic psychic
Health um and so on so we are offering a
lots of uh partner ships to the industry
to work with the industry and uh the
last years we had two canabas resarch
class so it canabas entered already uh
teaching at the University level um
funded co-funded by the industry thanks
to Aurora and Dian um and uh so focusing
really on this uh product which we are
rediscovering in horiculture thank you
thank you question AIA hello everyone
good afternoon my name is aasia I'm
originally from Greece but I've been
living in the north today is a is a lie
usually not as Sunny uh but apart from
my personal suffering I work for DSM
Firmin it is a company with a history of
a hundred years a leader in uh vitamins
and pharmaceutical ingredients and I'm
responsible for our Pharma cannabinoid
sector so through the highquality
pharmaceutical ingredients Innovation
capabilities and Supply consistent
supply chain that we can offer we are
hoping to be the partner for your
pharmaceutical development big or small
as many of our customers can
attest great and boo uh hello everybody
I'm B dadich coming from
Slovenia uh I'm started on the other
side as a uh activist uh 20 more or more
years
ago uh but uh uh soon we realize that uh
we can move uh the Cannabis to the
medical use just with the education and
with the knowledge so we organized uh
Research Institute in Slovenia and we
started to organize education for
doctors and nurses because you want if
we want to uh bring the Cannabis into
practice I think we need the
knowledgeable uh
professionals and uh if we start to you
know start to teach them today we will
have first professionals like in 15
years from
now
great all right um so we are in this
very interesting and unique time in uh
the the history of the the world and
here in Europe in that we have been for
the last 80 plus years in a period of
prohibition on a plant with an
incredible amount of potential to impact
human health and a variety of other uses
uh research has been constrained to very
very limited narrow uh focuses and uh in
many ways has been underfunded and and
not carried out nearly as robustly as
the plant deserves and we're coming out
of the backside of that now uh emerging
from what has been maybe a bit of folk
medicine and cottage industry into an
opportunity to sort of come back up and
address this at the level of
professional industry that it merits and
so what I'd like to do is ask um my
panelists what you feel is perhaps one
of the the most needed or prioritized
areas of cannabis research that you feel
should be emphasize moving forward and
we'll start with you
Franchesco well um I mean in these last
years we saw a lot of research going on
on the two main compounds produced from
the cannabis plant like obviously CBD
and THC uh we saw a boom in the market
as well on you know products that were
not properly
Medical but used from people as well for
medical purposes you know uh but for the
future instead we have I mean the the
cannabis plant is unique in these
aspects because produces a lot of
compounds we've studied very very few of
them until now there going to be a lot
of research done on minor cannabinoids
for sure in the future and that's going
to be a lot of new canab noids that are
going to be discovered okay on top we
need to address as well that the
cannabis plant is and the compounds the
secondary metabolites in general we are
talking about flavonoids we're talking
about Turpin but these compounds are
alive even when you cut the plant so
there's a fermentation process going on
there after curing for months okay so
actually the compound changes over time
okay and is a base of we can say
fermentation for example okay so in a
matter of turpins for example there's
turpins that are unique to the cannabis
plant and that turpins that are
unique after the fermentation and exist
only in the cannabis plant for example
this is a topic super interesting and
we've been researching in Canada this
for a little while but for example for
the future this is going to be super
interesting venue uh
unfortunately uh we like I said earlier
on uh we have a different model so we
try to actually bring to the market
right away our research okay with our
partners we try
to monetize okay to bring the research
further because investments in research
on these topics are really you know not
enough okay CU funds Edge funds capital
is looking for quick profit and research
for medical proposes is for the benefit
of the Society of the wellbeing of the
people so it's is a total different
approach a totally different philosophy
than the capital uh you know approach of
the finance and on the B business let's
say you know so we we're looking about
Healthcare and we're looking about
business we try to bring bring the
things together that's why uh our
approach trying to is trying to monetize
is trying to you know uh self sustain
itself over time to you know expand
research in order to um find new
compounds find new applications for uh
you know patients and you know for like
I said the well-being of the society at
the end of the day great um yeah
certainly uh business as usual isn't
necessarily a model that um we can adopt
moving forward to realize all the
potential what about um uh AIA you you
work directly inside the pharmaceutical
industry so you have more of an
Insider's view um when Franchesco talks
about the minor canabo or these other
elements that um have potential medical
application and value what's the
interest um from within the
pharmaceutical industry in researching
and and maybe developing uh products
based on on those other constituents and
compounds that you're aware of yeah so
we do I do have the joy and the pleasure
to actually have these conversations
with pharmaceutical companies day in day
out and um it is a very interesting
shift in mind mindset that's happening
right now it used to be a question of
big Pharma like oh this is cannabis
we're not sure how do we know what is
actually working and what is not and
this is changing Ing and what is very
interesting to note I'd say in terms of
what um the research is focusing on so
minors and combinations but when we
think combinations is our um our API in
combination with an existing medicine so
an existing approved treatment that
could help amplify its impact that could
also help reduce side effects and so on
secondly uh the patient Centric formats
we should all be aware that with the
knowledge and the technology that was
available in the time being able to
dissolve CBD in oil was the best
possible Solution that's no longer the
case we have solutions that are
particularly applicable for patient
convenience and patient compliance and
reducing variability and these could be
solid formats like an orally dispersable
tablet like a chewable tablet like
topicals and patients are asking for
that and we should be um we should be
answering that and we at DSM fir Minish
are actually developing some of these
formulations but we also see great um
applications from other parts of the
world and then a last area so when I
talk to to Pharma companies what do they
ask for and I think that's what we all
need to be aware of they will there are
two elements that will always come back
IP and Pharma standards so IP I think is
a no-brainer I've seen a lot of good
work around patents across our industry
but Pharma standards is something we
need to double down on because when
you're starting a development of a new
pharmaceutical product and short on cast
there's often a desire to limit costs
and that's understandable but making
discounts on the wrong things is going
to make your product an unattractive
investment down the line and it's even
more going to put patients at risk which
is not something that nobody wants so
starting right from the right ingredient
with the right standards with the right
certifications
all the way down to not just GMP and I
think we should be honest there is a bit
of a confusion on what GMP is being
manufactured in a GMP facility is a
prerequisite it's not sufficient by
itself there is a set of quality
standards and PHA prerequisites and
Purity uh data and stability data and
how you design your clinical trial that
you need to think in advance CU what is
the risk that you find yourself at the
end of the process of 3 years and you've
made a discount that actually now means
nobody wants to invest in your product
and who's losing people who invested in
you your time your money the patient
who's never going to get it so I think
we definitely need to have a wider
understanding on how we approach this ah
indeed and certainly uh companies that
are looking to place their products in
the traditional pharmaceutical model um
would be wise to to know beforehand
exactly what they're going to have to do
in order to have a better chance of
success um moar you've um worked with uh
a number of different uh you've worked
from your medical clinic over the years
providing cannabis and different forms
of uh delivery to patients but outside
of the pharmaceutical model um do you
believe that there's a place uh for uh
research and development in the kind of
the other sort of medical applications
that don't follow the strict sort of
pharmaceutical model and standards and
what would that look like for
you uh yeah I think that as atasia said
there must come to change of the mindset
of Pharma industry because cannabis
works completely on different way than
the certain remedies that are on uh the
market now uh yes we we were following
patients uh also not just uh uh as a
patient but also we followed what they
used how they used all the possible
applications so through the year we have
a lot of uh let's say experience and
knowledge uh but I think that uh on
the research that is providing by Pharma
industry now uh the Pharma is I think on
the complete wrong way because uh they
want to Let's this is the Pharma mindset
I think they want to develop drug which
will help for a certain condition and uh
I think we should uh adjust the dosage
and everything to human endocannabinoid
system so we can stimulate it on the
best way not for the certain disease but
uh for
the uh soall uh personal medicine
personalized medicine I think this is
the future yeah okay very different
approaches but um with uh similar kinds
of goals in terms of outcomes yeah I I
will I will add as well that obviously
the tayor made that's why is very
different than the pharmaceutical like
standardized product okay you cannot
think about Canabis an application uh
with cannabis plant itself and is
extract
as uh any other pharmaceutical existing
in the industry okay the thing is if you
take a cannabinoid okay then you
synthetize it so you make it P
proprietary technology you patent it
because it's no longer nature and then
you find something that is working on
that molecule which is no longer nature
then you can have a standardized product
but it's not sure that we work on each
and every one of us okay instead exactly
the approach of somebody that it's been
close to the patients can actually
reveal how the pharmaceutical
developments on the Cannabis needs to be
made which is the tailor made medicine
so we can give the
pharmacists not a prepared drug okay cuz
this is why the regulation is like this
at the end of the day and our would like
the the regulation on the medical
cannabis to stick like this and just
move on on the research side because
pharmacist is are so important at this
point because and obviously doctors
because we need to adjust the dosage as
well to each and every one of us the
endoc carabid system as well The
receptors because each and every one of
us has a different uh level of reaction
to uh the cannabinoids and as well uh
the endocannabinoid
similar that are produced by our own
body okay so there's three levels where
you need to look when you are
prescribing or where when are you
preparing a formulation for a patient in
the in the Cannabis you know space so
it's not easy that's why it's so
difficult to educate Physicians okay and
obvious ly another thing is that the
endoc cannabinoid system interacts with
pretty much every disease that we can
have all right so this means that can of
be
mimic we can actually interact with our
endoc carabid system with compounds that
are similar to carabids and as well tpin
and as well flavonoids and as well you
know protein and and uh amino acids so
it's very very you know tailor made a
person uh likes strawberry another lemon
you cannot uh that's why uh for example
France is moving on the right way uh on
the Cannabis medicine because they
flowers
are can is not possible to standardize a
flour okay so they are allowing on the
medical side just the oils okay because
is easier to get datas on the oils
because the flowers are so complicated
they just said okay let's get rid of
this so let's let's stop there for just
a moment cuz that's an interesting uh
place to to um maybe bring in Christian
uh here into the conversation there's a
real emphasis whether it's in the
pharmaceutical model or whether it's in
sort of the the um extent medical model
to having a standardized or consistent
product right and yet the Cannabis by
its nature is this very it's a plant
with a lot of plasticity expressed very
differently depending on the epigenetic
conditions so is there something from a
cultivator point of view that you think
in terms of research could um help
create a more consistent standardized
product that would be of use um in both
the pharmaceutical and the the more
traditional medical
model well Justin um I mean this is what
what is uh demanded even by the
regulatory framework we have uh if you
are going into the medical purpose of
course we have to go into control
conditions more control we have you know
um and more more you're focusing on one
genotype um more we can we can calculate
and predict what the outcome will be
however we are talking about a
bioproduct you know and the bioproduct
is still so diverse so tailor made
medicine um is so much in the future
when it comes to you know to bioproducts
which uh where all of the components if
affect each other as you pointed out I
mean the Entourage effect is something
which we don't understand yet we can we
have just bits and pieces of our
understanding here therefore um I think
that that from our Growers perspective
we are working on and we are getting
much better understanding now on on the
plant I mean there's a lot of companies
now who can produce Canabis but uh
they're all struggling you know even
within the production system um um on on
certain issues which will affect the
secondary MBL composition as well as the
amount of secondary metabolites which
are bioactive so uh I see both ways in
the future I mean the one is of course
going stronger into the medical part
where we really try to understand in the
beginning individual components then we
start combining components you know to
understand what is the the medical
effect here and we have seen this in
other products which have not been you
know so much stigmatized but when I look
into salic lates it's the same same
effect here um until we came up to a
product like aspirine you know but uh
still there is a market in addition to
the whole product and uh this will be
something which we will have also in the
future here with with
Canabis just a quick reaction to this
because I I what I really like about
this panel it kind of reflects the
industry we have completely different
parts in completely different groups and
people with different interests which is
great because a polyphony of Interest
means a polyphony of research you know
Avenues and I honestly do believe there
is space for very different segments and
very different different products so
long as we are clear what is the need we
are trying to meet here what do I mean I
live in Amsterdam there is a regulated
recreational Market Works fantastically
well right there is space for that type
of product in that type of market then
we are seeing more and more of the
Cosmetics food supplements there is
space for that market for people who
want to have a day-to-day functional
benefit there is space for the medical
cannabis Market as it is is evolving and
then there is the pharmaceutical
development which is meant to be a
product um that has been tested and
proven and we know it works for the vast
majority of patients with a specific
disease and can be prescribed based on
evidence knowledge and and the
confidence of the physician and so where
I am seeing that what my experience has
been in this space is we're trying we're
mixing things up and that is not helping
us because it doesn't help us explain to
the end consumer or the patient what
kind of need we're meeting with our
product we can't be everything to
everyone and and if we try to do that in
the end we will end up with more
confusion and everything that comes from
the cannabis plant is going to be
bundled under I don't understand kind of
area and that's where I would like to
caution us to be able to speak to what
is the need we want to meet and what is
the pathway we want to follow so we
chose the pharmaceutical pathway cuz we
have a lot of experience in that and we
are convinced that once something is
proven it can be reimbursed it can
actually be easy to access for a number
of patients that doesn't mean it is the
only way that it means that so long as
we all understand and probably what we
should be investing in is the library of
knowledge a bit of a structured
organized way of understanding
documenting and uh proving the benefit
of different parts of the plan and
different uses I love that term a
library of knowledge uh and something
that um has been unfortunately a little
bit impoverished over these Decades of
prohibition because we haven't been able
to effectively address uh the research
need to be done and create a language
that contextualizes everything in sort
of the path or Lane uh that segment that
it would be uh appropriately placed in
so when we look at the the landscape of
cannabis This research moving forward uh
I'm curious what you all see as um
obstacles that we'll need to overcome uh
I've heard people speak to the stigma of
um working with cannabis uh we're
speaking to not being able to
differentiate the segments and the
different approaches in the context of
application um so I saw you nod your
head first Christian I I'll give you
first shot at this I think I'm going to
get everybody here on the panel a shot
of this what are the obstacles that you
feel like um we need to overcome and and
briefly how might we do that well
talking about obstacles it's always a
money first but this is not what I want
to mention here uh now the for me the
stigma is really one of the the biggest
obstacles I have lots of colleagues who
are working with cannabis and research
and they do not publish papers and they
don't talk about it you know because
still we are coming from a different
generation and uh it's still in the mind
of of in the mindset of many people um
when I uh we we open a lab a cannabis
lab now at the University but when my
president comes she doesn't want to get
a picture because she's a politician of
course you know she doesn't want to
become involved in in in this too much
she's more Curious oh we are working now
in Canabis at the University now that's
kind of strange you know uh we'll see
what what the politics in Germany bring
and I think this is something which we
have to really overcome that's one part
and the second one is you know um in the
moment research is very much within the
companies so research and development is
within companies and they are you know
have of course their own interest they
protect their their research they are
not willing to share among you know but
what what we need is not only a database
of knowledge you know we need also a
solid ground um for you know for getting
uh rid of all of those stigmatization
and uh I think this is something where
where the public needs to jump in in
open markets and markets which are
getting now like in Germany are open
more open and start supporting and this
is the money part you know supporting
public research so that we have all kind
of a of a minimal Baseline and then it
you know the rest can be differentiated
between companies great um AIA is there
something that you'd like to add on or
we could go to badar no I always have
something no I think I already talked
about the patient Centric formats I
think that's number one patient
acceptance will increase the
prescription will increase the use and
will help reduce among other things one
more thing that from a formulation
perspective is important to look at is
the biovailability challenge with many
of these cannabinoids uh we all know CBD
many other cannabinoids have very low
bioavailability very low absorption
because of um first pass metabolism and
incomplete absorption in in the gastric
root so what are we doing about that how
can we actually make sure that the
patient takes enough of the of the
medicine that is going to be good for
them but not more than what they need
and that it is effective so here we at
DSM for Minish have been working on that
and are aiming to have um we're putting
actually a clinical trial together this
summer to test an improved bability uh
formulation but we need more of that
everyone thinking together I'm sure
there are lots of Technologies out there
that have that aspiration eventually and
finally something that's not um that's
not an obstacle
internally so I think viability is an
internal obstacle intrinsic to our work
one that I think is extrinsic is um
regulation legislation being built
without full understanding so I think
our duty and our opportunity is to help
inform uh legislation based on the
research that we do right help the
legislator who's never met uh a
cannaboid medicine before make informed
decisions and there's a really good
example uh there's many but there's one
that sticks to mind in Me is from the
Lambert Institute in Australia where
there was a very specific question from
the regulator do the workers in the
mining and transportation industry in
Australia can they use medical cannabis
and come to work the next day so they
did an observational study and they
proven there is no problem with memory
with driving with anything they could
measure so actually the regulation came
out and said okay that is not not a
problem medical cannabis can be used in
the space and I think we can do a lot
more as well to help invest but that
shouldn't be only on us right it
shouldn't be only on the industry public
private Partnerships shared costs and a
shared understanding of if we are able
to prove that this medicine works and
actually helps relieve pain which is a
massive loss of quality of life how can
we get access to as many patients as
possible great really appreciate that um
B would you like to speak about either
the obstacles uh that you foresee to
research or perhaps the the need to
educate um decision makers and
stakeholders in the industry yes of
course uh bad legislation is always a
big obstacle for any research and uh uh
since uh very recent ago everything uh
about cannabis was illegal you know I
think with the change of the legislation
in Germany and other countries uh this
stigma will very quick disappeared and
uh uh cannabis will come to the
mainstream research because
people demand it you know patients are
very informed about cannabis and now
it's on the
professionals uh side to bring this to
life as soon as possible great
Franchesca do you think that there's a a
way that the the um the regulators and
the decision makers uh uh can be more
informed and more responsive to a
patient Centric approach to something
that considers uh you know really the
the
efficacy um in in an area that's outside
of their um experience outside of their
wheelhouse um and how would you um like
to see us approach that as an
industry well uh we we saw the European
Union last year made make a huge step
forward on cannabis research because
they actually the European Union said
okay let's invest in medical cannabis
research we we give him funds for the
medical cannabis
research uh as well I had the privilege
to work uh back in
2020 with the an in an ISO project that
was was uh to create a standard for a
recreational Market in Europe okay so um
actually I see that the the long story
short we develop the standard there's an
existing standard few people knows this
there's an existing standard ISO
so ISO say for international standard
organization is uh in Geneva I mean
hopefully everybody knows about this
because is every day in our lives
constantly these kind of standards and
regulations okay so we basically develop
the standard for an European
recreational Market how needs to be the
you know the settings and developed but
still is isn't isn't approachable as um
to bring everybody together is uh uh not
applicable cuz simply everyone has a
different approach uh on in each and
every country but I see the legislators
at this point moving forward toward
cannabis okay we tried on the
recreational doesn't worked so they
moved on the medical side and it's
working a lot because anyways we seen a
lot of projects going on as well funded
from you know public entities about the
about cannabis research so I'm very
positive about this unfortunately like I
said the institution is there but the
private sector not much simply because
of the financial issues the return on
investment so fast they want uh they
think like cannabis says uh cryptos uh
and you know so this sort of stigma on
the financial industry and on top
obviously there's a uh the problem of
some patients that really needs canab I
met a lot worldwide
the patients that really need cannabis
but they are afraid of using it they
never used it because of the prohibition
and everything obviously was not
accessible but now they actually have a
problem because I cannot solve it cuz
they using paliative medicine uh but
what if they use cannabis it will be
much better for them CU there's no or
very little side effects compared to the
traditional medicine all right so um
I believe that we can move forward fast
if the finance uh sector is going to
invest in research in pharmaceutical and
we have the backup of the institution so
we can do a lot of great work over here
in Europe but as well I saw companies in
Canada getting Millions for research and
is is exciting you know for on the
medical aspects it's very very exciting
so I hope that we can get to that point
as well over here in Europe cooperating
with institutions like universities
private sector companies
so this is going to be uh the future
great appreciate that yeah we can see
here from the discussion today that it's
a complex sometimes convoluted landscape
um as we emerge out out of the
prohibition era and um and the different
interests that uh that have influence on
where cannabis research is being
directed and to what end uh so sometimes
it it it feels like a lot to try and
overcome but at the same time there's a
lot to be excited about I think we are
finding now that there is going to be
new models of uh public and private
partnership that will come together to
um invest into research that's needed
and and so in the spirit of kind of also
looking at what's possible and what's uh
you know it's what's exciting and what
creates optimism in the space I'd like
to give each of you guys a chance to
speak to just something in the world of
cannaboid or cannabis research um that
you're aware of now that's kind of a
Cutting Edge and an exciting thing um
that really gets you fired up and that
you'd like to share with our audience
here and we'll start with you down there
badar
uh yeah cannabis is the most actually uh
research plant on the planet with 50,000
studies about it I think uh but I think
uh we need more um let's say not that
high science but the uh something that
it would bring cannabis uh more towards
doctors you know they need not high
science but they need the protocols they
need uh applications methods uh they
need uh right
dosages uh and this is uh what is
actually missing because until we don't
have this the doctors is I don't know
this is my opinion from Slovenian uh
aspect uh it will not come to the
general use uh among the Medicals in the
medical system got it so uh education of
healthc Care Professionals and and in in
that sort of field there um development
of that is is a a piece that you see in
um the ex the support and extension of
cannabis research that's exciting yes
and I should also I think that uh
the canab theology should be part of the
curriculum in the medical uh faculties
and all other professional schools
because without the educated
professionals it will never be a part of
of the mainstream
medicine got it thank you uh what about
you AOS here what do you see out on the
horizons of cannabis research that you
find um exciting uh or inspiring on the
horizon so immediately I'm very very
excited about the premium formulated CBD
powder we're bringing to the market
because we are talking enhanced bi
availability solid formats patient
Centric formats and increased API
loading we're talking enabling res
search on a different level but okay
that is for now on the longer on the
time frame on the longer time frame I
really um am encouraged and hopeful to
see that some countries are enabling
regulation that is helping the
traditional way we've had to learn in
this industry on how the plant works
from observational data from Real World
evidence from case studies which is not
something that normally farmer would
accept as part of a weighin this is
becoming part of informing how we will
do pharmaceutical development and how it
will work practical example what's
happening in Brazil you can bring a
product to the cannaboid product to the
market you have to demonstrate quality
and safety and you have five years to do
a clinical trial what happens in those
five years the Physicians learn which
indication it works best which patient
population it works best the legislator
is learning which of these products are
actually uh best to use and which ones
are not foring to the promise 5 years
down the line you have a well-designed
clinical trial that can show benefit in
the right patient population and you
have full Market access this is not
something we've been used to in the
pharmaceutical sector and I think it is
a wonderful step forward that some big
countries and big markets are working on
it oh that's exciting still the
formulated CBD powder is more exciting
so the change of the
mindset Shameless plugs are are welcomed
all right um Christian what about you
where do you see uh the horizons of
cannabis research in in the fields that
you're um involved in that are exciting
and inspiring for you well there there
are two different approaches uh the one
is um and I've heard today in in
different panels uh that we are all
going when it comes to medical cannabis
under really controlled conditions but I
think we are going now under semic
controlled conditions um and we are
having new technologies using lots of
sensors to manipulate the plant during
the production process so that we really
can forecast what the quality is uh what
the THC content is uh and we are able to
um find the right algorithms during our
production system you know um that that
we can um yeah create a plant a Model A
plant which is then maybe the first step
to a tailor you know medicine tailor
personalized medicine when it comes to a
complete bio product uh so I think this
is really uh something which I'm looking
for forward um and and we are learning a
lot in in the last years even the second
part is we are combining now systems in
in Horticulture um you know everything
should be more sustainable because
agriculture Horticulture is of course a
lot of under pressure when it comes to
climate change and all of this and so
hot sustainability plays a major role
and uh combined farming system so where
we use uh not only produce a plant for
for one product where we use the full
plant where we combine it uh to save
energy and so on this is something which
uh is really inspiring and we are we are
running a project where we combine
different production systems and
cannabis is only one part of it where uh
where we work for the uh for the medical
industry but we fully use the plant for
um everything else you know to feed uh
uh to as as a fiber um um and so on so
lots of different products which are
coming here and I think this is really
really interesting to see what's going
on how many people are interested in
Canabis that is a great reminder that
there's often times such a hyperfocus on
you know the particular canabo or
compounds as a result that you find in
the infloresence and the flowers and so
much of the rest of the impact of the
plant and its life cycle and the other
constituents in the plant are forgotten
in these
conversations and you know I'm reminded
that uh in crop rotation with uh wheat
and corn hemp has shown uh 18% increase
in yields in winter wheat for example
just by being in rotation so when you're
talking about using the plant and multi-
um uh multiproduct systems right
producing more than just the Cannabis
simple things like crop rotation uh have
been a part of the the process that has
been forgotten because we weren't
allowed to plant cannabis for I was
thinking even about completely different
production systems like combining it
with aquaculture we can use leftovers
from from the medical industry as a
protein source for aquaculture as a part
of fish feed that's you know this is
something completely different you know
which most people have not in mind but
if you start looking into nature where
you know where the whole plant is used
you know and and there's never when when
when you produce something there's never
waste the term waste does not exist in
nature so you know everything which is a
leftover which is not used by one system
can be used by someone else so uh and we
have uh lots of different production
systems which we can combine thinking
about insects you know fantastic protein
source for maybe the future protein for
humans so insect production is is
emerging field like cannabis you know
and uh the cannabis plant as a whole is
fantastic
yeah yeah okay franches the last all
right so we're about ready to wrap up
Franchesca this is your chance to to
speak to something that you see on the
horizon that's inspiring
well keep I mean yeah I keep I give I'll
try to keep it long story short uh yeah
uh so uh in immediate future there's a
really interesting Nano
formulation that is coming up combined
with other Botanical compounds so
totally natural
medicine uh for patients there a huge
project to bring uh uh you know
compounds uh with fiber as well cuz this
is underrated over here everybody speaks
about the medical use pharmaceutical use
but the amp industry is very underrated
and that this is really the Cannabis
industry should be really the Cannabis
industry so if you guys uh don't want to
invest because it's too risky to
pharmaceutical industry then invest in
amp industry guys textile
buildings I mean compounds uh we there's
a group uh my colleagues are working on
carbon fiber made by amp so like
unbeliev able stuff and another project
the director is right up there uh is
bringing cannabis amp and all the
compound secondary metabolizes to space
guys so this is a really really really
interesting stuff and uh yeah I'm
looking forward if everybody any of you
is interested in this kind of research
just reach out and uh we can cooperate
for sure I mean our philosophies of uh
you know cooperation and in of
competition so we're trying to build a
lot around us and with our partners so
partner up let's do things and like you
know the ICBC is a huge venue to meet so
thanks thank
you we are out of time I'm sorry we
don't have time to get to questions but
I'm sure we can have many discussions in
the foyer and what not I'd like to thank
our entire panel this concludes uh
today's panels at the international
cannabis business conference series
Berlin 2024 my name is uno beum I'm your
host we'd like to thank the tomman group
we will see you tonight at the party in
the showroom starts at 9:00 wear your
badge and you know dress up a little if
you can all right ciao all right
[Applause]