coming up next to discuss Germany as a
cannabis economic Hub the chief econ the
chief Economist for Whitney economics
I've said economics like four times now
let's hear it for Bo
[Applause]
Whitney well thank you very much um
really appreciate the the strong turnout
and it's great to be back at IC BC again
um I think I first spoke here in
2017 um I spoke on the second day I was
talking about why people consume
cannabis um and Dr um rapael mulam spoke
the first day and he was going through
all of his um medical research and it
was striking to me that the research
that he was doing the clinical trials
and showing uh the effects on the human
body um very early on and he's doing IAL
trials and the like it mirrored almost
identical to why people were choosing to
consume cannabis there was anxiety uh
pain management um you know um dietary
stuff and and so um it was quite an
honor to be on that stage um and it's
quite an honor to be back here today so
today I'm going to talk about the
economics of of cannabis and and what
the impact of the reform is in Germany
um I generally go through I I gave a
similar presentation yesterday at the
global investment Forum which I thought
was an amazing event very very
successful um and then but I generally
go through just a high level Global and
then I'll look at the US I'll talk about
Europe and then we'll dig into some
details on the German Market always when
I started to talk was like and so a
little bit about me I'm from Portland
Oregon um I've been in the Cannabis
industry looking at this from the oh
there we go from the economic
perspective I've been looking at
cannabis for about 10 years now what's
up um and my firm Whitney economics is a
global leader in cannabis and hemp um we
do business Consulting we provide data
to the industry economic research we
advise uh individuals businesses uh
governments um Regulators legislators
and the
like and so just at a high level
cannabis is really three Industries in
one there's the adult use the medical
and the industrial
and the industrial can be broken down
into um fiber and grain fiber used for
Plastics and automobile parts and like
uh grains for feed for animal and human
consumption and then the cannabinoid
sector um and uh um countries are
viewing cannabis as a tool for economic
development um they really see the
growth potential they see the
environmental impacts and they really
like it um and um can abis in general is
a trillion Doll Market and so it just
needs to be realized it needs to be
supported and nurtured um as it
transitions away um and into um you know
more environmental environmentally
friendly practices um it can help
transition away from the traditional um
Industries um let's see oh and one thing
to note is that a lot of countries are
waiting for the US to uh reform and when
the US reforms then um other countries
will choose to reform um but my
hypothesis now is that with so much
things so many things going on in Europe
in Germany and the like that maybe
European markets will take the mantle of
leadership in the Cannabis Reform
movement um and displace the US there's
just too much dysfunction in the US
market right
now so currently there's 115 countries
that have legal access to cannabis um
and they choose the reasons for legal
access for different reasons it could be
um environmental it could be um you know
economic it could be job creation and
the like um but nonetheless it's a
there's a lot of um reform and this
reform is accelerating um the there's
about a half a mill or half a billion
consumers on the high end uh globally of
cannabis
um it's it ranges from a 250 to 500 um M
billion dollar market and then you've
got another 500 billion to 750 billion
on the hemp total addressable market so
um this is a a global industry and it's
huge so um I I do modeling economic
modeling using different data sets and
the more conservative side is the orange
bar and that's data taken from the UN
ODC the um un um they do these surveys
every year well not every year but from
time to time in different countries on
cannabis consumption and like drug
consumption um and their usage rate
levels um for consumers are are very
very conservative and it's
understandable if a government official
says hi I'm from the UN do you smoke
weed then you know if you're in a place
like Singapore or something then
generally your answer is going to be no
um even if you do consume cannabis so um
the the UN ODC numbers are rather
conservative um the green bar is um some
data that models that I put together
that I leverage the UN numbers but um
then I um update them a little bit from
what I'm seeing in different markets and
I tap into all these different markets
all over the world and then there's the
high end which which is um a you know a
little bit more aggressive approach to
the Cannabis consumer consumption rates
um but what I found when I looked at all
these 115 countries is that the total
addressable Market that's illegal and
legal consumption um put together what I
found is that in countries that have
medical reform there's actually those
are the largest markets combined right
now and so there's a lot of Economic
Opportunity if you get into these
markets and then um get a foothold and
then as they transition into adult use
then you're already um in those markets
and so you can just expand your capacity
um so this is the the 237 billion is
based upon the conservative side so just
think of the upside potential on some of
these more aggressive
forecasts so in the US um people look at
the US a lot so I'd be remiss if I
didn't mention a little bit about it um
last year $ 28.8 billion um in legal
sales in the adult use in medical space
um we're forecasting 29 billion U for
this year so it's 10% year-over-year
growth um most Industries would love to
have 10% year-over-year growth um but um
in the Cannabis space because in the
early days they experience 18 20 30 35%
growth um you know 10% is um kind of a
disappointment um but when you look at
and peel back some of the layers of the
onion um 10 states there's is kind of a
different story uh 10 states actually uh
saw declines in their revenue I and
that's kind of surprising because you
still saw growth but the growth wasn't
coming from the mature States it was
coming from all the new States um and
then there's you know some regulatory
issues there's test inflation um it's
rather rampid um THC um test inflation
uh less than 20% of lenses in a recent
survey that we put out and published a
report on about a year ago um less than
20% of the lenses were actually
profitable and um so there's economic
stress in the in the US market right now
um $3.8 billion in delinquent payments
so um vendors aren't paying each other
and Retail isn't paying their
cultivators and the like and so um this
is a major issue um we just put out a
report on this as as well um and there's
this hyperfocus on by Regulators on the
hemp derive cannabinoids and and they're
trying to bring that under the marijuana
um
jurisdictions um but I'm not quite sure
if that's the right way to go um and
then you've got a nearly 80 billion
elicit market so even though um there's
a lot going on in the US market um it
could be regulated much better than it
actually is um and there's some federal
reform that's um on the discussion table
from safe access to interstate commerce
um legalization efforts um but it's
really fragmented and it's really
dysfunctional at the federal level so
I'm not anticipating very much Federal
reform to occur in near term and so it's
going to be kind of the status quo um
you know at least for the next few years
um and resched is being talked about in
the US um but I don't know if that's
going to be the Panacea or the it's
going to it's not going to be as
beneficial to all as people think and so
um there may be some unintended
consequences on that
reform now um despite the challenges you
know we're looking for strong growth in
the US um and this a lot of this growth
just comes from these new emerging
markets and some that have already
deployed their programs but are just
ramping up and there was a question in
the audience in the last panel that
talked about um the Social Clubs and and
how do you get a bigger Market in
Germany and one of the panelists Riley
said that it takes more than just having
Social Clubs in order to expand the
market here in Germany and I totally
agree with that because um unless you
have access you don't have legal
participation and so the more access
that you can get to Consumers the more
opportunities there are for legal
participation and that's a big key I and
I'll go into that in a little
bit but you know by 2035 we're you know
we're looking at what $87 billion it's a
pretty decent Market it's taking a big
chunk out of the Elissa
Market but it's all because of
access so contrast that to the EU in the
US they look at hemp and cannabis
differently um um in the EU it's all
cannabis and I think that's refreshing
and then they just regulate it based
upon the product intention and so that's
reasonable and so people aren't tripping
over themselves trying to figure out
what's hemp and what's not um and um a
lot of the countries here in Europe are
defaulting to the EU rules and
regulations um and but this this German
roll out here is one of those indicators
that could be a catalyst
um to um have different reform and
accelerate the reform throughout
different European
countries um but um I think that uh the
EU could be you know a sleeping giant in
this Regard in terms of not only um
showing increases um in reform movements
within the EU but throughout the world
as
well and so in terms of numbers the
total addressable Market that's ilicit
and legal combined in Europe
conservatively using the UN data is $ 53
billion um but if you use a more
aggressive U modeling then it's $126
billion and um a lot of the countries
are looking at reform and they're doing
things kind of differently some want
pilot programs some want Social Clubs
some want other things and so um it's a
little bit
directionless um there's no one model
that's emerging quite yet
um but if you think about it for the
Eastern and Southern parts of Europe
they could become the providers of raw
materials and and um finished goods U
product manufactured goods and then they
can export them into the central part of
Europe and I think that's a viable model
because you have lowcost producers and
suppliers um in the periphery and then
you have the the more um higher
generating income earners and consumers
in the central
part um but there's not much data on
this quite yet um we can help of course
I have to Shameless plug right um but um
there's the we're getting better in
terms of the data and the data offerings
and so but I'm always looking for data
and I'm always willing to share my data
so if you want to collaborate with me
I'm I'm wide open I'm happy to do
so so of that 50 3 billion just five
countries make up the bulk of the demand
um France and this is based upon
consumption rates um and then
multiplying the number of consumers by a
certain spend and so France is at the
top um and it toggles between France
Germany and Italy um but those are the
the big three markets and then the UK is
in there um I call them EU even though
probably shouldn't um
um but it could be if you if you include
some of the other periphery countries in
Europe like Russia and the like then
there could be um as many as 84 million
consumers in the
space so that's kind of the background
so I'm taking a little bit of a breath
uh let's go into some of the data about
Germany so there's roughly 4 million
consumers on the conservative side it
could be as many as 8 million consum
consumers um now in Germany in a recent
poll 47% of the Germans supported
legalization and 42% opposed it and so
that could be the reason why there's so
few relatively few consumers um when
compared to the US Canada Uruguay and
others um and in order to support all of
the demand um for uh cultivated or for
products regardless of the delivery
mechanism oils flowers and like um it
would take about 948 th000 kilos of
cultivated output in order to support
the entire Market um now this looks at
Europe in this chart um 7.8 million
kilos of total demand in the market um
17 million pounds um now for perspective
California produces 22 million pounds
every year even though um about 18
million pounds of that is exported
outside of the State of
California um and so the total
addressable Market total potential in
Germany is 7.8 billion EUR um and with
greater social acceptance and increased
usage rates um that could be as high as
15.6 billion EUR um now for perspective
at 7.8 billion that's roughly the size
of the Florida Market or the New York
Market it's not quite as big as uh
California or Texas um but it is Florida
and New York and so those are sizable
markets Florida is ranked number two in
the US by the
way um in terms of consumers I mentioned
this 4 million as many as 8 million and
this is why this is the slide where I
mentioned the Social Clubs may actually
limit growth in the near term because if
you only have 500 um club members per
club and you don't deploy as many clubs
fast enough if there's obstacles then
you're not going to get that legal
growth legal participation that people
are
anticipating and so I mentioned the
total Supply um it could go um the upper
bound is around 2 million
kilos um but this this total Supply um
isn't needed and so as regulations are
deployed um you need to kind of baby
step you need to grow into the you need
to grow the supply as the demand
dictates it and so a lot of the common
mistakes in these jurisdictions um in
these countries or States provinces is
that they tend to overs Supply the
market at first they issue all the
supply licenses and then all of a sudden
there's over Supply there's not enough
demand prices go down and cultivators
are left holding the bag they're not
making any money um and so the initial
Supply requirements in year one from
what I see is between 25 and 50,000
kilos now last year I think Germany
imported 30,000 kilos and I think
13 um 13,000 went to the
pharmacies so you know there's if
there's already a lot of supply and
you're going to add more in these
suppliers um domes ially then this is
really setting up for an over Supply
situation so in club openings I I
thought that it'd be interesting for
people to kind of understand my take on
the number of clubs and how they would
roll out over time so in the first year
we're looking at 200 to 400 clubs now um
you know the policy is one club for
every 6,000 residents but not all cities
are going to deploy not all cities are
going to have clubs um and it's going to
you know take time to ramp this up and
this is not uncommon in any new
jurisdiction where there's
legalization um it takes a while for the
for the um consumers to participate and
join into the legal um system and it
takes incentive so the government The
Regulators The Operators all need to
incentivize provide a reason for
consumers to participate legally but as
they eventually um do then there'll be
more and more um clubs required now um
you know I'm not this this model um has
some ranges here um we'll know more
about um and we'll be able to predict
this more precisely once we see the
first year results once we have an
anchor um in terms of the data for the
first year then it's very very
predictable afterwards um and so you
know I'll keep you up to date maybe next
year um at the same
conference um people like to talk about
employment especially policy makers
because when you're adding jobs when
you're adding tax revenue and the like
then that gives the politicians cover it
gives them protection against people
that are more in favor of prohibition
but when you're adding jobs then that's
a good thing um and so the total
potential Market um is worth roughly
367,000
workers um but you're only going to need
4 to 8,000 full-time equivalent workers
in the legal market now the way it's set
up in Germany is you have all of these
part-time workers in these clubs and so
you're only allowed to have a certain
number of hours or pay them a certain
wage per month um and so you know the 4
to 8,000 workers is really 12 to 24,00
workers um part-time workers so I just
combine them all into one now for
comparison we just published a report
with um um a company called vanst in the
US and it just came out the report came
out last week and um we show that there
were 440,000 legal workers in the United
States and so I just wanted to provide
some comparison um the total market for
employment in the United States is about
1.5 to 1.6 million workers so when you
think about this um 360,000
workers um that's a lot of employment
there's a lot of economic impact that
cannabis has in these countries in these
communities and this is why there's um
it's accelerating the reform um
throughout the
globe and so in terms of opportunities
there's some immediate opportunities and
then some long-term opportunities um in
the immediate term
cultivation um software to track all
this stuff crm's customer resource um
management
software um you know because you want to
track your club members and like um
medical research this is one of the um
significant benefits to the deployment
of legal cannabis um in Germany um and
medical research is desperately needed
more and more of it and then there's
other ancillary businesses so if you
walk out in the exhibit hall you've got
all these ancillary businesses from grow
lights to you know um cooler dehumid
dehumidifier easy for me to say and um
you've got all these ancillary
businesses and so there's going to be um
a surge and demand for these ancillary
services so if you get in early um you
can really set yourself up for success
in the future but there are risks right
it's not just you enterer into a market
and all of a sudden you're printing
money um you know there's risk of
oversupply there's risk and delays in
deployment um it may be tough to find a
location because of um you know certain
jurisdiction restrictions like um
permitting and codes and compliance and
all this other stuff so um it may be
difficult and then there may be other
barriers to entry that um you know that
go beyond the rules and regulations um
you know access to Capital and other
things so um it's important to
understand not only the opportunities
but the risks when you um when you enter
enter into this
space and so in terms of predictions
I've just got a couple more slides and
I'll take some questions if I have time
um but you know expect except expect an
acceleration of reform as a result of
Germany um and there's bound to be a
response from the EU and the UN um
because does it violate certain parts of
the international treaties does it not
um how does the one country if it's
legal in one country it's legal in all
in the EU policy how does that affect
now that um Germany has entered into
this space it's very compelling um and
then look for certain restrictions or
barriers um to get into these markets
like requirement for certified seeds or
GMP and GAP EU GMP
certifications um those are good things
because they um um enable the companies
to track and Trace um uh they do more
discipline in their operations and so um
and this also is something that North
and South American and African suppliers
should be aware of is that if um that's
a barrier to entry to get into the
European space too so there's a trend
towards GMP and GAP certifications in
South America um less so in the US but
definitely in Canada so this will
differentiate who can participate and
who cannot so it's really important to
be aware of that and prepare for it in
the future because it takes a little bit
of time in order to get those
certifications um and then you know I'm
also mentioning um in addition to Pharma
being more of a Pharma play and a
medical play here in Europe um but you
know hemp will also become a major
Market in the EU they already are um and
they have the possibility of expanding
if they have enough land and cultivation
in order to
support and so
recommendations um communicate talk to
one another go to conferences like this
um it's really critical to do that
networking um and then get established
in j Germany or in Europe but in Germany
initially um so that as the Market opens
up you already have a presence here so
if you're a us uh supplier
manufacturer um it's important to
partner up with folks in this
market um and know your cost structure
um the reason I've harped on I've
mentioned oversupply a lot is it could
lead to a deceleration in price and it
decline price and if there's a decline
in price then it could put people out of
business if they're not aware of what
their cost structure is all about um and
be prepared for that and it's important
to also use data right to understand
what the data is um talk to me talk to
anybody that has data um and make sure
that you use datadriven uh decision
making because um cannabis can be very
emotional at times and while you know
know cannabis is very
local um it's important to be aware of
the global Marketplace and so when you
act local that's good because you have
to but be sure to think globally um
because this is definitely a trillion
dollar Global
Market so um that's what I've got so far
um thanks for your attention really
appreciate it if you have want to copy
of my slides happy to provide them just
shoot me a note um and so we're ready
for we're ready for some questions let's
hear it for Bo
[Applause]
Whitney we have three minutes three
minutes so that's like one or two
questions but apparently you have
educated them fully and they are all
experts okay Derek here we
go just the one question about the hemp
where you say that you think it' be a
big Market in the EU as well my
impression is that in the states it's
not going that well with the hemp
industry so could you expand a bit on
that in 2 and 1/2 minutes oh hey if you
can bring up my slides um just for a
second I've got some in backup that I
can I can show and demonstrate the
market for
hemp so with oh thank you
okay so in the backup of my slides I
talk a little bit about the modern uses
of hemp but then I also looked at these
various Industries so with the hemp you
can make um construction material
automobile parts textiles you can make
EV batteries for cars um you can make
Cutlery um like my sister company
everyday hemp um company does um you can
feed this to animals and the like and so
even with just a small percentage of
market share capture by
hemp it's a half a trillion dollar
market um and so you've got these
traditional Industries and then then
you've got these industries that you can
support and um transition over to a more
environmentally and sustainable product
and so um this is what I'm talking about
when I say that there's a major
opportunity in Europe um and um this is
already in existence it's just it needs
nurturing and growth um and so in
countries where they have favorable hemp
laws um you can look at what industries
that they're current have in their
country like Automotive for example um
and then you can start building products
to substitute for existing traditional
Industries um now 20% of
BMWs are made with hemp parts and so
already that's on their website and so
they already have this sustainable
mandate in the EU so this just like I
said needs to be expanded now when you
compare it to the Cannabis Market total
addressable Market 237 billion
you've got 500 billion for hemp
conservatively that's why I say that
there's these great opportunities that
just needs to if you have a good product
you have a vision and you follow through
with it um there's there's tremendous um
upside potential as well in this space
fantastic thank you we're up here uh
right way to ask a good question and get
a bonus slide way to go Derek one more
question up here um kind of picking
backing off of his um comment of how the
US hemp Market's not doing so well you
stated that it probably would not be
best for Regulators to bring hemp under
the Cannabis umbrella however wouldn't
that create an unnecessary competition
between the hemp and cannabis industry
such in US Florida's baned on hemp
derived products in your opinion what
would be a better
route um yeah that's a great question um
the what is going on in the United
States is that Regulators are not sure
what to do with hemp versus adult use of
medical they're trying to bring it all
Under One Roof um but they're focused on
the intoxicating
canono and so they're not really um uh
able or qualified enough to look at the
fiber Market or qualified enough to look
at the food market the animal feed the
human feed and so I think to in order to
solve this they need to look and
regulate at the product in ttention
level and not it's hemp or or marijuana
and so if you look at it at the product
intention level if you have intoxicating
cannabinoids sure that might be
appropriate to be regulated um under a a
medical or a marijuana regulator um but
certainly roof tiles have no business
being regulated by a marijuana you know
and so um but right now um there was an
over supply of hemp in the United States
um which led to a deceleration um a
depression in pricing and a lot of
people lost their um businesses as a
result they went out of business because
of the following prices a lot of people
exited and so now the um hemp Market in
the United States 30,000 Acres I'm not
sure what hectar that is but 30,000
Acres of licensed capacity um look for
that to actually grow that's actually
lower than it was five or six years ago
so there's tremendous opportunities even
in the United States um but it's just
going to take a little bit of investment
and a little bit of discipline and when
it comes to policymaking they need to be
much more precise in their rules and
regulations otherwise they could have
unintended consequences like in Florida
um that's a multi-billion dollar market
for hemp and it it's generates thousands
of jobs tens of thousands of jobs and so
if you um ban something without being
disciplined um then you're not going to
meet your objectives for um Public
Safety public policy objectives and
you're going to have all of this
displaced workers and other things so
fantastic Bo Whitney we're out of time
Bo
[Music]
Whitney thanks