right here on the front row big support
you know Colombian weed Expo Medan Expo
uh Henry right here a big up big support
of the ICBC right here really appreciate
you Henry I just got my new goo hat now
so we're ready to we're ready to rock
and roll my name is Alex Rogers I'm the
CEO and I'm the founder of the ICBC this
is our fifth uh Edition in uh Barcelona
we started our first edition was 218 we
made a beautiful partnership with
spannabis and we decided to rock and
roll and bring B2B to Spain um I would
like to thank the tomman group for
sponsoring being the head sponsor of the
event go see the check them out they got
a booth here um we got a big party with
DJ mugs tonight at
9:00 and uh I just want to say that um
you know I heard some coffee shops got
raided last night did anyone hear that
that some coffee shops got raided yeah
you know it's so ironic here we are it
feels like weed is legal but I always
say that the battle's Just Begun so even
when uh uh uh we make uh progress with
policy that's really when the work just
beg is begun begins because the devil's
in the details right and so they say 90
uh implementation is 90% of the law and
so it's incumbent upon us to educate and
push it out there in a diser Babylon you
know what I'm saying cuz we all live in
the institution right and we all have to
St strong and stand up now in some ways
I think I'm preaching to the choir
because I think that's most of all of
you right now right here we're not
complacent we stand up for what we
believe in and that's not just cannabis
that's human rights and treating each
other with respect and dignity all the
time right because unless you're a total
[ __ ] then you can [ __ ] off right but
we have to have tolerance for uh for for
people and things and we have to
understand that it's a magical miracle
that we're all here together and have
this be share this beautiful life on
this planet for this brief time that we
get here so I just want to say thank you
I feel very blessed I want to thank you
all and can you please give you all a
round of
[Applause]
applause thank you so much um so I'd
like to let's get it going y'all y'all
ready yeah um so so let's get it going
um I'd like to introduce uh first uh the
MC of the ICBC for the last 10 years my
main man for 30 Years everybody please
give a warm welcome to the one and
only once again for Alex Rogers and the
whole ICBC team they put this whole
thing together span man it's just it's
always a pleasure to be here so being
venos of Barcelona and uh you're you're
really going to enjoy yourself we have a
great a great group of panels and
speakers today it's going to be
fantastic uh a couple quick
announcements it says in the program
that the party starts at 8 that's
ridiculous this is Barcelona the party
starts at 9:00 right and that's still
kind of early but you know some of you
are old
so I include myself in that statement
right so the party starts at 9:00 uh at
the addition Hotel DJ mugs is going to
spend it's going to be a great time
there'll be drinks and snacks and food
and all the stuff bring your badge
you'll get in it'll be fantastic also
tickets for Berlin are on sale right now
and Berlin is crazy because their their
legalization program is going forward
and so this is the time to go to learn
about how to get involved to learn what
to do to meet all the people who are
going to be involved in it it's going to
be great so don't forget to get your
tickets to Berlin and also like Alex
mentioned we'd like to thank our title
sponsor the tomman group because they
are also awesome and this is how things
get done come on in come on in everybody
so with that being said let's just get
it started we have our keynote speaker
uh she's amazing they say that knowledge
is power right she knows a lot of things
because she is the founder of New
Frontier data so she can she can break
down all the all the analytics for you
and all the different things and she's
going to talk about a bunch of different
things here and um she's also the
principal in blue onyx Horizons and I
like you to put your hands together and
welcome to the international camp
business conference G de
[Applause]
morning good morning good
morning um I was I was talking outside
and we're we're sort of reminiscing
about wow it's been 10 years and I've
had the privilege of of attending uh the
ICBC for a decade now and it feels like
a College reunion it really does it
doesn't feel like work it feels like fun
so thank you acbc for having me uh very
exciting time Germany finally legalized
recreational
and I am here today um to help draw some
parallels from what happened in the US
after the first recreational
legalization what can we learn The Good
the Bad and the Ugly the risks and the
opportunities from the
experience that um that we can see from
the United States of North America in
general
yep it
works so fun and games
aside we say that you know we're history
repeats itself and um you know we're
doomed if we don't learn from it I
believe that it creates a great
opportunity for us here in Europe given
that we have our peers in North America
that have truly had their first chance
of making the mistakes learned the
lessons and that if we look back we may
be able to expedite uh and
maximize uh what we can truly we can
truly do for the industry here uh in
Europe so who am I a little bit of
background uh well I've had the pleasure
to see a lot of friendly faces um there
also a lot of new faces so I came into
the industry in 2014 in the US I founded
a company called New Frontier data and
we were the first to come in uh trying
to really look at Raw data uh draw
analytics and be able to predict where
the risks and the opportunities would be
uh 2014 was an interesting year in North
America because in
2012 uh Oregon uh uh and was uh Colorado
and Washington state were the first
states to legalize recreational Cannabis
despite the California was the first
legalized in the 1990s we really saw a
shift in the marketplace
both from an investment and a new
business perspective really in 2013 and
2014 so I've had the privilege to sort
of had a front row seat at what happened
and what was the
story so what happened since so I want
to First Take sort of a look at the
globe and then bring it back to Europe
we have over a 100 Nations around the
world that have either legalized or
decriminalized cannabis today I remember
saying that there were 18 States now
it's over a 100 Nations we've gone a
long way in just a
decade and what's happened in this last
decade if we begin to see some uh
Regional Trends with some specific
specialization in each of these regions
when it comes to the Cannabis industry
which is really unique uh because the
Cannabis industry went from being an
Emerging Market to a global phenomenon
so North America really sort of the
epicenter of consumption um a lot of
sort of uh plant touching uh Innovation
uh and b2c sort of types of businesses
uh also North America continues to be
the largest consumer Market in the world
mind you Europe is expected to sec to be
the second largest then we have Latin
America where we have seen some serious
deregulation and they seem to be
positioning themselves as more of a
lower cost cultivation Hub uh with an
intent of really exporting to those
consumer markets so Europe and nor North
America Asia Pacific very interesting
region as far as the Cannabis industry
really looking to focus in R&amp;D whether
it is from medical use or Industrial
Hemp applications so we're seeing a lot
of uh new uh IP uh in terms of the
graphin of hemp and we're also seeing
some very Advanced um research in terms
of the medicinal applications of
cannabis for things such as
cancer Africa Africa is very interesting
as well while there aren't as many
nations that have legalized uh or
decriminalized Africa has been an
agro-based economy as a whole mostly
dominated by tobacco cultivation given
the decrease in tobacco consumption
around the world they have been looking
for an opportunity to both diversify out
of tobacco but also I must admit um cut
the bonds from Chinese sort of financial
dominance I'm sorry I'm going to say it
and so they're looking at hemp as an
opportunity to get out of that situation
with a hope to also export lowcost uh
hemp and cannabis to Europe with of
course some regulatory challenges
they're still trying to work through and
last but not least Europe Europe is the
big question mark we all want to figure
out what's going to happen in Europe
Europe is really specially
positioned Europe has had the
opportunity to look and learn from
what's happened around the world they've
taken their time they've been very wise
as the old Nation uh to wait for the
right time Europe also has the benefit
of a very mature uh food and beverage uh
and health and beauty um industrial
infrastructure whereby those Advanced
application of cannabis for those
sectors may be the true opportunity so
maybe it is a processing Hub maybe it's
a consumer goods export Hub uh the
question mark remains but the
opportunities are certainly
material how material are they the
global cannabis industry today is that
of over 300 billion it is massive and
that's a conservative number mind you
you're going to see a lot of numbers uh
from a variety of data and analytics
experts which I'm very happy to see that
since new data was born now there are
many looking but what we all agree on is
that it's huge and that it's growing
interestingly look at Europe Europe it's
almost a $70 billion opportunity Manu
that does include illegal use and what
we have seen in North America is as
states were legalizing there was about a
30% shift from illegal use to Legal use
so there is a material opportunity an
early stage opportunity here in
Europe what else can we see from a trend
perspective when we look at the US well
we talk about the 8year economic cycle
guess what that really does work it's
real because that's what we saw in the
US from 2012 to 2020 we sort of saw a
bell curve type of shift in terms of the
volume of investment that went into the
industry the number of companies that
started and went to
Market as well as a quite diverse
sequencing of shift of the types of
businesses that were ripe to Pro Prof
and succeed and I'll talk a little bit
more about
that so let's first talk about money how
did the investment how did the capital
markets in North America and the
Cannabis industry sort of advanced
you'll notice that I the numbers do not
start in 2012 or in 2014 and that's
because the type of Investments that
went in early on in the Cannabis
industry were primarily from Angel
Investors some of them not even
accredited uh and they were really Small
Checks when I came in I raised my first
million about 25 to $50,000 at a time it
was gruesome but that's what happened
there it was the green Rush there was
there was money floating around there
were a lot of investors sort of writing
checks but there were small checks so
the overall amounts were un llarge we
did begin to see a shift in 2015 and
2016 and what happened is the industry
was getting smarter and folks from
outside of the Cannabis industry venture
capitalist created canab abis specific
funds so this is still not non-cannabis
it's still not institutional investment
per se but it was beginning to sort of
operate These funds were beginning to
operate like more mature uh venture
capitalist so they were starting to look
at financials it wasn't just about ooh
you have cultivation and weed let's
invest we started to begin to see sort
of a shift and
maturation in 2017 to 2021 is where we
really saw the boom and if you look at
the graph you can sort of see that
increase so what happened well first and
foremost institutional investors finally
paid attention they began to see
consumption in the Cannabis industry go
up they began to see States legalizing
being able to have extra Revenue to
spend in things like education and
decrease in crime and so the interest
was there so number one institutional
investment came in number two there was
a begin beginning of sort of this idea
of going public I mean it wasn't
necessarily sort of the boom that we saw
all the way in 2019 and 2020 but there
was a
shift 20 2019 is where we really had an
explosion and that was absolutely driven
by the public market both in Canada and
the United States but mostly Canada and
then you see this drop in 2020 yes Co
happened that's what happened really but
what's interesting to note in 2020 is
that the size of the checks of the deals
were the largest ever in history we're
talking about half a billion
plus then 2021 we saw sort of a
continuations of do that public market
activity with a drop in
2022 now why the drop well variety of
reasons the biggest one is poor
performance of
companies companies were just not
performing as well as the investors were
expected and those institutional
investors that mature Capital Market
that came in were not okay with the
financial performance and the
ineffective operation of some of these
businesses remember that the the the
birth of the Cannabis industry in the
United States was really stemming from a
movement so the folks that came in were
folks that mind mind you might have been
in the illegal Market coming in so they
weren't necessarily you know work and
graduates not that it matters a lot of
them succeeded but overall they didn't
have the level of sophistication in
business to grow and scale a business
something that is probably going to be
very different here in Europe another
interesting thing to note about 2022 is
that we begin to see a shift from Equity
to debt why why well again Equity was
too risky so um operators that now
really needed to scale and grow
especially with from a surge of
consumption during covid needed capital
and they had nowhere to get it and so
they went for debt and that has become
very expensive since so in the United
States today you have a really really
tight Capital Market and many of those
operators are coming into Europe where
they feel there's more opportunity
there's more liquidity
so both from an operator perspective and
an investor perspective so it doesn't
matter if you're looking to invest or if
you're looking to put in a business what
can we learn from what happened in sort
of that 8 to 10 year experience in the
US well that 2012 to 2015 as I mentioned
really Angel investment Small Checks
seed the green RH if it was Cannabis you
were in
great well here in Europe arguably we've
kind of gone through that honestly we
skipped the green rush because of all
the reasons I mentioned before this is
already a market that is starting from a
much more mature position The Operators
and the investors that are looking at
this space are either coming from the US
where they've or North America where
they've already learned their lessons
and earned their stripes or they are
mature investors and operators already
established in Europe that are looking
to diversify into the Cannabis space so
let's say that we skipped it now I
putting the European opportuni sort of
still a little bit to the left because
there still are some seed and plant
touching uh
opportunities but we I believe that we
truly are in sort of that second phase
and what we saw in the US between 2016
and 2018 where it really is post seed
not so much plant touching right
especially in Europe um still some plant
touching but really we're looking at
more
sophisticated uh um business and value
propositions that truly are looking to
support those plant touching operators
and the plant touching vertical of the
industry other things that are very
unique to to Europe and that we saw in
the second phase in the US is this
introduction of hemp specific not so
hemp for CBD of course medicinal use in
Europe is extremely important but atast
Advanced industrial applications that
the European market today has the
benefit of really capital relizing on
because research and development has had
10 years to um evolve around the world
and not necessarily specifically in the
United States of North America a lot of
it is happening in Asia
Pacific and last but not least real
estate interestingly enough uh real
estate in the United States well it
seems like a no-brainer right if you're
cultivating or you're processing you
obviously need real estate how come
there's not a lot of investment in it
well lessons learns tell us real estate
is going to go up and it's going to be
very interesting once we reach that Apex
of consumption in Europe real estate is
definitely something that Europeans have
an opportunity to look at right now as
it pertains to the Cannabis space and
then in the US between 2019 and 2022
what we saw as I mentioned really the
public market but specifically we we saw
the emergence of REITs um we saw the
emergence of ETFs specific to cannabis
lots of SPS For Better or For Worse uh
and I don't have time to to dive deeper
into it but the spax phenomenon in the
United States when it comes to cannabis
was quite tumultous let's just say and a
lot of m&amp; and iOS and the m&amp;a was really
sort of a a consolidation phenomena
whereby unfortunately the smaller
companies or the companies that weren't
able to scale and grow or secure Capital
to grow to scale and grow were absorbed
uh by others or when out a business and
we are still at that stage I would say
in the United States today
some very high level key Lessons Learned
and mind you I expect that the audience
today is sophisticated and some of this
is going to feel like a duh we know that
but this is more a way to look at what
happened in the US and the mistakes that
we did make there and the the lessons
that we learned from those mistakes uh
and also after 10 years at looking at
Dex and um For Better or For Worse
raising Capital um these are sort of the
things that truly Rose to the surface as
far as not what to do and not to do at
this point in Europe so
dudes honest and diverse leadership that
may seem sort of like a silly thing to
say or an obvious statement it isn't the
Cannabis industry for better for worse
is still a little shady it's still a
great area so having an honest and
diverse given that it's a global uh uh
industry and mind you I'm a woman and
I'm a you know I'm I'm a half Cuban
woman so that's also very dear to me but
diversity and honesty in the industry
from a leadership perspective is
extremely important in order to have a
successful business if you believe in
karma but also have the trust of an
investor and the Capital
Market knowledgeable and Professional
Management may also seem obvious but
guess what in the Cannabis industry you
do need those folks that are veterans in
the Cannabis industry that understand
the plant that understand the market
that understand the consumer but you
also need folks that truly understand
business and mature business because the
competitive environment today is much
tougher than it was when I came in in
2014 you have pharmaceutical you do have
health and beauty you have food and
beverage you have some serious money and
knowledge that is interested in this
space so your management needs to be up
to the task of navigating it and
Defending Your
Position clear and
substantiated and this is something
that's true in cannabis and it's it's
true anywhere else and before preparing
for this chat I did kind of call all my
pals that are still investing in
cannabis and not in
cannabis and I kind of you know I asked
I asked the question you know what are
the three things that I really sort of
Make It or Break It For You in your
thesis of investment regardless to what
you're investing in they said three
things number one clear Market
understanding what that means is if
you're in the Cannabis industry choose
use your vertical don't be like all over
the place you want to be vertically
integrated great be very clear and be
able to substantiate what your target
addressable Market is because there are
a lot of shiny objects in the Cannabis
industry and they'll continue to be and
they're very distracting and investors
do not like destruction and destruction
leads to inefficiency for
operators two clear and substantiated
product what is it that you do I don't
think doing it all is really the way to
go that may have worked in the United
States 10 years ago but today I think in
Europe there's really an opportunity to
specialize and the deeper and the niche
the more Niche you are the more likely
you're going to be able to defend and
plant that
flag traction and this is something that
definitely wasn't on the board 10 years
ago because it was new how do you prove
traction well now you can and investors
are expecting you to prove it and
substantiate it have that pilot show
what your consumer wants and that
engagement because it's going to be
expected it isn't the green Rush
anymore the
does well alas a good idea is not
necessarily a business a business needs
a business plan I mean I remember uh my
first my first pitch was in Austin Texas
in like
2014 um I was the only woman on stage
and I was the only one talking about
something that didn't involve smoking it
in fact someone on stage and I I tell
this a lot literally booed and said if
we can't smoke it we don't care because
I was talking about data but at that
point basically if you had a power point
and it said cannabis in it it was a
business plan well that's no longer the
case you need a real business plan maybe
not a 50-page PDF but certainly
something that's well thought out with a
mission a vision um an actual financial
plan I mean all of the sort of
infrastructure of a real house when it
comes to a business two competition
cannot be ignored and anymore it is a
global market where you're getting
competitors no no longer just locally or
across the street your competition is
regional and Global uh and that makes
makes it that you leasts to number three
that you need to be extremely thoughtful
about your strategy so businesses that
do not have a very very clear
operational financial and strategic plan
are not only likely not to be of
interest to a sophisticated investor but
also likey not going to be able to truly
make it and succeed in the Cannabis
industry today
so yes history does repeat itself but
every time it does the price goes up and
I think that for us that means that we
can make more money so I wish for all of
you to be very successful and very
profitable in the Cannabis industry in
Europe and thank you so much