thank you all for joining us here a
global investor Forum we're going to
talk about some interesting stuff about
exit options we're going to talk about
the picks and shovels I'm Alex revic
been coming here since 2017. so amazing
to see all these people here and
watching Berlin grow to what it is today
and uh I've been doing this now for
almost 10 years in the legal industry
now I have an Edibles contract
manufacturer in Canada and a pharmacy
called hybrid farm and I'm gonna let my
awesome panelists introduce themselves
go ahead Phil
hi guys my name is Philip I work for
carterage it's not my first rodeo in
cannabis I started in the Cannabis
industry in 2017.
I joined pedanus which was the first
cannabis Wholesale in Europe which was
later acquired by Aurora and I became
the managing director for Aurora Europe
and built a European platform for Aurora
as we all know Aurora had a quite unique
operating model vertically integrated
from sea to sale
and then with kantaraj we came up with a
new operating model which is at least to
me quite unique it allows us to partner
with any legal grower worldwide bring
their cannabis to Germany manufactured
here according to EU GMP and then sell
it all over Europe
as of today we've signed long-term
agreements with more than 50 cultivators
from 18 countries
and brought cannabis flowers from
Jamaica Uganda Uruguay Portugal Spain
into German and UK pharmacies so that's
quite unique it definitely improved at
least from our perspective the quality
of flour currently available in Europe
and it also shows in our development we
went public last year in November and so
far we've been growing steadily and
we're one of the few companies I think
in Europe but also worldwide that's
actually already profitable
so very happy to talk about counter rash
today but also any types of questions
you'll throw at me
Kiora everyone my name is Carmen Darren
I'm the CEO of Helios Therapeutics which
is New Zealand's largest producer of
medicinal cannabis so Helios is a
medicines company we exist to improve
the quality of life of those underserved
by conventional Pharmaceuticals we are
vertically integrated EU GMP end to end
as well as gacp a little bit about our
journey so hillius was first founded in
2018. uh we entered the New Zealand
Market back in 2021 and last year we
brought new zealand-grown New Zealand
made medicines to our kiwi patients for
us now the next step is bringing those
new zealand-grown New Zealand made
medicines to the rest of the world and
happy to be here and talking to people
about that today
from an investment story perspective we
are 100 New Zealand owned currently
we've had 60 million dollars invested
into Helios 60 million New Zealand
Dollars which is around 40 million euros
all through private investment so
individuals who are very passionate
about
the health journey of our patients in
New Zealand they have high expectations
but they also understand the long game
around making medicines and I think that
that's a really interesting point that I
can bring to the panel today
um I brought 20 IMS with me today
they're all sitting out in the table
there's two left so that means there's
18 people out there thinking about
investing in New Zealand we are at the
moment taking expressions of interest
for a capital raise later in the year
for 5 million New Zealand Dollars the
interesting thing if anyone really loves
New Zealand and wants to come and live
there is if you invest five million
dollars into Helios the New Zealand
government will give you a Visa and you
can come and live in New Zealand so
we'll see you all soon
so if you're looking to escape your
country you know exactly where to go
Luke just a visa on her passport too
the visa to start with but we'll see
what we can do come see Carmen
um well first of all it's an absolute
pleasure to be on stage with you a
gentleman lady Luke richner it's my name
I'm from Switzerland
um I'm the co-founder and CEO of a tech
company in this space called canavigia
where we looked at the global supply
chain we identified a couple of issues
that are lack of harmonization
standardization and all the the sexy
things in the back end that everybody
loves thinking about and putting in the
center and found kind of a common
denominator there understanding that not
everything the US does works on a global
scale and created a software from
scratch fast forward today we by
coincidence 18 countries as of next week
actually 19 they are not the same
countries yet maybe we'll talk about
that later
um I think our main
hate the term clade to fame but we have
a 10-year contract with the Swiss Health
Ministry for all the pilot projects so
which is the exemption status towards
the single convention in the U.N that
allows for a slow approach towards
legalization the same way Germany is
going with model projects and and
Holland is going that direction too and
um fun fact we're also doing around
right now so if anybody has any
questions afterwards no Brokers please
I'm very very happy to talk that's right
very cool well quick run to Applause for
our panelists up here thank you
great group
yeah we're um you know we're going to
start with talking about the exit part
of this uh there is one panelist here
that quote unquote exited but you know
people don't understand exiting is not
like okay hey thank you very much
there's a bunch of money and I can just
go hang out on a beach and just sip
Margaritas uh that gentleman is right
here to my left Phillip went Pub they
went public recently A lot of people
look at that as an exit can you quickly
talk about the uh kind of the process
there and does it feel like an exit
because I I'm gonna guess it doesn't and
talk about tomorrow
um yeah it doesn't feel like it actually
but it was never meant to be at the end
of the day um I just mentioned the first
company I worked for was acquired by
Aurora there was a proper exit and then
you had lots and lots of cooks in the
kitchen
uh this time around we wanted to stay in
the driver's seat so the the founders
and the management team we still own
more than 75 of the company
which is also a testament of what we did
before as we raised less than 5 million
in order to come to a market cap as of
today of roughly 130 uh so we believe in
being a bootstrap company we believe in
profitable growth and we thought being
at the Capital Market gives us ample
opportunity to raise money quickly if
it's needed so if there is an exciting
opportunity
and nothing against you guys but talking
to investors for three to six months
doing due diligence after the other
maybe the opportunity is gone given it's
a highly Dynamic it's a really
Innovative market and if a New Market
opens up I want to be in there and make
some money and we thought it's it's good
to have that additional opportunity to
also raise money by the capital markets
that's for sure
um yeah
and we also wanted to give retail
investors especially in Germany the
chance to invest into a company rather
early so we also tap in Internet retail
investor potential here
there's lots and lots of pent-up demand
we sold it so after our listing the
price went up and it stayed up there so
it's not like in the US and Canada so
there's definitely a high demand by
investors in Germany or maybe maybe all
over Europe to invest in an internal
company quite early on
we're the ones giving them also the
opportunity right and and that's a key
thing to bring up is that when you're
investing in these types of businesses
you're investing in a business I mean
coming from Canada people were investing
in dreams and stories and hopes and
we're raising hundreds of millions of
dollars with companies that didn't even
have a dollar all three of these people
up here have revenues have market share
and now talking about getting some money
it makes perfect sense I know Carmen you
were saying people ask you all the time
like what's your exit plan like what's
it like getting asked that all the time
and what do you tell them
so the answer to that is we don't have a
short-term Exit Plan
right now our investors that came on
from the beginning came on for the
journey and actually and really
challenging Capital markets last year we
made the decision to go out and
diversify our shareholder base and so we
added 18 new investors into our
portfolio last year knowing that we're
going to keep on this journey for a bit
longer and that really is because we are
a medicines company and to build value
and IP in a medicines company does take
time we're a medicines company that
grows things from plants that also takes
time so really to give us time to build
that value for our shareholders who have
backed us all the way you know that's
why we look at a longer term plan uh
before we start talking about exits yeah
that makes perfect sense and and Luke we
were talking backstage about kind of
some of these things what are some
thoughts you have on exit uh because I
really like to please share with the
audience
well in general I think the overall
landscape has has changed dramatically
and while the early days of this
industry was built on dreams and you
know storylines and I would say press
releases and events where people scratch
their backs and kind of you know built
uh let's call the US dream uh or
Canadian whatever you want to call it
um in general Capital markets have dried
up there is a different kind of uh
uh appetite from investors and our
strategy went from two years ago well
let's you know just Europe Africa and
Asia is where we're focused on that's
where my Network's at that is where you
know we we we're very strong uh uh and
then sell to whoever makes the race in
the US once they go Federal blah blah
blah blah blah now we pivot it to a
quick focus on on break even we've been
self-funded so far we did see a need for
quick Capital as you said before when
Germany went model projects suddenly we
were the only software provider in the
world that actually has done this before
our reporting goes to the Swiss Health
Ministry to the UN so so we know what
they want and and then overnight we're
like okay oh [ __ ] this is now and we
need cash and it's been three months of
the most beautiful times of my life
great Foods great drinks amazing people
but I could have definitely done a lot
of more value for my company in that
time so pivot from you know sell the
dream to make it happen and once you
have that trajectory to making it happen
there's a lot to be done and really be
picked if you have the luxury pick and
choose who you bring on board ideally
somebody that can throw in cash again
and again when it's needed and fast and
stay close with whoever you get behind
you and in general it's it's a constant
shift with a lot of different
factors that determine an exit strategy
yeah and it's very important you know we
started talking about it with exit and
we're going to get into some other stuff
but uh one piece of advice I remember
someone asked me what's the number one
piece of advice and it's so hard to say
number one but really who you take money
from and I think all three of these
people here are talking about how
important the right exit and if you're
not in the right exit situation make
sure you're taking money from the right
situation but enough about exiting you
know let's talk about entering uh we're
going to talk about the entering the
market kicks and shovels and we're going
to open up to some questions now when
you're talking about entering the market
uh one thing that we were talking about
is how do we build value in the business
through brand reputation and IP so
before we're exiting let's talk about
entering and Carmen maybe you want to
kind of start us off with that and we
can just talk about you know how do you
build value in this business so we can
one day exit yeah so I think one of the
key things around building value in the
business is going out there and doing it
um you know you were mentioning Luke
about all the press releases and all of
the big Fanfare about things and we've
all seen that we've all seen a lot of
public publicity and big Fanfare around
the Cannabis industry
um for us I think it's really key to be
going out and delivering so getting
product to Market we always chose for us
to deliver for kiwi Patients First
delivering our home Market first we're
very careful on what we promise we want
to make sure that what we promise we do
deliver and sometimes those things are
outside of our control and so we you
have some very honest conversations with
our
Partners you know our distribution
partners with our patients with our
shareholders and I think that you know
rather than trying to sell the story
building the relationship is really
important in how you build value in the
business you know the other part really
around brand and IP are in a medicines
Market that does take time the next
steps for us are moving into a clinical
evidence base and clinical trials the
great thing about a medicinal cannabis
scheme is you can put products into
market and get feedback and that's
different from other medicines where you
come up with an idea you develop a
product and 10 years later once you've
done clinical trials and invested all
the money you can put it into market so
we're actually using that opportunity to
build value by learning about the
markets and learning about the clinical
results of our products in Market which
we can then feed back into our
Innovation and IP pipeline
sense
I think in
no just real quick in terms of entering
a market is also how how do you
differentiate yourself
and also I mentioned it's it's not our
first rodeo with counter rash as we
firmly looked at the supply chain and
asked so where is actually our core
Advantage it can't be cultivation
because there's so many excellent
Growers out there it's bad about
manufacturing or knowing the regulatory
framework in Europe
um that's why we came up with the model
let's partner with the best Growers out
there get their product to Germany and
then we take care of the rest which is
actually quite challenging because the
framework differs from Germany to Poland
to the UK but that's what we've been
doing for the last six seven years we
didn't cultivate but we did the rest and
that's why we came up with the new model
which was very unique when we launched
it in 2021 and that's part of a success
story at the end of the day there needs
to be a differentiator
yeah so that's a good point and you're
investing in people and their experience
and their ability to differentiate
that's a really good point Luke that's
why you should never let somebody else
take a question when you actually had a
great answer for it but actually the
differentiating factor also goes for
investors
um what is your Niche what do you what's
your added value what can you bring to
the table for a company looking at
everybody right now no in the end of the
day it goes yes from from our side from
the industry and we have to find our
Niche we also have to then be agile
lovely word and kind of like pivot a
little bit I wanted to do Global Supply
Chain management and now I have a
software company
um
which works luckily for us but don't be
too agile kind of try to stick within a
bit of the boundaries of what you know
and I think the same goes for investors
uh it's not just here is a million or
ten or whatever by the way a million or
ten is a lot of money in Europe it's not
a lot of money in in the US but uh find
someone that can spend this sensefully
uh uh first and uh and really what is
your added value or can you bring them
can you bring them Network can you bring
them more Capital down the line can you
bring them advisory in which direction
and and this is something that I think
gets lost on both sides and then we're
here one inside yes we're taking the
side of of the industry here but but for
me what I'm looking for in an investor I
want him to tell me look I'll bring you
this this and this because just to get
cash yes of course cash is King and it's
very important but from the side from
our side is this USP as you call it goes
both ways and and this is what I'm I've
been missing in the last three months of
talking to people it's like what do you
need more than money and I'm like yeah
absolutely it's called smart money and
and stick talking with with you Luke you
know we had a conversation recently and
and I know Luke doesn't take it the
wrong way we talk about the not sexy
part of this business you know everyone
wants to talk about all this genetics
and growing and the flower and all this
fun stuff but actually the important
part about investing is making sure that
the not sexy stuff is really taken care
of and Luke sorry to talk about software
is maybe not the sexiest thing but it's
so critical to all this and and you're
you're the first person if you can touch
on certification and how software helps
with it is so critical like we were
talking about backstage that you can't
even get insurance if you're not
compliant and the software which helps
you with it so you might not realize how
important something not so popular is
and you might not even know about but
it's critical and don't invest in
businesses that don't understand that so
maybe Luke if you can kind of start us
off with uh maybe not the sexiest topic
from such a sexy gentleman like yourself
but please go ahead thank you thank you
sexy is always relative
um in the end of the day it lays in the
eyes of no I'm just kidding
um look yes exactly because everybody
loves those you know everybody wants to
be the Superstar but in the end of the
day it's not the superstar that makes
the most money in the end of the day
maybe in sports it is more or less but
then in industries that are developing
if you uh let's go back to to the
non-sexy part that I found which is
which is compliance and transparency and
standards and Regulatory framework
harmonization and all those
lovely subjects in the back end
um what what if I do a little detour
there with the insurance thing that you
threw in it's really nice to get 20
million to make a facility and grow
cannabis without anybody buying it at
some point you have to sell it at some
point you have to ship it somewhere at
some point you want it to be shipped
with insurance because otherwise uh you
know something happens and by chance
cannabis is proud to things happening
that are not planned
so you need to really you know factor in
everything and the amount of money that
or the amount of companies that I spoke
to on four continents in 18 countries
and so forth that have raised and I
almost said tons you know lots of money
um and then go like yeah but why should
I pay for compliance and like you do one
wrong batch and you lose your license
and everything is gone and you want to
really skimp out like that fraction of
your investment on that one important
part that if you do it right you go into
a bank with a de-risking kind of like
reporting and say look here give me you
know Finance bits and pieces of my of my
beard letter credits and you know in the
supply chain and so forth and uh or you
can just go and raise money again for
that but that's uh it's in everybody's
else's owns interest to be see what they
want to do and insurance in the end of
the day which industry do you have
shipments worth a couple of million
dollars depending on the volume and that
you ship from you said before Jamaica
Uganda uh let's throw Zimbabwe in there
and then go to insurance and say I want
to ship cannabis from these countries to
where we're at so it really helps if you
have a Swiss software with a Swiss
de-risking aspect that is accepted by
the Swiss Health Ministry for
recreational numbers adult use pilot
projects no but but really put put some
thought into it what can you bring into
your uh production flow whatever supply
chain and to really uh let it flow
afterwards and it's usually the unsexy
things
no very good point uh any other kind of
picks and shovels or auxiliary
businesses that you want to just touch
on that you think maybe is not as
popular or you know people are excited
about but are still so critical to your
businesses uh you know anything that you
can think of yeah so I can add an
example there around banking so we
changed our bank last year to one that
was going to better suit our needs as we
go into the next phase of growth
um to work with our new bank the Bank of
New Zealand they had to change all of
their policies to be able to work with
medicinal cannabis but they chose to do
it because it is a new industry that
they really support and they have high
growth and and we work with them as a
really strong partner so they support us
with our uh FX hedging for example but
they also support us with capital
raising and introducing us to some of
their High net worth individuals they
support us with their connections which
then help with things like insurance and
so I think you know there's a lot of
things to set behind from a partnership
model and when we talk Partnerships in
this industry we're often talking about
the physical Partnerships the movement
of goods and materials but the
Partnerships on the services side can
really
help move your business forward or make
your life really really hard as a CEO if
you have to spend a lot of time managing
that partnership it's something that
your customers don't see it's something
that your investors don't see but
actually you can't run a business
without some of those service providers
whether it is software banking Insurance
Logistics all of those pieces have to
work to be able to deliver and I'm
really happy you actually touched on it
because we are want to talk about the
elephant in the room that you know this
morning I heard a lot of kind of
frustration around a lot of different
stuff but the elephant of the room is
the challenges of actually getting the
money right now I mean it's we were
talking backstage about the importance
of being even Keel and profitable rather
than being at the mercy of investors
there's a lot of importance about being
Nimble and the ability to Pivot is so
critical in an Emerging Market while
we're pioneering this thing so uh the
question that we have is what are the
key Focus areas and challenging economic
conditions when capital is scarce what
you know it would be nice if we just
raised money like we did in the past but
what what can you all maybe suggest uh
until all the money's being thrown at
you how do you survive long enough until
you can make some money and potentially
exit you look eager to jump in on this
one yeah yeah we just I guess we're in
the in the end of the or tail end of the
first bus yeah the second one it's
called the bell curve then you have m a
uh which is all lovely lovely people
coming in telling you what you can't do
and and then they tell you you know
drive you into the ground and bring
three companies together with for
getting uh the company cultures and then
m a blah blah so from an industry
standpoint uh in those moments
Partnerships go a long way and maybe try
to understand how can I add value there
how can I what am I really good at I
don't have to do it all and this is a
big problem about the Cannabis industry
everybody wants to do it all and this
vertically integrated uh um you know
model
worked wonders in New Zealand and and
worked wonders in in Canada and the U.S
but it's not really how the world works
so so really find your Niche what is
your actual USP are you you know do you
do clones best do you contract
manufacturing contract Farm whatever I
find strong alliances and capital is not
going to be uh flowing uh in bulk over
the next couple of years or at least
that's what every Economist out there
will tell you every investor will tell
you no no next year next year
everything's gonna be fine but there's a
strategy behind that
um so so really Partnerships is is my
answer there and maybe you know got the
ego bit back here and find long-term
alliances and survival mode is at the
moment what I think is key for for many
industry players survival mode that's
that's definitely good advice uh Carmen
and Philip is basically that's our
operating model so we believe in
Partnerships
um so our cultivators they are Partners
they're not suppliers
um so we basically work together to get
the best product available into any
medical market so that goes a long way
though so if something doesn't go
according to plan it's still it's still
a partnership we can work it out at the
end of the day uh if you talk about
Supply agreements supplies it's it's
difficult to if you're if you're in a
challenging situation
um and also um again so back in my
Aurora days we had to do it all
ourselves uh so nobody is an expert
along the the full supply chain focus on
what you do best provide a value-add for
your partners and then I think you're in
a pretty good position
um and at the end of the day everybody
wants to grow but try to be profitable
as quickly as possible so because you're
not in at the mercy of investors and
then you're again in difficult situation
trying to raise money quick we never
wanted to be in that position so that's
why we're adamant on growing profitably
at the end of the day and uh and Carmen
it was awesome what you said about the
support from the bank and it was awesome
hearing your story of how the government
is supporting you I mean in Canada I can
tell you that the banks were very
difficult even were federally legal and
they give a hard time for cannabis
companies to come and uh when I was
executive director of our trade
Association we met with the banking
Association and they said the number one
concern from the banks is they don't
know who's legal and who's not and I
said oh really because here's a link to
a website that has a full list of who's
legal and they can send you a copy of
their license so you know we're not
buying that so but that's awesome that
you're getting the support of the bank
is there any other kind of thoughts of
what people can do when the banks are
maybe not so supportive uh not everyone
is as lucky to to have the support like
in New Zealand but any kind of thoughts
on that and then we'll take questions
from the audience yeah so back to the
support from that we get from the
government so a big shout out to New
Zealand trade and Enterprise shout out
to New Zealand are they back there Shout
Out New Zealand man over there where to
support your industry can we come and
raise money
so New Zealand trading Enterprise do
have an investment arm and Helios has
been certified under the active investor
program which is where I say you can get
a Visa if you come and invest in Helios
or in the other companies in in New
Zealand but I think our New Zealand Eco
structure around supporting the industry
we get a lot of support from the
government nzte is one of those Callahan
Innovation also support a lot of our
research and development Frameworks and
Helios has just been named in the top
100 high growth companies for Callahan
Innovation so that's supporting things
for us like our breeding and genetics
program it supports some of our
purification new technologies that are
coming online it also supports our
talent so we have three PhD students who
are developing products who are funded
mainly funded by the the government in
New Zealand and that means that it's
bringing our next wave of products but
at the same time as bringing our next
wave of talent into the organization so
I do have to give a big shout out to the
ecosystem that we we live in Back to the
point around
you know what do you do in these really
challenging times then whether it's
support from Partners like government or
from your existing shareholders that's
really important but I would absolutely
agree get to break even as fast as you
can focus on what gets you there so that
you're self-funding and you can invest
then in the sexy and Fun Stuff yourself
and then you also get the rewards as you
get to being investing in that sexy and
fun stuff as well
I think it's a very very good point I'm
happy here in New Zealand is that
forward thinking actually Germany is
also I know two people in the room here
who got 20 percent uh grants for their
facilities uh r d is usually something
that is always also very much supported
you can get tax breaks but you've got to
go there and talk to them they don't
come to you and just throw it in your
face so uh and there are a lot of
approach programs Switzerland is where
I'm from there's nice programs Europe
has Horizon 2020 so there's there's a
lot of different kind of approaches for
let's call it alternative financing
um and it's the government's job that
when they have a business that is
functioning and giving jobs to make sure
that it kind of doesn't not go bust so
don't underestimate how much you can do
in that last stretch before you get
completely desperate but again you have
to do it in proactively find someone
that supports you either internally or
externally for them yeah and and really
important point is uh you know sometimes
you need the experts like Consulting is
to help you apply for these grants like
it's you know no they're not going to
knock on your door and say hey can we
give you some money sometimes you have
to call them but you have to know what
to say there's people who that's their
job is to know how to push those buttons
to get those type of Grants and they
work with all other Industries and you
know maybe they're not calling on you as
a cannabis company so you might have to
seek them out and I like something that
Carmen also said we here we're talking
more about investment and money but it's
also investing in people and education
and all these other Investments That
might not turn into money the way that
oh we're going to build a million square
foot facility it's going to cost 50
million dollars we're going to invest in
it but you know what if you take a
fraction of that invest in people invest
in research invest in things that you
know you're planting the seeds now for
an industry down the road you can really
reap those rewards so that's a really
good point and again shout out to New
Zealand for for realizing that and hope
more governments kind of realize uh that
these things take time and they're going
to reap the benefits if they actually do
some Investments now so excellent and uh
yeah opening up to questions uh from the
audience all right let's hear it from
the panel one more time
questions anyone ah okay why do you
always wait until I'm on this side of
the room don't be shy do it on purpose
you prepare one over there after please
they want to keep you exercised
often when private investors are
considering an entry into new into new
business or a growing business
the first question that they ask
themselves at entry is how we're going
to exit right so in your experience uh
when you speak to private investors uh
what type of exit options are they
discussing and what type of exit options
are you seeing for yourselves and for
them is it trade sales trade sales to
home is it IPOs and then you know how do
you think in terms of you know how big
you need to grow
to be IPO ready within sort of some
foreseeable future timeline
it is uh rather than a question that
we get asked by our investors it's a
question we ask our potential investors
what their goals are around the
investment so that we start off on that
same page and
um that really helps us to understand
what they're looking for in terms of
value in the business and those very
early conversations rather than getting
all the way down you know the courting
process and then realizing that you have
different expectations around timing and
exits for us at Helios we've gone
through probably all of the different
options we haven't landed on which one
is the right one for us because I think
it'll depend on the conditions at the
time as to whether it could be a a trade
sale or an IPO
so it really will depend on the value
that we build in the business over the
next three to five years and also what
the international market looks like New
Zealand is quite a small place so we
have five million people we have three
publicly listed cannabis companies in
New Zealand
um I think two of the three are here
you'll get to meet them over the next
few days and we are privately owned so
we see both those business models
playing out in the New Zealand market
and we'll see how that progresses and
what we can learn from that as we go
okay excellent point
another question for Carmen great
conversation so far by the way
um so Carmen I had the pleasure of
getting to connect with you before the
conference and one of the things that I
was really impressed with was your true
patient-centric approach and you told me
that the market is growing really
quickly in New Zealand because stigma is
dissolving more quickly than you
expected it to and I was wondering if
you could talk a little bit about why
you think stigma is dissolving and
perception is changing and what you and
your other companies have done to help
support that work
yeah absolutely so my favorite thing
about being CEO of a medicinal cannabis
company is the emails I get back from
patients so I've worked in medicines
most of my life but I've never actually
had those emails from patients to tell
me good news stories normally you just
hear from patients when something has
gone wrong and I think that's a really
powerful thing that when patients are
able to access medicinal cannabis and
get life-changing experiences they
actually go and seek out they seek out
my email to tell me that and to say
thank you but they also tell their
friends whether it's over coffee or over
the back garden fence so a lot of our
demand in New Zealand is patient driven
in New Zealand any doctor can prescribe
medicinal cannabis for any condition and
that's for CBD and for THC and our
doctors are learning about medicinal
cannabis in some cases they're referring
people to specialist clinics which are
also growing but I think that the key
thing is the openness to learn and
myself plus the other medicinal cannabis
companies that are here from New Zealand
we've all just come from a GP conference
there's two each year and we all have a
presence there
this year there was a two-hour plenary
session at that GP conference around
education around medicinal cannabis so
those environments and being there and
working with doctors learning from
doctors what other tools they want in
their toolkit what other dosage forms
they want to be able to deliver for
their patients is a very very big part
of our ethos and being able to deliver
for our patients just in terms of how
quickly things are growing in 2022 there
was 60 000 patients in New Zealand that
doubled from the previous year where we
had thirty thousand and we thought it
was going to double again this year in
2023 but it's growing way faster than we
thought and so I think that that's a
really exciting thing
for companies that are setting up in New
Zealand
if I go back two years I thought the
only way that Helios or other medicinal
cannabis companies in New Zealand could
survive was all about exports our New
Zealand Market has grown quickly and
that's really supporting us to be able
to get to the point where we can export
and being able to deliver in our local
market is really helping the
relationships we have with our export
and distribution partners because they
know that we're able to consistently
deliver so there's lots of great things
around this story for our patients that
we're delivering for but also for our
shareholders and it sounds like you
almost have as many patients as Canada
you're going to Awards and actually very
important point and I've mentioned this
to some of the people in the room have a
domestic Market first I'm so tired of
all these industries that oh we're going
to grow but only for you guys we don't
want it for our people I think it's so
important to have cannabis for your
people and then worry about export and
not make the mistake of like Denmark or
others but yeah you have another thing
if you're lucky and you do have a
domestic market so talking about our
partners in Uganda for example there is
no local and domestic Market still they
grow very good cannabis and you should
partner with us you can bring it into
Europe and start building your business
and waiting for the domestic Market to
actually open up so they're excellent
grows out there but they don't have a
domestic market then they need to
venture out and go International but
then they need to be wise about whom to
partner with in order to do it cost
efficient and get in the right types of
Market where you can actually make some
money so maybe they should Lobby their
government and say Hey you know we're
doing this in Germany look at all these
customers in Germany having an awesome
experience with our cannabis maybe we
should have some our own people uh have
a good experience as well yeah makes
sense yeah very cool fantastic our time
that's it thank you everyone
thank you