I'm gonna let these three kind people
introduce themselves so I'll start with
Todd
sure hey I'm Todd Bourne
um I am with MacArthur capital and now
currently the CEO at alpen group so my
background comes from
30 plus years into private Equity uh
prior to entering the Cannabis space and
private equity and Venture Capital my
firms managed about four billion dollars
in assets and then about 10 years ago we
made a shift into U.S cannabis
we've deployed between five funds that
I'm involved with about 220 million US
Dollars those have been about let's call
it 30 some odd companies invested over
five funds we raised capital from a
hundred thousand a person to a million a
person so it was a grind you know 220
million in the U.S space was a lot of
work to gather those assets I will say
we're very well known for a transaction
that we had where MacArthur put about
three and a half million dollars into
two companies that we merged into form
Factory we sold and had an exit with
that company in less than 12 months for
160 million dollars
subsequently our investor is quite happy
with those returns um but in the end we
have pushed all our chips in now and are
focusing on Europe the growth of Europe
the opportunities globally helping group
we consider ourselves an MCO a
multi-country operator versus MSO LP Etc
so that's my background
Joel hey Joel redelman so I've worked in
a
was the founding partner of Redfield
group so we're in alternative investment
fund and always looked at Emerging
Markets
Tech space cannabis space anything which
was a little bit on the Edge at the time
and now really focused on promethium
biopharma which is our cannabis play and
we've really focused on drug development
efficacy and how we can deliver a better
product and better access to patients
hi everyone Gerald decorser I'm the
founder a New Frontier data leading data
analytics and collecting information
collection of firm in the United States
covering the Cannabis industry worldwide
a founding member of sea trust currently
introducing the first investment credit
rating and scoring and monitoring
solution specific assessing exposure and
overall risk in the Cannabis industry I
also sit on the board around carbon
which is a company out of India that is
doing research looking to understand the
applications of
carbonization of hemp for industrial
application
that's kind of why I asked the question
I asked earlier and my background is
really in data collection analytics and
fintech which I now apply to canvas
well thank you all
I think I'm gonna start with
Capital has always been feast or famine
in this industry and
for so how can operators
be more proactive in trying to seek
capital and provide investors with the
knowledge that they know
so they can make investments into these
companies
I'll kick off with that I wish we at
least had a famine
in capital right now this is probably
one of the most difficult environments
I've seen to raise Capital
um for this industry uh and and thus for
us that's why we've deployed a lot of
our own personal Capital into what the
project we're doing right now
what I'm seeing though is is also let's
call it just from the fund level and the
investor base level the U.S let's just
call it all North American investors
have run for the hills it's just been a
complete disaster what's happened in the
U.S and I'm talking about not bad
companies in a bad environment I'm
talking about Good operators with a lot
of demand and and tons of sales uh
completely implode because of a lack of
banking proper Federal guidance
regulation Etc
so when it comes to Capital now let me
just be the investor versus an operator
for a second as someone that's probably
vetted and on due diligence on 500
companies maybe more than that across
all of the sectors that that cannabis
has to offer I what I see right now
Happening Here in Europe is the actual
right way to build an industry where
Capital markets can go into it versus
let's call it a gold rush mentality the
US and and Canada was a complete Gold
Rush mentality no realization of real
valuations all of that due diligence I
mean I remember the first deal I ever
looked at let's call it from the capital
space I got a shoebox full of receipts
and I thought I hit the the gold mine
for due diligence I mean now we really
are putting together a structure in a
Marketplace that can be Global in a
sense X U.S and X Canada of how does
really the market start to develop here
so capital is brutal out there but truly
the opportunity
that we see for massive multiple X
really is here now versus what happened
in the U.S and North America you would
look at at companies and and and and
valuations where you'd walk in the door
and see a 250 million dollar valuation
you know pre-revenue you know that's all
gone so we're you know I think we the
opportunity that we have in this
difficult Market is we're the real
winners will happen that's my opinion
but it's Capital really being brutal or
is it just asking the questions which it
should have asked in the first place why
why are you raising money again and
again and again without delivering on
what you said you'd deliver the first
time why why are you turning over a
billion dollars but you're not
profitable why what if if you can't run
a business sustainably then of course
capital is going to run away to an
industry where businesses can be run
sustainably and Europe has an
opportunity now to learn from the
mistakes from America and for people to
build businesses which are sustainable
like as an investor when you look at
things don't you say well
what's this money going to get you to is
this and when they said when a Founder
when you talk to a founder and all they
say is to the next Capital raise well
that's just not good enough right
in business business owners need to
understand that they need sustainable
businesses and that's what will keep the
money flowing and that's what will keep
things consistent like that and money
will come back to cannabis but cannabis
operators need to prove that they can
run businesses
the Gold Rush the green Rush is over
just just started like a proper business
like the industry is maturing
Germany is tightened up I can you know I
expect that things will be transparent
and sophisticated and reported and
operated in a proper business manner I
think that's pretty much it
I think a spot on I mean if you really
if you really think about it that whole
Gold Rush mentality green Rush mentality
what we might not be sitting here today
had that not happened in reality because
really then it was all in a sense
illicit market and so forth but the
problems that's continuing to go on is
really the economies that are built in
place right now continue to fester for
the illicit Market continue to fill the
coffers of really the cartels really
versus the businesses and Joel what have
you said I think is spot on when you
operate businesses as a business forget
cannabis just as a business as a
business as a private Equity investor
for 30 plus years that's exactly what
you have to do and so in reality all of
that gold rush and mentality and green
Rush that happened we probably wouldn't
be here we'd probably just still be in
the illicit markets so in a sense we can
think that but all the dumping of that
capital and I mean just irresponsible
dumping of capital you have to go into
opportunities now in an asset like
mentality so when we look at
opportunities you know we look at those
opportunities are are they sustainable
what's the path to profitability what's
the path to let's call it even Revenue
to profitability wouldn't you agree and
and why isn't it profitable now
what they said
so yeah you were um sort of going back
to regulation and
that how can these companies
benefit from Smart regulation and that
lead to investors being able to look at
the industry that way I know you're
working on sort of what your project is
working on with sea trust but
so yes as part of
boyfriend to do I don't
really trying to introduce and improve
on standards uh standards by which we
assess risk and investment opportunity
in sort of a more transparent
quantifiable manner in a more
sophisticated business-like matter but
if we take that up you know a level
above Beyond just the due diligence and
financial assessment of risk
um how can regulations
help I mean how much time do we have
the issue I think is is not how much can
they help the issue is how do we even
get close to have an environment given
that the industry is a global industry
whereby those regulations really do help
to continue to Foster good business
growth and international business growth
in the Cannabis industry I'm not really
sure I have an answer to that
I have a lot of hopes and dreams though
yeah I think when you when you look at
it holistically we you can really get
lost in the argument between adult use
recreational medicinal and everything
else whereas the question we really need
to be asking is do the patience or the
users that need the product have access
to it and ultimately the within the
self-medicating market or the
recreational Market whatever you'd like
to call them they're they're really
quasi-medical users they are medical
users and they're not
they whether they're not familiar with
with the term that they're a medical
user and they call themselves a
recreational user
it's it's really by the way but the the
increasing medicalization uh within
within markets is a path to getting
access to the people that need it
without running into the pitfalls of the
current uh regulatory environment with
um U.N laws and everything else
so a major difference and and and I will
say you know the fact of coming let's
call it from the U.S markets are now
being completely all in our fund and it
makes no more Investments really into
the U.S Marketplace unless it's more of
a global type of investment where it
where so we see what's happening here
the real reality is optimistically the
dollars and cents are enormous
that's not the issue the issue that the
companies are having and and and and I
always go back to it's very easy to
point the fingers and say oh well bad
operators spending too much money you
know we're unrealistic no not
necessarily way ahead first move or
David you mentioned that or first mover
is not where you wanted to be especially
in the markets and now if you're looking
at What's Happening Here in let's call
it Europe but I really look at it more
globally you know you know that's great
Germany Switzerland you know whatever
this is a global Marketplace X us
because the U.S market is is really a
disaster and you can't even ship across
the state line let alone a country line
so I mean the real reality is now you
know you look at the tremendous
Financial opportunity is here how do you
build it and what I think is going right
here
is is really the slowing down versus
racing in and all of a sudden you know
you have a Marketplace that's there that
isn't ready for it and then it gets over
built and then things get pulled back
and then the taxation kicks in and so
forth this is a slow methodical approach
that's happening here in Europe and I'm
very very bullish on it so you know you
got to go in very light and and slow so
to say but if you do that the market
will build itself the you know market
efficiency is is 101 when it comes to us
in the financial world it's an efficient
Marketplace but with that efficient
Marketplace we know that the clients are
there we know that the use is there
whether it be a medical one-day
recreational it's one day recreational
so I'm tremendously bullish on it but
you're going to see a lot of Battle
Scars From companies that are just not
ready and prepared for the marketplace
so cannabis borders have always been
pretty um sticky as far as
what people expect and what what do you
think we can do to improve that in the
Cannabis industry
Michael means
I think it goes back to my previous
point about the medicalization of the of
the Cannabis market and if you can
create a framework whereby the medical
Market can expand though that the the
cross-border regulations there are then
facilitated through
pharmaceutical agreements rather than
through narcotics agreements and that's
a
that's that's a path that's easier at
the moment
when you say borders are sticky
can you elaborate on that because I'm
thinking of how we use that term in the
U.S
yeah I mean
obviously I mean I think it's
the the fleet free flow of imp of goods
right doesn't occur in the U.S for that
I mean other than the illicit market
right so you're talking about the legal
market right yeah
I think Europe has a great opportunity
to actually uh have uh let's call it
interstate trade that the United States
hasn't been able to do or take advantage
of because the fragmented regulatory
environment
um however I don't know that Europe as a
whole has figured out what exactly it's
all supposed to look like as a region in
terms of their overall role and their
expertise and how do they want to
position in the the market in terms of
how are they going to be that strength
in that Niche which is going to be
needed and then within that region how
is each nation that is looking to
embrace and sort of move forward with
illegal cannabis industry also going to
position and bring their own expertise
talent and Niche
so
a bit more to do and as my colleague
said it's a good thing that it's been
taken slow and and deliberate and
thoughtful process is taking place
because there's no there's no point in
rushing and and the US and North America
has taught us a lot of what not to do
but not necessarily what to do we're
still trying to figure that out so to go
to your border scenario and quite I
didn't quite understand the question so
that's why I passed them I got it I
don't usually pass on questions often
um but no I I think that the issue is
the U.S market you just have to remember
it's federally illegal still what
happens state by state is is kind of
almost by the way and accidental
another reason why we believe in the MCO
approach multi-country operating type
approaches you really have a scenario
Without Borders here I mean you really
don't I mean we don't know how that's
ultimately going to lay out because the
laws are being written and if I think a
lot of us smart folks in the room can
help contribute to to how those laws are
written we shouldn't have let's call it
a border scenario you know in in
addition to that really banking is not
an issue here the big banks are not
going to touch it right now because they
still do business with U.S banks that
might frown on on their ability to bank
cannabis but if you have a free banking
scenario you have a free Capital
scenario and you have the ability to
move across borders those laws will be
ultimately laid out we don't have the
stigma and the issue of stigma what's
happening in the U.S so in reality it's
an open canvas now but going back to
what Giada says is it's being moved out
very slowly and that's not necessary
really a bad thing we can all be
impatient for for let's call it for
returns and on our investment as an
investor this is all about Returns on
our investment I mean if if you're an
investor out there you know that if
you're someone raising Capital you know
you better know that so
I mean isn't that what the EU was for in
the first place
right
um
so uh
so so going back to that so what do you
think the most important uh factor in
the future is for the sector globally
if that's the if that's the case
Giada you want to go sure
I thought we were supposed to rehearse
these questions ahead of time
excellent question I mean I think that's
a billion dollar question
um
what is the biggest thing that we can do
today on a global scale to help the
industry well shizen
I think the first thing is to realize
that it is a global market and it is a
global opportunity
and to start from that framework so
whether you are operating locally or
you're an MSO operating Interstate or
you're in Europe and you're beginning to
think about how you're going to plant
your flag in Germany but then at the
same time work in Switzerland
you really need to think like that you
need to to realize that it's not just a
matter of where you are locally but the
opportunity and the challenges are going
to come from all over the place more
interestingly to me specifically and
actually recently wrote a little
something that may be worth a little
something about it is that we are
beginning to see the emergence of
regional expertise across the global
industry regions really are beginning to
sort of develop their own personality
and profile as it pertains to what their
role is in the whole ecosystem of
cannabis
and so maybe would be valuable for all
of us in the industry to again think of
our own talent and expertise and what
can bring to bear while being very
cognizant of what's happening around us
are a big macro level on a global level
my potential two cents
yeah and I mean it's important to create
that we create an environment where the
the demand can be can be satisfied if we
we all know people want cannabis the
people are out there that want it but if
we don't have an environment where it
can be delivered from the grower or the
producer all the way down to the down to
the patient and the person that wants it
well then we can make as much cannabis
as we want it's just going to sit and
get old in our warehouses and
putting a system in place where we can
the Cannabis can be delivered to the
people that need it and drive that
demand is also is what's going to drive
the sustainability of our businesses
I agree with both of those those
comments I I think what I would add to
that is this
we have always let's call it at the
MacArthur level at my at my private
Equity Firm took the approach of to be
very collaborative and to not think that
we could either run any one deal by
ourselves take the lead and just do it
all by ourselves and then as we would
then do our due diligence on firms to
make investments in who would be the
most collaborative very difficult to get
in the U.S as you have that border issue
but to me personally what what
can now tee up the best opportunity for
the largest growth is for this industry
here to be a global industry to be very
collaborative because you know one level
of expertise may be coming out of
Portugal another might be coming out of
Switzerland another might be coming out
of Germany another might be coming out
of Columbia South Africa on and on how
did how does this industry now
collaborate because it is one big huge
industry the difference is it's not just
a pure Pharma industry so even let's
call it medical can still have that
approach of how does that ultimately
become a recreational or an adult use
product Etc I think the collaboration
between countries companies leaders
within the industry will be how this
really can be an enormous industry and
it has to be a profitable I I would love
to say this is philanthropy it's it's
not I mean there's philanthropy that can
come from successful companies where
they can then make a contribution to
making sure that it's you know let's
call it is available to everyone is
available to people that need Etc but if
this is not a successful viable industry
there is nothing to distribute so at the
end of the day that collaboration that
unified philosophy is what ultimately
makes this a successful successful
industry
well I think that's all I have on the
question side should we turn it over to
the audience and see sure
Rocky had his hand up
Rocky petrulo one world Legends Colombia
my question is the title appears
um cannabis sector to grow unbounded and
I think Todd just did a good job about
talking about collaboration and
um you know
working together which means to me both
ways earlier today we had a panel that
was saying it is what it is the
government's only going to allow Germany
to grow in Germany well if we're going
to collaborate and we're going to go
both ways if Germany's going to serve
France or Sweden or or there's you know
been a pathogen that's killed most of
the product in Italy is Germany going to
work with Italy or is Germany going to
only grow for Germany and not
collaborate and market and sell to other
countries so I think like you said it's
a big Global Market which includes you
know importation from Colombia as we had
a couple of people speak this morning
and I like your approach Todd so what do
you think do you think that to grow
unbounded we need to open these borders
you know versus America which we will
get there but the states had to move
forward because the federal government
was going to you know drag their tail
but now that there's 37 states in
America the next step is the federal
laws are going to have to change and
then we'll have interstate commerce
yeah I think you're exactly right that
guy knew what he was talking about
I think you're spot on it so it's it's a
global environment it's it's a and and
yes if anyone's saying is it's all just
going to be your way and not the other
way that will be the failure that
happens all over again so I think I
think what the guys were saying this
morning wasn't that
we shouldn't collaborate and we should
work within our countries it was saying
this is what the government's offering
us now let's take what we can get now
and keep pushing for what we want rather
than saying it's not enough and getting
nothing and those incremental steps help
the market grow and develop and build in
every place to a point where governments
are willing to give more and they'll
they see that the negative effects of
the changes in the regulations haven't
brought but brought lots of car crashes
because people are driving stoned or
something else once they see that the
regulations are working then they'll be
open to more regulations and we're
better off taking what we're offered
than saying it's not enough the Joel I
agree with you I mean if you if you
think about that all you can do is work
within the framework that you're allowed
to do it no one on stage is going to say
we're going to be able to change really
that environment so I agree that you
have to work within the framework we you
have that being said it's one of the
reasons and Daniel mentioned it earlier
this morning as well was that's why we
are in Switzerland you know I mean we we
we're going to be collaborative with
Colombia and markets like that using
what we have in place if you isolate
yourself you're only going to have an
isolated Marketplace I mean it is what
it is yeah and we should we shouldn't
stop lobbying just because we've got a
small step we should we should all keep
pushing right absolutely exactly
check check oh okay over here
a good afternoon thank you thank you
Derek Bill and metec farmer from
Australia on the question what can we do
for the global industry to move forward
one of the challenges I believe existed
in pretty much every single country is
driving under the influence of DHC at
this moment in time we don't have a
quantitative test
is that kind of test not relevant at
that moment to start to work as an
industry finding a quantitative test
rather than a quality test so that
people are not afraid of using the
product and with the risk of losing jail
or losing their license driving license
it is
first of all studies show that Stoners
are better drivers than regular people
uh the old joke slower correct well the
old joke is that a drunk person will
drive right through the stop sign but
the stoner will wait for the stop sign
to turn green
yeah I think these strikes are deep
Accord there which relates to the
misdesign of cities ever since the
invention of the automobile here here
Everything is Everything
yeah uh what can we do about that I mean
Washington state has tried to have a
default
driving Under the Influence law so if
you have five nanograms in your
bloodstream they can try to charge you
with driving Under the Influence but I
mean I have five nanograms in my
bloodstream just when I wake up in the
morning so I mean is there yeah another
thing where it's like an education thing
where we have to just educate people
that well it well it is but say like
Australia is a terrible example because
it was only a month or two ago there was
a fellow that was pulled over and he was
stoned and they
stole him not to drive and he got back
in the car and then Tebow and someone
and killed five people and so it's it's
not just given THC a bad name in that
situation but it's really changed the
public discourse was he just on THC or
was he on other things as well
I believe he was on a number of other
things yeah so but but that that's not
what's published in the headline THC is
what's published in the headline and the
if people aren't responsible then
they'll just ban everything
uh you all were highlighting how
difficult the regulatory environment is
in the United States and Todd I think
you said for that reason that you don't
invest any capital in in the U.S not
anymore not anymore and my question is
do you see that changing in the near
future and what I mean is I'm from
California for instance which you know
arguably has the most difficult
regulatory environment of any place in
the United States and by virtue of that
there are a lot of those first movers as
you were discussing are now distressed
and so there's a theory that you know
second movers might come in and
consolidate that market as the
regulatory environment gets more
favorable and they'll want people like
you right to to be investing capital and
just gave away my secret you you're spot
on I mean really the distressed assets
that are coming in the U.S and the
consolidation of of the industry and the
players you're spot on and and when I
say we're not investing in the U.S it's
because I think there's still a lot more
of
of blood in the streets before it's time
to go in there but again there are great
operators there so I mean California has
some of the best operators in the globe
I'd hate to pay those taxes and the
state taxes and all the pre and in the
280e and all that's that's going to
change the Opera there's going to be
that Tipping Point of when that
opportunity is is there distressed to
them boom back so no I think you're spot
on I agree with you if I may add to that
it's true that the regulatory
environment
in Jewish shift for the better in the
regulatory environment would absolutely
support
um struggling businesses but I think
that it's all at the end of the day it's
all about increasing transparency and
visibility into the industry and the
operator and the businesses it really
comes down to that so whether it is
catalyzed by regulation or just better
operation by the businesses
um I mean we're in the business of
distressed assets we know we we realize
that there are a lot of businesses out
there that are struggling and what we do
is we come in and we do what a doctor
does we give them a bill of health we
tell them here's your pain points oh and
these are your symptoms but this is the
disease and this is what you need to do
to get better and then if you get better
your medicine is going to be more
capital and then you're gonna survive I
mean so I think we I'm not saying the
regulation is not critical I mean I'm
all about you know let's have Federal
Regulation and federal standard around
everything packaging dosing like a
transparency visibility but I think we
also need to take ownership and
responsibility and accountability to how
we've been operating businesses in the
Cannabis industry as well and I think
it's time to raise the bar
fantastic what do they say the early
bird gets the worm the second mouse gets
the cheese
profound
my question is is primarily to the money
allocates can you hear me yeah you got
me it's to the money allocators on the
stage
um what psychology this is probably a
you know quite a pipe dream for Europe
at the moment but if if Europe really
does this right and takes off in the
right direction what's the right
psychology for operators with money
allocators saying hey we want to Pile in
now because you know because you guys
have seen that in the past what what do
you want to see from operators saying
hey no that's too big we won't take your
money because that's a very difficult
one as a CEO of a company say hey I
don't want your money I'm good where I'm
at so just maybe some perspectives on
that please yeah I'll hit that super
quick because I I think that's that's
the Tipping Point and the great question
I think all the people that kind of came
in and with a rush to Too Much Capital
too quick overbuilt the marketplace
before there was even a Marketplace so
as looking and again I mean I'm putting
my own money my partners were putting
our own money into this company but at
the end of the day very asset light not
over allocating to Psy ways to
Marketplace
Etc knowing who the client is today and
let's call it who it's going to be a
year and maybe two years from now 10
years from now it's going to look
completely different also phasing your
way in I've seen so many you know okay
all we need to do is raise 20 million
dollars and yeah okay good luck you know
what are the phases that you can go in
do I need a million here 3 million here
in five and Joel not to the and I'm
going back and raising all the time but
phasing in to that stage of
profitability okay we've got this we're
now moving with it now phase two will
kick in or phrase three will kick in
yeah and how many times have you seen a
company say oh we need five million
dollars to build out a facility so well
have you not thought about using a
contract manufacturer have you not
thought of someone else's facility that
already exists like why are we building
another facility or we need a million
dollars to buy this machine it's like
well did you look did you look in the
auctions to see if there's anyone any if
there's a liquidator selling one did you
look for a second hand one did you look
at least about leasing it did you look
of
there's all there's all these things and
if you if you focus on like like Todd
said asset light expense light keeping
your cost low then in lean times the
business survives if if you're
overloaded with costs then when when
lean times come that's where that's when
the dentist wedding just gets out of
control
if I may add a very macro level sort of
comment
we've we've spent the past six months
interviewing investors lenders and
creditors to understand while I'm not a
greater investor or lender but we did
spend some time talking to them because
we wanted to understand what is it that
you know that that turns you off when
you look at you know an investment or
you know what's making you know what's
about performing loan for you what was
that pain Point what what's the what is
it what is where does it stem from and
actually what we found out was that it
was a lot of
disappointment let's call it with
governance and management
a lot of it like it all no matter what
the symptom was that it came back up to
bad management
and I know that sounds sort of like a
duh but there you have it that's what we
literally did a survey and that that was
the outcome of it
you're a great one I like to see you
your Founders like putting lots of
photos of people in decks so the
investor think so they think the
investor sees it oh it's we're a big
business where we're going to grow
bigger we're doing everything else but
all investors look at that and they say
there's too much cost in this
they you have to be realistic about who
you are realistic about where you're
going realistic about forecasts and
realistic about how you're actually
going to make money and it's not by
getting a good valuation next round and
selling some shares down
what about when you investors get
overheated
sell it
[Laughter]
hi I think one of the biggest mistakes
we've made as an industry is and I keep
reminding people that this is not just
an agricultural industry you know that
is obviously the the source of where it
begins but you have to build a full
supply chain and I think there was a lot
of obviously over capitalization in big
farms because it was just completely
driven by metrics which in the beginning
looked fantastic have you seen we
obviously know that's that's changed
have you seen a shift
in where money is being spent to develop
the supply chain has there been a shift
in the culture of that uh that
deployment of capital
so that's funny because it's almost
instinctive and intuitive that the
capital comes in and goes in to the
front end always first because without
that there's really no product however
you're right the back end the last yard
of the field let's call it the
distribution cycle Etc you know that's
usually where the lease Capital goes
into and it's the most important part of
the chain and they're real I have not
seen that change really here you know
everyone's banking on the fact that it
really will be a Pharma distribution
model it'll go into the pharmacies it
it's a medical product so that
distribution is in place I'm not
necessarily convinced that that's the
scenario but but I agree that's what
what happens is that the capital seems
to come in on the front end and it's
very very light on the back end
I think we've seen some
further investment in technology and
whether it's through Delivery Systems or
engineered products and things like that
because it's a
there's a culture thing for you within
the recreational Market than people like
people within that market like really do
like flour but beyond that in a medical
Market
doctors and patients are looking for
repeatability for
consistency for dose dosage limits
things like that and the
techno technologies that kind of improve
the API improve the onset improve the
pharmacokinetics we're seeing investment
in that and we're seeing new products
come to the market which you could
describe as
third generation fourth generation fifth
generation and the these are products
which have the ability to shape the
medical Market of the future
I full hardly second that not only that
we've seen some innovation of technology
that has been tested in the Cannabis
industry and has been applied outside of
the Cannabis industry due to this
driving interest is exactly what you
said to increase sort of repeatability
to have more transparency scalability so
yes I would say I would totally agree
with that
like we've we've developed a cannabis
tablet that we're running a clinical
trial within Australia at the moment
which is a sublingual comes in a bottle
doctor says two tablets under the tongue
and it's taking taking the guesswork out
of oils taking the measuring out taking
the
uh the unpredictability of your spoon
out of it and it's it's improved the
onset improve the pharmacokinetics and
we're getting great feedback from
patients and is that is that going to be
the future of cannabis
you tell me
does it work
yeah hi so um
okay so I mean I I'm I heard you that
you know that it's been of course and I
think we all agree that you know over
over
overspending let's say in the Cannabis
in the US has been uh has been certainly
an issue also in Canada a lot of value
has been burned however the let's say if
we analyze maybe the last 20 30 years
every new industry
uh software I.T now artificial
intelligence electrical battery whatever
so the reality is that the US is
generating
the leading companies and in Europe is
uh is very good at you know
protecting consumers you know and from a
regulatory point of view but in the end
the U.S is always kind of dominating the
new Industries thanks to these huge flow
of capitals and and propension to
Innovation and disruptive innovation so
do you see any reasons for which the
Cannabis sector in Europe
should be or at Global level should be a
different industry as compared to all
the other
new Industries so why why do you expect
the the sector not to be dominated by
U.S companies in the next 10 years
if you've ever smoked Amnesia Haze
runner in Spain you know why the United
States won't dominate the entire
industry no sorry I think the farmer in
the US is missed the opportunity of
cannabis and farmer in Europe has an
opportunity to really generate some good
quality Research into
what works and what doesn't whereas in
America they've just completely
forgotten about it they've glossed over
it because
you can just go to the shop and buy what
you want or move to another state and
buy what you want if you wanted and it's
it it's been left in the hands of the
consumer and farmer just doesn't care
over there and Europe has an opportunity
to really Excel there and I don't know
that the us is going to catch up
got him I'm going back to the idea that
we're beginning to see sort of regional
profiles and expertise in the Cannabis
industry arguably in other Industries as
well but maybe more prominently in the
Cannabis industry because it's like this
controlled environment that we can all
sort of really like look at as it's
happening very quickly
I would say Europe has many advantages I
mean Beyond you know the research in
farming research being the operative
word there when you look at Health and
Beauty and food and beverage look at
where European stands in terms of
consumer packaged Goods I mean some of
the largest conglomerates come out of
here you look at L'Oreal and all these
these guys that have really led the way
and the US is barely touching so I think
it's about going back and thinking about
what is the talent and expertise that
already exists and how does that get
applied to the Cannabis industry and
then how does the regional industry
positions in this case Europe to compete
at a global level with other regions
when it comes down to that so Europe has
as much of an opportunity as Latin
America or Africa well maybe those are
not great example but they could also
have an opportunity when it comes to
low-cost farming where they could really
produce the lowest cost high quality
cultivation of hemp for instance and
give an example it really is going back
to what is your talent what is your
expertise how do you capitalize on it by
sticking to it
one more question last question
okay hi guys um I'm Nikki from sea salt
in China so I have a questions what has
the cannabis companies done in the last
three years that made most of the
company lose money sustainably
especially the public companies in North
America like canopy Theory they this the
share has dropped like a [__] so is
there anything that is there any lessons
that European market actually can learn
from it absolutely that's I mean that's
exactly why we pushed all our chips here
in in Europe and the MCO model
what happened in the U.S and I'll just
I'll speak to that because I've invested
more in the U.S than in Canadian
companies but having a government put
pressure having the wrong scheduling on
this drug by over taxing at a state
level not allowing access to proper
banking I mean there's no there's no
reason why Goldman Sachs isn't able to
go make investments in the Cannabis
space but it's because of our backwards
laws that we have here if Europe
and really ultimately the globe this
takes the right steps now and takes the
right actions and when when I hear
things that slow down here I know it
frustrates everybody oh you know this
this set us back no it really makes us
from keeps us from making mistakes right
now the mistakes that we've learned in
the U.S the implosion of let's call it
the stocks in Canada you gotta have a
company that has earnings you know you
in any boom of of a of a Marketplace
tech stocks telecom stocks biomed stocks
whatever those can only ride on a boom
for so long eventually you have to have
the earnings behind that that's why I
believe the opportunity is here I
believe the opportunity is here now and
I believe that the opportunity for
Investments and I I mean we partnered
with a Pharma company you know I think
to to jump on that as well of what can
happen now when you have where Pharma
companies can really be in business with
you
versus let's call it what happens in the
U.S we're only a handful of monopolies
get that opportunity I think the sky's
dilemma is here so again when I'm
optimistic I'm not just a little
optimistic I'm all in optimistic so I
think you have a great question we've
learned everything that can go wrong
there you name it it's gone wrong now we
have an opportunity really to to
monopolize
through those thoughts and now
capitalize properly
fantastic thank you so much
[Applause]