welcome everybody to National
perspectives evolution of the German
Market
um and I have the pleasure to have three
absolute experts here with me today
um to talk about this I mean everybody
is looking into Germany and what is
happening right here
um there's some great interest coming up
on to that but um more than that we have
an existing industry also so it's very
interesting to see and get some
up-to-date insights from today today
from our experts we have on the left
hand side Peter homburg he's a partner
at Dentons an international law firm and
he's head of the attendance European
cannabis group as well as a founding
member of the European cannabis
Association he has been working in the
lawyer as a lawyer in the field for
quite some time and in pharmaceutical
law before that and has following the
legalization process for quite some time
also from a legal perspective and then
in the middle we have Nearman Kai has
been a business a corporate lawyer in
Germany since 2003 he has started a
legal blog it's called cannabis minutes
legal with all relevant information and
for THC and CBD industry and Kai is also
an advisor to the European hemp industry
the Iha and which are working on the
joint novel food application at the
moment with Kai's support
um and in here we have Dr Cornelius
maurad Dr Cornelius Morgan is the
economist of the three founders of
demekan and he's he's one of the three
managing directors he's responsible for
finance and procurement so it's a
marketing fundraising and has worked
with the beef RAM and
um
but now most more recently
um Cornelius also started looking into a
venture
Venture funding
um yeah so let's get started straight
away so
um Kai let's start with you
um
there's this ongoing discussion about
cannabis reform but maybe before we dive
into that let's have a quick look into
the medical area and into CBD what's
your stance on that
you mean we got to the upcoming uh
legalization yes yes okay
yeah
um I think we're concentrating on on the
CBD side of of things CBD is very very
complicated uh right now since the
European Union decided in 2019 to put
CBD on the novel food catalog so the
member states of the EU decided that CBD
extracts are noble food and Germany
enforced this novel fruit directive
since 2019 very slowly we had the hype
in 2019 2020-21 and then
the law enforcement took place and you
will hardly find any CBD product CBD oil
labeled as food or as a food supplement
on the German shelves of the big
retailers right now and the last resort
was the Cosmetic oral care product
cosmetricious moonflieger spray the so
at first it was labeled as a supplement
and the Second Step was Aroma and the
third step was Aroma extract and the
last resort was now the Cosmetic oral
product and last week we got a a ruling
from the administrative Court of
digitaldorf saying that the ban of this
product was illegal so and if this the
court in Dusseldorf was referring to the
court in Hamburg which also said that
the ban of this product the distribution
band was illegal and now we have the
situation that you can trade CBD oils in
Hamburg and Dusseldorf but not in Berlin
and not in the south of Germany this is
due to the structure of the health
authority oversight in in Germany which
makes it also very very complicated and
I don't see any solution of that so you
have with these with these ruling you
have two to three years time to the main
proceedings and probably by that the
applications of Iha and the different
other players at the EU commission for
authorizing CBD extract as a novel food
will take place so it's due to the
legalization efforts it's still very
hard to sell the CBD and the the CBD
Market is is very very complicated and
it doesn't make any difference if you if
you look at the legislation which is
coming up that's why I started with this
question
um so maybe to uh to show you also that
we have an existing Market where we are
still facing a lot of challenges here in
Germany
um that are independent of all these
legalization efforts that are currently
talked about but maybe Peter could you
explain what is the Envision to pillar
model that we see and what are the two
pillars and what they determine
government proposed for that
yeah thank you very much Lisa for the
kind introduction I think everybody in
this room expected some good news from
Germany moving into recreational
I'm afraid we don't have these good news
let's look into what has happened since
2022 as you may have followed the German
government in 2022 in October 2022
released a position paper in which they
clearly outlined in which way
legalization of recreational cannabis
and let's call it recreational cannabis
for adult use and you just say
recreational cannabis in Germany it was
very clearly outlined in which way
Germany would cultivate distribute and
of course even control the use of
cannabis under the government control
that was the plan
the government noticed that this may in
conflict with certain laws in particular
with the Schengen agreement which is the
basis of the European Union
and actually
forwarded this pilot paper together with
an explanation and its arguments why
they actually turned around from a
Prohibition policy to a legalization
policy to the European commission
expecting that they at least not agree
but I would say not it's not a formal
process
so the European commission looked at the
paper and at the arguments and the
arguments were very much the same as
Canada has used them for the
legalization of recreational Cannabis as
well which is uh better control of the
distribution of the cannabis for
recreational purposes to protect the
youth uh better control for the
consumers to get high quality products
to the respective user and of course to
attack the illicit Market the same
arguments have been used here well the
European commission said actually no
this is going to violate the Schengen
agreement if you implement that in
Germany we are going to initiate the
respective proceedings before the
European court of justice for breach of
contract of the sharing agreement so
Germany turned around and now here comes
the two new pillar pro project
it was released in April the two pillars
are as follows pillar number one
Germany is going to allow
the home grow of up to three female
plants for every every adult
number one number two Germany is going
to allow the establishment of cannabis
clubs I would call it cultivation
associations because that's what it
really is uh each Club each Association
can have up to 500 members and can grow
cannabis for their members for
recreational purposes under very strict
control
number three of that our first pillar is
that cannabis and THC related products
will be taken out of the German
narcotics act and will be actually
transferred to that new cannabis act
with some impact also on the medical
Market which we may discuss in a minute
this is pillar number one
a respective law has been leaked
a draft law has been leaked it's not yet
released artificially or we have had a
look at that and of course there are a
number of questions with regard to the
implementation of how is this actually
working how does the Cannabis
cultivation Association really be
controlled who is going to decide where
and what is going to be cultivated so
how it's financed because it's a
non-profit organization and I think
that's important to know it should be a
non-profit organization so for every
every investor in this room this is bad
news actually actually because they
should not make any money so this is the
first pillar let me just introduce the
second pillar if you allow these are the
second pillar is that Germany will start
pilot scientific pilot projects which
are as we all know allowed under the U.N
conventions and the sharing agreement
under specific scientific control where
distribution will be done through
properly licensed shops or licensed
Distributors uh to those who have been
resisted and are going to use cannabis
for the recreational purposes this is
not yet even a draft law it's just a
plan probably the draft law will be
released after the summer break later
this year with regard to the cannabis
clubs or the calabas cultivation
associations just two more effects
number one there will be a limit of 30
grams per month for adults of up to 21.
so between 18 and 21 we have the
possibility to get 30 grams at a THC
level of 10 or below
oops
number two adults can actually purchase
50 grams with no THC limits from those
cannabis as cultivation associations so
that's what the laws current draft law
says whether it will be implemented in
such way is of course questionable it's
now discussed between the Ministries and
will be actually forwarded to the
cabinet probably not before the summer
break which starts in 14 days
thank you so Cornelius as a one or us
the only true German cultivator in
Germany what is your stance on the
current status of the industry and what
are you looking for in the future
good morning hello
good morning everybody
um so
let's try it here good morning everybody
it's a pleasure to be here to see you
all and thank you for having us on this
panel
um I I'd like to start with um telling
you a little bit about our story and I
think the biggest challenges we faced in
the germ market and then go to the
evolution and uh
forecast of what the German Market could
look like so I think the biggest
milestone in Germany we saw in the past
five years was the building of a
national the domestic supply chain so
there were three licenses tended out in
for cultivation of cannabis in Germany
and the idea was to have an entire
domestic supply chain and as an operator
in the space as a cultivator as an
importer as a Processing Company demican
we really saw this as a big Challenge
and we were very happy to be able to
start delivering last year
now
um domestic supply chain I think it's
important to stretch this one because in
the
um forecasted recreational Cannabis
space
it looks like in the draft law that all
cannabis needs to be produced in Germany
processed in Germany and we will have to
have a complete domestic supply chain
also in the recreational space and I
know many companies who started as
importers
they don't like it because they will
have to Pivot their business model to
either build their own cultivation space
or rent or purchase production
capacities at existing production sites
such as damikan or Aurora or Toure
whether they want to
so um I think yeah domestic supply chain
was the biggest challenge and now we
have it I think there's a fair chance
for
um the German Market to be able to live
up to what we have to which is to supply
the German Market if we look at
forecasts for the addressable Market in
the recreational space it's about 400
tons to be conservative of those 400
tons how much we will see in a cannabis
Social Club scenario which is pillow one
that Peter just introduced maybe 10
which is 40 tons 40 tons then we can we
could deliver half of that 20 tons
easily on our production Side by scaling
up and that within the first year of
delivery so when you hear people say oh
we have to import because we have to be
able to supply the demand yeah we don't
have to we can't produce it in Germany
and there are also other Market players
I look at York here in the first row
who's building a production site so
there is initiative there is
entrepreneurs starting to to jump into
this Gap and we can do it
now looking at the medical space what
happened
um we saw some nice growth I would say
from 2021 to 2022 and 2021 we had nine
tons of medical cannabis being sold in
pharmacies in 2022 we don't have
official numbers but if you extrapolate
the official numbers until September
2022 we had 11.4 tons that is 26 of
growth
um it's a small Medical Market but even
if we don't like the draft law for
recreational Cannabis because it imposes
many challenges for us as operators and
Market players I think there is a chance
to actually fight the black market and
grow interesting business models
thank you
so let's jump back over to yukai what do
you think
do you believe there's a possibility to
establish a legal framework from out of
Germany for Europe also
no
cannabis can't be regulated in the EU
for the as a sense right now if you look
at countries like Sweden or Finland or
whatever they have a such a conservative
approach to cannabis uh there won't be a
unanimous solution in the EU in in terms
of cannabis I don't I don't think so
so what's the option then I had the
chance to talk to Czech officials
in April and in May and June I was
listening to James Rich water check the
federal drug commissioner the ponderf of
pocardinet in in the Czech Republic and
he was saying they are working on a law
in the Czech Republic to legalize
cannabis and to open a commercial route
and they exactly know what's going to
happen that there might be a problem
with the EU commission with other member
states and they faced that they say okay
yeah let's let's get sued let's go to
court let's go let's take it to the ECG
let's see what happens and if the ECG
finally decides after five years we have
our industry established here and the
the industry won't vanish won't
disappear then anymore let's and if they
have some some regulations or some some
guidelines we have to obey okay we will
do that but we will work on this
commercial route
and we will we will do it and they have
a really interesting uh approach they
call it the cyclo psychomodulatory
Substances Act so uh psycho modulatory
means this will also cover low THC
products like in Switzerland like up to
one percent CBD flowers like Kratom and
it will also cover Kratom and you will
implement the measures of Regulation
according to the dangers to the danger
of the substance so the substance is
really dangerous you will have more
regulation if it is less dangerous you
will have less regulation and I think
this is a very very modern approach to
to cannabis policy in terms of health
issues but also in terms of Human Rights
so for freedom of person to use
substances
and this is the only way so small
countries like I heard Slovenia has some
some initiatives I heard last night the
Czech Republic has to move forward it's
not the big countries showing the EU how
to regulate cannabis it will be the
small countries to move forward and find
ways to to circumen these uh still stand
in the in the EU and uh in at the latest
point it has to be the courts but but
but not the member states they won't be
in unanimous Solutions uh it's single
countries moving forward or at least the
ECG has to decide on on that and if you
have facts like you have an established
Market in the Czech Republic after five
years you want you can't draw back the
the clocks then anymore
um Peter maybe also for you how do you
think that the Cannabis legalization
efforts in Germany will affect existing
Industries but also the illegal market
and how will this legal framework also
maybe affect changes in the EU
regulatory framework regarding cannabis
yeah let's let's start with the the last
part of the three questions
um indeed as as you pointed out Kai
there are a number of member states who
see it positively what the Germans are
doing the approach of October 2022 was
very much supported by the Czech
Republic anyway however
there are other member states who are
relatively conservative or to say at
least against the legalization of
recreational cannabis they are also
larger countries uh Germany would not go
the route as you described the further
Czech Republic because Germany lost big
times before the European court of
justice in other subject matters just
recently and as such Germany is not
going to take that route though it's
more a cautious approach which they are
taking coming back to your second
question well the actual argument of the
legalization in Germany was to attack
the illicit market and if you look into
the first pillar the question is is that
really the right instrument to do it if
you allow a home grow if you allow
cannabis cultivation of course under the
government control but as I said
non-profit it's still economically
questionable whether this will work may
not be a good approach towards the
illicit market and for the protection of
the youth I I'm going to question that
Frankly Speaking the second pillar with
the regard to the scientific pilot
projects which we see in other countries
happening as well in particular for
example in Switzerland Germany is
thinking about very much the same model
I I believe that this is even my
preferred solution take into
consideration the legal framework which
we have within the European Union Canada
had it had didn't have that problem when
they actually legalized in 2019 they had
just adjust the UN conventions they're
getting warning letters every year from
the national International narcotics
board but they they actually ignore that
though that that was easier for them to
implement because if you question why is
Germany taking that approach that's
because of the Shang agreement and the
respective protocols which have been
released and which have confirmed that
still the European Union is following
the prohibition of cannabis and coming
back to the last part of your question I
don't see that
I don't see that very much happening
within the European Union we will see
more and more
approaches towards the legalization of
recreational Cannabis within certain
European countries but this will take
some time and Germany is believing that
with the experience they are having
Within These two pillar models for a
period of four years they have
sufficient proof that the legalization
has a positive impact on on this Society
has a positive impact on on the
attacking of the illicit Market which we
see indeed growing every year and of
course what you can buy on the listed
Market has not has in in certain aspects
nothing to do with any kind of quality
or high quality
cannabis products cannabis flowers as we
see it which is our manufactured for
example by the by dami Khan and the
other local this local cultivators here
in Germany
thank you very much so Cornelius what do
you think how will the Cannabis
regulation also impact existing
Industries like the medicinal cannabis
industry in Germany for example
well um if we look at Canada or United
States we can assume that certain
product categories will contract in the
sense of for example flower we already
have between 30 to 50 percent of
self-paying patients most of them one
can fairly assume our consumers and not
are necessarily treating
pain issues so we will see a decline in
flower sales that's for sure
after an initial increase why is that
because what Peter described about how
they want to legalize the recreational
Market it's putting cannabis away from a
narcotic status to a non-narcotic and
prescriptions will very likely at least
double or triple in the beginning and
once the Cannabis social clubs are then
open for prescription and for becoming a
member and actually buying product then
we will certainly see in the product
category of flower a steep decline I
don't see necessarily a big change for
extracts so in the medical cannabis
space you have flour you have extracts
you have already made Pharmaceuticals
for extracts ready-made Pharmaceutical
ready-made Pharmaceuticals I don't see
that much change now
if you look at the market players many
of them have been set up to not only
serve the medical space but potentially
also be a big player in the recreational
space some of the market players want to
stay in the medical space and say that
very clearly others such as damikan we
found this company with a clear view on
regulation in Canada and the United
States and we saw medical cannabis will
be legalized first very likely and
recreational Cannabis eventually will
follow and that was the initial plan
from the beginning so for those who want
to Pivot I I mentioned earlier they if
they want to play in the first round
they have to become domestic cultivators
or get access to domestic product which
will be a challenge I guess for many
mostly a Time challenge
I think a fair assumption for any is
starting now to get a building permit to
get the funding to build the facility to
get the cultivars to get do test runs
you need at least two years so this will
be what everybody's had will be around
thank you very much I would open uh
first like a warm Round of Applause for
the panelists
and then I would hand over because I bet
there are many questions in that regard
for the German market so let's have a
little bit more questions they're all
excited okay I'm coming uh By the way
when we take the break after this panel
for uh coffee and refreshments we invite
you to visit our exhibitors uh 3C in ZTE
Tomlin group Vivaldi's Nabi and the
state of Victoria in Australia please
help our exhibitors out and now the
question
hi good morning thank you very much
I'm not sure if I should ask for my
money back I come from South Africa we
have over 90 licenses awarded by the uh
regulator and most of the talk fueled by
the government as one might call it
um is that South Africa is potentially a
huge contributor to the global cannabis
scene and of course Germany takes
private place as the market to which all
of Africa should aspire to export
um from what I'm hearing here unless I
misunderstood Germany's actually closing
down and Europe potentially thereafter
with regards to allowing the import of
cannabis
um let's talk a medical cannabis at this
point in time but there is a huge uh
developing capacity for cannabis growing
in Africa and particularly in South
Africa under the illusion that we grow
it better we have better land race we do
a cheaper our currency is feeble neither
the Canadians nor the Europeans know how
to grow cannabis like we do and they're
for the Futures ahead of us
this is just a belief
from what I'm hearing here this is
simply not the case it's all illusory
the biggest markets going to grow it for
itself according to what you want to
sell protection and therefore Africa has
to look to itself mind you apparently we
smoke three tons a day in South Africa
at school
but still recreational Cannabis isn't
legal just yet the clubs have not been
approved by the courts and those of us
who are medical cannabis cultivators
have invested a great deal at the
highest end seeking EU GMP
certification by the way under the
advice of European consultants and this
all looks like it's nonsense
that's tough
it's tough so
um I everybody here is very aware that
many countries have been scaling up uh
especially to be able to supply Germany
and Europe with the world-class high
quality Eugene P great cannabis and I
think they will be able to continue for
the medical space
this is clear in the draft law you can
export raw material send it to operators
processors such as demikan we transform
it into eugnp great cannabis that can be
sold in the German Market in the
European market or any equivalent Market
with eegmp requirements
but for the domestic recreational
Cannabis Market it will be domestic only
supply chain this is what says the law
I don't judge it I mean obviously I'm
happy about it but this is what we have
and and let me add there is still huge
potential in the German Medical Market
we are far away from any kind of uh
Market situation uh there are there's a
lot of more potential here what are the
hurdles uh for Physicians to prescribe
cannabis currently there are a number of
hurdles but it is of course also it's a
narcotic number one number two the
information which the Physicians have
and we have just discussed with a great
greater group of Physicians about the
possibilities to prescribe cannabis what
are the preconditions when can a
physician prescribe cannabis what are
the the the the regulations for that uh
if we need more education I think and
that's a part actually calling the
industry more education of the
Physicians to feel more comfortable to
prescribe cannabis as a medicine though
lots of potential in there and still I
believe that for the medic vehicle
Market there's still the need of imports
the medical Market also in the future
with regard to this high quality EU GMP
certified products will not be probably
not be satisfied by the by the current
domestic Market uh we will definitely
see Imports in the future we don't know
what is the future of medical cannabis
cultivation in Germany it's not yet
maybe you know more than I but
Cornelius I I have not seen anything
from the Bay Farm yet where in which way
they will renew or increase their
respective quarters which you have
because
you know that the cultivators in Germany
have a limit of 10.4 tons for a period
of four years plus an additional 10 if
I'm not mistaken that that is only part
a small part of what the medical Market
is actually needing that it's a reading
that's an easy reason why we are looking
into even in the future Imports so there
is space for improvement
yeah let me let me add to that there is
a
the the most of the medical cannabis
import companies in Germany they have
done their sourcing globally so they
have stable Supply chains now be it from
Colombia be it from Canada be it from
South Africa
but I wouldn't only look there is
potential in the German Market
especially if cannabis is moved from the
narcotics act prescription will probably
rise double triple whatever but still a
very small Market it's only 25 tons were
imported and dispensed 11 tons dispense
to the pharmacies
um there is still potential but I
wouldn't look only to Germany almost
every European country is setting up a
medical cannabis program and if you look
at the UK they have only five
indications in Germany there is no limit
of indications and won't be afterwards
so look at the other EU States as well
which are setting we're setting up a
kind of medical cannabis programs for
for chances to to business or to export
and I I must add there is
maybe hope for those producing outside
of Europe
that the law initiative might change
this is possible and one way it could
change is they try to ease access to
cannabis by making it a OTC so that
could be a potential way but this is not
what is proposed right now so I'm just
pointing out at the potential
Alternatives path but right now as I
said it's domestic only and and maybe
one more remark to that the second
pillar the scientific pilot projects of
course have also a need for Supply so
the question is do we see under the
first pillar the cultivation
associations popping up like mushrooms
everywhere
serving the the needs of their members
and who is going to serve later on the
scientific pilot projects how house why
it will they spread it out into Germany
does every city has these implementation
of scientific pilot projects has at
every state we see that in Switzerland
we have two projects which started
actually earlier this year in
Switzerland in in Basel and in Zurich
and we will probably learn from that a
little bit more but Germany is
significantly larger than Switzerland so
we'll see what how how this Market how
this demand will be then served this
will be interesting to see
okay
uh this is targeted mainly for you
Cornelius but I see that Peter is in
agreement that there's some kind of
importation in the future
Cornelius you're not for importation let
me just say this
I spent five years in Jamaica recently I
saw the program from the beginning to
disaster a lot of good things did happen
but
that's a medical program but they make
it easy you go into the dispensary you
make a phone call to a doctor that's on
board and they give you your medical
card right there and then you purchase
your flower or your other products
when it comes to consumption when Europe
finally
takes these steps baby steps now I
suppose
the consumption is going to be huge what
millions of pounds a month
the craft grows the the grow that you
talked about that you provide what would
you say 40 tons a year or something like
that it doesn't make a dent
in the overall require some consumption
that you're going to have so importation
there's so many countries that are
better geographically to grow than in
Germany you're going to have very high
costs here because of energy you have to
build you know facilities buildings
whatnot you know I'm talking about
Colombia mainly they've been shipping
for a hundred years so my question is
Cornelius would you be open to the idea
that importation has a place
as maybe a contingency plan but we
shouldn't I think politic against
importation because I don't think you
import call you don't grow coffee here
or bananas or or other things you go to
the geographical area where it best
grows at the most economical uh prices
and and the volume that you're going to
need yeah so for the medical space for
sure this will continue the government
hasn't said anything that contradicts
this assumption that importation will be
possible and we we agree that there will
be an increase in prescriptions once
it's delisted from being a narcotic on
the recreational side it is what the
government proposes domestic only supply
chain and I know it's hard to hear but
this is what's black on white and this
is in line what happened with
the legalization of recreation cannabis
in Canada no Imports I I hear you loud
and clear but it is how regulation moves
and this it's what is being proposed
here in Germany and let me add that
under the first pillar there is no need
for importation
first pillar is homepro and the
cultivation associations so there's
there's no need even for for any kind of
cultivation of recreational purposes
here in Germany at this point in time
under the first pillar if it comes into
place the second pillar is different
there we may have to see what's going to
happen still the plan of the government
is domestic cultivation will serve even
that market on the second pillar which
are the scientific pilot projects
been very patient and then everyone else
when we go for coffee and pastries you
can pile around these guys and uh and
and pester them uh to your heart's
desire
thank you hi I'm Nicholas from Colombia
so I wouldn't go as far as saying that
we grow the best kind of business as a
guy from South Africa say but we're
pretty good at large scale and good
premium quality flowers at a good price
um I don't want to go too deep into the
100 Years of exports of marijuana you
know from my country so I'm just going
to put that aside but I want to say this
I agree that the government is saying
that it has to be domestic only for
recreational space right but we're not
thinking about the
consumers in Germany when it comes to
pricing you know and I know that you
guys as pioneers and voices to be here
in the Germany legislation to be done I
think it will be good and very important
to be heard in the part that probably
some imports are going to be needed in
order to accomplish that market in a
good price and in a good quality we are
very aware the German cultivators are
not going to be
um you know producing at a very
affordable price so if we put so many
imports from countries that are doing a
good job you know could make actually a
good point for consumers yeah thank you
for raising this point uh production
costs I love it because there is a huge
misunderstanding here
um Demi can produces locally
domestically and it's about one quarter
of our Top Line and the other three
quarters come from importation so we
have several Global suppliers and I know
the prices for which I buy and I know
the price for which I produce
domestically and reproduce
full production costs below 2 Euros at
one ton annual production capacity so if
we scale that goes down and I buy some
product below two Euros
Eugene P grade or raw material but most
of them are more expensive and I know
they might be produced cheaper but if
you look at the market prices we're
actually cheaper in producing it
ourselves here in Germany so please keep
that in mind okay thank you I'm sorry to
cut everybody off I know you all had a
lot of questions so the great panel
let's hear it and uh