thanks again for everybody joining us
and that one last thing I failed to
mention the whole idea is to have this
to be a very Interactive
beneficial provocative discussion all
day long but the other thing you'll
notice this first panel we do not have a
moderator so the idea is to give
everybody a little heads up
is we're going to start off with one or
two topics and then from that point we
want to get in and just kick it out to
the audience because I think that's the
one thing that's going to be most
informed for you guys and certainly I
think for us so Bob do you want to kick
things off on an introduction of
yourself
sure uh good good morning everybody uh
my name is Bob Hoban I'm an attorney and
an advisor I run the global cannabis
division for Clark Hill an international
law firm I also own a company called
Gateway proven strategies a leading
Global consultancy and a company called
sea trust which is the only credit
rating system for businesses in the
Cannabis industry and it's a pleasure to
be here one quick note two quick notes
uh the the concept of THC plus and minus
I really really love this concept and I
hope that you can get your minds around
that today because this is not about
selling flour it's not about just
selling Vape cartridges with high
concentrations of THC and sometimes in
different parts of the world we get
caught in that little Silo where we
believe the industry is what we think it
is but it's far broader than that and we
have to embrace that concept because
whether we like Delta eight so forth and
so on it's the same sandbox and also
David you saved me and David by the way
when you go to if you ever gone to the
world economic Forum in Switzerland it's
a ghost town during this event because
everybody flies in and out so I drive
into this town I can't find anything or
anybody
except for this friendly face who helped
me find where I was going so thank you
for that David you saved me you saved me
Jamie
good morning everybody my name is Jamie
Pearson I am the President and founder
of New Holland Group which is an
international cannabis consultancy
um I spent seven years prior to that
running a company called bang Inc which
was famous for its cannabis infused
chocolate which when I started that
company or started working for that
company we were in California when I
left we were in seven U.S states we were
the number one two and six chocolate in
Canada and I brought our CBD products
into nine European countries so I've
been in the industry a long time and my
dad has been growing 56 years so I grew
up knowing what how you know how to look
at trichomes and how to trim weed
whether I wanted to or not and my cousin
on my mom's side is DJ mugs from Cypress
Hill so when I was in law school in 1992
my cousin lit a joint on Saturday Night
Live so I then in the industry in one
form or fashion pretty much all my life
good morning everyone I'm Rob McAvoy I'm
president of the McAvoy Management Group
which is a consulting firm to the
Cannabis space prior to starting my
company I was an owner operator across
multiple states in the United States
formerly I was a VP at a cannabis AG
tech company that was Knack desk listed
so a lot of global cannabis experience
and formulation cultivation extraction
retailing I've been doing this now for
over a decade in the commercial space
I've been on the supply and demand side
of cannabis since I was about 14 15
years old though so really looking
forward to the conversation this morning
keeping it Lively
thanks Rob so as you guys know the title
of this panel is to essentially look
back on the past and so that the first
topic we would like to at least start
out with the panelists uh is looking at
adult use and medical cannabis both here
in the U.S all over the world has been
treated uh differently or dealt with
differently
what did that what does that mean
historically how's that happen how's the
treatment been different and what are
the implications for the future so
ladies first Jamie do you want to
absolutely I think watching what's
happening in Europe I'm going to start
you know how did we get here where we
are right now is Germany and how did we
get here
um
we go back historically and see what
happened in California
in the prop 215 which was a let's put
medical program in air quotes which
basically was a way for people to go get
cards and get cannabis so that they
didn't have to worry about going to jail
and then the industry sort of blew up
from there but where we are now in
Germany it is a true medical program
this is in Germany Pharmaceuticals it's
going through the apoteca it's going
with a prescription and if you know what
you're doing you can actually have the
government reimburse you that's a far
cry from what we saw in California so
many years ago and then there's
everything in between the other thing
we're seeing on that THC plus and THC
minus conversation is the explosion of
hemp derived
products that are
getting people high and they're quote
legal THC and we're also seeing in
Europe that there are places that are
figuring out oh well I can spray
terpenes on my hemp flower and I can get
people high we're going to get to the
same result the reality is human beings
want this plant uh that's where we are
is it now as you you have more and more
people waking up with access to the
plant you cannot put the genie back in
the bottle so now it's not a matter of
if cannabis is going to be legalized
worldwide it's a matter of when and how
and these are the rooms where we're
going to shape that conversation
absolutely
so in Colorado back in 2009 2010 we had
a lot of medical marijuana migrants with
Charlotte's Web coming online we started
seeing a lot more firms bringing
patients with very high needs into the
state to gain access at the same time we
started seeing other medical marijuana
programs open up in Illinois and in
Maryland that started to require or
wanted to ask for a pharmacist
involvement to bring in more of that
medicinal check and balance as it
relates to the products as it relates to
the potencies and then of course their
therapeutic effects you know that got a
lot of backlash and resistance in the in
the program itself because what we
really have is a culture versus a
commercialization clash and there are a
lot of Legacy folks from the Cannabis
space who did not want medical
professionals coming in in those
capacities and so with that we started
to see the evolution of more and more
municipalities at a local level in the
states open up and create more of that
over-the-counter access through adult
use programs and of course then that
started to mitigate and you know
decrease can of Tourism if you will for
patients in the migration of those
patients into the programs I think now
when we start to look at where it's
going into the future as it relates to
cannasuticals there's a very big
opportunity Gap because as we've been
talking about we're really looking at a
molecular and a phytocompound basis
we're looking at active pharmaceutical
ingredients and so with that and having
a cache of those ingredients we can
formulate new products we can formulate
new Delivery Systems and of course new
product formats so I think that as we
continue to start to see the European
market open and up going through the
pharmacies going through the
extemporaneous compounding process of
different methods of uh delivery we're
really starting to see more of an
emphasis on a strained a symptom and on
a condition to compound approach
I uh it's important to know that every
country around the world
legalizes cannabis for a different
reason
you have to understand the quote unquote
why why did they legalize cannabis was
it because of medical reasons was it
because of Criminal Justice Reform was
it for Social Justice Reform was it for
economic development this is the very
Cornerstone that you have to understand
as an invinced investor or operator in
this space because if you don't you have
no chance of participating in that
region that jurisdictions Marketplace
for example medical quote unquote using
that note that notion medical marijuana
in the United States has nothing to do
with medicine
medical marijuana means this is how you
qualify a purchaser they have a
condition that a doctor has recognized
it's on a list of conditions and that
allows that purchaser to legally walk
into a store possess cultivate or
purchase a cannabis product nothing to
do with medicine nothing
very different in Europe very different
in Germany as you mentioned it's a
pharmaceutical model
and here's the notion that I don't and I
can't wrap my mind around
the notion that in Europe
flour can be prescribed
as a part of a medical regime as a as a
as a medical solution never in the
United States ever ever ever ever ever
is the FDA going to sanction a program
or doctors recommend a flower no it's
always going to be an extract and a
formulation
so to have these models merge in the
future is going to be really really
interesting and again I don't doubt the
efficacy of cannabis for a second that's
not what I'm saying but in the United
States medical marijuana merely
qualifies the purchaser the last thing
I'll note is it is important to
recognize that the sandbox so to speak
is not just about flour and I've argued
that Industrial Hemp really is the
backbone for the Cannabis supply chain
the entire Global Supply Chain in the
world can be built from extracts from
the hemp plant it costs 600 per acre to
grow
it's less regulated and guess what it
contains the exact same cannabinoids
just in different ratios as a high
concentration marijuana plant
so then why would you go through the
system of registering a medical program
going through millions and millions and
millions of dollars of infrastructure
development when you can grow it for six
hundred dollars per acre
extract the compounds and create
formulations based thereon that is the
future and the more that we recognize
that the faster we recognize that and
you may not agree with this but this is
a fact I mean these are this is the way
the supply chain is going to develop
globally the more that you can get your
mind around that I think the better
positions you'll be as an investor as an
operator to to work in this industry
thanks Bob uh two things maybe to bring
up real quick that's looking in the past
the adult use versus medical uh one if
you know about Oklahoma
is crazy right so Oklahoma is a medical
quote-unquote Medical Market right and
the first year I think second year they
had 800 million dollars in sales in
Oklahoma and anybody that knows Oklahoma
realizes they don't have that many
people smoking pot frankly right and
it's meant to be a medical State and
most of that stuff's probably going down
to Dallas Texas
right so here's this Medical Market
that's actually more adult use right and
then on the other hand if you know about
the recent weed CARE program in
Switzerland if you don't you should know
about it because it's I think going to
be probably the model
of the future so here you have the Wee
Care Program in Switzerland which is an
adult use program where they roll it out
in specific cities associated with a
given University and it's under the
federal Office of Public Health
in Switzerland but also under the
auspices of the UN narcotics board which
is a big part of if you know the U.N
single Convention of 61. so here's a
adult use Market that's actually being
rolled out like a medical market and I
think that's hopefully maybe going to be
the model that hope works in the future
because I think as everybody here on the
stage will agree one of the big things
we need to overcome is the stigma and
the stigma needs to be overcome by
information intellect data and and just
a clear path forward
and medical studies I mean I think at
the end of the day we we put air quotes
around medical program but I think the
reason cannabis is so popular is that it
actually works
um and it works you know from my
perspective having run a chocolate
company a lot of people would not read
the instructions and they would eat the
chocolate bar that had you know anywhere
from 100 to 420 milligrams of cannabis
and if you ate the whole chocolate bar
you might end up at the emergency room
with a panic attack but you wouldn't die
at the same time you're doing that
because you're seeking some relief
whether it's the ability to sleep or
it's pain or it's nausea from taking
chemotherapy whatever it is Parkinson's
you've got some sort of a seizure
disorder people are seeking relief
because the pharmaceutical industry is
limited from the compounds that they're
providing whether they're opiates or
whatever they are and our body has an
endocannabinoid system and we actually
need this medicine and so I read a
statistic and it varies depending on
who's doing the study but approximately
85 percent of all people using cannabis
in the adult use markets are using it
for some medical reason that's why I
know this industry is not going away
because people want this access to this
plant so to Bob's point if we figure out
the most efficacious way to deliver it
to them where we can as business
operators have banking have marketing
and get people access to this plant in a
way that we can actually make money it
sort of becomes a Snowball Effect
because we can get rid of the stigma the
more people that have a great experience
with it where they don't end up in the
emergency room where they end up
sleeping through the night they they
tell 10 of their friends then they try
the gummy or they try the chocolate or
they try The Vape and right now it's a
global phenomenon it is an action
industry and in our lifetime I think the
only other industry that's blown up to
this degree has been.com maybe web 3 is
coming but we are creating jobs we're
creating economic development in a time
where we desperately need it so I think
there's a lot of factors figuring into
this
the only thing that we're fighting is
fear the governments are afraid
and Isis I suspect that that fear is
coming from industry that is challenged
by this plant so it's alcohol it's
tobacco it's Pharmaceuticals because
they're wondering well what's going to
happen when everybody has access to
cannabis they're not going to be taking
opiates they're not going to be taking
Lyrica they're not going to be you know
drinking as much alcohol and it's
actually playing out to be the case so
we're we're a dangerous industry in the
sense that human beings are going to be
using this in higher percentages
just just really quick just a quick note
giving people access to whatever
whatever way they want to access
cannabis is important because
over-the-counter cannabis when I walk to
a dispensary I buy a flower or an oil
that's one way to access it but it's a
whole other way to go to a doctor and
get a prescribed medication or a
formulation that's been going it's gone
through clinical trials and is
registered but all of those things need
to be accessible but that's your point
David is this is moving towards the
pharmaceutical model which is the latter
no one's walking into a dispensary
necessarily in conjunction with their
doctor they're going and getting a
formulation and and that's how you have
to widen your perspective and realize
that patients need to have access as
many different ways as possible even if
it's not a specific prescribed medical
use it completely agreed Jamie and Bob
and I think it has to be mentioned that
there's an onus on the operators in the
program as well no matter where they're
operating they need to understand what
problem they're trying to solve and why
they're trying to solve it in order to
be able to create the physician in
campaigns in order to be able to create
the patient messaging that closes the
communication gap between how this might
be valuable and from there what benefits
it's going to have for whatever malady
we're trying to treat and so a lot of
operators are running before they're
crawling and walking and with that model
they're not slowing their scale to their
sales and now the priority is Shifting
in their business model and how they're
executing on their business plan and
with that patients and Physicians get
left behind let alone The Regulators who
are still trying to understand all the
different nuances of this plant and the
derivative Products that come from it
and I was just going to say we're in
prohibition right now so if you study
history at the end of prohibition of
alcohol
there there was a lot of I would say
danger a lot of people rushing to get
where they wanted to be or to make that
cash grab
the interesting thing about this
industry is it's both medical and it's
recreational in the sense that people
use it as a social lubricant as well and
so you know when we're looking at all of
that is it a plant is it cpg is it
medicine it's all of those things and so
what we haven't figured out yet as an
industry is where do we land where is it
going to be able where are we going to
be able to give people access the way
they want it
so I'd like to kick it out to the
audience any questions somebody want to
kick it off
does anyone have a question just raise
your hand I'm wearing comfortable shoes
we'll be fine all right here we go
thanks for that guys
um
is that close enough
um my question is what has gone really
wrong in the industry that set us back
and what how can we learn from that and
how does that project us forward
to uh it's pretty easy yeah no that's uh
it's the start of attempt well so you
don't have time for that question
I appreciate that but like if you could
pinpoint a few key things that you think
have been really painful and maybe set
us back a little bit but actually in the
long run we'll take us further maybe if
you can use that word frame is the easy
one and this goes across all kinds of
geographies too much arrogance and too
little humility
so essentially you have all these people
that jumped in thought that it was going
to be easy you know growing weeds easy
growing really good weeds not
then you had you know the constellation
deal five billion dollars put in and you
essentially had campy growth put in
2018 early 2018 they bought a facility
in Lesotho South Africa or Lesotho 28.8
million they sold it less than two years
later for who knows how much right to
the people that sold it to them yeah
yeah exactly totally and and the fact
that you essentially have these people
that that think everything is going to
be uh
I mean you know for example one last
thing and I brought this up uh when Bob
and I were in Davos the one thing that's
been a huge Advantage for my firm is the
fact I understood that biological Supply
chains are inherently unstable when I
was doing recombinant protein production
in the early 90s we scaled up from like
300 to 500 liters and all of a sudden
this protein impurity we're making phase
one material this protein impurity came
out of nowhere and we had to figure out
a way to get rid of it and having that
experience and you're watching canopy
growth and Aurora and all these harvests
go from like 40 000 square feet of grow
to four hundred thousand and about five
ten years ago and guess what we're like
well that's going to effing blow up and
what what happened right so that's a
just a real classic I will kick it over
to my uh
colleagues
I would say the problem in the industry
is that the types of consumers that you
want to walk into a store and buy
cannabis don't go to stores because they
grow their own or because the laws are
so flexible that higher quality cannabis
has grown in smaller batches and you can
go access cannabis from people you know
versus walking into a store I hate
alcohol analogies but I would suggest
that the person that goes in and buys a
case of beer or a fourteen dollar six
pack of beer every couple of days that
consumer is not prevalent in the
Cannabis industry that's my perspective
uh I don't know Jamie you you lived and
breathed it I would I would say it's
misinformation and part of that comes
from the lack of testing that we you
know University testing lab testing so
we have consumers that are buying Indica
sativa and we know that indica and
sativa is really talking about the shape
of the leaf of the plant and how it
grows but it's kind of telling people I
might be Indica into couch I might be
Teva feeling up but the reality is we
all in the industry know it's terpene
profile but we don't test for terpenes
and oh my gosh we can't even start there
because we don't have banking we don't
have advertising what's gone wrong
we're it's we're in our infancy right
all we can do right now we're like
toddlers stumbling around bonking our
head on the table we we're making
mistakes because that's what you do in
your infancy everything's going wrong
I mean every company is going out of
business right like what else can I say
um yeah there's a lot that we could talk
about
um you know from my perspective I think
it's uh people raising a lot of money
and building a lot of shiny things that
underperform uh because they need to
show investors that they did something
worthwhile with that Capital but the
reality is is that they're scrambling
now to sell through the product that is
of poor quality in unmanaged
environmental areas that now is causing
deficits and what those deficits come
cutting Corners when it comes to your
extracts and when it comes to your
plants as well and I think that you know
a lot of ego has been infused into the
sector that is of negative consequences
and I think that you know companies have
not truly looked themselves in the
mirror to understand what their purpose
and their passion is for being in the
space and then what their Niche is what
their competitive differentiator is to
motivate a patient to buy their product
or to be served by their product over
their competitors and it's really
business 101. again a lot of folks
jumping in really quickly with a lot of
money burning it to shareholders dismay
and then trying to recover which creates
inconsistencies within that business
model and high turnover from your
employees to your actual facilities and
none of that benefits any medical
program or adult use over-the-counter
program
this is not an easy industry there is no
easy way to make money and so a lot of
people get in get chewed up get spit out
and leave so I I will say that I you
know want to just raise the people up
like Bob like David
ones that are still here
um you know kudos to you
so Rob Kyle I like a question
is there another question
oh there you go we'll go here and then
we'll go there
hi thanks very much for a very
informative panel
um I'm kind of curious because I come
from a North American perspective but
I've lived in Portugal for the last year
now so I've really started to integrate
a lot and I've been in the industry in
North America since 2009 so uh there's
definitely been a stronger focus on
medical here but we've also seen in
North America that a lot of the quality
and The Innovation comes from the Legacy
Market comes from the craft Growers and
I I guess there's this underlying fear
that I have that this focus on big
Pharma taking over the industry will
stifle uh the small grower and in turn a
lot of the Innovation that we see from
the plant Germany's model with uh you
know forcing the different Social Clubs
to grow their own product could mitigate
that to a large degree but if we're
looking at a a broader European
pharmaceutical model uh do you think
that there are ways to ameliorate this
before we
you know run run headfirst into the
train real quick our perspective on the
Pharma is getting into this industry is
it's probably not going to happen if you
look at Pharma well it's going to happen
but not today I think people think it is
because if you really look at Farm
what's happened so the sandwich facility
which was responsible for Lipitor for
Pfizer Pfizer sold that off like 20
years ago 15 years ago Pharma companies
have been kicking off Innovation they've
been getting it from biotech companies
right and the problem too with Pharma
companies they're always looking for
composition matter coverage on molecules
to get that in these natural molecules
pretty hard so essentially the Pharma
companies and we know we've talked to
support you know we've talked to Pfizer
Novartis Lily Abby you name it GP has
talked to those groups I know Barbara
Dalton at Pfizer Ventures they still
supposedly say they're not interested I
believe they are but I think the other
thing is frankly the Pharma companies
come from a biotech guy and I'm sure
there might be some Pharma company
people in here but you know I think
we're going to be seeing more interested
in biotech than Pharma in the industry
I would say that they're not the same
industry a pharmaceutical company is
never going to own a dispensary they
don't want anything to do with it it's
not the same industry The Innovation
that you talk about from the illicit or
the Legacy Market that's for consumers
that purchase cannabis over the counter
a dispensary is merely an
over-the-counter dispensary access
conduit it has nothing to do with FDA
type approved formulations for specific
conditions so pharmaceutical companies
May own that they will own that
necessarily because it's a it's a
lengthy process that requires approvals
clinical trials IP protection and the
like but a pharmaceutical company is
never going to have anything to do with
the dispensary not here not anywhere in
the in the world ultimately those models
have to merge so that's why I say I
don't think pharmaceutical Pharmacy is
not going to own this Pharmacy is going
to own what they own but that's very
different than OTC cannabis which is
what a dispensary is that's all it is I
think it's it's
I don't know that they necessarily have
to merge
but they're they have to coexist because
there's two different models one is you
go to the pharmacy because you want the
cannabinoid as a an ingredient in
something you're taking for an effect
the person that wants to smoke craft
cannabis that goes as an
over-the-counter purchaser they are the
ones like I go into the wine Terror
sorry about another alcohol analogy but
the people that are really enjoying
cannabis socially that go and they buy
there are they do they want Merlot do
they want
um sauvignon blanc those are the people
that really want that craft cannabis and
I think both of those models can exist
and will exist because you're going to
have flower smokers and you're going to
have people that want to take a pill and
go to sleep and they're two different
consumers well it could be the same
consumer but they're two different
experiences
and God do we have a time for
this question that was just asked is is
a nice setup for what I was trying to
understand uh by the way my name is
Bernie sucher and I'm with Essence
investment which is a cannabis holding
based in Switzerland
um I liked very much David you're
nomenclature for
um for cannabis and
it clarifies things very uh you know
very nicely
but I was wondering if if the panel
could
using that nomenclature look forward a
little bit at on and kind of map the
supply chain that you and Bob both
referenced
um what are we going to be looking at if
we follow that logic from that
nomenclature and what are the business
models that as an investor and as
advisors you you see developing it it
suggests that at least for my first
glance
that most of the capital in North
America certainly has gone into the
wrong kind of business model
Rob yeah absolutely so
um I think that going back to my comment
previews for culture versus
commercialization you know when I look
at a plan I look at an ingredient
delivery system I look at a widget that
can manufacture compounds that I can
then isolate to formulate new
therapeutic kinesuticals where the
illicit culture grower the protector of
the plant sees something that they
whisper to and that is sacred and
frankly that's just not the case so what
we need to do is look at intentional
cultivation and crop steering strategies
in order to manifest certain compounds
out of these cultivars that are
chemotypic as opposed to looking at the
color or the aroma now I'm not saying
terpenes aren't important we all know
the Ensemble effect not necessarily the
Entourage effect of synergistic
compounds we've seen it done in
over-the-counter and in prescription
medication
but in going back to the previous
question as well I think that you know
Pharma is very successful because they
start with the patient and work their
way back cannabis starts with the plant
and works their way forward and so it's
not really the same process and because
of that it's falling short in delivering
True Value in a medicinal aspect so I
think that in terms of the Optics and
how you look at a process to give a
guarantee for the lifetime of the
payback over the patient over the
investor over the physician and over
that relationship it needs to start with
the patient first and not necessarily
with the plant going forward
agree more and one of the things I've
said repeatedly is we are seeing this
explosion of marketing Bliss sleep calm
because the marketing people recognize
when they do their consumer
research the people are buying the
effect that they want but it's a
disingenuous if you start with the
patient first you might smoke weed that
makes you horny it might put me to sleep
because we have a different
endocannabinoid system and that is a
fact because you're a woman well you
know then there's that on top of it
right
I always use that because I think a lot
of men buy cannabis that says Bliss
because they're hoping they give it to
their woman and something will change
but
we're buying an effect and we cannot
deliver that effect where every one of
us takes ibuprofen and it gets rid of
our headache that doesn't work like that
with just the plant so if we start with
the patient forward what we really need
is individualized medicine because
cannabinoids are individualized or you
have to use the ingredients in a way
that you can deliver that consistent
effect right now we haven't figured it
out it goes back to the lab testing it
goes back to knowing what we're doing
like you say it's biotech we're going to
get that Innovation from biotech but I I
will really maybe I'll you know in the
history animals 100 years from now
they're going to say I'm an idiot but I
really honestly think that that consumer
that loves the experience of smoking
purple flower or the smell of limonene
that's not going away either we know
that the majority of people who smoke
cannabis smoke flour it's still the
biggest percentage of the industry but I
think in terms of making money for
investors we've got to be looking more
at the pharmaceutical model so Bernie to
answer your question I I don't know that
there's a right answer for how supply
chain is going to work but I think if
Rob's point is accurate and if in North
America where we got to be shot out of
the cannon had we chosen a
pharmaceutical model we would have a
happier investors today two things real
quick uh with regards to the supply
chain uh is I think anybody would agree
that knows cannabis whether it's a phyto
source or a synthetic or chemistry or
whatever the the method that produces
the highest quality molecule at the
cheapest price is going to win out
whatever that is what and actually if
you guys stick around you know we have a
panel this afternoon in science and one
on cultivation where it's going to be
cultivated I think we're going to answer
both those one last thing is to Jamie's
Point there's a lot of genetics aspects
to this that we really haven't looked
into because everybody metabolizes these
molecules differently and my wife will
be the first one to tell you but I think
we're almost out of time but Bob did you
have any closing comments uh just what
we have time what's the future hold
um as I see it
um I mean formulations or formulations
supply chain wise cannabinoids the plant
is a treasure Trove of ingredients if
you think of it that way it's a treasure
Trove of ingredients what you take off
of the plant and you put into a
formulation that's the supply chain so
how does that transition into the
pharmaceutical World well that's
formulations based on specific
conditions run through clinical trial
processes which are available in
multiple countries around the world when
you look at over-the-counter cannabis
which again is sort of that current
European medical model it's not
sustainable because it doesn't jive with
ultimately FDA standards and where the
FDA is going to go with this
unfortunately and I'm not saying the FDA
is a great agency but it's an agency
that unfortunately is lauded around the
world and its standards will have
influence on how this shakes out going
forward so from an FDA standpoint it's
going to be isolated compounds created
formulations and those formulations from
a pharmaceutical perspective will treat
conditions but over-the-counter cannabis
supply chain that relies on flour and
extracts from that flower and what's the
future hold I mean we saw Germany's sort
of reversal of course with the adult use
program focusing more on medical that's
actually an interesting thing because
you never really needed adult use you
needed a more liberal medical model that
masqueraded as an adult use program
because of over-the-counter flour when
Colorado as an example had 100
000 patients registered it became a
commercial adult use system even though
it was called a medical system because
it had a severe pain catch-all Clause
that is a quasi-adult use system that
from an investment perspective it's
what's happening in Europe so instead of
saying let's go open up adult use
dispensaries and supply chain across
Germany and across Europe they're saying
well no let's invest in the medical
model and create a looser medical model
because it's really not a medical model
it's over-the-counter cannabis model
whereas the medical models of
formulation model that's not the end-all
be-all but that's my perspective on it
well the medical model allows them to
skirt the EU rules
to the world because right you have a
Social Club you have 500 patients you're
growing for them patience and then I go
buy my 25 grams of cannabis and I go
sell it to my buddy because that's
what's actually going to happen I mean
we know this from the Colorado model the
minute you have all of these social
clubs open up you basically and by the
way they also decriminalize possession
which means now I can sell you or you
know the selling is illegal but we know
it's going to happen right
give I'm going to sell you my lighter
and give you cannabis with it that's
what we also saw going on in Oregon and
everywhere else uh for sure do we have
time or
I have much more one comment regarding
we are discussing currently the
recreational medical way but what I'm
missing is that we have a lack of
knowledge about the plant and as long as
we are not solving this knowledge and
understanding how do we stabilize the
Genome of the plant how do we stabilize
our production that we have batch
consistency how we are defining what are
our deed compounds inside of the
Cannabis we will never come to a way
that we have really a standardized
reproducible product and as long as we
are not stabilizing this once we are
running in the situation that we have a
product which does not fulfill what the
market wants to see that's that work is
actually being that work is being done
um you probably know the most about that
but we absolutely have that now we're
definitely starting to see it on a more
macro scale which is very refreshing
because right now businesses need to be
more focused on what their brand benefit
ladder is starting with your product
attribute from there what the patient
benefit is and then from there what the
product benefit is and then the
emotional benefit and so if we actually
start to look at honing in on those four
different levels of the brand benefit
ladder and then in terms of intentional
cultivation and crop steering
Environmental Management AG Tech and
data analytics these need to be valued
in business plans and they are starting
to do so because it's no longer
acceptable for someone to anecdotally
say how therapeutically effective this
may be patients need medicine that is
predictable that is measurable that is
convenient that they want to take
patient compliance on these products is
very important too we've seen it in
pharmaceutical models which is why we
have flavonoids which is why we have
different form factors for people to be
able to achieve the therapeutic results
that they want cannabis is now starting
to embrace it because they're realizing
especially in markets like Colorado
that's very very old or Washington and
California those models are drying up
and they're not as attractive for
investment they're not as interactive
for scalability and so they're now
starting to pay a 10 attention to that
in some of our newer models like in
Pennsylvania where they had a clinical
registrant license where you partnered
with the university we're seeing
Academia start to embrace more in the
research and the development of these
products as well unafraid of federal
prosecution or lack of funding which is
where we're starting to see that
opportunity Gap filter you're absolutely
right that this gets back to my original
point about the biological supply chain
does not get enough respect so for
example if you really know about
cannabis it is very dependent on all
kinds of growth conditions CO2
temperature moisture humidity more than
that right it's a very sensitive plan
which if you vary any of those you can
have a different terpene and cannabinoid
profile the other thing that's
interesting if you know Jeff raber who's
one of the leading Chemists in the world
out of Southern California he's done
tests where you take the same Keem of
our cultivar whatever you want to call
it and concentrate it down in two
different process same process whether
it's ethanol butane and you end up
giving getting different ratios of the
cannabinoids and terpenes with the same
team of Art so this gets back to my
original thing that I've been saying for
years when people are trying to
establish Brands brands are built on
consistent quality right that's what
Coke made their name on and as your
point brings up it's hard to have a very
good brand when you can't control the
consistency and the quality of what
you're doing there's not enough respect
and you have a good point that's what we
need to do but
uh it's interesting we're sorry we're
talking about pharmaceuticals
Pharmaceuticals Pharmaceuticals what's
blowing my mind in the U.S right now and
also in Europe is this th legal THC
coming out of hemp and that goes back to
Bob's point that you can grow hemp for
600 an acre and if you do that and you
are extracting things from the plant
then you can formulate those molecules
exactly the same every single time so
when we start seeing the the legal THC
coming out of hemp I think we're going
to see an explosion of the University
testing and all the things that we need
to have that consistency for the Brand's
sake the only thing I was going to say
is this is not my perspective but this
is a perspective of many of my clients
dare I say the plants don't matter what
I mean by that I I'm not saying that
that's what I'm saying what I'm saying
is the the composition of the plant
doesn't matter because you're extracting
a compound you're isolating it and
you're creating formulations based
thereon it doesn't matter what plant
those compounds come from this isn't my
perspective this is something that's
prevalent so so I'm not saying the plant
doesn't matter but that's the future is
all I need is an isolated
kilo or liter of
CBD and then I create a formulation
based thereon that is is unfortunately I
think the future uh okay guys do you
have a question yes I do have a question
my question is so you're saying the
future is just pills and chemicals and
extractions and the future is not the
plants on the Pharma side not the
over-the-counter cannabis side where we
talked about terroir and yeah I mean and
that's the thing too and my other thing
too was like is it possible like you
said expanding so you're saying uh you
know a set of colleges uh uh adult use
thing it's a medical cancer dispensary
which I think is a great idea and you
can use that you can use the analytics
and the people who buy the things and
you can do surveys because I know a lot
of people who keep especially in the
early days who kept like a weed Journal
oh I smoke blue dream and this is how it
made me feel I smoked OG Kush and this
is how I felt about it and you can use
analytics to really get a feel for it
and the problem of course we've all
talked about it is a different uh the
same strain will affect two different
people too differently and also you give
two Growers
the same cultivar and you will get two
different results just because of all
the things so I think sometimes we have
to leave space for magic and not always
rely on this is how we got here on
strictness and this is how we got here
so anyway if you have a few more closing
things we'll go to the second I don't
know but thank you that's a good point
and
I understand it too uh you know
especially here in Germany where
everything must be so
oh no I guess we're out of time yeah
we're out of time oh man that was fast
let's hear it again for our fantastic
panel David trailer Rob McAvoy Jamie
Pearson Robert Hoban
[Applause]