hello everyone
I'm going to go ahead and have uh these
gentlemen introduce themselves we'll
start with um Dan Daniel
Heyman I'm from Zurich Switzerland I'm a
lawyer in a mid-sized Law Firm
specializing in corporate commercial law
and cannabis law health
and product regulations
I'm in the supervisory Board of cadify
AG as well as a CEO of midi orbers a
online publisher with a big reach in
cannabis topics
yeah hello everyone glad to be here it's
Benedict from kanzativa I'm in the
Cannabis space for over six years right
now founded the company together with my
brother Jacob for those who are not
familiar with kansativa our vision is to
enable cannabis and we're building the
largest cannabis platform in Europe and
we're offering the most desirable
products and brands at the moment
Distributing over 300 kg of product into
German pharmacies on a monthly base and
we are the exclusive partner for the
distribution of cannabis from domestic
cultivation
hi my name is Constantine vanagrub I'm
the co-founder managing director of
demekon and we're one of those companies
that are producing medical cannabis in
Germany and handed over to Benedict's
team to have it then distributed to
pharmacies you just served my co-founder
speak Cornelius Maura who's now on our
board and I'm still running the company
mostly focusing on the public affairs
division right now and have a close look
at what the regulation will do about
medical cannabis and about Recreation
campus in Germany I'm glad to be here
with all of you
thank you guys
um I guess we'll just Dive Right In um
so
what do you guys think is going to be
the driving force for the European
markets in one to three years and I know
that's not necessarily uh I mean we
could look out six months and have a
very different conversation right so
well
um
you want to go ahead and yeah sure one
one to three years is a long time right
now the next three months will I think
be very crucial for Germany because
that's when we'll actually see the draft
law on the new cannabis regulation and
that will
um apply both to medical cannabis and
recreational Cannabis there will be a
recur recreational Cannabis scheme we
heard Peter from Denton's talk about the
two pillars of all of that but we'll
also see an amendment of the medical
cannabis world and that will have will
have a tremendous effect on how the
market will look like in the next one to
three years and I have a very positive
attitude towards what is coming because
we'll see two things I think in the
German Medical Market one is a
reclassification of medical cannabis
from a narcotic down to a regular RX
medicine that will make access much
easier for patients and prescription
much easier for doctors and we'll see a
market increase of the medical cannabis
Market
and the second element is I believe that
we'll see more domestic production of
medicinal cannabis in Germany and that's
good obviously for demican but also for
other players who want to enter the
market of cultivating cannabis in
Germany
so with this positive attitudes I think
we'll see a positive development also
for the next one to three years
I actually couldn't agree more
especially the reclassification or
rescheduling of cannabis as a
non-narcotic would be a real game
changer that would be also accelerator
for the whole commercial Market of
cannabis and in particular for medical
cannabis if you ask me I could imagine
there could be a 5x on a addressable
Market
maybe not in three months but rather in
like two or three years I think this can
be very likely and shifts also the whole
discussion and the focus on the medical
Market because of course adult use
legalization it's all that we want but
at the moment let's face this we're
talking in the first pillar about a
non-commercial home grow approach and
cannabis Social Clubs approach so the
second part of this first pillar which
is the reclassification is probably the
game changer and can give the whole
industry a lot of momentum so I'm also
very positive about that
having a look at Europe
um we we are also looking at the UK and
Poland
we can see some traction
um gaining in Switzerland
and we also have a lot of small
countries for example Malta
um who are not so interesting in terms
of their population size however they
are also pushing
um
the the front line of of legalization
um a little bit more forward so I think
in the next one two three years we will
see a lot of markets opening in the
medical field
we will see as my colleagues outlined
them a a very easy process of
prescribing medical cannabis in Germany
thus a strong growth I mean
it is still one of the
biggest growth potentials
in Europe
and so yeah I'm looking very much
forward to the next years because I
think there is not that many markets
that actually have the potential of a
two-digit growth rate
I actually fully agree with your last
point this huge growth of potential
people are asking me if I'm a if I'm
pessimistic or optimistic a pessimist is
an optimist with experience so I'm still
an optimist though because I really
think in the medical markets and Peter
mentioned it before the bottleneck is
really getting doctors to prescribe
medical cannabis and to remove the
boundaries which are plentiful we can
speak about this in more detail but the
medical Market really is kicking off and
in Switzerland where I'm from
most barriers regulatory barriers where
you require the special permit to get
cannabis from the federal Office of
Public Health has been removed and every
doctor can prescribe it but most doctors
don't know how when why they need
education and we need to tackle that
problem first and foremost and when it
comes to other markets like the
recreational Market
their true three months is a long time
but at the same time it isn't I think
it's going to take much much longer and
when we see the developments here in
Germany which unfortunately have taken a
very sour turn from my perspective we're
going to see a similar situation in
Switzerland unless the government is
going to be a very Innovative and very
um courageous which I doubt they will be
so I think on wreck side we're going to
have to sit it out for quite a long time
to see any reasonable commercialization
possibility that could scale
so going back to that
um do you think
which European nation is sort of
positioned to sort of have success in
that short period of time like 18 months
or so do you think it's going to be the
ones that are more open or do you think
it's going to be
um
the question is how do you define
success you know are you targeting
medical cannabis so countries are
removing for example cannabis from the
narcotics act apparently in Germany is
going that direction that's going to
have a direct impact on how cannabis is
prescribed may may be really release or
remove some of the barriers make it more
accessible that's for me a huge and very
important step
by the way also it's a blurry line
recreational and and medical so there's
a question how far can you stretch the
medical definition
and then when you're speaking about
recreational
I think really Switzerland is pretty
good spot at the moment I would say
um I don't think it's the number one
mover but we have pilot projects that
are going on in Switzerland already for
a while and I think the structure and
the setup of these projects have been
very carefully designed and could be a
very good base to scale throughout
Germany
I think one thing you said is a very
important to notice that's the question
how far can you stretch the definition
of medical cannabis and once Germany
reclassifies cannabis from a narcotic to
an RX I think we can stretch the
definition of medical cannabis very very
very far and then yes we can keep
talking about the recreational Market
but that will essentially be just the
home Growers Market maybe cultivation
associations it will be a very small
portion of the market I think for the
foreseeable future and expanded and much
broader definition of medical cannabis
will be the thing we see in Germany and
that's what makes what will make Germany
the go-to place for cannabis I think and
also and that might be interesting for
you also for international companies
because as my co-founder canis has
pointed out in a medical Market Imports
will probably still be possible so
that's good news for the international
cannabis industry
and I think uh just adding to that I
think there will always be a certain
amount of cannabis consumers that
actually want a medical product in terms
of
um Purity in terms of safety and in in
terms of cleanness and then quality
oh and I don't know where to jump to
next
um oh we could talk about quality
because I I I heard people from South uh
South Africa in the panel I heard a
couple of guys from Colombia and we
discussed Imports and imports are going
to be as I said they will remain a
factor but you guys have to focus on
quality and right now we see a couple of
products in the market for some reason
they magically got a EU GMP
certification over like kind of tested
into EU GMP in Germany but quality is
going to matter I think we also see a
price compression right now in the
market so now the debate is going to
what's going to happen in the medical
cannabis market like what will Define
good quality and what will the role be
of price and I'm sure Benedict you have
a very good oversight that being one of
the large importers here I I really
agree on that so there are just those
two streams that can be successful clear
quality differentiation or focus on
price
um
quite a few companies right now and this
is also what happens and it's also part
of how the industry currently works is
that a bunch of
companies in the first half of this year
get bankrupt right so they're out of
business they sourced the wrong products
that they can't market so it's also
important that you understand what kind
of products you're sourcing why you're
sourcing them and to whom you're selling
them and I believe
using quality product is probably not a
bad approach but on the other hand we're
struggling a little bit when it comes to
the market size at least for the last 12
months we are talking rather about 10
maybe 20 percent market growth compared
to very very high growth in the past so
the situation that we might be faced
that we have a reclassification of
cannabis will really trigger again a lot
of momentum into the market a lot of new
players might try to access the market
we might get a whole new
competition in the market but I also
believe that those that are in the
market already that have established
Supply chains that have also low-cost
sourcing Supply chains in place and
quality Supply chains they have a pretty
much Head Start compared to all the
others
and I think if it comes to
differentiation it's not only important
to have actually products that can
differentiate but also to let the market
know it right and in Germany especially
in the in the medical market and we
figured out that it it's not enough to
tell all the patients you you got to
have the doctors the Pharmacists and the
patients
so I think it'll be increment
incremental important for um companies
within the next one to three years to
actually have a proper marketing
approach
and maybe just one one uh remark to that
and there is a lot of potential to
actually execute on marketing if we have
a reclassification of cannabis because
that's also important right now it's
narcotic so as an industry we're very
very limited about
addressing any other people than doctors
and Pharmacists and if it's a
non-narcotic there are at least
easier ways to talk more open and more
public about those things and I totally
agree education information marketing uh
will be very important things and also
here other countries can hopefully look
into the German market and maybe learn
adapt do things smarter better than we
do right now as a narcotic we have faced
a very limited system when it comes to
marketing
just a few thoughts on on price
sensitivity to Quality
I think if if you take a step back and
you look at the medical markets the
question is also what kind of delivery
forms are we looking at and where is the
trend going because this increase this
extreme sensitivity mostly applies I
would say to cannabis flower but when
you're looking at cannabis extracts or
even some products that may in the
future be synthesized that may also find
their way into the medical Market these
small differences whether you produce at
150 or two bucks or three it just
doesn't matter because the price points
are completely different
uh point so I think it's really
important to also take these Trends into
consideration
and when we're speaking about a certain
addressable Market in the in the in the
medical space especially when you say we
can stretch at some stage the definition
of what medical cannabis is you also
have to uh put this thought into the mix
and think about
um maybe for a certain specific product
that just use biomass and that it just
doesn't matter
um how much it costs and maybe also
there the quality you know that the
preservation of the bud and the drying
and all of that is just not it's on a
different level there's a there's a
difference different importance to it
yeah well I would I would say that the
U.S saw that I mean price
is compress
um drastically for for certain regions
right they just it was
it was three thousand dollars a pound
and it went down to below 600 so which
sort of drives to the points of
where is that production going to come
from right but that's for a different
topic but
so sort of going back do you guys think
that how important is the
U.N single convention going to be to the
cut the countries in Europe that are
looking into this
I think that the UN single convention is
um The go-to Authority here uh and that
is not because of it it's a U.N
convention but it's been adapted into
European legislation so it's EU law and
that's quite binding for
um for Germany and that is why if we
ever see a recreational Market will not
have Imports into the market not because
it makes sense economically I totally
agree with this the guy who asked the
question from South Africa saying like
doesn't Colombia doesn't it make sense
to produce somewhere somewhere else
where it's much more affordable of
course it would make sense but the
regulation just doesn't allow it so
always be mindful of where the
regulation goes because this Market is
not driven only by economics I would say
it's mostly driven by the regulation and
the UN convention is something that even
the the German legislator is bound to so
we have to like abide by it
um maybe in addition to that at the same
time the draft bill or the pillars that
are now discussed totally reflect that
right so we are already in a position
where the legislator and the regulator
understands not only the U.N single
convention but includes them into all
the discussions so for me it's more like
do we like it or don't we like it it
doesn't really matter because it is
already integrated in the the political
discussion over already like two cycles
of those kind of uh papers that were
published in October and March so and
and uh April I think so we have to
accept that maybe in the long run if we
think about global economy about Global
Supply chains there might be
the possibility four example Imports
however we're talking rather about a
decade or two decades but not about the
near to midterm right I think we'll see
that faster Germany is trying and they
have now figured out a way to like abide
by the convention and still go forward
with cannabis regulation the Netherlands
has started a model project uh Czech
Republic is eager I only kind of see
maybe a couple of Eastern European
States and France kind of opposed once
they see the economic benefit for
Germany from the Cannabis new cannabis
regulation I think they'll all join
together and we'll see EU regulation for
for cannabis medical and recreational
and that's more like a five year maybe
five years away from now
yeah I think it'll take at least five
years because currently there is no
majority for for European League
legislation on cannabis
um in terms of legalization so
um yeah I I think we are we are stuck
with the current situation
and we'll have to make the best out of
it
maybe just to to clarify I was very much
referring to a global supply chain
um in general I I would definitely agree
it can be a harmonized system how
whatever it looks like
rather than like five years then in 20
years so just to clarify
and we have to keep telling the
regulator because it's kind of
ridiculous that it's still the
prohibition going on especially for
medical cannabis it's so ridiculous
we're losing so much money people are
consuming cannabis anyways I don't know
who of you has been to Berlin last
weekend at the Mary Jane conference
right you have an impression that there
is already a full-scale recreational
Cannabis Mark going on right it's
happening it's there in the draft
legislation the person who drafted this
this first draft law she writes that uh
one or two out of four Germans have
consumed cannabis in the last 30 days
right they are aware we're all smoking
they're all smoking right it's
ridiculous that we still have this
prohibition so we all need to have a
concerted approach let's push the
regulator to accept realities and come
up with a smart regulation to make the
situation better by controlling the
quality and by you know by by
controlling the access not by
prohibition right
[Applause]
Daniel you
I fully agree
[Laughter]
start here we'll go there we'll go there
oh hey guys well it's me again
well um I'm an agronomist uh I did my my
PhD in physiology and I've been working
in the Cannabis space for the past six
years you know knowing the plant and see
how we can grow it better and cheaper
I've faced two
problems during my time in cannabis
um one a lot of prejudices from Cannabis
coming from South America and Colombia
and to lack of knowledge
the first one is the biggest one
and is what you mention uh Constantine
and it's like people believe that
because we grow cannabis at a lower
price it has no good quality
that is a huge mistake
you know there are several reasons why
we grow cannabis chipper and it's
because hand labor in our countries is
cheaper unfortunately second our land is
cheaper right and our wages for good
professionals like myself are not as
high as in Europe and other parts of the
world
so please take away that prejudice and
that cannabis that is cheaper is poor
quality that is completely mistaken I
can invite you to my growing facilities
in Colombia you can see my facilities
they are completely IMC gacp certified
BNC right Israel Market you know and
we need to do a better close-up so now
my question is why don't we take such
opportunities
to put this into a legislation you know
from you again as I said before you guys
are here in the legislation making why
don't you put this up and try to bring
it into consideration and just try to
accommodate and foreign you know company
that is doing a good job into your needs
thank you
maybe I I take that so first of all
things for the for the
um yeah your view on quality and price I
would also like to comment on that but
regarding your question
not only us but many others in the
industry lobbied probably the last 24
months or 18 months for Global Supply
chains on adult use cannabis
a lot of us did so but we need to accept
right now that the regulator and the
legislator is not in favor of that at
the moment and it's not that uh I don't
want to fight I don't want to continue
the fight but I also have to choose the
right fights that I I want to have right
and right now we're very close to have a
draft bill that might be presented to
the Parliament and this is huge this is
huge for us as industry this is huge for
Germany is huge for Europe and I believe
going down this route even if it means
we need to start with a non-commercial
home grow and cannabis club set up
uh with only locally produced homegrown
cannabis well I take that if it helps us
to come to the next step where we have a
huge medical commercially addressable
Market
uh which you could serve with your
facilities so I believe it's very
important that you need to understand we
tried to Lobby into this direction but
we also need to accept that doing the
right thing now is more important for
all of us for the industry than like
optimizing in the very very short term
on a specific singular question so
that's that's my my view here and with
regards to Quality and price I agree
yeah that can be cheap product at great
quality we definitely need to
differentiate is it indoor grown what is
the microbio what is the butt size like
all those things that we consider as a
high quality product and if there is a
cultivator in a low-cost country that
can produce those products in high
quality yeah they have probably the
great things that that should come to
the German Market
I would like to uh make one more comment
I really think the potential size of the
medical Market cannot be underestimated
and the reality is that in Switzerland
for example today when we're speaking
about the medical Market there's been
some estimates where the federal Office
of Public Health says that maybe there's
500 000 people consuming cannabis or
three to four hundred thousand people
consuming cannabis on a regular basis
out of eight nine million population and
a hundred thousand of these patients are
self-medicating patients but it doesn't
take into account for example five
percent of the Swiss population
that's not an official s that's just
inofficial estimates that are consuming
opioids on a regular basis
most of these patients could for example
they they could hugely benefit from
substituting opioids with uh with
medical cannabis
um
and that's just the in absolute terms
that's not in relative term so whole
Swiss population five percent so the
adult population probably even higher
there is so much potential there still
that we haven't been able to explore and
in that market cross-border trade is
absolutely open
and it's not something we really have to
keep in mind
thank you uh yeah uh we're gonna keep
going I just want to remind people in
the interest of time because a lot of
people have questions let's try to get
to the question quickly uh and we don't
always need the whole history uh behind
it okay thank you
all right so quick summary we are a GMP
producer in Spain we pay very close
attention to what's going on in the
Spanish Market where they have in the
government has a subcommittee they've
asked the regulatory body to produce
um guidance but it's been slow moving my
question is uh are you aware we've
talked a lot about Germany uh are you
aware of
um or can you highlight other countries
where maybe it's moved Beyond public
advocacy to actual deliberation
um in governments that could be some of
the next markets in Europe
um
I think a special interest should have
France I mean they're they're finishing
their budget in 2024 and and you due to
the sheer size of their population they
actually have the potential of
um being at least the second biggest
Market in Europe
um furthermore we as a company are
looking at UK Switzerland and Poland
however Poland is a little bit more
tricky in terms of Regulation
and um yeah so there is there's multiple
uh countries that actually
um are gaining traction
I thank you so yeah
um I was hearing Daniel saying that
um the definition of
uh of other products like extract could
be something that could have a big
importance also in the recreational
market so can you please elaborate also
maybe also uh Constantine what's your
view on the idea that there is at the
moment a threshold for THC potency while
eventually the best approach would be to
regulate more on the quantity and
therefore extract that could be
concentrated form could eventually be
favorite
on that regard thank you so I think in
the medical Market extracts will be a
winner midterm for sure all the doctors
we talked to I'd say 80 prefer extract
over flour
um so that's a no-brainer you just have
to come up with a stable formulation a
good product that can be uh delivered
sustainably so that's that's no-brainer
on the recreational Cannabis Market I'm
a little more skeptical
um because if you look at the consumers
uh reaction I think um in Behavior they
prefer the flour they like Edibles and
other other form factors but not so much
accurate extracts like as they are
applied in the medic medicinal market
and Edibles and so on that won't be
allowed in the near future and even with
extracts I'm kind of skeptical that this
will be allowed it would require another
level of Education towards the regulator
and we'll be happy if we have like
educated them enough on flowers so that
they will allow that so more skeptical
about the recreational Market definitely
a winner midterm in the medical Market
maybe let me add some some further uh
figures on the the extracts market right
now the total medical cannabis Market is
like 60 flowers around about 20 extracts
another 20
um isolates which is dronabinal mainly
um we see that the flowers market is
super patient driven we have again a lot
of self-players in that market some say
30 other say 80 it might be somewhere in
between and the extracts is pretty much
doctors driven and at the same time once
you have a
patient that uses a certain extract you
see that the quote or that it is
re-prescribed is very high compared to
the flowers market where we have a lot
of switching patients and from like a
pure Revenue perspective as a company
that offers those products yes I totally
agree extracts it's pretty interesting
especially especially when a lot of
maybe patient-driven people in like
really the future might go out of the
medical Market because they go for home
growing or get another product adult use
product to substitute that so it's a
very relevant category which is at the
moment pretty underestimated and also
you shouldn't underestimate the fact
that there's a most for example
neuropathic pain patients are in a
multi-medication setup it's not just a
single
you don't substitute five medications
with medical cannabis you continue to
take various various medication plus
cannabis and it's so much easier to
titrate
extracts than than having someone inhale
or even smoke a bud
okay
all right good morning
um I'm a producer in Argentina and also
in Colombia so and and this last point
is really what my my main interest is I
don't know if you guys are aware but uh
Argentina has a brand new cannabis law
industrial cannabis law on the table for
the president to sign
and we did my company did a lot of Lobby
into that new law
and
one of the things that we're going to
see very soon is a new threshold of THC
on Industrial Hemp
all of a lot of the countries in South
America are going to allow one percent
THC as a threshold
and also Argentina in particular which
is a very large agriculture country with
a lot of experience in large Agro
operations
we are going to allow up to 2.5 percent
with uh lab remediation
right so if you go over the threshold
you can go to the an extraction lab and
just produce an extract from biomass
and my question because I'm
I'm an investor also and I wanna we're
trying to figure out whether we should
be setting up a GMP uh flower drawing
facility or just a lab for extraction my
question is what do you think is going
to happen to this Market when good
quality extracts will come from you know
at a price of what happened in the US
with the CBD that was used to be a
couple thousand dollars uh a kilogram
and today it's only 300 is there is
there a place for in this market for
extracts that are cheap and what's going
to happen to the flower market if you
can buy a gram of extract 98 THC for the
same price as a gram of flour
I think it highly depends on the market
segment so um if you talk about medical
extracts you always need a doctor to
prescribe it right so as a as a foreign
company you should probably have some
some local partner that actually has a
network
that is able to educate and and and talk
to doctors right
um if you import flour
um I I don't think that it works just
just to put a flower damn cheap on the
German market and and and it will will
be sold uh initial yeah instantly I
think
um it is not that easy anymore in the
German Market but Benedict how do you
see this yeah maybe just one uh remark
here what you've mentioned is already
in a smaller scale reality in the market
to it to be honest we have flowers I
know five 400 different products in the
market or 200 I really don't know
already although we have all of them uh
the extracts we have a lot of different
suppliers we have one that is very much
leading the whole segment with over 50
market share and we have already pretty
low cost full spectrum extracts
available and at the same time we also
have
dronabinol isolates uh so to say also
available in the market so we already
see that a patient and a doctor would
have a choice of prescribing a gram of
flour or a equivalent of extract
dronabinol whatever but at the end it's
at the moment a very much
yeah patient focused thing what helps
the patient best what's the right
application form what is also maybe the
need that the patient has and right now
it ends up at the the
um yeah split that I've mentioned 60
one last
cannabis is the only medicine that
people uh really enjoy the side effects
one one last brief comment I hear a lot
of people from
an applaud to that one last comment like
if the entire world wants to cultivate
for Germany we will have an oversupply
even in Germany it's only 80 million
right we are the large will be the
largest cannabis Market but not large
enough for the entire world so please
guys also work with your governments
with your Regulators I'd love to see it
open up in our lives you know I'd love
to see you open up in Colombia right
let's make this a global cannabis
industry fantastic we are actually over
time let's hear it again for the panel
it's very fantastic
thank you