thanks everybody uh let me kick it off
so if you weren't here earlier uh I'm
David Traylor senior managing director
of golden eagle partners
uh World lead sponsor here because we're
a lead sponsor at benzinga in Miami can
Med earlier as you just to make sure
everybody knows we're the first
Investment Bank in the US to do cannabis
we've been doing it over seven years
internationally and I have 15 years
operational experience two undergrad
degrees in science through U.S patents
and certainly we've been we've had
cannabis clients on six of the seven
continents Peter
thank you David so I've been in the
Cannabis industry for eight years
focused in the United States I was a
managing director at a private Equity
Fund called MacArthur Capital we were
involved in different M A's for the past
year the past eight years we've seen the
highs and the lows and and it's it's a
very intriguing Market to now be in
Europe we are headquartered in
Switzerland we are a vertically
integrated pharmaceutical cannabis
company that primarily focuses on
genetics and Manufacturing as well as
Trading so import export
thank you
hello
um I started Distributing Medical and
Abyss to patients 27 years ago
so I was the first medical cannabis
distributor in Canada just after the
operations in California started I
started delivering cannabis with a
bicycle and a pager and a backpack it
was even before the days of flip phones
we essentially built a movement in
Canada focused on patient advocacy
physician education working with our
Regulators working with the public and
transformed Canada's perception of
cannabis we dragged our government
Kicking and Screaming through the courts
until we created a federal framework for
medical cannabis when the first 12 large
licenses were given out I moved from my
civilly disobedient activist Queen of
the rebels role and started working in
the corporate world I started working
with bedrocan and eventually became the
first female member of the c-suite of
canopy growth you know canopy growth has
since somewhat gone through a bit of a
decline so I have lived through the
Revolution and the legalization and the
ups and downs and now Canada is very
much in a market Recovery Place and I
look forward to sharing some insights
about that experience with you
thanks Hillary uh Louis Koski I've been
involved in the Cannabis industry since
uh roughly 2009 full-time uh did some
work in it prior to that almost entirely
on the government side of the equation
so I bring that government perspective
probably most notably I was the director
of the Colorado marijuana enforcement
division in
2013 going into 2014 when we first
legalized cannabis there so I was
largely responsible for leading the
teams that drafted the first several
rounds of regulations is also a subject
matter expert to our legislatures our to
our to the state legislature where we
kind of reported uh how we were
progressing with our implementation
since that time I have had a small
consulting firm that or had me traveling
around the US and Canada sometimes here
in Europe in the Caribbean helping
governments kind of grapple with more
permissive cannabis policy see they
helped design that for them and then I
started with metric which is a leading
seed to sale tracking software company
that contracts with 23 different
government agencies to provide track and
Trade Services for government and
Industry to create transparent Supply
chains
hello my name is Steve winiker I'm based
in Toronto I work at Canon Court genuity
I'm a managing director of the
investment banking group canacord is a
medium-sized Global Investment Bank I
lead the um the uh the Cannabis practice
globally I started raising money for
North America Canadian cannabis
companies in 2018 and 2019 I started
raising money for U.S companies since
then our practice has raised uh about
seven billion dollars for cannabis
companies in North America and we've
advised on about 20 billion dollars of M
A transactions so we have a a pretty
good track record most of that happened
prior to the last 12 months as a matter
of fact all of it happened probably the
last 12 months it's been quiet the last
12 months
I'm not
thanks Steve so if you look at the the
title of this uh
section that we're talking about and if
you're here when I kick things off this
morning
we like to we're trying to look and
change the nomenclature THC plus THC
minus otherwise known as marijuana
versus hemp so certainly we can cover
both of those uh not just the marijuana
side as far as Lessons Learned From the
U.S but I think what we want to do is
again this is not a moderated panel we
want to kick it off with one question
we'll go through that and we can
certainly kick it to the audience to go
to questions to you guys make it more
interactive so Peter's starting off uh
what do you think are that the three
Lessons Learned again whether you want
to talk of the framework on the THC plus
THC minus side from what you learn the
three things from North America weather
is Canada U.S
well since we're going to open it up I'm
going to keep it high level but I think
that being involved in building a good
regulatory platform is is um is one of
the best opportunities that a lot of
these Global markets have it's something
that in the U.S just in in many states
absolutely I mean they did not support
the businesses that were that were
building
um I would say that the early stage
valuation of a lot of these companies
were way too high I think that these
companies were focusing on what the
potential Market was not understanding
the Dynamics of how the product was
ultimately going to get to the end user
whether it's a patient or a consumer so
over built
platforms over value overvalued
companies
um I'll stick with those two for now
thanks Peter Hillary
how many minutes can I take you want all
three all in one go yeah well you know
it's uh yeah not 30 minutes okay
um okay so first of all in Canada we
legalized cannabis with a probationist
mentality so in order to sell
legalization to the conservative Law and
Order parts of our government we had to
basically legalize cannabis with the
purpose to reduce the harms of cannabis
my government didn't go so far is to say
let's actually in the legislation
acknowledge the racist history of
cannabis let's actually look at the
policies that America exported around
the world and let's deal with correcting
that from a legislative perspective
and what happened is the stigma that is
based in racism from 100 years of
Prohibition carried through and
permeates our regulatory framework so
cannabis is still treated with way more
stigma than any other industry it's more
highly regulated in many ways than
alcohol and tobacco are it's overtaxed
it's over regulated and my industry in
Canada is being strangled I spent the LA
my entire adult life working to create a
regulatory framework for medical and
recreational cannabis in Canada and
currently the industry is pretty much
devastated in Canada because of the
stigma that permeates the regulatory
framework and in Europe I'm not hearing
any conversations about unpacking the
history of prohibition and ensuring that
we actually create legislation that
addresses the history so that we're not
over regulating over taxing and
basically killing the industry
okay so the second issue is what I'm
seeing in North America and starting to
see around the world is that we're
treating cannabis and cannabis companies
like other any other cpg product
cannabis is not a product that you
simply manufacture and sell to a
consumer moving cannabis from an
unregulated Market into a regulated
market is a massive social shift I'm no
longer really seeing companies invest in
patient education some physician
education still
ensuring that companies are actually
diverse ensuring that there's actually
Community impact social justice work all
of the pieces that actually make your
employers your employees your consumers
and your Regulators actually have
loyalty to you and your company
that's number two ready okay so the
third piece let me check my glasses is
again you talked about
um Fair evaluations right and I want to
talk a little bit about Market
projections so my government projected
that the recreational and medical
cannabis Market was going to be about 12
billion and it's actually four so it's
much much much smaller than what was
predicted
um companies we were over invested in
there was like investment was falling
out of the sky my well my previous
company took in five billion dollars
from constellation Brands there's just
the the SK the the pace of scaling was
absolutely ridiculous so over over
investment over capacity build and now
we have millions of grams of unsold
cannabis in the market because
everything just grew absolutely way too
fast the survivors the people who are
actually starting to be profitable
they're not vertically integrated
they're special realizing they're
smaller they're keeping their overhead
lower and they're actually able to Pivot
quickly to meet the needs of the
patients and the recreational consumers
thanks Hillary very good Louis
that's really good no there's three I
don't know if I'm that structured on
mine but I the one thing I'm like taking
away from what I've heard so far and
kind of like play like can like speaks
to our thinking on this is the
legalization of cannabis is one hell of
a balancing act
um I I on one hand I think the
governance of legalization is really
important so you but but it but having
like too little governance or too little
government interaction isn't great but
having too much government action is
also like can can tend to be pretty
stifling and take away from uh how big
the market can be and how effective
businesses are
um so when you think of it in terms of a
balancing act like one thing that's
important is like getting like getting
government or having government engaged
in a way that is actually supportive of
the industry and I think to a large
extent you know what Hillary was saying
is is spot on and that we we tend to
think of this as like like bringing an
illicit Market into a regulated market
it so we have to be really kind of
heavy-handed with the regulation when in
reality what's really important is once
the decision is made to legalize
cannabis is for government to actually
really engage and collaborate with the
industry to come up with the right
regulations because part of The
Balancing Act is finding regulations
that really genuinely help protect
Public Health in a way that the illicit
Market doesn't but also try and
right-size those to where investment is
possible and that is possible for
businesses to grow and I think it's
really hard for a lot of people to
really get their head wrapped around an
industry that should be designed in such
a way where the businesses can actually
be successful and so I think I think
that's really important and then when
you have the the government like right
sizing the regulations for business then
businesses are actually like more likely
to be super supportive of government so
instead of like the normal regulatory
dynamic or there's this adversarial
relationship between the regulator and
the regulated Community you can actually
tend to like partner a little bit more
and collaborate a little bit more in a
way where products can be safer but
businesses is can be successful and then
I think the third lesson that that we've
learned kind of like on the positive
side is that once you have that that
partnership built up and you have some
trust between those two entities then it
makes it a lot easier to create the the
transparency that's necessary for
government to be able to efficiently
oversee what's happening in the industry
without like again a continually
burdening the businesses with reporting
requirements and
um uh um other like uh uh like uh super
complicated testing regimes and labeling
Pro of products Etc you can really start
to balance that in a way that that is is
beneficial both again to public health
and safety but the of sustainability of
the businesses over the Long Haul
Steve sure so I think it's over
regulation and under regulation
happening at the same time in the same
Market which has been the the curse of a
Canadian and and U.S businesses and I'll
give you a couple of examples so in
Canada
um they're they're at the peak there
were 1200 I think 1200 actual licensed
producers in Canada 1200 for a market
size of four billion dollars uh anybody
who paid five in the province where I'm
from Ontario anyone who paid five
thousand dollars could open a dispensary
so to at the peak there were I think
1400 dispensaries in the province of
Ontario there's eight million people in
that Province the one of the largest
dispensary networks in the country as a
company called fire and flower declared
bankruptcy a couple weeks ago uh the
biggest dispensary Network in Canada a
company called the high tide I think
they they do about half a billion
dollars a year in revenue and they have
yet to to make a profit so I think you
know on the one hand the the there's
there's an under regulation in the
government in that instance the over
regulation I would point to taxes uh
particularly in the United States right
now the uh the the the effective tax
rate marginal tax rate for U.S licensed
producer U.S multi-state operators about
78 76 percent
so how do you have a business that does
a billion to in revenue and forty
percent even down margins but has zero
free cash flow
um I think until some of these kind of
Institutions so that's that's the over
regulation in Canada the same thing with
excise taxes with with uh no uh
transferring across some across
provincial inability to transfer across
provincial lines
um you have an inability for the
Canadian licensed producers to make any
money out of the four billion dollar
market I think there's only the maximum
market share that any one large license
producer in Canada has is five percent I
think it was canopy for a little while
so you have 1200 licensed producers
maximum market share is five percent
seventy eight percent uh tax rate
effective tax rate in the United States
that because of both under uh under
regulation over regulation it's
impossible to make a commercial entity
firm for for for any cannabis producer
in North America yeah
thank you Steve uh so uh as I mentioned
before starting off I want to take this
in two parts first of all talking about
THC plus so as I mentioned I was in
Davos in 2020 before the pandemic shut
things down and in Davos I wanted to
pull three things that I thought we'd
learned in North America and the U.S
that were applicable and going to be
applicable to Europe and frankly I think
they still hold one is there's been very
little history first mover advantage in
this industry as I mentioned I was Chief
business officer Cerna CERN was the
biggest name in cannabis Full Stop in
2014. nobody knows who they are now
right timing
geographies always roll out not always
pretty darn sure most of the time roll
out much slower than you know if you
look at Spain UK
Nevada actually rolled out quickly
Colorado did uh you know but very few
times look at Germany right look at
Portugal everything's been slow the
third thing on the THC plus side is that
fact and you guys may remember hearing
it earlier biological Supply chains are
inherently unstable and whether it's
canopy growth Aurora Harvest you name it
pretty much and that's the thing that's
been an advantage for us is having a
biological biotech background when all
these operators are going from 40 000
square feet of grow to 400 000 we
predicted that it was going to blow up
and it did right so let's get to THC
minus or whether otherwise known as hemp
the problem with that in part of the
sector was the fact that there was very
low bearish to entry so and especially
you saw this in the U.S you had a lot of
people jumping in because there's no
real regulation or anything else like
there was on the THC plus side and then
you as a result had a lot of products
that were low quality and that result in
low barriers low quality resulted in a
ton of noise in the market so as a
result you had a lot of people patients
buying CBD or whatever the product was
mainly CBD and taking it and it doesn't
didn't work right so then you have this
mass of people saying hey this is great
stuff when it works for them and other
people trying bad products and it
wouldn't work so so that was the three
things we learned on the hemp side of
the THC minus but Peter did you have a
comment well I I just want to you know
the the net net is that the illicit
Market is a competitor until this is
properly regulated so it's um you know
you look at Oklahoma which is sure it is
regulated but it's under regulated and
they have over 10 000 licenses that
supports the black market or I'm the
illicit market right so I just think
it's important when you think about
regulation too much too little I I agree
with what the what the entire panelists
have said on on that topic thanks and
okay yeah first question from the panel
so far
um
I think you all make good points I think
I think some of the challenge with
cannabis is that yep is that uh
Regulators want to treat it like it's
yellow cake uranium and not just a weed
plant uh and so they tend to go
overboard
um also I think one of the challenges
too is cannabis has been maybe the most
successful decentralized business in the
world right because of prohibition
nobody
ever wanted to get too big because
that's when the the government will come
after you and so there were a lot of
small farmers who were making a good
wage and making good money and able to
pay their trimmers and able to go to
Thailand uh in the winter after the
Harvest was done uh but now we see in
these forums and and all this investment
everybody wants to monopolize everybody
wants to have 30 of the market share and
I think that that people are really
um
overestimating maybe perhaps or just in
their desire to be
super capitalistic are are missing out
on on how the actual
the consumers and the business and the
things work you understand what I mean
can I build on that quickly would you
please I know we're about to take a
question from the audience I want to say
that it's all of our Collective
responsibility to build this industry
and to build the market and I hear a lot
of projections I heard some crazy
numbers last night about how big the
German patient Market is going to be in
a year I don't hear anybody talking
about the Investments that they're
making that are going to support the
whole space and not just support their
one company like I'm curious of all of
the people that are here that are
interested in the European market how
many of you can have contributed to the
European medical cannabis Association
how many of you are supporting the
industry associations that are doing the
work on behalf of the entire industry
the other thing that I haven't heard a
lot about is about patient affordability
and if you want to grow a medical market
and you're actually dealing with
critically and chronically ill patients
you're dealing with some of the less
privileged people in your population so
I hear a lot about market share and I
hear a lot about margins but I don't
hear a lot about actually create
distribution structures and Supply
chains that are actually making the
product performance and that's what's
going to grow your Market
[Applause]
hey everyone
um thanks for a great uh perspective I
was curious are there particular markets
in the United States that you guys think
have done a better job at avoiding some
of the pitfalls you've discussed such as
high taxes and a persistent illicit
Market I can think of a few but I'm
curious if there's any that have caught
your attention and also I'm curious if
you have a take on what can be done to
ensure these that these uh policy
lessons are learned I think there's the
perception in the United States that we
fail to learn from our prior mistakes
and I'm curious if you guys agree if you
and if you have a reason as to why that
happens and how it can be addressed
I like Oregon
grows great weed and it's very cheap
it's not maybe so much for the farmers
now because they don't get the prices
they used to but in terms of getting rid
of the illicit Market when you can buy a
half a kilo of very good Oregon cannabis
for
50 Euro 40 Euro or whatever it's crazy
their prices are ridiculous
um and I think they've done a pretty
good job with it don't get me started
about Washington or California though I
got problems with those people well well
or I just I do want to stay Oregon have
the largest price compression in in U.S
history so it was a very difficult
market for the farmers to survive
um right now my favorite Market is
Missouri it's um you are on a state
level you can you can write off 280e
obviously not on a federal level this is
a major topic that everyone is talking
about the United States so to see States
override federal law or tax structures
is is is progress it's progress that the
the states have to take and and drive
forward they also have just generally
the lowest tax bracket in in the United
States so Missouri is my favorite Market
I think it hers it depends on what your
uh per I think Benedict or maybe he was
uh Constantine said your definition of
success and for example uh Oklahoma I
mean come on talk about success it's
Medical Market 800 million dollars
second year most of that's going to
Dallas Texas right so it's it's a you
know it's been very vibrant I would
think also uh Lewis with you on stage I
think Colorado definitely did a pretty
good job being the first roll out State
although they kind of screwed things up
on the public side but I don't know
Lewis could have a better perspective on
that than me yeah so since we uh
contract with 22 different states in the
U.S I'm a little reluctant to start
calling out like the ones that are my
favorites obviously I've got a lot
invested into uh to Colorado's Market
because that's where I kind of got my
start and
um you know well I think there was a lot
of things that went really well in
Colorado to begin with but I think kind
of like served as a launch pad for other
states to to kind of follow suit
um you know I think there's like some
pluses and minuses to a lot of different
approaches and I mentioned earlier about
like the importance of governance
um you know I I think where we've seen
the like most success is When government
is proactive in taking some level of
charge so like if you think about the
differences between like Washington and
Oregon and California and Massachusetts
and Colorado and Michigan they've all
kind of like taken different approaches
and at different times during the
history they've like been like more or
less proactive in how they're um how
they're they're uh acting as a
government and so
um we've seen like where government is
like either like being apathetic and not
doing anything we've seen like the
growth of illicit markets we've seen a
lot of criminal activity and we've just
seen like a lot of like uncertainty in
the market whereas on the opposite of
the spectrum where government has been
more proactive and collaborating and
partnering with industry we've seen you
know much more positive results in terms
of the the perception that people have
about The credibility of the market
we'll give the uh I think capitalist Pig
answer to this question I like the
limited license vertical markets because
it's the one that uh it's still true
it's the one that it's the one that you
can
get significant amount of market share
you can manage your margins and to the
extent you can do something with your
profitability given the tax regime those
other markets that you can have the most
impact can I ask you a question though
because sometimes
and I understand the vertical Market
idea but a lot of times you you try the
Cannabis from those cats and it just
tastes like commercial pressure like you
have to get it out in eight weeks like
you don't have time to you in California
now it's hard to find a good 12-week
sativa in the dispensaries and some of
the really nice old school strains
everything is growing so fast everything
is cured so quickly everything has to be
gotten out right away and I feel some of
the challenges with with a vertical
approach uh as opposed to maybe a
crafter or a smaller approach is that
you don't get the quality I mean
Budweiser is cool but you know I like a
craft beer
you might be right I don't have no other
answer me on saying you might be right
the quality might suffer but again I'm
looking at it through the prism of the
capital markets and from that
perspective
you know maybe the quality isn't as good
as oftentimes as a craft grower or a
more wide open market but
you can make more money well also to add
to that Steve I the the one thing that's
important too is not not being in
Limitless and State versus Limitless
licensed state right so I uh you know
we've been telling them forever if
you're in Colorado or California I'll
put those operators against anybody any
day if you can win in The Crucible
competition Colorado uh you're going to
be the next question
so I'm hi my name is uh Trenton Birch I
come from South Africa I'm interested to
know what the the sort of narrative or
view is in the states at the moment in
terms of I think we often forget and I
appreciate this as an investment Forum
where returns are are the most important
sort of conversation but I think we've
also lost focus on on the on what
cannabis and hemp can do for our planet
from a medical perspective from a
sustainability perspective you know
investing in in this industry is good
for business and it's good for the
planet and I feel like we've we've we've
raced so far forward at such a rapid
speed we've seen this happen over
capitalization especially on cultivation
a lot of people have lost money but is
there any narrative in the US at the
moment around people investing in this
industry because it's good for human
human race and and actually surviving
and and if and if not why not because it
it's it's a good narrative in terms of
you know sustainability is definitely a
a place where money can be made so if
people adjusting it to make money that's
also fine but have we lost our way in
terms of the importance of cannabis and
hemp for the future of our planet you
know
I don't have your I don't have an answer
about uh whether people are investing in
cannabis for those reasons in the U.S
um but I do want to raise that like for
me personally working to free cannabis
from the chains of prohibition a huge
part of it is about the potential that
cannabis has to actually address climate
change and speaking of sustainability
I'm curious how many of you maybe you
can show me a raise of hands know about
the legislation that the EU enacted into
law in April that is the corporate
sustainability reporting standards that
are going to impact cannabis companies
operating in Europe
yeah so a few of you do so this is
really something that's important to
like look around the corner and see what
is coming because for publicly traded
companies the reporting is going to
start at the beginning of next year and
for small and medium-sized Enterprises
you have about two years to get ready so
how many of you are familiar with what
scope one two and three is when it comes
to your environmental impact disclosures
so scope one and scope two is about
measuring and Reporting on your own
emissions so this is carbon it's also
waste and water but scope three which
the EU is going to be requiring is
actually about reporting on the
environmental footprint of your supply
chain so this is something that's
incredibly important to start preparing
for because if you're not building your
companies with the data systems and the
expertise to be tracking all of this
information if you're not building your
supply chain and thinking about
partnering with people who are going to
have the capacity to give you their
reports on their emissions you're really
going to hit a brick wall and it's going
to become very expensive to be able to
address it in short order so it's really
actually an amazing thing that the EU
has done it's the most I would say
aggressive but positive reporting
standards that have been implemented
around the world they will affect the
Cannabis industry and I'm really really
passionate about this and happy to talk
with anybody who wants to get a little
bit of an understanding about what's
coming and how to start addressing it
because the more mature your company
becomes and the more complex it becomes
exponentially more expensive to be able
to address this when the requirements
are going to be hitting you okay Trenton
that was a great question and I
appreciate one thing I would just like
mention I take like your question took
me back to like our like the early days
2013 2014 when we were first putting the
regulations together the narrative then
was more about how do we keep the
federal government from preempting this
opportunity to start legalizing cannabis
so I don't think we were thinking about
a lot of as as much as we should have
the social justice issues or the
sustainability issues we were thinking
more like how do we package this product
in a way where
um uh it's really obvious it's cannabis
and and how much testing are we going to
do we weren't necessarily thinking about
those things I think there's like a
growing interest and certainly
addressing a lot of the social inequity
issues that are that are really
prominent in the US but I also think
sustainability is becoming more and more
important to businesses in the and even
like The Regulators are starting to like
backtrack and say okay how much
packaging do we really need on a
smokable cannabis that is not a danger
in its current form to anyone right even
kids and so
um it's not until it's decarboxylated
that it that it becomes like a an active
ingredient that that's that's a more of
a public health interest so the other
thing I would say too is like part of
like creating the digital transparent
Supply chains in the US it's created the
opportunity to actually start to report
on that so industry itself is thinking
like how do we start to really frame
what our carbon footprint is or what our
environmental footprint is on on
um the Earth and like it's like start
coming up with ways or like in like
including reporting on that like how
what minerals are used what pesticides
are used how much water is uh being used
for irrigation or how much energy is
being consumed to produce the product
and actually be able to report on that
in a way that most other Industries are
not doing or even really willing to do
and so I think the even though I think
it's kind of like still in its infancy
the industry itself just like it's
wanting to prove itself credible
um from the get-go is also interested in
like raising the bar on sustainability
and being able to report
um in in ways other Industries are just
not interested in doing
oh real quick so Trenton you and I know
each other so one thing it's the
question you're posing is really good
but it's funny because you do we're so
far from what you're talking about I
mean right now we talked to what
somebody later on the panel here is
going around trying to find money for
investment and there's a lot of
investors saying yeah sorry we're not
touching cannabis because we saw the
[__] show that it's happened over the
last 10 years where good money's gone
into bad companies right and then you
have the fact that to Lewis point that
you know my I've worked at Cerna Cerner
was essentially making indoor climate
control systems for indoor grow-ops
indoor grow cannabis right now or THC
plus is not sustainable it's indoor grow
right it's that's not a sustainable
we're putting as much it's like a data a
data room where you're putting in a
bunch of energy and having to take it
back out so yeah it's a good point but
we're very far from that
all right so one last question right
here commandment and then hey everyone
uh my name is Oliver Cruz I'm the CEO of
takun USA we're a multi-state brand
focused on the medical consumer segment
and um David going off of you know kind
of what you just said
um I think a lot of investor
expectations have been out of whack and
in the past
um do you think that they're more
congruent with reality today and do you
think that the company valuations
reflect that
currently
I mean I I think in the past year in
Europe we've seen companies come to that
realization I I've seen valuations
throughout Europe come down anywhere
from 40 to 60 percent in the last 12
months so
um so yes
that's what happens in markets so when I
was doing biotech in 2008 when
everything went sideways it was
interesting if you know biotech phase
three companies are worth more than
phase two companies which were more than
what phase one and pre-clinical
everything was so out of whack in 2008
that you had phase three companies phase
two and phase one companies worth pretty
much the same amount of money things
happen like this okay it's it's the way
the world works so you know that's
what's done us a good job is that we've
been through biotech we know things
whipsaw back and forth and we knew this
was going to happen it might not it
might be around for another six months
12 months but you know if you survive
this and you can come out the other side
that's when your value is going to
matter
Jamie
[Music]
no pressure you have to put depression
yeah Jimmy I'm speaking for all women
could you tell us how
let's go to lunch everybody let's hear
it for the panel
we have lunch provided for you outside