thanks everybody uh I uh well doing the
science panel of what I will do uh since
we're not going to moderate this one
either I'm going to have these guys
introduced my steam colleagues in their
background science and we'll jump into a
question or two and then kick it out to
you guys on where these guys think it's
going uh Geo do you want to start
yeah sure thank you hi everybody again
so I'm Giovanni venturini so
um yeah I've been working in the bio
refining space since uh at least 15 15
years
um
after after graduating in engineering I
started to work on second generation
biofuels in in Africa from non-food
crops then I
I moved to the biomaterials where I
started a company called agroots and
that company is producing a bio glues
bioresins
for replacing formaldehyde in wood
paneling in Wood panel
production so and that's where
I actually I learned first time about
about the
um hemp because I was looking for a
protein sources to be used in the bio
resin formulation and uh then I
I I started a second company dedicated
to to cannabis and hemp in 2018
that's herbalea and we are specialized
in
solventless extraction we develop a
number of Technologies for obtaining
concentrate vape liquids with different
cannabinoids terpenes fraction starting
from fresh fresh material
and and what's your educational
background yeah I was saying so I study
in the Industrial Engineer in University
of Florence then I spent a year at the
kotehoa in Stockholm in Sweden and a lot
of experience on the ground I just want
to mention perhaps that had a as a
mentor a biotechnologist there was the
first uh inventor at Genentech
[Music]
a few years ago and I learned a lot from
from him is Professor Roberto Crea and
uh yeah I mean now I have like eight
between pattern and pattern applications
what's up
yeah so I started my career at Imperial
College as an academic drug developer
developed a number of targeted
biological therapies and spanout patents
that ended up in becoming biotech
companies then spent a period of time at
Harvard Medical School doing similar
types of research at which point I
pivoted my career into technology
technological entrepreneurship and then
spent the last 15 years in that sort of
vein eventually bringing myself back
actually to
cannabinoids primarily because what I
saw was an industry that really had a
deep need to be able to address complex
questions and the best process we have
today for that is called science and so
from that point of view I saw a real
opportunity with the way that things had
been scheduled and also therefore grants
had been blocked universities couldn't
do the research that was required that
we could create a an Innovative company
that could actually address or build a
platform and an innovation investment
system to be able to develop that early
stage research and capitalize upon it
my personal interest there really comes
from the fact that as a as a drug
developer in my early career it felt
like we were developing drugs that
blunted and kind of dampened the issue
rather than found real cures and
cannabinoids were interesting to me for
a long time primarily because they still
didn't teach them they still don't teach
them in medical school but they interact
in a fundamentally interesting way in
the fact that they interact with the
brain the neurological system and with
the immunological system and it gives
you an incredibly new way to think about
how you might cure diseases that are
more on the lines of complex chronic
Community non-communicable diseases my
background
I've got a BSC in Biochemistry and
genetics PhD in molecular biology and
biochemistry in an MBA
thanks Eric
let's see this is working here okay so
um I first became familiar with uh
cannabinoids in the 1980s I think in the
early 80s in the latter part of the 80s
and I'd uh been a member of the American
Chemical Society for I think over 23
years now most my most recent experi
experience with cannabinoids began in
2019 I was at the University of tubingen
at The Institute of organic chemistry
there and they had a vaping crisis in
the United States and people from the
United States had contacted me and asked
me what we could do as far as finding a
safe diluence for a THC that was going
into these vaping carts and so uh you
know I I studied a little bit about the
problem which was lipoid pneumonia at
the time and we began the looking into
this a little bit but one day as I was
looking at compounds we pulled into the
parking lot of the university and I
looked at the structure of CBD and then
I looked at the structure of THC and I
said wow these compounds are so similar
it would be very easy to um you know
cycle size CBD into uh into THC I I I
don't know I maybe they were doing this
in the United States at the time we
looked and we found in the patent
literature that other people had done
this previously but we thought well we
could make a nice uh solid supported uh
Catalyst for doing this and perhaps sell
it to licensed companies in the United
States and that was our our first
business model we we did that and then
we began
um
making uh derivatives of uh CBD Pro
drugs and THC which were water-soluble
and had increased bioavailability and so
uh basically I would say since that time
we've been focused on making
modifications to cannabinoids and novel
cannabinoids and lately I've been
directed toward the recreational markets
here in Europe and also in the United
States so that's uh that's primarily the
focus of tresco labs which as I said
interior educational background
educational background yeah my
educational background is a Bachelor of
Science degree so I'm not
as is uh decorated as decorated it's
decorated yes as Sebastian is and who
provides such a very uh articulate uh
answers to many of the questions we have
to say I am quite quite proud of you uh
for that Sebastian but I do have a lot
of uh experience in organic synthesis
over the years and that's that's
primarily what I'm uh focused on but I I
have just like Giovanni I have spent
time at uh Genentech where they teach us
that the process is the product yeah
so so so there's a reason why I put this
panel together so essentially Eric is
working out of Frankfurt you have Geo
working out of Florence and you have
said you're working out of uh north of
London south of London but yeah sorry
yeah I had that 50 50.
uh but so essentially Eric it kind of
does the the molecular side uh seb's
looking at the business and then
certainly Geo's looking and has
Technologies as far as separations or
inclusions so I guess starting with UGL
what is uh what are a few of the things
three two three things that you see uh
most exciting on the near-term horizon
whether it's 12 months 18 months that's
going to make the most impact what we're
talking about cannabis cannabinoids or
something in between
okay thank you so I I think that also
from the questions that I raised to the
previous panels I think that
here we are assisting to a bit of
dichotomy between of course the European
market or rest of the world and the us
where the US is a let's say an open lab
for experimenting uh what what is uh
what is interesting from from a consumer
perspective more than a patient's
perspective
so I think that uh
um if we go if we look at what will be
the development of the European sector
um maybe in a bit more than one year if
some recreational market for instance is
going to be to to open also also also in
Germany uh I think that
the importance of understanding what the
consumer not only the patient but also
the consumer that and I say patient and
consumer with with and we mentioned
today that is the the separation between
these two concepts is uh is sometimes
not easy to to make but what really the
consumer wants is is important so my
point is that for instance when I was
studying a bit the sector I went to to a
pharmacist and um
and I was looking at the way they were
producing the tincture
they cannabino tincture the boiling the
dry flour in in oil
they were obtaining a tincture there was
like smelling of rotten fish and I asked
but
so it smelled bad I mean and I don't
think this is we like and the answer by
the pharmacist was but that's a medicine
so it doesn't have to to taste nice or
whatever so that's that was the
mentality that I
that I found at least in Italy three
three four years ago and uh it hasn't
changed so much in in Italy at least so
I think that what is what is important
to understand is that the the quality
and and having product that really meet
the expectation by by the consumer and
and and can be good for them and they
can be
Pleasant is also very important also in
the medical sector so in that regard I
think that
for instance what we are doing with some
Partners in California we are developing
this solventless product which in my
view represent what is what the market
is is demanding from for many for many
for many reasons because you know it's
it meets a lot of ESG let's say uh
um point on on the way that
the consumer can can can understand that
there is no you know that is not um
let's say organic solvent be used being
used in the in in the production process
and um and and for instance in a product
that he has to inhale that's something
that
um the consumer is is growing a
Consciousness on what is inhaling and
that's very very important
so I think let's say
the obtaining products that can be of
high quality and can meet the consumer
expectations
now and the future expectation I think
it's very very important
thank you sir
yeah so I think the most exciting thing
in the next two years firstly I want to
say that science time is a bit like
geological time it runs way slower than
investors or maybe cannabis cultivators
would like it to but that's the nature
of the Beast so our I can tell you what
we're working on that we're
fundamentally excited about and that is
a platform for utilizing data science to
surface and develop pipelines of
biopharmaceutical drugs now historically
there are we've been focused on THC and
CBD fundamentally and most people in the
room today are focused primarily in
their knowledge based on those two
molecules there's a hundred cannabinoids
the 23 000 terpenes there's 10 000
flavonoids out there some of those you
can get to in high abundance in the
plants some of them you can't
however what we lack in this industry is
the ability to connect the market with
the production and that is fundamentally
a question of function in the human body
which we don't yet have a good answer to
so what I'm fundamentally excited about
over the next two years is the data
science that we're doing around
correlating Plant production or Natural
Abundance with known data in the in the
literature primarily scientific
literature and our own that we're
generating in our labs and then
developing concepts of how we might
think about disease not in the Cartesian
model of Alzheimer's cancer so on and so
forth but in what are the core
common features of those diseases like
dysregulated inflammation and so on and
so forth so that we're designing
clinical trials that actually have
relevant endpoints for cannabinoid-based
medicines or molecules that may be
coming out of that same plant because if
you look at the data I think there's
something like 400 trials only 40 of
them have reported that means the rest
of them are basically flunked and
they've not even bothered of those I
think 20 are around sort of successful
and most of those are based on CBD so
we're only just scratching the surface
of what could be a trillion dollar
market
in the future but we've got to go and do
the leg work to get there so that's what
I'm really excited about David thanks
herb Eric
well what I'm excited about is I speak
to people on a daily basis who in the
United States and in Europe move metric
tons of cannabinoids into the
marketplace and so I hear from them uh
every day and every week what's going on
uh in the industry worldwide
and it's a very it's a very volatile
industry but
I think personally that what we're going
to see and a thing that I'm very excited
about and what we're working on is
having materials that are
non-psychoactive that consumers can
easily access
but that they can have tools in place to
be able to modify these
non-psychoactive completely unregulated
compounds if they want to
into
compounds that are say for example CB1
receptor agonists which are greatly in
demand you know in the United States and
in Europe and in other markets so I see
this really is is the way forward and
also as the way forward for
marketers is being able to put tools in
the the hands of the the patients where
the patients can make a decision to if
they want to to produce a substance that
might be considered controlled in their
jurisdiction and so uh
this is an area that that I'm working on
every day and I think this is rather
exciting
uh just add probably kind of uh treading
the line in between everybody here uh so
we mentioned earlier we're a lead
sponsor of can Med
uh in April we were able to put on the
stage uh with myself some of the leading
scientists uh one of the things that was
really interesting that came out of that
is having the next killer app if you
will on cannabis and cannabinoids so if
you live in the states especially in
Colorado when you saw in 2012 a bunch of
a lot of people moving to Colorado was
one of the first legal states because a
lot of mothers and fathers had kids that
had epilepsy and the easiest access was
to come to Colorado as you guys know
mothers and fathers will do anything for
their kids and so that I think was the
first kill wrap if you will on canvas or
CBD and I think that's the thing that
we're searching for is what's the next
really killer app and one thing that
came out of can man that was really
interesting that came out of a
conversation with on stage with Teddy
meiery and Ethan Rousseau as they think
women's health is going to be one of the
next low-hanging fruits for cannabis and
cannabinoids the the other thing that I
think touching on Eric's and what Geo's
doing is where this molecular world is
going to go as far as making some of
these new I know Eric's said before one
of the main things he's selling here in
the uh in Europe is hhc
hexahydrocannabinol so a lot of these
miners in the production of those and
then actually trying to find out what
those do because if you guys everybody
knows here there's still a stigma and if
we can do more data get better molecules
more consistent high quality molecules
we're going to get rid of we're going to
definitely get rid of the stigma
one other question before we put it out
uh
really talking to all you guys on stage
innovation has not had a lot to do with
cannabis and intellectual property has
not had a lot to do with cannabis so
maybe getting two more specific points
Geo if you want to start off as far as
your thoughts on what we can do better
with the Innovation thank you I I think
that's a very interesting angle so
um you know I was
I've been keeping track on you know on
bad end but an application in the in the
canopy space
and um I think there has been a pretty
pretty interesting ramp up
[Music]
three four years ago uh on the on the
planet application that were filed every
every year on on on different areas so
it's interesting to notice by the way
that
one of the I mean some of the of the
largest uh
let's say some of the of the companies
most active in in filing pattern
applications on cannabinoids and
cannabis in general actually where we're
Pharma companies right so
but at the end let's say the their
commercial activity on on the field
that's been uh let's say with exclusion
of uh of GW
until until uh last year has been um
limited right so
I'm referring to the the big big Pharma
companies big Pharma so despite having
uh some interesting uh patterns around
that they they were pretty
um Limited in the in the commercial
exploitation and that's something that
that puzzled a bit uh me I mean having
having a patent a protection but not
getting to to the market with the with
um with final product is something that
really puzzles me I think a lot
um I don't have I don't have an answer
for specific answer for that there are
some ideas I mean but uh
if you look at the of the statistics
that have been published earlier also
this year
wherever cannabis has been you know
legalized to a certain extent there has
been certainly um
a decrease in opioids consumption right
and um
so I I maybe the simple answer is that
you know
um
allowing of course a big use of of
cannabis in the sector would have a big
impact also on the sales of other of
other products that's maybe a very
simple answer I don't know if that's if
that's correct but but the reality
coming coming just to comment also the
previous the previous point that you
were making uh David on the on the
stigma I mean it's
I think it's really ridiculous that you
know
in opioids prescription is uh is done
such a light and easy manner
I mean I was
like personally let's say exploring a
bit the the opioids consumption in
pharmacies in in uh just in my city
Florence and it's simply crazy I mean we
I mean we're talking about really a a
percentage of of of of the population
that is consuming this consuming opioids
and this should be a short a short
period of treatment of with opioids and
and they want one once these people they
entered the the loop they they cannot
exit easily so it's I found really
ridiculous that
the doctors then can prescribe and
pharmacists can provide opioids in such
an easy Manner and um and there is still
a stigma on cannabis so and actually the
the the the the length of the treatment
of for instance in Italy is often
um
made it difficult because of the lack of
of uh
availability of of the products to the
pharmacies so it's it's really strange
and I hope that you know this will uh
will we get better
I got three things on IP
um when we started five-time Life
Sciences we made a very strong decision
not to straddle ourselves between
production and Manufacturing and being a
research company we're 100 a research
company focused on the development of
intellectual property the licensing of
it and commercialization of it I think
that's a very important thing to think
about we do not start any wet research
unless we've done a patent landscape
search which we have an intellectual
property office for and number three
fundamentally is if you're not willing
to defend a patent I.E you've got the
cash to do so do not go and publish
everything you know about that process
because someone's going to copy you and
you're not going to be able to defend it
and you're going to be able to do
nothing about it I hope that's clear
enough for everybody in the room what I
think about that
so you were talking about Innovation
David in the Cannabis space and I have
to say what I think is interesting is
how fast the market has responded to
um some key uh peer revert reviewed
papers that we had on Alka chain
derivatives of for example THC so we had
and these I think papers at least the
first one came out of an Italian
University didn't it with what they
called um
the THC
by for all or something no it wasn't
that that was the heptal chain the
heptal alkyl chain derivative so then we
began to see in the United States
production of thcp they called it that
was for the heptal alkal chain
derivative and then of course
immediately after that came the hhcp
which was a heptal chain derivative
there so many people got to know
firsthand that these alkyl chain uh
derivatives of the classic cannabinoids
could provide
a more powerful effect or an equivalent
effect with a smaller dose and that they
lasted for a longer period of time so I
I think that the consumer base with many
of these products has experientially
learned how different
modifications
to these molecules are capable of
influencing the the perceived
central nervous system effect yeah so
that's one Innovation I've seen so well
real quick there was a a client of ours
and he'll be telling a little later on
who produced some thcp and he said he
took it and he was high for three days
so it's uh it's fun it's called fun with
chemistry no one thing real quick and
then I'll kick it over you guys then we
can kick it to the audience one thing
about intellectual property in the IP is
if you really knew the GW Pharma Jazz
deal that was really done it wasn't done
really on epidiolex it was done on the
IP that GW Pharma had so and that's the
biggest deal that's really ever been
done in the sector and really if you
look at GW it's it's more of a biotech
company than a cannabis but the the
importance of IEP and Innovation is only
going to grow in the sector for sure
yeah I think I think just to to connect
to the point of Sebastian so
we opened the our you know industrial
lab in in Los Angeles from Florence
um
at the end of last year and we started
to interact a lot with California
companies and I think it's very
interesting to notice few few things
one is that the
many producers they they they try to
just to stay secret about what they are
doing in terms of
the process their formulation because
Sebastian was saying I mean it's not
easy to fall apart and and and remain
protected and fight fight for that and I
and I I know at least a couple of cases
where actually there has been a file a
pattern that has been filed for instance
one is in the production of uh uh thca
diamonds okay and uh and the company was
a small company and uh many others they
started to copy to copy the process and
in the end he couldn't do anything else
that you know being acquired by one of
the companies that was copying their
method and uh and agree with uh you know
with their royalty whatever but it has
been a clear defeat okay on that regard
and also the is interesting the the the
case of uh of um
GW and and canopy and there has been a
an IP you know low suite and and uh
probably the the the end of the lawsuit
was a bit unexpected uh perhaps in in
the US and uh and therefore it is is
certainly a double a double-edged sword
the the IP protection I mean on our on
our end we we believe that
but in protection and Innovation pattern
protection is is important so we we we
find
uh five different uh patent families and
most of them they have been already
granted so because because our model is
also based on licensing this technology
but of course as always and every as in
every sector filing a pattern is not
sufficient you have to protect by
executing through the execution and and
deliver you know the best service or the
best product on the market in any case
so the IP protection IP protection I
believe is just a plus so
anything else no nothing to add on that
so we'll go
uh and guy we can put it out to the
audience for
for any questions we may have
um honestly uh it was hard for me even
to take notes because things that you
folks seem to assume
um
is so far over my head
but um in the United States recently as
you know the DEA has granted licenses
to a number of cannabis cultivators who
are meant to supply
product and competition with a much
maligned University of Mississippi
and
I am curious uh
in if you anyone on the panel has a
sense of how those business models what
kind of business models might develop by
having a well-funded DEA approved
presumably well regulated new suppliers
of of cannabis and cannabinoids into the
research space and into farm and into
Pharma like is this is this a big deal
or is it just
um TBC
Joe Montana
uh it is a big deal because it shows
intent federally that they want to
develop research and that possibly then
opens up grant funding In America which
is still the biggest grant funding
capability in the world so from a
research perspective I think is
fantastic news and basically Mississippi
cannabis was dust that was off the floor
I think in Mississippi somewhere so
fantastic on that front in terms of
really getting to the molecular level of
the issue I think it provides a generic
starting point for questions that are
molecular questions not necessarily
biomass or whole flower questions and so
it therefore has a certain limited
potential if it's just one strain of
cannabis grown to order through a
certain federally licensed site we are
much more excited about
organizations that can grow small
batches of material where you can still
do pilot studies but they're
fundamentally thinking about the
chemistry and the variable chemistry
possibly in polychemical format not down
to THC CBD but maybe it's Unique land
race strains or other things that are
producing really interesting things that
we don't see regularly that has huge
potential to be far more impactful over
time than just a generic centralized
source of cannabis but it's a great
start for helping the industry get
started uh it from the capital side yes
it's a big deal uh
uh because you know if you look at uh so
there's there's a we know a number of
these companies Sue Sicily who I've
known forever she has a D.A license in
Arizona she's doing some interesting
things it also helps on the Psychedelic
side but we've talked before I mean uh
you heard me earlier the Pharma
companies really are not the source of
innovation anymore it's biotech
companies but that has lowered the in
the U.S which is really still The Hub of
Biotech in the world
has lowered the activation energy to get
to market for example what is and why
it's a big deal BRC biotech research
company has a D.A license in California
hunter land who's a friend of mine is a
head Science Guy there they raised 20
million I think intrinsic lab or
intrinsic Partners LED that round uh and
so the 20 million bucks is a big deal
and then if you look at another of the
companies that owns a D.A license is
bright green they're public on the
NASDAQ so as far as capital yes it makes
a big deal
hi uh thank you for a fascinating
conversation
um I was particularly interested in the
data science aspect so about actually
clinical trials these past couple of
years I had some experience doing
clinical trials in cannabis from my PhD
research
um and
as I'm sure you know there's still
stigma still exists in senior scientific
boards like the incb it's still
um an uncertain regulatory landscape for
for a lot of Pharma companies to invest
in so I wanted to ask what do you think
of uh
real world data as an alternative to to
form the clinical research is it a valid
way around the problem and as a
follow-up question if so what kind of
what kind of data should we be
collecting what variables are most
important uh to to gather from The Real
World use of cannabis both medical use
or otherwise
do you want to go
so I mean I'm we are not as a company
involved in the clinical trials so we
are collaborating with um with companies
that are using our extraction system to
produce
compounds which can then be used in
clinical trials so
um
a comment that I would like to make is
that
you know a few some months ago there was
a research studies that hits the the
news saying that most of the clinical
trials were in conclusion inconclusive
regarding the digitization of a
cannabinoids for a number of
pathologies so we we took a bit of time
entirely to review these
these research studies
meta studies
and
what we found out I mean not being again
a a company specialized in this field
but what we found out is that it was a
very interesting uh correlation let's
say between the studies that found kind
of be nice to be effective
with the subministration subministration
method so what I want to say is that
apparently the inhalation is uh is way
more effective than other ways and
and I think that that aspect
for for cannabis again I'm not a doctor
I'm not a physician but uh that's that's
what we found so we reveal the 2030
studies that were considered in in that
meta meta-analysis and and clearly there
was a strong correlation between the
inhalation and the effectiveness of the
treatment
I think it's really helpful I think the
the challenges that the retrospective
work where you have no handle at all on
what the user is taking and possibly
getting a beneficial therapeutic effect
is quite limited so we're about to run a
pilot actually in a cohort of chronic
inflammatory disorder I won't tell you
what it is but it's a chronic
inflammation
where we are going to be working with a
major university in the UK to collect
the material they're actually using
alongside collecting the if you like the
clinical data or the feet the
questionnaire feedback to do the
chemical analyzes of the material
they're using and then using data
science to your point to be able to look
for signals in those data so I think it
has huge potential we've we've been
doing it for decades it's called
ethnobotany we've just been doing it in
the Peruvian jungles and places like
that but hey it's time for us to bring
it into the Western World and start
doing it here too
just at a point Counterpoint on that I'm
assuming if you're doing real world data
you're talking non-clinical trials that
are out kind of like a phase four trial
uh yeah I I think that's it's it's great
the more data we have the better it is
to get rid of the stigma on the negative
side we know a group that was asked by
Mitch McConnell and the FDA to evaluate
CBD and CBD toxicity with a range of
different products in the U.S and they
came up with some really interesting
findings one of them being that CBD is
not that dangerous and actually had
beneficial effects on diabetes and they
sent that into the FDA guess what the
FDA did they buried it so Frankly
Speaking our thought is if you really
want to do real science
on cannabis and cannabinoids go to
Australia do it in Israel don't do in
the U.S because I think the FDA right
now is abdicating their leadership in
the role if you really want to know my
opinion
hello
okay
um
cannabis Association I think the point
is you know to look for opportunities in
science is not so difficult and before
the allowance of the German law bee farm
who is known as one of the strictest
rapporters in any kind of registration
process already made an allowance
for 44 indications to get it on a
special permission imported so I think
the road map where to go is there I
think what we are missing is is a
cannabis industry is to understand
ourselves as part of the pharmaceutical
industry and to figure out the
regulatory path and the dosage finding
because I think this is where we are
lacking data due to the prohibition for
a long time and here I think there will
be no avoidance of Coalition in somebody
who is knowing the regulatory path and
the clinical trial path and I think the
the 44 indications are unmet medical
need so anything what you can provide in
this area will be more than welcome by
the EMA by bee farm as not no not be fun
because they're all strict conditions
you go to the EMA and you get 26 markets
so I think it's not as difficult as we
might think
yeah I agree fundamentally with you I
think it's challenging when um so that
that process already exists it's how
Pharmaceuticals are developed and I'm
like you're saying the same thing and I
agree with you on that
um I think it is a problem when we just
decide that cannabis is going to be
relevant to X number of conditions
because we kind of like it that's not a
very scientific process so I would
suggest that we need to be a little bit
more open-minded in understanding the
fundamentals of how the biochemistry and
the pharmacokinetics of the molecules
work which we still don't understand
before we just go and put a blanket
those 44 other ones don't think about
anything else because you might
fundamentally be missing an enormous
opportunity left field which you just
don't look at
do do it works it does work
um a number of questions were asked in
previous panelists what's the most
important thing that could be done for
the Cannabis sector and I think you guys
sitting up there you've nailed it
basically it's the science that
increases the knowledge
that reduces the stigma so the question
is this is the stigma still going to be
here in four years time
or do you think the actions that you're
taking now will have removed that stigma
within that four years and if not how
can we improve the removal of stigma so
that it is long in four years
I'll say real quick I mean just two
examples Geographic it depends on your
geography John I mean if you look at
Malaysia and anybody especially
Australia knows about Malaysia they have
capital punishment for anybody with any
amount of cannabis any drug right or the
fact here if you're in Germany and you
go to Bavaria Bavaria is still not very
keen on on cannabis so I think the
stigma and how long it lasts going to be
geographically determined
so
I have maybe wrongfully but I have big
hope in the completion of the assessment
in the US at the base of uh eventual
decision for rescheduling so
I believe that you know if
the final outcome that is supposed to
happen by the end of the year
uh it's going to provide the basis for
an effective
for real I mean rescheduling let's say
above
last three
um I I expect that to have a big impact
because in in the end the on at least on
the western world
the the influence of uh you know the U.S
in many manner
the same manner that revision has been
kind of exported I think maybe that the
same type of opposite Trend kind of core
so
I really hope that this assessment is
sufficiently clear
to to provide the basis for the DEA
to to reschedule cannabis
I see that as a major Milestone if that
would not occur
I think many other countries like I'm
talking about for instance Italy we are
really far from eliminating the stigma
but really really far
and the sigma is also present in still
in California
I mean uh the the the the the
so we have a local team there and uh
you know some managers they even in
California they are they are avoiding to
they are avoiding to mention what their
job is when they you know when they when
they go to the school you know like
that's that situation in California so
in Europe when Italy is it's not it's
not possible for years I see
if I can add a comment so I work in
Europe's third largest chemical Park
which is hoaxed and I can tell you that
uh many of the world's top custom
chemical manufacturers right and for
example one of them a pharmaceutical
companies sanofi divested their Fine
Chemicals uh production to a company
they call Euro appy and Euro appy are my
neighbors and I was speaking with them
about
uh some you know doing some work on some
cannabinoids that's you know perfectly
regulatory compliant but they still feel
a stigma with these you know it's like
uh and one of the the answers that they
gave me one time as well they had just
gone uh public you know uh been listed
on the German Stock Exchange and they
thought and they didn't they didn't want
to have anything to do with any
chemistry that touched upon cannabinoids
and that includes even you know CBD they
they didn't want to do anything with CBD
because there's still that that stigma
involved so I can say that a large
German chemical manufacturers at least
they still
there's still too much of a stigma
involved for them for them to become
involved with these types of compounds
can I respond to your question before
you ask another one just really quickly
I think
um anything that verges on a religious
experience or a mystical experience
which cannabinoids psychedelics may do
is always going to have a stigma
associated with it with those who are
looking to control the populace and
therefore I think education of yourself
so that you understand how to use that
medicine beyond the medical practitioner
is going to be a big part of how
actually this becomes destigmatized and
repatriated into the hands of the people
who can treat themselves with it
well put well put Sebastian thank you
just one point or more you mentioned
sorry can you hear me now yes so um one
point more I was in Singapore last week
we're looking at doing research here I
was in Malaysia we're looking at doing
research there so these Asian countries
are moving along despite them hanging
somebody in Singapore six weeks ago
right we already operate in five
countries so USA Canada UK Germany
Australia and funnily enough Jamaica so
I'm just the biggest problem we face
around the world is stigma
you guys have nailed it but we have to
actually work together to overcome that
stigma that's the one thing I think out
of this whole Forum we need to actually
grasp overcome the stigma the rest of
the route will follow
thank you so much let's hear it for the
panel
[Applause]