thanks everybody uh for staying so late
so hopefully we'll make it worth your
while actually this is going to be a
very interesting panel because we have a
very diverse set of panelists up here
hopefully I'll just kick it over to them
right now and you'll uh
be able to see that and also again we're
going to just do one question then kick
it out to you guys to make it very
interactive but only do you want to go
first
sure my name is orilan I'm co-founder of
Oscar capsule and we are eventually fund
specifically dedicated to the medical
and Pharmacy tool cannabis space
my name's uh Brett Worley I'm the CEO of
MC Global Holdings our main uh holding
is MC nutraceuticals which is the
world's largest caminoid distributor
uh good afternoon my name is Trenton
Birch I head up Chiba Africa we are the
leading
educator and trainer in the Cannabis and
hemp space we train across the full
value chain we also run a consultancy
South Africa is open for business so if
anybody would like to buy any of our
weed or immerse with us in any way uh
we're here and I'll impact it a bit more
as we as we get into things thanks real
quick I don't know if you guys worry
guys based uh so I'm based in London but
we have team in Paris and some advisors
in the US
Denver Colorado and uh czechia
I'm in Johannesburg so to wrap this
whole thing up for the end of the day
and again talking about maybe where this
is going in the future uh and as we've
talked about earlier today there's
certainly stigma remains and the
question to the panelists then is you
know what may be major events or what
they see in their business model is
going to change that mindset whether a
short term or long-term uh so starting
with you ollie too that you know there's
been a lot of capital put in this
industry and as a result of some of the
blow-ups that we've talked about a lot
today a lot of that capital is going to
still staying on the sidelines so we
want to talk about the stigma as it
relates to operations as it relates to
markets as it relates to revenue as it
relates to Capital Ollie do you want to
kick off that
I think
it's interesting hearing the talks today
because I think
obviously there's a lot of pessimism
there's a lot of frustration about where
we are today and frankly it's totally
reasonable you know we're in a a pretty
depressed state of the market but
ultimately
it's not surprising I think you know
this is an emerging sector this is a
novel therapeutic admittedly it's been
used for generations and generations but
coupled with the stigma that's been
surrounding it for so long you know it's
it's unsurprising that there was a
resistance to it being legalized
and then an extremely overhyped hype
cycle when it eventually was
and now I think we're in a sort of
strange
limbo situation whereby
in reality although everything does feel
very much appreciated
in terms of True Value it's I don't
think the valuations of today are
actually particularly
misaligned with what there is in the
market
um the reason why I say that is because
I think perhaps we got used to the
over-excitement of you know the late
teens of the last 10 years
and
realistically the only way was down and
had it not come down yet instead of us
being pessimistic here about the the
current low evaluations the current lack
of capital we'll probably all be
terrified about the impending implosion
that would inevitably come
so for that reason you know weird as a
capital are actually very optimistic now
I think we're we're at a stage where
valuations are reasonable where a lot of
the chaff has been washed out of the
market
and where ultimately the true benefits
of the sector are still there to be
realized nothing has changed
fundamentally about what these products
can do for consumers and what they can
do for patients and now it's up to us to
realize that
well I think I'm going to shake things
up a little bit
um so I'm in the hemp space we don't
have any of these problems we can do
interstate commerce we export to 26
countries last month we sold 600 million
10 million milligram doses
um so we don't have the restrictions
that the Cannabis Market has to go
through you know all these cannabis and
hemp
um I bank at Bank of America they like
my money
um so we we don't see it as much and
maybe it's a breath of fresh air for
everybody else maybe not uh uh but we
you know Florida is the largest cannabis
Market in the world and I don't think a
lot of people know that and that's
because of Delta a THC we did an
economic Report with Beau Whitney who
will be here in a couple days but is a
6.9 billion dollar market I don't know
what California is off the top of my
head but it's probably around 5 billion
is my guess
um almost every company I would say 90
plus cash flow positive no serious
Investments have come into the sector
for the most part so everything's been
pretty organic and honestly I would say
done the proper way because of the lack
of Regulation now that being said there
you know there's a kind of got to put
some guard rails in that's something
that I work on on a state-by-state basis
I write most of the laws that go into
place so we Lobby in you know 12 States
and we're putting everything a little
the GE in the bottle a little bit but we
have 480 customers and there's thousands
of online brands that you can buy you
know 42 cannabinoids that we sell from
and so Brad with what you guys are doing
do you think that's going to help more
quickly alleviate stigmas both here in
in U.S
yeah I think it's already doing that I
think we're also creating new customer
base a customer base that can go in and
buy medicine at a smoke shop or a gas
station I think it's creating almost I
don't want to say a soccer mom consumer
but it's it's giving people the
opportunity to try something that they
probably wouldn't have tried
alternatively and also it's killing the
black market which is good for some can
or it's bad for some cannabis companies
that are still engaged in that but it's
it's good for us
um or it's good for the hemp industry to
be able to say that we're killing the
black market
I think obviously there's there's a
degree of pessimism around where we're
at with the industry but I think what's
important to remember is in my opinion
this is one of the most important
industries of our time you know we we
forget about the impact that this can
have on our on our personal health uh
the impact that's Industrial Hemp can
have on on the planet and sustainability
um and I I'm excited for the future yes
we're all a bit burnt out we're all a
bit tired but you will you will not find
an industry on this planet right now
apart from maybe AI where you have such
a deeply committed
passionate and purpose-driven Industry
you know a lot of people in this
industry are in this industry because
they believe in this plant deeply you
know so I think we've been burnt and and
we need to learn from those mistakes you
know I'm gonna I'm gonna bang on about
the whole outdoor thing and endorsing
again because you know I know that
people in this room you know don't
necessarily have control over
legislation but if if your cannabis
clubs are restricted to cannabis from
Germany firstly you will fuel the
illicit Market because the Colombians
and the South Africans and developing
economies can grow for a fraction of
that price so I think there needs to be
a really a much more Global outlook on
on building this industry because
ultimately it has the potential to
completely seismically change the
trajectory of our planet in certain
areas and I think we've got to pull
together as a community in an industry
and figure out how we can Grease the
wheels to move this forward I don't want
to see anybody lose money anymore and I
think we can avoid that by learning from
from the mistakes that have and uh well
and just to add to the comments uh
to all these guys maybe we're wrapping
in a tidy bow because most of you
probably uh certainly weren't here when
I first started this morning but if you
really do look at cannabis being the
genus and then everything else
underneath it you know you have THC plus
THC minus which includes molecular hemp
which is flavonoids terpenes hhc some of
the miners and then you have THC plus
which is Delta Delta 9 thca you have the
regulated unregulated the whole kitten
caboodle if you will and the opportunity
there's a huge opportunity and I think
it's going to take some patience some
time and a lot of data whether it's hemp
Drive THC hemp to drive CB D CBC or any
some of these other things coming from
outdoor cultivation but that being said
you know let's we'd like to have this
interactive you guys have stayed so late
for so we'll throw it out Hirsch do you
want to you can just speak up or
workout
s
obviously the regulatory model for hemp
has grown up in a very distinct way than
the regulatory model for psychoactive
cannabis and so my question is do you
envision the regulatory model for the
entire plant ultimately resembling the
world in which you operate is that
something that you advocate for and I
guess the last part of that question is
if that's true I'm curious how someone
like Oliver thinks about that right if
that's the world we're going to live in
in a decade or two how does that impact
the way that you think about investment
I'll just tell you what my personal
belief is is you know in the U.S 21 plus
here 18 plus five to six percent retail
tax GMP EU GMP made call today give it
food guidelines make it a food it's
commodity that's the way we treat it we
treat it as a commodity we sell like I
said 42 of these things so
um you know let people decide how they
want to consume it just like a
nutraceutical product or just like a
food
and you know we also have a
direct-to-consumer company where we get
to see the benefits of that you know
directly and obviously I have my clients
that talk to but
you know this is how this medicine
should be accessed and that's why the
hemp industry and other another fun fact
and this will come out in the next two
months the hemp industry is bigger than
the Cannabis Market the hemp industry is
about 40 to 50 billion in retail sales
in the US cannabis last year was 33
billion we did that in four years
cannabis has been around for 14 years so
we're growing up three four times the
pace I know the Florida statistics came
out too for the medical stuff I think it
was 250 million milligrams are consumed
last week we sell that every day so it
kind of just shows you the scale it
shows you the size another thing is my
chemist does a better job of explaining
this but
um you know the reality is is the demand
is going to outpace what you can grow
for for weed hemp's easier to grow so
it's it's just what's going to happen as
these markets do open up and I think
it's a necessary you know it's necessary
essentially
and Oliver I think the question was to
you too on that yeah so with regards to
regulations we never make bets and
regulations I think um
you know I think we've all probably got
a bit over excited at the start thinking
that certain things are going to happen
especially in the US and also now in
Germany
and our view now is that we operate only
within the regulatory Frameworks that
are in place and don't put any money
behind anything that relies on
regulatory change in order to affect
their business model that being said you
know Brett sounds like you're in a very
nice situation over there it's a hats
off to you for that um but yeah I
suppose what we look at in terms of
investment is also much more on the
medical and pharmaceutical side
uh so that takes us a little further
away from the plant itself so we look at
anything that affects the
endocannabinoid system be that
phytocannabinoid or synthetic
um so in a sense that constrains what we
look at from the broader cannabis
perspective because we we don't
typically look at producers but rather
look at ip-rich businesses that are
typically developing assets through
clinical trials so again a very
structured pre-existing regulatory
framework where we know the risks to an
extent that we can we know the costs and
we know what the price is at the end of
the road
so to add to that hers so again we're a
lead sponsor benzinga and I got up on
the stage and talked about Delta 8 and
you do that and Benzene is really all
about msos LPS th what we call again THC
Plus
and I thought I might get burned at the
stake right and then a month later we go
to can Med and you're a can Med it's all
about science and I learned in the fact
that I I didn't know and that's the cool
thing about this industry you're always
learning new stuff that there's a guy in
the U.S who's actually studying Delta
eight years in 1942 much sooner what 20
years more than 20 years than Rafi
mashulum would found THC or Delta 9. and
so the main point I want to make is this
is all about Innovation that's the way
the world works man and if you want to
try to get in front of innovation guess
what you're going to get run over so I'm
sorry but you know that's where this
industry is going whether you like it or
not and a lot of these msos don't like
it and you know it's it's where it's at
I mean I mean I think the whole division
between
hemp and cannabis which is the same
plant I think will eventually fall away
you know because you know to to separate
these these plants this plant into two
different uh Dimensions just based on
THC level I think it's very naive
because ultimately I think where it
needs to be regulated is actually at at
what the product is going to be used for
so for example our our medical farms in
South Africa uh cultivate flower and
they have to incinerate the leaves and
the stalks I mean this makes no logical
sense at all likewise we have a lot of
rural farmers who are have been
cultivating for hundreds of years and we
are looking at creating special zones
where they don't need specific licenses
and the flower goes one way and the
stalks and the and the leaves go another
way and I think that's that's eventually
where we'll see it goes I mean this
whole you know 0.2 percent for hampers
just a load of [ __ ] you know it
doesn't make any logical sense and I
think that that is eventually that those
those those lines will start to
dissipate and it'll be based on what the
actual plant is being used for as
opposed to its THC level that's just an
opinion we have I was in a government
pakisa uh last week and there were a
hundred delegates all debating this so
we are also trying to be Innovative as a
developing economy uh to to figure out
how we can work within our environment
and our different sort of technicalities
and processes and that's something that
we've been trying to figure out uh you
know over the last few months
Jim do you uh have any question that you
like the panel
yeah I'm still
really not enough
um the amount of money that was made
in kids
what was that stand again yes so I can
give you more stats
or the floor Florida 6.9 billion retail
market and then we just did Texas Texas
at 3.3 billion dollar retail market so
Texas disaster
smoking it
yeah so there's you know we derive 42
cannabinoids from the hemp plan and a
lot of them are quite psychoactive yes
so Vapes gummies whatever you can you
can buy you can get high at something
you buy at the gas station now
we take CBD we isomerize it into Delta 8
and that's legal federally
um
it's him it's it's a cannabinoid derived
from the hemp plant is is the legal
definition
right and just
save families lives is this the same
time yeah we we so we take hemp we
isolate the CBD out and then we use it
to convert it to another cannabinoid so
we can make
yes
[Music]
es
almost anywhere that's a U.S based place
that hasn't banned it which is you know
West Coast essentially you can go into
smoke shops for sure but
about 25 percent of gas stations carry
it just you know not large
yeah
yeah exactly I mean people use it for
medicine obviously as we all know but
yeah it's pretty much
[Music]
no it's actually pure so we actually you
know isolate molecules to where they're
pure
so you know terpenes have been known to
be carcinogens for example we just make
pure molecules
so it's probably actually safer
isomerization is a pretty well known
process
so Pharmaceuticals you you know Hydra we
we do we do hydrogenation isomerization
you know your Butters hydrogenated
essentially so these are common
practices
so you're you're you're really trying to
and these are all phytocannon it's also
so they're found in the plant we just
have to scale them somewhere
one little gun creature
so people re-add in the terpenes like a
company like true terpenes which is a
Goliath Company now
pretty much people can formulate
whatever we want you know ads 20 CBN
into your Delta 8 Vape now you got an
end to cut add 20 thcv in now you got a
sativa so that's that's what we're
seeing another thing I guess I'll say is
we've expedited the Cannabis science by
probably two decades just because of
what we've been able to do you know
cannabis companies typically sell CBN
thcb if they're special and and Delta 9
THC like I said our company sells 42
cannabinoids and these are all over the
market
wow
that's cool man no it's actually a good
question because I'm sure a lot of
people have no idea what I'm talking
about
yeah yeah
because yeah
you guys all are hey wait how many
people out there would like to have Jim
join us on stage
[Music]
yo come on come on
it's all right you have to fight
no they're yeah
I'm a little ignorant
I'm a little I am I'm a little ignorant
to it that's why I'm that's why that's
important I mean there is a lot of
cannabis really stupid about hemp I just
know that when the hemp boom came in
Oregon and California
it was like everybody their brother and
the cartel were growing it and within a
year and a half everybody lost
everything every convention that had a
CBD in it and they didn't show up the
next year yeah so it was the one gold
rush I didn't go into that I want holy
[ __ ] I was smart for the first time but
now you're taking that hemp business
and creating really a business to get
high yeah we're taking all that crap and
we're converting it to Delta 8
essentially right okay
no I don't want to introduce myself
don't have to guess
if they don't guess
[ __ ] them I don't care
so so you're growing a tremendous amount
of hemp in Africa so I I don't we don't
actually make the CBD oh so you're a
consultant
no no no I own the company we're a
distributor
yeah yeah so we sold all right
6.6 metric tons last month we'll
probably do eight tons yeah okay you're
not a farmer no no no no no no no we
don't want to get involved in that oh of
course
we like we like the part that makes
money so the safe thing yeah you want
the safe yeah yeah but yeah but for farm
for example we on a monthly basis
roughly 600 000 pounds gets consumed
indirectly through us we've got too many
[ __ ] numbers for me in a row man yeah
yeah this is what I do for a living
too many numbers I'm simple I'm like one
plus one is two
hundred and fifty million and 260
trillion and CBD and 2B singing from 600
000 bombs
I feel like I'm I feel like I've been
sold some with all those numbers just
give me one plus one one plus one is you
take the hemp plant you [ __ ] with it and
people get high and we make a [ __ ] ton
of money and you make a [ __ ] ton of
money okay I'm not in it for the money
that's why I'm in the other business
I'm in the I'm in a cannabis business
that sells recreational and adult use
and medicine so I'm in a business that
doesn't make any money yeah
it's the same thing but we don't have
restriction that's like I said you know
I know it's a [ __ ] I get wire transfers
every day and my money's at Bank of
America it's the thing I always throw
some numbers in here uh I I will not
tell that tire transfer I got one today
for 250 years the Euros transfers it to
one of the dollars yesterday we did 380
000 in sales
euros dollars there was some euros in
there pesos it's actually probably
higher than that probably about 50 000
Euros okay I knew you had some more
numbers in there man come on let's get
some multiples going here that's why
we're here uh I don't mean to [ __ ] with
you but it's fun all right this is this
is great now now we're moving now here
we go
now
I I have a joint in my pocket
from Oregon
Southern Oregon and I have a bag
of
d8 what do you call it dh8 what is it
you're actually
Delta eight
I can give you a bag of Delta eight or a
joint for Morgan
what do you want to smoke
Oregon grows the second best weed in the
world
about the best weed in the world okay
just just you know
so it's a working man's weed is what
you're talking about gas stations and
it's a yeah like I was describing I
think we've converted a lot of people
that would never go into a medical
dispensary in a lot in most of these
states where we're big there aren't that
access anyway for example and and this
is a Florida's a medical State too but I
I was walking down Duval Street in Key
West Florida and there's three
dispensaries all shut down there's about
25 stores selling Delta 8.
so the Delta a guy just crushed the med
I have to be brought over to this don't
they just for some reason you're welcome
to chat about it yeah I I I I'm just I'm
not there yet I'm not there yet because
there are some stats that I heard but I
don't remember them see I'm not like you
40 billion yeah 40 billion uh in
Mississippi there was legislation that
they were fighting about trying to keep
the Delta eight out because of some
health issues that were sprung up from
the usage but that was I can't even
quote it so I don't have the credibility
here we get lots of propaganda against
us
yes right some anti-propagana yeah it
comes from the Cannabis side so usually
when we comes from my side yeah
you know what I mean you're right
what I heard was from a grower yeah they
really truly spent 10 million dollars
lobbying and we kicked their ass in
Florida up and down the street ah so
there is a fight between my side and
your side absolutely and this is why
here's the tension yeah and within five
minutes you'll be able to take bets
because we'll be wrestling right here
I'll make a prediction I think the fight
will be over but here's the irony here's
the irony in this discussion you don't
grow it
I do not
so in terms of in terms of what you're
saying where do you see things in the
next five ten years in terms of hemp and
cannabis how do you see the market
shifting based on what you think let me
do the numbers for them and then you
explain 250 something eight twenty four
twenty times twenty twenty six million
26 million Delta 24.6
I expect Canada distribution I expect
Canada oh no 288 tax form distribution
Capital go right back to the investors
1.6 in the military make me sound like a
genius
genius man you are a genius I'm not as
smart as you and if I had your shoes I'd
be better looking
how do you like my shoes I do like the
shoes look at my shoes like David's
better but I'm working on it why'd you
were curled under look at that I didn't
even do it right so I in the next year I
expect the fight to be over and I expect
him to win um there's some things that I
won't discuss on stage but
um things look very good for hemp that's
for sure uh the EU is a different ball
game but we do Lobby here or we do I'll
be in Prague tomorrow for my Association
so
um we'll see what happens there they're
actually supposed to make a decision
tomorrow on hhc but do you think at some
point like the FDA will catch up because
it is psychoactive we're we're talking
to the FDA
and there they actually well
they told us they want to regulate it
our way they told us that they want to
regulate Delta 8.
they want they want to regulate like we
don't expect to get jeweled which if
people aren't familiars FDA came out and
just banned Jewel it was a big concern
of ours actually so we're in discussions
with the FDA and and the federal
government and in state I was meeting
with the governor of Kentucky four days
ago and I go I need I need seeds in the
ground so we're working on the economic
incentives to help the farmer
um so we are so if you want to move to
Kentucky I can help you out but I need a
1.5 I wanna that's what I want that's
I'm going right for it a hemp Farm in
Kentucky
that's what I want I think it's one of
the largest hemp States right yeah it's
my understanding is I don't know about
Acres but I think it is Mr senator in
Kentucky Governor Bashir as who I was
referencing
and then I'm meeting with you know a
bunch of Staff members but we're trying
to get as much hemp in the ground as
possible because we expect demand I mean
we I we turn down business all the time
we can't even keep up I know that I know
that I knew that I read that on your
your ad
you won't take your business all the
time I don't even need to [ __ ] be
here
[Laughter]
Brad did they have to give you any
reasons as to why they want to regulate
it on how they were going to go about it
I wasn't I mean I probably shouldn't be
speaking about this but I wasn't the one
that had the conversation but um
they they just wanted the the FDA is not
going to come out and say hey Delta it's
cool you know do whatever you want they
just want it regulated at the federal
level with more guidelines in the farm
bill essentially so I guess I'm giving
out all the secrets now
so real quick uh
since now I have Jim Belushi on stage do
you have with regards to the title of
our talk your thoughts on the winners on
your experience the next couple of years
Jim
winners who will be the winners and the
losers
countries companies Technologies any
thoughts on that
it all sucks
it's uh it's
the only way you really can win in any
of these categories
is if you're driven
with purpose
and you have to be able to sacrifice
all kinds of [ __ ] to be committed to
your purpose
and one of those things you have to
sacrifice is money
and of your purpose
is embedded in your body and your heart
you can be a winner no matter what
and my purpose
is about
the healing benefits of cannabis
so when I see people veterans
that have PTSD that we're giving given a
bottle of 600 Oxycontin to help them
and
we move them over to cannabis
you know that changes everything for me
so I may lose money on my farm
uh
I can afford it
most a lot of farmers aren't they're
really struggling so it's easier for me
I'm luxurious to be able to keep on
purpose and my purpose is about healing
my purpose is about
you know taking people
sort of loved with the hemp when I saw
these children in Colorado Springs
you know there was a little place called
the realm of care and they had about 30
40 children there
varying from age from 5 to 14 that we're
having so many seizures in a in a day
that
the married couple it's hard for them to
stay married
because the mother is in the bedroom
with the son
watching for the seizures
you know taking the sun into hospice
with 14 different kinds of medication
she is never in her husband's bed
their relations have gone to zero
so this family because of this disease
is about to split this family up
and to see what a little CBD oil did for
that child it saved the child it saved
the family I think cannabis
has a multitude of purposes and it's all
driven to
helping families which is where we live
right
so there's a lot of guys smoking
I mean
so I think you're a natural winner
if you're in this industry
uh I don't know if you're the best
businessman I know I'm not but uh I I
feel good every day when people are
healed or I mean I have a strain
I have a stream that's
not hemp it's uh Cherry Pie and it's
called and it's got like a 19 THC and
about three percent terpenes you know
some limonene in it you know
and it's it's I'm a lightweight
so I
I took a hit one hit and came downstairs
and saw my wife
and everything she said was beautiful
I couldn't believe how beautiful my wife
was
and I called cherry pie the marriage
counselor
so I mean
cannabis heals so many things besides
besides can't helps with cancer and
seizures and back aches and
sleeplessness hopelessness it helps with
hopelessness
and uh can help with your partner or
your wife too you know I mean it's just
much better than alcohol
I mean the interesting stat and I'll
talk about it tomorrow because I do have
want the stats
I have one
the state of Illinois they paid
478 million dollars in
state taxes the Cannabis industry
in Illinois that year they paid
278 million dollars in taxes for liquor
there's a lot more bars and liquor
stores than there are dispensaries
so the War on Drugs is still continuing
with the over Taxation and the over
regulation and when this gentleman is
talking about is moving all out on the
side of that
which is cool
and if it's if it's medically motivated
I think it's even super cool
um but I don't know the medical benefits
of the Delta eight I hate to cut
everybody off but we're out of time
all day man I'll talk all day Thursday
I'm talking right Thursday you're
talking and also we're you're having a
meet and greet in the reception Lobby
right now let's hear it for Jim Belushi
look just like that
thank you