thank you everybody and uh welcome to
this panel on cannabis cultivation in
Europe mastering the challenge of Market
saturation over Supply and under
performance
um so on today's panel uh we have uh
David Engel he's CEO and president of
full moon real estate Investments and
ondara then we have Adrian Fisher he's
co-founder and managing director at
demikan he's the third founder next to
the other two Founders that you've seen
on stage before we have the honor to
have here Vera broader she's the CEO of
mhi cultivo medicinal Sr as well as
Alexander Rick who is the Chief
Operating Officer at Harper farm game
but also one of the Pioneers here in the
German cannabis industry and former CEO
of gecko Pharma
um so it's a quite interesting topic
here with the Cannabis cultivation we've
heard some controversy already there
have been some ongoing discussions
already in the audience
um so maybe let's start with Adrian at
that point again and see um Edwin as a
German producer of medicinal cannabis uh
what do you think what strategies do you
employ to ensure a consistent Supply and
quality to navigate a competitive
European market with your own
cultivation but also with the Imports
that you are doing and also maybe in a
perspective on other countries that you
as a company from Germany want to get
active in yeah yeah thanks for the
introduction um you're absolutely right
I think the response is twofold like the
first one would be a little bit more
technical on the side of the cultivation
um I think what's really important if
you're producing just for the medical
Market is consistency and control and
we've established a facility to do just
that
um I would definitely suggest everyone
who's going into that direction to
invest into two Labs which one the first
will be a tissue culture lab the second
one would be your own QC lab and if you
have full control over the product then
consistency comes
so for our domestic production that's
our strategy we can't produce any out of
specification batches because there's no
Second Use in Germany so everything that
is out of specification has to be
destroyed and there's also no way to
reroute it for example for exports but
the second part I think is really
important
um what we're also doing is we're
offering uh GMP services so we are
importing the ACP flowers from every
producer that is uh like fulfills gacp
criteria where we do the audit can
import the flowers and we do GMP
processing so I think that's a really
important part also to include other
people into the German market and offer
flexibility to include other people's
over the world to produce in or sell in
Germany
thank you very much
um David how do you perceive
European ecosystem production ecosystem
and complex regulatory landscape that we
have here in Europe
well this is
okay yeah it is a challenge
as as I've heard many times the European
markets are not harmonized the way they
handle you know every aspect of the you
know the GMP aspect even the cultivation
the the agencies are all learning a new
business they're a little confused by it
so you know we operate we're governed by
agencies that really don't understand
cannabis like in Spain you know they're
learning cannabis they're learning with
us so it makes it very challenging
there's no right answer always you can't
just pick up the phone and call a
consultant and get an answer so it's uh
it's a complex regulatory uh situation
uh as everyone learns how to navigate
this cannabis this uh this herbal
medicine
you know as far as the cultivation goes
you made a good point uh Adrian uh you
you have to control every aspect of uh
of your operation from the tissue
culture genetics which are highly
preferred to prevent uh to bet problems
in your crop but also it's very
important that your systems and your in
your cultivation facility are designed
properly that's where a lot of folks go
wrong in the states and in Canada in the
past we've done about everything you can
screw up we screwed it up in the United
States okay so we're we're hopefully
done screwing things up but uh every
aspect of temperature humidity control
drying
methodologies every aspect has to be
precisely on are you going to have a bad
product are you going to have a product
that fails or out of spec or what have
you so that's my two cents on that one
anyway okay thank you um so Vera you're
one of the Pioneers in Portugal can you
tell us what were factors that
contributed to the successful
establishment of a cannabis cultivation
operation in Portugal and how can
Portugal leverage its Advantage does it
that it has and maybe you can give us a
quick overview on where the Portuguese
Market stands at this point in terms of
cultivation
yes thank you Lisa so Portugal has been
very accommodating to the medical
cannabis industry in the sense that it
opened up its doors for investment
on the other hand the regulatory
framework is very conservative and one
must understand that when one invests in
cultivation in medical cannabis in
Portugal it is a long path it's the
Pharma path in a very conservative
European structure
and
many companies when they enter the
cultivation they are not entirely
understanding of the Pharma path and
that has created many difficult
situations for the Cannabis medical
cannabis industry alike all over Europe
and that's a bit the situation in
Portugal many many licenses many
licensed submissions many companies that
were set up and haven't made it through
because you really need to take a deep
breath and walk through every little
path
um with the first mover Advantage is
definitely uh
critical for success
thank you
um Alex what is your perception I mean
you're active in Germany and you have
operation cooperation in North Macedonia
um what do you think where are
cultivation markets going and how what
are some key considerations when setting
up a production for facility still
the most important thing is that you
have a very good team we have a North
Macedonia an amazing head grower and a
very well educated team and they are
taking control of the cultivation 24
hours seven days a week you always have
to control all the lights nutritions
water Etc so yeah you cannot sleep you
have to control the environment Etc the
whole time and the problem is to yeah to
cultivate a product
same amount with the same THC content so
that you had the specifications you
always have to produce within the
specifications otherwise you cannot sell
the product for example in Germany when
it's registered as a 21 THC flower then
you cannot sell it as a 25
THC flower that's not possible and yeah
when you when it comes to New Market so
I'm in the industry since 2017 and what
I really or I was always surprised that
the cultivators they have big dreams and
big ideas and they said oh we are we are
we are now building the the
state-of-the-art facility Etc so it's
good to do the homework but you should
also know the market where you want to
sell your products so in the end a lot
of producers came to me in the past and
take hey we Alexander now we have to
grow and photons and we are now looking
for customers can you help us I said no
now it's too late you should have come
earlier
um so um yeah in best case or I want to
give an example for the Polish market
the registration of the product will
take you 12 60 months or more even yeah
and it's very conservative everybody's
looking to Poland right now because it's
a very interesting Market uh there is no
insurance
paying the cost for the patients that's
why I'm always surprised that I hear
that it's a very big Market but if you
know some people there they will tell
you and I think what is really important
when you enter New Market you should
also know the regulation Side by
yourself and have very good contacts who
know who are also very good informed
what they are doing yeah
so we heard this topic of consistency
before and stable genetics
um David you work with genetics what is
your stance on how do you see the role
of genetics in overcoming Market
saturation to a certain extent and
underperformance challenges in the
European cannabis industry what role do
genetics play in this equation
yeah I see genetics as vitally important
to being competitive in the marketplace
um you know we saw the phenomenon in
Canada where certain genetics would
become popular
and then everybody's got their hands on
those genetics and started growing them
and then the prices you know just
plummet so we bought a genetics bank and
we have a genetics company where we
pheno hunt about 950 high THC genetics
we also have some one-to-ones and and
CBD genetics but we think that where we
can stand out in the market is we can
provide importers of cannabis
flowers you know and other products we
can provide them uh their exclusive
genetic from our genetics bank that they
can choose and only they would have
access to those particular genetics that
we we uh license to them permanently so
I think that that's where you can stand
out in the market as a distributor to
have access to the best genetics
uh we're totally introducing new
genetics you know over time every year
uh keep keep a really fresh
uh uh variation of genetics and uh and
we also uh prefer to start with tissue
culture uh clones
from from our cultivation
Adrian you're also doing tissue culture
and you're also focused on genetics uh
what do you think is the role of
genetics and also in scaling cultivation
operations or making genetics available
potentially for home cultivation and
those kind of topics what's your stance
on that
yeah we're thinking very much alike here
um this is also one of the focuses we
are we're having
so um as a little background in Germany
we're quite limited with which strains
we can grow currently are under our
government contract but we are not
limited uh for which strains we can do r
d
so we've began that already when we
started our company uh if you know
hunted our first strains and now are
running a lot more final hands using our
TC lab and preparing a strain database
for Germany especially when there's a
wreck market with the potential of
cannabis Social Clubs coming online but
also for our home cultivators and I
think there's a great demand for not
only good and stable genetics but also
clean genetics we know that many kinds
of different diseases are very prevalent
especially in the U.S market but since
we are now also having lots of U.S
genetics here in Europe all that has
come over
so it's a really important thing to have
something ready in that direction and
that's also something that we definitely
would like to offer
there are
I already have here a couple of overlaps
in what you guys are all doing what
would you say is uh are some of the
lessons learned from you in Portugal
about collaboration and competitiveness
in Europe itself
collaboration is critical because this
is a starting industry
especially at Europe we have a lot of
experience coming from North America
from Israel but in Europe it's a whole
different ball game the Pharma
regulation is completely different than
it is in North America or Israel and the
market in itself has a lot of potential
but we're far from reaching the
potential so if we all work together and
um
manage to uh
find the path to help educate the far
the the market educate the doctors
educate help with the regulatory path
ensure that the governments understand
the Pharma economics and the
sustainability that cannabis medical
cannabis can bring to them in terms of
less
expenditure with hospital beds with
drugs that can be harmful and create
worse expenses to the government
creating also establishing the
dividing amongst us the cultivation and
the entry as
we ourselves Medicare in Portugal are
also cultivators and an EU GMP
manufacturing facility we also have
strategic Partnerships in terms of
genetics so together we can unite rather
than be competitors we need to
collaborate and let each other
um
outstand in in their expertise to make
this a more successful established
industry and avoid the pitfalls and the
mistakes done in North America and
Israel
yeah thank you is very important I agree
um Alex what do you say what role does
collaboration
um play and how can everyone address
these issues of oversaturation and
ensure that there's a more effective
distribution of products in the market
so
um yeah
um
the authorities in Germany are very
different and to get products into the
market is often a challenge for foreign
producers and in the end to make an
example Bavaria you can import medical
cannabis flowers as an API if you
irradiate them then you need an approval
by the German bee farm then it must be
cultivated under GMB conditions and the
development last six or seven years it's
a very good development we have now the
knowledge with all the Audits and all
the GMP gsap GDP guidelines which yeah
there was a there was a way from the old
pharmaceutical Market into the medical
cannabis market so the development I
would say is very good of course
yeah you still have
or you still have to take some some
challenges in Germany because
um you know for example I know an
example from Northland Westphalia they
have to produce other GMP conditions on
the end and maybe another company has to
do it on a gsep conditions to produce a
product so
um yeah sometimes it's not easy for
producers to launch products here and
yes we have an oversupply in the German
market right now
in 2000 in 2017 I thought hey when
everybody built a facility we have so
much Supply worldwide who can smoke all
all the flowers and take the extracts
but in the end okay we have an
oversupply and I should or I would say
every company has to focus on themselves
there will be something on stock you
cannot sell in the in the industry or in
the market that's the truth but in the
end that it will come to this point it
was clear in the past and now you have
to stay or you have to survive and to
offer where high quality product or it's
a patient-driven market for for the
flowers
um and in the end I would say focus on
yourself on your on your goals and also
think about new formulations yeah I mean
now we have flowers extracts a lot of
companies are thinking about more and
new dosage forms Etc are the key for the
future yeah it's a great keyword that
you're saying that that would have been
my follow-up question how do you see the
role of pharmaceutical practices and
standards in shaping the future of the
whole European cannabis industry
I mean very important you always have to
control everything from the from the GMP
cultivation ghcp cultivation GDP and in
the end the monography and all the nrfs
out there now we have a new one for our
cannabidiol you have to know everything
yeah and of course the one thing has an
effect or an impact on the other thing
often the pharmaceutical entrepreneur
says okay
my responsibility ends at the at the
door of the pharmacy
but yeah that's true but in the end you
should also uh know uh the challenges
for the pharmacies because they are
giving it to the patients and if you
produce something and in the end it's
not compliant with the NF or something
like that uh yeah then you'll have a
good product but you cannot give it to
the patients
that's another interesting aspect Adrian
I mean you're a physician also
um we're talking here about cultivation
everybody can cultivate in the end we
need some prescribers who are putting
everything on a prescription so the
patient can have access can you tell us
a little bit maybe about what kind of
leg work is necessary for advancing
medical knowledge and improving patient
access because I think that's something
that people are underestimating a lot
yeah I mean of course education is one
of the most important things as long as
it's still a purely Medical Market there
might be some changes coming up you're
probably aware of the draft legislation
that is coming out that might be that
the status of cannabis as a narcotic
changes and it becomes an RX that would
at least
help prescription in in a lot of ways
that it makes it much easier for many
doctors to prescribe it because um I
think what people underestimate when I
talk to my former colleagues for example
from from my studies many of them have
never given out an aquatic drug
prescription it's something that is
relatively unusual to do and so it's
really something new so what we're for
example doing is we're inviting doctors
over to our facility and providing like
a first-hand impression on how medical
cannabis is cultivated and so that they
also can see the product smell the and
so far the feedback has been really
really positive even if you invite
people that you don't invite because
they are already in the Cannabis field
but you invite them because they are at
the forest way possible away from it the
feedback was always very positive that
when they learn and understand what
cannabis can do
um that they are supportive of it
afterwards
um David uh maybe back to you uh what
are other risks and opportunities that
you see associated with investing in
cannabis cultivation Ventures especially
considering that we have this fragmented
market dynamics and Regulatory hurdles
in Europe
well I was I woke up this morning
received the article on my phone from
Forbes Magazine and it said that canopy
growth at uh
has destroyed
19 billion U.S of value over the last
five or six years they've got about 400
million left that said they're going to
be insolvent so one of the risks of uh
importers of cannabis flowers from from
Canada and elsewhere is the supply chain
risk of the of the underlying companies
they're bringing in from there's very
much pain in Canada
right now uh all companies are losing
you know a Bunches of money not all
tributable to the Europe of course but
there's a supply chain risk when
bringing in uh from suppliers that
aren't reliable longer term
uh so what I would do is Hitch my wagon
to someone that's going to be there a
while and not losing money they the the
Canadians right now are able to sell
product
uh
below cost because they have an
unlimited public money supply for for
right now but that that'll soon change
so I think uh sticking together uh uh
you know partnering with suppliers that
are there for the long run I think is
key to being a successful Distribution
Company in the long term
and then
um as far as the the capital markets
right now
the the the the sentiment uh for for
cannabis capital is
as low as I've ever seen it uh because
the the sentiment in the U.S the
sentiment in Canada the sentiment really
never got too euphoric in the in Europe
but the sentiments is low as I've seen
it
um
I was telling somebody last time I asked
somebody for equity in a cannabis
company they punched me in the face okay
it's not it's not a popular thing right
now so it makes it very challenging for
companies out there
to expand their operation build their
grows
you know do things right so what happens
in a cannabis business in the states and
elsewhere
companies tend to cut corners on the
design of their facilities because they
don't have access to Capital they do
things wrong they don't set it up right
very important that you design
facilities to control the cultivation
process precisely
we spared no expense in Spain as we
built out
our well we acquired the greenhouse
which is 1.6 million square feet state
of the art but on the conversion of
cannabis on a small portion of that we
spared no expense to make sure we had
control of every aspect of the
cultivation process and that cost a lot
of money but I knew that if we didn't do
it we'd be in trouble like like many of
those before us that have had trouble
with cultivation and I see it in
Portugal
not you but some companies have ceased
operations because they had trouble with
cultivation it's it's about a thousand
things that can go wrong if you don't
have the proper facilities to produce
that cannabis reliably
you're going to run into a lot of
problems
thank you so Vera you're a marketer and
you studied business administration and
business management in Boston and in
Switzerland
so how do you what do you think what
strategies should be employed to
establish and expand the presence in
global cannabis markets and do you
approach building corporate Partnerships
or how are you dealing with this topic
well I think that David touched a bit on
it I think it's a time in the industry
we're called consolidation needs to
occur there's lots of companies
struggling because they did cut corners
and did not manage to create the
infrastructures that are required to
grow cannabis you said before Lisa that
growing cannabis anybody can grow
cannabis it's true anybody can grow
cannabis but not anybody can grow it
properly and that's the biggest struggle
in this industry if you don't cut
Corners like David says and if you do
invest everything that it takes to grow
a proper flower then your chances to
make it are very very high and the point
is that there are so many companies
struggling and so many that don't
deserve to struggle because they are
very good those need that's where we
need to take be
keep our eyes open and find them and
consolidate our efforts because that's
that's the path to this new era in
cannabis in medical cannabis to pave the
way another thing is to stay ahead of
the game and make sure to be Innovative
we have an r d
division in Israel that is working on
New pathologies on new formulations for
pathologies and that's the future for
this industry because as cultivation is
going it's becoming increasingly more
difficult the investment is very heavy
and the price of the Cannabis flower is
being is going down tremendously to the
point of a commodity where the Pharma
regulation does not allow it to be a
commodity priced product
so that's where we need to focus to
focus on consolidation to focus on where
we can make a difference and to make
sure that the governments and the
regulatory regimes that keep us working
will help us sustain this industry and
another thing is the sustainability it
was spoken before
how sustainability is critical in in the
future
there's this common miscon misconception
that only indoor cultivation is correct
and keeps makes consistency and allows
for high quality flowers well you have
to consider that countries like Portugal
or Spain or
sun-driven countries where we can expand
on greenhouse and enjoy the benefits of
what nature provides us while lowering
our footprint are definitely the path
forward
thank you thank you very much
um so let's have a warm Round of
Applause before we open the floor
questions
are there any questions in the audience
foreign
from Netherlands so what I actually see
when you have a mature plant-based
industry then usually you have
separate professional breeding companies
small number then you have a lot of
producers cultivating
the crop and then you have a limited
number of processing industry
making me maybe half products and then
you have
companies that make the final products
like a food or a medicine
so what I see is in in the Cannabis
industry this is not
happening it's it's out of balance I
think that's that's a major problem
so how can we change that and just
invest in a few very professional
breeding companies have good
producers cultivators
and have a good professional processing
industry for medicines pharmaceutical
companies so so I think
now what I I see is that companies tend
to do everything from breeding up to
making the products and maybe they're
all very specialized
businesses that need to be in in
different companies
the first I'd
um yeah I think you're right the the
regulatory framework is just very
difficult in the current situation so if
you think about a nursery concept it's
currently pretty complicated to export
plans from one facility to another in
another country but we're seeing that
that's happening in most of the states
in the in the US
so um I think it's definitely moving in
that direction but the framework is just
very complicated to to make it possible
and
um even then for the pharmaceutical
production that's just begun right we're
all learning how to do it how to do it
right to do something uh and do audits
from other companies work together
I'm pretty convinced that it's going in
that way in that way meanwhile I think
it's good to get an understanding of all
the steps a little bit also like you
said when there is no fully established
industry I think it's good for you to
know a bit of a bit of all the process
in the supply chain but yeah I agree
with you it will be in the future how
long it takes to get there it's very
difficult to say and I think depends on
changes in regulatory Frameworks
somebody wants to add anything
and even if you separate
during the supply chain you have
somebody who's doing the extraction Etc
the logistic companies uh everybody is
working together I know that
um or they are not separated from each
other
um and in the end yes we have a lot of
companies who are who are taking parts
of this supply chain to get the product
from the cultivation in the end to the
pharmacies in Germany
um I don't know if they are or there are
many companies in the market right now
that's true
um but is it more complicated if you do
it company or everybody's doing let's
say the extraction the next is
responsible for the logistic part or you
do it in-house like Harper does
um in the end it's always very complex
and it's there will not everybody will
survive in the future that's all also a
part of the truth
all right we have one over here
hi thank you so much
I was wondering if you can speak to uh
hemp cultivation in terms of industrial
applications
my understanding is at this point we
have Mercedes Audi as well as BMW having
a
biocarbon stemming from hemp so what do
you see the role of all of that here in
Germany thank you
anybody wants to I think most of the
panelists here have their focus more on
the medical parts or the industrial hemp
part
is not really represented on this panel
I reckon
um yeah but uh if you want I can connect
you to the expert in our industry
Association in Germany for that topic
and then you can discuss it with him let
me ask you then on the medical side
because there's been a lot of discussion
of uh THC derived from hemp or different
terpenes derived from yeah and the hemp
and cannabis are really the same thing
um THC level that's that's something
that's a very tricky thing we need to
talk more about standard of identity of
individual products and on the complete
value chain that they are produced in
and here we are looking at Medical value
chains it's something completely
different and the hemp value chains that
are mostly laid out for producing fiber
and seeds yeah but if you really look at
these things like cannabinoids and
cannabis resin it's still in the in the
bad schedule of the global drug policy
so we all have to do something in that
regards to First free debt so the
therapeutic potential can be used and
the industrial potential for Cosmetics
for foods and other fast-moving consumer
goods like smoker bills inhalables and
so on so forth but that's an entire
different panel I guess
yeah
actually that was exactly my question
too I was I was going to delve into the
the food and the nutrient uh aspects of
cannabis because the discussion is
Market saturation and just anecdotally
like in at can of Portugal last year I
had a bunch of old Farmers coming to me
and saying Hey how do I rip up all my my
apple trees and replace it all with with
hemp how do I rip up all my
um banana trees and replace it with hemp
and I said you know hemp For What and it
would the answer was universally flour
and and it's like well you know we we've
already seen that in North America like
everyone died dove in to to do flower
but I mean there's still plenty of
medical or at least health related uh
constituent the aspects of the
constituents of this plant can provide
such as the oil such as the seeds I mean
I'm vegan and a lot of my protein comes
from him it's a great vegan ingredient
but that is something that we need to
discuss more but alone in the medical
sector we can already see that there's a
lot of over supplied we've seen the same
thing in CBD actually like there was a
spike it was a hype yeah I will talk
about it in my presentation and a little
bit
um and after that hype like we had a
couple of hundred companies that have
been Consolidated the prices of the
entire Market have dropped
um three years ago or four years ago you
could get over 20 000 Euro for a kilo of
CBD I said that cost you now 600 euros
so all this Market is messed up as well
but again this is all negatively
affected by the drug status and that's
something we need to work on so we can
really use the economic potential use it
as a food stuff and so on so forth and
in Europe here we have the additional
challenge of Novel food where for
example cannabinoids need to be
registered so they are safe and can be
handed out on a safe scale to end
consumers
well that was great very comprehensive
let's hear from the panel do you have
anything we have like two minutes left
if there's anything else you want to say
are there any more questions I don't
know is there one more question regard
to Medical you've taught them everything
let's hear it again for the panel one
more time right