a little overview let's hit for for Bill
Whitney everybody but waiting so I want
to thank ICBC for hosting this event and
I've been really impressed by not only
the quality of the speakers but also the
quality of the participants of the
conference so hats off to you guys
really appreciate it really appreciate
the opportunity to speak for in front of
you today um there'll be a little bit of
overlap from the previous preventer or
presenter but he seemed a little bit
preventer because he was telling it like
it is but you know so my name is beau
Whitney I'm the senior economist at new
frontier data and I've been in the
industry about five years now and never
in my wildest dreams did I think that as
an economist I'd be talking about weed
in Berlin you know I mean it's just
phenomenal but I think that's
representative of just the pace of the
transformation of the cannabis industry
so today I'm going to talk about a
global cannabis outlook I'm gonna first
talk high level and then pare it down
into the European Union I'm going to
talk about higher THC cannabis adult use
and medical but I also want to touch
upon this emerging industry of the
industrial cannabis as well so a little
bit about new frontier data new frontier
data is a independent technology driven
analytics company and we're specialized
in the cannabis industry
we offer vetted data that is actionable
it's good business intelligence and it
looks at risk management as well we're
four years old and we have in that for
years we've been cited in over 82
countries with our data we have a media
reach of 7 billion impressions so we've
really been considered an authority on
cannabis data so
the way that we get our data is that we
reach into certain aspects of the
industry all aspects so we get
governmental data NGO data stayed and
provincial regulator data and then we
also marry that with consumer data
ancillary data and point-of-sale data
and we agglomerate all that data into a
business intelligence portal called
eques o and then from there we can have
consumers subscribe to the portal or we
can do custom the report and advisory
services some of our business partners
and clients are some of the largest in
the world from Bloomberg to Boston
Consulting Group but we've also touched
upon even the smallest of actors in the
space because we want to do our best to
look at all facets and all channels of
the market so over 60 countries around
the world have now legalized either
medical cannabis or industrial hemp and
so when you as operators and investors
even though it may be a local issue for
you
you really have to think global about
this you know we the previous presenter
talked about things going on in in South
Africa also you know advancements in
Mexico so there's this pace of
legalization that's sweeping the globe
and so this is a real exciting time to
be in this industry
so in terms of total demand roughly
based upon our analysis roughly 6% of
the adults in the world have consumed
cannabis in the last year so that
translates into almost 300 million
consumers if you look at Germany right
now what arguably twenty to forty
thousand patients have used got
prescription in the last year so even in
Germany there's this huge untapped
market that's associated with cannabis
so cannabis is
this is just the tip of the iceberg in
terms of overall demand now some
continents have higher usage rates than
others it's not uncommon for consumers
and legal markets to have higher
percentage of usage rates Africa is has
a long tradition of cannabis use and and
cultivation and alike but Europe is
right about where the average is across
the globe 6% vs. 5.9 now how does that
translate into dollars well we are in
the process of publishing a global
reports on cannabis it's due out next
month and our forecasts for the total
globe with just higher THC cannabis not
including industrial hemp it's three
hundred forty four billion dollars and
it ranges from 200 billion to five
hundred billion but the midpoint is
right right around three hundred forty
four billion dollars so there's just
once again it's this huge market that is
relatively untapped so as consumers
transition from illicit to legal
there'll be this greater opportunity for
you as you get into this market Europe
is the third largest it's on our
forecast at sixty eight billion dollars
Asia is just this tremendous market a
lot of its population driven but it's
also usage driven as well now
although we're in Europe a lot of the
speakers have talked about the Canadian
market in the US market and I've seen a
lot of eye rolls from the Europeans
present here but it's because there's
this legal market and it's because of
the size of the market that it's setting
the precedent for other countries to
follow so Canada is making good inroads
on their legalization it's not without
its weaknesses but definitely it's it's
setting the stage for others to follow
but in 2018 or I'm sorry
twenty
19:16 billion dollars of legal sales in
Canada and the u.s. combined and that's
growing to thirty two billion dollars by
2025 so and that doesn't even include
some of the emerging states like New
York New Jersey etc so the growth there
is phenomenal and so you can ride the
tide now in order to capture larger
markets later now because there's this
popularity in the US because there's
this large market in the US and Canada
investment funds have been I'm investing
tremendous amounts into the cannabis
space so since 2015 over nineteen
billion dollars having been invested in
North America now how does that apply to
Europe well the 19 billion dollars is
being accumulated and then redeployed
into other markets like Europe like
Africa and Latin America but it's a
couple there's a couple of notable items
that the pace of this investment is
accelerating you know 13 almost 14
billion dollars of investment just last
year alone and it was driven primarily
by some of these large players into
space such as Constellation Brands then
in their investment into canopy growth
and then all Trias investment into
Cronos so combined they're it's almost
six billion dollars of investment and
what that means is that big actors big
players are coming into the space so if
you're a small actor that's already
established then you really should have
an exit strategy associated with this so
that either you can be acquired by the
large actors or that you can understand
where you're at relative to the market
so I know a lot of people say well why
should I have an exit strategy when I
haven't even begun operations but it's
really important to have that already
established so that when the market
turns or modernization of prices occur
then you'll know where you stand and you
can you know
either get out or join forces with
others so in terms of the European
market like I mentioned 68 billion
dollars of the total addressable market
that's illicit and legal combined I
listed the top 15 markets here in
Germany ranks roughly third almost ten
billion dollars now all these numbers
are in dollars so I'm just moving
forward for the presentation but at 10
billion dollars that's a sizable market
it's relatively untapped it's only
medical but that's a huge opportunity
and so this is the attractiveness
because there's large markets there's
large potential and relatively untapped
that's why a lot of folks are preparing
to enter into this space either from
North America Latin America or Africa
now one of the ways that companies can
differentiate themselves is through
technology either to drive efficiencies
or differentiation and technology is
entering into this space at a massive
pace and it's disrupting a number of
sectors and all sectors actually so
between
cultivation processing delivery
mechanisms and data a lot of these are
are being invested in and disrupting so
you need to be aware as a as a investor
and as a operator that these
technological advances are occurring so
that you can keep pace with them now a
lot of these technology innovations are
because the consumer behavior is
changing as well so new frontier data
just published one of the largest
consumer data reports in the history of
cannabis and we its US and Canada based
but what we did is we did this consumer
survey and then we married
with six billion dollars of
transactional data to ascertain what the
consumer preferences were and then where
they sit relative to the overall use of
spectrum
so there's we've identified nine
different archetypes of consumers and
each one uses four different reasons
each one uses different amounts and they
have different preferences in terms of
delivery mechanisms and so this is
important to know as operators because
if you're targeting one product to the
wrong archetype then you're not going to
be successful so understanding the
consumer is critically important and now
for the first time we've got the data to
show the preferences and alike now
there's no longer just this medical and
recreational users and so this is a
deeper dive into the consumer behavior
and preference and so there's nuances
associated with this no it's interesting
based upon the survey results it's
interesting that the reasons that
consumers are using are not just for
social it's more so for wellness and
health and this is very interesting for
me because in yesterday's presentations
on the medical side there was a lot of
data being presented on the impact that
cannabis has on the human body and that
Alliance almost identically to what
consumers are using cannabis for for
relaxation stress relief sleep etc and
so this is what's surprising um
compared to what you know we were
talking about yesterday but if you look
at this only 19% use cannabis just
because they were bored you know I
wanted to do it socially now in addition
to that cannabis has medical
applications and 73% of the consumers
that are surveyed actually have used
cannabis as a substitute for other drugs
and this is showing up not only in
consumer patterns but also in federal
budgets and and the federal spending on
healthcare etc and so other countries
are interested in this development
because they want to look at their
healthcare expenditures in like Germany
for example and adjust accordingly and
support more cannabis use rather than
opioid use for as just an example but
94% of the consumers surveyed said that
when they use it for a medical reason
that there was some improvement and so
this is just another example of you know
why there's a benefit to doing more of a
deeper dive into the cannabis space no I
mentioned here's some data from the US
but I mentioned that as cannabis is used
as a substitute for other medicine
they're reducing the healthcare costs of
other at the federal level so in this
example 11 percent reduction in
governmental pain medicine spending for
healthcare so other countries are I'm
seeing this result in the United States
and as a result they're looking at this
as a way to adjust their healthcare
costs and address budget deficits in the
life so as more and more researches out
there and more and more usage behaviors
change so does the demand for the the
canvas products and originally
especially in the United States this was
a flower play and the majority of the
demand was in flower form pre-rolls etc
but as delivery mechanisms and
technology came in innovation then there
was different product offerings to
different delivery mechanisms and as a
result the consumer preference
and purchasing patterns changed so you
know over you know five three year
period demand for flour went down thirty
nine percent in the United States
whereas there were increases in
concentrates edibles and other delivery
mechanisms so there's a fundamental
shift in away from flour and into
derivative products and this isn't just
a u.s. phenomena this is a phenomena
that exists in all the cannabis markets
so consumer preferences change as well
based upon other disrupting factors and
so we've listed five here I'm not going
to read this whole thing but essentially
as legal access expands as social
acceptance increases then the the
changes in preferences of the consumer
adjusts to the environment and so these
this is a transformational event where
consumers change their preferences
change what they consume and as business
owners and as investors you have to be
aware of these disruptive factors so
that you're not left behind and so new
frontier data can provide that level of
granularity and the data and so that you
can keep pace and understand the markets
better so I've talked a lot about higher
THC cannabis so I'd like to switch gears
a little bit to lower THC industrial
cannabis as well so because this is a
big market that is rather
underappreciated and so I wanted to talk
a little bit about this as well
because there's a lot of business that's
conducted in industrial hemp in Europe
so new frontier data just acquired the
hemp Business Journal it's a very
respected journal in the United States
and so we brought on expertise for
industrial hemp and so our forecast here
shows that on a global basis there
there's a three billion dollar global
market right now that's occurring this
is a legal market
I mean it's increasing its doubling
essentially over the next two years so
and Europe is the biggest driver right
now in industrial hemp but there's
emerging markets that are coming in that
could disrupt or displace Europe as one
of the more mature markets so just for
to level set the the bright shining
object these days is CBD and so
everybody is is focusing and on the CBD
market but there's industrial
applications consumer applications
textiles food supplements and the like
and you know for example BMW uses
industrial hemp on the interior of their
cars so there's this huge industrial
application associated with it that
nobody's really talking about but
there's a huge market well beyond the
CBD play so I'm just I've got a few more
slides so I've got about five minutes so
hemp industry in Europe is farther along
now these are global numbers but they're
a billion-dollar market and textiles 800
million dollars and CBD for just hemp
derive CBD almost 800 million dollars in
industrial applications but if you look
closely at this chart you'll see that a
majority of this demand is being
satisfied by the European market and so
but as the US reacts a legalization of
industrial hemp look for the u.s. to
start flexing its muscle now there's
opportunities there that the Europeans
can take advantage of in the US market
so whereas a lot of other countries are
targeting the European market for market
entry strategies the Europeans with
their expertise in industrial hemp can
take advantage of the opportunities in
the US market as well
and the hemp market in Europe is very
diverse currently it's mainly on the
industrial like I mentioned and CBD but
the the market is shifting over more
towards consumer products and wellness
brands and so and that's just a small
percentage of the current revenues
derived from industrial hemp in Europe
now I talked about a little bit about
the demand for hemp products but it's
interesting on the supply side a lot of
the supply of industrial hemp products
is coming from China and Canada right
now with France also doing it being a
distant third in the space but look for
increases in cultivation not only in the
European Union but in places such as
Africa and Asia and South America and
that in itself will have an effect on
pricing and the like commoditization of
pricing so as business owners in the
hemp space you're going to need to be
aware of those outside influences on
localized market so some key takeaways
300 million consumers huge opportunity
they're surging investment that is being
deployed around the globe but the CPG
entrants big tobacco alcohol pharma are
providing the liquidity for the
advancement and development of the
cannabis space if you are an operator
now be sure to use technology be sure to
use data in order to drive efficiencies
so you can keep pace with the
competition and you know the European
market is a target of a lot of suppliers
from outside but what you'll see in the
coming years is that there's going to be
a consolidation but overall just in some
right now because I want to give some
time for questions
you know this is a global market 60
countries and then some and you're here
in Berlin you're operating in Germany or
France or Italy what have you you really
have to think about the global aspect of
this and and adjust accordingly so as
you act local you have to think global
otherwise you'll be left behind and
there's this tremendous opportunity that
you just you want to take advantage of
right now so at that point thank you
very much for for listening I'll take a
few questions if there are any thank you
very much but let's hear it for both we
have time for one or two quick questions
there's one over there please be brief
no rambling we're trying to catch up I
know we started a little late everybody
was a little how do you say hungover in
German hey thanks for taking my question
in Canada there's been some anecdotal
evidence fairly convincing but still
anecdotal that people have been
rejecting what they perceive as poor
quality government weed and staying with
their supplier do you see that the black
market presents any challenges at this
point or has that ship sailed the way
that I view the the illicit market
relative to legal market is not
necessarily on quality it's based upon
price we've done elasticity analysis
which means pricing sensitivity by the
consumer and the data is very convincing
that if that consumers don't want to pay
too much of a premium to do things
legally so as a result if there are tax
too much if there's too much of a price
markup they'll just revert back to the
elissa market so with respect to Canada
what's occurring there is that due to
supply shortages and the like the lack
of access at the retail level there's
not enough supply and so prices are high
especially with a one dollar per gram
tax that's just asinine but so what it's
doing is it's driving the
the consumer back into the illicit
market so once prices commoditized and
lower and they're more price competitive
relative to the illicit market then
you'll see more market conversions the
the consumer conversion i've modeled it
it's super easy to predict and it's all
based upon price all right well thank
you very much let's hear one more time
but whitney the vp from new frontier
data that was very informative and we
really appreciate you brother thanks for
coming