thank you and thank you to Alex for
hosting this fantastic event we are all
very pleased to be here I have very good
steamed colleagues on my panel today we
are the Canadian component of cannabis
I'm just gonna turn it over to my panel
to introduce themselves I will be doing
just a couple of presentations so that
you can get to know us a little bit
better and know what services we offer
in Canada and how we can help you raise
capital and go public if that's
something that you're looking at doing
so I'm just gonna turn it over and if
you wouldn't mind introducing yourself
hi my name is Anna Saran I'm director of
listings development with the Canadian
Securities Exchange we are a stock
exchange on the other side of the border
and hosts the most cannabis companies
than any other Stock Exchange
we are also open for business for US
companies which has has been great
things for us and put us on the map hi
my name is Maru freznar I'm with a I'm
the accountant in the room I'm with a
firm called M&amp;P in Canada we got in very
early when Canada was legalizing medical
about five six years ago we act for
probably half the issuer's in Canada and
since then we've broadened our scope to
obviously we were the only firm in
Canada that'll really do us listings and
now globally you know we're working
where anywhere cannabis is legal we're
trying to bring them into Canada and
help help some of our people there hi
good afternoon my name is Mark Lawson
and I represent Claremont Capital
Partners I'm based in Toronto and I'm
really here wearing two hats one being a
director of a listed company on the
Canadian Securities Exchange so here
with the rest of the team to promote the
virtues of accessing capital and listing
on the Canadian market to number two
also representing overseas family office
that invests in the cannabis space my
name is John Kirk I'm a stockbroker from
Vancouver BC we are a Canadian based
dealer we have a wholly owned subsidiary
called Hayward USA we finance a lot of
cannabis companies private public and we
have the unique ability that we can
service us investor
that are investing in Canadian listed
companies and we can deal with all the
legends all the resale restrictions and
this has been a fantastic opportunity
for us where investors we provide
service and happy to talk to any of you
after great thank you guys I'm just
going to start by introducing you to
stock house in general for those of you
who are unfamiliar with what we do we
are one of the largest small cap
investor bases in Canada we have over
1.3 million unique online investors
every month visiting our site so it's a
hugely trafficked financial portal our
membership is basically we have over 8
million visitors a month and they're
coming to our site to do their due
diligence and research any publicly
traded company with a ticker symbol on
any North American exchange and do their
due diligence we aggregate content so
you can look at stock charts you can
look at quotes you can look at any press
releases and materials of your favorite
companies and basically our investors
are looking to invest in the small cap
space cannabis in particular is a huge
component of our site currently and
they're spending time on our site
they're spending up to nine minutes so
they're really looking and reading and
researching what investment
opportunities are out there currently we
have a membership base of over 400,000
members and one hundred and thirty six
thousand opt-in subscribers in our email
component so membership is free on stock
house and we have sort of a unique
component online it's called our bull
boards and our bull boards are an
unmoderated almost chat that our
investors are going to to communicate
with each other again by ticker symbol
to discuss investment opportunities
what's going on with the company etc so
there's a lot of communication every
week we put out our top buzz on the bull
boards and it's basically the most
viewed stocks on site which really gives
you an idea of you know what
Nestor's are looking at what companies
they're keen on that sort of thing as
well interest on stock has has changed
significantly in the last 18 months we
have traditionally we've been around for
about 25 years and traditionally we were
I have a lot of interest in mining and
metals in 2018 with cannabis coming on
the same that's completely turned itself
around with cannabis tech blockchain
that's well over 60 percent of what our
retail investors are looking for and
looking at online our top reads again
are significantly in cannabis so we have
a new investor just to give you an idea
of what the landscape is looking at
looking like in the retail investment
community finally the Millennials have
come in to capital markets so you know
18 months ago people were saying oh no
Millennials aren't going to invest in
public equity they're not going to look
at that there may be looking at
crowdfunding maybe but cannabis has
completely changed that capital markets
they proof the capital markets
completely wrong so we have
significantly increased our millennial
investor on site and Millennials are
quick on the uptake so they're looking
for things they can relate to and that's
why cannabis fit the bill for them so
well
so it's a great audience that you can
target to teach them about your company
what you're doing and really get the
word out there and amplify your message
as far as what makes you unique and as
you sort of go look start to look at
going public and work down that road
just letting people know what your
milestones are with your company that
you're you're planning on hitting on
that note I'm going to turn it over to
Anna sarin again she's with the Canadian
Securities Exchange and she can speak a
little bit more about what the CSA does
and how they can help take you public
thank you Cindy's room
keep going hi um if I get a show of
hands in the room how many of you are
investors oh what a great room like I
said my name is Ana sarin I'm with the
Canadian Securities Exchange I'm gonna
get into some information about what it
looks like to go public so hopefully I
don't bore you too much we are based out
of our main operations are in Toronto
I'm based out of our Vancouver office
and basically what happened is there was
a change in the healthcare program in
Canada and we took the stance as a stock
exchange that we would allow companies
to list with us that we're applying for
their application the other exchanges
decided that you need to already have
your application and the way that the
platform was built out you had to grow
your facility build your facility to get
to that place which obviously requires a
large amount of capital and it's very
difficult to go and go find those sons
of capital you can't go into a bank and
borrow the money so the opportunity for
us allowed these companies to come
flooding to us at the same time what
happened as the retail investor
absolutely adored the product so they
were willing and happy to invest in the
space so this started around 2014 on the
Canadian side out of the 475 companies
that we host about a hundred and twenty
five of them are in the canvas space
about 50 of those have u.s. assets the
u.s. entrants came in our first
application from US company was a golden
leaf holdings and that was in 2015 I
love this chart so the CSE is a
overnight 15 year success and you can
see as we as we checked along you know
slowly growing as an exchange what's
happened over the past few years has
very much been driven by the cannabis
sector we have 124 cannabis related
issuers that's growing so quickly that
this is probably already out of date
25 billion enterprise value of cannabis
companies and 2.6 billion dollars was
raised in the US cannabis sector in 2018
again it's happening so quickly that
number is probably much more this one's
really interesting to watch so take a
look at the u.s. one in 2017 and the
numbers that were raised versus 2018 and
what we're seeing the trend is is that
the Canadian space although it did quite
well we have some issues with our
legalization process so a lot of these
companies although they have huge market
capitalization they don't actually
generate a huge amount of revenue and
the retail investor is starting to
figure that out
but the US companies and where the
opportunity there is on this side the
border is you have fantastic companies
that actually generate revenue that
actually have assets and so you're
seeing a lot of the Canadian companies
in the space start to go into
consolidation mode they have a lot of
capital they don't have a lot of
business so they're coming on this side
of the border and they're trying to
gobble up as many US assets as they can
as well US companies are just coming on
our side of the border to go public this
really is starting to become a global
play and my hope is that you know we had
the opportunity over the past few
decades to be known across the world in
the jr. space for the resource sector
and mining I'm hoping that we'll be the
next leaders in the cannabis space like
I said there's lots of consolidation
that we're starting to see and
consolidation you know really there's
just so much ability to raise capital
that people are racing out there the
other thing that I'm starting to see and
it's mainly on this side of the border
is at the branding side of things so
everyone's racing to create their band
there's there's obviously a lot of
product that's coming to market so it's
really hard to stand out everyone wants
to be the next coca-cola of cannabis
I'll try and go through this part pretty
quickly because it's just technical
information about what you need to go
public
but please do if you if you ever have
any questions give any of us a call at
the exchange we'll happily walk you
through the nuts and bolts of it you
basically need to become a qualifying
sorry qualify as a reporting issuer you
have to be an active business have
sufficient public distribution and meet
share structure guidelines there's a few
different ways that you can do this not
all are the absolute perfect way but for
each unique company
there might be one Avenue that is better
for you than another so make sure that
you're working with the right people who
understand Capital Markets and can guide
you down this road so the first route is
obviously the IPO that's probably what
most people understand the initial
public offering and people take this
route and start as a brand new company
they'll follow prospectus with our
Commission and raise capital at the time
they go public also gaining their
shareholders the next route is called an
RTO so this is traditionally for a
company that had an active business it
didn't succeed and they want to create
shareholder value so they're gonna
acquire a new asset sometimes this is
the right move for your individual
company but it does have its own
glitches in it so quite often if the
company was in an active business
outside of the space you need to do a
change of business you need to get
shareholder approval so there are some
added steps to it there's also an on
offering prospectus and that's
essentially for a company that already
has their shareholders you need at least
150 you'll already have your working
capital so all you're doing is filing a
prospectus with the Commission and going
public typically people will take this
route because the shareholders that come
into the private company it provides
them with an exit strategy there's
something else called shells and I get
this call many times a day we don't have
a shell program and what a shell program
is is when somebody builds a company
with no intention of putting in a
business they then go and seek out the
business once that's been built to bring
that into it so we don't have a shell
program at the CSC but our listing
requirements are much less less arduous
than other exchanges so there really
isn't any reason
you shouldn't be able to go through the
RT or IPO process business requirements
demonstratable Revenue recent history is
a listed company aka if you were listed
on another exchange minimum working
capital and resources to achieve stated
objectives for twelve months following a
listing we don't tell you what you need
you tell us what you need in the next
twelve months as far as your working
capital requirements if you go the IPO
route the one nice feature we have in
our policies is builder shares so as the
founders of these companies we know that
you guys are all very entrepreneurial
and deserve to reap the benefit of
building these companies up you can you
can offer out twenty-five percent of
your outstanding shares as builder
shares basically a company to be public
it means a hundred and fifty
shareholders ten percent of that needs
to be free trading I would highly
suggest that you always have more than
ten percent you know it's unfortunate
when we see companies stick right to
this and then they go to mark and go
well no one's buying my stock well only
ten percent of people have stock that
they can trade so it's really good idea
to make sure that like I said you're
working with the right groups of people
who are bringing in the right share
holders cannabis companies do have some
added requirements obviously it's still
not federally legal here so you know the
way that we have taken to it is we just
want you to disclose all of those risks
to your shareholders I think for for an
exchange that has four hundred and
seventy five companies I think we have
about a hundred and seventy in the Q's
last number I heard so we're growing
very quickly we see a huge opportunity
in the US and especially in the cannabis
sector we're open for business thank you
for your time
[Applause]
everybody so wanted to briefly chat
about the accounting side not to bore
you guys but but we wanted to talk about
accounting specifically because a lot of
the issuers that are coming north of the
border to get to get capitalized one of
the big kind of bottlenecks that they
end up you know getting into is not
understanding the rules that are
required to go public in Canada so we
wanted to and one of the main items is
the financial statement side so we
wanted to talk briefly about what those
rules are because if you prep in advance
it's gonna save you a significant amount
of time as part of it as part of the
process and you know from a process
perspective you know go public can take
you know two to three months it can take
six to nine months so depending on how
prepared you are with the financial
aspects of your ordeal and none of your
numbers you're gonna end up on the
shorter end of that that that time scale
so the primary requirement if your
company's thinking about going public in
Canada is you need two years of audited
financial statements the beauty from a
Canadian perspective is if you haven't
existed for two years that's okay you
can come in as a new business with less
than two years of operations so
especially for the companies that are in
the cannabis space sometimes they're
newer you know but they have the right
idea and the right team you can actually
go public without having this long
history so if you compare that for
example with the u.s. u.s. usually need
to have three years of operational you
know results that you need to report
which is not the same in Canada so
that's quite attractive from a new
company perspective coming in so again
both yours need to be audited there are
a lot of smaller companies that also
choose to go public in Canada because we
actually have great venture capital
money and so our our public markets in
Canada actually play the role that you
guys may be used to from from a venture
capital on of venture capital money is
raised here so not all of the companies
sitting there with you know 50 million
in revenue we have smaller companies
that do so what the nice thing is that
our exchanges recognize that and so to
provide less burden on those smaller
companies you only need one year of
audited financial statements if your
revenue and assets are under 10 million
so that's quite beneficial it eliminates
a lot of cost burden in terms of going
public so it's something you should
definitely keep in keep in mind
depending on the timing
you'll also need interim financial
statements for your latest quarter you
don't need to have those audited they
are reviewed which is a lower level down
but again it's a little bit more
streamlined and the final financial item
that you'd need that that part as part
of your listing is what's known as a pro
forma financial statement so that's you
know we used the word performer but it's
not a projection it's not how the
company is gonna do it's just a
financial statement that effects the
transaction to say here's how you're
gonna look like as a public company with
all of your shareholders with all of
your financings
and that's not audited or reviewed but
it's something you have to have in the
in the back of your head as part of this
process so one key item for the people
in this room so in in Canada we use
international financial reporting
standards it is different from what you
guys are used to from an American
perspective being US GAAP so for the
international people in the room then
exactly you know what I'm talking about
for Americans US GAAP is not permitted
and there can be substantive differences
so if your service providers or you know
the people you're working with right now
from a financial perspective are not
versed in this it's an area you may want
to think about from an auditor
perspective so obvious as a public
company you're gonna need an auditor
both before and after before you go
public you can use a an auditor that's
not registered in Canada if your public
your auditor has to be registered in
Canada and so we work with issuers and
we have partnerships both in Canada and
the US because obviously not everybody
plays in the in the space as
u.s. and certainly in Canada as well
most firms will not touch anything with
us operations
okay well we'll get into a little bit
more details as we go but that's sort of
the high level great thanks so much for
us alright now that you know a little
bit about who we are and how we can help
you and what we do let's get into
raising capital in the cannabis sector
maybe I can start at the end with John
and Mark you guys have a lot of
experience in this area what kinds of
financings are you seeing in the space
currently what are the company types
that you're seeing and what straits your
growth are they at and what's really
wetting the retail investors appetite at
this point from your perspective so in
the last two years there's approximately
six billion raised in cannabis that's a
lot of money that's been sucked out of
the system I don't think we're gonna see
as much this year I think that the money
is looking for maybe more unique
opportunities you really could have
bought anything 18 months ago and made
some money without doing as much
research as I think you're gonna have to
do now I think the ancillary
opportunities are very exciting this
could be anything package and packaging
transportation security distribution
insurance banking as it relates it's
it's not gonna be as easy but I think
the opportunities have never been
greater there's 200 plus public
companies as I understand right now
there aren't 200 phone companies there
aren't 200 beverage companies I think
we're gonna start to see some M&amp;A in the
coming years if we're talking about the
cultivators at the end of the day it's a
plant it's a strawberry it's a tomato
margins they're gonna are gonna get
squeezed prices are gonna come down
especially as we open up statewide I
think that means more M&amp;A I think you
have to have more scale like John Salley
said if you can find the louis xiii or
the lowest raise or make yourself unique
then then you have an opportunity
whether that cottage brewery type type
model i think you're okay but tom it's
gonna be about costs with the
cultivators and I think the ancillary
businesses are the most exciting for me
and that's where I see a lot of the new
money flowing so I want to touch and I
guess a few things that that John
mentioned
because it's you know it's a very
interesting time as he mentioned the
last 24 months we've seen unprecedented
liquidity and you know we'll see if that
continues but I just want to speak a bit
to evaluations and in my previous life
as a banker would always say valuation
is an art form and not a science so if
you look at you know we take a look at
you know where things are right now a
lot of the u.s. multi-state players are
trading at from a valuation standpoint
an average of about 6.8 times revenue in
about 22 times
EBIT uh which is interesting this
morning was was looking at a research
report focused around some of the
Canadian LPS and maybe this is you know
learn from us Canadians on the stage so
if you look at two of the two of the
bigger players you know canopy the
canopy and Aurora so canopy has about 30
percent market share I think some of the
the Canadian LPS will do about a billion
dollars in sales between wreckin and
medicinal and what's interesting is
canopy in Aurora or already reporting
there QT q2 and q3 numbers for 2019 and
yes tomates that they will report
anywhere from negative 37 to negative 44
million in EBIT ah and that's really you
know as they're ramping up they're
incurring all these costs so so my point
is is we're seeing private companies
that are looking to raise money their
valuations are being underpinned by
therefore looking you know EBIT de and
revenue numbers for 19 and 20 so that
then begs the question as an investor in
a nascent industry like this where
there's very limited history of
operating sometimes you need to take a
step back from the hype because no one
has really started to report yet so it's
really starting to change I think the
way investors are are approaching new
companies and you know we're starting to
feel like it's not enough just to you
know put together a sexy presentation
and project a hundred million in Eva da
for 19 and that's it because we're
starting to see the chickens come you
know come home to roost especially in
Canada in terms of what to actuality
versus you know what I like to call the
formal moment and the high
and as John mentioned there was just
just big retail rush no one wanted to
miss out on the next tremendous
opportunity and we kind of joked that
you know more unicorns were created in
the cannabis sector in a quarter than
probably here in Silicon Valley in the
last two years so you know just to take
a step back I think investors are
starting to look more I mean the
instrument of choice right now is really
convertible debentures and some people
are using caps on valuation to protect
their ounce their upside and downside
but the point I think I'm trying to make
is is as much as there's a lot of
excitement in this industry and I think
it's tremendous what's happening and and
the whole value chain has changed and we
think more people need to be looking as
John mentioned on the ancillary services
whether it's supply chain and logistics
or banking or you know anything else
part of us really need to go back to the
fundamentals of these businesses so
that's really what we're seeing right
now
great thank you guys I was just gonna
say you know I think obviously there's
just been it's been a big hype and we've
seen it going and running for a little
while you know as an investor what I
would start looking at in new companies
coming in is the ability to raise
capital doesn't necessarily mean that
you need to or should so some of these
more tightly held structures might be
something to look at or if you're
looking at going public you don't
necessarily need to raise hundreds of
millions of dollars and dilute out your
shareholders that's really hard to
maintain in good and bad markets so I
would definitely take a look at more
tightly held structures as an investor
perfect Maroof you have seen a lot of US
companies coming to lists in Canada um
can you speak to any major ports of
consideration for a US company that is
considering listing on a Canadian
exchange sure so I think this is
obviously for any company particularly
important as part of a go public
transaction as I indicated your
timelines to go public and can wildly
fluctuate depending on how prepared you
are
going in so some of the stuff we talked
about you know you need to know what it
is like to be you know a Canadian public
company you need to have people who
understand you know the international
accounting rules one particular area on
the accounting side that is specific to
the cannabis industry is in our we're
captured under this agriculture standard
that exists in accounting
the key takeaway for this group is we
have to fair value the accounting plants
as they grow so it's and it ties in to
some of the discussions that were
happening in the cannabis world for
cultivators you recognize your profit
before you sell and it's kind of a weird
rule and there's a lot of like the
judgments and estimates that go into it
that people are wholly unprepared for
and so a big part of that
eBay Dodd that comes in and people are
obviously trying to reconcile it out is
a big sort of non-cash amount that's a
fair value pick up that you that you
basically pick up so you have a
half-grown plant it's 50% well what you
do as you grow is you recognize the
profit on that half grown plant before
you sell it so it's very confusing to
investors you know it's something that
ultimately has to be reconciled so
that's something that there's a lot of
time and effort that goes into coming up
with that modeling and the securities
commissions are looking at that very
closely so that's something you know
from a purely financial standpoint that
you know we need to deal with the other
part and this is particularly a u.s.
issue on the tax side for the founders
on the tax side there's there's there's
a there's a US IRS issue called
inversion and what that is is when a US
company exits into a different
jurisdiction so a company coming public
into Canada as an example in many cases
the US doesn't recognize that as an exit
so they so they consider continue to
consider you as a u.s. entity Canadians
now cuz you're a Canadian company expect
you to be taxed as a Canadian company
and so there's an ability to be there's
a potential risk for double taxation so
it's something we structure around and
and you know we we need to but it's
something we need to deal with because
otherwise you're going to be
a situation where you potentially have
two countries looking at you from a tax
revenue perspective so I think that's
really the the high level great and
maybe you can speak a little bit to what
the benefits are to US companies being
is that's where we are to going public
on the CSE like what why what is the
advantage of a US company listing on
your exchange um well I'm their only
option firstly I know a you know there's
obviously with legislation going on on
this side of the barter border it's
really hard to engage in the capital
markets at this moment in time so your
ability to list in Canada I know it's
probably a little foreign to people to
think about listing their company on on
an exchange in another country but
there's been some real huge success for
US companies and I think everyone has
the desire at some point to grow and
move into a senior exchange and that
doesn't take their ability away what it
does is it lets them start off as a
public company on our exchange enjoy the
benefits of being able to raise capital
anytime that you need to because you're
set up and giving your investors their
exit strategy and anytime you want you
can move to the senior exchanges the
other thing about us is we have a very
close relationship with the OTC markets
so a lot of our companies that do come
and list with us once you're listed with
us were a recognized foreign exchange
with OTC you automatically get your OTC
ticker and now it allows your US
investors to participate in your stock
okay and along those lines maybe John
you can speak to this Heywood securities
is accepting u.s. clients currently so
that's a bit of a change in Canada as
well maybe you can explain how US
investors can actually invest in
Canadian public companies absolutely so
it's been very difficult for a u.s.
resident to invest in a private
placement or prospectus offering most US
banks haven't been able to touch it the
last two years or so
heywood securities through our platform
can actually service the u.s. resident
who wants to access some of these more
lucrative placements when you
participate in a private placement or an
IPO you'll often get a suite
a sweetener that'll be a warrant it'll
give you potentially 50 100 percent more
upside you're really missing out if you
don't get in the deals so to speak we've
seen many in the last year that if you
are in the IPO or the the RTO listing
offering they'd open up at very nice
premiums and you really never had a
chance
many of the platforms in the u.s. there
they're talking about going live I know
through OTC there are some options but
if you want to invest in a Canadian
listed company you're better dealing
with a Canadian dealer we know how the
stocks trade we have more liquidity and
you know it's been a fantastic
opportunity for Haywood because what
we're seeing is we're seeing so many
amazing investors who are investing in
these companies they can't get liquidity
they come to us and these are and this
gives me hope that this markets going to
continue for a while because I'm dealing
with you know X Blackrock guys X Goldman
guys have gone and set up family offices
to participate in these things and
they're telling me that all their
friends on Wall Street they cannot wait
to get into cannabis they have handcuffs
on they think they're gonna come off
this year and I think that really is
exciting because any of us who are
investing now that there truly is a lot
more money that wants to come into the
sector that can't or hasn't figured it
out so that could be the next the next
wave for all of us great thank you just
I'm going to throw this out to all of
you where do you see the next wave
globally in the cannabis sector and
Canada is obviously a global leader in
the sector so what other opportunities
in your perspective do you see coming up
um so I think like when you look at it
at a very macro level you know the last
couple of years certainly in Canada us
is obviously carved out of some of this
discussion just because of the you know
the way the regulations are here but in
Canada the last few years it was an arms
race towards cultivation space who can
raise the most amount of money and grow
the biggest and baddest greenhouse or
cultivation space nobody actually asked
the question is that actually a creative
what's your cost you know because nobody
was paying attention it was what Mark
was saying is people you know we have
this kind of fictitious valuation that
was there
but nobody actually said are these
companies going to be profitable so I
think people are recognizing that you
know cultivation in a place like Canada
is maybe not the highest and best use of
resources and so what we're seeing at a
macro level is a lot of these Canadian
companies that are very well-funded
cultivation is gonna be commoditized yes
there's gonna be a premium element for
the premium brands but most of it is
going to be going into extraction gonna
be going into you know yield so we don't
you don't care you know at the end of
the day what you care about is the cost
and so I think what a lot of the company
the Canadian companies are doing or
other companies that are coming into
into Canada worldwide is it's a focus on
you know low cost cultivation leading to
extraction and then leading to so I
think we're gonna see a lot of that
movement happening and I think Canada is
well capitalized either for those
companies to come to Canada themselves
and become public companies or for the
Canadian you know the big the big guys
to go out and basically security so
we're seeing a lot of Canadian companies
going on and securing licenses in low
cost jurisdictions I think Canada will
continue to be the IP and and capital
center we've done we've done that role
in other industries like like you know
in mining and oil and gas and it's
almost like it's it's replicating itself
in this sector as well I think it's
already starting to happen I mean the
next frontier is really in emerging
markets as an example two weeks ago
farmer Cielo out of Kim Colombia listed
that their stock was probably up to two
or two or three hundred percent so you
know that's really the opportunity I
think if you look around the world you
know sometimes we have a insular view of
our own backyard whether it's in Toronto
or California but as an example if
you're going to sell Paulo or Mexico
City or Lagos Nigeria you're talking
about cities that have 20 million people
do you know with 7% GDP growth and this
is really the opportunity so you know
whether it's the EU we've seen companies
that have already obtained licenses and
in Denmark and Israel wherever the case
may be and and you know we also need to
think about outside of North America
there are other jurisdictions where you
have ideal climates for cultivation all
year-round bogota-colombia
outside of Medellin or excuse me
medicine so you know I think we really
believe I think you know as as
valuations maybe start to get frothy in
North America we really need to start to
look to emerging markets and so ready
starting to happen I mean we're seeing
transactions in sub-saharan Africa you
name it it's it's coming I mean
yesterday somebody was talking to me
about Papua New Guinea which is maybe
it's a tricky jurisdiction in the in the
middle of nowhere not much
infrastructure but I think if you're you
want to expose yourself to returns you
really need to start looking at at the
emerging markets and to your point you
know we can argue that maybe the
cultivation play is getting commoditize
but if you are an LP here and if you
have an export license how do you ship
that product to the EU so hence comes in
the whole supply chain and logistics
piece in the value chain so there's a
tremendous opportunity to really invest
outside of North America in different
parts of that whole cannabis value chain
in the emerging markets yeah I think I
think what you're gonna see kind of in
the near future I think everyone's
really excited to get involved in the
recreational space we've all been in the
medicinal side for a few years as this
has evolved so I think the companies
that I'm seeing kind of really get a lot
of attention in the market is the
companies that are doing the pure
recreational play as well I think you're
also as discuss and Mark said the the
global stuff is really starting to come
to play and I think the people that are
coming to market you know it was we had
a downturn in the small cap space that
lasts about five years and and a few of
us held on but what was nice about this
is really kind of brought and it's been
brought up a few times now it's really
brought in the next generation of
investor and the next generation of
investor has a completely different
experience than than we did when we
started because they have discount
brokerage accounts and they have access
to information that is immediate it's at
their fingertips it's right on their
phone I mean we we don't realize it's
period of time that we've had access
this this immediate to information
definitely would guide people to go and
talk to proper professionals I think
it's going to be tough for investors
we're not quite sure where it's going to
go because we don't understand this new
investor that's come to the table and
and and they're moving along the markets
as they learn ring definitely okay thank
you very much for all your input and at
this point if we are going to throw it
out to you guys yes and please one more
time for Cindy broad and the fantastic
panel is very informative does anyone
have a question anyone Bueller right
here all right you're good you're quick
with the questions here we go Mike
Morgan do you see any company out there
putting together an emerging market
index fund let's take that way I mean
we've seen different some companies like
institutional asset managers starting to
put together funds but to date have not
seen any money asset manners that are
focused strictly on the emerging markets
maybe that's you so there's a there are
some there is a public company in Canada
it's not a fund but it has a focus of
just going and security in securing
licenses you know so there's a couple
like that so that's kind of their
business operational mandate but they're
not a fun I think in Canada there are
ETFs that are cannabis type ETFs but
it's not a emerging market ETF or
anything like that of the ETF or the
company will you can share it offline oh
soon as I sit down my socks here we go I
would like to recommend all the men
wearing fancy socks today this is
regarding price pressure how do you see
the deprives and impossible profit
margins and the curve looked like it
moving forward what are the major
drivers and secondly
a very other product category at the end
of the supply chain that might emerge
that half might have impact on that
profit pressure the accountant I can
answer the first one and and and the
first one and not to be facetious it
like every pitch that we hear across
this room and I'm sure you guys have
heard every person there's two things
they talk about how they're growing
technique is the best and how they are
the lowest cost producer and they've got
it figured out so my until we actually
see those results it's it's impossible
it's impossible to say all I can tell
you is in Canada people are struggling
to get under $1 all-in cost per gram in
the u.s. you know maybe it's a little
bit lower when we see sub-saharan Africa
there are ten cents a gram all in when
we see Columbia there are thirty five
cents a gram all in so you know where
your targets are we know the top lines
right so I don't know where they're
gonna shake out but that's what you're
competing against I think it's it's real
early days and my advice to everyone is
bet on the people people who can execute
they have realistic expectations we've
seen so many of these presentations with
these hockey stick graphs where they're
gonna go from 5 million to 20 million to
200 million in three years and it it's
just not believable I hope it's all true
but as Mark said the chickens will come
home to roost these presentations that
have been used to market and raise
billions of dollars it's it's gonna be a
reckoning for some of these companies
and some of them will execute and I'm
betting on the people who have a track
record not just in in cannabis space but
as businessmen as people people who've
gone to the markets and have had success
year over year different industries
that's what you want to look for no
promoters yeah I think one thing I'll
add is I personally and humbly believe
that you guys have a tremendous
opportunity because one can argue that
regulation in the u.s. kind of made the
junior cop capital markets extinct so
you know unless my numbers are wrong I
believe I think California is the
equivalent of like the fifth largest
economy and
the world so what we see in terms of
difference between the Canadian
companies and the American companies I'm
not being unpatriotic but in the u.s. is
just a history of building bigger brands
or house of brands and much bigger
markets and that's a tremendous
advantage for any entrepreneurs in the
room that want to access Capital in
Canada and list on the CSC I mean shoot
your former Speaker of the House John
Boehner sits on the board of of acreage
which raised probably half a billion
dollars and trades on the CSE so there
isn't a better case study I think for
all of you in the room
III think the other part of it is and
this is where the you know like there's
a big difference between the US and
non-us globally the US this whole
concept of a vertically integrated
operator where the the farmer is the
retailer and the distributor and the
dispensary that's a very like it doesn't
exist in any other industry in the world
right the pharmaceutical company that
makes opiates does not grow opium right
there's not it doesn't it don't start
with poppy seeds and so what so the
question becomes can you be good at
everything can you be the best retailer
and the best farmer
I mean economic history would suggest
otherwise but but because of the way and
Canada was the same because of the way
the rules were written you had to be
right you have to be you know part of
the entire process change so Canada
we're already seeing that right micro
licenses are coming out where you're
gonna specialize you're gonna be
extraction only right you're gonna buy
your product and you you have no
interest in cultivation why would you
you're a pharmaceutical extraction
person what do you know about growing
cannabis right why would you bother
learning right when somebody's doing it
perfectly and efficiently and so I think
from a product perspective who knows
what products are gonna come out but the
segment's are absolutely going to
separate us who knows but rest of the
world it is it is gonna be different
people doing specialized aspects of the
value chain
thank you all so very very much let's
hear it once again for the panel I'm
sorry we're out of time for questions we
have to keep moving on I'm sure they'll
be happy to talk to you on the other
side of the wall over there what would
you like to say you have a microphone I
just let you guys know that we are all
available all day for any questions
stock house actually has a booth that
we're sharing with the CSC in the main
exhibit hall so if you do want meetings
or you want to come pick up a card or
you have any other questions that you
didn't get to ask us please we're all
happy to take your questions I also just
wanted to let you know that we have
partnered with ICBC and MMP and we are
putting on a portion of this conference
with some of the exhibitors that are
here today Garden Society bang just to
name a few
plus products flow canna
Wagoner DMS as well so that online
conference will be on you've got a card
in your bag February 20th at 9:00 a.m.
you can jump on and see everybody
presenting their companies live and then
you can ask questions of all the CEO is
live online as well so it's a text-based
chat you can learn about the companies
and then ask questions directly to the
management teams and the CEOs and that
is produced as part of the event as well
so please be sure and check that out
thank you so much