hello is in many ways has been leading
the global marketplace in cannabis both
in their own country and exporting to
other countries they will soon be
legalizing for all adults cannabis
commerce across the nation and I'm going
to introduce the moderator who will
handle the rest of the panel she's
really all around Rockstar pioneer in
the British Columbia cannabis scene
she's the director for governments for
MMJ Canada she is the director of BC
independent cannabis Alliance and a
partner with groundworks consulting
please give a warm welcome for miss
Jamie Shaw greening the north and
obviously we're gonna be talking about a
lot of Canadian specific details but our
goal is to kind of give you an overview
of what it looks like when an
industrialized nation legalizes cannabis
some of the different things that happen
we've got an amazingly diverse panel
here right now that represents a wide
variety of stakeholders within the
industry first we have Clinton young
Clint is CEO of MMJ Canada which has
eight stores and growing across Canada
we've got licenses in two different
municipalities right now Clint works
closely with the lost organization it's
a mental health division that reflects
Clint's main focus with cannabis it's
called the living outside suffering
trauma and it provides services to
homeless or the under homes that needs
some support because they're also
suffering from mental illnesses so
please welcome Clinton
next up we have Nick Pateros he's the
vice president growth of lift company
limited Canada's leading cannabis media
technology and product platform I would
also point out it's it's pretty much the
only cannabis industry specific media
rather than just cannabis news with a
mission to empower informed cannabis
decisions lyft collects and disseminates
big data with the goal of bridging
informational gaps between buyers and
sellers please welcome Nick Pateros next
up is Robert Lloyd Laurie he's an
international lawyer writer and speaker
qualified qualified as a solicitor in
both England and in Canada he was
Roberts also the chairman advisory board
that's actually changed aren't you
actually a director of Liberty Leaf no
chairman of the advisory it's a Canadian
based public company which also is
will--or asking he comes to Liberty Leaf
with 25 years experience in the
investment brokerage industry most
recently as a partner
senior investment advisor with northern
securities just before we kind of get
into this I'm gonna give a very brief
and very condensed version of how Canada
actually sort of got to where we are
right now in 1969 the then Liberal
government decided that it wanted to do
a study on illegal drugs and on cannabis
it was called the lydian Commission took
them three years when they came back
they actually recommended that cannabis
be legalized nothing was actually done
about that at all for quite a few years
before there was any more kind of
government movement on this there were
battles in the courts lots of battles in
the courts and so courts had decided
that patients had right to access that
they had right to have someone else grow
for them that that person could grow for
more than one person then more than two
persons it was actually just a constant
fight for about 20 years while that was
going on dispensaries sort of exploded
as a gray market option some of them are
actually now
licensed in Vancouver in 2014-2015 when
the ACN part ACM PR was launched at that
point we had the first sort of fully
functioning legal medical system
unfortunately it still didn't work for
everybody in the country particularly
those that were already being serviced
by dispensaries that had a wider variety
of product that they were allowed to
carry we're allowed to talk about the
product more than the licensed producers
were and then in 2015 we got court cases
again decided we're gonna have edibles
at some point and other forms of
cannabis we do have an oil that was
introduced legally following that court
decision but that's all we've actually
seen on that at this point and we've put
medical on hold we you know in 2015 we
elected the first political party to
really run on a platform of full
legalization they won and we've been
sort of waiting to see what's gonna
happen with that first they've been very
clear we're not talking about medical
we're not gonna adjust it or do anything
it's just gonna stay in place we'll look
at it later after we've got some data
back from legalization we know we're
gonna have edibles but they're not even
gonna start talking about that for
another year so we know that that's
coming eventually the government's been
making some huge strides in terms of
easing some of the burdens on the large
licenses creating classes for smaller
licenses including micro producer
microprocessor and some nursery licenses
so we're seeing a lot of movement but we
haven't seen any sort of applications
yet for that and and provinces are
starting to roll out their retail models
we're in the East they're mostly going
to be controlled by government stores
and in the West they're mostly gonna be
private retail mostly still have to buy
from the government in between so with
that sort of as a context of where we
are overall in Canada Clint where are
you nm MJ exactly at within all of that
it's it's a little bit complex for us
because we are a Canada wide based
dispensary which meaning each province
has its own regulations and
as Jamie said Ontario where we're very
strong based out of we're having issues
with the government they want to have
full control over all distribution and
all levels of cannabis I'm working hard
right now with municipalities and
lobbying provincial government because
of the election coming up to have us
carp in either a medicinal and or
recreational component I'm not quite
sure yet how will look for MMJ Canada on
the west coast we have two licenses and
one in a variance with the city so for
us it's it's we have to be very patient
I said this last year when I was here we
had to be very patient and a year later
I still have to be very patient so it's
getting closer to legalization it's
getting closer to us figuring out which
path we're going to be going we are
trying to vertically integrate our
company on many other levels but as of
right now we have to let the the
government kind of unroll platforms and
we need to kind of make our next move a
very strategic one because it could make
or break us so so you guys just
announced that you're going public which
is kind of big news because that hasn't
been on the horizon for most people
that's right what has been going on for
you guys within all of this and yeah so
we play a role in bridging the
informational gap between buyer and
seller so essentially we're Canada's
largest cannabis media and tech company
whether that's through our events our
educational contents or our data
solutions and training services so
essentially the need that we've
identified in the role we play is as I
mentioned closing the informational gap
or the informational asymmetry between
buyer and seller and so where there's
min extremely tight advertising
restrictions and promotional tactics
that have been prohibited by the
government in the past we try to do the
best to inform and empower patients to
make informed cannabis decisions that
was true in today's market in
the medical world it'll be even more
true in the adult use world and so our
role becomes important because we know
that there's a lot of consumers will
come online for the first time or
consumers who have been buying the
category for a number of years but just
unfamiliar with what a legal market
looks like and so the idea is to
cultivate and disseminate the
information to help people make those
decisions nice thank you and Rob you
know you and I are kind of all over the
place with this stuff we've got our
fingers in a bunch of different pies but
overall how's that loosen it where's it
positioned within this whole frame ech
well I'm in a very unique position
because I grew up in the black market
but I also have a law degree from Oxford
University and I used to work in capital
markets in the city of London and on
Wall Street actually one of the firms I
used to work at was the cia's law firm
Sullivan &amp; Cromwell on Wall Street so
when I was done with that work and went
back to Vancouver my hometown I set up
shop with my own law practice well
because again I was known in the
industry and had training education and
experience that is certainly a value to
any emerging industry let alone the
cannabis space I've been very busy
and so with that we've seen a tremendous
amount of change from a few people with
pot to now everybody involved with pot
or cannabis and the proud the pride for
me is that legalization in Canada has
been driven by a court process it's
actually the people who've taken the
federal government to court and we have
in Canada what's called the Charter of
Rights and Freedoms and under the
Charter we have section 7 which is life
liberty and security of the person and
so it's basically through that
[Music]
fundamental right that the cannabis
program in Canada legally is started
going back as far as 2002
rushing fast-forward to today what we're
seeing and again why it's exciting and
frustrating for me at the same time as
we're seeing lots of interesting
endeavors and enterprise and cannabis
however those who have been the pioneers
of the market those who have been the
ones who've gone to jail for the right
to grow cannabis or to produce medicine
are not necessarily allowed to
participate in this new market in fact
Justin Trudeau our prime minister love
him or hate him I have mixed feelings
about him personally but he is agenda
with legalization is threefold
right one is to make our streets a
community safer okay that's an a good
idea
remove the black market and keep and
make it safe for children all of those
are noble endeavors but the execution of
them when you actually get behind and
look at how cannabis is being legally
regulated in Canada it's rather suspect
that those goals and endeavors will
happen
so really to sum up here I'm seeing a
lot if this marijuana industry was like
a roulette game I see red and black
legal illegal the difficulty however is
until we know what the actual rules and
the regulations look like anyone out
there who's an entrepreneur is not going
to know we're there to put their chips
on red or black or what number and then
to leverage to get an investment so I'm
confident and I'm also excited that as
we do see the rules and regulations in
Canada begin to normalize and level out
we're going to see even greater
entrepreneurship but at the same time I
also want to see greater inclusion from
the original og pioneers if you will who
got us this far and so with that and
either an I in and either way you look
at it Canada's a very exciting market so
glad that we're here yeah and you bring
up a very important
I mean one of the weird things to me
about this whole legalization thing is
that there's the it's you they're using
the same tools that they used in
prohibition so there's still some
lessons I think to be learned we'll
where where do you and your company all
fit within this this what's been going
on in Canada yeah yeah well first of all
I'm thankful that Rob is the chairman of
our advisory boards I just let him do
all the talking so but you know with
that said I can speak from the
perspective of a publicly listed company
in Canada we went through the transition
a couple of years ago like many cannabis
startups we went from the mining
industry which was depressed to going
through the whole change of business
scenario and becoming a listed public
company in the cannabis sector and and
through that process you know we've been
able to acquire to late stage applicants
under the ACM PR program which which is
the path one needs to take to to have a
license to to grant you the opportunity
to cultivate and sale sell product and
the medicinal space right now but you
know the opportunity I see for Canadian
publicly traded companies is we're
really at the tip of the spear when it
comes to raising capital and deploying
that capital internationally so specific
to Liberty leaf you know we're listed in
Canada on the CSC we're listed in the
oTCQB in the States and we're listed
here in Frankfurt or and in Frankfurt in
Germany and so the reason I wanted to
come to this conference was to learn
more about the aptitude for the the
German cannabis investor and you know
from what I can see today there's a lot
of interest in cannabis in investing and
so the the the where we fit in the mix
here is you know we're able to raise
capital deploy capital internationally i
I do feel that
the Canadian sector per se is getting a
little saturated when it comes to
licenses and and and what-have-you so
the opportunity we have again having the
platform of being able to raise
capitalists to deploy that whether it's
in Germany or Greece or Malta or you
name it whatever the countries are are
bringing medicinal legislation to the
table we want to be we want to be there
thank you
I also just want to apologize I
shouldn't a sat next to Clint it's like
if we went to high school together we'd
have been the kids in the back of the
class just take that every day one of
the big things for me that was the
biggest surprise in the legalization
process was the inclusion of the
different classes of licenses that kind
of came out of nowhere that was a big
step as you know an advocate lobbyists
that took about five years off my career
so I was kind of surprised to see that
happen so quickly what were some of the
biggest surprises for you
well the the biggest surprise was the
fact that everybody surprised that the
government is late leaving it up to the
province is the fact that everyone in my
industry seems to be shocked that the
government is going about it the way it
is when in reality no one should be
shocked they've always wanted to have a
strong control which is understandable
they've they've always kind of done
things the way they want and I think in
my industry you need to be prepared for
anything that the government is going to
do if you're if you're only
one-dimensional you're gonna be in a lot
of trouble I think you need to be able
to have your fingers in all pots in all
aspects of the industry so you can
prepare for the worst and or the best
pending on how it goes you know the
government has made it clear that
they're gonna leave it up to each
province
you know it's in no surprise to me you
know that it's it's each profit is going
about it drastically differently I I
guess I was surprised a little bit that
there wasn't any inclusion of a
dispensary model in Ontario at all like
really no no even talk about it no if
ands or buts
but it seems like now at the new
election there might be some hope for
that so we'll again have to be patient
wait and see so for myself I think what
I was not surprised about but perhaps I
would like to see the government show
more movement on is the treatment of
medical cannabis is distinct from adult
use cannabis and the regulations right
now very focused on the recreational
market I mean it has been a sprint since
the government announced the bill on
April 13th of last year but with every
iteration of regulations that are
released we continue to see that there
actually isn't a robust enough
distinction between the medical market
and the non-medical market so by way of
example medical cannabis in Canada is
still taxed unlike any other
prescription medication they're also
proposing an excise tax on certain
medical products once the bill comes
into play in the fall and the packaging
regulations that were released a couple
months ago it dictates that packaging
for medical cannabis must be the same as
non-medical what it actually looks like
is completely plain packaging with a
list of health warnings and a massive
red stop sign that says warning THC so
if you're a patient that you're looking
to medicate and this is a medicine that
actually unlocks for you a day's worth
of functioning fully wear previous forms
of treatment were not effective for you
and you receive your medicine like that
it's not not the type of patients not
the type of health care we like to
deliver in Canada and yet that is the
reality we're facing now and so I'd like
to see more of a distinction between the
medical and the adult news markets and
though there is a lot of noise around
the recreational side of things and
rightly so it is a massive market and a
massive opportunity we mustn't forget
the patients who got us to where we are
today those who fought in the courts who
have advocated for decades and ensure
that their access to their medicine is
not limited and were potentially have
that in jeopardy if we don't take the
right steps now
yeah and that's been one of the the
concerning things about the liberal
platform you know they first came out
with it in 2013 way before they were in
power and
and they just never looked at medical
that was never anything medical it's a
little frustrating yeah I was just going
to say I mean I think that we recognize
there's only a small percentage of
people who actually go through the legal
medical channels so right now 19% of
consumers who report that they use
cannabis primarily for medical purposes
go through the legal channels that is a
you know a comment on access it's a
comment on price it's a comment at a lot
of things actually we need to do more
convenience we need to do more to ensure
that patients are treated as patients
distinct from a recreational consumer
well and the really interesting thing is
a large part of that percentage that you
just mentioned are new patients that a
CMP are actually opened up access to
people in rural areas that didn't have
access before so it was basically a new
market that kind of came in and opened
up Rob Lowe's live big surprise for you
about liberal legalization well yes
actually I have Jamie Shaw to thank for
the biggest surprise that Clint rightly
hit on that when it comes to government
money and control there aren't surprises
that's there to emmos but the biggest
surprise that Jamie informed me about
was when we started looking at the new
ACM PR or no excuse me the Bill c-45
cannabis Act now I know the Germans like
a good scary story
the Brothers Grimm right here's
something pretty grim so when you read
the definition of cannabis and then you
go to the cross reference schedule 1 and
schedule 1 the definition this is the
scary part says that the definition of
cannabis includes all phyto cannabinoids
derived from cannabis and non cannabis
derived sources we're similar to or
similar to so basically let me boil that
down why I find that so scary and
unforgivable is it's not the
government's job to say if you don't get
your phyto cannabinoids from us you're
going to jail that's a slippery slope
from if you don't get your water from us
you're going to jail
you don't get your food from us or if
your food is not prepared in the way
that we say so you're going to jail so
ultimately the scariest thing about Bill
c-45 is the degree of control by which
if you're doing anything outside the
circle
we'll call it the sacred circle of
legality if you do anything outside that
or produce phyto cannabinoids the same
phyto cannabinoids that you can get from
kale and echinacea you technically can
get from cannabis so I mean is anyone
else not alarmed about that it's it's
again and if these laws are not
challenged the scary thing is this gives
government and unfettered control over
essential aspects of human life and I
see cannabis being one more step to
where governments will be able to try to
control plant life organic material
which again next thing you know we'll be
cloning so that's the scary thing is
that people see this as just oh it's
cannabis it's a medicine it's a weed
toxic move on ultimately I think is a
fundamental human freedom around access
to a substance that we all need for
survival but for the last 93 years have
been denied by the government so yes I
find not quite surprising and scary
think strap well what's kind of been the
biggest surprise for you in this process
well you know not so much surprising
it's I think from our perspective as a
pub Co we just have to adapt and be
nimble in in our sort of approach to
cannabis so a good example would be the
the recent advent of the micro
cultivator status and the it just sort
of dovetailed quite nicely with our
distribution sales only license that
we're on we've we've got a late-stage
application through the Health Canada
CMP our process but what that means is
the micro cultivators are the the
smaller MMAR growers that the the
government wants to basically roll into
the
the program here and so the advent of
that level of Licensing will allow those
individuals to continue to grow that
they cannot sell direct to the public so
specific to Liberty leaf with our
distribution only license those micro
cultivators will be we'd be a
partnership with those growers and so
again and then we would take that
product and take to the to directly to
the market to the retail consumer so not
so much surprising on our end it's just
all about adapting with you know the
ever-changing rules and goalposts that
that come our way please I think another
good surprise as well as the licenses
was the changes to hemp regulations that
was another kind of unexpected thing
that came in our old hemp regulations
were ridiculous you could basically grow
the hemp and then had to destroy the
rest of the plant you weren't allowed to
extract any CBD or use the roots or do
anything else with it and that's that's
eased up a lot so I think that was
another kind of nice surprise other than
you know the space that we're in is is
very rapidly evolving and changing all
the time other than some of those what
would have been sort of the specific
issues or challenges that that you have
with your company and how its positioned
and how regulations are coming one of
the major challenges we've had with MMJ
canada is that each province is
drastically different per regulations so
you get comfortable with a way you're
doing something in the industry for
example in Vancouver and then they
announced a regulation in Alberta and
you're filing and doing an application
that's something completely out of your
realm and not what you're used to doing
the the fear of the unknown of where I'm
gonna get my supply in the future how
many licenses I'm gonna have is is not
concerning but you know it's definitely
something I think about on a daily basis
so where I see myself and in the space
is that
got to be very vigilant on on how we
approach each province I think we need
to do a lot of education on each
province Jamie also works for MMJ Canada
as a government relations director so
having her on my team has really eased
up a lot of the things and the processes
for each province because she is an
educator and she investigates into each
province on how they operate so that's
made my life a lot easier but moving
forward I think it's going to be key on
who you partner with key on your
standard key on your product testing and
I think if you cross all your T's and
dot your i's you have a good chance of
longevity in the cannabis space as long
as you're willing to adapt one of the
things that you're doing but would have
been some of the challenges that you're
seeing coming I think where we position
ourselves at the centre of Education and
introducing and welcoming new people
into the into the market whether that is
regulated consumers or non consumers or
business people it's just ensuring that
we're deconstructing that stigma that's
still it still remains a problem
probably not in a room like this but the
reality is that a lot of people still
continue to harbor demonization of the
plants and so where we have to work
extra hard is to deconstruct that poner
potheads donor archetype that really
doesn't resemble anything but the
unwanted poster child and so for us
where we have you know 250 odd thousand
medical patients through the legal
channels now and we'll have five to
maybe up to 8 million consumers come
online as a result of legalization a lot
of these people have no idea how
cannabis interacts with the body they
have no idea what the different
molecular compounds are the difference
between you know THC and CBD and and all
the other ones I mean it's it's a fun
opportunity to be able to educate them
when you can speak about some of the the
details that people may not be familiar
with for example I love talking about
the myth that cannabis necessarily
induces the munchies if you talk about
cannabinoid like THC V tetra hydro kind
of bitter in it's a very effective
appetite suppressant and so can be used
in weight-loss routines these are the
kinds of conversations that had people
take a step back where they thought they
already knew something and you're really
helping them you know swim across that
lake of misinformation and so to your
question the biggest challenge we have
is is education because people are
coming from a place of at best ignorant
at worst
opposition because of the results of
ninety five years of prohibition
yeah absolutely and the previous speaker
also referred to one of the things
around this is that we don't actually
know that much about cannabis for as
long as we've been using it within our
new scientific system we don't really
know and most of the research that we're
doing isn't really telling us anything
because we don't know what cannabinoid
profile was tested how many what the
terpene levels were it would be a very
simple fix to just you know if you're
gonna do research maybe find out what it
is first but yeah and that's I think
responsibility the the industry needs to
take on where the result of almost a
decade of prohibition in Canada at least
results in you know two different
extremes where you have one extreme of
people making therapeutic and medical
claims about the plant that aren't
backed by clinical aids data clinical
studies and you also have one the other
end of the extreme where people are
convinced that cannabis consumption
leads to rape violence murder and so on
and realistically we know neither of
those are really supported by science
the truth like most things live
somewhere in the middle and so that's
where we aim to insert ourselves so it's
our responsibility very particular with
our words and and admit where we don't
have all the facts where we're doing
more to learn more about thank you yeah
Rob what do you what do you see coming
in terms of issues whether and and you
know specific to the work that you do
well I see more of the same really I
made a career of essentially being a bit
of a thorn in the side of government if
you will in a good way
I've also been knowing I've helped
government I've recently been appointed
to a municipal cannabis task force and I
guess what it comes all down to is like
my colleagues have said it's there's
education and they're standing up for
instances involving cannabis
you see and injustice how ignorant you
see people being put down because of
their cannabis use or making false
assumptions do the cannabis I mean
really it's as a conscientious cannabis
user over those those situations we're
going to see certainly a lot more I look
at it this way
there's the folks that are getting
licensed sand and so on and I'm happy to
represent a number of those clients but
I also represent probably that
ninety-five percent who are getting
screwed by Health Canada so there's
gonna be no shortage of work that will
continue unfortunately as Nick pointed
out we have and we see the from the
government a little bit more clarity in
the direction upon which they're going
to take I think continued to be a little
bit of more of the same change will
continue to come through courts
government will continue to do what it
will do in its best interest and
citizens of course have the obligation
to engage in legal methods of changing
the law but at the same time the success
that we've achieved with cannabis at
least in Canada Canada has come through
you know decades of civil disobedience
and I think we're going to see more of
that too so it's an exciting time for a
lawyer I mean I really look at it with
my law firm being you know ad lose some
law corporation it's my ship and I'm
sailing right into a perfect storm which
is exciting but if I hadn't been doing
what I've been doing for like the last
two decades of my practice I wouldn't be
ready for these changes and I believe I
am ready for these changes because I've
done what's been necessary every day to
prepare for these noel NBC bill c-45
sister bill c 442 because it's not that
impaired dry
I mean rates are gonna go up but charges
certainly our news will be tightened
around everybody's neck which is why
it's imperative that you understand
these laws and how they affect you
because I think you're going to realize
that cannabis regulation is going to
pervade so many aspects of human rights
civil society and and what we consider
normal tenants of being being a
community it will all be challenged yeah
I mean we've already seen that with
medical patients that have won the right
to grow but if they're renting from
somebody the landlord doesn't have to
let them grow on their properties so
really it's only if you have a house
that you can actually grow if you have
neat medicine we'll what's what's coming
for you guys in terms of issues or
challenges I think for the the pub Co
perspective the challenge for us is just
to stay focused there's so many
opportunities to to invest in the
cannabis sector and whether it's in you
know in our own backyard in Canada and
going through the the typical AC MPR
process and getting licensed because at
the end of the day that's your ticket to
participating in in the business - you
know internationally the opportunities
internationally or it could it be in in
in science and R&amp;D is it in CBD pet
products which were involved with with a
partnership in Israel there's so many
opportunities that that were shown that
the the challenge for me as a CEO is
just to stay focused and but but that's
that's a good problem to have because we
get we have a lot of opportunities that
we we vet and and thankfully we have the
the capital that if we do see an
opportunity that we like and and and
fits the build and then we can react so
that's probably a good challenge and I'm
really quickly just to touch up on kind
of what all of us have been speaking
about it seems like Canada's going
through like Rob said at one point a
pretty grim transition it's really not
so bad
from all the challenges that you hear us
going through all the the ups and downs
it's it's quite a blessing to be a part
of this you know the fact that I'm
working with somebody like Nick who's a
part of the media company that's not on
the dispensing side the fact that I'm
friends with somebody like will who was
essentially a competition he's a
licensed producer which is awesome the
fact is that we're all up here and when
you find good people in the industry you
learn to work with each other and you
start putting your heads together and
you start doing some pretty impressive
things so I just don't want Germany to
think that what we're going through is
all trials and tribulations it's it's a
pretty awesome experience actually let
me qualify that it is pretty awesome and
let me make it clear we are
transitioning from a time where people
aren't necessarily going to jail anymore
for roaches or joints or you know for
inconsequential issues are at regarding
cannabis so I think we've turned a real
page there where now we're going to see
instead of you know the traditional
arrests for possession and trafficking
we're going to see more sophisticated
issues involving cannabis such as
proceeds of crime money laundering and
probably still the same old usual
suspects of trafficking and possession
but the circumstances by which people
will actually go to jail and where
families will be torn apart and where
children will be taken from their
parents and in ministry cases I'm happy
to say that that's the end of Act one
and as what Clint said and with Nick and
what we're all involved in we're all
very fortunate to be part of what's
coming act to legalization it's not
perfect but you know it that's why I'm
proud to be Canadian I'm proud to be
here I'm proud that we're the first g7
country may not necessarily be proud
about how we're going about it but I'm
proud to be here and proud to be part of
this group yeah but they're always you
know mistakes made anytime a country
does something for the first time and so
we know we were obviously so proud to be
here and to be represented Canada at the
same time we recognize that though
differences the government
approaches the government could have
taken or different tactics the general
theme is one of optimism and and support
we just think there are certain things
obviously there can be but over time the
government and you know all the
businesses involved in the space will
learn from themselves and you know 5 10
15 years down the line you know
hopefully we'll have ironed out some of
those kinks and after talking to
government officials for a long time and
having them just say well I can't do
anything about your patience sorry it's
not legal that that is the biggest thing
when once it becomes a law there's now a
process to change it just like any other
law and so while it's not going to be
perfect and it's probably gonna be
pretty rough for the first couple of
years there's ways to fix it and improve
it now and so that's we have we have to
recognize that legalization though it
may often be purported as an event in
the media is actually not it's a process
and therefore it's iterative and so we
see the changes over time it's an
evolution it's not a marathon and and
we're certainly not done I mean what
we're seeing in Canada is a lot of
people just kind of went oh well the
federal government's doing it now and
forgot about the provinces and how much
power they were gonna have for a little
while and they forgot about their cities
so there's cities that are saying you
know what we don't want to be part of
legalization so there's still a lot of
work to be done on on every single level
there and we kind of can't be negligent
on that and and you know the other area
is that what we've seen in Canada is
what we've seen in Washington State and
what we've seen in Colorado being
justice is built into prohibition don't
actually go away with legalization you
actually have to provide incentives to
make things better for those communities
that have been paying a higher cost for
this all along I think we're close to
very close yes we have maybe five
minutes left let's hear it for the panel
one time I was that for no Q&amp;A does
anyone have any questions for the
questions over here all the way over
there all right I'm coming I tried to
guess that it would they would be on
this side but apparently I was close I'm
in the front quadrant but here we go
everything into the last question as
Hippocrates put it let my food be thy
medicine and medicine be thy food
cannabis is most definitely a medicinal
food so government's often controlled by
divide and rule a drug is etymology
etymologically a dried food from the
Dutch drogue so my question is as we all
have an endocannabinoid system surely
all cannabis use is medicinal direct
statement is that a question so I mean
surely is is medicinal and the argument
obviously can be made I mean insofar as
you have that endocannabinoids system
with which all cannabinoids can interact
where that's phyto or endogenous
cannabinoids you have a central nervous
system that interacts with any substance
as well I mean the way I see it more is
the use case in the eyes of the consumer
so to the extent that I have friends who
purely enjoy the recreational and social
properties of cannabis
I would actually label them a
recreational consumer not a medical
patient even though it's therapeutic
of course of course and yeah exactly and
so it's in the eyes in my mind in the
eyes of the consumer but you make the
point that yes we have an
endocannabinoid system which is kind of
why the plant is has such a beautiful
harmony with our bodies well and I think
the whole issue is one of taxation
despite the fact that we've had legal
cannabis for a long time and the courts
have consistently said you have to
provide medical patients with access to
cannabis they've not called it a
medicine which is why they've been able
to put these taxes on it so it is kind
of a false definition that's born of
prohibition we you know dispensaries and
early activists we're trying to target
those that needed it desperately not
just made people's lives better right no
that's why we've ended up with this sort
of weird definition to answer your
question though the reason and it's very
important thank you for bringing
endocannabinoid and the fact that you
know regardless dr. Guevara matei would
would agree I think with with your
conclusion of cannabis being medicine
due to the fact we have an endo can
monoid system and regardless of how it
was Recker met regardless but you have
to remember that out of the legal
process so again in California which set
the stage for a lot of what's going on
in Canada proposition forget the number
but again it was it was medical and 215
so you have about 45 more seconds Rob
good luck with that
I'm just going to turn over to Jamie
well yeah well we'll all be around
you're gonna get a lot more Canadian
panels coming out so our goal was again
cut to kind of just give an overview of
what kind of things you can expect where
you're gonna get sudden opposition from
senators or from certain pounds and
things like that one more time for the
panel is in for Jamie and Clint's
[Music]