I forgot to wrap this one the
championship I did I've been smoking a
lot of Canadian weed so it makes you
thank you for having me
and yes I am now along with my wonderful
daughter Tyler Milan I'm the CEO
Abdullah's 22 that's chief visionary
Oracle I gave myself that title she's
the CEO listening to this panel was
amazing because we've been doing this
well I've been in this what do they call
it in Canada at a great market I've been
supporting the great market with half my
salary since 2000 we got involved and in
this business three four years ago and
it is amazing where it's gone from then
to now I was on stage three years ago at
the ice ICBC in San Francisco we now
travel everywhere because we realize our
import our input helps move this along
and as much knowledge as we can share
amongst one another it it's amazing I've
won four championships like he said I've
never done it by myself
I've only done it with a team so it may
seem like we're going to be in
competition here we literally are in
unity here because we are still illegal
in California we're still illegal in
America we still in a situation where
people are getting I just talked to my
friend here right people in jail for 20
years 25 years New York just released
10,000 people on a state level that
means the state jail is ten thousand
dollars like ten thousand people like
people are making means and means of
dollars offer the backs of people who
just wanted to smoke a joint who wanted
to be healthy so I recommend and I will
encourage you everyone if you weren't
gonna be in this business do not come
into this business with the mentality of
mimimi
this weed is about us us us the best
thing about having flower is being able
to have a community joint also herpes
but we won't talk about that is why we
have four for joint so with somebody say
let me hit that here's one for yourself
right community amount of yourself what
I'm just being serious
but don't net on that thought when we
came up the first place I smoked weed a
lot of weed was in 2000 here in
Vancouver I was doing a movie called an
ultimate Christmas present I bought some
weed I didn't know it was a lot I just
knew I could not go through TSA so I had
to smoke all of the weed and look at the
water I have seen things that I have
never seen before and I was like I need
more weed to the point where I recommend
this to my children I recommend that
they swear I caught one of my daughters
with a vape and it was nicotine and
she's trying to be all cool and hide it
and I was like I got CBD vape if you're
gonna vape vape this now somebody would
say but you should have told her not to
vape no she's already proven to me she's
going to do what she wants to do and how
it's my job as a parent to give her a
healthy alternative to the other this is
this is what it is
in Colorado alcohol has dropped 30
percent right duis have gone down the
cops can't sit around and pull you over
they can lean in your car sir do I smell
marijuana I don't know what you smell I
can't answer that question I mean things
are at a total disconnect from the old
way the fact that he just told me that
the person in charge of regulation in
Callen Canada was a chief of police
that's that's ridiculous that's almost
as ridiculous I'm having sex ed at
church you just
this in the kona it doesn't make any
sense they're gonna tell you not to
unless you're catholic they're gonna
tell you to have as many to bring back
to the church as possible but and come
tell me your creepy stories anyway go
back over that again alright enough of
the jokes on catholics and i'm just
joking
kinda this is the this is the spot this
is the place i'm glad no one got out
that everybody that comes after i want
you to pay attention because there's so
many avenues just so many ways we need
to touch i live a plant-based diet with
my family my daughter we're vegan so we
believe in every part of the plant we
believe in that in the hemp plant we
believe in the sister of the cannabis
plant
we believe in the tomato we believe in
the cucumber the asparagus all of that
we don't believe in murder of any kind
of any earthly so if you you don't have
to be of that kind but imagine how good
it feels to have plants to nourish your
body right that's why you see the
strongest oxy that's why you see the
gorillas eat this plant is amazing they
just finished talking about the car
sister's outing out in Palm Springs we
are we are on the verge of living longer
i don't know if you noticed but we
started living longer in the 50s and 60s
would penicillin and some of the things
that they put forth ways we were gonna
eat then they'd started destroying us
again we're packaging and processing
it's back to that wave a wave now is
back to nature our wave now is back to
enhancing you as a human this plant does
it this is a wonderful place to be I am
ecstatic I met some wonderful people
from New York Jackie and her crew
literally here to get information to
bring back to New York more people doing
that throughout the United States
expands it the United States richest
country in the world maybe not with all
of its minerals but with the minds to
think in mind is the fact that when we
get 25 states that say we're
recreational
soon they're gonna drop and they're
gonna start thinking what's they're
doing they're gonna start thinking of
ways to take it over they just told the
young lady here to stay in the gray
market keep knock on a door keep pushing
it I don't recommend you go to jail it's
not a lot of fun so I hear
so I hear and if you don't like gray all
the time you don't want to go you're the
only thing bright is the suit you don't
want to go that and I'm gonna be smoking
weed outside going you shouldn't listen
to that [ __ ] so the cool part is
this is an industry as we said we are in
the beginning stages it's up to
everybody in this room to make this
thing stay for two people it's up to us
to make sure they don't bastardize it
make sure they don't make it such a
chemical that you forget that you are
smoking this wonderful healing plant it
is important that we stand for all of
these things that help us as a race
human race then we might not destroy
other earthlings we might not think of
the worst thing we might not want to go
to war imagine smoking weed and just
sitting back and going I like you man
but I like you a little bit better now
that's what this plant does this plant
opens up parts of your brain that you
don't have closed by restrictions you
don't have clothes by hate you don't
have clothes by programming this helps
you deep program this is a plant that
helps you become the best human you can
possibly be all right anybody got any
important questions let's hear it one
more time for John Salley it's not one
love that's it oh all right John Salley
everybody one more time fantastic
cannabis is great