in the mid 80s AIDS epidemic was in full
flight in San Francisco people realized
that cannabis had a lot of medical
properties and it was helping people
live longer Better Lives look like a
hippie but I wasn't right you have to go
and you buy your cannabis and then you
go back home and you smoke your cannabis
you know all by yourself full of shame I
know a guy who's actually fairly
successful uh and he's on micro does of
cocaine almost daily back to the blood
again the blood again blood again well
again get it in okay bro the whole point
is just to be chill handle your drugs
matter what you do no matter how you
show them the Cannabis makes money for
communities cannabis keeps your
communities cleaner and safer cannabis
provides good jobs cannabis provides
good training or or
whatever net win it's a safe access it
helps people with with things they're
still going to hate it I'm lucky enough
that I had a show on
Netflix Jackie Jill went up the hill to
have a little fun silly Jill forgot her
pill and now they have a son everybody
go oops up your head oops upside your
head oops upside your head say oops
upside your
head all right that's that's all right
ICBC family welcome to where the world
meets cannabis uh we are on the grounds
of spannabis right now the day before
everything pops off uh first the ICBC
then spannabis we're at the auditory
Cornelia and we have a very special
guest we're right on stage here with the
one and only um how do you describe this
man he's the MC of the ICBC he is
prolific one of the top cannabis
comedians in the world and just an
allaround great guy Uno beum welcome to
the show good to see you dog how you
feeling respect feeling good man just
getting ready for a big uh big week here
oh man the the Barcelona uh
International cannabis business
conference is one of my favorite
conferences uh oh stop no I mean first
of all every International cannabis
business conference is good and I'm not
blowing smoke up your ass like I I do a
lot of things uh but you know me and
Barcelona we We Vibe we have a thing we
understand each other we get along
really well no you do love Barcelona I
know that about you I know a lot of
things about you because the first time
we met was
exactly almost exactly 30 years ago geez
Louise yeah and that was on I'd like to
say we met on ha Ashbury but we met on
Lower hate lower hate like around
Filmore yeah how was it Debbie or it was
at the hemporium wow and I you walked in
and I was doing some work there and then
you you were looking at these books and
all of a sudden you like you [ __ ] did
the the Cabbage Patch and the Bart
Simpson in one move right it wasn't just
running man right it wasn't just Cabbage
Patch you just went like you just busted
out in in in in dance and I was like oh
who's I was like this is my man right
here yeah and next thing you you know we
were we were uh you homies and friends
playing basketball freestyling together
basketball freestyle and doing events
too back events we played the fil War we
did we did all those um you helped
produce all those Maritime Hall ones too
right I didn't do the maritime Hall but
I did the hemp Expo the one in Golden
Gate Park oh yeah I remember that that's
right why don't you tell us a little bit
Uno because really that was the
epicenter of what every where everything
is at right right now it was really the
heart of the Cannabis activism movement
the Bay Area was for for a long time
could you uh could you speak to that a
little
bit uh yeah man I grew you know I grew
up in San Francisco born and raised uh
and right around um in the mid 80s when
when the HIV AIDS epidemic was at full
flight in San Francisco people realized
that cannabis had a lot of medical
properties and it was helping people
live longer better lives and so people
like Dennis Peron people like brownie
Mary they pushed really hard uh to to
make medical cannabis at least even more
legal I mean San Francisco was
always somewhat tolerated I mean brownie
Mary would come into the hospitals
actually but if the cops wanted to
bother you they could and so when it
started to get bigger when brownie Mary
would show up at the hospital with pop
brownies when Dennis Peron had his he
had like an open air cannabis club you
know his belief was always any form of
uh cannabis's medicinal cannabis so he
wasn't very strict about who he let in D
yeah Dennis was a character for sure
yeah man rest in peace he's the the fair
godmother of the medical cannabis
industry for sure he has Dennis IND dud
and a Libertarian too and down with
Harvey Milk from from from all that
hardcore libertarian Dennis yeah man
Dennis was a he was a force of nature so
yeah so I learned from those guys I
learned from hanging out with Jack Harr
and and Debbie and Don from the canvas
Action Network and Steph from
American shout out Don Duncan Don Duncan
Steph uh Steph
sh yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah so Chris
Conrad Mickey Norris Christ and Mickey
right right uh um I can't remember
everybody Shaw Lynette Shaw huh break it
down yeah Lynette Shaw for sure and a
bunch of people so that's that's where
you know that's where I I got my start
and we we did all the we produced events
we did cannabis comedy fundraisers we
did man so many things prop 215 uh I I
ran West Coast cannabis magazine for a
while when we were trying to get Prop 19
pass before the the the other one passed
I remember that and all and that the
this whole time you're doing comedy
you're traveling around you're doing
comedy around America around Europe too
yeah yeah I guess so huh yeah wow that's
pretty impressive sometimes I never
really think about it cuz I'm doing it
and then and then remember when we did
the Cannabis Cup in uh you you were the
MC of the Cannabis Cup in like 99 the
High Times Cup in '99 and fishbone was
the head at the milk at the milk and
canol machete from Mexico was there too
were they were fantastic yeah yeah that
was fight right I got into weed activism
so I could go see the bands really
so well you've always been a fishbone
head always hardore always I saw him
open for the Beasty Boys I don't mind
getting old cuz I can say I saw fishbone
open for the Beasty Boys I've opened for
a couple times that is dating yourself
You' opened for what what with the the
slack mob back with with the most chill
slack mob and at the milk vag when I was
the MC for the for the High Times
Cannabis Cup so you did it all man
you're so you're hardcore activist
hardcore spokesperson comedian but you
also had this dope band in the 90s
called the slack I did have a band in
the king slack was your was your mon the
one and only King slack that's right
that's right and in fact one of my
greatest moments 15 minutes of fame
which is only about 3 minutes is when
you invited me up at the
Filmore and it was a you were headlining
that show and it was a 16 and up show
and it was almost completely full were
pretty popular for a hot minute it it
was so fun for sure we did that
freestyle with psycho kinetics and
bazooka Jo yeah that's right that's
right that was a good time he could go
all the way I found that tape I sent
that tape to Mark our DJ d DJ media you
got to ask Mark he might have that got
God that be crazy to listen back to and
that was 30 years ago that was I was 30
years maybe 29 I mean you know I was I
was
six very smart spry I was just big for
my age I lwi and [ __ ] the black Stewie
and [ __ ] Stone six-year-old 6' 6y old 6'
6y old oh my god um yeah those are
magical times and you were living in
Europe doing your thing I got to Europe
a little bit later yeah I mean I was
there the pre 215 and then we did the I
worked with Jack and Debbie and and Ed
and all that stuff and so that's how we
really just got got down and then of
course I was I was from Minneapolis and
you know I was from the the city right
and so I always was you know I came out
to to Cali and like I didn't know there
were black hippies and [ __ ] until I got
to California right and I was like this
is amazing black people do everything I
know I know well I knew they did
everything but I just didn't know there
were hippies I guess almost I didn't
know there were cuz cuz I get to Santa
Cruz in like ' 92 and it's like I'm
dropping into the Last vestages of the
Summer of Love and [ __ ] right sure and
uh but what I but what I brought to the
game was like they were just I look like
a hippie but I was
right sure and uh even though I respect
the hippies and respected the hippies um
but what I brought what I think I
brought to the game was uh just a little
flavor and a work ethic that wasn't
quite that Minnesota work ethic that
puran work ethic yeah yeah we're in the
west coast man take your time yeah I
know but yet you were you were you were
all you were all King slack but yet you
were getting I looked up to you so much
cuz you were get you were getting so
much done you were I mean dude you had
you you were you were the [ __ ] man in
in San Francisco and uh yeah I don't
know about all that but you know dude
okay so here's a story here I think this
represents Uno's character we were
playing basketball one day and we come
back to your Brownstone where you living
in the mission right yeah and there and
we pass your car sure and there's a
there's a dude in your car and I'm
thinking oh man it's about to be on you
know what and you're like oh hey
Fred and I was like you know and and I
was like so you taught me this comp like
cuz I'm from the city and we we have
compassion you know obviously but then
you get anesthesized to it when you just
see the [ __ ] everywhere you're like what
the [ __ ] can I do hard it's hard and you
know it just makes me angry every time I
see a homeless person I get angry at at
humankind yeah well I didn't know there
could be such I never saw such a Pious
gesture in my life I think and it was
actually uh it was actually a a it it it
changed me it was like damn I got to wow
I got to get with this this is the next
level Consciousness right here sure Fred
sure oh Fred yeah thanks you know I even
have any place to stay so yeah so you
let him stay in your car man that was
like some every day
but and it wasn't no Mercedes either no
it like a green Pontiac like a four-door
Pontiac yeah but why not man why not
everybody needs help so so now we've
been doing these shows now in Europe
since 27 yeah uh tell us a little bit
about tell us why you like Barcelona so
much cuz it obviously is a special town
for many different reason
[Music]
um it's just like if you know I'm a West
Coast kid and I know this is the south
of Spain but it's got a very United
States West Coast vibe in that it's like
it's on the water everybody's cool it's
not you know it's like San Francisco in
the 90s it's not super expensive so you
can do your thing you have a little and
still be in a band or still DJ or still
do art and have a nice apartment and and
and kick it and everybody here is cool
man I've never I haven't met one
[ __ ] in Barcelona yet no it's crazy
chill right the search continues I'm
sure I'm sure there is one it does a San
Diego Vibe a little old school like from
the it do '90s and [ __ ] I do not I
disagree I mean just like the looking at
the palm trees okay maybe superficially
it has a San Diego Vibe but like the
vibe itself
San Diego as the West Coast goes is
really closer to Bakersfield than it is
to
Portland I'm going be honest Portland
you didn't say like La you said Portland
so that was the two extremes right so I
I I agree with that but the weather's
nice the weed's good the food's good
like you said everything's good it's
easy to walk around public
transportation is great so what what's
up with the the coffee shop scene or the
social club scene here is it popping is
it uh what what if if for folks who
haven't been to Barcelona what can they
expect and can anybody just pop up and
break to while cannabis is still
technically illegal in Spain uh their
Supreme Court decided a long time ago
that you have a right to put drugs in
your body if you want and so they have
social clubs so you have to join a
social club and the social club is
allowed to grow weed for you and you
have to know somebody you have to be
sponsored as a member you can't just be
walking into the social club you got to
know somebody you got to know somebody
yeah
camera apprciate it it's my fly up too
so you got to know somebody you have to
have a letter recommendation to get in
and then when you're in there you can
buy cannabis uh but you're not supposed
to take it with you outside of the club
uh right so nobody ever does that uhuh
right right and and they're all very
different some are really like sports
bars or some are like gaming bars and
some are like co-working offices and
some are just like little chill
nightclubs or coffee shops and so
there's a lot of different Vibes you can
find the one you like or there's
generally one in the neighborhood if you
can get invited to one I belong to like
10 10 I think so I think so how do you
get invited is that what type of process
is that um I'm lucky enough that I had a
show on
Netflix so if i' send them an Instagram
message and go hey I'd like to uh come
to your club they're like yes of course
what but but some of my friends would be
like hey we're coming to
Barcelona uh how do we get to these
clubs and then I'll send I'll send the
the club a message be like my good
friend Eric is coming into town and
April he would love love to be a member
like of course uhhuh and if you had to
pick three of your favorite clubs oh
that's easy uh Dr do Dr do d o shout out
fantastic shout out lalala lalada k a l
a d a they're they're really cool they
have great variety uh a really good vibe
and they're very active in the community
they push they do a lot of events and
they push a lot of things for cannabis
acceptance and whatnot m um the third
one that's tough because there's so many
good one I mean there's gorilla there's
shoko there's
G13 there's uh turpy HQ right I got to
get to all these spots this weekend I'm
gonna be broke but I'll be high okay so
you've been to Amsterdam and quite a bit
and uh We've I I I lived in Amsterdam
for a couple years how does the
Amsterdam coffee shop scene compar to
the SP Spain social club scene is it I
know it's similar in some ways they're
very similar how's it how's it how's it
what's the different feel the Amsterdam
coffee shop scene is way more wide open
right you could just walk in off the
street to any coffee shop and buy a
little something and sit there cons it
or take and take it with you although
it's still technically illegal in
Amsterdam it's just uh is there a 5 G
there's a five G thing or something yeah
I don't I don't know I mean I never
carry more than a few grams on me uh so
I don't know about that but they they
also want you to be way more Creet and
and I think the problems that they're
having in Amsterdam and the problems
that they're kind of having in Barcelona
right now because I was talking to some
people and they said they the police
have been doing more inspections and
they have a new mayor who's maybe not as
happy with cannabis clubs as as the city
used to be and the Dutch are always
trying to kick the tourists out uh up in
Amsterdam they're always trying to well
you and you know because people show up
and they especially in Amsterdam they're
kind of drunk and then then they walk
into the coffee shop and then they get
stoned so now they're cross faded right
and they're matur and so now they're
stumbling around they're falling off the
thing they're falling in the canal
they're starting fights bro yeah the
whole point is just to be chill handle
your drugs yeah right be an adult yeah I
think
that's I think that's a great philosophy
in general for I try that's that's what
am I have fun be yourself handle your
drugs be responsible for your own drug
use yeah right well because we all are
really and truth truth be told I mean
well that's the Mantra you can't
legislate morality no but also I mean
but it's also things like this you know
like uh I throw cannabis events and I
like to keep them no to low alcohol one
it keeps people from getting cross faded
and puking on my on my floors two it's
funny to me to watch the boozers have to
sneak off to a corner to have a drink
and I can come over and bust them you
guys drinking
beer D the opposite go smoking a big
joint like hey hey no don't be doing
drugs in here man well was it was Dr
Carl Hart that told me one day don't be
drug Prejudice no don't be drug
Prejudice and I thought that was so
people do drugs man I used to be I mean
I'm not I don't do a lot of drugs I do a
few drugs a lot like I always like to
say but uh I'm I'm more understanding of
people who do drugs that I would
consider my vi just handle it yeah be an
adult yeah I I know a guy who's actually
fairly successful uh and he's on micro
does of cocaine almost daily
yeah I know people who take heroin who
are successful CEOs so you never know no
well I mean never know well Carl Hart
would say uh to invoke uh Dr Kart again
is he said that no matter whether the
drugs are legal or not there's always
going to be a consistent people are
going to do drugs and in terms of like
uh doing them responsibly there's like
maybe 1.5% or something I don't remember
the exact will become addtive addicts to
whatever it to the detriment to the
detriment to their detri not just the
habitual user like say a coffee user or
or I guess you have to Define addiction
right that's that's a habit you have to
Define addiction and I guess I guess
ultimately I think we're all addicted to
certain things but caffeine is addictive
nicotine is addictive jogging is
addictive yoga is addictive for sure so
like you say to the to the detriment are
you doing it responsibly are you
handling your [ __ ] um are you functional
in society and high functioning cannabis
user yeah high functioning cannabis user
get it I'm a
dad um so uh so the coffee so but but
and so you're saying in Amsterdam it's
more it's more wide open and it's more
dis it's more discreet in in uh CU I
know you don't really see the coffee
shops off the street see them it's like
the secret doors yeah yeah yeah yeah
yeah you there's like a maybe a little
camera or maybe you see their logo right
you see the logo of the of the social
club and then so you then you press the
doorbell and a little door opens and and
do they serve alcohol in these beer
coffee yeah some snacks yeah yeah hard
liquor in Amsterdam there was like three
types of coffee shops there was that
like total local coffee shop there was
like the the the the total like tourist
coffee shop and then there was the
hybrids where the locals and the
tourists were there like remember the
roai on lights of roai was very popular
I think I went there I think the last
time I went there was like 2020 right
before everything went crazy oh really I
was in Amsterdam a year ago and it
doesn't exist any it's not well at least
it's not in that place anymore right
right right but I thought that was one
of the dopest ones and they had they had
uh they served alcohol and but not all
coffee shops did serve alcohol and then
there was some places in Amsterdam where
you could go that were bars that allowed
smoking yes right but you couldn't get
the weed there no and that's that that
should be a problem you know if you if
you're I mean I think we need more
Social Clubs and more I mean a lot of
the times in this push toward toward
legalization people are really treating
alcohol or not alcohol but cannabis like
it's like it's a shameful dirty drug so
you have to go and you buy your cannabis
and then you go back home and you smoke
your cannabis you know all by yourself
full of shame
but weed is a social drug you stand in a
circle when you smoke it everybody's an
equal everyone's a peer uh cannabis
clubs cannabis Social Clubs uh medical
cannabis dispensaries they were all kind
of social hubs uh before legalization in
in the states at least and then the
states are like well no nobody can
consume outside you just have to buy it
and go away but the clubs are coming
back and I think we need more of those
we need you should be able to pop down
to your local same way you pop down to
your local bar and have a drink after
work or whatever you should be able to
pop down to the local have a puff or
have some sort of cannabis cocktail play
some chess with your homies watch the
game or whatever and then go home so
that's the one cool thing about
Amsterdam though is that it is wide open
and you can just have your weed and take
it and smoke it and bring it and what
generally as long as you're not a dick
yeah well that's in general any for
anything right yeah um do you think what
do you think what do you think the fate
of of Barcelona's uh social club scene
is I don't know enough about the current
politics of Barcelona really to talk
about it but I hope that they would stay
and even be grandfathered into some even
more more accepted and and for sure I
think it would be great if uh I mean I
really like this the smooth this and the
discretion of it right now I don't think
we necessarily need to see giant ads for
can Canabis clubs everywhere people know
where to go the the social media will
tell you where to go and the whole point
is to ask a homie so but you know where
you don't have to maybe it's not so much
a private club as it is now right you
become a member you pay a membership fee
you become a member of of the club in in
in Spain uh but maybe you could just
have some drop-ins or walk-ins that
would be that would be cool yeah I think
that's where I mean I it seems like
implementation is 90% of the law and so
you know the I mean it wouldn't
hard no but but you're fighting 100
Years of of anti-cannabis propaganda
right you're fighting a small percentage
of people who were just going to listen
if common sense and science were going
to win the day cannabis would have never
have been made illegal right so we
have to overcome negative stereotypes
and and negative propaganda and there
are a percentage of people that you're
not going to reach and those cats are
going to be the loudest and they're
going to be the biggest haters and no
matter what you do no matter how you
show them that cannabis makes money for
communities cannabis keeps your
communities cleaner and safer cannabis
provides good jobs cannabis forides good
training or or whatever
it's win it's a safe access it helps
people with with things they're still
going to hate it yeah right and so you
have to figure out a way to work
around you I mean you could work with
them up to a point but they're not
really going to go for so what about
social uh clubs in the state are there
any places where you can smoke weed
inside not my house you just come
over Colorado do something where they
Colorado's just starting some uh
Nevada's got a couple um there's newo in
Las Vegas which is on uh indigenous land
so they their rules are completely
different but they're opening a whole
new uh like a Las Vegas certified social
club in Vegas right now but isn't that
funny so this is so interesting that I
think Vegas used to be so mean about
weed they would throw you under for the
like 10 years for a joint or whatever oh
oh yeah that wasn't that wasn't 1975
1983 they used to have signs up right I
mean don't remember that that fear and
loathing picture you know but even even
yeah they got all the drugs in the car
and the one joint's going to put him for
life or whatever pretty much um uh so so
but so so so let's talk about Berlin for
a second yes um I know that's another
city that you adore I also love Berlin
Lea Berlin yeah
um yeah I've been working on my trying
to decide what my German accent is going
to be like I think I'm going to go with
a high pitched voice like oh good morg
fright oh we not hungry yeah it's good
to see you yeah the stere to Indiana
Jones
villain that's wrong don't don't tell
the Germans I said that oh yeah well no
you won't tell anyone this won't go
anywhere um uh we love Berlin but here's
what I like about Berlin
butwhere this a bence American weed
culture and or culture in in European
culture is that they still smoke in
Europe you know they still they still
smoke everyone even healthy people smoke
and you're talking about tobacco smoke
to SM smoke in general yeah so so it's
so in does not care yeah so you ride
your bike everywhere you eat healthy and
you smoke a few cigar and it feels like
weed is legal it feels it feels it's
more free even even though it's not
technically legal but just the fact that
you can smoke it outside and in America
we smoke outside too right I mean [ __ ]
in 30 years ago we'd smoke inside in San
Francisco at the con concerts it was
just
right it wasn't a thing and then smoking
just got really Taboo in general yeah
it's really funny it's really funny
about that U because you know back in
the more illegal days of cannabis when
we go to throw a cannabis event you know
I would tell the person who owned the
warehouse or whatever listen there's
going to be a lot of pot smoke in here
and they be that's cool as long as
there's no cigarettes right right and
now you you go to a thing you be like
we're going to throw a cannabis event
they're like uh that's a great idea but
you can't smoke what do you mean we
can't smoke inside well you can't smoke
anything you can't smoke tobacco you
can't smoke cannabis you just we don't
it's a smokefree environment that's my
point right I'm like well then we can't
we can't use your Venue I mean listen in
their defense your Venue is going to
smell like weed for a couple of days
after we've left exactly I mean and and
I have to tell some people sometimes I'm
like we're going to throw a Canabis EV
is it cool and they're like yeah man
that's cool I'm like no you don't
understand is it cool right it's a this
is a serious cannabis event everybody's
going to have their own joint there's
going to be a six foot Vapor bag flying
around there's every table is going to
have a bong like the room is going to be
full all the window's going to be open
your block might smell a little
bit right so just be ready yeah well but
that's isn't that why Europe's cool cuz
you can just light up outside and or at
a cafe in Berlin
I mean where I live in Slovenia lublana
extremely cannabis friendly city is it
legal technically no but it's
decriminalized de criminal and and
people literally smoke everywhere in
people grow it everywhere in everybody's
got it in the garden next to the
tomatoes in the strawberries I think
it's the most I I wrote this article
that was slightly injust but me m meant
to be poetic and a Gonzo style saying
that Slovenia was the most cannabis
friendly nation in in the world and it's
a I understand it but I qualif I made
interesting qualifiers why hey it's the
[ __ ] is you feel so safe no one's going
to bust they grow pretty good weed too
I'm not going to lie because they're all
nerdy smart people you know they do
everything well SL how do you feel about
Slovenia do you like Slovenia I kind of
like Slovenia married one bro but I fell
in love with Slovenia before I fell in
love with a Slovenian
girl trying to become the ambassador to
sloania hey we'll see man we'll see
Canabis ambassador to be there bro but I
know you like Slovenia too I love
Slovenia had a great time and we're
going to be back there in September
September 13th be there September 13th
Science and Technology Forum yep Science
and Technology we're taking it to the
next level the back to Lake bled back to
Lake bled tell why don't you tell the
people how the blood again the blood
again back to the blood again the blood
again blood again welled again get it in
okay uh it was uh man it's beautiful out
there it's the the what do you call it
the Balkan Alps or whatever back to the
BL the jul uh what do we call them you
guys they're not the Euros
what yisi the
Yuli ulis scalped ulis scalped yeah I
mean I can speak lenia but somehow I
can't get that one yeah uh I I forgot
all My Slovenia in the minute we left
but I was there for three days and it
was starting to come around yeah well
you know it's such an easy language to
learn you just have to listen no you do
your thing you're like I speak many
different langues hash yeah listen
people always want to sell me weed so
that's the first thing listen I get in
in slania I catch 30% of the words but I
catch 80% of the Vibes and so that's the
important thing right but Lake bl's dope
right Lake bled is beautiful and you can
walk around it and people parale and
it's and yeah it is very very uh very
Alpine well it's the Alps it's it's the
other side of the Alps so it's very
Alpine very beautiful the air is fresh
and clean the food was really good uh
man I had a great time and and Luana was
cool too yeah yeah yeah we went over to
Pops Pizza it was like a suburb that
thinks it's a city or it's a city that
acts like a
suburb it's a we call it a we call it a
village oh okay fair enough so it's a
it's a it's the smallest capital in yeah
I mean it's it's got the Big City Vibe
right it's got a few giant buildings and
some old school just a little bit it has
a big city city Halls a tiny little bit
just a little bit of a big City Vibe
like it understands that it's the
capital city it definitely understands
it's just you know it's smaller yeah
it's very quaint it's quaint that's a
good word for it but I loveed it I had a
great time yeah it's super chill it
might might not be quite your speed of
Barcelona and I mean it's not New York
or or Berlin but I could I would you
know I could live there in the
spring I wouldn't be there in the
summer you could winter in Slovenia I
could I could spring and summer I don't
ski a lot oh
[ __ ] so tell us what are you doing now
besides ICBC what's Unum up to is uh you
got any TV shows coming up or I'm
working on some things like that um I
have a TR you know everybody wants to be
uh the travel log guy so I'm working on
my my little travel log Tv show uh I'm
chopping up with the cats at Connected
.tv on some things I'm going to be
hosting the Arizona Growers cup um and
and The Growers cup Cup Series so we
just did the Missouri Growers cup doing
the Arizona Growers cup and I think
we're bringing one to New York as well
you can follow me on all the on the
Instagrams and whatnot NG a o420 to get
the latest news um doing some comedy
shows man writing for High Times in
Leafly the the usual stuff prolific pro
pro yeah that's what they say I always
think I'm not doing enough and then I
look back six months later I'm like hey
[ __ ] slow down
day off hey as long as you getting paid
yes yeah I that's a good idea yeah what
a concept getting paid I should talk to
somebody about that I'm fortunate enough
you know to get paid for stuff I do for
free but the people who pay me know I do
it for free so they take advantage it
sounds like you'd uh fit in just fine in
Slovenia right U well dude uh thanks so
much for that was so fast that's it we
don't too long yeah meanful we I mean I
know we're we go bro and you know thank
you dog like
the the international cannabis business
conference is fantastic I'm not and I'm
not just kissing your ass because you
know I would tell you if it sucked I
would be the first in line to be like
bro we got to get our [ __ ] together but
it's a good time man and we've come a
long way from Medford Oregon right yeah
and uh yep and as just it's just it's
just impressive I'm always just
impressed because when you first said
Berlin me and everybody would the what
why and then a month before it Berlin
was like we're starting medical cannabis
program we're like Alex you're a genius
so however you whatever you caught with
the Zeitgeist or your little connection
to the universe man keep that [ __ ] up do
that [ __ ] it's fire bro I appreciate you
there with me on the journey and all
that [ __ ] yeah boom boom yeah all that
all right thanks huh where the world
meet cannabis we love you thanks and gum
we'll see you next time big up boom
atino V
standing on the wall get your back off I
heard all the people say Get Down On It
Get Down On
It Get down on
it get down get down on it Get Down On
It Get down on it every get down you
really get
down what what you going to
do got to get on your
groove if you want your body to
move tell me
baby you know it and
you you know