this is a panel on differentiating in
the CBD space the crowded CBD space and
we've got a really an interesting panel
of diverse views
that'll be chiming in give you guys more
perspective from different smart minds
on how to accomplish the differentiation
grow your products and brands in the
panel we have and I'm going to sort of
give them up just name them and they'll
give you a quick once-over on on who
they are and a little bit about their
companies so first I've got Scott Goldy
CEO of golden seed yeah I am Scott Gould
a the CEO of golden seed in golden seed
as a corporation and we're involved in
both the cannabis and the have space so
we're vertically integrated in both of
those sectors started in December of
seventeen and our first crops will be
coming to market in the next couple
months
good afternoon
my name is Omar Figueroa I've been a
lawyer in cannabis for 21 years here in
California and I'm also a director of
the National cannabis Industry
Association as well as the California
cannabis tourism association as well as
the International cannabis Bar
Association I'm also the author of a
book California cannabis laws and
regulations 2020 which is basically
carefully curated compendium of laws and
regulations pertaining to hemp and
cannabis here in the Golden State
hello this really works
my name is Ken Stratton I'm a partner
with the law firm Rockaway law group the
firm was established in 2011 we have
three offices in the state one in LA one
in San Francisco and one in Santa Rosa
my practice is about 50/50 corporate and
litigation and firm-wide the litigation
as
50/50 between defense work and
plaintiffs work before rockaway I was in
private practice as a laborer an
employment attorney and a corporate
securities attorney for ten years and
then I went in house and I helped run
three life science companies as senior
legal counsel
two of the life science companies were
publicly traded with about fifty five
hundred million dollars market cap both
developing therapeutics for different
indications in the human body and
another was an international
conglomerate called Medtronic
alright guys so I think we're gonna jump
right in this is a it's a very deep
field and I think feeling exactly what
the title that this panel is I think
it's a really really poignant question
and I think there are some direct
answers that you'll get from everybody
on here so we'll start out by saying
what are the keys to differentiate your
product or brand in CBD I will start
with Scott yeah so we started growing
him last year actually and the key for
differentiation I think for us is a
couple things first we have proprietary
genetics that have been developed really
over the last decade and the uniqueness
about them is that they're very high CBD
percentages some over 20% a very very
high terpene profiles and very unique
terpene profiles so if we're going out
to the market and we could have those
types of attributes it lends its up
really well well for instance the
smokeable hemp and Dean and I are
working in a partnership to create a
retail product that would be him
cigarettes and that's something that's
very large and your up and I think it's
gonna be very large here in the United
States and they're really at the
forefront of that but what they're
looking for were the type of genetics
and have CBD that we can grow the second
thing that I think is really unique for
us in terms of branding is that we grow
everything organically even to have so
it's very sustainable we have our own
worm farm we create our own soil
amendments no chemicals or pesticides
and so we're meeting with the wellness
company last week you know they're
selling products that are there to
benefit people they love that kind of
ethos and it'll actually be incorporated
into their marketing of their products
and then I think for us because we're
vertically integrated
you know we've started with growing we
have seed production eventually we want
to get into our own retail products as
well maybe some of our own hemp
with Dean AMP cigarette and other
products so that would be my answer I
think there's gonna mean to be a focus
on product safety and on testing there
needs to be more awareness that cannabis
and hemp are both incredibly effective
fight over mediators that means that
they are organisms that remove toxins
from the soil and these toxins usually
end up on the plant body itself and so
this awareness of cannabis and hemp are
both bio accumulators and that they can
accumulate toxins really then the next
question is which products are safe for
human consumption and that's where I
think a focus on safety and on testing
will really give somebody in a very
crowded marketplace an edge because they
can say our products are tested
everybody knows that cannabis is super
effective at removing toxins from their
environment and so you have to be
careful to not be buying gas station CBD
you know because those products are
probably very poisonous so I think
that's one thing the other part in
differentiation is building a brand and
in order to build a brand you need to be
able to first of all pick a distinctive
name don't say you know north northern
emerald wellness because that's so
generic and it doesn't really like stand
out from other similar names so you want
to pick something that's either what's
called in trademark law fanciful some
made-up name or you know hopefully
arbitrary something that has nothing to
do with describing this brand and also
tell a story like the brands that really
resonate have authentic stories you know
I'm thinking about how Lowell forints
had like some invented story about
Lowell in 1913 and you know it was
really like a man wearing a ball wearing
a suit was really the story it was kind
of like a made-up story with no
authenticity so I think
when you're building a brand you want to
you know focus on telling a story that's
authentic like what I'm hearing from you
as you know a focus on sustainability
and organic inputs and you know that
resonates with the consumers in the
marketplace so I think building a strong
brand is important now try to leave some
stuff for Kenton agreed now pen I think
these network so so said from my
perspective and I approach it from the
perspective of a corporate attorney who
has raised capital for countless
companies and helped them sell
themselves helped founders realize their
liquidity of being events in the dreams
to grow businesses that are going to
last for the long term right you can
differentiate all you want but what you
want to do is differentiate yourself in
a way that is destined to last for the
long term and to me it all comes down to
trust
maintaining trust so when it comes to
making claims that you can't support
that defies and breaks down trust and
then control and discipline right so if
you're trying to build a brand and
you're trying to convince people that
your product is always going to be on
the shelves and will always have the
same sort of impact and effect on your
body it's not good if the product
doesn't do that it's even worse that the
products not even there right so at the
end of the day having the kind of
discipline and control to make sure that
you have operational control you have
legal control and you're able to to
continue to build that trust all right
so to me the world is divided up into
Joule and Walt Disney right so jewel is
a company that violated people's trust
because it's pretty clear jewel targeted
children in a way that was inappropriate
so you know we already know how the FDA
feels about CBD products you know don't
target children right that's that's not
good for a number of reasons but but
that violated trust while Disney is
every bit as aggressive and successful
as jewel has ever been Walt Disney
single-handedly destroy
a copyright law in America to save
Mickey Mouse right to make sure that
Mickey Mouse continue to make them gobs
of money into the foreseeable future 200
years how right they're very successful
but they built trust and they had
operational control and I think that's a
from my perspective as a corporate
attorney that's what my advice would be
to you
so can I think those are all great
answers and sort of my takeaway first I
just realized I didn't didn't introduce
myself but I helped run but calm and
Wagner demas which is a technology that
that is patented for the production of
pre-rolls and scale I think so I'm I'm
an operator an investor a lot like Scott
and so I think everything that I heard
resonated with me I think it starts with
safety because I don't think you're in
the game unless your product is is is at
that par I think from there I would say
quality I think if you have a quality
product irrespective of what sector
you're in relative to the other entrance
the competition if you have a great
product you're gonna be your your your
there you're gonna be positioned to win
you've got a mark and do some other
things but I think at a banal level
you've got to know that you can come out
with a quality product so for us we were
operating in cannabis and it became very
evident when the farm bill passed that
our technology for rolling pre-rolls
was going to be very applicable to hemp
and the the type of smokeable hemp flour
that certain forward-thinking breeders
were creating and Scott happened to be
one of those folks who was forward
thinking and creating CBD strains
essentially over generations Scott's
partner was breeding down the T ace
from strains that we all know and
breeding it into other cannabinoids and
also terpenes so they've got this high
Terp flower and then I see my service
our asset is is that we build these
machines that are able to produce joints
unlike tobacco equipment that don't work
with sticky residue substances ours do
and so now they're sticky hemp and our
technology can come together and see a
market that is far greater than the five
hundred and forty dispensaries that my
our cannabis pre-rolls are in in
California so it's just a much bigger
addressable market if your resources as
a business are conducive to being unique
and coming up with a great product I
think that's what it is for me so I'll
jump to the next question here which is
now that we're talking about products
and the fact that quality and all these
different factors are gonna be sort of
really determining factors that you're
gonna win what can you do to take steps
to appealing to consumers I think we've
touched on this a little bit but what
can your products do or what can you do
with your products to best appeal to
consumers let's start with Omar here I
would think you know like really being
careful with the packaging and labeling
and not like over selling the products
not making any medical claims which are
for sure gonna draw FDA scrutiny yes you
know those are like the pitfalls to
avoid it's just basically the
understanding about the medical benefits
of CBD is already out there there's no
need to be repeating it and drawing FDA
scrutiny so I think that's something
important but others are making those
claims for us let them it's a good plan
I agree Ken about products
well I have to defer to the operational
folks for for most of product
development questions but I can I can
say that you know as you are thinking
about your products and you're thinking
about differentiating yourself you
should also be thinking about protecting
your intellectual property around the
products and we've already talked a
little bit about trademarks but there
are things like trade dress which is
it's a trademark for the look and feel
of your product I've found my own
business experiences that some degree of
consistency helps build that trust it
becomes familiar and whatever is
familiar is loved and then whatsoever is
loved is bought so that that I find to
be important I think anecdotally I would
say that you know I there are a lot of
products out there there's a bit of for
the the newbies who are going into the
local dispensary it's a bit of an
overwhelming experience if there are
ways to simplify and get your message
through clearly and and it works for you
then keep driving at home driving at
home because I think there's a lot of
noise and a simple consistent message
can can help build that brand simple is
generally good Scott you've got several
SKUs of products what do you think here
yeah for us again it was said earlier
creating a lifestyle brand is really the
key to creating the enterprise value of
the company and for us when we created
our golden sea brand a lot of thought
went into that and actually where we
located our farm a lot of thought went
into that we're in Santa Cruz County the
culture of that area is very embracing
of cannabis and it always has been
and we're really looking on the cannabis
side to national distribution at some
point so we wanted to create a very
iconic California surf brand we
concentrate on serve our music in fact
some of the more prominent investors in
our company they're already in those
sectors you know I see a lot of brands
out there that have very blase names so
I'm very and
trio very they're not really picking up
the spirit of the culture of these
industries so and I also agree that the
lifestyle aspect of it you know has to
start with the story and our story you
know we have a worm farm and that's
where it all starts so we go for all the
way from worms to wheat and then it's
really well branded and distributed in
that order worms to eat so let me twist
the question a little bit and I'll go
back right back to you Scott and take it
down the line so we're talking about how
to appeal to consumers is there anything
different or what do you need to do to
to appeal to investors because this is
an industry that it is competitive and
funding is something we're all battling
for so what can you do with the product
skews how can you frame the business for
investors and one caveat being that
golden seed has just recently launched
it's a series or it's a reggae offering
in January so we'd love to hear about
sort of how you position the brand and
how that process going for you so the
capital side of this industry has become
very challenging and when we started our
our company a couple years ago it's very
important for us not to give up control
I think Ken mentioned that earlier so we
invested quite a bit of our own capital
into it we have very little debt and we
waited until our company was far enough
along to bring an investment because we
have a higher valuation so we start with
the Regulation D offering which is been
in the securities act since 1934 and
that's where your selling shares to
accredited investors that would be at a
lower valuation as we continue to build
our brand in 2015 the SEC approved
amendment to the Act that allowed for
sale of stock to anyone and it's it's
anyone really in the world so that's
called Regulation a and we're qualified
first week of January of this year to be
the first cannabis cultivator and retail
product in the country to be able to
sell shares and so yesterday was our 30
day anniversary 30 days since we
launched and right now we have
applications for investment from over a
thousand people in 46 states and 17
countries literally in every continent
in the world and what that does for us
is not only at most will give up 10% of
our company so we're still in control we
didn't take private equity I think the
capital markets a lot of people are
taking too much money and they're
looking for business you know we're a
business that's looking for money we're
a credible we're very near-term gonna be
cashflow positive and that's just a
great story so through regulation a you
raise capital you create brand
ambassadors throughout the country when
this becomes nationally legal will
already have exposure in all those
states so for us we kind of approached
it differently but it's gone really well
it's on an investor call last night
through over a hundred people out of the
thousand that have already come in and
it's just been very well received it's
very transparent they take ownership in
the company and we communicate really
well so it's awesome and I think the
benefits will alone only begin to come
as these folks are champions for the
brand so I think democratizing that that
process is just add so much to a brand
now as far as having brand ambassadors
out there essentially let's get to the
lawyers who've dealt with this quite a
bit and your view as far as positioning
the company towards investment
definitely I think something that a lot
of my clients were in the hemp world and
creating hemp derive CBD are doing is
they're registering federal trademarks
with a US Patent and Trademark Office
for all sorts of brands because USPTO
will register hemp trademarks after the
farm bill they will not yet register the
cannabis
and so now you can have federally
enforceable federally registered
trademarks for hemp to write products
that the USPTO you know just keeps
issuing and so that's something that I
think investors will look at is if you
don't have any registered trademarks of
the federal level what have you been
doing with all this investor capital so
far so I think that makes somebody you
know more appealing from the investment
perspective I think your point of like
you know recruiting using crowdfunding
and regulation a investors all over the
country who will later become brand
ambassadors is a brilliant idea and I'm
glad to be standing next to the you know
the first company to have done this I've
been thinking for years like when will
somebody finally implement crowdfunding
and regulation aid for the cannabis
industry and you know I would say
deserves a round of applause thank you
and I'll pass it on to Kay okay so I
probably should say that again these are
my opinions only legal advice but my
perspective having helped a number of
investors make investments and countless
companies raise money it comes down to
answer the question two ways one it's
about pulling together assets so we
talked about intellectual property
assets but there are other really
important assets that investors will
always look at they'll look at your team
so consider your people as your assets
they'll look at your supply chain
they'll look at your consumer let your
customer list though look at the
contracts that you have on an earlier
panel there were some cautionary tales
about not having a clear understanding
of who your owners are right so we all
understand that in California you can
make a contract just orally you can make
a contract by implication you don't need
to write it you can just sign it so we
do see an awful lot of people who step
forward
when they see some sort of great
opportunity to a profit claiming to be
an owner of a cannabis company right so
having some degree of good paperwork so
your leases your contracts those are all
assets right to the extent that your
contracts don't aren't terminable you've
locked in good rates things like that so
you you assemble together all your
assets and of course revenue streams
[Music]
so that's one way to answer it I think
the other is more of a process driven
one just some suggestions it is very
very off-putting to try to bring money
in if you are shitshow right and you
don't have your things together and
lined up it's very hard to do it's very
hard to close a deal if you negotiate
backwards it's kind of like dating you
you really do want to build trust in
that relationship too so one of the
things that we try to do with our
clients is to be very careful in how
they present themselves when terms are
proposed how they're proposed the
process is really really really
important because it is data and in that
regard you know it doesn't need to be
our firm but but but having someone
who's done the process can really really
help and we have been pulled into nearly
failed transactions where there was no
legal advice or no business advice
frankly and unwinding that and trying to
get it back on to the rails can be very
very difficult I do think there's a lot
of value in having someone who's been
through the process many times in your
corner to help you with the process of
completing that relationship there's a
node out there I just want to add a few
things that Ken made me think of you
know I've only been in the can I was
for a few years now I come from a real
estate background about my own
development company for many years and I
see a lot of different companies and
sometimes they're too heavily tilted to
the business side and they don't really
know that much about the plant or you
have people starting with the plant that
aren't associated themselves with
competent business people and I have
been in front of a lot of investors we
had some really large-scale investors
early on in the Regulation D and they do
want to see that they want to see
competent compliance accounting systems
and controls implemented in your in your
business and without that I think number
one you're not going to be that
successful number two you're not going
to get investors I think I fully agree
with that if you want to make yourself
more attractive to investors basically
reverse engineered the due diligence
process and see how they're going to be
looking at you and make sure that all of
the metrics are going to be favorable
before you put yourself on the market
you know hemp world
it's about acres it's not about square
feet like we talked about in cannabis
and so when you're going to scale to
meet the kind of demand that Deen's
company's gonna have you're talking
about Hunters acres maybe several
hundred acres and then you're getting
into really kind of commercial
agriculture that's not our experience as
a cannabis grower of that scale so it's
very important for us we actually
partner with local strawberry farms so
in Santa Cruz County there's five
thousand acres of strawberry farms we
only deal with organic strawberry
farmers and organic strawberries can
only be planted maybe every five years
so they need rotation crops and it's
been a great experience for us to give
our genetics to that farmer and let them
grow a consistent and very clean and
good product and it is a consistent and
clean product by the way should show
that was a legal term yes so actually
let me just sort of pin this down so
structurally because again this is it is
you know a lot of uncertainty here
federally and then their departures at
the state level on CBD is there a
preferred sort of formation structure
because we're talking about we're
talking about the ops is is there
anything to be lent there as far as kind
of a smarter way to form your company
when you go out specifically you to guys
I mean I think definitely have having
some sort of like corporate entity so
that if there's gonna be an audit it's
gonna fall on that entity and you know
you always get the protections of the
corporate form protection from civil
liability and so I would say definitely
always operate with the legal entity as
opposed to being a sole proprietor or
just a general partnership sometimes if
people work together and they don't have
any you know any agreement to the
contrary they never formed a corporation
they've never formed an LLC the law in
California will infer that there's a
de-facto partnership and you know now
there's gonna be all sorts of like
obligations from one partnership to
another so I think it's always good to
like Gabe thought to which corporate
form you're going to have and follow the
formalities of that corporate structure
so you get all the benefits of having a
corporation it doesn't do you any good
to incorporate with the Secretary of
State and not develop any bylaws and
never hold any meetings because that
corporation will be pierced there's a
doctrine known as piercing the corporate
veil which would basically go from the
immunity from civil liability to immune
to civil liability for the individual
owners if they don't follow the
corporate form yep
so there's no one-size-fits-all but I
will say that our firm tends to prefer
California corporations largely for the
reasons that Omar has gone through it
gives a level of protection for the
individuals it creates a certain amount
of formality that people are familiar
with right so that when you look at most
of the investors they know corporations
down pat but they're a little less sure
what a partnership actually
is or what it means corporations allow
you to bulk up on shareholders - it's
easier to manage a business that has
multiple shareholders of your
corporation than say a limited liability
company so you know one of my last
companies had 12,000 shareholders but it
does scale I mean we like California
because we have we had this belief
rightly or wrongly that it will help us
if there is ever litigation because we
almost certainly will end up in a
California Court rather than say a
Delaware Court and I know that there's a
tendency towards Delaware law because
those courts are very predictable smart
judges and there's lots of jurisprudence
so you can call upon so you know what to
expect
but we don't want to be in Delaware and
that's because cannabis is still illegal
in Delaware I guess for like a hemp
derived CBD products company I think
Delaware may be a viable option you know
in terms of going public in the future
you know because I it's just something
that the market understands how to
analyze that's a good well so we
actually looked at that and I think
Scott may want to chime in as well but
we looked at that and I think the fact
that yes there is there is no cannabis
law on the books in Delaware that's one
but at the end of the day there's also I
don't believe of hemp law on the books
so right now you'd be hoping that you
know federal law sort of makes its way
down and so I think when you look at all
this even on the hemp side our attorneys
have advised to stay in a state that
expressly has legal hemp rights yes god
I just wanted out an additional
complexity in terms of organization
we're in both cannabis and we're in half
and you know because of federal banking
laws a lot of different compliance
issues way more compliance in cannabis
we found that we had to keep those
companies completely separate and even
then
you know if you're in HAMP that could
affect your landing on other properties
we're kind of going through that right
now said be interested you guys take on
that well that's a really good point I
was thinking like it you know you could
have a intellectual property holding
company because I mean if you're gonna
have one brand with one pillar of that
brand is gonna be this hemp company and
the other pillar of the brand is going
to be a cannabis company but they're
gonna have the same you know branding
and they're gonna like have that
synergistic influence then you probably
want to like structure it so that their
core you know that they're basically
like licensing the brand from an
independent IP Holding Company yes and I
think that that goes back to your
initial question of how would you end up
structuring it I you know we do see that
the intellectual property tends to
reside within the IP holding company and
then there's a whole bunch of other
holding companies potentially for you
know the property ownership and
equipment leases right and then license
out to the to the more regulated the
other regulated entities operate
basically in silos going up to the
holdings company at the IP level right
yeah so we use organizational groups for
all kinds of things and they can be very
strategic and they're particularly
interesting in the regulated cannabis
space because we're all aware of the
restrictions that so many places have on
an alienation of the licenses right
licenses and the permits and some of the
localities are way worse than the state
level try to change something at
bellflower for example right so you know
it's you can use organizational
groupings for a really really good
purpose and I have one other thing
that's not so much corporate formation
but it's just a it dropped in my mind
when talking about the forum of dispute
resolution I am a big fan of arbitration
arbitration and every single commercial
agreement arbitration and every single
share purchase agreement arbitration in
employment agree
those are a little tricky but they can't
be done they're still enforceable here
in California there are lots of good
reasons for it the two that probably
matter most to this group first as you
can almost by contract shape the kinds
of disputes and the kinds of remedies
available to the parties so you have
tremendous power to get exactly what you
want in a given relationship and the
other is its completely private and it's
in front of someone pretty much of your
own choosing so if you're worried about
being in front of a 75 year old who is
you know dead set against what you do
and think you are evil into the
courtroom and you can't really strike
them for for that you really can't you
could try but you're not gonna be
successful but you can choose your
arbiter and as the industry gets older
and we have a working experience we'll
get to know who the other reason why
arbitration is so appealing and why so
many cannabis or you know amp derived
CBD agreements have arbitration clauses
is because the justice system is broken
when it comes to resolution of civil
disputes it takes approximately seven
years to get from filing of a complaint
to a judgment in California just because
the criminal cases take precedence they
have all sorts of deadlines some time
limits and if you don't get prosecuted
within the speedy trial rights then the
prosecution has to be dismissed and
therefore in custody criminal cases
basically go to the front of the
judicial processing order and it takes
like years to get justice in the
California courts so that's a big reason
why arbitration is you know becoming
increasingly more common in the cannabis
world and now we have you know like
private dispute resolution companies
like jams
they have cannabis aware neutrals
whereas for a long time like you know
even finding neutrals that were aware of
cannabis was very difficult
interesting so let's enough about laws
let's let's take it maybe thirty thirty
thousand feet we've talked about brands
ops formation one of the interesting
dynamics happening I think is that
you're seeing different types of
entrance into the space you see folks
that are essentially sort of wellness
brands coming in and again working off
that ethos and then you're also seeing
cannabis brands who understand the space
and obviously are looking for
diversification because they've got
resources that are really conducive to
him so you've seen these two factors
come in and sort of clash just
interestingly wanted to hear your guys's
opinions on how that landscape is going
to look of CBD companies sort of
globally I just my perspective starting
out as a cannabis company and moving
into M there's a lot of cannabis
companies that are diversifying into
hemp flour I mean the distribution is
different but selling CBD products but
hemp flour hemp terpenes we're seeing a
lot of people in the camps will try to
get into that space some were
considering ourselves I think you know
there's a lot of growth in the hemp
industry because a lot of the people who
were afraid of euphoria that in the
undesirable side effect of cannabis are
completely okay with like CBD and with
the hemp effects and so I think there's
may like whoever wanted cannabis is
already like a consumer is my belief but
there's many people who are trying to
transition from all these opioid pain
medicines who will find tremendous
relief in CBD and that's a tremendous
growth market and we also have like the
boomer population that you know it's now
looking for alternatives to opioid
painkillers and
- like the whole pharmaceutical
cocktails that they're being described
and they're looking for like one
alternative herbal solution so we do see
I mean I think you know we haven't
really it's it's hard to predict now
what its gonna look like but we're gonna
see like a lot more innovation you know
especially as there's like different
formulations when I see cannabis drinks
we haven't really seen the full
development of cannabis drinks just like
10 years ago it would be difficult to
predict that the vape cartridges would
be one of the biggest segments of the
cannabis industry I think now it's
difficult to predict what the next big
summit will be but it's gonna be it's
gonna involve technology and
technological innovation they will and
then it's a super dynamic space so now
they're it's off you know 35% in the
last three months
right so room for new innovative
products I agree that it'll be a
confluence of folks coming from
different sectors that bring I think
different viewpoints and and different
stories that they can craft to I think
different segments of the audience so
let's do this I think we have time for
maybe one question maybe one question
let's see one question for Dean and Omar
and Ken it's got who's got one question
one
oh all the way they're always in the
back never fails when Iraq stand in the
back there in the front then when I
stand on the front exercise I had a way
to make them work I remind you to
download the huva app also the after
party tonight at Pier 23 thank you if
you are not expecting outside closer can
you hear me yep if you're not expecting
outside investors or don't need outside
investors do you still recommend having
a California corporation over an LLC if
you are in the hemp space as a farmer or
in the cannabis space as a farmer what
the lawyers go so do you think that you
can keep your membership down below say
35 yes so I think it probably isn't the
most important decision on your plate if
you're already an LLC just continue to
be one operating agreements are very
flexible corporate affairs if you will
match your business interests perfectly
I think the big appeal of an LLC is
streamlined corporate governance but in
California we have a statutory entity
called a closed corporation that also
offers streamlined corporate governance
in a corporate form and so that's also
an option to consider it would be like a
closed corporation and you know many
wine companies in Sonoma County my home
county are closed corporations like all
the wineries and just because it's
they're very easy to manage you don't
really have to so good question my two
cents is I'm with Ken if you're not
taking on a bunch of investors LLC is
easy easy peasy hey thank you guys thank
you all very much once again for Dina
Scott and Omar