hello
thank you very much it's a pleasure to
be here uh always great to see alex and
our friends at icbc we're big fans of
this conference they really bring people
together around the world in i think
almost a unique way so it's really an
honor to be here i'm here with some
friends some old friends from europe
we've got a great panel here i'm tom
zuber i'm the managing partner of subaru
law or as mentioned we've been in
cannabis a long long time
and we're quite focused on the
increasingly global conversation
relating to cannabis uh zubra lawler
represents a disproportionate percentage
of the biggest brands in u.s and
increasingly global cannabis
i also founded globalgo which is one of
the premier canadian consultancies
around the world it's got brand
affiliates in 10 different countries in
the magazine global cannabis times i'm
delighted to introduce this outstanding
panel
i think of three of the top attorneys in
europe and i've known each of them for a
period of years so it really is an honor
to be here
moderating this panel first is daniel
heyman a dear friend of mine going back
quite some time daniel i think was the
first attorney in switzerland so come on
up daniel please introduce yourself and
he's with mlmll legal
and i'm going to invite everybody up to
the stage and then everybody uh daniel
and everybody else will introduce
themselves say a little bit about
themselves and their organizations kai
uh fred mcneerman uh also one of the i
think the earliest attorneys in germany
by far and a friend of mine going back
several years kai it's great to see you
and peter holmberg
with dentons and if we could just maybe
say a few words i don't know how however
brief you want to be peter we'll start
with you at the end there about your own
practice
at dentons yeah thank you so much
these chairs are much too comfortable
feeling feeling home at actually
yeah uh peter hambrick i'm a partner
with denton's dentist is by far the
largest law firm worldwide with over 20
000 lawyers
we have active cannabis practices where
we advising cannabis companies all over
the world in particular in canada in the
us and in europe but also in asia
i'm now for 30 years in business and 20
years i'm as you can see there in color
for my hair
and advising companies in the life
sciences field for over 20 years right
now
thank you peter kai
yeah i'm kai friesman i'm a lawyer since
2003 started to work in the cannabis
industry started working the cannabis
industry in 2017 as germany legalized
medical cannabis by that time the first
cbd products came up and no one knew how
to regulate it and so it took a deep
dive into these uh legal landscape and
started to block and this block was read
by prohibition partners prohibition
partners was read by mgbs daily
so since four years i'm consulting
medical cannabis import companies in
germany cbd companies ham companies and
now we are preparing for legalization in
germany thank you kai and daniel a few
words about yourself
i was a commodities trader before i
turned lawyer i was in business for
about 12 years in 2019
we decided to
establish the first dedicated cannabis
desk at the large law firm in
switzerland we represent a big part of
the big players in swiss industry
along the value chain
and basically that's it
three kids always tired
[Laughter]
thanks brother uh and kai why don't we
start with you as an update can you tell
us about uh from a regulatory standpoint
uh the status of things relating to hemp
and cbd as well as medical cannabis and
also maybe give us a glimpse as to
recreational reform here what that's
going to look like
okay how much time do i have yes
where can we start
so yeah okay let's talk about about
legalization i guess
so
the german government decided last year
in november to legalize cannabis and
they set up a coalition agreement
stating just one sentence
so we will allow the distribution of for
of cannabis for adults in licensed shops
just one sentence okay
so and now we're in the middle of the
debate how to do that we are talking
about maximum numbers of licensed stores
of caps
we have an actual debate of
thc content in the flower to use or to
limit the thc content in the in in the
dried flowers
we are also talking about
if we shall allow finished products like
waves and edibles and beverages
and it's still in in in in a flux so
we expecting the first draft in october
november
it's presented by the ministry of health
because we think or the politician the
policy
things the this is in health issue so
you really have to understand that it's
it's all about health it's about harm
reduction
and if you want to do business here you
have to keep that in mind so
all the debates around this health issue
because we have really bad
stuff in the illicit market right now it
got better it got worse and worse over
the years
so the need for reform is very very
strong here in germany right now
but that's the point so if
we have the drug addiction societies for
example they're making a lot of pressure
on the ministry of health
they want these
reduced opening hours they want to
reduce thc content they want
no advertisement no
no
logo no brands on the finished products
and
we as the industry are just fighting all
these points right now to have a liberal
market model to have so that the
industry is incentivized to invest and
to establish a business and to take the
fight against the illicit market right
now so that's
some for the beginning
thank you very helpful uh and daniel we
hear that the medical cannabis market in
switzerland is opening up we're very
excited about that what are some of the
specific changes we can expect and what
challenges still remain
that's a big subject a lot of questions
uh we have in switzerland we've had a
medical system where you required a
special permit from the federal office
of public health to be able to get
access to medical cannabis for a long
time
and that has made life for a lot of
patients difficult
around a hundred thousand patients in
switzerland today are known or estimated
by the federal office of public health
to consume cannabis for medical purposes
out of maybe four or five hundred
there's a dark number obviously of
cannabis consumers in total
and the tragedy was that out of these
hundred thousand patients only three
four thousand actually had access to
legal medical cannabis so
96 97 000 patients actually had to
resort to the illicit market
and procure cannabis from
sources they knew or didn't know and as
we know and as
my colleague kai here mentioned the
quality is not controlled in the illicit
market and we have a big issue with
cannabis that's
spiced up with all kinds of some
synthetic materials that nobody knows
exactly what it is so it's quite a
tragedy for the patients associations
now what happened is that this special
nature of the permit
became to some extent mute because such
a an overwhelming demand
emerged in the market
and what happened now is that the
government realized it and now
after many years the change is going to
be enacted in the beginning of on the
1st of august in fact where two things
are essentially changing cannabis is
moving from
the schedule of prohibited narcotics
into
narcotics that can be used for medical
purposes without this special permit so
every doctor in switzerland will
essentially be able to prescribe medical
cannabis which is a very big opening and
then the second thing that's going to
happen is that the export market is
going to open up and that's interesting
for investors to realize because swiss
producers
a lot of whom have been very active in
the cbd market in the last few years
they're going to have a possibility now
to legally export
medical cannabis in all forms
so that's these are the two main
uh changes that are going to happen
specifically now you have you've asked
me as well about the challenges
of the challenges are many i would say
one of the main challenge starts with
education because most doctors don't
really understand
cannabis or didn't have the experience
to prescribe cannabis most of
whom have not heard about the
endocannabinoid system
they don't know which cannabinoids and
which
mixes of cannabinoids prescriptions
match which
indication and for which indications you
can prescribe medical cannabis so that's
a huge
field that's opening up and for
investors i would keep my eyes very
open on opportunities in education
so that's one field that's uh that's
very challenging the other field i would
say is of administrative nature
there is a problem with um
filling in magisterial preparations
there is only one way to prescribe
medical cannabis in switzerland similar
to germany i think you don't have
finished products
fully licensed drugs
the path to go there is very wide except
for maybe
sativex and and epidiolex which are a
very narrow band of indications of
course you can
have off-label prescription but in
general
it's all through magisterial
extemporaneous preparations
and it's not easy to prescribe based on
extemporaneous preparations because you
have to grow with the patient which is
also one of the beauties in this product
that you can really try
it's trial and error but a lot of
doctors will be very reluctant to just
go for trial and error so there's the
swiss society of cannabis in medicine
and other organizations that are working
very hard
to establish some standards with which
you can actually
start to to prescribe
and i would say the
third
challenge is that there's no
reimbursement from the health insurance
and i think that's one of the main
issues that we have is that efficacy is
very difficult to prove
and
as long as we don't have
reimbursement the question remains
whether this uh this market's really
going to open up for a lot of patients
who
will be struggling to finance
the high costs of cannabis medication i
think of
very helpful daniel thank you and a
great great overview uh peter uh what
regulatory challenges do you see with
planned recreational cannabis
legalization in germany which has all of
us in america very excited yeah indeed a
very very interesting question let's
take a top-down view at first
germany as well as another over 180
countries a member of the un
convention
and two other conventions
regarding the
transit the transfer of
drugs
and cannabis is still considered one of
those drugs which fall under the
respective convention
number two germany is also a eu member
state and has signed off on the schengen
agreement which also refers to
the respective u.n conventions which
means that
the export of cannabis let's say flowers
or other products for recreational
purposes from one country to the other
country is strictly prohibited by these
conventions in the schengen agreement
so when the coalition actually
wrote this one wonderful sentence into
the coalition agreement they did not
think about it and that's in my personal
opinion where can we source the collapse
for the recreational for the adult use
market in germany
and that's the first issue which we have
to solve it's it's really an issue
it is now being discussed are there
solutions to it well there are solutions
to it to a certain extent at least as we
have seen in uruguay canada and the
netherlands where recreational use is of
course
happening so
domestic cultivation
for example or home grow for example are
our solutions to that and i may address
that at a later stage a little bit more
in detail then the next step is we have
to create a respective legal environment
we need a law we need a control
body
with regards to the distribution of the
recreational cannabis in germany will it
be through pharmacies would it be
through licensed shops as it is
mentioned in the agreement or how do we
do that infrastructure
what is the legal basis for it who
controls it
so
lots of other challenges are of course
coming from the quality
and we heard about that the current
illicit market has
cannabis products on or sold which have
additions
which have supplements which are
definitely unhealthy so the illicit
market is using drugs which do not of
course have the same quality as as we
would like to have it on the market but
the quality control of a recreational
cannabis product which is then sold
under the government control that needs
a legal basis so we have a number of
challenges which have to be addressed
very good thank you peter that's very
helpful overview kai let's take it back
to you what are some of the distribution
rules for medical cannabis and what is
the process when trading these products
medical cannabis is
only traded via the pharmacies
okay
so the first step for you as a patient
is you go to the doctor
you have a condition
the doctor has to be convinced that this
condition is uh suitable for cannabis
prescription
and the decision of the prescription is
in the uh sole discretion of the of the
physician of the doctor
so
there isn't it's not limited like in
portugal where you have seven
designations or applications
and uh yeah with this prescription you
go to the pharmacy and uh get your
medical cannabis so what was uh as we
started in 17 the
price per gram medical cannabis was
22-23
euros per gram
that's a lot so what we saw now the last
two years
a couple of pharmacies
really invested in logistics got really
really big sometimes
employing more than 100
pharmacists
and the prices dropped to
9 10 11 euros per gram so almost
comparable to the illicit market
and on the other hand we saw business
models
like taylor medicine so
you
go to the physician and they have sort
of clinics all over all over the place
all over germany and you have to show up
the first time in person and get your
prescription and then your following
prescription you can get you can obtain
we are online via internet
so we see a huge number of patients
of private patients of self-paying
patients
they are not
applying for reimbursement um
they just take it okay it's like
it's like 10 11 euros i would pay that
in the in the illicit market but now i'm
a patient and i have control over the
quality of control over of the product
and i don't take the hustle with my
public or private
health insurer to to get reimbursed so
that's the latest development we saw in
medical cannabis the big question will
be will all these people who are now
in the medical cannabis market will they
withdraw and switch to the
legal market or
does the medical cannabis market
even increases further
very good thank you kai
daniel what's the status of cbd products
in switzerland are they marketed as
tobacco substitutes fragrant oils
cosmetics novel foods therapeutic
products meaning
drugs i'm going to try to keep this one
a bit shorter than the last answer
all of those products
in fact tobacco substitutes i would say
counts for one of the biggest markets in
switzerland
which is just dried flour perfectly
legal to be sold as long as the thc
content is below one percent which is a
bit of an exception in europe
i think czech republic just uh
introduced the one percent thc limit as
well by the beginning of this year
then we have
cannabis oils there is a big issue about
cannabis oils that have been marketed to
some extent is chemical products
the federal office of public health
realized that
these oils that have been sold as
scented oils could be abused for
um
for other purposes
and came to the conclusion and
issued an ordinance that
basically said that you have to
denaturalize this product
and now
you basically can't
consume these products without the
extremely bitter taste so that market's
not really existing or it's at least
expected to be disappearing
then there's uh cosmetic products which
are a perfectly legitimate way to uh
to bring cbd products to market today we
think it's one of the only ways
that in the in the
non-medical use field you can actually
apply these products so cosmetics is an
absolutely valid way to bring cannabis
oils and other products to market uh as
uh on for topical and even
um
use in like mouth sprays and so on so
that's also something that's uh that's
possible
then we have the medical applications
which obviously have to run through
a different kind of route but that's
absolutely also legitimate way to market
and already we see cbd oils that are and
tinctures that are prescribed for
medical purposes as well
very good
peter let's talk about the illegal
market how do you assess the impact of
recreational cannabis legalization on
the illegal market in germany and
if you care to uh throughout other parts
of europe
yeah well that is one of those crystal
ball questions
and i try to read my crystal ball right
now because we don't know how the market
will develop and when we have
recreational cannabis on the market here
in germany
uh from my point of view definitely not
before
2024 but
if you look into the developments for
example in canada how the impact was on
the black market i think we have three
factors which are extremely important
number one price
number two accessibility availability of
the product and number three it's
quality
these are the three major factors who
have an impact on the respective uh
legal
cannabis market for adult use if we have
the right price if we have the right
availability and if you have the right
quality
i'm sure that we definitely could cut
the the black market
by half
but let's talk about how big is the
black market actually in germany
we are talking about a medicinal
cannabis market around now
between 18 to 20 metric tons per year
with an increasing quantity
the black market is
judged
by at approximately 700 metric tons in
germany
that is a significant market
and now the current calculations uh even
for a how do we tax
cannabis for the recreational market uh
is uh cutting it by well it's uh
estimating 400 metric tons which is
around half of the black market
so very very important as i said price
accessibility availability and quality
if that is
competing with the illicit market we
definitely are in a position to cut it
short by 50 or even more very much
depending on
how this will be done the current
discussion about
implementing a certain
cap on the thc level
is definitely from my point of view
helpful for for this
discussion because it's going to
divide the illicit market
and the legal market by the factor of
whatever percentages may be maybe 15 16
we know that currently the medical
market demand for cannabis products with
high thc content around 20 percent and
above is definitely the market at this
point in time it may change it may
change to
extracts but that's what we have now in
germany it's the majority is a flower
market with high content ghc flowers
with
a constant quality
so
we can transfer that to the through the
legal market as well
but i don't think that a limit of
whatever the limit may be
would be helpful for the legal adult u.s
market
very good and peter orkai
i have a follow-up question relating to
taxes so in the united states
particularly when we went from medical
markets to recreational markets
we
couldn't resist the temptation to tax
very heavily
just saying wow here's an opportunity to
bring in some extra money to the
government and there's a notion that
this tax money will go to educate folks
on the dangers of cannabis and so on and
so forth that never really works out
and the end result on the illegal market
conversation is that the illegal market
thrives because the pricing of legal
product goes through the roof and so in
the united states we obviously have been
further along in terms of years
but there is a great big mess because
the illegal market continues to to
govern over half of the revenues of of
the market just in california which is a
very advanced market so my question to
you is do you have any notion as to how
germany is going to
approach taxation of the recreational
cannabis market
yeah sure so the government is aware of
that problem
of that tax and price problem there's
one draft on the table by the green
party the cannabis control act that
drafted this law already back in 2015.
it was in bundestag in 2017
rejected of course it was
in bundestag in 2021
rejected of course by the last grand
coalition
and they propose four euros per
gram of dried flour and six euros per
other products for extracts
that's too much so
then you will end up at 12
12 to 14 euros per gram
but there was
an economist a very famous economist for
regulated markets here in germany
professor houckup and he did a study and
he suggests a 2.6 euro per gram
so that you end up with 10 euros
including vit of 19
and that's the price which can compete
on the
with the illicit market and some
consumers of course are prepared to pay
a little more because you have a
controlled quality
and
probably of course there will be
room for for
even higher prices for craft cannabis or
something
not the 50
euro per gram i saw in barcelona i guess
but
for one gram per one gram but the
government the lawmakers are quite aware
of that so
i'm pretty convinced i'm pretty sure
that there will be a fair price at the
end
very good that's wonderful to hear and i
hope you're correct peter yeah maybe
maybe some some
additions to that the point is of course
who which cultivator is in a position
to provide this
high quality cannabis at that point at
that price
of course you can
have a relatively uh cheap price for
specific cannabis not but not if it's a
gmp
uh controlled uh if it's good
manufacturing practice following which
is
from my point of view the minimum
quality which we which we have to look
at and i don't think the government is
going to change that we have to find
cultivators who are in a position to do
that
probably not in canada probably not in
colombia maybe yes maybe portugal yeah
malta for example we can talk about that
macedonia north macedonia for example
greece i have cultivators coming up
there as well as denmark oops take into
consideration the current energy prices
i have my doubts so that that's number
one which we have to look at who is in
the position who which cultivators on a
position to provide than the respect of
kind of it it would be exported anyway
but i'm coming back to uh the first
problem which i mentioned is the 1961
single convention which means
uh
how can we import
can we import at all any kind of
cannabis for the recreational market yes
or no so we are maybe looking at
domestic growth and how this is going to
be achieved the next question we have
three cultivators in germany who are
doing uh relatively low quantities for
the medicinal market uh afria aurora and
demi khan as we all know
and they have put the first first
cannabis cultivated germany on the
medicinal market so they would be in a
position to increase as they have
announced already uh the production uh
domestically but well others should
participate as well so do we have a
tender process probably not do we have a
licensing process as we heard this
morning probably yes
so that is from my point of view the way
going forward and
finding
licensed producers in germany as we have
it in uruguay as we have it in the
netherlands they just tended by the way
our
domestic uh cultivation for the
recreational market in in the
netherlands
is that the right way we will see that
we'll probably hear that tomorrow at the
icbc conference from mr wienert
what kind of ideas he may have on that
and
we'll see the next issue we have of
course a lot of calculations on what is
uh the the positive impact of the
recreational market uh and take into
consideration that we really would cover
400 metric tons
the actual advantage take into
consideration a tax on the product like
tobacco
then of course the vat
and all the other taxes which are
surrounding the whole industry
we are talking about an advantage of
around 4 billion euros per year
for the for the for the government a
rough calculation of course not very
founded because we don't know how it
will work out but that's that's an incr
significant figure which is of course
also driving that process here
and you know four billion income for for
the government is definitely something
which is worthwhile to consider and of
course it is tempting
always tempting as we have seen that on
the tobacco products and of on alcohol
to just squeeze a little bit more of the
tax into
from from the respective product just
that percent here that percent there
and then of course we are exactly at the
problem which which kai friday just
mentioned we have a non-competitive
product on the market for the recreation
of our use and that's something which we
have to look at
what is also discussed is to have a
mixed taxation model
so to take more taxes on high thc
content products
and low thc content products uh taxed
differently then
this is uh because
again this is a health issue uh
people think that high thc content is
more dangerous more um
to to be controlled more to be
there needs to be some prevention of of
using high thc content products and they
want to do that
with taxation that's also a
proposition on the table
but i think you can't handle that in the
beginning so then in the end it will
come up that high thc products are too
expensive and is still
traded on the on the illicit market
and we don't want that we want a
complete fight
against the illicit market
and
you really can't
estimate the tax
in the tax revenue if you have if you
split that up in in thc content
but we will see so
it's on the table it's discussed right
now because of the high thc content the
health issue let's see
very good thank you both gentlemen that
was very helpful very informative daniel
germany is out a bit
in front obviously as respect
switzerland on the recreational cannabis
conversation what is the status of
recreational cannabis in switzerland
in switzerland
the both the national and the state
council last year approved a change
following a parliamentary initiative
to regulate
cannabis and create the legal market
so we're also moving right ahead it's
just taking a bit more time
the health commission of the national
council is now in a process of preparing
draft legislation
for the purpose of debate with the
federal council which is us our
executive power
and um so the conversation is ongoing
what's also
happening in parallel is that the
federal of office of public health
there's been a change in the narcotics
act that allows for pilot trials
so as of uh autumn this year the pilot
trials will actually start to kick off
it's all in the context of purely
scientific
context
um as peter mentioned uh the factors
that will be
checked will be price availability
and
quality of course but also other
socioeconomic
concepts
the effect on the on the black market
health will be measured data will be
collected and so on um
that will start
uh i'm a bit skeptical about the trials
that they will be able to produce enough
statistical relevant
statistical data before the legislation
actually has to move on because i think
we're in where in
a time where if germany starts to
legalize
and has legalized
cannabis switzerland will have to make a
move much quicker so it's actually good
that our neighbor is now moving fully
ahead and all the tough subjects are
being discussed and what i can imagine
is that once there is a draft
legislation in germany that the swiss
will simply more or less look at that
and copy paste and make give a swiss
spin to it and
move ahead a bit faster
very exciting well i'm hoping that that
happens
kai let's come back to you what are the
administrative uh court of cologne and
the eu commission on novel food
applications doing that can ultimately
affect the cbd market uh in europe as a
whole
oh yeah
so there was a ruling of the
administrative accord of cologne in
march this year
saying that
cbd is in general a medicine and as a
medicine you need an authorization
by the bee farm like a regular medicine
with the clinical studies phase one two
three uh double blind placebo et cetera
so this uh this process takes ten years
cost you 10 to 15 million euros at the
best
and the cologne ruling said okay
even if you under-dose it it was a
product with a recommendation for 18
milligram of cbd intake per day and even
this under-dosed
dosage
makes the or shall make the product
to a regular medicine um and um
that was like oh everyone whoa what's
going on here we
we are applying for noble food
authorization we the ihear is spending
uh three to four million for these noble
food authorizations
for toxicological studies with
with rodents in the first place and then
human
exposure in in the end and we
expecting that the first results are
coming in the at the end of next year
so that you can market cbd as a food
again as a supplement again that's not
possible right now
but if this cologne ruling would be
right
germany would opt out of
of the complete cbd market in europe so
so we took a deep
analysis of this of this ruling um and
the administrative court of cologne has
a special role in
in its history they are the last
fighters for
finished medicines so to say
and
but this ruling is against the the ecg
rulings which have been issued the last
20 years
so in my opinion it's uh it's it's it's
wrong it's a wrong ruling
and it's only in the first instance so i
can't imagine that this
will be that this will survive
the the next instances
and at in the end at least
the european law will step in the free
movement of goods principle
will
also apply for these products in germany
so
you have to handle it you have to look
at it and have to be very careful
especially when you
make health claims or any other claims
to your cbd product you should be very
very reluctant and don't do that and
don't
[Music]
alarm the regulator
because they don't like that if you if
you promise too much for these cbd
products which everyone in the zebra in
the cb in the cbd business did uh you
know it cures cancer it's good for
anxiety for sleep disorders etc and you
can prove it okay
so uh just don't do it and then we won't
have rulings like the one in in cologne
very good
uh peter
how do you how soon do you think when do
you think recreational cannabis will be
legalized in germany and in other
european countries and
on what factors does that depend
yeah a very good question tom
um
as the ma as the legalization of
medicinal cannabis in germany wasn't
really a masterpiece
now they want to do it right
why wasn't it a masterpiece too many
gray areas too many
issues have not been regulated
and came into
practice and
even still discussed uh for example with
regard to the import of flowers which
are just gacp processed
and then gmp processed here in germany
is that a possibility yes or no
so a lot of issues uh haven't been
addressed at that point in time when
liberalization in 2017 in march 2017
took place
now they do want to do it better which
is which is a good idea we had
five or six now five hearings uh during
the march of
uh june sorry during the month of june
with respect to various issues expert
hearings regarding various issues uh for
the legalization of adult use
we will probably hear a little bit more
about that because only the last one was
public uh by tomorrow uh what the
outcome will be and how it looks like uh
the current plan of the government is
that to have the first draft of uh a law
let's say let's call it cannabis law uh
because it just has more facets let's
call it cannabis law we'll be on the
table by
october november i won't uh
i believe it we won't see it before
december this year
then of course it has to be uh
accepted by the the the parliament uh we
have to have one reading maybe a second
reading in the bulldozer
which is our second chamber
which currently doesn't have a majority
of the uh
government so we would see how the
reaction will be
whether the bundesar the second chain
was going to approve that law and when
that will be the case so i probably
foresee
in germany the uh respective law to
liberalize adult use in germany not
before the end of
first probably in the second quarter of
2024 maybe even later this is 2023 maybe
even later and then the whole process
started with regard to where do we get
the cannabis actually from uh are the
current cultivators in germany
on the move already can they increase
the capacity for the first demand of the
recreational
use which is one of the
solutions uh which may maybe take into
consideration uh and i probably foresee
not before to mid of 2024 the first
recreational cannabis on the market well
of course it's a look into a glass
crystal ball
but take into consideration how long it
usually takes to have not only the laws
in place but also then the respective
infrastructure in place with regard to
cultivation and distribution uh and i
said accessibility uh availability of
the product is is a major issue
i think the timeline is probably right
okay
yeah so that's
perfectly right so if the draft comes up
in in bundestag the first time which may
be november december then usually four
to six months later
the parliament will agree on that
and peter is completely right but i
think there are solutions either to the
u.n the signal convention problem
and as well as to the eu level we
learned the last couple of days that the
german government started negotiations
started talking to the european
neighbors to malta to luxembourg
to portugal
they are meeting already trying to set
up a new framework a new legal landscape
for cannabis in europe which is
necessary there are lots of diplomacy
diplomatic efforts are necessary now to
establish new trade relations to
amman to alter all these international
obligations germany has and they started
this process so i'm confident that there
will be a solution in the end
what probably will happen first is that
cannabis social clubs so
homegrown and
corporate home grow will be allowed as
the first measure so if the law is
agreed on in march next year probably
from that day on cannabis will be
decriminalized and you have the right
for homegrown and to grow together in a
cannabis social club
and this will be probably a long longer
time so 10 12 months still the legal
commercial sales maybe really can start
and in this meantime
which is good because then the pressure
of the supply for the german population
is
as
east
but probably we will see then maybe uh
cannabis social clubs with thousand
members or three thousand members in
berlin
and of course then you delegate the
right for planting the
the proposition on the table is three
throwing plants for every person
so you can delegate your right to grow
three plants to a community
and then you have huge uh growth
if you have thousand members so we have
three thousand plants and you need a
facility uh you need the all the um
the equipment and you need the corporate
structure and the government or the the
regulators have to control it have to
check it regularly so let's see what
happened
um i have one follow-up question here
and then i do want to leave time for one
or two questions from the audience and i
have many more questions i'd like to ask
um but why don't we direct this to
daniel in the first instance and then
open it up to the panel i'd like to hear
from everybody quick answers though
please leave questions for the audience
uh what place or places do you see
providing uh product for germany and
switzerland uh assuming uh that peter's
implication that not all the product
perhaps will come internally from these
countries but actually will be imported
so in the united states of course um in
each state particularly in regards to
thc there is no transporting thc across
state borders um it's it's perfectly
illegal there and so that doesn't happen
at all whenever you start a new uh
whenever a new state in the united
states emerges becomes uh legalized for
recreational cannabis purposes uh
operations start a novel meaning you
have to build cannabis businesses from
scratch in that state in order to
provide cannabis to that state that's
not going to be quite the same in europe
i'm curious as an american just
understand and i think just as a as an
international business person i'm
curious to know how that international
conference is going to work so quickly
aside from germany's internal production
in switzerland's internal production
where do you see most of your cannabis
coming from both for the medical and
recreational markets in terms of
countries in europe
okay i was a commodities trader so i
very much believe in pricing as being
the main driver so when we're talking
raw materials i think maybe south africa
will be a very interesting
uh place maybe thailand
could be very interesting
um happen in the short term
in in a very short time yeah like next
few years
all uh in switzerland everything from
switzerland everything from switzerland
yeah pretty much canada maybe canada
maybe yeah okay uh kai or peter any
thoughts on that yeah
well thank you for the for the medical
market we have new cultivators coming up
in other european countries
uh we have malta portugal not to forget
spain maybe we have to see how the
legalization
legalization will work there we have
greece
not to forget we have northern macedonia
denmark already so there are
competitors to the
uh
current large exporters like canada and
the netherlands into germany up coming
up
so
for the for the
recreational market i don't see any kind
of export happening uh uh of course i i
i agree with you kyrie there should be a
solution but on the other hand you know
we
28th member state have to change the
schengen contract with regard to that
subject matter this will not go within a
couple of months so this will take much
more time as far as i can see
i don't think that the schengen equity
has to be changed because you can
have a different interpretation on it
but of course you have to talk to your
european neighbors and you have to find
a unanimous solution you have to
convince european neighbors
yeah as peter said exactly the year so
in the first years in 1718 only imports
from the netherlands and from canada
were possible to germany and then
many many other countries came online
like jamaica australia ali soto
european countries etc
and
the decisive question is the the carbon
footprint of of cannabis i think so
if you really have to import most of the
stuff from other countries the 400 tons
at
100 times for the tourists which are
coming then to germany
so i would prefer that the cannabis is
coming from a country with
ideal climate conditions so that the
carbon footprint is as
low as possible
because we have to think about that look
look outside we have a gas crisis we
have a ukraine war uh the next winter is
going to be hard germany wouldn't be
able to afford
400 tons cultivation domestic in in
germany
yeah
so i see we're out of time here do i can
i take one question from the audience
maybe two if you have a brief question
you don't need to tell a whole story
oh there you go yeah
thank you let's hear it for the panel by
the way make some noise
hi good afternoon uh good morning
actually uh thank you very much for the
presentation i'd like to come back with
you and of course to all of you
gentlemen and the question that you
raised peter which is quality you know
right you know how you're going to
certify this and and we're talking about
some possible countries and things which
already happening uh we have a company
required uruguay sports a lot to
switzerland we have a company in
portugal porsche exparts a lot so it's
already happening it's not like you know
we have to think of so portugal has
become a major exporter and as we know
you know today the gold center is gmp
farmer you know gold manufacturing
practice of the pharmaceutical
industries for those who are not allowed
what's your bet gentlemen what would be
the minimum requirement for producing
countries being either south africa as
daniel had mentioned as possible new
entrants or you know existing players
like uruguay and portugal
well i i'd certainly take a crack at
that just from the perspective of what
we've seen happen in other areas of the
world outside of europe it's going to
come down to as i think
kai had mentioned certainly carbon
footprint but i think also it's going to
come down to uh as daniel mentioned cost
right ultimately
the biomass is a commodity right but the
brands that sit on top of the biomass
whether it's it's a vape brand it's an
edible brand um that's where the real ip
and i think you see the discrepancy and
pricing occurring right so ultimately
those biomass that the commodity prices
will iron out so what you're going to
see is that the product will have to
come from places in europe where it's
cheaper to produce it under great
conditions for growing cannabis portugal
is a great example the short answer
regarding quality is eu gmp
i believe in eu gmp of course it is uh
necessary for the business market triple
doubles uh and i don't see a different
quality happening for
the recreational market
oh sorry
well i'm coming and this will be the
last question because we're starting to
run out of time i'm sorry
go ahead
quickly quickly it will be very quickly
when he's speaking about augmp speaking
about only the final product also for
the cultivation now of course the whole
process has to be eugmp compliant
currently for the medicine market
and i believe this is going to happen
for
the recreational market as well
i don't believe that the
our
cultivators of of a salad at this point
in time with some green houses would
qualify for the cultivation local
cultivation of cannabis here in germany
endorse
thank you very much thank you very much
daniel kai peter great to see you
gentlemen always
one more time tom zuber daniel heyman
peter holmer
very informative