hello everybody and welcome to our panel
on operating a medical cannabis company
post-recreational legalization um i
think personally this is actually a very
very important
topic because we have to make sure that
patients can keep access
and that the dispensary is not the
alternative option for patient access
and i'm very very happy to have four
very experienced entrepreneurs on my
panel today who have a lot of experience
with these topics
i have diane scott
from jmcc group
she's the chair and ceo they are a
company from canada but they are
operating in
jamaica and new jersey
we have dave bradman who is counseled
with redmond mayfield bastard reisenthal
and from california
we have alex ravitch equity partner at
hybrid farm and a cannabis education and
medical partnership in loose friends
from canada thank you
and we have stephen farbek president and
ceo of taylor cannabis but hello
cannabis has two branches they handle
cannabis clinics and to have kind of
this retail concept
so i'm super excited to have these
experienced panelists here
and i'd say we just
jump straight in and start with you
diane
i am i understand most of the gmt
group's operations are based in jamaica
but you're a canadian company so how did
energy use legalization and cannabis
affect your business
not very much actually lisa because um
two things to start with can't the
health canada has
banned imports in canada so despite the
fact that we have exported
between 2018 and 2020 about 30 000 kilos
of dried flour today you cannot import
into canada the other thing is we at the
time started to see the writing on the
wall we have an excessive amount of
cannabis available in canada today and
so it was very clear we were going to
see some downward pressure on the
pricing
so in canada what we do is we support
research we are in a pediatric and out
of epilepsy trial
with the university of saskatchewan but
that's all of our activity
at this time so for us it had very
little impact on our business model
yeah that's very interesting to see um
dave
um what do you think as your europe
looks ahead to legalize uh recreational
cannabis what are three or four most
important things that we can learn from
you from the u.s particularly in
california all right thanks thanks very
much thanks to icbc for inviting us here
today and to all of you and to my good
friend over here matt cumin who's my
guru and mentor who brought me into this
12 years ago
i've been in san diego by way of new
york
since
2010 we've been watching
california in particular transitioning
from
medical to adult use
we tend to
try to refer to
recreational adult use on purpose
because we think that
this is one of the things i think we've
learned is that
calling it
recreational plays into the hands of the
haters who think that we're trying to
pervert their children
so this is something that we've been
trying very hard to change the messaging
on
these last few years it's been quite a
transition
uh 2018 was the first year that we've
had adult use in california
[Music]
and it's been
challenging
so one of the things i think
uh i can say uh it's there's an old
saying uh
when i was growing up
those who don't know history
are content condemned to repeat it so i
encourage you all in europe to watch
study
what we've done in the united states
states like california colorado
washington oregon more recently states
like new york new jersey canada
and
almost scientifically study what we've
done right and what we've done wrong
and try to avoid the mistakes
that have been made
and try to emphasize the things that
we've done right
so for example
um
[Music]
in the united states
particularly in california
we have not really streamlined use
technology as much as i think we could
have
to streamline the licensing and
permitting process to make it more
efficient and economical to get people
into the business and to get them
to do what they want to do
and
it's the licensing and permitting
process has become very cost prohibitive
and i recommend that you try to find
ways to use technology to keep keep
streamline the process and keep costs
down one more thing
don't look at excise taxes or vat
as the way to make money for the
government solve all the problems
pacify the people who are against this
because the the more the product ends up
costing the patient or the consumer
the higher the likelihood is that the
illicit market is going to thrive
and that's going to make it harder for
those of you who want to operate legally
and then i guess the last thing i'd say
in my little three or four points what
we can learn
innovate
interview
never stop innovating
yeah super important point thank you for
saying that
um alex how did the legislation of
cannabis affect medical patients in
canada and what lessons were learnt to
prevent
or can we learn to prevent the same
issues here yeah i really want to bring
this over again thanks for having me
again it's great to be back in berlin so
uh
i really
wanted to express that yes everyone's
excited about recreational everyone's
excited about having cannabis everywhere
we believe that cannabis should not have
been prohibited to begin with that you
know the listed market has a lot of the
challenges that we want to do better in
the legal market but we cannot forget
about the medical patients i think this
is something that has to be stressed
because what happened in canada and uh
i'm almost still steve stuck here
because this is something that he's
lived through is once that once
recreational happens a lot of the
companies who are fake medical start to
come out you start to realize who really
cared about medical who didn't and then
you start to realize a lot of these
companies that were talking medical the
second the wreck happened they
threw everything on the ground and ran
as fast as they can to go public and
open up retail stores
which is not as wonderful as people
think it is but that's another topic for
another day
the thing is that i think germany can
really learn from our mistakes is around
like we have a maximum on the amount of
thc for edibles as an example
but why not for medical purposes why
should there be a maximum like there's
no maximum on the amount of other
medications and you have to trust
patients to be able to take the right
amount so that's one example also taxes
on medicine is ridiculous we canada
don't tax any medicine
except we have taxes on medical cannabis
um
so that always made no sense uh
but so so there's a few things that we
did wrong uh but one thing that we're
starting to do right but i think germany
has an advantage of is on the pharmacy
side
very proud to see that germany is going
full speed ahead with going medical
cannabis to pharmacy that would have
helped canada a lot because to have
pharmacy led cannabis
is really the way it should have been
done and i think that's going to be a
big advantage for you here
uh but and the last point i'll say then
we'll let steve uh kind of talk to this
point is around uh insurance that's
another thing in germany because you
have some insurance covered i know i
hear a lot of people complaining about
uh it's not covered enough and you know
not enough approvals i can tell you with
canada we only have one group and there
are the military veterans who have
coverage
and that's considered a very lucrative
kind of offering for licensed producers
but here in germany you have way more
coverage already so
and this is something very typical in
canada too like in canada we sometimes
complain about our industry and then we
go elsewhere and we realize how good we
have it and i would also just last point
to express that to the german people is
that as tough as it is you're still so
much further ahead than you used to be
and there's a lot to be proud of so uh
you should definitely be proud of the
fact that you even have pharmacare that
you do have coverage for anybody even
though there's a lot to be desired and
there's more coverage to be had
there are some things to be proud of so
those are just some quick thoughts and
i'm sure i'll share some thoughts
yeah thank you um stephen
can you tell us a little bit how do you
differentiate between patient access and
to recreational side of your business
what are the main differences between
those like if you look at it yeah this
is um one of the largest challenges that
we faced and one of the key things that
we wanted to
want to actually be able to do at hello
cannabis
um
what we found is this big blend blurry
area between medical patients that use
cannabis and recreational users that use
canvas
and
one of the key goals that we started
trying to do and uh when i moved from
the legacy market over into the legal
medical clinic market
is to be able to try differentiating
between
medical patients and recreational users
and there is a distinct difference
hello cannabis started as one of the
first independent legal medical clinics
we're now operating with over over 6 000
patients and we've gathered enough data
to see distinct differences between
medical patients and recreational users
some of that is derived because of
essentially how access is given so we're
seeing some very similar
similar
trends basically with
how they have access right now it's very
easy to walk to a brick and mortar store
and typically you're starting you see a
different demographic when you look at
medical patients you're seeing a
different demographic
when you were trying to differentiate
between medical and recreational
um i found that a very very very
difficult challenge
because i i will candidly admit i i'm a
patient first i've always been a patient
first
and i was blessed to be able to share my
origin story here some six years ago and
it's very nice to be back alex thank you
again on cdc for having us
um
i do use cannabis recreationally as well
and i think there's a very distinct
difference between when i'm using it
medically when i'm using it
recreationally um
what
we did differently is we opened up the
one of the first legal recreational
stores in the country and we actually
intentionally put it right beside where
our brick-and-mortar medical clinic was
we're unfortunately hindered to be able
to give any medical advice with respect
to cannabis in a recreational store
yet one in three people would walk in
and ask a question about the medical
properties of cannabis and legally we're
not able to do that so of course
everybody finds a loophole on how they
can talk about a medical
aspect of it but not
talking about a medical aspect of it
just like wow
you really want to feel
relaxed
you know you do this and and you have 25
year old kids that are coming in
asking medical questions or pseudo fake
medical questions to be able to find
something for their grandmother who's a
75 year old lady who probably has a
whole host of other medical conditions
and medications that would definitely be
interacting with cannabis in a different
way
they need to speak to especially
they need to speak to somebody that
understands titration that understands
their personal needs and how to be able
to use it properly and unfortunately
that's completely lacking the
recreational world and we were the first
in the world to do this and it's a model
that actually worked far better than i
expected and i really encourage people
to look at this we have the model for
this this truly is not meant to be
a self-promotion here but it worked and
having a medical clinic beside that
recreational store and being able to
track these trends and offer
the services for every single different
consumer of cannabis was an absolute
game changer for us and i think an
absolute game changer for the area in
southern ontario for us to be able to
have a 25 year old kid come in
and ask questions for his grandmother
but then be able to immediately give
them access
and
most importantly his grandmother's
access to a doctor to be able to speak
about what specifically
they need
really changes the game and there is a
distinct difference between canvas when
it's used medically and recreationally
and unfortunately you do need a doctor
to be able to differentiate that or at
least a formal educator
and that's where the pharmacists i think
come in also
uh because with their formal training
and that's where germany is really going
right
yeah but you have to understand that in
germany we are at a very critical point
at the moment our observational survey
that was running stopped they published
the results
it goes a lot against flower and
like a lot of patients are scared that
they will lose access now once
recreational reform counts that they
have insurance say we won't pay for your
solid products anymore it found might
have just like 10 seconds there what
what we noticed as soon as recreational
opened up not only did the licensed
producers
that had this fake medical it was the
only we were their only source of
revenue if you were a medical clinic you
were the only source of revenue for lp
and when rep came out they all ran and
unfortunately we saw that access to
medicine became extremely limited the
resources we had to be able to help
patients became extremely limited and
everybody went straight right and
unfortunately a lot of those lp's that
went recreational stop even paying us
i have absurd amounts of
accounts receivables from lps that just
said we're not supporting medical
anymore
and these are very very
critical elements that have crushed very
good companies with very good people
that were driving them and their
elements
that will come out of germany does not
do this right
it can actually destroy an industry's
morale it can actually destroy
the real core purpose and economics of
this industry as well and i've seen it
destroy a lot of people in the country
uh in canada we survived this some way
somehow i had a full head of hair at one
point it wasn't that long ago
sorry lisa can i just ask that the other
thing that happens
when you see these players go rush into
the rack and pull out a medical
is your research funding dress up
so
i can't tell you how many
requests we get for supporting research
in canada right now because our friendly
competitors
have all pulled out because they're so
much focused on the recreational market
so we've got patients who have
challenges with access we have patients
who can't afford their medicine because
we have excise tests and that we have
research that is not getting kind of
funding that we should we should have
and we had at the beginning of this
so i think it's not just yes we need to
make sure the patients have what they
need but if we talk about this industry
around the world the regulators are
asking for real world data you cannot
get real world data if people are not
investing in the science
and so again that's part of protecting
your medical cannabis industry while you
bring up a wreck industry again i'm
biased i don't do rack
power to you i think you know it has a
place but shouldn't that be true also
for example for if you say cannabis has
certain effects shouldn't you also be
able to provide some data that really
absolutely and that can happen if you
don't do the research
all right
dave i wanted to ask you a question
about compassionate use and patient
collaborators and those kind of things
do you have those kind of things in
california can we talk a little bit well
california has for the most part since
2018 really the
adult use market aka recreational has
really taken off
and
in the eyes of most of the public has
more or less replaced
medical
we don't have separate
dispensaries or separate medical
pharmacies
um a medical patient with a medical
recommendation
because in california
a doctor can give a recommendation it's
not a full it's not a formal
prescription fulfilled at a pharmacy
it's a recommendation that
law enforcement recognizes
um
so if you have a recommendation you can
go into a adult use recreational store
buy
a wide variety of products deliverable
in many different formats from
flour and pre-rolls to gummies beverages
to chocolate
and many other things in between
and
the main
difference for the medical patient with
the recommendation is
while they're gonna pay they will pay
the same state sales tax that any
californian for example will pay on any
product
food
electronics they're going to pay the
same state sales tax they won't pay the
excise tax the extra special excise tax
so the medical patient gets that
break if you want to call it that and
then the medical patient can also still
grow
at home
there are you know you can grow
six eight ten plants uh
and even get together with a few friends
uh who are also medical patients
there's an opportunity there that um
has not been
i don't think it's been
mentioned or utilized as much as it
will be
in the years to come as the adult use
market continues to struggle with the
illicit market over taxation and over
regulation
well like this part is particularly
interesting because we have of course
patients who do not have access yet who
are still illegally growing and who get
ready by the police and these things are
happening in reality
like it's crazy but in the end it's also
about access and here's this discussion
going on the patients are not able to
cultivate the cannabis so it can be a
medicine what's your stance on it
that's going to change
i mean that's fine and simple
that that's going to change
yeah and you know on that note it's
funny uh i gotta say there's just it's
so repetitive and deja vu like it feels
like such a flashback of 2013 and canada
all the same things that i hear complain
about here is the same thing we complain
about oh we can't let people grow we let
them grow
we're not going to have an industry it's
like what the hell are you talking about
we've been we've had people growing look
i grow in my house i still buy plenty
don't worry uh you know
your industry is safe from people
growing their own do not worry about
that
perfect example is how many people have
a vegetable garden in their backyard and
still buy fresh fruit and vegetables
everybody has a great point like every
point
i've been in mmar since 2010
i first started with a 50 plant limit
like that's that's even far more than
enough medicine that i could maybe
and it's just for playing names how do
you grow still still purchasing from
stores
of course like everybody it's
there's so many
exact carbon copies that are happening
right here and we're hearing the same
fear stories
that led canada down a very
very odd path
and we're seeing it all being planted
here right now and that's really
important that alex said people think if
you're going to grow your own cannabis
it's like well if they can grow tomatoes
like like all these greenhouses are
going to be toast nobody's going to buy
any tomatoes the tomato industry's going
to be dead like i grow tomatoes in my
backyard every year i buy a shitload of
tomatoes
and just quickly sorry before we go on
the key thing also i want to express is
from processing it's about finished
goods the actual growing the actual bud
is not where it's at and i know
everyone's setting up and raising
millions and we did that in canada too
we had words like uh funded capacity and
uh cut canopy size and just silly stuff
like that don't get fooled by that it
doesn't matter how much cannabis you can
grow it's what you can do with it so i
can grow my own cannabis but can i
extract my own oil no i don't think i
have a million dollar extractor that can
do the oil extraction or can i make my
own edibles oh yeah sure i could make a
chocolate but can i make ten thousand
and a million chocolates like these this
is where the money is in this industry
not on the growing so anyways uh just
quick little rant on that apologies
no it's good i hope you all carefully
listen
um
so uh diane you mentioned before that
patient act about negative negatively
impacted by the introduction of
canada's recreational market um
what uh what happened there and how long
did it take to work itself back out
it hasn't worked out
if germany doesn't look real hard at
what happened in canada and california
but you know i think at the end of the
day
this is something i said last month
sorry boys you're hearing me again but i
said last month in canada is that we
need to ensure we have almost two
divergent industries here i'm not saying
there's some degree of
similarity particularly when you're
looking at quality i don't care if your
consumer ingesting this or your patient
you still have to have a significantly
high bar when it comes to to quality um
you know again i have extreme medical
bias so you know we don't believe that
smoking is the best way to take one's
medicine
so
you know we
look at best-in-class technology like
nano-emulsification i think when you're
truly putting your patient first
that
is a different discussion than when
you're creating
a consumer product for consumer
enjoyment right when you have people
like we do who are compromising
compromised immune systems they could be
out there with their life that's what's
at the heart of our products so the
things that the panel before we're
talking about eugmp quality standards
gacp these are all extremely expensive
um endeavors to to get to and one of the
things to get back to canada we also saw
i think that um that guys would agree
with me
is when we had the rush for wreck we
also had significant downward pressure
on the economics because we had so much
product in the
in the industry that was shifting into
the wreck industries do not have
patients who can't access medicine but
we have a massive black product which is
pushing pressure on the economics and
what suffered was quality
right and so now you've got consumers
and patients who are suffering from
quality and so again it's it's just
another flag that we would send to
germany and for me personally why i say
you need to
look at these industries in relation to
who the end user is and a patient is a
different end user to steve's point
than somebody who wants to
you know have a joint on their death on
a saturday night with a nice glass of
wine right it's a completely different
situation just one thing to add to that
you know
why does equality suffer it's around
economics this is another lesson to be
learned
once you let no offense to any business
people i mean we're at a business
conference so
can't be saying anything negative of
business people of course but
when it becomes about the dollars and
cents much more than the patients and
money is raised you start to figure on
wait a minute how do we save money how
do we cut corners and that's when
quality really starts to suffer
there's very few high quality growers
it's very expensive to grow at high
quality but there's a sure a lot of low
and medium quality growers trying to
bring their costs down and i think
that's a lesson to be learned also is
you know cannabis is not very expensive
to grow
you know we talk about it being very
expensive but the actual cost of growing
cannabis it can even be done really high
quality for not that expensive but then
you know when you talk about taxes it
was funny earlier this uh talk here with
all the government officials uh they're
all taxes are all just waiting like
salivating waiting on the tax dollars
same thing happened in canada you know
right now every dollar that's sold 50
cents of it is going into taxes in
canada like that's disgusting
if i i can add 71 cents and this is an
actual real data 71 cents out of every
single dollar um for the retail brick
and mortar is to the government we're
scrambling over 29 cents
right absolutely and so
you talk about low quality so you know
the economics it could be really well
that once too many people get their
hands in and you know greedy people want
to make a lot of money on it with low
expenses and the government sees how
much money is being made and before you
know it
that's why we get into this problem
you wanted to add something no i could
just say the other thing um again
bringing my
my focus is
you know when we're looking at what's
coming in addition to the growth
standards the other thing to look at is
you know what is going on your plants
and what if you're growing in ground
what can leach into your plants
not that that is an important consumer
it is but as a medical patient
you know if you're going through
chemotherapy
and you're
taking something that also has heavy
metals in it never mind people have
blown any pesticides on it but the heavy
metals from something down a road has
leached into you that that is a very
dangerous situation for a
we've been talking a lot about
differences between the industry maybe
we can talk a little bit what is similar
between the two parts and what can we
learn from the existing medical part for
the recreational market
i'm gonna go first therefore alex or
nation
well let's see um
[Music]
i i think you know the the uh
one of the things that we observed as i
mentioned earlier in
in the california experience is that
the
delivery
system
if you will pretty much
got emerged uh
so that as far as
where to go to buy
your medicine or buy your
used product there's one place instead
of a pharmacy for
uh your medicine and the the the
canvas store for your adult use product
it's pretty much one retail store so you
you're going to want to decide here
in germany and in europe is that a model
you want to follow or do you want to try
to divide it up because as we talked
about there's really
two different two different products
here
uh and there's a very very important
decision to be made
sooner rather than later
and
i'm not saying
that the
the california or the u.s model for that
matter which is pretty similar in most
of the states
is the best model
um
but
it
it has
been working to the extent that for the
consumer
patient or adult use
[Music]
there are if you haven't been to
california please come to california for
many reasons but if for nothing else to
tour
our
you might want to come visit one of our
canvas stores
some of them you feel like you're
walking into an apple store
you know with all the sales people the
bud tenders all wearing the same
you know introduce themselves and get
your name and what are you there for and
they will
show you around a wide variety of
products now
as we talked about there's some care
that needs to be taken about where
you're getting your advice if you're
there for a medical product do you want
to have
um
you know some uh
some person maybe who has
been
in the business for
six months or two years giving you your
advice on what you should be taking for
your
neuralgia your
your aches your pains
your stomach problems probably not
but it's an interesting model
and
as a consumer it's
fascinating
so
um
i recommend
and for any journalists in the audience
if you haven't written an article yet
about the 50 things that the
50 states or the 47 states in the united
states and canada have done right and
done wrong i i encourage you to write
that article
um because there's a lot of data to
learn from yeah
on that it looks like one mistake that i
hope uh germany does not make so you go
to vegas and you go to like this one
place planet 13 which is
just it's so ridiculous and maybe that
works in vegas but you know if anyone
out there is looking to buy a retail
store
most people want to buy their cannabis
and get that effect
so before you start spending all this
money on all these fancy stores and all
this experience inside your store most
people are not going to care and you're
not going to realize that until your
store is open and you're just watching
people not even look at your fancy walls
you spend thousands of dollars on and
they're just being like looking at you
and they're leaving yeah see who knows
about that
but just to talk about some of the
positive things i know we've maybe been
a little negative up here uh but
somebody wanted to say something
no no but we want to be positive like
one thing that is very very important is
around education we came here to icbc
six years ago talking about the
importance of education here we are six
years later still talking about the
importance of education so i hope
germany really gets that right is around
the education side of it and something
that me and were talking about backstage
is around the importance of research
you want medical to really be separated
you really need to focus on the research
there's a lot of different modes of use
now uh you know in canada's defense we
started this with only bud everything
else was illegal you could have gone to
jail for making oil that's how we
started 2013. it's observed
germany has a chance to be so much
better because we know so much better
there's a bit more research done more
needs to do invest in the research don't
just put those money in the pockets of
your shareholders put it back into
cannabis research so that's it
if i may i'll keep this short and sweet
please
see the value in people that are
actually operating
entities now
we have been doing this everybody that i
have seen that was in 16 countries a
year before coveted speaking at many
different places working with many
different governments around the world
and
some countries are actually paying
attention to people that are actually
doing it saying you can do it having a
vision having a sales that having the
best team in the world all that's great
it's super great talk to people that are
actually doing it it's a lot different
when you actually do it
and the value and the little tips and
tricks
that you can get from people that are
actually doing it please do not
underestimate it
five minutes with somebody like alex
somebody like myself when you're talking
about each different specific thing when
you're talking about
all of these different specialties that
we all have i'm telling you five minutes
of time with us can literally say that
be the difference between
a profitable
long-term business and completely
getting crushed we have watched some of
the best teams that raised the most
money get absolutely slaughtered we
bootstrapped this ourselves and started
taking actual seed funding after we were
generating remedy
we
really eat what we cook and we learned
the hard way and we learned the right
way in my opinion and i beg for germany
to do that too
i've
seen the exact same things happening
here and the exact same
overconfidence thinking we know exactly
what we want if i walk into a store i
know what i want if i'm going to grow
cannabis and own a production site i
know exactly how to do it i'm telling
you though
i'm sorry
you don't
and we have and this information is
vital it will save you millions of
dollars
and a lot of us have this experience to
be able to help we are people that
genuinely get more joy out of sharing
this knowledge to be able to help people
knowing that this is a product that has
saved lives i know this firsthand i have
helped more hands on people crying
saying that i have saved their lives
than in any other industry in my entire
life this is a special industry with
special people but it is also a very
special industry with some very terrible
people that will absolutely crush you if
you are not guarded or following the
rules
please i beg talk to people that know it
talk to the people that are actually
doing it that have real revenue real
experience they will help a lot and most
of those people that are successful
doing it want to help
not take advantage and i hope
[Music]
in a second but and they give you the
possibility to pose questions i just
wanted to ask the penalties for one last
piece of advice for the german
colleagues if you could each maybe like
this was pretty good to advise already
but maybe if the other three of you
could also add a little bit to that and
just give one piece of advice and then
we can open the floor to questions
mine would be uh from a medical
standpoint as product innovation
it has to be continuous you have to
continually be looking at
um how do you make sure your product
looks like medicine it looks like
something your child with epilepsy would
be comfortable to use or your
grandmother or grandfather would be
comfortable to use
and it just takes constant innovation
constant investment and if i could just
add one other thing
just something steve said do not rush to
the almighty public money
right we stay private
um for seven years at this it was
supposed to take four
uh so
you know
don't rush full of money because it gets
much much harder once you've taken that
money
it keeps you prudent if you're private
it really keeps you prudent with your
operations and your spending if you're a
profit profitable private company it
speaks absolute volumes look at what the
public companies have done
99 dropped in the last like three years
i'm looking at when we took our final
like our seat round like 3.5 million
um we were the number one peer-reviewed
store in ontario we did 14.7 million in
sales our first year and we stayed
private and i was looking at what
happened with he went public and what
people were doing these companies have
dropped
in three years
and then they just used their stock as
currency and drag everybody down with
them the amount of deals that i've been
offered that i wanted to take with paper
money and a few of them that i did take
i would i would have been holding eight
cents on the dollar
and i got strung out and nearly nearly
ridden into bankruptcy more than once
because of chasing
a big exit and don't make that mistake i
had a little bit of greed in my eyes and
i would never do that again i want to
see anybody else do it
well i um i'll try to make this quick i
i started out uh
working with canada's clients and in the
cannabis field as i mentioned earlier 12
years ago i've been a copyrighted
trademark intellectual property and
innovation lawyer for 40 years but i
started taking those skills into the
cannabis space about 12 years ago
because as we were starting to see
california move from
recreation
from uh
medicine medical to
adult use i started seeing that it was
inevitable that the investors and the
partners and the
wall street
finance companies were going to start
coming in to try to get into the
industry and
innovate
but they were going to want to know how
to collateralize
their investments and so
it was only a matter of time before
the companies that were moving from
medical to adult use we're going to
start asking
where are my copyrights where are my
trademarks where are my patents where
are my trade secrets so i encourage you
as you're making this transition if this
transition is inevitable which it looks
like it may be
to start thinking now learn everything
you can
about copyrights patents trademark
straight secrets because they're going
to help your industry stay ahead of your
competitors
um and it's
it also
encourages you to stay innovative
and
there's the four basic tools copyrights
patents trademarks trade secrets learn
learn learn figure out what's most going
to be most important to you and then how
to roll them out how to implement
those
those processes in your business in what
sequence that makes the most sense for
you for your budget and uh i'll close it
off i will open up the questions uh
further following on what steve was
saying is that
talk to people with experience
we didn't have that luxury we were
starting something that no one else has
done so it was very difficult walked
into a lot of brick walls in the dark
not realizing it but now you have people
who have done it
and not only who have done it make sure
when people tell you about what they've
done make sure they've actually done it
make sure they've actually executed on
what they said not just in theory uh you
know i'm here with my company luch
brands we've done things on a large
scale and don't get fooled by people who
say they can do something that haven't
done it when you're giving advice make
sure it's from people who have done it
and if they have done it then they can
help you and they can save you tons of
money and tons of headache and time so
that's my last advice and a lot of
stories not a lot of action all right
thank you everybody and we'll open the
floor okay it's all round of applause
give him a microphone
hello
nice to meet you my name is steve alex i
love you guys um i used to run the
biggest medical cannabis illegal
dispensary in canada before legalization
mmj canada
these problems that you guys are
speaking about now even after
legalization
are the problems that i was screaming
about at the top of my lungs about
research and development lack of support
from the government
we're all going through the same thing
now that we're legalizing i'm going to
be opening uh another multiple
medical cannabis chains in the next few
months licensed
we all know that the government's
corrupt they're not going to take care
of patients the way they should be
we know that there is no support for the
patient
so instead of being upset about it
constantly
what are we going to do as a group diane
steve alex myself what are we to do
differently to protect the patients
because we have to be a lot more
creative
than any other person in the industry
because of the lack of resources that we
have even with
proven research which is being denied by
the recreational market
for financials
because they want to keep the profits
going instead of taking care of the
patients so my question truly is
how do we work together and how do we
fix this moving forward i love it i can
answer that very shortly
[Music]
um hats off to you as well uh no matter
what i've always took my hat to this
gentleman that we're from the same area
and he was kind of like the the king of
the uh illegal cannabis and i was the
i i can't even teach that word for
myself
but i i was the guy for the the legal
medical side and people thought it was
like
we were
arch nemesis but it was very much very
very very different than that um so what
what can we do differently
um i candidly i'm not going to publicly
disclose what we're doing to be able to
bypass what the government is taking out
of our pockets that literally makes it
financially impossible for us to have
longevity i'd be happy to talk to people
individually about that i'm dead serious
it works and it's a plan we're doing it
clint's on the same page as well
but the second part is helping other
countries to not make the same damn
mistakes man
because we're passing point and overturn
in many areas in canada
and i'm a chartered investment manager
i've worked on bay street for 14 years i
own my own investment firm as well
i know i know finance and i know
cannabis and i know business i know
those three things exceptionally well
and i'll stand toe-to-toe with anybody
and help and want to learn more myself
but the only way that we are going to be
able to change this is if we're able to
help other countries because canada in
many cases is beyond the point of no
return unless you are able to
really put a creative hat on and uh
unfortunately i'm not going to publicly
disclose that i'm here
can i add something for that for germany
we have the advantage here that we have
an industry association that is
representing the entire industry and
that we are working across sections and
it's not only affecting something that
is for cannabis still the hemp is in a
horrible situation and we need to do
definitely some changes there and get it
out of narcotics laws and just not only
think about the recreational part but
this is the important thing so if you're
here in germany you want to make a
difference please come and trust me
afterwards and see how we can all
collaborate and create this industry
okay we can do
[Music]
[Applause]
because actually this morning we heard
from three representatives from a
coalition of government here who were
saying in my mind all the right things
things that we haven't heard in canada
we didn't have a government saying that
they support access to medical cannabis
there should actually be more insurance
coverage these are the things i was
hearing this morning so i was interested
if there's a consolidated plan coming
from the industry association of how to
protect medical cannabis
post-legalization
and
whether uh in canada if we had that
opportunity from some of the experts
here if we can crush our cynicism for a
minute and think about what uh we might
have said to health canada if we had
their ear
like you may have here so can i answer
that because i had two i had two very
specific friends with health canada the
last time i met them which i'm going to
raise my hand and tell you it was
pre-coded first and foremost um i don't
believe the economics or long-term
health of a medical product
uh
north of the equator are going to work
and so in a country like canada where
you were borrowing imports
and so you're denying your patients
access to affordable medical cannabis
products that okay they weren't from or
produced in canada but if they meet the
same standards if they are held to the
same obligations as canadian licensed
producers then that medicine should be
allowed to your patient so that's number
one and number two
um i argue with them about excess tax
because we are
taxing medical cannabis the same way we
tax alcohol in canada today at very
minimum i said if you're going to do
that you should be taking that money and
reinvesting it into the research in this
country so that we can again ensure that
our patients are getting the benefit of
the funds that are flowing through this
industry
that's really interesting fantastic i'm
trying to cut
thank you so very much
[Music]