what happens when a movement becomes an
industry
most importantly what happens when that
industry happens
in a fragmented way globally
and there's no uniformity how do people
create Commerce
well that's what most people in this
room and most people in this industry
are figuring out on a regular basis and
that's the exciting thing that I get to
talk about here so
as I mentioned I'm a lawyer most people
don't want to hear from a lawyer unless
you have to but I'm here to try to give
you some context
why does an american-based lawyer matter
in Berlin Germany
I've seen a lot in 13 years in this
industry and I can tell you and what
you're going to hear next from Bo
Whitney
is that there are repeatable patterns
there are demonstrable Trends those
patterns happen over and over again all
around the world
they do the exact same pattern
what changes is the timeline of these
those changes coming into play
that timeline is often dictated by the
population of the jurisdiction
so it's that patterns those patterns
have timelines that I'm trying to talk
about this afternoon if you have a
question please raise your hand if I can
work it in I will I want to make sure
that this is as informative as possible
at least Clark kills Global cannabis
division a couple of my partners are
here with me Sanders exevski from Los
Angeles he takes companies public he's
an SCC lawyer right now those companies
here that are operating lawfully in
whatever jurisdiction you're in
there's access to public markets to
Capital markets in the U.S today you
don't have to wait
secondly with my partner Sam out of our
Dublin office and I'd encourage you to
take a close look at your operating
globally
and incorporating your company
registering it in Ireland
there's a number of reasons for that
that I won't get into but if you couple
those two things together
you're situated properly you have low
taxation rates you have protection
from insolvency which you don't get in
the United States
and more importantly you have access to
Capital or more access to Capital than
most companies in the space but when I
talk about the global supply chain
why does that matter for you folks
working so hard here in Germany to get a
license
to get a store to hire people that are
competent and qualified
how do you do that why does this matter
to you well here's why it matters
because this is a global industry you
don't see it today but the supply chain
is global you don't see it on a mass
scale but you will
commoditization is coming it's not here
yet it's not really that close yet
you know what commoditization is what's
a commodity
what's a commodity
commodity is something that occurs
when you buy or trade it before it
exists before that seed goes in the
ground it's sold that hasn't happened in
cannabis yet it's not likely to happen
even in a specific geographic location
why
because the supply chain needs to sort
itself out it needs to course correct
multiple times
so let's talk about some of those
changes that form the backdrop
the UN convention on narcotic drugs
raise your hand if you've heard of the
U.N convention on the kind of drugs it's
certainly a place that we need to start
in November of 2020
the U.N convention the committee on
narcotic drugs recommended changes they
recommended the recognition of medicinal
cannabis
as something new to be treated
separately and differently from the
prohibition of cannabis
number two
they recognize that cannabinoids from
Industrial Hemp or industrial usage such
as CBD
are not subject to U.N controls
but yet we have not had any mechanisms
no distribution of these Concepts
to the member nations because it's
challenging it's time consuming it's
complicated
so that forms the backdrop for what is
going to happen however
we are not waiting for the United
Nations when I say we I mean operators
within the industry our clients no one's
waiting for the United Nations in fact
look at a country like Uruguay our
friends more acquire out on the floor
one of the first the first country in
the world to outright legalize cannabis
now it's a small country four million
people plus or minus
but it has a big impact
because they're participating as one of
the first Nations along with Canada now
Colombia Israel
for the exploitation of catalysts the
Netherlands so forth and so on but
they're small trade why is there small
trade right now
because the Distribution Systems are not
built
for commoditization they're built for a
tightly knit
closed loop system where every single
gram is tracked very strictly why
because there's a stigma to cannabis
have you heard about this stigma
Stoner mentality
Etc that exists and that what is what we
have to deal with
moving slowly giving policy makers
elected officials comfort that operators
in the industry are actually doing
things the right way they're doing
things in a way that's strictly
compliant
in turn
that makes people regular people mothers
fathers
okay if not accepting
of the Cannabis industry
so the U.N convention has allowed to
a lot but countries are not waiting for
the U.N convention to be modified
look at what's Happening Here do you
simply opt out do you wave it or you
make an argument
that we need to
go against the tenants of the um
convention regarding cannabis
for purposes of Public Health
and Public Safety National Security
that's what Uruguay looked at looked at
it very closely and we've seen very
little repercussions for that so it's
happening quickly but the U.N convention
is an impediment it's a blocker to the
establishment of a code
cannabis supply chain
now
in the U.S we may gain major distinction
between hemp and marijuana that
distinction in the U.S is point three
percent THC of course THC the
psychoactive compound
it's relevant but a lot less relevant
that distinction in most countries
around the world and I would suggest to
you here today that you don't really
need marijuana
for the global supply chain
you really just need cannons
hemp is cannabis too
you can grow hemp
for six hundred dollars per acre in the
U.S
you can grow a thousand acres
you can capture a thousand acres and 10
metric tons per acre
at point three percent THC
there's plenty of THC you can convert
the other compounds to THC
you can isolate those compounds in a
formulation and a process that is in
fact
a pharmaceutical ingredient standard
right
but that's a different industry than
what we're talking about mostly today
that's the evolution of the global
cannabis
supply chain
shipping cannabinoids compounds and
formulations
formulations being the key around the
world for a variety of purposes do those
formulations make their way into a
dispensary in Los Angeles California
do they make their way into a pharmacy
in Montego Oregon
do they make their way into a dispensary
that's adult use in Berlin Germany
it's a different industry and it's those
segments of the industry that I would
urge you to challenge yourself
just because you have a supply chain
because you have production extraction
manufacturing packaging and resale
retail capabilities does not mean you're
participating in the same industry that
exists for every person that invests in
the industry
there are different sectors and segments
now the THC percentage is important
because if I want to buy a flower I want
the THC percentage High
I want the oil extracted from that that
distally I want that THC percentage high
but is that the same ingredient is it
the same standard if I'm going to create
a formulation that's designed to treat
pure address a specific condition in the
human body
they're different I don't think they
cross in the future so please understand
that that there are different segments
in the industry I'll talk about that
from a policy perspective
look at this this map look at the
turquoise color the bluish color that
represents regions of the world and it's
not complete there are some new regions
of the world that need to be added on
there
but look at that man who'd have thought
about this I've been working
specifically in this industry only in
this industry for 13 years now
13 years of commercial practice working
on transactions regulations
Etc this map gets Bluer every single
year so congratulations to all of us and
the policy makers that make it happen
so let's look at some of the pieces here
of course what happens in Germany is
spread across Europe in many ways that
tends to be the pattern for other policy
developments particularly controversial
policy developments when the German
government takes it on regulates it does
it well it will take hold in many
locations around the globe there was a
meeting recently
and that was in Luxembourg with German
and several other nearby Nations where
they talked specifically about the
tenants for the program with Malta
involved Malta being the first European
Countryman of course to legalize
cannabis but it's a small small country
actually I think Luxembourg was first
but not for a commercial dispensation
scheme my whole point is there's
movement happening with small but
powerful and important countries
understanding how these countries fit
together
but Mr Holman I'm just trying to open a
dispensary
in Berlin Germany why does this matter
to me
it matters to you because it will be
allowed to be traded commercially many
countries around the world develop the
program particularly the Latin American
countries
that program allows for exportation only
there's an imbalance from the very
beginning
if you don't have exportation balance
with domestic use it's not much of an
economy we're seeing the Latin American
nations change their laws change their
policies in real time very rapidly to
address that fact
but that's what has to happen when you
look at European countries we are
imported
into just about every country with some
new exceptions in Germany and Beyond
that's not necessarily sustainable so
where does the Cannabis come from if
there's new cultivation coming online
and
let's face it does it make sense to ship
cannabis no matter how high quality it
is does it make sense to ship it
from Colombia for example all the way
to the European Union to Europe
I don't think the cost of transportation
and the cost of production would support
that in the long term particularly when
you have multiple African nations
producing cannabis for exportation and
domestic Supply pardon me International
Supply so those are some of the things
that we're seeing
in the Western Hemisphere I believe that
this will be its own supply chain when
you look at the United States as the
outlier where we have the Holy Grail so
to speak of consumers but those
consumers are limited to the states and
limited by the fact that they operate on
the marijuana side in the face of
federal illegality
yet our neighbors to the north and by
Supreme Court mandate our neighbors to
the south of Mexico and multiple
countries across the entire region have
an exportation policy which they'll soon
balance with a domestic policy
this is its own supply chain
it doesn't seem that way today
but it will be it's important to
understand that understand the economics
in the Western Hemisphere
so
when you import or export the questions
becomes and I think somebody asked a
question on the wolva app don't we need
standardization globally don't we need
important and Export uniformity
if you want your prices to go down the
answer is yes
uniformity and consistency does what
it allows more people to participate
if you allow more people to participate
what happens with the law of supply and
demand what cannabis is produced if more
cannabis pins produced and the standards
are easy to understand and navigate
is your price point higher
or is it low
typically it's going to be lower
substantially lower so not having
uniformity globally supply chain
perspective is actually not an adverse
condition
it's an asset if you can figure it out
and there are people there's many people
at this conference and in this room that
know how to navigate that complex Global
Marketplace
to navigate the lack of uniformity
and that's an important piece
when you have distinctions between hemp
and cannabis CBD and THC CBD we're
seeing the the marketplace explode for
the last 24 plus months here in Europe
we see the products particularly in line
of the novel Foods rolling in some of
the inconsistencies there but does it
really only matter that I'm producing
something from a cannabis plant and the
country or the jurisdiction in which
that plant was produced
allows it licenses it and and
facilitates the exportation
and the recipient country
you need to have the same thing they
need to be able to possess material that
meets their standard they need to be
able to import it into the hands of a
licensed producer or participant and
they need to have a structure behind it
for the dispensation of that material
those things exist mostly
and there's a part to navigating it
right now that if you can navigate it
now now is the time to go out and build
that infrastructure as the price points
will be much higher
we look at the limited movement of
infused cannabinoid products
oil moves right we see oil move around
the world we see flowers move around the
world both hemp and marijuana flowers
but what we don't necessarily say
s are cannabinoid finished products
because in jurisdiction by jurisdiction
the types of ways to consume cannabis
it's regulated different
it's regulated so differently that you
can't import an edible in most
jurisdictions but maybe you can import
the oil and produce the edible in that
jurisdiction or the consumable
so the regulations are your friends not
your fault understanding that
understanding that intellectual property
matters
the brands matter in cannabis today what
do you think yes or no
Brand's math but it depends where
we saw the Willie Nelson
Snoop Dogg Brands come out in the United
States
there's not a lot of loyal following for
those products
we see brands that people buy brands or
they simply buy consistency
isn't that brand new
Snoop Dogg product doesn't sell but the
consistent product cells
these are important things to understand
but also to protect
protect from an intellectual property
standpoint
most recently in Mexico City
Mexico City
there are dispensaries the dispensaries
are not legal but they operate they look
they feel they smell
like a dispensary that you walk into in
Southern California
and guess what
all of the products in that dispensary
are branded like California products
so the question becomes which I didn't
ask
it's driving here from California or
didn't you simply print it on the
packaging it's a little bit of both but
my point to you is protect your brand
protect your intellectual property today
the protection exists in multiple
jurisdictions that multiple
jurisdictional registration can protect
you
it can be enforceable
despite the Cannabis nature of the
industry
and that's an important thing to protect
because if you're not protecting that or
are you taking steps to develop your
brand beyond the boundaries of your
country for example
if I have a solution here in Germany and
I have a THC brand
but I want to go to the next country the
one that I predict is going to be next
what if I did a soft launch without the
problem I created CBD products with the
same branding and same packaging in a
jurisdiction that was lawful but didn't
allow THC products that model has worked
all over the United States marijuana
brands in the U.S have gone into new
jurisdictions that allow for CBD from
industrial hemp and created the brand
awareness and brand recognition before
the market allowed for THC products to
be sold in that market
industrial HEPA applications we're not
here to talk about him but that's very
exciting and as I mentioned cannabinoids
from hemp can be aggregated all over the
course of thousands of hectares or Acres
and when you have cannabinoids guess
what
cannabinoids are cannabinoids
it doesn't matter whether I get my
cannabinoids from marijuana or hemp
the concentration in the individual
plantable matter but that's dictated by
what the consumers want
we're seeing major exporters we talk
about Colombia recently changing the law
which by the way
for those of you non-legal Minds in the
room there's legislation
and there's regulations legislation
requires elected officials to vote on
something typically the top executive
would sign that law into effect
but the regulations the regulations the
details how something is done
that's left to agencies
agencies can change rules very quickly
it doesn't require voting of a
legislature does it require political
capital
regulations can change very quickly and
that's exactly
what happened in Colombia recently when
they were only allowing exportation of
oil and they have shifted the policy to
also allow for the exportation of flower
why because they recognize a global
market need for flour
the country was producing flour The
Operators were not doing so well because
they didn't have the capital to build
out their own extraction facilities and
they changed the rates they changed the
law and that allowed for exploitation
uh China is the largest cultivator of
hemp in the world if you didn't know
that I was in China advising the Chinese
FDA in 2016. in 2016 they told me there
was no THC in that country
we did a test on one of their head
clients a 14-foot hemp plan two months
prior to harvest
it didn't flower like a traditional
marijuana plant but it was 13 THC
so they use it for industrial uses so it
does I guess it didn't matter at the
time my point to you is that countries
look at things very differently you know
that I may be stating the obvious but
it's for you to figure it out and create
that as an asset for your business or
your opportunity
Israel has an insatiable demand for
product right now uh the United States
from a Industrial Hemp perspective
Germany of course
um Australia for medicinal purposes very
strictly and Brazil I think Brazil
changes the global landscape immediately
210 plus million people
with a nationalized Health Care system
that on their own
adopted the use of medicinal cannabis
with a nationalized healthcare system if
I didn't mention that already and Visa
it is a market to watch closely does it
mean that Europeans will be shipping
products to
Brazil no but what it does mean is that
the other Latin American nations will
and that will open up opportunities in
the in Europe and in this region of the
world that is now being satisfied from
Latin American exports
follow these Trends watch those trends
I want you to really take away the four
elements
of the Global Campus supply chain when I
talk about these four elements I talk
about them as four policy Lanes okay the
first one please think about these
because you need to place your company
in one of these four lanes if you don't
or if you're an investor and you haven't
figured out which lane you play in
you're going to lose your dollars if
you're an operator and you don't know
which lane you plan the business is not
going to succeed we've seen it for 13
years the first lady
OTC dispensary model
this means that I walk into a store and
I could purchase high THC flour
I can purchase a number of other high
THC products over the counter what
qualifies me to buy that maybe I'm a
patient with a specific condition
maybe I'm just 21 years old if it's an
adult use Market
that's over-the-counter marijuana do you
plan that lane what are you playing
you're going to jump down to the to the
second one after pharmaceutical
ingredients this is medical marijuana
folks API grade ingredients
that's medicine
those will be formulations approved by
the equivalent of the FDA
in every jurisdiction
it will be real medicine if I have a
condition I go to a doctor the doctor
will say it will take years to get there
but the doctor will say take this tablet
that may not be for some of us maybe any
of us in this room that understand the
benefits of the natural plant but will
exist and it does exist and we shouldn't
be scared of it we should not be scared
of pharmaceutical companies working in
this industry it's just another Lane
it exists side by side with the OTC
cannabis thirdly industrial I don't need
to go into that it speaks for itself
cellulose lignin sugar fuels plastic
building materials fiber
50 000 uses
wellness and nutraceuticals this is the
lane that would be non-intoxicating
cannabinoids primarily derived from
Industrial Hemp right so if I take CBD
out of a hemp plan if I take CBN out of
a hemp plan and I create those
formulations
those are over-the-counter nutraceutical
or wellness products they're rich in
proteins
Omega-3s omega-6s and they contain
cannabinoids it's a different Lane
so please understand where you fit the
biggest thing I can encourage all of you
to do in this room is understand your
context this is a fragmented
decentralized industry please understand
your context what you are where you fit
or else you won't succeed and I want you
all to succeed we all do
the versatility of cannabis
all right let's talk about this for a
moment this is not what you came here to
talk about but fiber is making a major
push
this fiber from a marijuana crop have
any value not really you want long
fibers that's the added value for
industrial hemp
you want long fibers and those fibers
are being developed in terms of
infrastructure for so many uses from
textiles of door paneling and
Automobiles
the Plastics and whatnot
wellness and nutraceuticals speaks for
itself you see those main uses of
cannabis to the right and ultimately
those things are all happening so will
somebody come and buy your stocks in
your stem and your waste material from
you not just for extracting that extra
one percent THC out of it but for
industrial uses maybe maybe in the
future
but Industrial Hemp is designed to do
all of the above including produced
cannabinoids in Mass
you guys know the products you've seen
the products out there you're familiar
with the products
this is an example of what the
marketplace looks like today
it looks like fiber products
over-the-counter medicinal or wellness
products vape pens apply these to hemp
and or marijuana
apply wafer board or fiberboard on the
end from Industrial
this is why this industry is not going
anywhere but it's also why you need to
understand the supply chain because it's
not just intoxicating materials from the
plant and by the way with more
uniformity with more people
participating
yeah intoxicating products out of the
industry doesn't get more valuable
either as I mentioned it gets less value
when you create more opportunities and
standardized
so understand the entirety of the plan
some product categories that are poised
for growth we see Cosmetics whether
those Cosmetics include
CBD for example or THC depending on the
different systems you see the Cosmetic
development going a while across Latin
America it's the first products that
we're seeing in many Latin
american-based stores lawfully or
otherwise
there's some of the first products that
we see going through marijuana
dispensaries with high THC for topical
application and of course products
across the United States and around the
world
pet products pet products we had a
Uruguayan fine of ours A Week Ago
getting a 15-year contract
15-year Supply contract for cannabinoids
including THC for pet products in
Southeast Asia these Agreements are real
they exist today
please understand that and don't get
caught up in everything in your world
because understanding to look up is very
important
important concept in the states recently
by the way
the DEA sent out a letter
in response to a lawyer's inquiry
that letter said there's really no
distinction between heaven and marijuana
in fact every seed is presumed then
until it's harvested because you can't
determine whether it's point three
percent THC until the time of harvest
legally
Well That Shook things up so all of
these European countries that have
produced hemp seeds marijuana seeds over
the years are rushing to the U.S market
but you'll see that distinction between
seeds as long as they're stable and
registered under various oecd or the
equivalent functions can be utilized
some of the investment Trends as we
bring this to an end where are the
dollars going uh Geographic source of
funds we see a lot more money outside of
the United States than coming from the
United States although as I mentioned if
you're locked on your jurisdiction
licensed appropriately public markets
and capital markets are available to you
in the U.S
uh what's the purpose for the funding
are you building out facilities are you
expanding are you hiring people where
are you going to spend your money
matters it matters to supply payment
matters and trends
domestic versus export that matters I
would suggest very strongly that if the
U.S passes the safe Banking Act or the
crime Act
that the international companies have a
much better chance
of operating in North America because
the U.S companies tend to exist and
survive sometimes in spite of themselves
because this stuff sells itself
whereas International companies have had
to go through many more Hoops operate
much more complex outbreak much more
sophisticated fashion those are things
that I would pay attention to
product verticals to avoid intoxicating
products from hemp
um we see that Delta eight
Delta 10 a number of these products much
aligned but something to consider high
THC products the products themselves are
not necessarily being shipped
internationally but the base materials
are the novel cannabinoids I touched on
that with intoxicating products
smokable
smokable head who thought that was
coming we see that as a trend in U.S
states that don't have lawful marijuana
people smoke out
produces a mild buzz but it's probably
not what the people are looking for
at the end of the day this number is
wrong
23.6 billion I saw an article this
morning
it said 75 billion dollars by 2030.
roughly half of that in the U.S North
America half of that International in
the aggregate that's what I think we're
looking at guys that's the opportunity
here and participate in that
International Aggregate and when the U.S
opens up access the capital for U.S
based companies the opportunity will be
yours because you'll have gone through
hoops that are much more stringent and
significant
okay
at the end of the day
the next presentation of the bow is
about market conditions I urge you to
listen and listen technically to that
because that will flesh out this broad
end of the funnel with some concrete
details and then right after that at 5
PM it's another conversation which would
be great about the global supply chain
look so marry these things together put
a few of these things in your bag of
tricks and please don't ever ever
hesitate to reach out to myself and my
partners anybody at Clark Kent
if you're looking to participate
globally please take a look at the gcnc
the global cannabis Network Collective
is an aggregation to network the top
players around the world and we're very
proud to have many of them here thank
you for your attention thanks for
everything
[Applause]