good afternoon everybody my name is
Lorenzo and I work for the European
Industrial Hemp Association and I'm very
happy and I see that we are super
excited to discuss about Fighters so
[Applause]
[Music]
um we will share the presentation with
me and my colleague Francesco some words
so I'm Singapore's advisor I covered
mostly by economy applications of hemp
so an agricultural environment it's also
super boring I'm really boring because
I'm covering the upper part of the
plants where we find the seeds in some
cannabinoids the leaves and the flower
so we are a great Association we are
sitting in Brussels you can see our
offices in the it's just beside European
Parliament European commission we are
doing advocacy and loving at the
European level as I said before we are a
small team I'm the managing director and
with Monica that she's in the room as
well we take care of the upper part of
the plants while Francesco and yeah as I
said we mostly work on agricultural
environment and bioeconomy application
with another colleague of mine so it's
half an hour so we focus on both aspects
of the plant
okay some numbers on our association
today we count nearly 240 regular
members which means companies we have 32
Nation with 32 associate members that
are individual that can join Aya to have
access to the information we are
building hopefully a little bit more
some Nation Association
we are doing that and then we have 12
membership Plus Membership plus tend to
be a consultant or
a Tax Advisor or lawyers that again they
can join us and participate in all the
activities that we are doing our biggest
target I would say is try to Advocate to
obtain a positive legislation around him
and all its derived products from
Another Side we build as well some
Network for allowed our member to create
hopefully some business opportunities as
well we cover mostly Europe and however
we are active for me a little bit too
much on National level but we are doing
that because the national level
unfortunately all over 27 member states
we cannot count today on strong National
Association therefore we go beyond our
mandates sometimes and we are active a
national level as well however when it
comes to International level the seats
is empty actually the seed was empty as
we have recently founded the Federation
of international hemp organization where
all the association coming from
different continents we have Australia
New Zealand China U.S and Canada We join
forces to be the voice of the sector
within the International Panel meaning
codex sedimentarius FAO and United
Nations where they do not love so much
yeah but we'll make quite good
progresses actually indeed next
so what we're talking about we're
talking about Cannabis sativa L we
should only speak about one species of
cannabis which is the Cannabis genius
instead of keep speaking about
sativa we believe that there is only one
Genius of cannabis and then we have
different scientists that evolution of
us so indeed and we follow so next
and how to define in industrial hemp of
course we usually use the the THC level
in the on in the on the field
uh which uh can be between it can be
between zero to zero three percent and
one percent because these are the
average values around the world to
distinguish hemp Industrial Hemp from uh
medicinal or adult use uh cannabis
um now just maybe like a question like
sort of a question our members cannot
reply yes so maybe even you a question
for you so who would you think that
who's defining the THC level that is
allowed in hemp in Europe do you believe
that it's European union or its member
State assignment can we make this little
survey you believe that these European
unions please raise your hands now
okay wonderful so all the others are the
others believe that it's National
actually it's a bit more complex on that
because we always hear about this zero
three percent zero two percent of the
European level but that is only the
threshold for the purpose of giving
direct payments to Farmers so maybe you
know that in Europe pharmacist they
receive money from the European Union
to produce whatever property or whatever
but of course industrial have to below
zero two percent and that will be zero
two percent so there is an established
THC level for these payments and many
members State basically copy pasted that
level and use it for the purpose of the
legality of the crop but infinite it is
the member state that decides what is
the maximum level of THC in the hand
plant and there are countries for
example a Czech Republic that adopted
one percent recently enters Italy uh it
went up to 0.6 percent so it's a sort of
a margin when it comes to controls on
the field but overall uh the 0.3 percent
will be the least it will be at least
0.3 percent from the first January 2023
Jesus was an advocacy
um battle it was it was a battle
actually because we have we had many
many people against increasing the
increase of the GHC level on the field
from zero two to zero three so it will
be industry from next year so again in
the end it is member state that decide
what is uh yes let's rate it because
it's so important and so many many
people have no idea so the zero three
percent is linked to direct payment what
does it mean it needs it if I am a
farmer wherever I am in Europe and I
decided to plant up to zero four if
there are no other
regulation on National level that
doesn't allowed me it simply means that
Brussels is not sending me the money
as a farmer not that I'm not allowed and
this is very important so the question
that we have asked to everybody is the
zero cream illegal or whatever it is a
legal limits yes or no the answer is no
it's just linked to direct payment but
then as Francisco explained each member
State can do a little bit whatever they
want and most of the time they misuse
these limits that again it's only for
direct payment the case will be 30 up to
zero six they adapt the case of Czech
Republic performance
and also this is more like our
definition of hemp what is industrial
hemp or what should be Industrial Hemp
so it should be cannabisity varieties
that are growing open field in a using
sustainable farming practices ideally
this is where in Europe we're moving
towards more sustainable farming and
where the whole plant is used you can
see here there's a seed in production
and a
hemp for for fiber whole plant approach
it is key for us because it makes sense
from a sustainability point of view from
economic point of view of course we have
to work a bit on the varieties on the
farming practices to make sure that we
can Harvest both seeds and fiber flowers
and fibers it will do a title you will
try to use as well so uh this if grown
this way is a highly sustainable crop
you all know the advantages of hemp for
the soil for the air for the bees and
for the bioeconomies a little bit
clearer please if you plant
hand into a greenhouse in pots this is
not so sustainable we believe that
industrial hand cultivated in this way
meaning double of triple use it really
becomes a sustainable plant so it is a
different sector I mean of course you
can I mean I'm sure we encourage those
who plant indoor to make sure that they
have a higher sustainability when it
comes to for example energy consumption
which seems to be the only things you
can play with so how much energy used in
your Greenhouse but of course we cannot
make the same claim for indoor grown
hemp cannabis whatever as we can for
outdoor ground cannabis
that point
so what are we observing now what are we
stand when it comes to hand products
Market here in Europe uh are we
experiencing a Renaissance of hand uh
well we believe that we are moving from
Zero to Hero uh we're maybe not there
yet but we'll we'll get there and please
do not underestimate the potential of
fiber and ships application because
and um is is looked at by big industrial
companies working in construction sector
in the textile sector not modern sector
and it is the best resource for
transition towards cleaner economies
because it's the only fiber crop that we
can grow everywhere in Europe from
Finland to Sicily
and it is also very high quality crop so
uh it is it is a great opportunity not
only for the medical purposes that have
been discussed until now at the
conference but also for bioeconomy
applications and of course a food
application does not forget seats and of
course the flowers for CBD products as
we said it's a highly sustainable crop
and it can also bring opportunities for
repatriating Value chains maybe for
those who come from from the Americas
are not uh acquainted with the
vocabulary that has been used by the
European institutions but they've
they've been speaking more and more
about getting back to Value chains all
the I mean the trade war between China
and U.S and then the Ukraine war and
then the covet we saw how fragile our
value chains are Global level and we are
we like European institutions and
National institutions institutions are
trying to rebuild those valuations here
in Europe and this is a great
opportunity for those who want to invest
in industry
let's
talk about feeding the food and feed as
well absolutely food and feed belongs to
the seeds so we can harvest the seeds on
top of the fibers as we have said before
why we are interested in in the seeds
because it's a it's a good protein it
contains a good protein contents it's
it's a plant-based alternative we know
that there are many people that are
switching their diets towards a more
plant-based diet so hemp could be on top
of all the others a good source of
alternative for meat it's a it's a trend
that is increasing dramatically we have
seen some figures during our conference
and it's a it's a booming sector that is
still for me untapped when it comes to
to hemp but the margin to grow are quite
are quite good it can be sold as well as
a food supplement and of course we are
not throwing away any parts of the
plants which makes one more time and
really a sustainable crop next please
when we talk about seeds The Operators
have a small issue which as well issue
that we saw the useful
we also absolutely and so when The
Operators are trading hemp seeds there
is only one thing that they have to
control is the THC limits in the seeds
meaning in the final product so still a
couple of not till the 1st of January
2023 in Europe there are no maximum
level of THC in the seeds which make the
operators became crazy because there is
different value or there is no value
because till today we only had the next
opinion by definition an opinion is not
a legally binding however my mistakes
were looking so closely to this opinion
coming from Elsa which is the sorry
European Food Safety Authority
so as I said to see now there was no
maximum level
Association advocate for many years and
finally convince the member state to
adopt the maximum level that is similar
from Poland to Lisbon and especially its
mandatory meaning that all member states
have to comply so you see in the slide
these are the limits let's explain a
little bit a little bit so the bad
mistake gave us three MGS per kilogram
for seeds and 7.5 for the oil
on top of that they allowed us like any
other protein or any other food they
allowed us to add an uncertainty factor
to make sure that the range is respected
so when do we count the maximum level we
should make a simple calculation the
maximum level plus the uncertainty
factor which brings us to the value that
you can see on the right side of the
screen so this value let's take the 10
the 11 PPM PPM is equal that milligram
per kilogram this is the same value of
Canada and us so we are quite happy we
are still have some limits that are
lower compared to Canada anyways when it
comes to seeds but so far we cannot
increase them more why because we do not
have any studies that show that we can
go beyond the irdf which stands for
acute reference dose for THC so this is
why we are conducting but we see that
later the biggest trial on human beings
on THC next please
these are some examples of products that
we can find today on the market that
derive from seeds as you see we do have
products we do have this product you can
find them in most of the supermarket in
in Europe and is a growing sector
definitely
it's the same
answer we have to talk about the fiber
are you alive so when it comes to the
flower and the leaves we would love to
sell them as food supplement members
they do not agree European Food Safety
Authority is needed so we have an issue
as you can see and what we do not like
and this make our members very angry and
I have to admit that I agree with them
is that member states are changing their
mind
in 1997 the European Industrial Hemp
Association had received not one two
letters from the European commission
saying guys go ahead it's not enough
food it's original food therefore our
members instead the money into her into
processing line to Market this product
as food supplement then comes 2016 there
is a booming on the market the members
they are getting nervous so they've
decided to change the so-called novel
food catalog which again is not
politically binding document by member
State because there is nothing on him
they tend to follow even a non-legally
binding dog what is another answer
food is a food that has not to be
consumed after a significant degrees
before 1997. we can discuss hours what
does it mean significant we will not
agree so imagine if I do agree with
member State on that so 2016 we
experienced the first change some of the
products are novel some of them are
still not novel Foods so the market is
still surviving quite well 2019 I joined
area 10 days after we got the change on
the catalog everything is now released
flour and extract again what does it
mean novel it means that you need a
pre-market authorization before
marketing this product again what does
it mean it's a very complex and very
costly process that allows you to obtain
a paper that makes authorities feel more
comfortable when they see your products
on the market
and then it happened 2020
we I would say that we never expect such
a change but in 2020 for a moment that
was hopefully very brief was brief
couple of months the European commission
and the member State thought that hemp
was an narcotic then they said that they
were joking so at the end of the 2020
they changed their mind and they
confirmed that all parts of the plants
can be considered a food novel but still
a food let's see what's going on
afterwards
this is our position the the position of
Our member the position of the
association guess what we do not agree
with member states so we do believe that
only isolate and enrich cannabinoids
should be considered as novel food while
low concentration or what we call the
naturally curing level of cannabinoids
should be should be traded like it was
before 2016 and before as a traditional
food
next
so what we are doing we have decided I
don't know why but we did it to do the
novel food application on the behalf of
our members so we have founded a
Consortium of companies we have
collected 3.5 million of euros and we
have launched southern food application
we have one for isolated CBD we have one
for synthetic CBD nobody no one of our
members care about synthetic CBD but you
remember hemp was an narcotics so only
synthetic was a viable solution for us
so we have filled in even the
application for synthetic but where we
care the most are the full spectrum
extract which are the more complex why
because they do contains THC so for
these three type of products we have
conducted and we are still conducting
another food application on the behalf
of our member next where we stand
these are the talks that we have been
doing two big
expenses nearly 2 million of Euros were
spent on the toxicity of isolating full
spectrum these are all the studies that
we have been performing so far and then
in parallel as I said before because
food Spectrum contains THC we decided to
invest 1.6 million of euros into the
biggest trial for THC on human beings
that will start in couple of weeks in
Portugal
so we'll see we'll get results next year
next year for both the THC the sorry the
isolate CBD is over so always submit the
application to us a very shortly the
full spectrum is still ongoing will be
done by the end of the year the trial on
human beings will be 2023
so we'll discuss about flower sheets and
let's get back to the fibers and the
ships for just a quick reminder it's
it's a bit different than harvesting
flowers and seeds there are specific
farming practices harvesting machines
and the very important part of hemp
processing for fiber is erecting which
can be performed in many different ways
according to the geographical area with
the program so you can do directing or
green writing writing on the field where
you have enough rain enough water or
humidity but you cannot do that for
example in Italy and then you need other
Technologies like ultrasound microbial
enzyme writing so in a controlled
environment possibly in water and then
of course you go you get the Bales and
you go to the blood pressure processing
site and there are two different way of
processing and fiber depending on what
you want to get if you want to get the
long fiber you can apply the same
Technologies actually it's a bit more
complex than this but I would make it
simple so if you want to get the long
fiber for textile applications
basically like flux you can use the same
sketching lines as for flux and we're
pretty good at that in Europe because we
produce 85 percent of the flex volumes
in the world and we have all discussion
facilities basically otherwise if you
want to work on technical fibers or
short fiber for cottonization for making
cotton-like
um Yarns or for insulation material
paper crate the fiber you go through a
decortication facility so those
countries who do don't do not have the
communication facility might have a hard
time or scratching blind hard time
investing in the in in the fiber market
so numbers how many qualifications we do
have in Europe we have around between 10
and 15 the corticators some of them they
are assembled but not active but we have
for example we have two in Germany I
believe
see see we have two in the Netherlands
five or six in France
and there are more elsewhere uh uh
whereas I understand that there are some
uh some Canadian and U.S nicoticas are
coming up but I'm not sure I don't know
where they stand
um the core product which is byproduct
whether of the fiber production is our
ships huge market for ships you kind of
give an image imagine imagine it's mulch
it's animal padding animal batting
Market explode in the past years because
everybody was getting like profits and
stuff at home
um but it's also very important yes many
companies are out of stock but also it's
it's a material used in construction
industry and you cannot imagine how many
construction companies some of them that
are also in the stock markets in Europe
are getting interested in hemp in
construction and are already producing
um amp-based construction material lines
well I don't have to repeat myself uh
especially by economy products are those
where the the carbon storage potential
of hemp is at the its best
um we have huge markets in perspective
and just to give you I I will not repeat
myself about reputation of value chains
but just to give you a few numbers of of
the huge Market side uh so the non-woven
uh
huge Market again it's a medical
applications absorbent papers hygiene
products it's 99 billion euros turnover
in 2019 only in Europe if we're talking
about natural fiber overall for any type
of application globally we have 60
billion of markets
synthetic fiber 147 billion and
Construction Products that is sorry
Euros not US Dollars 800 billion worth
Market only in Europe for Construction
Products so even if we had like 0.5 of
those Market I would I would believe
that would that will represent
great opportunities for
for companies so
um
just some some products uh in in the
different applications so this is
textile you've seen for sure Patagonia
costs so H9 group Nike
Etc
um construction product construction
materials I mean they're quite good we
have France UK that fight much Advance
there are nice companies also big ones
uh using hemp for installation or for
making hardwood
bricks NC to cast MK prefab walls uh
Romanian as well but we will have also
Italy there's any Italian company also
of a conventional company
so uh very good because they perform
very well in terms of quality they store
Carbon on very long term they have good
terminal cost acoustic performances
and on top of that we have Composites
and Plastics let's all forget that you
can also extract cellulose from him
you can use the fiber to reinforce
biomaterials more than in any shape you
you also have granulates and filaments
for 3D printing so basically you can do
whatever and either from the cellulose
or for the fiber you can mix the fiber
with the resins as I said and then so
yeah maybe the question would be
where to invest or rather how will be
the economy of the future
um I mean
all countries on geographical areas have
their own peculiarities I believe that
it's interesting to see what's going on
in the U.S and Canada but it's not the
EU we have a complete different path
different societies different
philosophies different political
institutions
and different objectives and in some
ways we're also opposite for example to
the American culture on some things
um I personally believe maybe we believe
in any cases Ayah that we have great
opportunities ahead for him especially
in the by economy for food for the food
market and so let's let's not forget
about industrial hemp and all its
applications so some take-home messages
as we said invest on sustainability on
outdoor hemp
investment processing facilities for the
fiber extraction because again huge
markets ahead uh use old core products
because there are markets for all of
them
but always aim at one application when
you grow and you grow and for one
purpose but then you valorize local
products and with the time today we have
around 82 varieties in Europe we've seen
many new ones in the past four or five
months there are few uh not eight as it
was arrived in a paper but okay there
will be more coming up so uh variety of
research will will develop further and
we will achieve like full whole plant
approach uh hopefully everywhere in
Europe but of course you have to take
into account that you have to aim at
something in particular and when it
comes to CBD Lawrence a few final words
um yes CBD as food supplement as I said
before it will be tough but this is the
product that we believe is much more
suitable for our Market the talk studies
are coming and science seems to be with
us so today is not the value to share
preliminary results this is something to
be discussed with our members
but it will it will support science will
be with us and hopefully the all the
application will be submitted to Absa
and then we will wait for their risk
assessment
there is one take-home message which is
join Aya join the association uh
participate in the working group neither
many neither Francesco we have no clue
about the technicity or all the the
peculiarity so we need your expertise
and then in this way the better informed
we are the much more efficient we will
be in front of the authorities without
you without your support we don't go so
far indeed thank you they pretend to
have a Saturday so now we're four right
so thank you
[Applause]
does anyone have a question
there's one right there hey bro
microphones coming to you one more time
for uh
Jessica
[Music]
hey thanks a lot for your presentation
today
um I actually have two questions
what was the argument against super 0.2
percent versus point three
um but that wasn't my main question
it with emphasis superfood
um is there an opportunity for grain
Farmers to ship to Africa to backfill
the loss of Supply from the Ukraine for
wheat and other grains I was just
wondering if there's an opportunity that
I taught a class in the University of
Nebraska on the economics of him and we
talked about this but the U.S isn't
ready I was just wondering if if the U.S
I take the second one oh can I if you
guys I will leave you to you to explain
the French situation so when it comes to
protein you're right there is an
imbalance in moment because we we cannot
count anymore on Ukraine at least for
this year so we need to rebalance again
there is a lack of protein around the
world and certainly hemp with other
Alternatives could Supply this Gap
Europe is not ready we have 50
000 actors where do you want me to go I
cannot even feel half of Malawi I mean
it's impossible so Europe is not ready
yet why we are not doubling the actors
because the regulation is locked so
there is no real wish from that farmer
today and then the farmers now the
prices are different after the Ukrainian
so they are thinking why should I invest
in plant hemp then the police can came
here and probably throw away half of my
of what I've been growing so and
everything is a little bit blocked today
so probably there is a much there is an
opportunity for U.S or Canada but
certainly we don't have enough to export
we need a little bit more also if I may
let's not make the mistakes that we made
in the past with with countries around
the world basically shipping everything
and killing their value chain so the
objective is to empower those countries
to make sure they have the value chain
so they can produce their own food
because I mean that would be a very good
purpose yeah but in the short term yeah
on producing them before feeding I think
it takes a little bit longer and then on
the Zero t zero two zero two percent
they're nasty no there are so uh the
point was that there were some players
that detained you know there were some
players that they had the commercial
interest in uh keeping the 0.2 because
they could sell varieties at 0.2 and
opening going up to zero three or
potentially one percent means more space
for new varieties to be registered so
yeah he was terribly politically correct
thank you thank you all so very much
[Music]