hello everybody uh thank you guys for
staying for the last panel of the event
uh i know it's been a long couple days
so i appreciate you guys all coming out
and participating still my name is
clinton young i am the president and
founder of charlie's farmers market
which is a medical cannabis dispensary
chain that will be coming to market in
the next few months i'm the former ceo
of mmj canada which is one of the
largest black market dispensary chains
in canada
and i've been fighting for legalization
and the cannabis plant for over 14 years
now
so i just wanted to introduce the panel
here we'll start with jordan wegman
jordan tell everybody a little bit about
yourself
um hi everybody
welcome
hi everybody
my name is a classically french trained
chef and cookbook author i'm the host of
a podcast called in the weeds that
some of you have been guests of
um really happy to be traveling and
educating people on infusing cannabis
into food and beverages
[Applause]
benjamin paddock
yes
hi everybody
hi
thank you
so much benjamin i work for a company
called bobada which is we're the
producers of the black so it's two-way
unity control
i'm in charge of all the international
markets basically at boveda
that's it thank you
and finally kyle george
hi everybody
hi
so yeah i'm kyle georges and uh i'm out
of toronto canada and another canadian
here so
uh thanks and then um there's one with
meritek and we've been around since 67
we focus on specialized equipment for a
variety of industries including food
pharma and so forth and we've been doing
a lot in the cannabis and have industry
for about eight years now and it's about
60 to 70 of our business and growing so
it's a lot of fun
amazing so we're going to talk about
sustainability and we kind of switched
the topic a little bit from safety to
education because in canada anyways and
i know a lot of markets they over
regulate the cannabis plant which means
it's probably one of the safest
industries out there so i felt like
education is probably a more suitable
fit for the topic that we were speaking
on so i'm just going to start with you
jordan because uh you know you're right
beside me um you know what are the type
of things that you're wanting to do and
aiming for
to make your brand and sector
more sustainable and how do you plan on
educating these people during the
process of this
you know i am
and i feel like i talk about this ad
nauseum i think the real opportunity in
cannabis is not to educate or
necessarily create products for stoners
like me
i'm easy to create products for the real
opportunity is how do you create
products for my mom how do you solve for
specific needs states and then it goes
into how do we actually create that food
and beverage
that is healthier and you know i feel as
though and i was saying this to you in
the green room that i feel like you know
we've really got it backwards where
if you think about
product formulation as a relay race
we've started the relay race with this
food scientist rather than a culinarian
or mixologist who uses their palette for
a living and then actually passes that
baton and that chain of custody someone
who can work with shelf stability and
scaling and so on and so forth so i find
that there's really a lot of the same on
the market and i think that as we start
talking about or we continue talking
about what health and wellness looks
like and medical looks like in the
cannabis space then we really have to
look at ingredients and why are we
including refined sugar is something
that we're actually calling health and
wellness or medical
now do you find with
the new demographic of people that
you're trying to hit the the non-classic
stoner like you said which is very easy
to appease
do you find you have a lot of hurdles
being a private chef that's doing
private infused cannabis culinary
do you find it hard to market and
educate these new things that we need to
speak about if i told you the number of
you know i work at sick children's
hospital um i i work with a number of
jewish foundations and not-for-profits
across and i'm very proud of you know
all the philanthropy that i do
and all throughout the pandemic there
was one topic they wanted to talk about
virtually that's cannabis food and
beverage people want to understand it
they want to understand it better you
know i say it like this and my brilliant
brother wrote these words so i certainly
will take you know credit for it but we
are not going to reach these people by
handing them raws or zigzags and some
flour and saying go and roll your joints
you're going to say here's tomato sauce
you already use it take your mint tea it
doesn't have any sugar in it it actually
has some terpenes in it and it has the
benefits that you're looking for
whatever that case may be so i just i
think there's there's bigger
opportunities out there especially to
educate those that are
supposedly educating others i think
that's a big part of the opportunity too
amazing now ben
bovida clearly for years now has been
leading in
humidity packs and keeping your cannabis
healthy
clean and stabilized
uh for sustainability for yourself you
know clearly boveda is
actively doing that yeah i mean we win
the market for 25 years yeah so what
what cigars and multiple other products
so is there anything that ovita is going
to be doing in the future that's going
to be
accelerating sustainability even more
for you guys
like certainly
as a company yeah yeah of course i mean
we are constantly innovating for
instance we just introduced
like the over the principle into a cap
that you can just
just screw onto like a standard like
dropped plastic jar i mean i think that
you're taking the same principle and
like we're basically a one-two pony
you know with that that one trick we
survived 25 years and we still grow 30
percent here today you know as a 25 year
old company of course thanks to
us being able to have a myriad of use
cases for our application cannabis being
one of the more fun ones i have to say
right so it's uh so yeah but we do we do
a ton of stuff so for us i mean we're
constantly innovating um even though it
might just be small changes right but
but we
are not this goes back to our leadership
so san diego is a big part also about
the culture that we that we have
um
it's really like a community almost like
a cult if you talk with people they work
up over there they're all like ooh they
were raving but it's almost like a call
because everything everybody's so
positive and so forward thinking it's
it's it's really amazing i have to say
yeah and you guys got a great education
team that i've noticed you guys are
great educators and it's something that
is crucial because you know leading back
to the original panel we were speaking
with safety
safety you know comes with education so
yes
yes and for us i mean like our product
is very simple yeah
but yet if you really want to explain
how it works
there are two ways of doing it either
educate you just have people try it out
but i mean like for you i mean if you
just have you just
just try it out doesn't work in your
case it's too complicated it works in
our case luckily
you know but no education is vital for
us i mean it's just we have a very
niching product it's just about moisture
cannabis but i mean we can all agree
that dry weed just sucks right it's
terrible you know when it's too moist
it's also bad because all the microbes
you know so it's like bad for your
health yes right so you need something
that will keep it just right in between
this week but this is what we likely do
and we just happened to screw on us do
we we're the one from pony which is
that's what we do yeah right so yeah all
right definitely yes it's great it's an
awesome product
it is quite amazing
thank you
and then kyle you know ameritech's been
around the space like we were spoken
about earlier uh for
decades in multiple different markets um
i just learned about your new vapor
static distraction this week which is
very something new to me something that
i've never even seen or i've heard of
yet um why don't you break down the
process of your extraction um what your
team does and your plan for
sustainability and also educating moving
forward in your sector
so
well
the vapor static extraction it's a very
new type of technology that we're taking
to market right now
where we're really changing up the
extraction game with a big focus on
saving
reducing the amount of solvents and
going completely solventless being
better for the environment and also
reducing the amount of electrical needs
to extract as we're helping our clients
become much more sustainable in their
processes and what we do with it is we
actually vaporize the cannabis and then
we use as a technology called
electrostatic precipitation to
recondense it from a vapor back into an
oil form right so we also do other
things in regards to ethanol co2 water
extraction types but here's a new
solution that we're taking to market
right now where it's a much more
sustainable option a lot more easier to
operate and also from an education
standpoint of the operator team a lot
simpler right one operator can easily
run 100 pounds a day or 5 000 pounds a
day right so it's a very you know much
more sustainable technology too for the
environment as well with the you know
going to a completely solvent space now
when we spoke earlier on we spoke about
how you're doing the the thousand pound
a day machines right now
and when you explain the price to me
that it may scare certain people away
but you came back with a great answer
and it actually extremely excited to be
for the small people to be able to
operate these things you guys will be
coming out with a 100 and a 400 pound
extraction machine well for the smaller
clients as well correct yes yeah we're
going down to 100 a day system and
that's over 24 hours so someone's
looking to just operate let's say 30 40
pounds within a shift you'd be perfect
for that type of person an individual
too so amazing amazing so to me you know
with charlie's farmers market and
sustainability and being a retail store
especially with medical cannabis it's
very important um you know that
education on medical cannabis uh is the
most important as alex has mentioned
before
the lack thereof
uh in the cannabis space right now um i
think more education uh is important i
think to create any type of
sustainability it starts with the
regulators because there's a lot of
regulations in canada that they put into
place that doesn't always give us the
freedom to do what we need to do to
maybe make the industry more sustainable
and or educate better
so i'm hoping that lobbying the right
different sectors
and creating more sustainable products
whether it's hemp containers instead of
plastic containers like canada's got
more plastic in their container it's
it's crazy so to me there's multiple
ways to to stay sustainable and educate
and i think that everybody here gave a
really great explanation on each parts
of their industry so um thank you for
that guys if there's any questions or if
anybody needs to add anything else
go ahead what i want to say is that
especially being in germany and me being
german now we look at the issue right so
we are where you guys have been
obviously we're trying to learn you know
from other like more level market canon
and stuff but at the end of the day
this is this is a giant thing to do like
to legalize a drug yeah you know you
create a market that has been
existing in a regulated form tomorrow's
already there of course you've been part
of the of it before
but uh so and there's a lot of fears
obviously and fear is always a bad
advice it might be of course right so
that's uh it goes to the contrary of
what would be sustainable in most of the
times
you know you talked about just education
and which you know i'm sure alex was
alluding to it but you know it makes it
very difficult for us to do what we need
to do
when all of our friends and colleagues
are being de-platformed and shadow
banned on instagram and facebook
um we can't really go out and you know
there's brilliant marketers standing
right there or sitting right there but
you know there's there's there are
creative ways to educate and people love
anecdotal evidence people love to hear
stories when i talk at length about how
i removed gluten dairy and refined sugar
and began consuming cannabis and in 60
days i healed myself from my psoriasis
or my father came home from florida six
months ago and has a big fat brain tumor
and now he's on two thousand milligrams
of different cannabinoids every single
day and played golf with my son three
weeks ago that [ __ ] is powerful and that
those are the stories
[Applause]
now
do you think george when we're telling
our stories because we spoke about this
upstairs which is very important i think
whether it's mental health uh psoriasis
parkinson's all the things that we need
to educate on topics that aren't being
really educated on
i think it's very important and it's up
to us to do our due diligence to remind
these people that although say what
works for you with psoriasis and or with
my adhd and ptsd
that specific cannabis we're an end of
one yeah we're an end of one dr deb
camilla said that on in the weeds i give
her all the credit here to weeks great
podcast um but you know she was she's
right it's a hundred percent we are in a
new one but and here's the but
you're gonna employ cannabis um you know
i'm just staying in my lane here but
you're an employed cannabis with an
unhealthy diet i'll tell you i don't
even bother spending your money on
cannabis of course cannabis combined
with a healthy lifestyle now we're
talking so that's sort of if you break
that back to you know
the soapbox and all the [ __ ] that's on
the market where
all of its corn set up or some sort of
refined sugar and it's supposed to be
solving for a need state you've got
something like refined sugar that's
causing inflammation combining it with
something like cannabis that's supposed
to lower our inflammation and what's the
net result
double negative it's negligible yeah
yeah okay amazing god one thing i'd like
to add to this too it's not a goal
educating the general public is a huge
aspect too but the other thing is as an
industry together we need to educate you
know the politicians and the regulators
that are making these regulations right
a lot of people like to talk and
complain about the regulations that are
being made out there but we need more
people to be joining the associations
working together as a unit right canada
business as a history comes from unity
and working together to move the
industry forward we need to continue on
that path and not go separate ways or
you know go against each other it's
about working together and you need to
really move forward so if you're not
already part of one of your
organizations or associations in your
own state province or country please
make sure you do so because that's how
we get this through and that's also how
we will be able to educate even the
masses and the people even better is by
pushing it through through the
regulations aspect and that's that's
exactly what we did pre-legalization
like that was the main thing that we did
we united as groups and we fought and we
fought so hard to the point where the
regulators finally broke what i don't
understand is when kyle you're making
such an amazing point it just triggered
me what i don't get is now that they
legalized the plant and we've just
accepted every little regulation that
they put in 10 milligrams or 10
milligrams into your into your edibles
okay great give somebody sugar diabetes
before they can actually get medicated
from the cannabis there's so many things
that we have just chosen to accept
because they've given us what we wanted
with regulations that no one's fighting
in the house of commons anymore no one's
fighting in the provincial levels i want
all the legal companies to go back the
way the legacy companies fought and
fight for the things that they want and
change because they're not going to get
in trouble for fighting these things the
worst case scenario it turns out to be a
no if they give a [ __ ] if they care what
does it say here so
whenever big corporations
or marketers come into play they just
[ __ ] it up i mean that's that's true now
i mean
at the end of the day
when
your stock price becomes more important
then we deliver back at sustainability
right when your stock price becomes the
most important
aspect of your day-to-day operations
then something is wrong in my opinion
very very very true so sure and then to
add to education
and we have to fund research yes there's
not enough funding in research do you
have to research because
like i think kind of is a magical plant
but it's only magical because we don't
know how that works yes
right so and there are ways to decipher
this at some point and figure the
positive stuff
what do you need which of the what
potentially 500 kind of noise you need
for your helmet yeah you probably won't
need over 500 yes of course right you
got to fight it out and then get a way
for better treatment and distal space
and also for more fun in the rig space
exactly right so and that's that's
amazing
is there anybody that has any questions
for the group
or remarks
hand up down
let's go with you what's your name
hi allison just want to say hi to
everyone specifically my lovely
brilliant friend jordan
thank you all for for talking about
these things it's amazing and it's
amazing to be in europe i think that's
what most of the canadians on the panel
are articulating and seeing everybody
out of the industry starting to build i
just wanted to touch on what you were
saying about the regulators having sat
on the industry association board in
canada and i was privileged to meet with
health canada the head of each
department twice a year and i can
promise you that change
probably doesn't come through
pushing on regulators as much as it does
from communities just saying we're just
not going to do that yeah and i think
what we saw in canada and i keep
encouraging my european friends here i'm
like don't follow all the rules
they really there have been very very
few consequences and it's all they're
all very busy and all very
overwhelmed so you would be surprised
where you could find those moments
allison's the former ceo of 48 north i
mean she was opp oh amazing allison
thank you very much for that
very tough bill
the federal government the federal
regulators and the provincial government
regulators they're nearly impossible to
deal with right but i mean and you're
right that
being a community and getting the
message out that way sometimes is the
better way to get progress and just
don't do it or just don't yeah yeah and
kind of push it yeah push the
push the envelope with the rules but i
do believe at some point communication
between the two
of the people pushing the rules and
regular regulators there needs to be at
least a
topic of conversation oh there and there
is yeah and there has to be but yeah
yeah i'm just saying like as a german we
love rules right so maybe you follow
themselves no don't stop okay i've seen
you have your red lights
i got a question over here
has your company
developed or looked at or tried to
figure out what to do with what is about
of the material that's waste that comes
out of the extraction process or are
there plans to do that or any thought on
that great great great question so
my father is a big mentor of mine and he
does a lot in other recycling industries
especially plastics and so forth and one
of his favorite trade sayings is trash
is cash
and um there's a lot of opportunities
one of my things i'm most passionate
about with the hemp and the cannabis
plant is you know there's so much that
can be done with this and so many other
building products you know everybody's
heard about you know different building
products you know uh hem create you know
insulation
you know the fibers can be utilized in
clothing um and that's an area where
it's it's also about you know us pushing
as an industry for these to be adopted
more
surprisingly a lot of us up here are
more focused on the extraction right now
and growing aspect of the industry but
like some of my very large large large
hemp clients you know a lot of their
focus right now there's a lot of
movement going into
especially the fiber the herd and
utilizing a lot of that as that starts
to move forward more and more it'll be
easier to adopt offshoots of the from
your industry and find buyers for that
expanded material now one thing i do
want to chime in youtube one of the
beauties of the vapor static extraction
process too is it's like if you put a
if you have like a pax 2 and you put a
little bit of butt in there and you burn
it on a light setting and it comes out
like a light brown that's how the
material comes out after this it's not
like it's being demolished or crushed or
soaked full of solvents and hard to deal
with so from that then too you can
easily take this material and put it
into pelletized feed or other other
options too or even using it as a
fibrous product in you know different
building materials and other things too
so as people are starting to scale and
look at how they're building up their
facilities right it's all gonna at the
end of the day margins matter and
optimization matters right but if you
can find value in your waste stream that
helps make you even more profitable
which then allows you to also make
product more affordable to the masses
right so anyways and we're working a lot
on a few other things on that aspect and
you know maybe we can chat some more
after this as well
does anybody else have any oh
mr revitch
i feel like you guys are talking about
education i mentioned on the last panel
how there should be some more
consolidation of education i feel like
everyone is doing their own education
uh you know as a chef or extraction is
there any like associations of cannabis
chefs or or extraction international
that you guys can work on an education
together so that you don't all have to
do the same thing over and over
if there's not you're going to dig it
you're going to know what right now no i
mean the fact of the matter is there has
to be some sort of governing body to
issue this certification so who's that
governing body in culinary ideally it's
the culinary schools which is why the
american colony of culinary federation
has brought a culinary program online
and there this this is coming online so
from that standpoint i think that
cannabis as part of the you know
mixology and sort of culinarians journey
that will just be table stakes as time
goes on for now it's it's you can't be
a certified culinary
cannabis professional there's just no
governing body there dude there
definitely does need to be something and
i think it will happen in time like
allison said though if we just break the
rules and create our own governing body
it might force them to
allow this scenario that's a heavy lift
my brother okay and added into that too
um one thing is yeah it's not about just
creating like you're saying like
everybody's kind of pushing individually
but it's also not about like having a an
extractor's association a culinary chef
organization so in my previous life
where i was in plastics as well like i
used to sit on the boards for like the
apr association of plastic recyclers and
navcore as well north american post
consumer recycling organization and in
these organizations what you would have
is on these boards you'd have companies
that were from all the other aspects of
the industry so you have manufacturers
of technology you'd have groups that
focused on testing you have groups that
you know focused on turn those plastics
being into clothing or carpets or
bottles or whatever it was and everybody
would work together to basically create
a cohesive voice as a sector right and
then you put together you know be it
like uh you know your recycling cans you
know the number system how to recycle
what is considered a recyclable product
what is not considered recyclable we've
got to do that exact same thing here
together but as a unit in unison right
so there are a couple organizations that
are starting but there's also too many
if that makes sense right so we gotta
find a way to bring those organizations
together as well
yeah and i think has to do also the
maturity of the market at the end really
right then let's take germany for
instance we have
basically one major industry association
and that will cover everything and make
sense because if you legalize cannabis
of course you have to look at hemp yes
of course you have to look at cbd and
all all that right it's it's it's not
just an island
so from
from us as a
economy and as a country you know we
have to have to uh have to have a
holistic approach now
but of course in the future this will be
different if you if the market would
choose you have more players
you know if different groups that will
form it's just i think it's part of
uh like a natural life cycle too
right so
you know it's funny we have this these
content leaders out there and i my mom
raised a mensch so i certainly won't say
them by name but you know they curate
content that's just incorrect it's just
it's not correct when it comes to how to
infuse culinary or food and beverage
with cannabis
and unfortunately you know whether we
want to believe it or not we are still
so nascent in many respects in north
america and i live in a federally
legalized environment we have so far to
go in terms of
getting this right and having these
thought leaders at the top of the food
chain who actually know what they are
talking about when you have the biggest
of the big information companies that
are slinging all this content and it's
wrong
i mean what kind of message are we
sending and then unfortunately you have
a lot of these periphery companies that
are out there that are linking to this
sort of mother ship and it all goes back
to curating incorrect information and i
think that you know it just speaks to
how nascent we are we'll get there but
it's just going to take some time
yeah and i also hope there is a little
bit of a cultural difference there
because i think
not you know to you know just
hit on all the anglo-saxon america but
american advertising and marketing is
very different from what we do in europe
okay so
yeah so it's it's just like everybody is
the best and the biggest and you know
that wouldn't be illegal you know to
have that as a mugging claim in europe
right so and i hope that um
well because that's also like like with
us i mean we're very niche product yeah
there's even so much disinformation
they're brought in from other from other
companies that are in the same
marketplace about our product
you know it's time to basically say i
have to give like a 45-minute speech
just to debunk all that all that
information
yeah so that's and that's also a part
you know and i hope that hopefully
hopefully hopefully that europe will be
a little bit different because nobody
everybody everybody wants to grow
but i feel like especially i said
everyone should be the best and the
biggest you know and everybody will do
that that's a mantra yeah brand presence
is massive in north america and it's
almost problematic to be honest with you
you cannot
i was gonna say but you can't lump
canada and the us together because i
think our
environment is going to be even more
restrictive than germany and
and we can't even you know it's all
warning labels and you can't really
brand market advertising so they're two
very different markets but um
yeah i think germany might even be less
strict than canada ultimately i wouldn't
bet on that to be honest but uh yeah
because the difference is germany just
to your point is that like on a societal
level we don't have like a
a wide
public that's for legalization it's
really 50 50. and this divide really
between the young and the old people and
we have a very old society right now so
there's the divider goes right through
it and that divider is one of them is
countless
right so it's so it will be i think this
is why
also knowing how the legislative process
work and knowing that in our second
chamber like what would be u.s senate
when we have the different states
um their conservative leadership
majority sorry you have a conservative
majority in this
so and then you have to make it work you
have to go through this second chamber
as well
so i could really see that as being very
conservative and also you want to have
to
come back to sustainability when it
comes to policy making again so you
don't want to have you want to have a
policy or regular framework that would
not be overthrown by the next government
if there was a change
right yes as well so i wouldn't bet that
so i i hope i hope that i'm wrong but i
have fear and i'm german it's not
pessimistic right i'm allowed to be
better
so
i'm talking not to the process to get
there but when you get there and there's
like a pack of cigarettes like this is a
german pack of cigarettes right like
what they make you do in canada every
company whether your marlboro
anyone you can't see they must use the
same color same pack same font no logo
it's just you know it just just shows
that we have better tobacco lobbyists
you do
well i think that does it for the panel
guys i i appreciate your time
[Music]
let's
this has been the international cannabis
business conference berlin 2022
you