I'm an extraction guy myself I've been
involved in just learning and educating
about the glandular trichomes and where
these medicines that we are so often
talking about we're there biosynthesized
in the plant where they're produced and
so I learned a lot about glandular
trichomes and the different types and
how these different cannabinoids and
terpene compounds are biosynthesized
inside the glandular trichomes head and
of course I helped popularize water hash
over the course for the last 17 years
I'm very much more into like sieving
than extracting so it's very it's going
to be a unique panel for me to moderate
because both of these gentlemen are
doing things that I haven't been
involved with as much over the course of
the last 20 years so I'm also very
excited to hear what they have to say so
I'll start out with but my name is Andy
Joseph I'm from apex supercritical my
story briefly i started apex
supercritical as a side job in 2001
spinks spent six years in the Navy did
submarines at a Pearl Harbor and after I
got out of the military went to I estate
for welding engineering GI Bill doesn't
pay for all of your school so you got to
make a few extra bucks so I started a
fabrication business ran across a
customer who needed some botanical oil
extraction equipment and I said I don't
know what that is but I'll make it and
give it a shot we really wanted to have
boots on the ground to understand the
industry most of our employees are from
the medical industry both the growers
and our lab techs we kind of were good
at knowing what we don't know and we
knew we didn't know enough about
extraction and about concentrates so we
we found the best team that we could
brought them in and that's really when
we started exploring molecular
separation and distillation we brought
the technology in about three years ago
and really had to dial in the parameters
of the equipment that we were using once
we figured out how you were able to
basically target cannabinoids and leave
behind the
parodies and the undesirable part of the
plant we really thought we were headed
somewhere with it we contacted the
manufacturer which was BTA in Germany
they've been a global leader in
manufacturing distillation equipment
over the last two and a half decades and
their equipment is used in petroleum
industry they're used in agricultural
industry and the pharmaceutical industry