san francisco is number one
manufacturing
and distribution
we also cultivate flowers and have been
in this business for about 20 years
i was arrested by the federal government
in 99 which then positioned me now to be
the social equity commissioner in san
francisco which allowed us to pull
licenses for those who had been
disadvantaged by the war on drugs
you might know some of our strains like
lamb's breath sunset sherbet those are
some of the strains that we are behind
so that earned me the honor to be here
today and to moderate the panel with
a group of very very knowledgeable
growers in cannabis folks so
that moved far away from you i don't
know why you guys went so far because
you're very scared it smells good oh you
got some light all right
so
that being said i'd like to start the um
panel we have one question that we kind
of like to use as an icebreaker which is
where the panel sees international
cannabis going in the next few years and
with that i'll pass it to travis
uh thank you very much ali um
[Music]
international cannabis uh as we've all
heard throughout this uh this this time
here
is
really headed to where can we learn from
the places that have already done this
right and i think
uh it's very interesting to
equate it to a match uh every single
state that we've looked at in the past
is a match that takes a while to get
started but once it does it burns really
really bright for a period of time let's
call it three years and every single
person who gets into it uh franklin is
going to make money for a period of time
and then it's going to burn and simmer
down and those who
came into it from with the right
headspace and really
double down and really focused on
systems and process right from a uh an
optimizing cultivation those are the
ones who in the long term are going to
make it past the ember and we've seen
this in every single state where they
burn bright and they kind of dissipated
the ones who make it all the way to the
end will be the ones that are around for
a lifetime so that's my point of view
thanks travis
um i think to add to that
the international scene is not unified
yet you don't really have legislation
that is overarching where germany can do
easily business with the us for us
coming from the u.s side of things
exporting california or colorado buds to
germany is
very very far away on our legislative
map of i would say what like five to ten
years maybe something like that
so i think it kind of depends what
countries do individual trade deals with
each other and that will then kind of
lead to an international umbrella of
companies
anyone else want to add to that
yeah i think you're you're internet
start looking at how how you want to
play in this market so
if you're going to be somebody that's
going to be a large grower and you're
going to make a single product that is
going to be very good i always equate it
to like the brewery industry
if you're going to be a lager be the
lager you know make the same thing get
big at that and make a lot of it or if
you want to be a craft brewer which is
more of your craft mentality it there's
still a good market there's still good
market in the united states for that too
you have to be able to be very
innovative you have to have the right
brands
you have to go back just very similar in
touch with people that are in your area
very similar to a craft brewer and then
the third part third market a third
place that would really play at
is more nutraceutical pharmaceutical
products so there's a huge amount of
opportunities within this plant there's
over 120 different cannabinoids you've
got over 400 different terpenes there's
a lot of different things you can do
you'll find find what really makes the
niche that you can you can get into a
supplement or pharmaceutical find the
right partners and i would i would also
say you know
you find people like the people on this
group
and start learning from them and figure
out what what are you good at what do
you want to do and start playing in that
space
yeah i think that's actually the most
important part to your point the
cannabis supply chain from cultivation
to what it becomes when you're
purchasing it in a store whether that's
a hash an edible pre-roll a flower a
tincture every one of those is produced
and processed by somebody who
specializes in that particular
particular
discipline so and and to add to your
point we're a very small san francisco
brand if you smoke cannabis in san
francisco there's a likeliness you
smoked some of our stuff outside of san
francisco probably just you know maybe a
few miles here and there because we're
really hyper local we focus on what the
san francisco smoker wants and that's
very high potency so everything that we
grow everything that we make really
caters to a high potency where i think
what you'll see in europe because it's
more of a novice market and you have a
lot of the so-called canon curious that
you will probably to this point kind of
be very successful with nutraceuticals
with more approachable potencies that
are in the 18 to the 20 range so i think
europe will kind of find its own way and
its own preferences and cultivation as
the years go on i think alex can
probably speak a lot to the terpene
profiles that europeans enjoyed
when it comes to
well in europe we like about this of
course when it comes to the aromas that
we enjoy the aromas a lot the most cured
they are the more we are
lighting them
as to this
and timo what do you see as one of the
biggest light suppliers to cultivators
i'm sure you've seen plenty of really
state-of-the-art facilities um what do
you see the strain profiles that are
being run here and i'm sure you also
know what we run in california so you
have a pretty good idea of what the
taste in europe is versus
versus us
the question is do we know the taste of
europe right so europe is a huge it's a
continent and consumers are very very
different and with more choices also
their taste will develop
right now there are areas where there
are have not these choices now so still
taste and
you know demand
needs to still be developed um but i
i think it was a great discussion at the
beginning
when we see
you said something about focus
you know
we saw we learned from other markets
that a lot of
companies tried to be
everywhere
and that
really i mean everywhere at the same
time and then totally vertically
integrated you know from i do my own
genetics until extraction my own brand
distribution and so on
this is for every business independent
from cannabis
it's so complex so i think focus is
important where is your
play in the value chain and then
also what we easily said earlier
don't develop your own lines don't
develop your own rats don't
pick the things which work because then
you can
you know forecast and make a business
model in the business cape which is
fulfilling the customer demand what you
said you know what's my business one who
do i want to supply to
and i think this is um
interesting because we see all this
right now developing into different
countries in europe and
yes it's exciting times but for
entrepreneurs
the challenge is these times are totally
unclear when it's regulation coming here
when it's happening that and having the
agility in the business model to adopt
is i think
very interesting to see who will then be
successful because i think it will be
the ones who are able to adopt the
business model fast
yeah i think that's really on point to
add to that
the key thing there is pick your area of
expertise whether it's cultivation uh
whether it's manufacturing whether it's
packaging if you try to own them all
you'll be a master of none and
you know what we really see from working
based out of california and working in
the vertical growing space with many
cultivators who have been successful is
the ones who who've really excelled you
know companies like kirley verano
h medicine and steezy they really focus
on what they're good at and they didn't
try to make everything themselves like
to your point making your own lights or
racks yeah you could go that route but
you could be better off focusing on your
your own systems process to be first in
that given field
and also did i see it in our own company
you know we we did a lot of cannabis
lighting and then we decided oh let's go
also to europe and let's go do also much
more in you know food crops and the
complexity was like boom
so it's not like i experienced it every
day in our own company how hard it is so
focus is really for us as well because
it's
immediately you need to put new people
new um you know skill sets in the in the
company and then it gets really
difficult to scale and keep the focus
um so yeah
yeah and if you add to that that when
when you're in a new cannabis market
like germany or even you know markets
that that
legalize in the us the
states that do um if you do let's say a
processing place where you're just
processing
oils or making you know white label
stuff that will already generate you a
decent amount of business because to
this point there is going to be a lot of
growers that don't manufacture
themselves they're focused on
cultivating and they don't have brands
so they want somebody to buy their bulk
flour process that into products so
there is opportunities to
um to to
start facilities and just make money on
the square footage of that facility even
if you don't have a brand but to timo's
point you have to focus on one thing
you're good at are you going to make
creams and nutraceuticals are you going
to do pre-rolled joints but if you
become good at one thing your facility
will generate revenue
yeah i agree again i'd still equate it
back to you know any kind of craft
industry so
they're you know what there's 1500
different varieties or strings out there
if you try to do all 1500 you probably
won't get the customer base that you
want so your customers are going to be
after bothering me like hey you make the
best whatever so if it's crap brewer you
might say it's an imperial stout and
this might be a train wreck but these
are the guys i always go to i get the
best train wreck i get my best feeling
from that that's where i go they're my
guy and i'm willing to drive by five
other dispensaries to get to them
because that's my guy because what's
going to happen is there'll be
additional dispensaries and the people
that really are not connected with you
are going to go to the closest
dispensary and that's what you want to
employ
i think another question that was asked
was if um what we see happening to the
race to the bottom when it comes to
potency basically thc per milligram
whether it's going to become sort of a
brand war to sell you the most thc per
gram for the you know best price and i
think that's something that the whole
panel can speak to
um i'll start with with travis if you
want to
start that one we've seen it in
california so i think you have a little
bit of experience already
yeah definitely i mean it's besides like
the from the brand standpoint right
there's a few brands that have really
done it pretty well and i think that
they
they have they're doing all right in the
whole vertical chain but they're they
have experts who they brought in from
each thing they just tried to figure out
themselves because you know going back
to that point but i think the race to
the bottom is really going to come to
who
um if you look at the price per pound in
california it went from you know 2 000
to 800 right and if you're producing
pounds at 800 the whole time in the
beginning you thought you're making a
ton of money and all of a sudden you can
barely keep the doors open so i think if
you look at it from day one from a
cultivation standpoint how do i optimize
for as cheap as i can make it for at
still holding the quality level that is
you know important to you and your
customer whether that's to your point
you know the highest thc or the
smoothest for the entry-level uh
cannabis curious consumer um how do i
get to that 400 price point per pound to
grow so that when i'm making 2000 i'm
making even more and i can turn that
money and reinvest into my business but
when it gets down to 800 i'm still
profitable so process in any business
that you look at you know we fly planes
and naka wood don't crash very often
because we follow processes um that's a
very long-standing industry we have to
get to that point to where everybody is
following the same type of processes
internally
and you know at groveglide we looked at
that from a systems standpoint uh with a
cultivation kind of task overview and
some educational components that we're
working on internally but that's where i
see is a key thing
is don't focus
on how much money you're making now
focus on
where is it going to be in five years
and optimize for that day
yeah i totally agreed on processes um at
my manufacturing we've implemented
flourish which is a compliance and vrt
software and that even you know captures
our cost of goods on latex clubs or
whatever but what that's done for us
it's increased our output by 30 while
dropping our cost of goods like seven
percent but
you also see what kind of wastage you
have once you have systems in place that
actually track this so one tip that i
have for people that are starting a
cultivation is first of all look at the
time of the growth period of your
strains if you're running a 12-week
strain that is an extra month of rent
you have to pay where you're not
generating revenue so always keep a good
mix of 12 8 and 10 weeks straight so
that you're always harvesting and always
generating revenue so staggering you're
staggering to grow is something that's
really really important and the other
thing is really look to have to to
stuart's point the flavor profile maybe
it's not a super high potency one but it
has a really unique taste that people
really want so there's ways to
manipulate your catalog to also be
profitable not just for the love of oh i
want to grow this 12-week strain so you
have to you have to pick them well
so to the question of the race to the
bottom
um if we see
the sales price yeah there will be craft
growers there will be different business
ones you can play and maybe also sell
premium but the big volume
will be get under a lot of pressure
it will happen it's an agricultural
product it gets commoditized and it gets
the pressure will happen as it did for
tomatoes as it did for corn and whatever
um so it's i think
having the operational spendings under
control
and the two biggest blocks of your
operational spendings if it's a
greenhouse or indoor facility will be
labor and electricity
and labor goes down to processes
procedures and so on
being effectively you know i always like
also the example of if i go into a dutch
greenhouse
it's it's beautiful right it runs like a
perfect machine and
10 20 years ago they produced or
now the example of tomatoes 80 kilograms
sorry 40 kilograms and now
20 years later it's 80.
so they could increase the production by
and they thought back then they already
had it
totally under control right so where i
want to go with that is um
if the prices drop sales prices drop
then you need to preserve your gross
margin by having your opex under control
and that is electricity and this is
labor and these two things is important
and if we now go back to the example in
california the prices drop and everyone
who didn't have the opex under control
having for example hps lines yeah then
you have no operational income anymore
no gross profit and then you cannot um
survive right and to to the point with
matches i really like this we cannot
afford in europe really
i don't want that all the matches burn
through the end because we have the
opportunity to take learnings from other
market and do right so it's all
collectively our responsibility to not
repeat because actually we saw it
already so let's make it better
i think it's important to add though
that
in in the us there was always a lot of
30 40 year old existing industry that
had a say in what we had to do so you do
have a clean canvas and it is really
nice to have a clean canvas and we do
hope that germany takes from all the
different states that legalize them and
grabs the best of it that's definitely
the hope and i think stewart had
something yes i i 100 agree with with
with uh with what you're saying it said
you have to run it like a real business
it's not you're not just gonna go hey
i'm gonna i'm in the weed business and
i'm gonna get rich it doesn't really
work that way you have to work hard
and there's a lot of different ways to
do it so certainly you know labor
electricity you're going to look at a
return on investment you've had
financial model people talk to you
earlier
you're going to
you may have the cheapest operation but
if you're not getting yield that doesn't
make a lot of sense so you're going to
say i'm going to pay x amount to be able
to get x amount of yield and whatever
that number is also depends on
what you want to grow so product
selection is extremely important
branding you're going to have to brand
so you look at the companies there are
plenty of companies out there that are
commodities look at bananas anybody here
of chiquita bananas probably everyone
right
because why because they branded their
product it just isn't called bananas and
i'm a commodity and they demand more
money for that and so you've got to get
into the brand of discussion and then
there's a matter of innovations
and innovations certainly have a thc but
then you're going to add in
terpenes and terpenes to me are
extremely important i'm going to let
alex talk to that yeah but i'll have
nothing to add for the determinants of
the second what i'd like to say is that
we see here in europe when it comes to
the cbd business at the end a good
example of how it can go down and how
you can lose your money for your
investment because a few years ago the
price of the kilo price was still 4 000
euro and now you can buy the 200 euro
the cure
so you can see that even the investments
back for indoor facilities for cbd
flowers have been made in millions and
millions and millions
the roy nowadays is not given anymore
because the price has been dropped so
much because everybody started it
without giving any regulation for
nothing and everybody's just winging it
trying to bring the biggest proposal
trying to bring the biggest consultants
ranking the biggest investors trying to
build the biggest facilities and at the
end you have
bad outcomes the prices are dropping
it's too much and you will never get the
investment back at the end
so
let us try to make concrete how how if
we would have a magic wand and could say
okay how it should be germany to not
repeat the question how would we build
it let's let's let's discuss this
because i i i get asked
would you limit the amount of licenses
in germany
so then to to produce so that's pretty
question okay
do we produce only in germany or do we
can we get also import so
let us discuss what do we think should
germany it's a huge country over 80
million people should they supply their
own cannabis or should they allow as
well import what what do you guys think
about that i think i'd like to kind of
take the lead on that being that i can
still touch the plant every day and i've
been cultivating it for 20 years so i i
do take a little issue with saying that
it's a commodity um it's a part of it is
commoditized but when people spend 50 60
euros on you know five grams a week
that's a really nice wine bottle that
you could afford for that price and
grapes may be a commodity but wine is
not
so i think we really need to
differentiate and when we grow hemp we
can grow hemp like we grow corn we can't
grow cannabis like we grow corn cannabis
the footprint of an individual plant
takes space you need to care for it you
need to prune it it gets different it
gets a different regimen of food every
week of fertilizers it gets enzymes so
there's a lot of work that goes into
creating really good cannabis right so
it while it gets commoditized on like an
outdoor for we see the commoditization
in california without
outdoor wheat we don't see that on
indoor as much while the price has
dropped there's still a strong market
for it so i think to
transition to your point of what to do
in germany i think yes the wheat should
be grown locally that sold in germany so
you can foster small business
so you can give outdoor farmers the
chance to grow
a commodity but you give indoor farmers
a chance to be craft brewers and i think
that's aligned with the german culture
as well
but would you do it only
only in german germany for germany
i'm not i i'm for export but what i'm
saying the first right of refusal the
first right to grow cannabis should be
given to the locals but they should also
be allowed to export sure i mean i think
you can have a problem
with what you're saying i think you're
gonna have a problem on day one is that
demand is going to greatly outplay
supply right so what's best for the
transition period is is likely going to
be something where you have to allow
let's say 50 to be imported on year one
and then you could trail that down then
40 and then 30 10 20 all the way down to
10 i don't know that i would necessarily
agree that it should be zero uh is
allowed from import but something along
a transition period otherwise you're
just gonna have 10x the demand and if
you say there's no legal import it's
just going it's going to come in through
the black market right so i don't
disagree with that you need a
transitional strategy sure yeah and you
know i think the way that we that uh to
your point i to 100 agree i love the
brewery analogy you know there's in a in
america there's there's the budweiser
there's the coors you know there's only
a couple of those guys but that to the
equate that that's your your outdoor uh
grow quality is going to be low it's
going to be inexpensive but there are
hundreds and or thousands even of
flourishing micro breweries and craft
breweries who are looking at growing
their indoor space and they're not
trying to sell to the world they're
trying to sell to san francisco right
and they're putting out an amazing
product and i think that's why when you
go back to that operational efficiency
you know for us at groveland you know
multi-tier growing is crucial and if you
look at that from an offec standpoint
your first tier is going to cover your
labor costs your second tier coverage
your rent and your third tier is your
pure profit and that's really how a lot
of people are transitioning to they
learn how to grow in a single tour
outdoor but the ones who quickly
transition to a multi-tiered like very
uh process-driven environment are the
ones who are winning now so europe can
really look ahead and say like let's
skip the wasted time
to your point power and space is really
expensive and we talked about earlier in
the green room the cost of
transportation and supply chain you know
the the your to your point uh cannabis
is really old by the time it goes from
canada to here or wherever
and that's not really helping the
quality uh inconsistency versus if we
can grow it inside of berlin for
instance and supply just berlin that's
going to save on a lot of things
including you know benefits for the
environment
and i think it's important to say to
your point that a budweiser and a craft
brewer can't live next to each other and
both have a market the big brands
attract they attract attention they
attract awareness they bring in a ticket
price that's affordable across all tax
brackets and then you have your little
nice gems that you can pick from i think
it should be driven by getting the
consumers the freshest best product
whether that's from a commercial
industrial outfit or from a craft outfit
yeah completely green certainly i've
been on both sides of that with cure
leaf and uh and and small craft brewers
that are craft campus guys that we work
with today with agrippa
and it's really
it's it's it's really you know that
they work together but a large cara leaf
are large and you have like three large
ones within germany
those folks will help push regulations
those folks will bring and drive
process improvements so those folks are
bringing in product safety standards and
instead of having all these little guys
trying to spend
hundreds of thousands of dollars
let the big guys do that let them let
them pay it that way
and don't try to compete with it you
don't need to compete with unless you
unless you're the guy that runs around
here with two or three billion dollars
i'm guessing none of those people are in
this room
and
you're gonna go like how do i get how do
i get to the craft site so
you know
you know back to travis point you if you
do vertical grows you can do
you know they're they're a four by eight
section that's one strain
so you can do multiple strains within
your facility which are you know which
you can keep on getting your customers
more and more aware the new thing so
craft brew and large brewery is a very
good
it's a very good analogy and that's why
i would look at in as far as licenses as
far as limiting i wouldn't limit any
licenses
and i know that's not certain popular
but
i would limit the licenses based on you
have to hit a product safety and product
quality standard that's that should be
your only limitation
i agree and i think it's also important
to say that craft and commercial we
actually all use the very similar
equipment so for you when you walk into
industrial grow or you walk into my 200
lighters it's both fluent so it's
something that we all do use the same
equipment it's really just the intent
with which you approach your your
cultivation not all unfortunately but
we we try we try our best um
but but what i heard what we are all
saying i agree i would give license to
growers in germany for germany because
you can create great value propositions
and branding
here the brand brand book or berlin
cush or whatever you can make a nice
strain and you can label it and this is
yeah people want that they want to be
associated with their with their
community or region i i see that but i
totally agree we need to enable and
have in germany
import because we need so much weed
unbelievable to fight the black market
and where i'm from in bavaria
a lot of people are buying
cannabis
through the darknet and they are very
well educated consumers because if you
go into the darknet it looks like an
amazon store where you have all the
references and all the
customer reviews and so on so there must
be
volume and choice
because otherwise you just decriminalize
the drug everyone is still going to the
dealer and we don't achieve the goals
with the german government wants to
protect miners
to get tax income and to to ensure
product quality and safety these are the
three main targets for the government
this you don't have if you don't have
enough wheat and everyone is just buying
or less decriminalized from the dealer
and so i think
we need to have enough and i really like
this princess position
process of maybe phasing it slowly out
yeah to to to to support um you know
german
cultivators but we also need to be
clear on
electricity in germany is ridiculous
expensive
and this country is pretty crowded
already it's a tiny country with 80
million people so also permits and you
know growing facilities to build them up
is is expensive in germany so i i just
hope if germany gives regulation that
it's long term because if you cannot
make your money three three four five
six years but they change all of a
sudden you compete all of a sudden you
get cheaper cultivators for cheaper
prices
and then the business model is broken
again well one thing i can assure you
that's happened in every other state and
country that did legalize cannabis is
that you're nowhere looking at the near
the final legislation
it is that i can
i will put money on that the other thing
i do want to mention is to your point
with the black market um one thing that
i really feel like is lacking in the
german legislation
is an incentivizing people that have had
a record for selling cannabis and give
them a path to a legal industry and
there's no program for it they're not
considering it in their laws and that is
it's not fair towards those that risk
their freedom to make something socially
acceptable but it's also
counterproductive to your goal of
wanting to eliminate the black market i
would take every kid that's selling
eights on a corner and give him a bud
tender education because that kid to
your point will be a knowledgeable
salesperson so i do miss the restorative
and the social equity justice component
[Music]
in in the legislation that germany is
drafting and i wish they would put more
effort into that but do we know that
still i i don't think that we know how
they will change the btmg law because
they need to if you
legalize recreational cannabis you need
to also change how right now consuming
cannabis is punished
so that's
this i personally have no
view into but they will
need to change it because otherwise we
have conflicting
laws actually but what i'm saying is the
people of the past that have been
thinking
they need to be incentivized or the
people that are right now still dealing
in the illegal market you incentivize
those people look i was one of those
and the city incentivized me to come out
of all my basement out of the back of
the restaurant that i would get a
pre-record and they gave me a priority
permit what did that do i invested two
and a half million dollars into building
a business in the city so you have to
incentivize those to come out of the
underground and then you end up being
the chair of the oversight committee and
you have a voice and you have a voice
for people that didn't have a voice
before but we're also one of the best
manufacturers
our joints are the number one selling
joints because we really love what we do
right we risk our lives for it so i just
think the people that have had
convictions should have an opportunity
now that everybody says hey it's okay to
smoke weed why don't they get an
opportunity a first shot i did mystery
do we have do you have any more comments
because i think we were going to open up
some public questions too what i wanted
to add to chemo before was that why was
the big reason why you have people more
turned to black market against the black
market educate you better than any
pharmacist
just actually where you can get
information or i can get any kind of
knowledge about what you would be
growing how the bank would be for you
what kind of benefits you could have and
if you go to the pharmacy he will look
at you like
it could be this i don't know
you're absolutely right and
then that is why it's so interesting how
the point of sale looks like you know if
we would know how the point of sale
looks like we can also imagine how much
they can sell and what and who is
selling it and how much this person
knows to educate so this is like one of
the questions um which is yeah and
you're right we hope for people who are
in the cannabis industry today being the
people telling
possible consumers
what benefits they have because in most
cases they know it better than a
pharmacist at nothing against bonuses
and that's not the point but they are
have not been part of the industry so
far so there is also a learning curve to
to to take
yeah i think that part is it's it's the
black market's there it's it's not like
if we we act like we're gonna legalize
it and then there's gonna be weed
the weed is already there people have
been doing it for a long time
and all you have to do is basically say
now you can do it the right way
instead of all the other stuff that goes
on just take the people that already
know how to do this business
and give them a license just providing
that you they have to meet certain
regulations for sure without that we
don't want to hurt anybody
but just give the people that know how
to do this the chance to do it yeah
there's no bigger incentive than not
going to gym it's a great answer
[Applause]
um i think we should start with some
questions from the audience if you guys
have any
everything to you
no questions at all over there
straight to smoke session well we're
getting him a mic i think
while we're waiting to get a mic i think
you know everything we said about like
eradicating or getting towards a a
reduction in the black market is crucial
the one big caveat there is like going
to be the distribution right if it's if
it's
6 p.m on a friday and you and your
friends want to you know get some good
quality if you have to drive 25 miles
even if you're like i'm trying to
support the legal market you're like i'm
just going to call my dealer right so
there needs to be that distribution
market you know um
maybe amazon one day gets into drone
deliveries and i agree i think access is
like i was asked in san francisco why we
don't put a cap on retail licenses and i
said well everybody should be able to
walk to a dispensary within 10 minutes
so until we have three or four in every
neighborhood that's accessible we don't
have enough because look at how many
liquor stores look how many species we
have embedded right so why not we need
axes everywhere like to your point
shouldn't take you more than three
blocks to find a wheat shop
yeah but i guess you call the global
services and everything you just order
it or just eat in a few years and we'll
deliver it home and with convenience
yeah like we have ease and stuff they
deliver it's it's convenient
so um the question is
we're talking about
illicit versus legal market and one
category that feels completely not
talked about but widely used in germany
is hashish so
i'm curious to hear
what if any opinion you all have about
hashish and and how that will will or
could fit into this
you know new world
that's right
in my wheelhouse so we're the biggest
hashmaker in san francisco and have won
just several awards this month for our
temple balls
um
hashish is
so culturally ingrained here in germany
that i think what you'll see is an
explosion in the market of rosins
turp sauces diamonds traditional ash
temple balls
you'll see less and less of the
so-called shoe hash
kind of the the flattened the flattened
hatch the way it gets here right now um
but we see in california for example
that hash is exploding so the last
this 7 10 is you know the official hash
holiday so 710 hash sales went up 70
and then they've kind of flattened out
but they're overall up now 30 to what
they were before we see an incredible
explosion in hash i think to go back to
the point if i was making hash here i
would definitely look into
um into some you know
local ethnicities and cultures that have
that ingrained imagine i could find a
hell of a lebanese hashmaker here so i
think cash will be a part where john
germany can really dominate some of the
markets but it will be so hard to push
away the illegal market it's like i
cannot even imagine it so we what we
feel about hashes we love it and
we get great hashish from morocco from
lebanese from afghanistan and they do it
in massive fields and do amazing hashes
it will be brutally difficult to push
this away for a good price point because
quality is good and
but here
the politicians have an interest because
this is a
product where potentially
and the quality could be
somehow
changed because you can mix easier stuff
in there than on flower
so there is a big interest to push away
the illegal market but it will be tough
i think it will be very very tough to to
push it away but um who cares and finds
her in a sweet spot yeah
a lot of consumer wants that for sure
and i think once you see a tested
product with a lab test
and then you see one that's not tested
and you see what they test for you're
probably going to go with the tested
product and to this point yes they make
good land raise techniques but you're
not going to get a butter or a rosin
that's like bright yellow or white from
them right you're not going to get a
sauce that pulls a spaghetti into your
dab break so yeah you'll you'll have
your choices but he's right you have
you're spoiled with really good street
cash here that is an issue but it's also
often contaminated that is a that is the
issue but
who is not saying that maybe morocco is
changing the laws it's a sleeping giant
who could also
change the law and if germany have a
bilateral agreement with morocco it
could be also that then it gets imported
i was
not not something that is not
potentially possible right the real
optimist this one i would have said in a
real bright future maybe we have
cultivation licenses in morocco and we
can export an important actual real
hardship but legal this time for
moroccan we can serve it everywhere
there you go
let's keep on dreaming does that answer
your questions a little bit
if you have any other questions
all right let's hear it from the panel
all right thank you