hi
do you know who i am
i'm your good con science i'm the good
conscience of this conference and i
think that might be the reason why alex
always wants me to speak here you can go
home and tell the people and maybe your
kids if you care about what they think
about you
it's not all about money so it's not all
about business there was a step one
guy some kind of in blue
who has been proven in more than 25
years of activism that he's not
out there for the money
looking for
big business looking for big money
we collected a lot of money spent it for
legalization
reached kind of legalization did a lot
of the development we've seen in germany
and so it was a business and
a much sense conference kind of that
and i'm doing the joking job again um
unless
i've seen lots of you
giving a on that kind of politics
and
bringing society forward and explaining
[Music]
why should you spend money for others
for society or something
if you are
in charge for your company but i've also
seen a lot of companies coming here to
germany
spending a lot of money to to bring
their
name
between the people
become well known having big plans
uh managing money in germany and then
seeing well it was not like i thought
that end of
2017 you have to have 100 000
expectations in germany
and the whole legalization train is not
going that fast forward as i thought
with
10 years
now since colorado made that decision
politicalization in 10 years and we have
still only two
countries in the world that legalizes
cannabis that's not your plan right
that's not why you are here that you are
here because you see perspectives that
you are here because you see fast
development of that cannabis business
so it's also also in your
interest to spend some money for
politics for activists or for your
industry association bringing the
political
situation forward
otherwise uh well you shouldn't take a
lot of time if you wait until the
attackers come kind of alone
and
it's also in the interest direct
of your company because it makes good
karma to spend a little bit of your
money for sense
i don't care much about company names
and i don't know
but
from the american companies i know
one that's dr bonner
because i heard they spent a lot of
money for
things that make sense and not just for
their
direct advertisement in soup
they spend money for the cents
and there are some other companies doing
that like icbc icbc alex watchers is one
of them uh who understood that um taking
care about legalization in germany or
johnson picker for example uh volunteer
providers in germany another example of
a company that
brought us forward also here politician
in germany
and
people in germany know that this company
did something good for people so
i just call you again here a little bit
dr bona
and
support your collectivist
[Applause]
you