welcome to our
to the next panel here on icbc
we are talking about the question what
does gmp really mean
of course we all know gmp means good
manufacturing practice
but what's behind it is there any
differences within the national
regulations is the difference between
european regulations and u.s regulations
and i'm glad to have two experts here on
the podium on the panel
which is nina kemp from switzerland he's
owning a cannabis company there
and
he's he's a ceo of oh it's
[Music]
uh
charlie's lap and of hamcare i know a
lot but the other one i was not so
familiar with uh tell me about your your
two projects please nema
um well first of all thank you uh for
having me here
so as misha said from switzerland um the
ceo of swiss hemp care and charlie's lab
swiss hemp care has nothing to do with
gmp it's a recreational brand we grow
cbd
high
content cbd
strains in switzerland and then we also
produce oils and sell those oils it's a
lifestyle brand charlie's lab is the gmp
part that's why i'm sitting here
we started it about two and a half years
ago
and now we are shortly
before the the certification process by
swiss medic which is the authority in
switzerland which
certifies
companies and manufacturers
and that's the the charlie's lab part
and
so as i said end of this year we should
receive the certification
um
shortly yeah thank you
thank you nima and to my left we have a
peter sickerty who is is that pronounced
the right way
she gets the getty okay yeah and he is
the
ceo and the founder of welcome medical
and uh welcome medical is a danish
company uh
specialized in extraction of cannabis
and peter is gonna tell us a little bit
more about the profile of his company
so
first of all a small disclaimer i was
presented as an expert on gmp
i think
i have a commercial background so
that will be sort of my perspective on
on gmp
and not so much on the specialized
quality assurance
or regulatory perspective
but valcon medical is based in denmark
and we are gmp certified
under the danish law for medical
cannabis
and we're a contract manufacturer
so what we do is we
we support the growers in denmark to
make extracted products that they can
sell under their own brand
we also have a wide label product a thc
white label product that we are bringing
to market later this year
and also selling bulk
um so we received our license here in in
the end of may this year after an
inspection from the danish medicines
agency
and
now we have products and stability
and uh looking forward to the results
yeah
thank you very much peter
and as many of you know uh we have a
different gmp regulations
all over the world
within the european community
the gmp regulations are kind of
homogenized but the national application
routines us
still differ from country to country we
come through that later nina will tell
us how the application process works in
switzerland pete will tell us how the
application process
works in denmark and then we don't we i
regret that we don't have anybody from
overseas here on the panel because
in the united states we have even a
different regulation it's called cgmp
cgmp means current good manufacturing
practice which is updated every year in
the european community we have a cbdi we
have gmp regulations which are updated
every few years in the usa the gmp
regulation is updated every year and
it's even more stricter but the usa also
accepts the german and the european gmp
regulations but not every country you
can look that up
in the mutual recognition agreement the
mr agreement
and germany's gmp
is regulations are accepted since 2019
from the usa so anybody who wants to
know more about that should just check
the mri regulations and it's mentioned
there country by country which country
can export medical products under gmp
regulations through the u.s and which
national regulations the u.s the fda
does not
does not accept okay then i start with
the european regulations because
despite we have an official home
organization a home organization in the
european community and in switzerland
national application routines as i said
before are different and so nema please
tell us what what did you have to do to
get a gmp license in switzerland
so uh
maybe just to to uh
say the same as peter said to call
experts
me personally would say that's a very
to too good description um maybe in five
years i would call myself an expert um
so what you need for gmp
with my knowledge what i have now is
definitely a lot of money that's always
good
the right people with the right
knowledge
and
a bulletproof plan
so we started we had uh big ideas we
wanted to do everything and now
basically it's tailored down to
something very small and specific and
for what we then specifically applied so
there are forms that you need to fill
out by the swiss medic which i said
before is the the authority in
switzerland which certifies
uh companies
um we applied for specifically um
blending
oils now um
in different uh percentages
which we also defined already
um filling them in 10 uh 30 and 50
milliliter bottles
and capping them and labeling them so
that's the that's the whole gmp uh chain
that we applied for everything before we
didn't do that no extraction that's what
peter's doing so i'll be the customer of
peterson we just realized before
and then we can bring gmp products on
the market so
basically
you need the right team um you need to
build up the quality management system
you need to know exactly what you want
to do what product the inspector wants
to know exactly what you
what you intend to do is it realistic um
and then the process from the day you
give your your application and can take
up to 18 months
until they give the certification so
that's basically
the procedure in switzerland yeah and
with that application or as soon as you
get uh
as soon as you have it you're also
allowed to export to other european
countries because switzerland is not
part of the eu but this form is accepted
in other countries as well isn't it
that's correct yes it is yeah and uh
yeah my question to peter is you are
from a country within the euro computer
community denmark is a member of the
european community
and
in the green room before you told me
still your application is a little bit
different from for example the german
application form
and first of all why do we need gmp in
the cannabis
farmer
why do we need gmp
so so i guess
what is gmp which is kind of like the
the question here and
and is it different or not i would say
within europe
it's uh it's pretty clear to me
what it is because
the european commission and the ema have
set out the um
the guidelines um which is in the
uterulex and the directives
then it's up to each country to
implement those directives in their own
law
and then there is also the ich guideline
so
basically the whole framework for and
and all the rules and guidelines and
regulations exist and are the same
when it comes to
to to cannabis
i guess the whole purpose of gmp is
taking care of the patients really and
making sure that there is consistency
traceability
everything and as cannabis is a medicine
and it's a prescription medicine that's
being prescribed to people with
illnesses
then of course it should be
produced under gmp
now
in denmark
we have a
like a special law governing medical
cannabis because it does differ from
other medicine that just applies to
the medicine law
um and the reason for that is partly
also that we don't have to go through
clinical trials
and that's really the catch with medical
cannabis that that's how it really
differs from
conventional
medicine so to speak or pharmaceuticals
so the application process in denmark
and the
inspection from the danish medicines
agency is
very much the same as it is for other
companies producing medicine
everything is
everything we do is embedded in the
uterus and in the law
and they do a gmp inspection
the license we get is
the same as a gmp certification it's
just under the danish cannabis law
the catch is i would say
when you have your
gmp certification as a manufacturer
is the product registration
and that's where country to country it
really differs a lot
because in denmark as an example
under the danish program
you can produce a product under gmp a
flower or an oil
and you can file a product registration
application
and it if it's approved it's on the
market at market and it's on the
pharmacy shelf branded under your
company brand
and the doctor prescribes it to the
patient
right now we have a
we have jill capsules on the market in
denmark
there's still magistral prepared
cannabis on the market too
but else we are going to see more
products coming into the market
it's also going to be
a lot more common for the doctors to to
prescribe cannabis because they have
more options
in germany
i'm not an expert on it yet but i know
that it has to go through some steps
in a magistral process it cannot just be
registered and put on the pharmacy shelf
there's a few additional steps
and that's really where it differs a lot
within
the european union
the last step of the supply chain
would you say peter that
this is one of the reasons why denmark
meanwhile has i think six cannabis
producers and the law is not as uh long
implemented as it was in germany it's a
lot much newer and yeah in this uh does
it is it easier to start in the industry
due to the to the uh
to the regulations or to the
registration to the cannabis medicine
registration would you say it's easier
to make a startup in denmark
i would say nothing is easy when it
comes to starting a cannabis company and
i think most people in this room will
recognize that
i guess the framework we have in denmark
is
more transparent
and the
room we have to conduct commercial
operations is probably also more
transparent
as i think i heard earlier there was
only really three licenses for
cultivation
and some extraction that has been
granted in in germany
whereas in in denmark
i think there were at a time about 50
companies
that had gotten a
development license which means that you
are allowed to
practice sort of with cannabis until
you're ready for your inspection
so
easier that's a relative word but i
would say more transparent
yes i believe so
thank you
nima a short look in switz a short look
to switzerland
when i when i see all those cbd
productions in switzerland
i see
some of them are gmp
some of them are not
so
what advantages do you have as a gmp
producer in switzerland
that's a good question
i think the it depends
what we're talking about is it flower
production um because if it's flower
production
it can currently only be for export
so that that's already paints the
picture for switzerland we only have
small small patients for certain oils
which are produced under gmp yeah so you
you do need that plus the narcotic
license because it's still a narcotic in
switzerland the thc um but cbd stories
dvds are like cottages thc no no cbd is
basically free depends then in what what
kind of products you put it on the
market depends then on under what
regulations in falls then the whole
novel food story comes
so
maybe i'll just use that that example so
um at at the moment as we speak many
oils cbd oils under under zero two
percent are being taken out uh from the
stores from the
uh pharmacists the cantonal pharmacists
which have the power to do that
and just last week they came to a store
where our product was inside and uh
we we had a different approach of um
registering the product and also the
whole documentation which we already
have i mean we don't have the gmp gmp
certification yet but 95 of the of the
95 percent of the sops are all already
in place we're already working like gmp
um our products do cost more because the
employees cost more the qps cost a lot
of money
and it just costs
the costs are very high and
when we talk to the to the cantona
pharmacist and showed him all the the
paperwork we have
at the end our oils are still on the
shelf now so i think that
that is a major difference it's it it
shows that there's some security behind
that and they also understand we want to
bring safe products
to the to the shelves
yeah
and generally also we speak about two
very different markets because in
switzerland cbd is also a recreational
product but also a medical product sold
in pharmacies
in denmark uh
there is actually uh in your in your
company we only talk about medical
credit products
and
what would you say um in in denmark
what's about the domestic market we're
talking all the we're talking about
exporting all the time but what is about
the domestic market what about selling
gmp products in danish pharmacies is
that already a big market there
well i mean
we're obviously also focused on export
because denmark is a small
small country with only about six
million people so
it's not a huge market um but i think
when we're talking markets it also comes
down to
the doctor's perception of of medical
cannabis
the challenge in denmark is that the
like the doctors
don't really understand it and they
they're not educated and they're very
reluctant to prescribing it so instead
we have we have some cannabis clinics
that are specialized in prescribing it
and confident with
with having patients and starting them
up on on medical cannabis
same thing as the at the hospitals they
also have doctors that are
using medical cannabis and prescribing
it out of the hospital
we have seen
some products on the danish market there
was an oil that was imported from from
canada
it was on the market for about
i think it was two years or a little
less than two years before it was
unfortunately taken off the market again
in three years and two quarters i think
the total cannabis sales was about 10
million euros
in in denmark which is definitely not
insignificant and there is a there's a
reimbursement program that's 50 for for
patients of the price they pay at the
pharmacy
and 100 if you're terminally ill
so
i think we will see over time when more
products come into the market because
now there is really only one which is
the gel capsules
and we'll start to see that the
doctors get more confident in
prescribing it the patients are showing
good effects
and
i guess that's when it will start to be
more normalized and
a general perception in the public that
this is
this is a thing that works for many
patients and that's when the acceptance
will come
and what i hope is that
um if we manage to do that
in denmark as sort of a platform that
works well
um other countries within the eu will
look at us as a as a case
and take some of the
of the knowledge we have created um to
open up the markets there
thank you peter
in switzerland nima it's a kind of a bit
a little bit different situation you
have a very big recreational cbd market
you have kind of a small medical cbd
market in switzerland and as you told
before you have the
possibility to export gmp products
is there any
idea or do you know
would it be possible to export gmp
a cbd flower and products to german
pharmacies is there is there any uh
anything going on in the in this
direction
so me personally since we do not produce
the gmp flowers
i'm not really
100 up to up to date with that but i
would now assume that if if you can
register a medicinal product which is a
flower with
certain content of cbd and and thc
um
then you and it meets all the parameters
then i don't see really
an issue with that because i i was
thinking in german pharmacies uh the cb
we have a very
small range of cbe strains and
switzerland has a very big range of cbd
strains and a lot of patients in germany
say oh i don't find the right cbd strain
and i wonder why no company had the idea
yet to import medical great cannabis via
with a gmp production certificate to
germany because it's also paid better in
the pharmacy you know in switzerland
there's a very big competition on the
cbd market and if you can export to a
german
pharmacy or to a german medical market
the prices are much more stable than
what you have in switzerland and
then sorry what you have in switzerland
right now so
so you don't know anything going on in
this direction
um
what about cbd
flower production or
extraction in denmark is that also a big
thing
um
well i can't really speak for the retail
market or the cosmetics of fast-moving
consumer goods because we're not at all
involved in that
we're only focused on medical
and prescription medicine but
in that context with cbd that's also a
product that's going to be available
from us too so extracting cbd flour
that's cultivated under
gacp and gmp as well
but it is prescription medicine in in
denmark and
it's they're not allowed as a retail
product oh it's prescription medicine in
denmark so that also differs from the
rest of the european market kind of
doesn't it yeah i mean there is
obviously opportunities to buy it online
and and whatnot but um but no it's it's
not allowed under any novel food or
anything in denmark you see
products that it's that's extracted from
hemp
um
it's a it's him seed oil branded as cbd
so
yeah it's a little bit of a graystone
and i i'm i don't know much about it but
um it's not a it's not a huge thing in
denmark this retail cbd
as we see like two countries and two
very different circumstances as i say
and i'd really like to go a lot deeper
into it but time runs away we only have
i think four minutes left for this panel
and this is the time for the audience to
uh for questions so anybody who has
questioned him to me or the panelists
please it is the time for questions
i need my exercise
hello my name is renominio i'm from the
holland green science group
uh
you asked one question michael is why do
we have gmp anyway i can think of these
things but there was not an answer of a
straight answer maybe the panel can
answer that question
pete yeah
i actually believe that i i did mention
it
but know why we have gnp that's because
of the patients it's a it's rules and
regulations uh
embedded and directed from the
directives from the european commission
and the ema to protect the patients and
take care of patient safety
so
gmp i mean it's a it's rules that you
comply with it's a
the way you you build your company based
on on those guidelines and it's
it's consistency it's traceability um
it's patient safety really
well
he was asking if it's the same for the
recreational market and we don't have a
recreational market in in denmark so
we can maybe hear over here i can answer
this question
for example
the
market which is gonna be hopefully gonna
be built up in switzerland is planned to
be gmc
which is not as high as gmp
over here
yes uh hello my name is is martin
um mr nima maybe this is for you what is
the the difference between what you do
then what standard pharmaceutical
companies do for producing syrups or
medicinal shampoos etc because you are
only doing blending and packaging as i
understand so what are the the
difference in the regulations if you do
it with cannabis based products
um so we we are just
purely concentrating on on the filling
capping
blending
because for us in switzerland that was
the the most clear way we can go without
going into any gray area
and we wanted to
have a have a bulletproof business plan
and not hope okay novel food will kick
in will not kick in so basically we can
fill in captain anything it doesn't have
to be cannabis at the end of the day
that's like plan b in case everything uh
you know goes the wrong way basically
so
we we chose that strategy that in case
that route doesn't work we can do that
our lab also does analytics we also
focus on analytics and on different
cannabinoids we're working a lot on on
those because we believe in the the
different
compositions working together
and then we also have two other
technologies which will implement in the
laboratory and we are purely focusing on
that um especially in the cannabis side
and if i'm allowed to add i think
anybody should know when it comes to gmp
the packaging
is the most uh
the thing you have to invest the most
money in
yeah the production of course if you
don't make the production yourself you
just have to do the packaging but the
packaging is a very big investment isn't
it it's not cheap
any more question we have time for one
more question
apparently you're very comprehensive
okay then we are again the ones who save
the time for the next panelists so we
catch up the five minutes we lost before
i would suggest
and i thank you peter for being here and
thank you nima for being here i think we
got a very good information on gmp and
gmp practices
and maybe
let me ask you a very very final
question
um
how important is gmp to have cannabis
accepted by the
traditional pharmaceutical industry
well
i i believe that it's more that doctors
and the patient safety so gmp is vital
being a doctor having a
an ill patient with a serious disease or
being under chemotherapy or whatever
it's vital for them that that
that cannabis medicine is produced under
tmp
that's uh i would say that's the that's
the whole concept and the whole idea is
patient safety
would you agree if i say without gmp
cannabis had no chance to be accepted on
bicycle cannabis medicine has no chance
to be accepted on a broad range
yeah i would definitely agree
okay um thank you thank you nema thank
you pete uh thank you all for listening
enjoy the rest of icbc enjoy the evening
that was fantastic thank you so very
much let's hear it again