hi everyone pleasure to see you all
hope you're having a great time in
berlin as as we are and thanks to alex
rogers and everyone at icbc uh for a
wonderful conference so far
and it's always a pleasure to be a part
of their programs they really do a great
job of bringing people around the world
together i have a fantastic panel here
to discuss entry into the european
market so i'm going to briefly uh
say hello to our panelists here allow
them to introduce themselves we'll start
at the far end my friend martin martin
could you please say a few words about
yourself
yes hello my name is mark
i'm a partner of skw schwarz i'm a law
firm freeman people
i have 70 years history in germany with
a large international network also
working with tom very closely
i'm here with three colleagues of mine
that's julia margaret and oliver all in
the orlando hall and yeah i'm an mna
lawyer practicing for 20 years
venture capital m a private equity and
part of the cannabis team skw
thank you morgan and my dear friend
guillermo uh safety worldwide soccer
thank you my name is
we were following spain since 13 years
ago
and
we work around europe and
also some
in u.s
wonderful benedict can stigle
yeah so first of all
thanks for being here very great looking
forward forward to this panel i'm better
the co-founder and managing director of
cansativa canzativa is like really one
of the first companies within the
cannabis space in germany we're active
since 2017
and are the exclusive partner of b-farm
when it comes to the distribution of
cannabis from domestic cultivation
and our simple goal is that we want to
enable cannabis and become the largest
retail platform in the leading b2b
marketplace within the recreational
space thank you and sonia
um hello everyone it's great to be here
my name is sanja bonnevi and i'm the ceo
of new garden group
our business has two focuses and we have
one medical
gmp
facility
in north macedonia
and we have a second intelligent
facility here in the heart of berlin
where we produce
health and wellness products
as white and private label but we also
have
successfully positioned um our brand
hardness on the market and feel free to
come and visit us
downstairs thank you sonya and for those
of you don't know me i'm tom zuber i'm
the managing partner of super waller we
have many candidates uh in america since
2006 which makes us a dinosaur that was
uh i think we were probably the first
bonafide corporate law firm to be in
space or certainly one of them so we
represent a large percentage of the
biggest brands
um in
north american candidates and it's
pleasure to be here so let's go ahead
and get started uh with sonya uh sonya
uh this is a question for the whole
group let's uh start with you uh where
is the european cannabis market heading
over the next six twelve months
thank you tom um
obviously we all want to see
the recreational market opening
and following the the
public consultation hearing
which has been concluded
in the past month
i think the regulation is now heading
towards the final stages
and we will hopefully see a draft law
reaching the parliament by the end of
the year
the agenda is clearly very ambitious
and
but however there are a lot of political
and legislative hurdles such as the u.n
single convention
as well as
the shame treaty for example um and
yeah and i think that
i think the most important thing is
really
to see
government um
let's say establishing those social and
and health as well as commercial um and
taxation policies um
to be able to
um
let's say provide or secure
a functioning market
when
looking at the
the cbd industry
this is
let's say
it's going through quite a rough time at
the moment
especially in germany and simply because
of the very
complicated regulatory environment
non-foods is still an issue and
especially in germany we are still
seeing authorities going against cbd
products
and
which makes it really difficult for
companies to
to really deliver a sustainable business
model um
i think that um
looking at some other markets in europe
like like uk for example or um or the
netherlands where
cbd is tolerated but it's still sold as
a food supplement
they are performing much better
and even
the conversation that we're having now
with the uk companies they're all saying
that the market has recovered quite well
possible or post lockdowns especially in
the brick and mortar market
um but the the trend in germany has been
mostly negative and we're seeing
declining revenues
but also um
there's very little willingness um so in
terms of scale we're seeing very little
willingness um from the the bigger
retail chains to list cbd products
in absence of um legal clarity so um so
i think that
this is we're still far away um and the
normal foods um
process and then and everything that
is doing also on the toxicological
studies and so on i think this is this
is gonna take a while so it's not going
to be an easy fix we'll see how this
will this will evolve
um but
yeah but in general it's uh it's the cbd
industry at the moment it's not not
not an easy place to be i have to say
it's not impossible we have managed with
our own brand our risk together quite a
bit market share and even last year we
expanded to 30 countries and and we are
a place that's our say our products are
placed with the
major retailers because we have been
building a brand since the beginning and
i think this is something that is
very important and something that has
been neglected in the past in the cbd
space
and the the
we are seeing much more quality brands i
have to say on the market but i think
that as we move on and um as the
industry expands this will be even much
more important and i think those brands
who are those companies who are building
brands and who are building a compelling
story behind the brand will ultimately
be the winners
um in general i think when we look at
the the
market from medical perspective and
there is or in general just the catalyst
market there is still a lot of
stigma there is still
a lack of understanding of cannabis
um
the medical market in germany
is by far the biggest in europe
um but
there is only
still only two percent of the doctors
willing to prescribe
a medical cannabis there are different
reasons for that but i think it really
comes down to the to the legal framework
to the education and um and also to to
to people at the evidence that there is
just not enough although there is real
life out of evidence which is has a lot
of validation and it shouldn't be
ignored
but that educational process needs to
happen um
uh education needs to happen and also um
let's see a more simplified little
framework in europe
um
just to
be able to to allow the industry to
expand
um so
so yeah i think
for me that legal
clarity both on the thc and cbd side
will have to happen um and we will see
the industry expand and um which will
then hopefully bring the
the very much stability um
especially on the on the capital markets
thank you that was very helpful overview
and martin or benedict um would you mind
telling us doing a bit more of a dive
into germany what's going on here as
long as we're here uh particularly on
the recreational front what are we going
to see
over the next couple years in regards to
recreational candidates here in in
germany
shall i kick it off
so so first of all what was already
mentioned is we're like in the middle of
the legalization process which is
amazing um germany is like really the
driving force i would consider that
and
it might be that germany will be the
starting point for a whole domino effect
across europe so what we do here is like
really
a thing that didn't happen in history
it's huge we should be all aware of that
and when it comes to the german market
we already know that there is a existing
illicit market they are already
in on an annual base
400 maybe 800 metric tons
sold on an annual base
um trying to translating this into a
addressable market we're talking about
maybe four or even eight billion euros
as a addressable market when we use the
10 euros per gram as a
figure for
a ballot price
so the economic perspective is massive
and in addition to that
it is also clear that
the state
the federal republic they can benefit
from such a program
and i think which is good and what we
heard already today among
those great panels
is that everyone is aware of that
and i think
everyone here in this room feels this
intense
process already is excited about it but
me as someone who's like in the middle
of the industry
obviously talking to
politicians talking to other suppliers
talking to distributors talking to
pharmacies or potential point of sales
there is still just this aspect that we
need to to wait for some further clarity
so
a lot of things can still go wrong but
if we
have this debates these discussions um i
believe that also timeline wise what mr
lienert mentioned earlier this morning
if we have a draft law beginning of next
year there is a real
opportunity that
quite shortly after that we have the
first start of sales and that's
something i'm super excited about
and then what we also saw last week is
that malta luxembourg and germany
published a joint statement on certain
regulatory aspects of the
cannabis frame work which is also a nice
indicator that things are also
discussed on the european level that's
what also you saw you mentioned
during single convention european
law and all that and that's a good sign
and i'm very optimistic
very good and what's a short timeframe
assuming
that legislation passes early next year
it's a short time frame six months 12
months 24 months before we see the first
sales recreation
so it's really hard to assess because a
lot of
bits and pieces
are irresponsibility of the regulator
and of
yeah governmental authorities but we
have a clear commitment from our
government that within their legislative
period there will be cannabis legally
sold in germany that's what they
mentioned in their coalition agreement
so it definitely will be before
september 2025 that's a clear commitment
and if i were them i would try to make
this happen earlier to also have this
like
yeah
support for a future election maybe from
all the people not only in this room but
out there because i believe the society
is ready for it
indeed uh gyarados would you mind
telling us what's going on in spain on
the thc front
medicinal and if you if you care too
recreational as well
sure sort of thing
in spain medical regulation just just
happened
it will be implemented like
like in a year we are
one step behind from german for example
but that's a good news for spain the
medical agency has now like six months
to to study the health subcommission
resolution
and this medical revolution
revolution will allow people access to
cannabis and
with medical conditions like multiple
sclerosis sounds seizure disorders
endometriosis natural and vomiting or
chemotherapy
pain related to cancer chronic pain
including
neuropathic pain so it's believable to
grow in spain for
a lot of years but when this medical
regulation
is implemented pharmacy will be able to
dispense
to qualify patients the situation is not
as commercial
in other countries but
it's a significant progress and
for growth
and this is the situation now but keep
an eye on
spain because
the political party in power they asked
to my field to draft an adult
jewish regulation last year the
regulations would be imported as soon as
this year
it doesn't make it within that is an
important first step to lead more change
in the near future so let's see what
happened
wonderful and
uh why don't we stay with you uh uh
guillermo and can you tell us a bit
about the spanish cbd market and what's
going on
yeah of course
and
like the minority countries in europe
spain has not its own cv regulation but
there is a huge market above security
products in
in spain and
i think spanish consumers that's why
actually use cbd at much higher rates
than
other countries in europe so as i said
there is a really really big market in
there right now we are seeing a lot of
companies making moves to
establish their position in the in the
market ahead of
legal change in the future
i don't think changed after the european
court resolution on cv a lot of things
change something in a in a good way and
i'm going to spend
weekly like these three segments of the
mic we have you know we have like silly
flowers uh cosmetic products and
food supplements
talking about silly flowers and as i put
that there i have to tell you that you
still can get in trouble and you will be
cd flowers but there is a lot a lot of
demand for this product and
risk comes
with a good business opportunities also
i want you to know that we are being
successful in every single case we are
in every single location
on course because obviously yeah we are
selling a serious area
but acid flower is not
this psychoactive
is not psychoactive the public health is
not increased and this is what what our
judges and brazilians are starting to to
understand now
you can also if you want to see the
flowers import these flowers from any
european legal market and for you to
know if you have been explained
in a short video for in the last one two
years there is so many stores and city
flowers and thankfully this is not gonna
appear to be a priority for for the
police
cosmetic products and
cosmetic valve containing cannons were
never focused for
the police and even less now
after the
after european added cbd cbd and syria
to
all level ingredients in cosmetics i'm
talking about possibilities and as
everybody knows the european use for
cosmetic ingredients and about food
supplements i think that everybody knows
that i said already we'll have to wait
what happened with the european food
administration let's see that's what
happened but especially
really good place now to set up a
company you can do it quickly and
expensively there is a huge market there
is a present
a significant sort of
mid-term opportunity for growth
and for interpreters who are not afraid
of a piece of risk there is
another opportunity to get an
early foothold in the market with many
kind of users prior to further
realization and just regulates a really
good moment to think about franchise as
well
thank you guillermo uh it's very helpful
with you uh benedict uh do you want to
tell us the medical campus market is so
exciting uh to watch uh from the u.s
perspective here in europe um i'd like
to hear your thoughts on the whole
panel's thoughts but starting with you
uh
is the medical market here still
attractive from your perspective and
what um what is the right timing to
engage uh the european cannabis market
from both domestic
practitioners from domestic companies
and inspiring companies and also from
the international perspective looking
into europe
yeah so first first of all exciting that
you also talk about medical cannabis
today i think of many are very much
focusing on recreational but let's face
it the only
legal market for germany and many other
countries in germany is the medical and
cannabis market and the development
first
it's super exciting
how it started here in 2017. we were
talking about 1.7 metric tons
sales in 2017. last year we were up at
15 trans so it's quite a significant
increase and we expect for the next few
years a
further very positive development
however if we when we then
deep dive into
different parts of this german market
and i talk about the european market in
a bit we need to look at
patient
numbers of patients we need to look at
pharmacies and we
need to look at doctors first there are
around 300 000 patients in the general
market if we compare that for example to
canada in a world
pre-legalization of adult use in this
country there were figures like one
percent of the population
that seem to be pretty reasonable so we
have some uh potential here in germany
300 000 versus a potential of maybe 800
000 that's
0.1 and those patients are divided into
self-payers so very cost sensitive
payers and
people and patients that are under
statutory health insurance coverage
and this is important to understand that
the part of
those self-payers that are
rather constant price sensitive they
might transfer in a
legalized analyzed market maybe into
cell therapy if the offer in a adult use
market
is maybe cheaper and you have comparable
products so that's that's important the
second group i wanted to to look at is
the numbers of doctors and that was also
already mentioned
there are not many doctors actually
prescribing medical cannabis in germany
it's a limited number there can be still
a significant
growth
and this comes back to a
more professional application
which needs to be implemented and we as
an industry need to work
on and last but not least
i think it's quite interesting that out
of 18 000 pharmacies only around maybe
two or three thousand pharmacies in
germany are regularly dealing and
handling cannabis and
just maybe 100 are responsible for
significant portions of the market and
and
revenue and it's also
exciting to see that we have on each of
those
groups still a huge uh potential but if
legal legalization
of error use happens there might be a
effect however i still believe it's a
attractive medical cannabis market in
germany so there's still plenty of
opportunities to enter the market
however it's not like two three or five
years ago um where you just needed to
had a product and then
somehow you get
can can sell it you need to be smart you
need to really think through what's your
business about what's your part of the
value chain what's your value
preposition and then there's still a lot
of opportunity to make a good business
and for the european opportunity
obviously
germany is a bit unique because we have
statue health insurance coverage which
helps to like really accelerate
potential sales accelerate
revenues but we see in other markets
let's look at malta let's look at poland
um we see that exports are already for
example happening into those countries
so there is something happening and on
the other hand
there are suppliers cultivation sites in
denmark in spain and portugal so there's
a whole ecosystem that um developed over
the last few years and those companies
are also
making good businesses
it's wonderful any any other thoughts on
the panel here particularly as to the
timing when is the right timing to enter
the european market from the perspective
because others put inside uh inside it
um yeah
i just wanted to say i'm also thankful
to be here and i think the recreational
thing they will do it it may take longer
but they they want to have the tax
anyway so um but again this doesn't help
us over the next to 12 months
so this is the original question what
what is not going to look like in 6 or
12 months so
you know
middle year we have crisis going on in
europe we have a very
tense
macroeconomic climate we have
we're struggling with european finances
european central bank is not really
daring to put up the interest rates
to a certain level
because they say that the economy will
go down again so these are all framework
conditions that are not ideal for the
market not even in the healthcare market
it's not a b2c if we're talking about
medical cannabis it's not about it's not
a b2c business right here um but
nevertheless investor climate
is is decreasing it's getting worse and
yeah and we as m a lawyers we see that
we've been are told by the by the pe
investors what the climate is look we're
like like pre-indicators
um we're not driving with this but i see
what's going on in deal activity and
this is already reproduced
and and this is um i think it has to be
regarded closely but look that closely
we cannot say because recreation of this
is a good new thing
hey this is two years ago at two years
in the future sorry two years to go and
this will not help us immediately and so
the industry
has to face and also
companies willing to do business here
have to face that this is still a pharma
business it's a real pharma business and
pharma is complicated it's highly
regulated it takes long it requires huge
investment it
takes years
i mean investors have really bought up
the order into the infrastructure
already
yeah
so they they have this
um i would invite investors to go on and
and you know develop new um new um
medicines on cannabis spaces and we've
just had little products and the market
is not unlimited but it's still there
but the recreational will not help us
out of this out of this situation
um and nevertheless i'm confident that
this this industry will grow and
i mean in terms of the political
plan here in germany
it's good that we have this kind of
leadership in this area of cannabis i
would
hope that
government would show this leadership
maybe in other areas as well i mean they
need to drive this because the economy
in the world is not great at the moment
you know we have divided worlds they
need to help the industry move forward
that's that's my that's my that's my
view and uh yeah i hope you all can
contribute to that
thank you martin and mark let's stay
with you uh but this is really open for
the whole panel i'd love to hear
everyone's perspective
on this do you have any advice for
companies that are looking to enter the
european market and that's a general
question
yeah you get a general answer so i
cannot comment on the on the european
individual you know we have no harmless
market in this area apparently
so um i would just say um if we talk to
people willing to enter the market
well go to germany
it's the largest market it's well
equipped we have the infrastructure
and the infrastructure
also the players in this area we've
spoken about this before we have this
panel and it's already set you know
there were a couple of deals they have
bought in every now everyone knows what
to do the cannabis agency is working so
the volumes are not high but the
infrastructure is working so you can
settle here and you can use germany as a
starting point for a european expansion
i mean if you you have to be sure when
you come to germany of course apart from
the regulatory stuff and the the tax um
and set up you have to be sure what
product are you accepting are you gonna
be an investment company like a buy and
build company
so you know we know that in germany also
these concepts are pursued or are you
a developer are you are you trading a
mixture of everything in early stage
in early phases of a market this can
attract attention from investors but it
also dilutes your business case and in
the end investors want to earn money and
they want to have also key investors
they want to have a clear view
on the on the cash line yeah and if you
guess
i think there can only be one platform
or two platforms but not a third and not
a fourth fourth one you really need to
specialize you need to be aware that
this is a farmer
and this is this is really complicated
maybe i'd like to add some some further
aspects to
these points
you have the opportunity if you enter
the
medical cannabis market to learn a lot
about cannabis about regulatory about
quality systems about distribution about
sales channels about so many aspects
that are super important for not only
the medical cannabis business
but also for the recreational
um uh yeah cannabis system
that will happen at some point so i
believe that some companies maybe this
is a bit cash intense but it might make
sense to
enter the market to
learn to get
exposed to the mechanisms because let's
face it the adult use market it will be
a regulated market
we need to accept that it will be highly
regulated and we discussed some of those
aspects in this morning what if the
point of sales is
license dispensaries but also pharmacies
what if
uh marketing for products is not allowed
those are all things that
uh in
a certain
form we already have
existent existence in the
medical market so i believe exposure
here
can be worth and for us as a company
we're in the industry
you said dinosaur for the yes
we are maybe dinosaurs from germany uh
when it comes to medical cannabis this
is a real value proposition that you
have because you have a team you have
processes you have the knowledge and all
this is probably
one of those
things
that are super important
for the recreational world as well
that's great and anyway do you have any
thoughts on um yeah i think that
the cannabis market is um
no country there's absolutely nothing
transparent transferable
from territory to territory and i think
this is the challenge in europe that you
know
every single market is handling
differently but i think that you also
really need to be operational on the
market to understand how to work within
the confines of the existing legislation
and um and quite a complicated and
restrictive supply chain
so um and i think that you know
ultimately also in the recreational
business um
supply chain and for those companies who
are already in the supply chain have
built
a distribution network this is going to
be really really important it might be
different distribution channels but at
least
they understand the supply chain
and when you say nothing is transferable
market to market what do you mean
by nothing is transferrable market to
market because the the the
the legislative frameworks are
completely different in every european
country
um and
how
the license the imports and the gmp jsp
the products all goes into the
formulation and so so it's it's it's
very different to to to each market
um so that's what i what happened with
underscore that's that's a fascinating
topic to me because uh the united states
obviously is split up by by sovereign
jurisdiction over 50 states uh and each
state does it differently and
furthermore unlike europe you can't
put cannabis in the trunk of your car
and drive across the state line without
risking getting arrested right um so
europe is in some sense going to develop
a little bit like the united states i
think if it's okay to say that um but in
some ways it's going to develop i think
in a more exciting way with greater
interaction between jurisdictions so i
think sony at that point
it's worth exploring i think um that
where we're at exactly things are gonna
fall because of course you're right uh
markets market is going to be very
different but unlike the united states
you're going to be able to have
operations that distribute cannabis to
different territories within europe
way sooner than that's going to happen
in the united states which will require
federal legalization in the united
states so on that note maybe martin will
come to you weighing this one at you
first but this really is again for the
whole panel
if i'm a company outside the united
states outside of europe and i'm looking
to enter leverage from africa from from
anywhere else uh
where do i want to set up my holding
company what country do i want to be in
uh
and launch operations from which to to
send cannabis out to the other european
territories
in germany
yeah no
there's not one answer apparently um but
definitely i mean
there are a couple players with the
holding structure also in germany
and i think the couple of
aspects are important substance and
where is your focus this is not only
relevant for tax purposes so even if you
have a holding structure under the
european regulations the european
guidelines you have text of preferential
text treatment in a group but also then
you need to have substance
in the individual group entities you
cannot say it's just a shell or it's an
it's a post box this doesn't work
anymore you know it's like 20 years ago
and
therefore i'm
i think
germany would be would be a good start
and
if you have your substance in your focus
there if you want to control the group
from germany then germany is your place
to be also for for the for the holding
but if you are based in the uk or if you
are based in if you are original from
originally from north macedonia north
macedonia and you have a plan there
not a problem to have the holding
company there we've spoken to sanya
there are also groups that have their
holding companies
offshore
not really but in tax um
preferred countries like cyprus um malta
and
also the netherlands we know have a very
a rather low tax and corporate tax rate
also the uk and ireland have a low tax
rate so tax can be a driver but it
doesn't help you if your substance is
somewhere else because then it will just
um
put you really it will put you into
trouble and because then you may risk if
you have a permanent establishment
abroad and
if these are the two so where substance
and do you have a permanent
establishment um a fictitious permanent
establishment
a problem or
the wrong one in another country that
will put you into tax trouble so and
therefore um in in this regard i can
only advise
substance
um look at your organization where are
the people you want to you want to hire
what is an attractive market um
what is maybe the first place for your
product roll out and and then put this
all in a reasonable compliance regime
don't stop with the regulatory filings
also include a corporate compliance
system because otherwise you know um in
the journey it's particularly strict if
you don't have a compliance system you
are committing an offense if you are a
manager and you're not looking after the
system you can say this by my
minus two manager did that mistake i'm
responsible for what's going on in the
business and and that's that's basically
so we have a lot of flexibility um
but but these are the aspects i would i
would put in the center
um maybe i add some some color or
comments on
what we also discussed just before that
particular question with regards to
harmonization of eu regulatory
frameworks and also what you mentioned
cross-border and trade because what we
see already in the medical market is
that there is a product flow from
denmark to germany from germany to
poland from spain to germany from
portugal nevertheless whatever to
germany so we have a existing cross
border trade already and that's when
talking to u.s folks that's pretty
exciting i think and this is also a huge
opportunity and chance when we're
talking about the recreational system
because
harmonizing it across europe is probably
crucial
to to make it right
otherwise we may
end in a situation where we have
individual solutions in individual
countries and this will definitely not
not work out and at the same time it
gives us already in a existing medical
world quite a taste of how
a
inner european ecosystem and supply
chains could look like and that's pretty
exciting and here i actually disagree a
bit
with your statement that
things are not transferable
between territories i believe we already
have in the pharmaceutical world quite a
harmonized system as i said trade is
possible and a joint goal of the
european union should be to
adapt to that and adjust it and also
make a harmonized recreational system in
the future
possible
very good thank you and i'm going to
have a final question i want to leave a
few minutes for questions from the
audience here this is going to be an
open question for the panel we talked
about entering european market by way of
setting up company
what about through investment do you
have any advice from folks looking into
your from other parts of the world that
want that are considering entering the
market through a substantial investment
into an existing uh or soon to be
launched uh cannabis company in the
european market that's open for the for
the group here sonya or anyone else
and we have already several companies
producing medical canada in spain i
think the first company started growing
i started producing canvas
in spanish like
seven years ago and you have absolutely
security to
run your
your business and now as things have
become more like
friendly in
europe the spanish medical agency is
making it easier to
to get a lesson to produce cannabis and
why would be a good idea to come to
spain to produce
cannabis there is a low cost of
production
we have and as everybody knows excellent
climate to out to
outdoor cultivation and i wanna remember
everyone has the brightest price
electricity going so that's a disappoint
rapid approval process and opportunity
for first
mover
advantage at the market is poised to
open up after investigations very soon
and the market is not crowded
at all yet
so there's just like four main
requirements to realizing to grow
in spain you need a loi you have to sign
a loi with a medical
company
in spain also you have to obviously to
provide that and the seats or the clones
you want to work with are
certified clones or seats and just a
security plan and an engineer engineer
project that's all we can expect to
become a
cannabis medical producer
so anything we
could have
maybe try to add some
ideas on how i would look
into a potential in investment so i
would really look at what is the vision
what is the team
what is the operational track record
um and if those three items somehow
match together and i would believe that
this team is capable to really drive the
cannabis industry then i would believe
those are good indicators
for for a
potential
investment
couldn't make a bit more
just just maybe to act if you have if
you have an international structure if
you have a large player on the banker um
easier to invest because you know you
can make use of cost advantages to the
the the expensive dollar at the moment
so and you have
a longer value chain so you have more
flexibility
um but
another tip is only invest in what you
understand and the german market
generally the market that is a complex
picture so if you invest
speak to other investors co-invest
with with other smaller funds that have
already been invested in that company
ask them look at the due diligence they
have done you don't have to do your own
due diligence you know
very good and uh with that uh we'll
leave a few questions from the audience
here
all right
you got your hand up right away
please keep your questions to the first
four rows so i don't have to walk too
far i'm kidding
hi uh recording from macmillan's
listeners in london just a question
regarding
allegiance between all european
countries when it comes to
recreation which benefit you were
mentioning i can see that happening for
germany because germany has gotten
advanced
medicinal space but don't you see there
being a problem this is open to all the
panels
by having a recreational market in the
rest of europe where their medicinal
market has yet to develop don't we run
the risk of cannibalizing the medicinal
market with a recreational market that's
my question
you know i'll actually uh take a shot at
that just because i think there are
lessons to be learned from how we screw
things up in the united states in some
respects so so i'll take it from that
perspective
i was just having a conversation with a
new friend just maybe two hours ago when
we were talking about how in the united
states there was a shift in focus from
the medicinal market to the recreational
market and that's sensational in many
respects and it's very exciting
i've been very excited about that and
still am but there was something that
was lost too which was the medicinal
conversation it got lost in the united
states and that indicates that obviously
uh legalizing the recreational level and
that is a significant loss because
there's so much technology that god put
into this plant and we really don't
understand and and through all the work
on juvenile science nerds so we actually
love that stuff uh and love hearing how
this stuff not only alleviates the pain
of cancer patients for instance but
actually may help fight cancer i mean
that is just an amazing statement that
we have exploited and it is a wtf sort
of moment where you realize we just
forgot to really focus on that as a
nation and so i would love to see things
developed differently here in europe
where as you go to the recreational
market it's great to be able to buy a
drink to relax but it it is there is a
danger so and i agree with you there's a
danger that the medical conversation
will be lost here as it was in the
states and i think that would be very
sad for the whole world because this
this plan can do much more than helping
to relax it is medicinal it's medicine
and so thank you for the opportunity
just to talk about something we screwed
up in the us and i i hope our friends in
europe get it more right than we did
[Applause]
my question is what is your advice for
learning american markets to access
european markets and
what is your vision on the atlantic
american markets
maybe i take that one so
first of all the question
would be what is your business model you
want to bring
isu cannabis into the german and
european market
then my question would be
do you want to
do everything on your own meaning
building your own assets building your
own license sets and be a operational
company in the
target market or not
if the question is yes
build it
get
the funds get the team and go for it
if you want to go for a partnership
approach having someone that can
actually enable your market access can
take care of the nitty-gritty stuff like
distribution storage packaging
yeah addressing the point of sales there
are
some very good
companies that could help you um and
assist you and give you this room to
market
and obviously this is
one key activity of one of our business
units so we're very much
doing this as a daily business
hi guys i'm steve mckenzie
germany taught me about the role in
general and how it's going to develop in
the medical also
it's obviously a very big pharmaceutical
producer and what are the pharmaceutical
companies doing to support our
roadblocks and and when it does become
you know from medical and recreational
whatever what do you think the role of
pharmaceutical companies will be
moving forward
the rule
the role
what will they what can they do after it
becomes recreational there's no need for
the doctor to grow it
so
the
like exciting part of it is that
most of the companies in the
pharmaceutical medical cannabis space
are not big pharma traditional companies
so like probably the leading companies
they are not pharma companies from the
background
there is actually just maybe one or
let's say two players in the german
market that at least got some traction
and have a pure traditional farmer
background
so i
if i would look um to our competitors in
the market i would assume as long as
this is a valuable maybe profitable
business why exiting it so my first
statement would be that those that are
engaged in the medical market already
without a farmer background or a
traditional farmer background they will
stay and this is also something if you
look into other
countries like canada many companies had
a medical background but not a
traditional pharma background they
stayed they added recreational
activities and that's what i believe
will also happen in germany and the
second part is maybe
the
further
traditional pharma companies are getting
engaged in the market seeing this
opportunity but maybe not in terms of
manchester formulations but rather with
very traditional finished products
running through clinical trials having a
real market authorization but that's
like really the long-term game we're
talking about years we're talking about
ik protection we're talking about
significant and
heavy funds and this is probably the
space where those traditional pharma
companies have significant
advantages compared to other companies
that are engaged in space if i can i
think consolidation will tell
so
they will buy as soon as this industry
has developed they will not
try to copy paste business models but
they will
do them they will unfold every day
activity sooner or later
great thank you all very much
[Applause]