join us for the next International
cannabis business conference in San
Francisco California at the Hyatt
Regency February 15th and 16 that's the
conference we're having here at the
Oregon Convention Center it's the
international Canabis business
conference and Alex Rogers is putting
this on and just been remarkable a great
set a diverse set of vendors and a
fabulous set of speakers there's been a
great crowd a great vendors great
attendees the feedback has been
extraordinary I've had so many people
tell me that this is the best conference
they've ever been to and I'm here to
learn how to tell the future uh and uh I
think we're getting a lot of great
information the people here are great
and uh it's not much
stress and they have free coffee and
someone's walking around with sandwiches
the beauty of ICBC is meeting all the
activists lawyers um gardeners and
people on the Forefront of providing
medicine and good product to people and
patients very knowledgeable people
people from all over the world it's it's
been a great experience so far heard
some amazing things already um there's a
a congressman here who is speaking about
where the industry is headed where the
laws are headed federally which it is is
very important if you're going to be
investing in the Cannabis business my
name is Ed
Rosenthal and it was a pleasure for me
to come to this conference it addressed
the needs of the local people of Oregon
amazing the speeches have been
incredible I've met a lot of people that
have been great just making contacts
with different dispensaries and grow
grow houses and kind of forming
Partnerships we're here at this
conference to uh talk to Testing
Laboratories and producers and
processors about laboratory
accreditation and what it can do for
them and what we're about is about
promoting Organics in the Cannabis
industry magazine uh stands for
something defending our patients
everywhere the magazine allows us to
actually put
input and relevant articles out into the
public oh it's great this is our direct
target market really anybody who trying
to get into the Cannabis industry trying
to start a business trying to make sure
that they're doing things right doing
things legitimately that's what we're
here to do just to help the industry and
make sure everything's done and done the
right way give Al
Mr Rogers uh full credit because this is
a really good event I like it a lot we
I've got many good contacts and I hope
we will meet again they got a stack of
business cards here meeting a whole lot
of new folks that are just getting into
the business but also a few of the
business people and a lot of the
activists that I've been working with
here in Oregon for the past 10 years so
it's a combination of family reunion and
uh kind of a speed dating
session is just some of the things at
the international cannabis business
conference we're going to keep this
thing rolling join us for the next
International cannabis business
conference in San Francisco California
at the Hyatt Regency February 15th and
16th