[Music]
we're starting in just a couple minutes
so get in and take your seats
y'all
[Music]
this is the international can business
conference and many people who came here
kind of took a chance bought a ticket
wasn't sure what to expect right and the
feedback I'm getting is I can't believe
this I didn't know it was going to be
this good what they mean by good is
information and networking and just the
general attitude of the people here just
want to thank Alex and Anthony and gu uh
for putting on in a event that really
Blends activism and business uh in a in
a really really great way the Outreach
has been phenomenal people from Brazil
to Mexico uh Texas uh the West Coast uh
let's see Michigan and other places in
the country are here today A lot of fun
a lot of nice people with a lot of
information you can see the people kind
of go oh I hadn't thought about that
before it's raising a lot of
Consciousness about the social
percussions of prohibition and I'm not
sure that everybody here came in the
door worrying about that but more like
oh how can I make money or how can I fit
into the industry and I hear that
they're being inculcated with more and
more Progressive thought about why we're
doing this why we're fighting to end
prohibition so what's happening in in in
this situation right here is people are
a bit overwhelmed by the breadth of the
understanding that people have for one
another and empathy and and you know
this might sound like some hyy toyy uh
stuff to if you're if you're just a
businessman well I'm a businessman I do
well in the industry and I believe in
karma I believe in community I believe
in love and understanding and I actually
believe if you hold true to some of
those tenants and precepts that you're
only going to benefit yourself for so
many reasons and and in my case it's
actually helped me make money also so
it's this new win-win situation that's
happening uh with the Cannabis industry
uh in particular and I think that's what
people are very surprised about that
that they can make money they can be
successful and no one else has to to
lose all it's the fastest growing
business in America and I just want to
thank Alex for bringing the keynote
speakers that he brought the panels Dr
Carl Hart and um Ethan nlman and Rick
Steves and yeah there're celebrities
they get people in the door but they're
saying
really change happens when people get
involved in step forward and come to
conferences like this today check check1
two this is Unum NG AO 420 on Twitter
the culture editor marijuana
politics.com and uh we just wrapped it
up here at the international cannabis
business conference it's been a
fantastic time uh Steve Bloom from celeb
Stoner and freedom Leaf magazine was
here uh Steve D'Angelo was here uh Ethan
nlman from the drug policy Alliance gave
an impassioned impassioned speech about
what we need to do I mean as all the
suits jump into the business we got to
remember to keep the hippie ideals right
uh I've always proceeded from the idea
that the hippies were right and I try to
let that guide my actions uh but this
was a great conference what's
question we've had an amazing weekend
here at the international cannabis
business conference you know when we
when we started doing this or when we
had the concept to come up with the
international cannabis business
conference uh of course businesses is in
the title however we wanted to do a
whole ton of ad eacy politics and
culture that's our that's uh our passion
that's what we were pushing and we were
curious of how people would react to it
there's so many other business
conferences out there that uh talk about
Investment Banking or penny stocks or
whatever and we thought if we did a
business conference that was not just
focusing on on business business
business and money money money we
thought we were actually taking a chance
and people might not groove on that or
not get what they expect for their
highend uh ticket price well uh what's
happened in fact is people are actually
overly excited and happy that we have
decided to dedicate so much of this to
culture politics and advocacy and I'm
tremendously happy with the
feedback never doubt a small group of
concerned citizens can change the world
it is indeed the only thing that ever
has thank you for being a part of this
with
me
a