okay today we're talking about cannabis
legendary uh cannabis legacy is uh
something which is not always lovely
outcomes electricity although it also
has something with the future of
countries so please
allow me to also give an outlook on the
future of cannabis in that uh here in
that panel it's not only about the
history of cannabis but of course i
think we start with the history of
cannabis because we have two very
experienced
players from the cannabis injuries
industry here
we have
ben brockers from
amsterdam from holland from netherlands
he's a founder of fancy seeds and
please give a warm welcome again
to my right side douglas jordan is the
founder of uh connex it's the
jamaican cannabis expo which is uh
like uh similar like our congress here
like the icbc but a little bit different
garden will tell us about it later and
at least another bomb or spawn
thank you
and
before we start i think cannabis legend
and drunkards because
i feel really appreciate
i really appreciate it i feel uh
honored that i can interview you the
second time in my life thank you very
much for that uh
option
and ben will introduce his short history
of his long cannabis history the short
movie and uh i would say or in a short
video and i would say if i give the
microphone to ben and he can explain
this you can see all those there on the
monitor
okay yeah it's
this is somewhere i started
naughty and
dangerous sometimes
finding seats
all over the world
this is with my son ellen
the guy with the airplanes
um
this is also nice
we did give some awards and some
beautiful people got them
it's all in the museum to see
i'm sorry about this video because
somebody just put it together and
it's uh that is a barcelona museum
something really you have to go to
and um
we have a museum in amsterdam
here it comes
and it's already 30 something years
nearly 35 years i think
uh this is the scentsy seat in amsterdam
and uh this is the center city barcelona
next to the museum
it's a flagship
show
that's another shop in accident the
flying dutchman
the way we also
sell seeds i took that bread over from a
very close friend of mine
this is what we do
with the with the breeding
um
it's quite a big and it's changed a lot
since i was the breeder and my son
was the breeder so there's a lot of
change there's a cbd i have to tell you
something about it later on
important stuff very important stuff
beautiful stuff for the people
of course the protein and the the sack
of the seeds
is very much needed in the world
this is the museum in barcelona it's i
love it
we took nine years to renovation it's a
modernist building it was terrible when
we started
but it became really nice you should
visit barcelona is a nice place
there's even a beach you can swim naked
[Music]
it's a little city i love barcelona
um
so they make it a bit long i'm sorry but
you have some impression
for what we do
this is amsterdam
small but very very cozy and nice
objects inside
i collect
around 40 45 years
so i have a lot of stuff you know
we just make the catalog and it's nearly
9000 pieces it's
you have to be an idiot to collect so
much but it is so nice you know
it is the passion what is there
we do some
cannabis college people from all over
the world come there to
introduce there there's a group of thai
people that want to know
all about the hampton cannabis now you
know about thailand what happened
my son allen teach entitlement on two
universities
already a couple of years i think three
years and he got an honorable doctorate
in september from the university so
that's he teach campus
and he was also on the barricade to
legalize
happy what happened in thailand it's
amazing ah this is this is so beautiful
this is happening which we did flags
right
and it's so sad and it's a little bit on
it because hemprex helped his future and
no doubt about it
we have a company in holland for 27
years
25 years we lost that money a lot
and now finally we've made some money
especially with the cbd
and because of code and all the other
things is going down again but now we
make the insulation factory just uh two
years open two and a half and the
insulation is amazing you know all the
glass will the wrong rule
all the pollution they put out and the
energy it takes to produce it and now we
got this hemp wool and this
hemp insulation and the crazy thing i
never knew
we isolate for
cold here in europe and it's cold we
isolate good and then we're not cold
but hemp is not only for the cold it
protects much much better than
uh glass wall
for heat so
in our borders little stand you can see
how fast it takes out the heat and
it's amazing so this is the future for
hemp is absolutely there
even
you know we are quite industrial now all
financed by ourselves by sensing seeds
mainly
so we need also more investment in that
sense that if we really draw on if we do
3 000 hectares now
uh then we need to get investments you
know
uh what else i want to say you want to
can i go on or on yeah
well the other thing is there's two
things important
uh the first thing is i hear that
there's a there's a
sort of meeting now between different
countries hall and germany portugal and
another few countries and they want to
change their cannabis
rules in europe
and that is probably important because
cannabis
is a social cultural possession
that means
cannabis is from everybody
like a tomato
and from that point of view
you have to see that legalization is
very important soon and the best way to
do that is like the thai style you know
they just like legalize everything you
want to grow you grow you want to sell
yourself
whenever you do you do it
so that's very important
we received was also a new thing was
um
i was worried about already a long time
that you know all the cbt you have the
extraction
co2 attraction
full
and then you have all kind of different
distractions and you got the isolate
well
there is a big research going on on the
moment about the toxicity of
cbd in germany the ayah
european
organization
uh
study for more than one and a half
million something like that
and the first results come out that cbd
is okay for people
isolate not sure so i'm i'm scared that
isolate
will be again something that the
anti-cannabis people gonna smash us with
that always bear this terrible there was
even a new doctor's group now they say
cannabis can cause cancer
can you imagine and it's in the
newspaper again
one of the cures cancer it's proven so
it's a it's a funny world you know this
is crazy world so if you ask me anything
later i talk too much i'm stoned also
actually
thank you very much ben
let me ask you one question uh you
founded scentsy seeds i think in 1980
also said cc to 1985.
uh you were the founder of the first
medical cannabis company in europe not
everybody knows that because you're not
into that company anymore
and you're also founded one of the first
camp uh
fiber
hemp companies in the netherlands which
is hand flex
and now you have your cbd line from
scentsy seed and
my question to you is quite simple
what is morpha
to run a seed bank in 1985
or to run a cbd business in 2022
well you know
um
the difference is in in the old days
it was all
all
dope heads mostly only noped
who had the dreams like jack herrera
very good close friend for me
all these people that had their
ideal not only about
cannabis is a friend
but also the possibilities of it and
that's what you see in the museum you
know if you're talking cbd now
until 1900
eighty-five percent of its medicine
contained cannabis and i got a beautiful
collection of old bottles proven there's
something for uh euphoria is something
for uh
for hysteria this whole kind of cannabis
of old bottles is beautiful
oh nice
you see i'm stoked
hold on
so
in those days the guys they were working
with the pond
everything was the plant
you grow it you smoke it you sell it
you know you make some money here and
you put the money there again
and it was all about the plan
and for me it is still all about and i
know you guys a lot of people here
everybody
we need money we also netflix needs
money we show the money
everybody needs money so it's all
business just me
it's all business
but it's now
business about making money
it's not anymore and it has to be like
that
i respect it
you know i never expected that i'm gonna
be
a big example we have three factories i
just was inaudible in the insulation
factory
and it was running and the insulation
came out and i cried
it's so beautiful
we got it
and we don't have enough customers
and it's all
no subsidies and all this you know
yeah yeah yeah it is still the same
and we still want barricade it's not
there yet
and now they come with rules and
regulations you're over every way
and it's terrible the banks don't accept
us
even the bank in holland abn amro is our
bank
they take all the millions we got they
took it and they
okay we can pay your bills we cannot
borrow 100 euro
never
and they have a director new one
a special director for sustainability
so maybe you see my book meet of wonder
it's a beautiful book so i sent it also
to him
and i said to two thousand people about
the full seventh senate of
holland
the first and second chamber the total
city council from amsterdam from
rotterdam
we sent it to about 100 journalists
and we got one reaction from our people
from the politicians
they scared they're still scared of it
it's like oh you're you're stoned and
dangerous
wake up
let me know if you have been anything to
ask otherwise i can talk for days you
know especially when i'm still
uh let me know
here and uh
god comes from a country which also has
a
very big cannabis legacy which has
cannabis as a part of its culture
different from europe
since a long time different from europe
in jamaica where government comes from
cannabis
is part of the society
ever since one time in germany in europe
that changed the hippie area
when
before cannabis was known but not was
not very widespread so my question to
jordan is in which way
you found it
you're in the cannabis industry in the
legal cannabis industry now but how did
the jamaican cannabis legacy influence
the
industry are the development of the
cannabis industry in jamaica with the
strains with the growing techniques in
general is there is there any influence
or did you just make your grow your own
grow up your own business
um well i think from our perspective you
know when i started chemix it was
because
i saw a huge reaction in the market um
that was based in fair
um a lot of the traditional farmers were
scared that you're gonna have you know
canadians and just people from overseas
come in and take over the market
and there would be no space for them in
the industry
and
you know it was a very
it was to me it was very very impactful
i mean i don't have a
you know it's funny you you're bringing
all the legacy catalyst
here and i don't really have a lot of it
outside of a real deep-seated desire to
see
the caribbean thrive and what i saw was
on the horizon this
that we could get left behind to make it
get left behind all jamaica represents
for this industry
um culturally
um
you know how it's inspired
so many people around the industry to
sort of embrace cannabis embrace the way
of life
it had the real possibility of being
left behind being excluded
and that was something that really
didn't sit right wrong with me at all
and so my reaction was what could we do
to
ensure that did not happen
and i think
the biggest the biggest
thing we did that helped in that is we
decided to bring
to our conference to host a conference
first of all the international community
could see was at a certain standard
right but to then bring
growers from legal markets to come and
talk to cultivators in jamaica to bring
doctors from legal markets to speak to
doctors in jamaica and scientists and
business people regulators etc etc
because you know everyone's speaking
their the same language at that point
and i think what has been lost over time
is the deep history of jamaica with
cannabis and i'm very happy to have seen
this evolve
you know we're all experts until we know
something we don't know so we learn what
we don't know we all know everything and
i think what we have seen
is cultivators when they've been able to
be exposed to cultivators from other
communities other markets that have the
same
relationship with the plant the same
care the same understanding of the
energy that it represents then they
build trust and they can let their guard
down to say well and we saw the cannabis
it was uh sorry cannons it was so
touching
i saw and it's a guy from amsterdam
actually um
i forget his name was captain hooter and
somebody else but they sat with you know
we let a lot of the traditional farmers
come in um without charge so they can be
part of it
and on the first day they sat and were
sort of assessing their bug
and it was like what are you talking
about what's wrong there's nothing wrong
with my body i've been doing this
and then
because i saw the expertise the care the
attention the knowledge
then the following day here were these
two guys from amsterdam sort of um
critiquing some of the grow the
following day there's probably about 15
farmers waiting to talk to them to hear
for them to assess their blood and say
is mine better look at this one and you
know and it was a wonderful thing
because
when you break down these walls that
we've artificially erected
then you have this this energy that can
flow and i think
you know i i hear you know obviously
your legacy is way online but if there's
one point of coming in clean in the last
sort of six seven eight years this
industry
i have seen is that
yes it's a business
but if you try to do this business
without the essence and the heart of
what this plant represents
and i'm going to use some of the
colorful language you use because i like
to you're going to get
period because the plant knows what it's
doing and we have seen so many people
since we started mechanics running to
jamaica and yeah we're going to do this
and they promised the sun the movement
stars and the bamboozle people out of
their businesses and what have you and
none of those people today are thriving
in cannabis you know this plant has
taken them apart
spat them out and now you have to come
back to the reality that you can build a
pharma based business you can build a
therapeutic business you can build any
ancillary
business that touches this plan but if
you're doing it without an appreciation
and understanding
of how it can help people how it can
serve people
i don't care how smart we all are i
don't care how well we've been trained
you're gonna get eaten up and splat out
as it should
[Applause]
when when it comes to the european
cannabis industry you are part of it for
a long time
god just mentioned some fears
jamaican organic farmers and traditional
farmers have
and what do you think about the
development of the
cannabis of the
produce producing cannabis like cannabis
production in europe do you think the
people who should be in the position to
to produce cannabis are there or do you
think in general
we waste a lot of knowledge because it
cannot be used in public so far well i i
think
yeah it's a question like uh
do you still grow
tobacco in your garden you know you
don't
you buy it in the show
do you grow your own wine in your garden
you buy it in the shop
i
it will be that in the future it has to
be industrial so it
it's like you said it is for the people
so
but also one thing is for sure
quality conquers all and a lot of
companies like you mentioned
that
they can do any kind of things even the
biggest i hear i don't know names i
don't want to mention
but
the quality is not good so it's
it's like that
so it's always
about
the quality and
you know it's it's always difficult
because i never met anybody who didn't
say oh my god my grass is the best
it's always the best when you grow with
your own
so
grow your own the only thing what i see
is that
genetically you know there's so much
hybrids
and
i met a guy who was quite known
uh in the field and he said well in
america
it's 80 percent
your genes since you see genes in it so
it spreads out and that's good it's okay
and that's the best thing you can happen
but in the meantime there's a big
uh demand now bigger demand on the right
uh regardless so everybody wants
feminize everyone want these but regular
seats also you know that is still the
beautiful races a long time ago so
that's interesting
um when we talk about regular races when
we talk about selection of strengths uh
god
i want to know from you
um
i've been in jamaica
31 years ago and i know there were a lot
of collectors of strains already at that
time
strains were a topic in jamaica before
they were topic in germany i know in
netherlands they were also a topic but
is there a chance or was there a chance
to bring the jamaican genetics to the
industry or do they still grow import
genetics i no i have no idea about that
yeah
that makes two of us no uh
i think what what i've seen in jamaica
and what i hear in jamaica and you know
you know actually is very disturbing
i remember being at a conference in
vegas and a canadian girl actually told
me that they don't need to grow jamaican
genetics and bring them out of jamaica
anymore they're going to do it in a
greenhouse in canada
put the jamaican stamp on it and that's
the end of that and it was that attitude
that i just felt was so
it's it's just completely out of sync
with what this industry represents and i
think you know there's a lot of there's
a lot of work being done in terms of ip
in jamaica and how you protect the seeds
and genetics um where that sits today
it's still being still being developed
and evolved i think unfortunately for
jamaica we have not seen
yet
the kind of
progress in the industry that i would
like to see i think the industry is not
working as closely together as it should
to to affect the positive impacts that
it has
um you know why i like to go to all
these different international
conferences is it's a very sharp
reminder
of
the potential of the jamaican industry
again i go back to sort of the
references in the culture we talk about
brands all the time but what is a brand
brand is a construct of values that it
represents to a consumer
and
the jamaican brand quote unquote is that
because i have some friends
in this industry as they like to tell me
they were in this industry long before
it was legal
and they're shipped all over the world
and they tell me that they can tell
folks how to organize the banking they
can figure out everything
but you know
again we get so complicated and
sophisticated today
and this is what this is what one of my
friends said he said
let me tell you something see all this
strange strange train talk
back in the day we used to take all the
jamaican mead compress it together put
in a brick ship it off to new york and
you know the people would say
damn
because it's jamaica
and there's a this is a real in in terms
of the consumer and i saw this when i
was first starting this event
off
i went to la
and i told him i was going to do this
event in jamaica you know a ganja event
in jamaica the first person says to me
that's a idea like where are you
going to get the good weed from and i
was like what are you talking about i
start to get defensive but this man
had been to jamaica in the past three
years over a hundred times he'd been to
all the different cultivators all the
fields he knew exactly what he was
talking about
later the same day i go to a friend of
mine who's a music producer and he says
um tell him the same thing and he said
that's a brilliant idea
because the weed in jamaica is the best
in the world
now i'm hearing this both sides of the
he says to me they brought the game down
to record music
and from his first day he's like forget
the music we're smoking weed the whole
time we're here
and
why am i making this point because
on the seed side of it on the genetic
side of it there's a market just like
fine wine there's a connoisseur who
knows that product and who's going to be
able to sip that line and say this is
good and this is not good
but 95 percent of the consumer
it's it's a different experience
it's a different experience when you
land in havana and someone hands you a
hand rolled cigar
you're like this is
a cigar
when you're buying a quality cigar from
your little cigar shop in idaho you're
like yeah i bought a cigar and we have
to be very aware of what the whole brand
um experience is
not not to move it away from you know
the sort of historical nature of it but
those are the things that i look at with
the with a pure vision i learn a lot
from
folks who did it for as long as you have
and it's such a deep and rich history
that we must not let go of but i think
in this next iteration from my
perspective with this this industry is
understanding
what those things
potentially mean for today's consumer
you know i hear and i was guilty of this
in the beginning
we talk a lot about you know academics
being a commodity but yet the
interesting thing about cannabis is
cannabis can be commoditized but it's
also a finished product raw flour is a
finished product there's a consumer for
whom that is the finished product and we
as an industry have to represent and and
protect
these different ways of consuming
the cannabis because ultimately and you
get to where you talked about
you know it's grown
in your backyard and look at what we've
seen with alcohol and beer
we've gone from mass production to now
a real a real value for craft that's
exactly i i mean and
but you
talk about
quantity different different
and i said well i never met anybody who
would grow him his own he got the best
that's not with countries even jamaica
has bloody good grass
census seas have about around 1 000
different varieties
and about uh
400 we keep constantly alive so we still
have the same plants like 35 years ago
that is
important because
it's it's like wine you know you can
drink a glass of butter while you say i
like that you like that like that
and even with
everybody here we can smoke different
grass and everybody will pick his own
you know it is nice for me and medically
it's gonna be also like that so it's
always nice to try different
varieties i think and and then you find
the one you like the most you know and
that is but it's important still also
for the consumers
to have those choices i see now i hear
in america
you have two choices about 100 different
strains
so that's going to be difficult you know
to choose you
and the funny thing is
today you pick these and then three
months later they have a new name on it
and then so like shakespeare said
already what's in the name you know
and yeah quality is
number one and then and then you have
real something
that you can keep constantly the same
and it's important and that is what the
medical marijuana from holland is from
jack's heritage stream
it is super good it's superb
so i'm happy for the for the patients
they smoke that stuff
and of course they can't go to a coffee
shop and buy something else and maybe
they like it more it's also
so is everybody
different in a way
when you were collected seats in the
1980s
i remember i don't remember but i know
that you were actually the only person
who brought in indica genetics into
europe
there were only people bringing in haste
dramatics like the sacred seat grew like
shirt makers they were all bringing in
so
actually
i don't know if
the audience or in the industry the
cannabis industry knows
two or three
strains of your company are the basis
for any hybrid and for any any indica
indica cannabis which is now sold as
medical is that right that's it's
correct
um of course it's not us to do that but
it's true
well that is fun you know we were also
in holland the first would be the
cloning nobody hear about cloning
everybody always with seeds so that was
also a new development that right away
you know we could put a greenhouse full
of the same plants like wow
and before that you had all kind of
different plants so it was
but you know it's it's also true that of
course the new technologies now in the
laboratories are going on
they are far you know we are classical
breeders
right the old style and
my son ellen is already a step ahead
he's all i mean and now my other son
ravi they're working already in the lab
with all kind of stuff so it's going
really to scientific matter and it has
to be like it has to be industrial it
has to be business
like anything it's not anymore
under the table marijuana should be
legal open for everybody as a social
cultural
possession and
people should make money on it
in all kinds of ways with all everybody
you try to do and we all try our best
and so what we can do but we have to do
it for the people i think
you too
when i was
when i was a
young guy
and i was 18 years old i went to my
first coffee shops in netherlands it was
a very very nice experience for me
and i was kind of expecting
that netherlands is kind of legalized
someday in the near future
and
then
the whole situation changed in the 90s
it became
i thought it became clear the
netherlands will not legalize very soon
and
in the first decade of the 2000 i
thought okay netherlands will also not
be the first country in the world to
legalize cannabis because there were
other players on the scene which
were faster than the netherlands
so
you developed your business everything
in amsterdam at the center of the
european cannabis culture for decades
how do you see the future of the dutch
cannabis
culture and industry is it
like going down is it dying or can it
like come back again
i just wanted i hope that all that does
become stoned like me you know
because all the dots kind of smoke you
know
what the you know what to do um
you can't look in the future in that
sense because the politicians are
totally spaghetti you know they go this
way that way you know and they find
always something and so
it is hard to say that they make an
experiment now that density is going to
have
or something tenses you can have an
experiment that they don't buy in the
back door illegal anymore but now
they're gonna have producers and they
buy it legal
and then i'm wearing it you know because
i like the smoke hatch also if the
coffee shops only can just sell drugs i
wouldn't like you the other thing i
would like i can say
open the world and we can have the good
hands that i smoke in afghanistan
in my museum i tell the story that
the in afghanistan again he got about
two or three hundred maybe maybe
something like that at dollars a kilo
and the coffee shop financial amsterdam
it ends up into the consumer for 16 000
so couldn't we
buy
good afghan ash there for a couple of
thousands the afghans make schools farms
and
hospitals and we can smoke with them
wouldn't that be nice
and we also did not talk about uh the
american
hush yet because this is also a kind of
the market
supplying europe ever since which
until the early 2000s it was had 90
percent of the market now it went down a
little bit but still
it has all
big part of the of the german cannabis
market is covered by hashish for morocco
and as we all know morocco is
changing policies right now and i think
this would also be a very very good
chance
to bring morocco into the boat so not so
many people have to
die in boats you know because america's
industry is dying and a lot of people
are dying every day trying to enter
europe through morocco and i think the
working cannabis industry in north
northern africa it's not only about
morocco a work in canada with industry
northern africa would be a very uh a
very good reason not to try to come to
europe you know if we have a world
market and drawn in in the mediterranean
sea
this is a very sad situation
the same thing bombing now
ukraine
but the bombing yemen they born in
palestine
a part of syria still occupied and
drinking all
the streaming
a lot of
people died
and i was saying a long time ago and
talked my friend here
he said
let's bomb seeds in the world instead of
bombs
let's grow marijuana all over the world
let's
let's take this out all these bad
things that happen what how can we stop
it we can't we just can
try to do our best to be friendly to
people
and that is what to do it's politics i
don't you cannot talk about it anymore
you're wrong all the time
people don't know what to believe
anymore i don't know
it's just more and more to doubt about
it
but john let me ask you um i i would say
um
it's not possible to legalize without
politicians and it cannot stay like it
is so um
[Music]
we have to speak both languages
but you know you know the story in
america i was i don't know where exactly
you know
there was a senator who always wanted to
have more punishment more punishment and
the sheriff who convicted or uh arrested
thousands of people they have a growing
license now you know there's two guys
it's true right it's something
uh
[Applause]
do you have any questions
anyone have any questions before we move
on to the next panel
you've learned enough
[Applause]
museum
it is fantastic
um
do you have any closing remarks
if you go to the barcelona museum please
check the windows not everybody sees the
windows and
on top of the museum the windows are
really unique artwork
that's what i want to add
you