I'm going to talk about therapeutic
potential of acidic cannabinoids and the
cannabis and taraji effect I'll start
out with this statement first of all
that without cannabis plant and the war
on drugs we would not know about
endocannabinoid system
because the war on drugs and the idea of
sponsoring cannabis research that shows
that cannabis is harmful letters to the
discovery of the endocannabinoid system
and
without war on drugs we would not
witness the end of cannabis prohibition
either so it was in a way of
self-destructing war on drugs that is
now ending the second statement if it
were not for the endocannabinoid system
we would not be gathered here at all we
would not be interested in knowing the
relationship between our body and the
cannabis plant and I'm going to move on
to the city cannabinoids now this is
from Lithuania where we grow our hemp
wild organic where when I go I'd like to
pitch a tent there for about 23 days and
go nowhere else
we inspect our plans here and this is
from about I think three weeks ago it
was the beginning of September actually
so about four weeks ago about three
weeks before we harvested those plants
that were about 16 feet tall at that
time
hi my name is Kelly I'm really
interested in the neuroprotective in
capabilities of cannabinoids and I'd
like to know your thoughts on the acidic
or the natural versions of THC acid and
CBD acid for ya do you think they're
more effective and for treating things
like dementia and neurodegenerative
diseases like Alzheimer's or and Ann
dolls and secondly you know are there
any trials going on because there's lots
of anecdotal evidence about this stuff
and I'd like to hear more
it's a great question neuroprotective
effects of cannabinoids is you let's
start with the US government owning the
patent on cannabinoids was
neuroprotective
there is evidence and there is evidence
mostly for neutral cannabinoids THC and
CBD
there's evidence and all time disease
reduction of beta-amyloid plaques and
senile plaques in the brain so far it's
in in in vitro studies so have not been
done in humans in vivo and we should
look into apart from one Parkinson's
study in vitro there's nothing on the
city cannabinoids it relates to
neuroprotection when we think of
neuroprotection we have to think about
things like inflammation the brain when
the brain is on flames things are not
good when the brain is inflamed its
associated with epilepsy its associated
with dementia and so controlling these
processes that we know it controls
inflammation is very likely is what's
also contributing to neuroprotection now
if we look at human studies to my
knowledge they're very limited to survey
studies and I just learned that I think
tiller is doing a PTSD study so I think
that's also important to see what
results are going to come from from that
so it's a little bit of hand waving
about neuroprotection we don't exactly
know how it works we know that controls
the balances neuronal activity its
anti-inflammatory and those could be the
things that contribute to
neuroprotection