so hello everybody welcome back to
um
i guess cannabis technology
so i know that a lot of you are very
very interested in in these issues uh i
think today we're going to be discussing
the many many ways that
technology generally is going to be
if not has already begun to
revolutionize our business so cana tech
is a very very broad term
but what i'd like to do is start with
some
sort of to give you an understanding of
how broad this is and how
many aspects of the cannabis industry
technology effects starting with
legalization but beyond that we have
some very very interesting panelists
today with a wide range of technology
that's being deployed right now and the
impact on our industry is going to be
really really huge so
i'm going to start with a question that
i'd like everybody to answer in a very
short
um sound bite kind of way
what and where do you see technology
playing a role in the cannabis industry
and maybe everybody can give a very
brief
introduction of what they do and how
that's important as well
well hello everybody
i like what lisa just said
said something about us all needing to
work together
we are integrating things we are
integrating technologies and you talk
about the technology i think this is the
perfect place to say that
we can all drive this forward
both
on the product as well as the
technologies used to actually grow
cannabis and so
this is a very interesting topic and i'm
very happy that she brought that up it
we're in this unique place that we can
all work together and i i love that
opportunity um technology itself can
help us
create new products new chemicals well
mark can you tell them what you're
you're in grow tech right what does that
mean exactly so we grow
we
create
facilities to grow
cannabis
and food and vegetables
and we
think about sustainability i want
as my mission i belong to the 60 plus
that the previous speaker talked about i
want to make
the world a better place for my children
and all of your children and so
sustainability is one of those
possibilities that we want to push in
order to have a more sustainable world
and that's what we're trying to do okay
so i'm going to actually bounce over
here to lucas because he's also in
grotech although from the american
perspective um where do you see
technology playing a role in grow tech
and how does that use and and why is
that cool
sure so you know i think it's a very
broad uh question but it is something
that is very important to the industry
moving forward and
i think a lot of times what we we look
at is new technology and it's not
necessarily that we always need to focus
on the new technology on the cultivation
side of things it's also
addressing
new ways to address old challenges right
and i think in the cannabis industry we
have a lot of what we refer to earlier
as the black market i like to consider
it as the legacy growers right is
understanding
where they came from this plant and and
really how we learn from that and build
it into a commercial optimized uh scale
so that we can have a consistent quality
product going forward for both the
medical and for the adult use markets
so zia you're also coming to this from a
very different
role with some very very new technology
used in new ways but generally what do
you think technology is going to mean to
the cannabis industry from your
perspective
yeah thank you
oh um we are coming also from uh
software development and we were
developing different technologies in
fintech and healthcare technology
and we saw that the industry is in need
of new technologies from the software
technology perspective and that's why
there is a huge perspective uh in just
to to move forward and to develop uh new
technologies indeed in the software
there are
a lot of done but uh
a lot much more can be done in
cannabis industry well actually you're
using a technology
artificial intelligence and you're not
the only one up here that's going to be
using ai can anybody else talk about why
ai specifically is going to be very very
useful to this industry in several
different ways i mean maybe starting
with sales right yeah i mean just a
short hello merry uh is a
like traditional e-commerce platform
what we did uh we added uh we developed
uh
ai-based voice assistant
which brings the level of the customer
journey in different level whether you
don't have to
and all information which is in the in
the in the verb or in their uh
let's say data they will be given to
customers or to doctors or to
just the person who is looking
information very fast that's what
we see the technology is to bring new
technologies to the industry to help
and contribute
so what about you to be as you're coming
this from something a little bit
different nanotech which is really out
there
what what does canotec mean to you
nanotech sounds extremely fancy many
things
to come back to the start um technology
is always an answer for a problem and
three years ago we defined the problem
our visionary founder mr targa deibus
defined a problem and that is the low
bioavailability of cannabinoids and
there was an answer in the scientific
literature
drug delivery systems predominantly used
in the pharmaceutical field and we
adapted this technology to make a
carrier system that helps your body
absorb cannabinoids faster to a higher
extent and with longer lasting effects
and one thing we combine our carrier
systems with uh synergistic combinations
of active ingredients to get specific
effects with high bioavailability
cannabinoids so i think you can see that
everybody up here is using technology in
different ways to make their jobs easier
as my late uncle peter drucker used to
say technology is great but it's just a
tool and if it doesn't achieve your ends
then don't use it but let's do a little
bit more of a deep dive into some of the
specifics
what i'd like to focus on is you know
what exactly is grotech is it about the
breeding of the plants is it about the
building is it about the tracking tech
is it about automation is it about
sustainability the two grow tech guys
what what how does that work sure so i
think i think there's really two silos
that that really fits in the first is
going to be in automation as you
mentioned
and that's really in terms of driving
down the cost production producing a
very consistent clean quality product by
leveraging that automation um on the
front end of the cultivation side of
things um the other silo is really going
to be on the techno the technical side
in terms of data right so how are we
actually growing these plants what are
the climates that it's that it's
thriving in um and what are the climates
that are creating stress and um you know
informs for pest disease pathogens
things like that right so i think it
really comes down to you know how we how
we gather that data how we
translate that into information and then
use that into insight for our our
growing needs well we have we actually
this is great basically we've got an
american grow tech and a german grow
tech so so i'm going to also then throw
this out to mark how do you see this
kind of technology aiding in the
assistance of say meeting high
compliance standards like eu gmp or gacp
or sustainability etc etc
the wonderful thing about technology is
that you can combine
what nature gives you
for example the sun
with the technology to control the
environment to make plants happy it is
in the end we all want happy plants
because they give us the best product
and so the question is how do we how do
we make the best combination um with
that we can use ai
to control the climate to pick the right
cultivars
to grow the best plants in the shortest
amount of time to make the most of my
money and that is a business conference
here and so we're trying to do
the best we can with the technologies
that are out there and then we're
developing and pushing these
technologies that don't only apply to
cannabis they will also spill over which
is really exciting partly in the food
industry and food production
as well as into climate control etc for
for housing for example and skyscrapers
and all of that so this industry is
driving
a lot of parts
into our society and it is exciting that
we have the opportunity to be part of
this forefront of a new technology that
is emerging well i think every there's a
theme here which is the technology is
being combined so i'm going to throw
this back to zia who uh hello mary is
actually you know uses uh ai to create a
customer journey that is really
different and i think in general ai is
like the future of sales in general but
why is it so important to use something
like say medically trained ai and
cannabis in a sales application
um yeah as i mentioned we are our team
coming from healthcare
digital healthcare and when we see their
perspective of using
as we discussed before data
i mean
using ai or new technologies in cannabis
will give us
much knowledge to
develop a
current market to
to develop new instruments for medical
cannabis i mean medical cannabis is a
next uh
kind of there will be a fusion of the
digital
technologies with medical cannabis
that's one of the products we're
developing as well where we'll have uh
the the data will be used explicitly for
that purposes now we're working also
with one
software uh developing with one software
where we'll get
medical data from variable devices
this is part of our
product development and that
information will give
customer uh
will be kind of a breached in the
telemedicine between custom patient and
a doctor if the doctors want to see how
the specific cannabis or those or strain
affects to the patient that's i believe
it's the new future and we're also
working on that
so so i want to flip back over to bs can
you tell us in layman's terms what
exactly nanotechnology is
i'm relatively sure i can try
um
basically if you are in a
certain size range um below 500
nanometers depending on the definition
then people speak about nanoparticles
nanomaterials
and
if you have sizes that low then some
physical parameters change giving
interesting opportunities for new
technologies
so so when you are you using this with
what bioavailability can you give us
a sense of what you're using
nanotechnology for
again i try my very best
let's start with the term
bioavailability
it describes the fraction of active
substance that you take in that is
actually absorbed by your body in
contrast to the amount of substance that
you take in and that is metabolized and
released without being used and for cbd
the official who number is six percent
meaning more than ninety percent of the
cbd you take in simply goes to waste is
not used by your body and this is where
we come in with our technologies we help
your body with absorbing cannabinoids
and other active ingredients by
transporting them them in nanoscale
lipid carrier systems okay what what
does that mean in english right
milk is an emulsion
two immiscible liquids homogeneously uh
dispersed now you have an oil droplet
and you make it really really really
small
50 nanometers you fill this oil droplets
with cannabinoids
and stabilize it
um
within so-called emulsifier
so that's like mayonnaise basically
right
exactly
okay
and
those small particles they give the
active ingredient a huge surface
between oil and water and they
they help these active substances to
transfer into the aqueous phase for
example in your liver or into your
gastrointestinal tract
and provide a huge surface for
absorption by mucosal membrane so it
makes everything more efficient
basically right
you can sum it up with that word yeah
awesome so the next thing that i'd like
to get to is the idea of technology in
personalized medicine which i think
everybody up here is involved in in some
way and we were actually talking about
this in the green room i mean when it
gets to that point obviously you'd be
able to have
a system where you can find the best
medication that you need and maybe back
that into a plant which is growing you
know a greenhouse or an indoor grow
which is growing for people who need
that and then it's put into some sort of
you know high absorption nanotechnology
but um where do you see personalized
medicine cannabis and technology
crossing
and how
oh uh good question actually that's uh
that's exactly where we say ai can play
a big role to to find um
personalization of and finding a product
uh that the customer or patients are
looking for
and we just observe how
high tech is
developing in not only in software also
in the hardware and cannabis hardware
yeah i mean we were discussing a few
days about this high-tech vaporizers
just to see to find a personal
uh
dosage or personal use how they can help
that's uh i i believe
uh not on the software but also hardware
will be play will be playing a important
role because other industries they're
already using it's just have to
uh
get more attention and i believe with
the legalizations will be more attention
to bring available
on the market technologies to the
cannabis industry lucas you're coming
from the american market which is very
very different can you see a time when
say in colorado there's going to be a
green you know a section of greenhouses
that can grow your own personalized
medicine is that
feasible viable how far away is that
yeah so i think it's a great question i
think you know what it really comes down
to is is driving two things is the is
the genetics right and and the
cannabinoid profile that comes from this
plant and and specific genetics and the
consistency and the cultivation they're
in right um as we refine our practices
downstream of harvesting um we need to
ensure that the product that we're
producing before that harvest is is
consistent right and and we have a
consistent basis that we're building uh
for this post-harvest processing um as
it gets more complex right and and if we
are going to um which i absolutely
believe enter more of a medicinal market
that's specific to each patient
and we can hone in on those different
aspects of different genetics and
different cannabinoids
the cultivation absolutely needs to be
dialed in and that's where we really
need to leverage that technology that
automation and those systems
to really refine that environment right
and then build this build this genetic
code within the plant as we cultivate it
all the way through harvest so that
everyone on the back end can can use
that precision
to to really refine it to each patient's
needs so from from colorado to germany
can you see personalized medicine within
an eu gmp framework and how do you think
that that might work and be aided by
technology
well
we're happy that gmp and gacp is going
to be pushed it's it's helps us all
to create better
plants healthier plants
and
have a consistent process and we're all
into that we also have the possibility
using ai to actually looking at the
chemicals and how to infect these
chemicals by changing the climate just
like lucas has said that the beautiful
thing is for me as a chemical engineer
like the old saying you give a kid a
hammer and everything looks like a nail
but once you are
a chemical engineer you look at the
plant not as a plant necessarily by the
chemical factory so which
changes can i make to the environment to
create the changes in the plant that i
would love to see
we need people
like to be us to tell us how to
what they need and how to actually
deliver those chemicals and that's it's
an exciting prospect to
change things still holistically
not talking about
isolating one specific
um
chemical but
having still a plant that creates a
holistic
medicine and so
in that scale you have to use
massive amount of data to actually
create what you need to do and that
takes
technology so to be as i want to sort of
get into some of this because i think
that nano is absolutely on the front end
of personalized medicine can you talk a
little bit about not just the
nanotechnology but things like patches
and the things that you're doing to
bring
cannabis as personalized medicine into a
medical stream that can be used
talking about a vision yes many things
what is important for personalized
medicine i would say is that you control
which substances you give a person okay
this is quite clear but how much is
applied and if you look at the
the the body them
as an individual system it is hard to
control how much of a substance is
really absorbed taken in and there comes
nanotechnology
in play and especially what you
mentioned patches with patches you can
control how much substance is
applied to a person with the right
combination of substances according to
the needs of a specific patient you have
personalized medicine the right amount
over the right amount of time
that's awesome so so a lot of you guys
were mentioning data so now the next
question is
what is the role of regulation and
compliance within tech and gdpr is just
one of them but would anyone like to
take that one on first
oh well i can take a stab at it um so so
we work uh pretty heavily on the um the
gacp and gmp side of things uh largely
with our our lp clients up in canada and
with some some of the clients who work
out here out in europe with and
the large uh portion of that is in the
process flow right of how people plants
and products move throughout these
facilities and tracking that a lot of
gmp compliance and and gacp compliance
come with a chain of commands right
understanding really what happens in
these facilities and what happens to
this plant throughout its growth stages
um and and leveraging technology to
gather that data so that we can create
that chain of commands right and we can
we can show that very clearly throughout
from seed all the way through sale so
ziya i mean this is also an issue right
so so your system is going to be using
ai but potentially can be pushed to very
personal devices and wearable devices do
you see privacy and gdpr being an issue
and beyond that what other regulatory
issues do you see
crossing into this space
yeah i mean it's a big issue the i mean
we are german-based company but the
reason why we are going actually to
start at us of course it's the biggest
market market another reason is because
of the regulations uh i mean european
gdpr regulation regulations does not
really allow personal assistant
to uh suggest you
you know a product uh that's a big
problem with voice assistant we can't
get to that it's like medical device
license we can't get to that and we have
we are planning to to go uh for that but
in the beginning it's uh
us's more liberal market for that uh of
course there are their own limitations
when we are talking about uh
recreational and medical cannabis and us
drug not only government limitations but
also different corporate limitations or
banking limitations what we are like
facing uh once we're going to such
market but uh we feel how it changes
that that really i mean recently
from our perspective uh for instance
apple was
not really supporting
cannabis based applications recently
they just issued that they are like
welcoming now uh applications which are
considering also cannabis so we
we observe to change how uh
not only legislation is changing but
also uh
corporate policies changes in the
positive side which is good
so i want to come back now to tobias you
know nano is interesting in and of
itself right especially in europe and it
potentially could really sort of stretch
the edges of things maybe you can
explain a little bit how that might be
or in terms of i mean if you have you're
using a new kind of technology like nano
and it's delivering cannabinoids into
the cellular level i mean you're
starting to talk about manufacturing at
a cellular low level in a human body
which is pretty wild right i mean that's
also pressing certainly in europe there
are all sorts of laws that discuss those
things um can you comment on that and
and sort of where you see your
technology developing in a strange
regulatory space just because of the
unusualness of the technology and how it
impacts the human body
yeah interesting question
give me just a few minutes and i answer
in two points first the definition of a
nanomaterial given by the um
[Music]
eu regulatory
now the framework is um the definition
is if you are below 100 nanometers
if you have a solid
and if it is not biodegradable then you
have a technically produced nano
material and this needs extra testing
safety standards so on and so on which
is needed
if you have a nano scale metal inside of
one of your cells it can cause oxidative
stress
inflammation degradation of proteins all
sort of problems that you do not want to
have
now for our systems they are in the
range below 100 nanometers or carrier
systems but they are liquids and they
are absolutely biodegradable because we
build them with regular food ingredients
plant oils lecithin as emulsifier and
some other substances and those
particles they they don't
they don't cross the barrier of your
cells they don't really go into your
cells they help active fat soluble
substances to be transported into your
cells it's a different different way of
of transportation
so we are not producing nato materials
according to eu regulations and
there is no harm in our carrier systems
because they follow the after
after releasing the active ingredients
they transport they follow the standard
route of digestion
so i'm going to throw out another one
because that's actually for those of you
who've been wandering around outside
there's a really cool 3d printed
personal oil maker which is pretty cool
but i want to sort of come back into
this idea of 3d printing
how and where do you see 3d printing
making an impact on this industry
generally and why and where maybe we'll
start with tobias i mean could you 3d
print your patch
to be honest i have no idea okay that's
fine is anybody else like on the
construction side or the greenhouse side
where can you see 3d printing playing a
role or not
i i mean i think it would be tough i
think where where you may be able to see
it as maybe in sensor technology
possibly um to where you have you know a
small let's say something similar to a
raspberry pi right where you could build
a modular around that and be able to
mass produce that off a 3d printer
you know there's you know especially in
our world we try to
streamline everything we can when we're
building out these facilities so that
there's not very customizable very hard
to get pieces and parts but in the event
that there are that is a lot of times
where 3d printing can be leveraged
awesome we want to throw this open to
the audience so if anybody has questions
can you put your hand up and we'll try
and get a mic to you
anybody now
i have already a question here
oh there you are i didn't see you
i should wear my glasses more often hold
on
well first thanks a lot for the inside
was super interesting uh i would like to
go further or a bit further into
i guess more of a feel where tobias as
active
because like you've been talking about
cultivation and it's about distribution
and so on i would be interested in what
perspective or potential would you see
for new technologies in certain drug
development like
new
yeah stuff like youtube basically you
know nanotechnology whatever do you
think there would also be possibilities
to improve i don't know whatever you
name it flowers or
different new extracts or
do you see other potentials of
technology in making new
cannabis drugs
i didn't only ask you by the way like
you all can ask anybody i think could
ask to answer that one i think
yeah um
i believe it's
it can have a huge impact i mean if you
look at the uh growing or using
technology and growing it can be
you know from the light
that's adopted from the air
clear climate which is adopted and we we
heard a lot about ai being used and
not only optimizing but that's also
optimizing growth i mean if you go to
the uh more we were discussing yesterday
with one company here also that uh
they are
trying to uh
communicate with the uh
with the plant uh and and crack uh
the and and uh manipulate the
growth yeah that's the
more or less biochemists uh by cracking
the the growth of the plant i guess
there's a lot has been done in other
plants and
again it will come it's coming
and will will be entering to the
cannabis growing as well yeah and
i'd like to answer that too i i want to
add
that we're now at about
production cost of
a kilogram of the highest
flower quality that you can buy
at about 500 euro per kilogram
um and i don't know if that's a high and
low number around here i i would assume
that for the highest quality that you
can buy
that is a pretty decent price
for production all in meaning facility
and depreciation all of that in
that number will come down because
there are new technologies
that will reduce
the price of
growing and it will
increase the yields
both of those are happening they're
continuously happening
ai adds to that so that that number will
come down
in part it has to because prices will
come down too
not quite as fast but we are looking at
that
at any time it's always how can we
produce
better
at a lower price and technology
in fact we could go into many different
ones it comes from the water delivery
system nutrient delivery system that's
all you know anything about
knowledge about the
temperature and humidity in your grow
facility the drying process
all of that is continuously evolving
we have never built two of the same
facilities because there's always new
things coming and it's really really
exciting and what other place can you go
where you can just continuously innovate
and it's really that's fun that
so thank you for that question there's a
question here
yeah it's a it's a comment on the whole
3d printing discussion
my name is peter i'm from from the
danish company drizzle and we create
small extractors designed for for
personal use so the end user can do
their own
customized personalized cannabis oil
and we've managed to get a complete
extraction system down to this size
about two kilograms and doing so has
required a few innovative steps and one
of them has to do with plastic and 3d
printing now we've really investigated
into using plastic instead of stainless
steel
because stainless steel is super
expensive to work with and it's kind of
the go-to thing when you do
chemical processing but we figured out
how to use plastic in chemical harsh
environments and
once that was in place and we could do
that in a food safe
environment the next obvious state for
us at least was to do the entire thing
using 3d print
and that has actually led to some really
interesting
derivative advantages in what we're
doing and there's specifically three
things when it comes to 3d printing and
3d printing in production that we've
discovered
and the first one is innovation speed
when you do stuff in stainless steel you
need to have someone do the drawings you
need to mill something out you need to
test it and ship it blah blah blah blah
it's expensive and takes usually up to a
month if you 3d print you can sit down
over a coffee table sketch something out
print it test it in the evening figure
out what's wrong with it and next cycle
the next day so instead of having
iterative cycles of one month you're
down to one day so really
charges your innovation speed i'm
actually going to interrupt you here for
a second but i mean that actually i was
showing that product to a gmp
distributor here in germany and his
first comment was yeah it's really cool
it's 3d printed but actually that's
technically illegal here in germany
right so i mean that's one of those
areas where i think that i mean as much
as i mean it's a personal discussion
right if you're going to make canada
butter in your microwave versus using
your you know your system but i mean
that's i think a place where technology
is also crossing into a new regulatory
environment so people can actually make
oil at home more easily but how does
that then become a standard that the
medical environment that the medical
community can accept those are many many
different questions i think that's
coming together
with your product so i'd like to sort of
we'll come back to you but what i'd like
to do is sort of open it up to other
questions here unless you had another
point to make i had two quick points i'd
like to make and and the second one was
size because when you 3d print stuff you
can put in details that are impossible
to make with other production methods
and that means that you can shrink both
size and cost of your products and
that's important when you do consumer
products
and the final thing is production
because it's quite easy to set up
scalable production facilities with 3d
print you just need a bunch of 3d
printers so you can set up clusters
let's say we want to produce in the us
you can just set up printing farm in the
u.s asia and this send send files and
you have the exact same production
globally so you kind of have a global
and local
approach to production that's really
interesting to work with
so
okay so i'm gonna have a quick round
robin here and i'd like you guys to do
this like really fast what are the
biggest challenges and opportunities of
technology in this industry like a
sentence
for me it's ai and the
appropriate use to to develop better
methods to grow
generally research science is awesome we
need to find out more new things it's
frustrating because often things don't
work and it's expensive because it takes
time and it's challenging to explain to
future customers or partners why it is
necessary to do research when you do not
know what will be the outcome
i think it's
keeping focused on the goal ahead
not reinventing the wheel and leveraging
parallel industries to
further this cannabis industry into the
future
i believe right now legislation and
limitations that's a big challenge
for for canadect to be developed in the
level where it can be developed
not only in tech but in general cannabis
industry i see that's the biggest
challenge actually are there any more
questions
okay so i'm going to actually come one
or maybe our last question what do you
see the role of technology in research
and development of new drugs generally
if not the advancement of understanding
of cannabis
sure i can uh i can start up so yeah my
background's actually in commercial
vegetable production before i started
growing cannabis and you know i think a
lot what needs to be focused on now is
largely on the cultivation side but more
specifically is on the genetic side of
things i think there's a lot of um
mis understanding around really what
these genetics are and what sort of
cannabinoids they produce and what sort
of environments produce those
cannabinoids of that genetic right and
so i think a lot of it needs to be
focused on
gene editing and understanding these
genetic codes that we have and and the
cultivation systems we use to identify
these things and bring them out in this
product it's an amazing flower that we
have but it really comes down to the
cultivation side of things and the
environment that you put that plant in
to allow those those genes to come out
okay last call any more questions from
the audience
no if you have burning questions you can
look us up later but what i'd like to do
is end just a little bit quickly unless
anybody would like to have last closing
comments generally about technology or
what you're doing with technology that's
cool and awesome that we need to know
about
i uh yeah i i'll i'll say
sorry i feel like i'm talking a lot here
but um automation so i love automation
it's the when push comes to shove the
industry needs to commercialize and it
needs to optimize itself and that comes
down to as mark was referring to as cost
production
we really need to adopt things that
we've learned from our dutch partners in
terms of bringing plants to people and
not people to plants right we need to
limit our human touching as much as this
is a very artistic thing that is for you
to do
at home right but when we're doing this
on a medical platform on a commercial
platform we really need to leverage
technology and automation and those
systems therein to create a consistent
quality product for the globe um and i
think that's really where we focus on at
urban grow is is leveraging that
technology those systems and integrating
them all together see do you have any
last comments there about
oh
um
yeah
i guess we mentioned that we
we see
new technologies being part of their
industry and
with i mean
software development
and hardware development will be
one of the main stuff which will be
happening
[Music]
this side anybody
i think what i'm seeing is that we're
still only
maybe 10
of the way of where where technologies
will will go in the following years we
made a lot of progress but there's so
many new things happening every single
week
and
that's to do with lights and nutrients
and everything
this industry will change and it's
exciting to see a change and get better
and i think
that that certainly ends
with fewer diseases fewer pest pressure
it will get a lot better and
healthier
over time
would you like the last word here
the exact last word
we need more science we need more
research in this field we need to solve
the problems and not just
ignore them and i think we all need to
be curious and excited about what we do
and try to improve ourselves
okay well i think that's it unless one
last call for questions no thank you all
for listening thank you guys for all
being proud for the panel
[Music]
[Applause]
you