thank you everybody and welcome to this
panel um
so today my panel is because
due to some travel uh situations in
heathrow airport and due to covet we had
a couple of
translations but
now i'm happy to announce that we're our
ladies panel which is also something a
topic that i really care about to have
the ladies on stage more and give them
more visibility so i'm very happy
that we're like all ladies panel today
um i have the pleasure to have claudia
del mora on my panel she's an investor
director at blac black legend capital
they do corporate finance and are mna
expert in several sectors they are
experts on international legalization of
cannabis and run a boutique advisory
service group based in la
and then we i also have on my panel ria
green from the uk
she's involved in a company called eye
counter link or the founder of a company
called icanna link they do cannabis
supply chain solutions and she is the
publisher of queen queen magazine in the
uk and therefore has a lot of contact
with all kinds of businesses and
active in the market
so given that we just have a half an
hour i just jumped straight in and my
first question goes to claudia um
claudia provided that cannabis is not
yet federally legal in the world's
largest market in the united states
cannabis companies any vertical have
historically struggled to raise money
what have been the roadblocks for
cannabis companies this far in the
capital market
okay so this is thank you hello
everybody so this is a question that has
been discussed for many years right but
we've seen
major changes from 2017 18 19 2020 2021
2022 i mean just 2022 is extremely
different from 2021 right
so in general the differences have been
that not being federally illegal
in most countries i mean at least in the
in the main countries uh besides canada
which was actually a very very good uh
example that's why canada was able to
raise this huge amount of money through
the public market
um
so uh the the problem of listing
companies in the big exchanges
uh
the companies that touch the flower
cannot list on the nasdaq on new york
stock exchange and we know that listing
a company the big big exchanges uh is a
big source of capital right so they they
end up
listing the small exchanges like the otc
market
and that has never been you know a very
favorable uh solution for uh
for for big raise or cash flowing or
growth right of value
so this is this has been a problem for
many many years
um but then we've seen
many changes in the economy right uh
after the big bubble in 2019
then we got you know of course investors
got extremely you know disappointed then
we got covered 2021 2020 2020 was very
difficult to raise equity mostly was
that
all of a sudden in 2021 we've seen a
major shift
um the the equity value went up of
course that was also due to
the elections in the united states and
the the expectations of federal
legalizations coming really soon or um
or
federal
legislating legislating bills like the
the safe banking act passing and
allowing companies to to to source money
and cheap money from banks right
um then after that we've seen 2021 you
know did not do not satisfied investors
did not satisfy you know the
expectations of federal legalizations
and all of a sudden the the equity value
and uh dropped enormously uh and now as
of you know
june 2022
uh equity value
uh the the average equity value of
companies comp year to date compared to
june 2021 there was a drop of 40 percent
40 of equity value
so then you know we've seen
a major shift also uh in invest in
raising equity versus debt right so in
um we've seen of course the equity value
was much higher so
m a activity was was more frequent
and
and companies used to prefer using
equity for acquisitions than debt
at the same time debt slowly but surely
became cheaper at the same time so as we
know since there's no safe banking act
and you cannot raise money from regular
banking
um has been it's been extremely
expensive to finance these companies
we're talking about rates in the teens
okay even over 20 i mean usually rates
um then in 2021 we've seen all of a
sudden that some of the best performing
companies best performing i mean
positive gross margin okay like truly
gti
they were able to raise that seven
percent eight percent unheard of before
right so cheap that now this cheap that
really is only available for big
companies multi-state operators okay the
small companies are still paying 15 16
or plus percent in that right so this
was 2021 then all of a sudden 2022
there's this huge
crash in equity value so nobody wants to
use it's very tough to raise equity
right also because you're going to get
deluded a lot as a company or acquiring
you know
other companies with you know with
equity
so we've seen an increase again in debt
in that race
and what what's been actually very
interesting
is that um
lenders
uh you know big lenders companies they
are raising a debt a really cheap
interest rates like on the five six
percent and they're making a huge spread
you know so this is my you know point of
view yeah super interesting um to see
that developments um ria for you uh like
you're more active on the start-up side
um and in the uk which is also like that
it's not federally legal or anything um
but other than recreational cannabis
reform what were roadblocks that you saw
for the startups companies that made it
also difficult to raise funds
well everybody's had a rocky couple of
years you know in 2018 there was so much
momentum and excitement about the
potential of cbd products the whole
shift in legislation and a lot of
companies came in and came hard and
exhausted their marketing budget then
were hit by kovid and then were hit by
the novel food act and they've just had
one problem after the other so
it feels like also the hearts and minds
of these companies they've kind of lost
their drive and momentum and and they've
had so much red tape
money they've just thrown so much money
at things like legals and
also
when we're in an industry that's so
unique and doesn't
work in the conventional way so we have
to think outside the box with marketing
with banking with everything so because
it's just one roadblock after the other
i think the novel food act for a lot of
companies was the last straw to be
honest and it knocked out maybe 80 90 of
the small
small momentum that was just starting
within the cbd industry
but
the reason why we created the magazine
was to be a container to document these
shifts because it's such an
unpredictable territory nobody really
knows what's going to happen the time
scales are ever changing and it's a
global it's a global global ecosystem
and each ecosystem in turn affects its
neighbours and europe
is so privileged because we're at the
point now where we can stand on the
shoulders of giants because we have an
international community that are coming
over
and they're willing and able and they've
got resources to help this help us not
make the mistakes that have been made
over the over the other side of the pond
and the other thing that i've found in
europe is the attitude here is just
completely different it's got a very
different paradigm towards cannabis
we've had coffee shops in amsterdam for
a long time and it's not only the
population density that makes europe
exciting for these investors so i think
this is the prime time
to optimize this window of opportunity
to create these symbiotic relationships
that benefit not only the suits but the
roots and everybody in between and
hopefully the main people who benefit
are the users and the consumers and the
patients and what i feel
personally i've worked in the cannabis
industry for 20 years i'm not a root or
a suit i'm a fruit
my mum has been in the cannabis industry
for a long time and if you want to speak
to experts and veterans you don't find
them in the legal market you find them
in the legacy market the legacy market
does not need the regulators the
regulators need the legacy and once we
realize this and we work in a symbiotic
symbiotic harmonious way
everybody benefits in a rising tide all
the ships come up together and if we can
create these relationships that's where
i believe it's all going to thrive yeah
that's very true
so let's go a little have a little look
into vertically integrated companies
historically verticality has had
successful cannabis apart from their
competitors merger and acquisition have
been the best method of growth to remain
competitive how do these mergers and
acquisitions been financed providing the
constraints on these capital raised
markets
so we we actually touched on the really
integrated companies and you know the
the
the roadblocks right uh you know united
states uh has been a good example of
having to recreate manufacturing
cultivation facilities in every states
um that's why we have to you know m a is
the solution because you need to acquire
you need to expand and uh
i mean think about it right so if you
have to
start as a vertical integrated company
start uh cultivation facilities
extraction facilities manufacturing
facilities in every state you know it
takes time right not just money so it
might as well just acquire you know uh
the the companies that already have been
you know
successful or they're already existing
so
now i mean in the in the
lately we've seen also um
a lot of m a uh from uh
public public companies to public
companies
okay
uh briana goodness and of course now
columbia care and crest collabs
now we just said five minutes ago that
equity value dropped enormously in the
past year
and why are these companies doing stock
to stock right all stock acquisitions
and that's because you know if they
acquire stocks dropped also the target
stuff the stocks dropped right so it
just makes sense and also for the target
companies it makes sense to sell
and receive and be paid you know with
stocks because they know the upside
at the moment
at the moment the the market is is
trailing at a big discount
uh and
we have an ebitda multiple in 2022 of
six percent
uh six times sorry and 2023 over five
times
ebitda multiple which is you know
typical of um
of mature mature mature industry
and not definitely not uh you know a
growing and upcoming and you know in the
industry with all of this upside all
over the world
um so it's a you know it's it's
basically
way better to as i said to to use that
or to use equity only if you're
acquiring you know with equity and other
companies
um ria what about the uk do you see a
lot of m a happening in the uk or what
is the situation other companies more
vertically integrated or do you have
more specialist countries what is the
situation there
i think the only way the companies are
going to work in the uk is if they've
got american partners realistically
because they're coming with the
experience the knowledge and the money
and they're just forward thinking if
they're thinking about the future and
the long term plan and they're not
looking for an immediate return
they they can work in within europe if
you look at cookies for example even
though it's not a legal market they're
getting their clothing brand shops all
over europe they're preparing for things
to change even though they don't know
what it's going to be or how long
so i think that the long game players
look at it through lifestyle through
culture through celebrating things i
mean realistically all the market that's
coming through the medical patients the
the notoriety come from people like rick
simpson frenchy colony who's another
legend that's that's part of the the
black market the great well black it's
not they were they were original
legends and found that foundations that
have then we've start we've stand on the
shoulders of giants you know and these
are all from the
fringe
fringe illegal
people that had the bottle to go out and
do things because they had a need their
need was more important than the
financial benefit
um just out of it just out of interest
let me do a crowd participation who in
this room
is here because they have a personal
story about cannabis cannabis help them
over in their personal house or in their
own family
and i think these are the people
that are going to change the industry
because their drive isn't conventional
their drives deeper the purpose is more
important and for me as the daughter of
a patient as somebody who's treated
cannabis to 7 000 patients illegally for
the past six years in the uk
personally if i spend the rest of my
life working for this plan i could still
not repay everything that she's given me
and i know there's a lot of people that
feel the same way and it's that passion
and that drive and that fire that's
going to make sure that this doesn't
become extinguished and i loved what
jamie said on the panel earlier about
it's the ceo who's going to have the
biggest balls
and i believe that ceo is going to be a
woman
and that's why we're telling the story
through the women and what i believe the
the female way to tell a story is it's a
circular model and the beautiful thing
about this industry is there isn't one
person in the world who knows everything
there is one doctor you can go to who
can give you all the answers there isn't
one specialist but there's a circular
model of everybody who's got a little
piece of the puzzle and it's forcing us
to come into a situation where now is
the time for radical collaboration and
we need to work like nature nature
doesn't compete it collaborates and if
we can work out what that looks like the
foundations we lay in these next 10
years are going to be felt for decades
if not centuries to come this window of
opportunity
is is a privilege you know those with
the
those with the privilege to know have
the duty to act the people in this room
and tomorrow we're letting we're laying
foundations that are far bigger than us
and if we don't do it with integrity and
correctness
what are those what are the future years
going to look like we've got 100 years
of r d to do because it's been
prohibited globally so we haven't got
time to waste and we haven't got time to
mess around there's so much talent and
beauty and skill and passion in this
industry the next 10 years are going to
be key and the only way to do that is
with sharing and mergers
thank you for saying that it's very
important
so let's have a look at a little bit at
trends um what are some trends that have
been holding capital raises in the
cannabis space claudia
well actually i mean we just attached on
this right 2022
um has been
you know very difficult to raise equity
as we said because of that you know
lower value and equity so more debt even
the debt funds have raised you know
more a lot of money with you know which
with with cheap interest rates for them
and high interest rates for you know for
the companies
um
so so at the moment at the moment uh uh
let's say that equity raises uh year to
date are like down 70 to something like
this 74
in the united states even more in canada
um debt raises are high a lot in the
united states but also very very down in
like 90 percent in canada year to date
as of june 2022
so basically it's like a moment of of of
pause okay
this in addition to
the general public markets i mean you
know the regular sap s p 500 and uh you
know the other industries everything is
down so if you speak with any investment
bank or investors they kind of uh
there's at this very moment they're
saying that they're just waiting for for
the dust to settle basically and that's
why you see a lot of consolidations
right now for you know economies of
scale and
ability to to continue growing right on
uh with just some acquisition of stocks
to stocks but you know i'd like to you
know uh ria victoria she's she's an
expert in the industry uh more in the uh
the legacy industry where i come from in
a finance world so it's very different
so um
i wanted to ask her you know what what
do you think uh the
you know the the legal uh the legal the
legal space of the industry can take as
as you know
examples or directions from the legacy
world in terms of you know growth and
survivals
best product wins if you've got a good
product it'll last the test of time if
you're selling a crappy product because
you expect your audience to not know the
difference between a good product and a
bad product
then
you don't deserve to succeed in if
you're giving bad products to cancer
patients and people that are really
suffering and need that medicine and it
isn't the best you can possibly produce
why are you doing it you know and i
think if though if you've got a good
product and you're coming from a good
place those are the ones that will last
the test of time so so can you grow
organically without big fundraising
if
if your products are you know
particularly good well this is where we
created icann a link because we found
there's such a need
because even though we're speaking the
same language it's not the investors and
the money people aren't speaking to the
legacy people it's like we was at the
mary jane show and
you know hydro guys and black market
guys they're a very special they don't
talk to everybody and they don't open up
to everybody and they don't want to talk
to the suits necessarily they don't even
want to and not only do they not want it
they haven't got time they don't want
investment and they think the whole
thing's dirty ironically
and i think if we can create these tools
that become the bridge that's what
icanna link is it's a way of
bringing in all our expertise from the
i mean if you're speaking to somebody
with over 10 years experience they
haven't got that experience in a legal
market and why would you want someone
with less than 10 years experience doing
anything for your company so we're using
icalilink as a bridge for industry to
connect with black market and we're
using green queen magazine to document
the story and shape the narrative
constantly with the three pillars of
destigmatisation decentralization
decriminalization this is our plan they
can't give us back because it's ours we
need to claim it and i think that this
process this dance that happens between
the legal market and the legacy market
is the legacy market's all about
education like if you go to these
weed shows and secret sessions and cups
they've got so much knowledge in the
room it's it's above and beyond what you
could eat like some people you can get
to them and they just keep going for
hours days
and yet you've got patience we were
speaking to hannah deacon who's a legend
in the uk she is the first um her son he
was the first child to get cannabis
prescription she's been fighting
endlessly for epileptic children access
and she said on one of the panels that
we did she said i don't care whether
it's good i don't care whether it's the
best i just want it to work i don't want
to know any of this information that
you're talking about i just want it to
work for my son and i don't want to have
to worry about it and this is
the two different languages that we're
talking but actually if we bring in the
best products and we bring in the best
teams and we're bringing this experience
that's been learnt through the test
through the
trial of fire what else could happen but
succeed so i think if we come in with
the best intentions the best will happen
and if we can create these
vehicles that allow the black market to
connect to the industry that's where it
will be optimized
um you also did something interesting
recently you issued an nft like we also
have alternative fundraising models
happening it's not only debt and equity
investment anymore like there are still
so many
different options nowadays can you let
us know a little bit about that and how
that went wow the cannabis industry is
it might be short of many things but not
creativity so
the necessa
the mother of invention is necessity so
because we can't go to conventional
routes like banks we're having to think
outside the box a little bit with how to
fundraise and
we created an ethereum smart contract it
exists it was created on the 22nd of the
second 2022 and
the idea was to use it as a fundraising
platform to then feed back into all of
our other projects um
as many things it's another lesson in in
how to do things right and wrong and i
think
even though nobody understands nfts at
the moment doesn't mean they're not
going to be integrated into every
industry over the next couple of years
so
even though we are first in the space
we're trying to integrate things like
utility events and create these
partnerships in the digital world so
there's two aspects to sharing knowledge
there's knowledge and wisdom so wisdom
is these
this example of like an ongoing teaching
so your relationship with your business
partner your children the forest
your yoga practice it continues to teach
you it continues to grow whereas
knowledge is like a snapshot like a um
like a photograph like if you get
somebody's written a book two years ago
it was a snapshot of their knowledge
then now they think something completely
different
so what we're doing is we we're creating
both simultaneously to celebrate this
culture so the wisdom is the web page
the on-site portal we've got a metaverse
training academy that's in the wings
we've got the nft and all of these
digital wisdoms about creating a
container for the community so we
continue to grow through each other and
then simultaneously we're doing a
printed book that's kind of bringing
back these collectible
physical printed things because we're
taking back our history the first thing
they stole from us was the story and
afterwards everything was a was a domino
effect and if we can take back the story
and start celebrating the things that
this plant does through
personal
real people how could you argue with
that it not been accessible so our
pillars are health environment social
activism and culture and i think one of
the problems we've got with cannabis is
the compartmentalization of oh this is
medical this is recreational this is
hemp it's not it's the same thing it's a
plan and it's a human right and we
should all have access to it and this
plan is the biggest solution we have to
so many of the problems and as somebody
who deals with sick patients we have
7000 patients over 66 years
what i think cannabis gives
in the most hopeless time in the most
desperate time in the worst time in
people's life it gives them hope
we're the custodians of that and this is
a position of service this isn't about
making money this well obviously we're
here to make money but the money should
reflow and re-irrigate back into the
ecosystem that benefits everybody and
when we work like that we use nature as
the example and everybody thrives and i
think that's what the plan is constantly
teaching us the more you give the more
you were given so
it's very interesting struggle between
uh like doing something good and
idolized and actually just going for the
money and making a profit right i mean
we've seen um
both in this industry because we got
wall street in we got
um
activists and scientists researchers
in the industry
so
i think you know it's going to be very
interesting to see how this develops
throughout the world with developing
countries
coming online producing for developed
legislation kind of you know creating
reasons for slow downs i mean you know
we see in the united states so this
cultivation facility is done in michigan
massachusetts
uh illinois i mean what will happen what
will happen right when federal
legalization happens and mexico goes
completely legal uh you know to to those
to those
to those to those states but also at the
same time uh in the u.s there's a big
deal about uh social equity i don't know
if you know about about that and uh you
know
if there's a similar situation in the
united in in europe
but social equity is basically
helping uh minorities and uh uh you know
develop
developing their dreams and and
establishing businesses and
i think that
that that is also very important but it
has to be done in an intelligent way so
if i want to advise someone who you know
doesn't have the same opportunities as
someone graduating from harvard or
whatever i wouldn't just tell them to go
and do a cultivation facility in
massachusetts because in our next few
years they're going to go bankrupt right
so i want to actually help them to to be
successful now to fail so i think
there's a lot of ignorance
around all of this and legalization is
definitely going to an international
trade is going to affect
how
uh you know the success of this industry
and then again we go back to the funding
and why
why some companies especially the
consumer product focused companies are
are trying to to
to take the market in north america
which is a cash flow rich
cash flow rich market
mostly because of
because of a recreational recreational
cannabis right while uh wellness and
pharmaceutical companies are
investing and focusing operationally and
and financially into latin america
europe or asia asia is going to be the
biggest market and nobody even talks
about it but it's going to be strictly
uh medicinal
so yes uh so there's a lot of m a lot of
expansion in different different uh with
different uh you know strategies
you just mentioned also the recreational
cannabis reform in in the u.s um like i
personally hope that like with all this
uh recreational reform sweeping across
the globe that we will also have
improvements in other areas what do you
think
will the for example for the states
change in the current relationship with
capital markets once they potentially
legalize on a national level so you mean
like capital markets and and federal
legalization the openness towards
investment with uh federal reform coming
in well i mean i'm sure everybody knows
about this in this room but i mean if
you come from oil and gas or consumer
products or you know they're pharma you
and you're in your fund manager you
raise your money from
you know institutional institutional
sources such as
endowments insurances pension funds you
were talking about billions and billions
of dollars
while in cannabis you can't you raise
money from high net worth and family
offices uh
uh we've seen it
so so also there's a difference between
private equity
and public equity and of course the
private debt because right now there's
not much you know
commercial bank debt right so in private
equity um
again they source money from high net
worth family offices very limited money
most of the private equity funds are
struggling i mean they have a nice name
they've done a lot of work but they're
not big fans you know there's not much
money available uh so they've been
focusing mostly on private equity
strategies always long term kind of you
know kind of five years exit for any
industry right or more so they've been
focusing more on ancillary companies no
non-touching the plant companies
uh while the public equity such as hedge
funds right they always have more
capital why not because they go to
pension funds absolutely but because
they trade so
hedge funds you know the trade trade the
market and therefore they just have
bigger volumes but but it's more of an
arbitrage short term you know
taking advantage of the situation so you
you this is why we've seen in canada so
much money being you know raised
since 2016 and 17.
the public the public equity have been
focusing more on touching the plant
companies such as cultivation
uh retail dispensaries and manufacturing
why because it just generates more cash
flow you know with all of its problems
it just regenerates a faster cash flow
so so that's that's some of the trends
that uh that we've seen right now and
also you know lenders i mean lenders
prefer prefer uh cultivation and retail
because they have collateral right for
safety
and that's been you know most of uh most
of the money raised has been into these
sectors much less into uh pharma or or
ancillary
right maybe is something you still want
to add to that also given that uk
also doesn't have recreational reform
yet and i've been in contact for example
with a couple of investors from the uk
and they've they cannot invest in
germany for example due to that fact
because they don't have cannabis reform
in the uk
well i think the the best way for
everything to work is global decent
global decriminalization whether that's
going to happen or not is another thing
but i think all this red tape that's
being created
is making us think outside the box and
one thing we're not sure of in this
industry is creativity like we said
earlier and i think
the best examples we can look at is if
we look at nature like the greatest
minds in the world always look at nature
as the best example and how does
cannabis work in the body well
homeostasis and adaptogen so what does
homeostasis mean it means all the cells
share their resources and poisons and
they communicate to each other to allow
the ecosystem that the whole thing to
thrive and the adaptogen aspect is each
area needs something different and the
plant has this amazing intelligent
healing that fills the gaps that it
needs at the time and it's very
difficult to articulate that because the
plants driving driving in my opinion so
what will happen i believe if we come
from a point of service the plan is
driving and she's got all the answers i
hope all right our time is over so thank
you to the audience thank you to the
beautiful ladies on stage and if you
have any questions feel free to approach
us outside because like we now have to
give up this stage to the next one more
time for lisa and claudia and victoria
green very informative