is this an international business
company and many people who came here
kind of took a chance bought a ticket
wasn't sure what to expect right and the
feedback I'm getting is I can't believe
this I didn't know what was going to be
this good what they mean by good is
information and networking and just a
gentle attitude of the people here just
want to thank Alex and the dial for
putting on an event that really blends
activism and business in a really really
great way and I believe in karma I
believe in community I believe in love
and understanding and I actually believe
if you hold true to some of those
tenants and precepts that you're only
going to benefit yourself for so many
reasons and in my case it's actually
helped me make money also so it's this
new win-win situation that's happening
with the cannabis industry in particular
and I think that's what people are very
surprised about that that they can make
money they could be successful and no
one else has still to lose we just
wrapped it up here at the international
cannabis business conference on a
fantastic time steve blum from celeb
stoner and freedom leaf magazine was
here Steve DeAngelo was here Ethan
Nadelmann from the drug policy alliance
gave an impassioned impassioned speech
about what we need to do if people are
actually overly excited and happy that
we have decided to dedicate so much of
this to culture politics and advocacy
and I'm tremendously happy with the
feedback ever dad a small group of
concerned citizens can change the world
it is indeed the only thing that ever
has