good morning everybody my name is claude
de la mora i'm a managing director of
black legend capital
i've been in m a and
invest in being king all my life come
from merrill lynch and
cover several industries so far from
hospitality to
consumer products oil and gas natural
resources and finally cannabis in the
past seven years i'm based in los
angeles california so i'm going to
introduce the panelists here marcus
moser based in germany right
his partner at zurich and moser
consulting so consulting firm advisory
based in germany
um
he
is focusing also in different industries
and he comes from natural resources
mining but in the past few years has
been focusing
into the cannabis industry in uh in
europe
then we have david traylor
golden eagle partners the managing
director holding partners a consulting
advisory service uh group as well
focusing cannabis and finally we have
jamie pearson president ceo of bank so
this panel is uh
is comprised of three advisory investing
banking consulting people and an
entrepreneur ceo of the multa state
operator vertically integrated cannabis
company in north america
all right great so
what are the differences between u.s and
global strategies for investment and
operations let's start from moser
um moser can you tell us a little bit
you know your point of view on
differences and similarities
between us or north american you know
canada as well and european companies in
their operations strategies
i think first of all
if you look at us
there are front runners in the sector
and the companies are much larger than
than in europe and i think
in u.s a lot of companies acting
globally in europe most companies are
just acting in their countries
because it's a bit i would say a very
fragmented sector in europe right
and just to elaborate on that why do you
think north american companies are
acting internationally versus you know
differently from european companies
acting more domestically
i think first of all they have much more
money because
the money markets in north america
especially in u.s also canada are much
larger so they have a lot of
cash funds to invest approach and of
course they invested
you know too much money so they lost a
lot of money if you look at the stock
market if you look at you know the
the listed cannabis companies the stock
went down market cap went down because i
think they invested
i would say not smart the money they got
beautiful actually i'm going to jump to
jamie here
because i know
you know her background so
based on what moser
just said right marcus
so sorry
um so he's saying that the reason why
north american companies are going
internationally is because they have
more money do you agree with that in
terms of you know is there like a growth
problem here i don't think so i don't
agree with that i think
um what and i don't think you're wrong i
think it's um i think there's more to
the story and i think the
the piece that i would add to that
couple things number one
let's take the publicly listed company
true leave for example
um their market caps down i think
they're trading around 12 when they
normally operate around twenty eight
dollars there they were around a ten
billion dollar market cap i think now
they're like two and a half billion
um
that's they've put up 18 profitable
quarters they've continued to exceed
analyst expectations
that's not because they're making bad
decisions that their market caps low as
i said in my keynote the entire sector
is down so i don't think that you can
say that american companies are making
bad decisions i think it's cannabis
you're swimming upstream
you are operating in prohibition and
capital is not easy to get doesn't
matter what continent you're on um
because there is a stigma there's a lot
of fear
um but what i will say is you can run a
fantastic company right now and your
market cap's going to be
in the tank that's just the reality of
the world that we live in right now i
think to answer your question why are
u.s companies looking to come to europe
it's a burgeoning market
we're we're starting to see
the
you know
playing out of what we witnessed and
what we experienced in the us in 2016
2017 as different states started to
legalize and you're starting to see the
spread of cannabis
across the european continents very
exciting and for those of us that have
experienced that first to market success
we've got another market that we can go
jump in and be first to market i think
that's why these american companies are
looking for other opportunities where
they can jump in and take a stranglehold
on a market and be first to market
that's what i think is happening exactly
other opportunities so
what are the current u.s msos expansion
consolidation strategies and reasoning
you know behind that
well i've had several msos approach me
to
you know
put my fingertips out into the world and
see where there's opportunity and what
they're what they're doing is trying to
smell who are the operators that are
tied into money who are tied into
legislation and who are tied really kind
of are operating in the background and
they know what's happening and so the
msos who've been there done that are
smart and they're looking for the
operators so
with that being said
if you're an operator out there and
you're running uh an operation that is
well-funded that's connected
legislatively
and that has the ability to to do big
business across multiple countries you
should come find me
let's ask a question to david actually
uh
as a you know continuing from this topic
can you tell us a few strategies for
cannabis investment operators that uh
that we've seen uh
work internationally um well better or
worse you know from the united states
into into other countries
thanks claudia
actually let me step back a little
because first of all
i'm an investment bank uh banking firm
golden eagle partners uh we're the first
investment bank to be in cannabis in the
u.s we jumped into 2013
but i think i want to tell a little
story because it helps inform our
perspectives because i've been very
lucky uh to do what we're doing because
i started out in biotech have two
undergrad degrees biochem molecular
biology and got into biotech companies
actually one based here in berlin book
15 years operational experience luckily
got inventorship on two u.s patents for
my work in bioprocessing with
recombinant hemoglobin
so that's as you guys know
processing is a huge part of this
industry whether you're talking hemp
marijuana cbd thc whatever you want to
call it got an investment banking 2005
doing biotech deals i also did five
years of business development working
with companies doing deals with pfizer
astrazeneca
and then moved back to colorado in 2009
to lead the life science group at a
group called headwaters
and then left in 2012 to found gold
legal partners and that's when
colorado and washington voters legalized
it so in 2013 we started working in the
industry
we've done 25 deals in the space we
helped pharmacan raise one of the
leading msos raised 30 million we helped
a panacea which is a leading hemp
processor to a strategic deal
in 2019 uh but we've also spoken around
the world
uh on cannabis we're the only investment
bank in davos in 2020. uh we've spoken
in dubai
toronto twice cayman frankfurt earlier
this year
and obviously now berlin
and one last thing too if you guys know
athletes for care it's a great group
i played pro lacrosse so i've been an
athlete
ambassador for athletes for care for
five years and then also i'm the chief
scientific advisor for the industry or
for athletes for care so i put together
a group of the leading scientists
including ethan rousseau guillermo
moreno-sans from spain raquel perube
from uruguay and also deb kimlis from
the u.s so when you're talking about
science cannabis and finance we
certainly are a global leader but as far
as getting back to
hey nick
as far as the the strategies for even
investment and operation the title here
one thing i want to say quickly is
failure coming from the science side is
a great teacher
especially if you learn from failure is
not so bad right uh so essentially
we've seen a number of things failures
and i mentioned this in davos uh
certainly one a couple of the problems
people assume markets are going to open
up much quicker than they do
uh we see that as a problem you may know
canopy growth
put 40 million into a facility in south
africa and selling it for pennies on the
dollar
the other thing that we know a lot about
is the biological supply chains are
inherently unstable and so a lot of
these growers you name it i mean uh
aurora had the big facility out of
edmonton that they shut down and i'll
tell you if you want to talk to me later
i actually know the reason why uh but
they assumed all these producers assumed
okay we grow they'll come which is
another uh fallacy and then the other
thing that we've found and i think jamie
will agree
uh there's actually been very little uh
history of first mover advantage in this
industry serna where i worked at i was
chief business officer and i failed to
mention one of the first public
companies in the space it went public in
march 2014 they were the biggest name in
cannabis in 2014 they had the biggest
booth at the ntia events they're nowhere
to be found now if you've got dixie
they're gone uh canopy growth who knows
what's gonna happen with that right so
uh those i think failure when you can
talk to me later is a great teacher on
whether what you do with operations or
what you do on investment
can you elaborate a little bit more on
the first mover advantage
actually first of all i want to
introduce
yes sorry uh i'd like to introduce
nicolas fais senior research analyst at
brian guernier so another research
channel is consulting advisory guy here
hi how are you finally he was talking
another uh he went to the other hotel
unfortunately
yeah and on top of that and you couldn't
enter the hotel here because there was
uh an important person who was trying to
get out of the hotel so the police
blocked everybody getting in there's a
delegation here at this hotel
welcome so sorry to be late thank you
so so now just david uh quickly really
quickly like the first movie advantage
because we're seeing like you know
mexico coming online like brazil very
soon of course all these countries in
europe and now thailand as well right so
you know
what why do you think first mover
advantage is not a good thing uh well
actually
people like jamie will love this the
problem is there's been too much
arrogance and too little humility in
this industry
people think that their first mover
they've got them they've got four
billion dollars i mean that's gone from
canopy growth so that's i think the very
short and sweet of it is if you're going
to be successful in this industry
take a little humility and don't be so
arrogant
to that point i think what happens a lot
is
people that have had success in
mainstream business
have a level of arrogance and they come
in and they're like oh well there's a
bunch of stoners we're going to come in
and we're going to show them how to do
stuff
and then
they don't realize it's not not that
simple cannabis is a very difficult
business and it's its own
um industry it's its own community
and
there's a lot to know about operating
both
in and out of the legal sphere or in the
gray area and a lot of you know
traditional business people aren't
comfortable operating in the gray area
and you better get used to it if you're
going to be in cannabis
right so cannabis actually is comprised
of so many verticals right so we're
looking at agriculture of course biotech
manufacturing now technology
distribution
and consumer products and pharma right
so
so bank is a consumer product company a
little bit like you know also canopy
took
that approach right um can you give us a
comparison between
the normal consumer product cpg industry
versus you know the one in the cannabis
and the problems
the most obvious one in the u.s is
um if i were let's say producing i don't
know why tampons come to mind
if i were producing that i'm going to
produce it in one spot
and then i'm going to put it on a truck
and i'm going to ship it to all 50
states but in cannabis i have to have 50
different manufacturing facilities
because it's federally illegal
which means that i can't do interstate
commerce i can't cross state lines well
that means as a manufacturer of
chocolate i have to have 50 different
chocolate machines
and when they're let's say 150 to 250
000 a piece it becomes cost prohibitive
to automate the manufacturing of the
product times 50. so then i'm making
decisions about how many redundant
machines do i want to have
there are some places where i can't make
the decision to get rid of it i have to
have a tempering machine in every single
facility where i'm at but i don't
necessarily have to have the big fancy
flow wrapper i can do that manually or
with a foot pedal because i don't want
to have 49 redundant flow wrappers
i'm always parallel processing federal
legalization um and then the other thing
is basically in cannabis we struggle
with banking
and we struggle with marketing uh right
now every single person i would argue on
the globe
is buying their products
on their phone right in that device they
have in their pocket cannabis companies
are not allowed to market on social
media on facebook and so we kind of have
to swim upstream in the marketing world
and do what i call guerrilla marketing
so you have to do targeted marketing you
want to use influencers and you kind of
have to figure out ways around it so if
you're an agile business operator and i
would argue that's the other reason why
we need to pull
people from
the roots in the suits we need to pull
the roots into the into the industry is
that these are people that already have
experience operating in an upstream
environment and having to go around
being out in the open uh so those are
the people that are going to give us
advice about how do you get your how do
you get the word out how did jungle boys
for example when they opened in florida
jungle boys outsold every mso
on day one
with no social media tell me how they
did that we need to go talk to them
because they can tell us how they did
that
but if we have the arrogance to think oh
well i come from cpg and i know what to
do
i can't tell you how many times i've had
an executive come from mainstream go oh
all you got to do is i'm like well if
you want to spend your money doing that
but i'm going to tell you right now it's
not going to work
and it's going to be a waste of money
and that's what invariably happens and
that's why canopy is losing
you know 100 million dollars or 300
million dollars a year is because
they're just throwing money at problems
and you've got to be strategic
so you don't think consolation gave a
good direction to the company
i think constellation came in and
thought they were going to treat
cannabis like alcohol and it just
doesn't work like that
so you touched on marketing marketing is
a big problem in the united states
what about it's global
facebook isn't going to let you market
cannabis in europe either
it's a global problem right right
perfect
so let's ask a question to
you have a deep knowledge in the market
your research analyst
so um
what advantages
does the european market have over the
u.s market for investment operations
have we seen
european companies attracting blue chip
companies like you know north american
companies have
so can you repeat the question okay um
so let's talk about the you know the
advantages and advantages of european
european and u.s companies right
um
with your expertise in different markets
can you tell us the advantages or
disadvantages of um you know european
the european market over the u.s market
for investments and operations
have you seen a european
cannabis camp based companies attract
blue chip you know investment strategic
investments
as much as north american companies well
but
even the even the north american market
initially there were
large cpg companies who were starting
looking and putting their toes in the
water
we had some tobacco companies we had
some beverage companies including
constellation brands
but i think
that they have been drawing
have been
um
coming back from that idea
take imperial imperial brands for
example who took a stake in oxley and
in the uk uh oxford cannabinoid
technologies
initially they were very much looking at
cannabis as something that could be a
new
product and and relieve some of their
growth problems but
only to uh to realize that they were
actually uh
defocusing from their core business so
they say well okay let's let's stop that
uh i think also constellation brands
have been
looking at like that same with a b
that joint ventured with
with tillway but i said well no we think
that the risk is too high for us to uh
to to to be involved at this stage in in
the cannabis area so i think that most
um
large cpg companies who initially were
looking at that sector they have come
back from that idea so it is uh
unfortunately it will be just uh
on our own and we don't need to look at
those bigger
companies to to support
the cannabis industry
okay um so would you agree
that you know the biggest the biggest
multinational cannabis companies can be
divided kind of in two
in two sections
consumer product
and
pharmaceuticals
so what kind of trends have you seen in
europe versus you know north america i
think also for the pharmaceutical level
it's exactly the same
i take for example a belgian company ucb
is very strong in the epilepsy
didn't dare to touch at all
anything that has to do with with
cannabis just because there were are
afraid that it could back could come
back with them and hurt them because
they all had of course
the the decent opinoid crisis uh in in
mind
and uh they are a bit afraid and say
well if only that something similar will
happen to uh to cannabis let's stay away
see how things
develop so i think also for the
medicinal
cannabis market it's a little bit like
that and what happens with the canadian
companies who initially were medicinal
cannabis companies then came adult use
and then they didn't not know what to do
so they just do everything oh we're
doing a bit of medicinal maybe doing a
little bit of adult use and
oh
let's go in
europe let's go in europe as well and
have um
and do a bit of that as well and they
just spent money without
having uh their
basis
operations in order and that was the
problem with the canadian some of the us
msos are slightly better uh in in doing
so
i call that the something shiny syndrome
and part of it is
oh there's something shiny over here and
over here and over here because there's
so much opportunity
that there is a bottomless pit
of where you could spend money to try to
make money but i think you're right you
have to stick to your core focus and get
really good at what you're
doing i will say
it makes me
angry that
the stigma is stopping these big
companies from diving in and i think if
there was one company that had a ceo
with big enough balls to do it
they're gonna go make a lot of money
but everybody's afraid and i think this
fear it's time for it to be over because
we know that cannabis is helping people
with epilepsy and parkinson's and we're
only going to know what we're able to do
with research we need medical research
we need the governments to knock it off
and i mean if i could ring all of their
necks personally i probably would
or a ceo with big enough ovaries
well ask me to do something and i'll
probably do it
i just
why not
exactly so what this is completely out
of you know but um what have we had here
but nah so would you recommend the
government or fda to be way more
involved and
you know
basically regulate better but also
substantiate what's going on the hard
part is
anything that you say is going to be
controversial because if we ask the
government to deschedulize to deschedule
cannabis from schedule 1
then it's going to open a whole nother
can of worms but what we really need is
access to medical research
so that i look at it like
we just don't even know how many
cannabinoids exist right now
we don't know what the combination of
this one that one and this terpene could
do for this or that ailment what we have
is a ton of anecdotal evidence
and we know that nobody's ever overdosed
on cannabis so we know that it's a
plant-based medicine we know that it's
generally non-addictive we know that
it's safe
all of those things i'm making these
statements and i don't even know if i'm
speaking the truth because i'm
going off anecdotal evidence what it
would really be great is if we could
figure out that when you have epilepsy
of this sort that you take this
combination like i my daughter has
epilepsy she's probably gonna kill me if
she hears me
we have her on cannabinoid therapy they
give her
thc
full spectrum cbd which includes a small
amount of thc
thca linoleul
limonene and turmeric well is there a
pill that she can take that has all of
those no
i happen to be a cannabis executive so i
can go get linalool i can go get
limonene i can get thca i can get full
spectrum cbd so i have my daughter off
of anti-seizure medications which were
making her
sleep for 18 hours a day at 21 years old
we should be that should be available to
everyone who has epilepsy not just the
daughter of a cannabis executive
because we
she's not had a seizure in two years on
that medication
that's groundbreaking
because we know that these anti-seizure
medications have so many side effects
that's one ailment
but think about parkinson's and think
about all the other things
think about anxiety just think about the
people that want to use cannabis instead
of alcohol which is a poison
opiates which is a poison and super
addictive our governments are going to
have to step up and give the people what
they want it's time
globally
so do you think that more clinical
studies uh would benefit not only the
pharma
you know vertical of the industry but
also the consumer product vertical in
the industry absolutely i mean the more
we know the better we do right
correct exactly
um nick give us a little bit of a um
a
you know information on the european and
german market
so i heard that the german market could
be potentially as big as the california
market
can you give us some you know
can you shed some light on this
and if you look at all the markets
across across the globe
and
when we look at
how large has those markets
and the complicated calculation on how
often does somebody consume cannabis and
at what rate do they consume but on
average it's a it's around 160 grams
per annum
for the the cannabis consumers so that
and that is true in canada that's true
in california that is true in florida
so it's around 160 grams on average so i
would expect that that's exactly the
same in in europe
so if we then look at what the
prevalence rate is in in germany for
example that's that's just over seven
percent so 80
million uh at seven percent that's a 5.4
uh i believe uh 160 grams well that is
close to a
thousand tons or 950
tons and that is at at the current stage
and
in all the markets whenever they
is a trend to legalize uh cannabis we've
seen an uptick in those prevalence rate
because there are consumers who would
love to try it would love to be on on
cannabis but don't dare to go to the to
the black market also and that it's a
quite a significant topic it's about 50
uptick that we're seeing for example
canada
2015 or so
the balance rate was 15 percent
now it's 21
same same was true in in california
although we had that all heritage in in
california so so
same will happen in in europe and in
germany so for example if you go back to
my seven percent well let's say it ticks
up to ten percent or ten that's eight
million times 160 that is uh 1 300 tons
uh
way more than the 400 tons that somebody
came up a couple of years ago um so i
think that was a very strong under
underestimation um
and i think you need to couple with that
the fact that
germany is the size of
oregon
geographically and has public transport
and when you think about the whole us
market or you just think about
california geographically
getting product to all of the people of
california is a challenge it'll be much
easier to do it in germany i think the
distribution in germany is much more
sophisticated so if you do have that 10
percent and you have that small
geographic location i think you're
you're going to see the penetration um
increase at a much higher rate
well that's a good point uh what about
other countries in europe at the moment
can you give us some information
everybody's looking at what germany is
going to do how they're going to get
around legalizing um adult use cannabis
and then others will very quickly follow
portugal
italy probably as well
luxembourg malta who
has tried before switzerland is already
legalizing adult use whatever way you
you look at it so but give us a little
bit of some numbers like you know the
projected market size in europe or in
germany well
well the same reason that we did earlier
for germany we can use for uh for for
europe
because okay in some countries like
france or italy or
spain the pre-valence rates are higher
already today than than that seven
percent in in germany um but then if we
look at it all in all
well we come at a market which is
probably
six thousand seven thousand tons and
then uh pick your price at which
current black market price is ten euros
probably will go down because the 10
euros black market that is a that is a a
not competitive price it's a it's a it's
a monopoly monopoly run by the
cartel so we'll come down say to i don't
know seven euros just to say something
seven thousand dollars times seven
that's
449 that's 50 billion
markets in europe
mortgage markets
i mean
seriously as i mentioned before they've
always been over hyped i mean that the
problem with this industry is it's going
to be a race to the bottom it's going to
be a commodity and it's going to be
about your supply chain okay
you're talking about europe
where is it going to be produced and how
is it going to be produced is it going
to be colombia is it going to be lesotho
is it going to be canary islands is it
going to be greece guernsey jersey
cyprus we've talked to groups all in
those countries macedonia maybe portugal
i don't know the freaking answer and
nobody in this room does the other
question is how is it going to be
produced is it going to be produced
just as a phytosource is it going to be
for example there's companies now in the
us that are producing hemp growing it
outside producing cbd and cbd and doing
a simple chemical conversion to delta 9
thc
then do you have yeast you have a coli
do you have chemistry or do you have a
combination thereof where you grow as i
mentioned some kind of certain
cannabinoid or or purify it out and i
don't have the answer either although
i'm i'm pretty smart scientifically so i
think you know the markets have always
been over hyped and you name it the
question is what is the supply chain in
five years going to look like and where
is it going to be produced you know i
agree and and um whatever market that we
look at is
always an oversupply
and and that will be a feature of this
industry for for the decades to come so
in the growing there will be oversupply
uh
way way more than demand can uh can can
stomach so
on growing at that yeah wherever it
comes from initially germany probably
will be the the
the
the garbage bin of the world probably
everybody who has some excess capacity
uh will start if they are allowed to
export into germany
part of it's because of the energy
consumption
and so i what i'm hoping is that germany
will
allow
growers to grow
in germany i don't predict that that
will happen because of the energy
consumption
and so it is i think you're right the
garbage i wouldn't call it the garbage
but whatever i think the cannabis will
come in but
i think that david makes a great point
because you can grow outside you can use
the sun i think it's weird that we
thought that people were going to grow
cannabis indoors in canada
and mimic the sun
how expensive is that for you to have a
giant warehouse have a bunch of lights
and then grow it inside when i think
about from a chocolate standpoint nobody
grows sugarcane in a warehouse
and mimics the sun so that they can make
a product you know ultimately it is a
commodity
but i do think and the market market
thing i agree with but i also think you
have to have market predictors to know
what the demand is going to be so that
you can kind of wrap your brain around
it what i've seen is this
cycle of
governments always
come in with fear and they don't issue
enough licenses and then the people sell
out it's crazy though i predict this
will happen in germany they're gonna the
day one of sales doesn't matter what it
is everyone's gonna sell out and they're
to go oh crap we need more and then
they're going to open up the floodgates
and then too much cannabis is going to
come in and you're going to have an
oversupply this happens every single
time and then the market speaks and then
it's the good operators who are
running good companies that will make it
and everybody else gets flushed out so
these companies that you talked about
the very beginning in 2014 that don't
exist
you know it's it this is the cycle
there's a reason they don't exist right
so
in the end it will be and that's where
uh cannabis is very similar to um to
other cpg companies it are the proper
operators who have a strategy who know
their consumers who
produce at low cost or and trying to
differentiate their product and and
brands
i thought they going to be the winners
uh and and in that sense it's very
similar to other cpg companies at the
end of the day
the commodity that we are all going to
end up fighting for is shelf space yeah
let's talk about that by the way yes
it's important the consumer product
space so what is the difference between
a shelf space
seen as a commodity in regular consumer
product companies versus cannabis well
think about when you go into a grocery
store you have these end caps you have
merchant you have entire companies whose
job it is is to merchandise products so
they come in and they teach the cpg
companies how to put products at eye
level how to bribe the store so that
they're not down here on the shelf that
they're not up here on the shelf you all
want eye level you want to have
their
colors in your branding so we all know
all the fast food companies america
they're all red and yellow wendy's
mcdonald's they're all red and yellow
why because that is the psychological
color of hunger etc etc it becomes very
sophisticated very scientifically
oriented
it's big business
that is all big business
cannabis right now is
everybody who's got a little bit of a
creative you know bone
they create some cool brand and
that's all going to wash out and we're
going to see it become systemized and
scientifically designed
i'm wondering if um marcus has
any insight into that coming from
from your area
but what i would add that in europe the
companies have
less money and i think the problem you
mentioned and you know coming back to
the
i think truly is a good company is a
good example but there are also negative
examples in the industry and i think
europe has the advantage that there is
not enough money available
for the sector at the moment so the
company really have to spend the money
smart and then i think
that's an advantage but also
disadvantage because um
it goes lower
as expected and i think the problem is
really the legal frame because i would
compare europe with u.s because you have
28 countries with different laws and in
us it's similar you have different
states some states is allowed some not
and i think that's the problem that we
need a
european
wide legal frame that companies can
operate
so we have we have only a few minutes uh
is there anybody here who would like to
ask a question
to the panel just raise your hands yeah
for claudia and the whole panel first of
all it's fantastic
hello good morning my name is philippe
rogerdark i'm from mercury in the uk we
make inhaled cannabinoid therapy we come
from the pharma sector
i have a question about investment the
big elephant in the room particularly
when it comes to clinical evidence
so you jamie particularly said we need
clinical evidence that's very expensive
and at the moment i don't think the
margin on the products particularly
flowers justify the the investment so
can someone comment on that elephant in
the room how are we going to raise the
money
who is going to pay for it and how the
product is going to pay for it
let's let the investment advisor answer
that
well come from biotech i think there's a
company called radical science if you
know out of la started by jeff chen
who's essentially doing this with
cannabinoids where you can do like
what's called a stage four trial
essentially it's kind of out in the
market where you're doing really good
data analytics so that's one of the
things you guys i look them up they're
doing some really interesting things so
that's a cheaper way to go
we actually are working right now with
epm which is one of the leading israeli
companies
generating cannabinoid acids and they're
going to do a clinical trial process
they need to raise a lot of money but
you bring up a good point you need to be
creative and find a way to finance
really good science it's not a clinical
trial because
most people we know and we we've been
raising money for science-based cannabis
companies since 2015. it's not easy
because you're straddling the biotech
cannabis sector and the biotech
investors don't want to do cannabis they
don't like to do weed and then you look
at the cannabis sectors and they're like
that science makes my head spin so it's
a very good question and frankly uh i
don't have an answer especially in 10
seconds well i think necessity is the
mother of invention
so the fact that we need it somebody's
going to figure it out their people are
figuring it out like jeff chen but i
think the other thing is
what i find in cannabis is that there's
a lot of personal stories that you have
incredibly high net worth individuals or
family offices
where they have a personal story or a
personal connection to the plant and
then you have some
people that are
single-handedly funding things because
they're passionate about what's
happening
anybody else
would like to ask a question we have one
minute less than one minute
all right i think you've taught them
everything they need to know
all right perfect
let's hear it again
for claudia marcus and jamie
and everyone