all right so yeah my name is beau
whitney i'm the chief revenue officer at
mantis growth investments basically what
mantis does is
is we buy companies
we
keep try to retain the management
in the company
optimize them
take profits and then invest those into
other companies so we're multi-state
operator we're
currently operating in nevada with
cultivation and retail
um
so today i wanted to talk about
the cannabis industry
first globally i always like to start
globally and then
talk about europe and then throw in a
little bit of hemp
and then talk about the impact of u.s
regulatory changes on the global market
so the
reform in the global basis is
accelerating
over 60 countries have
legalized cannabis in some form either
for industrial purposes adult use
medical
cbd
and by our calculations there's roughly
250 million consumers
generating about 250 billion dollars
per year and that's excluding him
and governments are
driving this reform because they see the
benefits of cannabis on their economy
either from a taxation perspective a
development perspective employment
perspective and the like
but current policies in the u.s right
now i think are actually hurting the u.s
global competitiveness
relative to you know the global market
and it's opening the door for
the rest of the world and so i'll go
into that in a little bit
um right now we're estimating the total
market between 230 billion dollars
and 250 billion dollars um
us currently holds the top spot
um but the eu represents the second
largest market
in the on the globe
but this is from a revenue perspective
there are currently 24 eu
countries that have some form of legal
access
now there were some questions i inserted
this at lunch there are some questions
about the total
legal market for
for cannabis in the united states we're
forecasting
about 25 billion this year growing to
about 45 billion by 2025
so there's still
good opportunity for growth assuming
that there's some regulatory changes now
when i look at this graph i see that
green
as the legal market
but the difference between that green
and the top of that orange there that's
opportunity to me and so there's still a
great deal of opportunity within the u.s
market as there is in the european
market the african market the asian
markets
now
mantis collaborates with
my firm whitney economics and so we do a
lot of data sharing and we use data in
our in our decision making process for
investments
market entry strategies and the like
and we have a forecast for every country
in the world from a total addressable
market perspective
now what we're forecasting actually and
this seems counter narrative
we're actually forecasting an eventual
decline in the total addressable market
in the u.s
and it's because that as the market
opens in the u.s there's going to be an
influx of low-cost cannabis products
which will drive down the price
and there will be less spending even
though there may be more consumers
there'll be less spending and so we're
actually
thinking that
north america's nearest peak in terms of
total addressable market value
now
on the eu side
just five countries represents about 60
to 63 percent of the total market value
in the european union it's about 63
billion dollars
italy france germany uk and spain
um
now
if you think about this at look at
germany for example 8.4 billion dollars
you've got 80 000 medical consumers
arguably a couple hundred billion or a
couple hundred million in sales
so the difference between that couple
hundred million
and eight
point 8.4 billion once again is
opportunity
and i think governments like to see
large numbers
they like the taxation they like the
employment
they like all that
which is represented in that opportunity
so
there's
it's important to
realize where the opportunities lie
and then position yourself in order to
enter into those markets at such a time
that you can take advantage of that
growth situation
so being a medical supplier for example
especially in the eu
could pave your way towards accelerated
growth
once more reform occurs
or establishing a brand say in cbd or in
hemp
positioning yourself in the market and
then taking advantage of growth that way
too
and one other thing here is
that
access defines
opportunity so if there's a great deal
of control over the market you're not
going to have as much opportunity but if
you open things up for adult use and
like
then you can accelerate and capture that
market share
so access equals opportunity
so
we also
look at markets
not from a dollar perspective i think an
earlier
speaker mentioned
that there's a human element to this and
so let's not forget about that
but it's surprising to note that
europe is ranked fourth when it comes to
the total number of cannabis consumers
globally
and
asia and africa actually represent the
top two markets
um and so
the way that i view this as well is
if you can look at these markets
see where there's a lot of consumers
even though it may not be a tremendous
amount you can position yourself and
capture that and hold you know your
first mark first mover position
for quite some time
so
western europe there's really no
surprise here italy france germany spain
there's a lot of consumers there from
this perspective but there's also a lot
of consumers in eastern europe and
southern europe
and there's a dynamic here where the
periphery countries are the suppliers
and the western european countries are
the consumers
and so there's this you know center
periphery dynamic that's in play and
so
seeing this and understanding it is
going to play a role
in how the market is shaped moving
forward
so there's
like i said there's
a lot of economic benefits associated
with cannabis um
you know in addition to
medical and full legalization
and there's a lot of traction
covid was interesting in the in the
sense that it actually hurt people's
access through the lack of ability for
regulators to get to
inspections and like but it also
accelerated the conversation
saying hey there's maybe a constraint
like they occurred in italy or france
and we need to
drive greater access because there or
greater supply in the market because
there's less access
and brexit was kind of interesting
timing as well because that kind of
messed up
that the opportunity in the in the
trajectory of the uk market
um basically it stifled the imports that
was driving the supply and as a result
it stalled out the growth in the market
um
and
you know each one of these
markets is different
and
success is defined by the ease of your
regulatory activities and the like
and there's some obstacles obviously
there with
barriers to entry and the like
but
but you know even though there are these
opportunities
there's still a couple of headwinds like
regulatory murkiness high barrier sentry
in the like
but i think if these five or six
countries i have listed here
if they all converge about the same time
it'll drive opportunities not only
within western europe but eastern
southern northern europe as well
so rather than takeaways i think these
are more observations
um
a lot of the suppliers that i've talked
to
in asia and india
in africa
south america and like
they're all focusing in on the european
market in germany in particular
but if they all actually are able to
supply into this market there's going to
be so much supply that it's going to
drive down prices
it's going to create an oversupply
situation
so even though european market
represents great opportunity um there is
a risk that operators need to be aware
of
um and one thing that's interesting
about europe is that they're actually
setting standards i know there's been a
lot of discussion
about the problems associated with
with
eu gmp and getting certified but i think
those standards will proliferate across
the globe and will drive standards in
the u.s as well
so
you know it's kind of take the good with
the bad i guess
and it's still dynamic
so
you know i think most of the issues
if you're a supplier trying to feed into
the european union
a lot of the issues occur on the inbound
side it's easy to get product
out of the country but it's really
difficult to get it into a country uk is
a prime example but switzerland and and
other countries within the eu are are
facing those problems and so
it's i think it's critical that you
partner with
not only a good eu licensee but partner
with a good european familiar logistics
company and supply chain company so that
you can
not have your product sitting at the
port
gathering dust or rotting as it you know
sits in a container
so i've got some recommendations here
i'm not going to go through them all but
here's some of the top five markets and
some areas where you might want to look
at positioning your your products and
there's really three big opportunities
pharma medical and consumer product
goods uh cbd
falls into all three of these
but it's really important to
knowing what market you want to get into
having a vision taking advantage of that
and really committing to it rather than
trying to be all things to all people
that's
very rarely successful
and i think it's important also given
how dynamic the market is to remain very
very nimble
and adjust to the market conditions as
they change and they will change
so i want to switch gears a little bit
to him
there's a lot of discussion today about
hemp as well
hemp has a long tradition in the eu
mainly on the fiber and grain side but
now
there's a
you know this emerging cbd market
i have here is a
number of acres planted in a number of
acres that were planted that's
associated with cbd
globally it's about 56 60 percent
is dedicated to cbd of the planted acres
but maybe
50 or so in the european union
and
if
if there's not enough demand
and you start importing from canada from
the u.s from china
there could be a pretty significant
impact on the on the market both here
and abroad
so
i look at the
at the market somewhat differently seems
like a lot of the analysts right now are
focused on the retail demand
i look at the capacity in the market how
much can the market supply
and it really
you know shifts your focus a little bit
um and i'm
because
um there's the forecasts right now are
so dynamic out there that it's tough to
understand who's the most accurate
or you know and like so there's some
problems with forecasting these days
especially given the lack of systemic
data systems
but i'm forecasting that the eu has
enough capacity
on the hemp side cbd side to satisfy 4.3
billion dollars in retail demand
and this is based upon
isolate i could do this for full
spectrum
or whatever but i just chose
isolate because it's
the
lowest yield and so it's this is
but high cost of production
now there's lots of forecasts so
depending upon which forecast you
believe
there's either too much supply
of cbd in the from the europeans or
there's not enough and if there's not
enough then that's great for
importation for exporters from other
markets
but if there's
too little
um
or if there's too much then
you know
that you know that's problematic as well
so i think in europe for cbd the
opportunity is good but
it's not
a panacea
uh you know you're not gonna plant some
plants harvest them
and then get rich right and live in
mallorca or something um so and not
everybody will win
so in terms of an outlook while
cbd is sexy for now
there's lots of opportunities the
opportunities for fiber and grain is
transformational there's opportunities
in automotive
in textiles in plastics and construction
especially on the fiber side
and there's strong opportunities in
grain as well for animal and human
consumption
so
my best advice is
establish relationships now
develop the supply chain
partner with eu members and then partner
with people abroad
and then expect price decreases as the
market settles
and pick a path you can't do it all
so
the topic of full federal legalization
has been
in a lot of the media especially in the
united states
and
there's some bills that have been
proposed
that could be really just horrible for
the u.s cannabis market the higher thc
side
and
a couple of the bills namely the
more recent caoa and the more act on the
house side
is they're not expected to pass but
they're setting kind of a dangerous
precedent for
policy
but assuming that those
don't pass
there's still a movement afoot to drive
full federal legalization in the united
states
the impact that this will have will be
rather profound
it'll accelerate the pace of reform
worldwide
it will influence international treaties
because
cannabis is demonized throughout the
world
and that will draw the attention also
into the u.s right now some of the
policies being proposed allow for
immediate importation from other
countries into the u.s
so
while the focus right now is on the eu
there's going to be a lot of opportunity
on the export side into the u.s
given that
international suppliers will have a
competitive advantage
relative to the u.s suppliers if a lot
of these policies are implemented
um
and so this will lead to an expansion of
the global supply chain
it'll introduce opportunities in on
practically every continent um and then
ultimately as the market settles then
proximity to markets will play a role
you know the suppliers in azerbaijan
will
be here the suppliers in central and
south america and mexico will focus on
the on the north american market
so in that sense as the dust settles
there'll be this proximity play
and so right now
is the time to set up those
relationships
but
in the meanwhile this this whole
regulatory murkiness
regardless of if it's local
in germany
in switzerland
in south america and north america
that remains the number one risk to the
industry
until that's settled
then it's really tough to understand the
rules of the game it's really tough to
understand your business plans your
profitability and the like
so in summary um
well
i want to thank the icbc team
uh for this opportunity to speak um this
has been a great first day we've got
another speaker coming up which we'll
talk about investment and like in in
both cannabis and hemp but
um you know
this marketplace is very dynamic right
now
um but this is just the beginning and so
a lot of folks are thinking that they're
fatigued that they've been doing this
for four five ten years and they're done
but this is just the beginning
but when you do operate
be sure to think about this global
opportunity in the global competition
the global supply chain
but when you're thinking about that
global
situation global environment be sure to
act local because really
right now
cannabis is a local phenomenon
so thank you very much i can take some
questions yes yes let's hear it one more
time vote whitney
um thank you for the presentation and i
can subscribe a lot of it but i'm
interested in your assessment that
when us is changing the legislation
europe will follow
what makes you believe that i think
there were a lot of u.s companies who
thought putting the boot on the grounds
will change his europe
and move to the u.s attitude and we did
not see that we see tesla now failing
why you think it will do so because
exchanging with the international
narcotic control board
i don't see that
yes so thank you for the question
um really it the question is is why do i
think that
the u.s legalization will have an
influence on the european market
the way that i view this is that
when you have a large market
and they legalize adult use then there's
this ripple effect we saw in the united
states on the west coast one
state legalized then the next then the
next
that same type of phenomena will occur
from country to country so if the u.s is
legal and there's this great opportunity
then not only does it drive these
international treaties and changes to
the un unodc and all these other
policies but those policies have been
restricting the growth of all of the
markets in the world
so by
by influencing these treaties
and by driving this cascade effect
through legalization at the adult use
level it will have this contagion that
will carry over into the european market
and then elsewhere
thank you very much for this very
informative
speech my name is luke i'm a cannabis
filmmaker
um
i really loved your last point like this
think global act local
my first cannabis hemp reference was
visiting the himalayan mountains in
nepal witnessing minorities excluded
from society using wild plants for good
for establishing a very local
beneficial economy model that is
basically beneficial for everyone so
my question is like how do we get there
we are talking about legislations laws
like so much bureaucracy
just taking your last point for me it
seems like the easiest way to make this
think local
think global act local point
happen
is to just leave everyone using the
plant the way they want to
what do you think about this
yeah i
right now the way that regulatory
structures are operating is they want to
control things they
they think that cannabis is is a bad
thing and even though they're trying to
reform
they're still trying to control even on
the hemp side they're treating it as
though it's illegal even though for the
most part it's been generally legalized
and
but
i think on the local side
when there's job creation
where there's that
you know everybody has a story about
their cannabis use and their cannabis
story it's you know they got into the
industry because of
of their sister or their brother their
wife or their husband you know because
of some ailment that cannabis has been
used to help address
it's those localized stories
that really change policy and generate
momentum
and so
so i think on the on the act local side
it's more about how to drive reform
and one are the comment on that
i've been giving a lot of speeches
around the globe recently
but i've been speaking to small
audiences
in some instances like
city councils mayors police departments
and you know they once they're
they see the value and that the plant
actually does a lot of wonderful things
then they tend to
be more willing to embrace it but that
educational process it takes time
and you have to do it on a city by city
community by community basis so
it's really at this point it's still
very very local
hi first thanks for all the data
material you shared with us was exciting
great numbers and i wanted to ask you
about what you said about regulation in
europe and how it would affect like the
global market i was pretty surprised
about that because i wouldn't have
expected that new usa would have an eye
on european regulation
and which field exactly and
why and how do you
think
like european regulation could affect
for example u.s market
yeah so
so currently in the in the u.s there are
some standards but they're not very
uniform or widespread they're not
adopted
um and as a result there could be some
public safety issues associated with the
way that the market's operating right
now
and so by having an example like
eu gmp certification
if that it becomes the de facto standard
in the united states
then there's this public safety
element associated with that and so i
think
on the public safety side this is where
europe has the lead right now
and are starting to influence and given
the fact that there's so much
focus on the european market
people want to conform to that standard
and that will be a differentiating
factor for operators in these other
countries that don't have these
standards already established so i think
that
that will become
the it'll take kind of the wild west
out of
the american market and other markets
and will actually drive
responsible practices throughout the
entire supply chain
are there any other questions
no
well fine then
i'm not running all the way back there
all right let's hear it one more time
for beau whitney
[Applause]
[Music]
you