hey it's great to be back to icbc again
this year uh
uh it's my second time attending this
conference uh i was really looking
forward to this this year last year was
so good um and i made so many contacts
and got the chance to learn a ton about
what's happening here in europe uh i was
really excited at the opportunity to
come back
and be part of
this program so uh i wanted to maybe
just
spend a little bit of time this is
always uncomfortable for me so bear with
me but just kind of talking a little bit
about my background
so you guys kind of give some context
for some of the other things that i'm
going to talk about
and
some of the experiences i've had here in
the cannabis industry so
getting into that
i started my career as a police officer
so i was a police officer in a city just
outside denver colorado
and while i was a police officer i was
going to grad school getting my mba an
international business
and i got recruited by the department of
revenue which is the agency that does
all the taxing et cetera but they also
have enforcement groups like law
enforcement agencies that oversee gaming
liquor
and in 2010 we started overseeing
cannabis regulation when we started
licensing on businesses
in colorado and that's when i
transitioned from the gaming division to
the marijuana enforcement division to
help
establish that agency and when i first
got involved in that on the medical side
my boss told me it's gonna be about 10
15 maybe 20 years before we legalized
cannabis for adult use but it was only
two short years later and we
had a constitutional amendment that
changed the law from just medical to
including adult use and we were
implementing that as well
so my job at that time was as the
director of the marijuana enforcement
division and i was responsible for
starting a new agency
leading the teams that created all the
regulations in colorado
and also i served as a subject matter
expert
with our legislature to help kind of
inform how that policy could evolve over
time so all in all i've got background
in law enforcement
background is a policy maker
i'm also a
business background now that i've been
working in the private sector with
metric for 2019 since 2019
where
we operate in 20 different states where
we help track all the cannabis for uh
regulators in those states
and then i also have an academic
background and the reason why that's
important is because
over time i've really developed a
passion for
arriving at balance public policy
because i really think it's possible
especially in the cannabis space where
everybody everybody industry
public health officials government we
can put public health and safety first
but also do that in a way where we
balance
the business interests of cannabis
companies operating in the framework
all right so i thought i'd start with
where i've had most of my experience
um as you look at this uh map of the u.s
you'll see that uh like 36 different
states have adopted some form of
legalization whether it's medical or
retail by the way if you see uh the dark
i'm sorry the bright green states are
the uh the recreational states um those
all have medical programs as well but 36
states that are operating in this in
with legalization
and
as i mentioned before we operate in 20
of these states uh tracking cannabis for
government
but what i think is most important i
really want to emphasize here is
ten years ago most of these states
didn't have any kind of program and this
these these changes don't occur unless
you have public policy to support it
right so public policy has to change
from and in our case in the us it's
changing from a policy was more focused
on criminal enforcement and
transitioning to a regulatory model that
was much more permissive
so
if i think about it that way and i think
there's i look back on everything that
i've witnessed over the last 10 years
operating in the space
i'd say there's like three forces that
are at play
that if you can kind of understand those
three you kind of start to anticipate
when you think public policy in this
particular area is going to change
and so there's three areas the first one
i want to talk about is uh the problem
like think of it as a stream
that's flowing they're all three
independent when all three streams come
together
you have a window of opportunity where
you'll see public policy change the
first stream is the problem stream
and in the problem stream
basically the the public sentiment is
changing such
that
you can it favors one or new outcomes or
evolution of public policy over the
others so think of this as public
opinion shifting
from one one to one one aspect of public
policy to the other so as i mentioned
earlier uh we were shifting from
criminal enforcement type of posture
more towards a permissive cannabis
policy and we knew that because public
polling was telling us that
the mood was changing the media was
talking about the need for change so the
problem was really kind of palatable i
think most of what i heard yesterday
um about europe is the same is that the
the moot's changing so that's the first
stream that's the the problem stream the
next one is the policy stream and the
policy should just think of it as
everybody who wants to get involved with
solving that problem so once the problem
gets to a point where most people kind
of agree that it's a problem that's time
for change the status quo needs to
change you start seeing lobbyists
entrepreneurs businesses all starting to
come up with ways to be able to solve
those problems
and so they start to collectively get
together to come up with ideas on how
that's going to best be served
and if that does really well then the
third stream is the political stream and
the political stream is such that
you start to see elected officials or
people that are in
uh
positions of trust that have the ability
to create public policy like regulators
etc they start to get actively involved
and coming up with
the actual outputs like bills and new
regulations and those kinds of things
so we saw this play out in the u.s time
and time again from one state to the
next state where the problem stream
the policy stream and the political
stream all started to converge and
create these policy windows and one
consistent thing that happened in all
the states was a interest in being able
to collect data
that can help inform a lot of those
decisions and one other consistent piece
of that was track and trace that's where
metric is really closely involved is
helping government track cannabis from
the time baby plant to the time it's a
final product at the point of sale so we
collect a lot of data and the reason why
data is so important is all three of
those streams the problem the policy and
political they all feed off of data they
look at they use the data to make their
points
for change in the future
so that's the u.s
we see all three
of these police all three of these
streams
actively involve or actively increasing
and converging here in europe and
thinking more specifically about germany
we all have seen
the the end result or like the all three
of these streams active over the last
couple of days so if you look at some of
this data certainly in europe it would
appear that public sentiment towards
legalization both on the medical side
and the adult use side
is increasing
so public
opinion around a particular policy issue
is really really important to that
problem stream
so it's getting a lot of attention and
on the policy side of things which is
almost everybody in this room in some
way shape or form is trying to find
solutions to
uh that problem like how do we
change from the status quo that we
currently sit in
and get to the next level of change
that's going to be meaningful that can
protect public health and safety but
also create a business model
um and then the second thing that i'd
like to say is that we also like so look
just back back a quick step i think
everybody in this room is in some way
shape or form actively involved
like whether you know it or not in the
policy side of things we all want to
find solutions i heard yesterday on
several of the panels and from some of
the keynotes that
we
are the ones that are most likely to
bring the best solutions to government
to be able to fix this and what i think
makes this more exciting than anything
is that yesterday we also had
politicians that were here we had point
e we had elected officials that were
basically telling us that they already
kind of concluded
that the current situation in germany
uh needs to be uh needs to evolve and
that we want to see
uh change and that that change is likely
to be in the form of either expanded
medical or adult use but which but even
though i think
we didn't get like that clear framework
like this is exactly what we're going to
do this is exactly what the bill is
going to look like it was very symbolic
to have people who are operating in the
political stream
come here yesterday and talk to us about
how they're committed to
some form of advancing of legalization
policy here in germany so we're excited
about what's happening here in europe
there is all three streams are are there
i think
uh you have public sentiment
is really geared towards
uh more towards legalization or at least
it's heading that direction there's a
lot of groups getting together like this
to come up with solutions uh and the
politicians are actively involved in in
change
so
now that we're if if we're kind of like
somewhat in agreement that that's the
situation we should start thinking a
little bit more about what government's
role should be in this
and uh i think
like one of the biggest challenges the
government faces uh in this is balancing
all the different interests that exist
so i kind of explained earlier the three
streams
the problem stream
and all the people that are engaged in
that
this policy stream
and all the groups and people that are
involved in that and all the politicians
that are involved in the political
streams i kind of explained all those as
being monolithic groups
uh that uh
um
all agree on the direction but that's
not the case there are all forms or
there's all different types of opinions
on how this policy should evolve over
time
and
government's role should be to try and
help
include all those different voices to
find out where the bridges are and being
able to form public policy uh that works
for everybody if i hadn't seen myself if
you're skeptic or just really tired
because it's so early in the morning
about it if i hadn't seen it for myself
i'd probably join skeptics in the room
on how challenging that is and while it
is challenging and it is hard i really
believe that you can hit but you can
reach public policy that balances public
health and safety and some of the main
concerns the government has but also be
able to
like allow for
a business or or an industry that can
not only survive in that but actually
thrive in that in that arena so the
government's role should be
trying to balance all those interests
and there's like four things that we've
seen i'll go through these pretty
quickly but
there's four things that that we've seen
uh that we see as success factors so
when government really considers these
four things deeply um and they're in the
process of developing public policy if
they
if they take these into consideration
there's a real strong likelihood of
having a strong regulated market so the
first one's implementation timeline the
next one is including diverse
stakeholders
in the process
talk a little bit about financial
expectations in particular like tax
structure
and what's important there and then also
the centralized data collection
so i'm going to go into these each a
little bit more detail so the
implementation timeline so
what often happens is
uh public officials who are responsible
for writing the first public policy
um they pass it
they go out on the steps of parliament
or the steps of the state house and
they're high-fiving each other with
their big accomplishment and that's
where the real work begins that's what
regulators are coming in to to implement
the policy businesses or trying to
make sure that they can keep up with the
short timelines what we've seen time and
time again
as government have been implementing
this policy is that they didn't give
themselves enough time or they didn't
consider all the different voices that
were important to determine whether or
not those timelines were realistic or
not so a couple of
a couple examples of this
often times
the testing facilities that are
responsible for
providing tests
there's not enough of them so so you
have this public policy in place that
says it's
got to be january 1st of 2023
and you have to do all this testing and
there's not enough testing facilities to
actually test the product
or similarly
there's this expectation that there's
going to be 200 cultivations that are
licensed by january 1st there's going to
be 500 stores and they don't take into
account the fact that local
jurisdictions so cities
where these flights and premises are
have all sorts of system
processes that they have to go through
to approve a business
that's not even canvas business
sometimes it can take six months to a
year to get that done and so if you're
not thinking about that oftentimes the
tax projections are off because
those businesses didn't open up as
quickly as they thought so on the
implementation timeline side of things
but i would just like make sure that
it's like important understand is that
you've got to give yourself enough time
and what's even more important is you
have to make sure that you include the
right stakeholder groups in the process
of determining determining what those
timelines are because if you don't
chances are good
that you're going to miss something and
you're not going to be able to implement
on time because it's just not literally
not possible for
the different
dependencies to be met in time
so
diverse viewpoints this is that area
that i was talking about earlier that
i'm so passionate about you cannot reach
balanced public policy in a vacuum so
government officials and a former
government official admit i couldn't do
this i couldn't just like listen to a
few people and then lock myself in a
room and write about a bunch of policy
and have it be effective right you have
to
include as many stakeholders as you can
to the table to be able to
better understand uh what their needs
are what their limitations are and the
types of things that they can or can't
do to get a policy implemented this is
very very important in legalization in
fact i would say that um
with the research that i did while i was
finishing up my dissertation a couple
things that i found
that helps make
public policy effective and that is if
stakeholders are involved in the process
feel like they've been heard during the
process chances are good
they're going to support that policy
going forward so as a government
official i wanted as many stakeholders
to support as possible but it gets even
better if they feel like they can
educate others on their position and
they can learn from other stakeholders
we saw this time and time again in
particular i saw law enforcement's
mindset change a lot during the
regulatory process when they were
hearing from industry on some of the
challenges there were
getting the right labeling requirements
on labels getting like how like how
quickly label brick labeling regulations
change might take six months for them to
actually be able to turn that around
and get the new labeling requirements
put on the product so it was really
interesting to see law enforcement in
particular say like wait a second i
hadn't even thought about all these
challenges the business i just thought
businesses were always able to move
really quickly and so they learned a lot
so then so so it's being heard being
able to educate get educated but also
ultimately every stakeholder that's
involved in the process regardless of
which stream you're in you want to be
able to look at the public policy when
it's done and say
i can see where i influenced this public
policy i didn't get everything i wanted
but i got a bunch of what i wanted and
so i think i can live with this public
policy and i can support it going
forward so diverse viewpoints is really
really important
for
government to be successful
the next thing i wanted to talk about
was tax revenue uh and the financial
expectations around that
i don't know about you but i've heard a
lot of politicians when they think about
legalizing cannabis they kind of
gravitate towards the tax revenue that
will come in
and oftentimes the expectations they
have are high because they they think
that cannabis businesses are
wildly profitable and that they're
wildly successful and they're just
rolling in cash so we should be able to
tax i think we heard yesterday canada i
also know that california
and some of the other states the tax the
tax rates are really high and a lot of
those were set when
uh the wholesale price of cannabis was
fifteen hundred dollars and now when you
have more and more players entering the
market the cop or the price of wholesale
cannabis is going to go down and so tax
tax models based on those types of uh
wholesale prices can have impacts down
the road and so expectations around
taxes should be
that
you can certainly fund the things that
need to be focused you need to focus on
from taxing standpoint so the cost of
regulation
um
funding uh like different types of drug
treatment programs etc but you're not
gonna be able to fix all your billion
dollar problems you're not gonna be able
to fix
uh any like social injustices that
you're trying to or
fix like just with cannabis money
but you can't but it will fund itself so
cannabis legalization and the taxes that
you get from it
can do some really good work in that
case but it's not going to fix roads
it's not going to build new schools it's
not going to do a lot of those other
things
so setting some of those financial
expectations as a government official is
really important but it's also be really
mindful of how you structure that such
that industry can have competitive
pricing
to an illicit market you have to be able
to compete with the illicit market if
you if you if you don't then then it's
difficult and i think like people always
ask me like hey what keeps you awake at
night when you were government
officially trying to do this my one one
thing that oddly enough was i was really
concerned
that consumers wouldn't shift their
buying patterns from
an illicit market to a regulated market
i was afraid that the price was gonna be
so disparate
that that wasn't uh that that wasn't
gonna be something that they did right
and so we were hoping to try and set up
the the regulatory framework such that
there was some level of parity or at
least close between an illicit market
and a regulated market think about this
the canvas market is very artisan
right so they're very
tied closely with the the group or the
or the producer of their cannabis and so
it's not easy to get them to change even
if it's better quality product it's
tested there's good information on the
labels
so
being able to switch those buying
patterns the taxing structure can't be
such that they can't compete in price
the the last thing i want to talk about
of these four is the the database and i
know this gets like really into my
wheelhouse
and my role at metric and i've kind of
talked a little bit more about what
track and trace is but
it's very important as i mentioned
before to everybody in this ecosystem
around cannabis legalization it's very
important that we have data to inform
decisions about the policy whether it's
trying to
increase public opinion about the
potential for a credible regulated
market whether it's trying to find new
solutions to complex problems
that we face
in new regulated markets or whether it's
politicians using that data to help
evolve or evaluate the policy all those
things are important and there's a great
opportunity
at
right now in europe as governments are
contemplating new regulatory frameworks
to create a data collection methodology
that that helps to inform all the
stakeholders in the ecosystem
so
what we do as a company is we track
cannabis for government
from the time it's a little baby plant
until it's final product at the point of
sale and all that data uh is utilized to
inform a lot of those decisions that
that um i was talking about earlier but
the most important thing i want to
to say here's it is possible to
efficiently collect this data in
like during normal operational business
routines
and utilize that data to be able to
keep your regulators informed almost in
real time so that the work that they do
to do audits etc like that is not
creating like a hardship for the company
it's very very important that government
can be efficient so i'm talking about
roles for government very very important
that they can be efficient and how they
do that so here's kind of how we do it
so we have a database
um uh every
plant
every
movement of that plant through the
supply chain harvesting
all the testing results
all the transportation
and all the financial transactions that
happen at the wholesale tier
and at the point of sale are collected
in companies normal like every day
business systems that they use those
business systems typically uh integrate
with our system and they share data back
and forth so that government has
one database
with a with data in it that's
consistently collected all the way
through
the stream of commerce so in other words
regulators don't have to learn
20 or 30 point of sales systems or 15 to
20 different erp systems
or
various different data analytical
systems they have to know their system
and the licensees report while they're
doing their normal business activities
their systems report back and forth into
it symmetric
taking a little bit deeper dive on that
is uh
as plants are as marijuana is planted
um each tag once it gets to a certain
height or each plant once it gets to a
certain height gets attacked
that tag has information about the name
of the license
where it where the license is located
etc and so
as those plants work their way through
the process as they trim them
as they record waste
all those things all that information
like movement from a veg state to a
flowering state all those data points
are collected
until it's harvested and then is that
because that material is ready to move
either to a manufacturer decree
concentrates or it's ready to go to a
store with smokeable cannabis um the
transportation's uh information is
collected and stored in the system along
with all of the testing that occurs
and
we can also go so far as to collect any
public government wants all the
nutrients and pesticides and things that
were used in the system in fact we're
currently working on uh some additional
functionality in our system where
licensees if they want to report
sustainability measures they would be
able to do that in the system to how
much water how much energy those types
of things would be things they could use
to help not only inform their own
business decisions but also to keep
government informed on what's going on
bottom line is this
product gets tracked all the way through
government has real real-time access
into that and so they can monitor
activities for compliance in real time
uh as uh the data's being collected and
they can make it a lot easier for uh
compliance to be shown and demonstrated
without having to go in
and move uh plants around and scan
barcodes etc
so
um as i'm getting ready close up because
i did want to leave a few minutes for
questions if i if i can but i want to
just like the benefits of having a good
track and trace system and the benefits
of having collecting the right data
along the way is really crucial
especially at the point we're in for
demonstrating credibility of the
regulated system i think all of us are
really interested and are genuinely
concerned about public health and safety
and wanting to be able to show that the
that the the industry can show
demonstrate to other stakeholders in
this in the space
that we can form a credible regulated
framework that we care about public
health we care about safety use
consumption all those things are very
very important to us as an industry and
we have the ability to be able to
demonstrate that so it creates
transparency in the marketplace
when i think about transparency in the
marketplace i'm not talking about just
us as an industry making the case to
government it's us putting government in
this in a position where they can be
transparent with us too this is how
we're going to regulate these are the
requirements if you do this you can be
reasonably assured that you're in
compliance all those things are really
important and by doing that we're all
kind of like benefit from having a
really safe marketplace
where product
quality goes up
product safety goes up
and we can provide a much better product
that is at the right price where
consumers will change their buying
patterns and also too there's uh the
security
side of things where
we're talking about
um
uh being able to ensure that
illicit actors that are not wanting to
on-ramp into the regulated marketplace
are not able to participate as easily in
the regulated marketplace because the
regulated marketplace
is such that uh it shines a bright light
on illicit actors the plan by itself is
indistinguishable as a regulated plant
or a illicit plan so the regulated
marketplace
can really benefit from being able to
secure the regulated market or the
supply chain such that it makes it much
more difficult for illicit actors
to get in and to the to the industry or
infiltrate it and do greater credibility
and then the last thing is just the
reporting side
i come from a regulatory background i
know from a lot of the from a lot of the
interactions that i've had with licensed
businesses
that
demonstrating compliance and the cost of
regulation can be very very high and so
we've gone to great lengths as a company
a lot of the work that i did as a policy
maker was based on hitting that balance
to where businesses in the cannabis
industry
not only can survive but really thrive
if it's done well
and they can report and kind of like
reduce those costs of compliance
so
with that
i would also just say
even though
i kind of focused on track and trace and
some of the benefits of tracking trades
all four of these things that you're
looking right now are also benefits or
good outcomes for any regulatory
structure we care about transparency we
care about safety uh we care about
creating efficiencies for businesses and
in in in building a secure a secure
supply chain so that i'd love to like
take a few questions if we have a few
minutes lewis koski everybody let's hear
it
uh i have a question why are we treating
weed like it's yellow cake uranium okay
uh we have time for one question up here
and then we have to move on
that was very good
uh lewis thanks for the presentation uh
brian roth with elevated signals i'm
curious if you could comment on
the alignment of a best interest
in the states
obviously you guys are contracted uh in
the u.s you guys are contracted by
states or the government is your
customer
um how could how can
the alignment of
business interests in terms of data and
what the government wants to track be
kind of better aligned in terms of
regulation um you know how can that
happen in europe
so from understanding your question
right i think i think what um
we've seen in the u.s and i think is
possible here in in
europe
um is
for government to be really in tune with
what the business interests are so i
think everybody recognizes the fact
we've heard this time and time again the
last couple days we we're here
we have an interest in making money we
want to create profitable businesses i
think if government can get past the
fact that businesses are looking for
that they have other needs that they're
trying to meet too there's a lot of
companies in the cannabis industry there
are mission-driven companies that care
about patients they care about providing
quality product
and they want to do a lot they have a
lot of the same
objectives that government has
is trying to make sure that they're
aligned with
the burdens of being a part of a
regulated community that's why we think
it's so important for government to make
sure that they're engaged with
stakeholders
to better understand those needs not
just hear a couple of comments here and
there but actually
like meaningful engagement with them uh
to better understand what their needs
are and then also to having efficient
systems in place if you've been like i'm
sure most people here have been to
cultivations i've been to hundreds of
cultivations in my career
and there's just no way to
audit uh plants that are in uh like a
veg state to a flowering state without
moving them all around you know so we
try to create a system where
government's able to be able to do that
much more efficiently without creating
business disruptions and so i think when
we're trying to balance those needs you
have to be able to
balance like what's the right level of
public health and safety
versus what's uh what's the business
needs and then create systems and
processes like that so it's efficient
thank you very much one more time lewis
koski
[Applause]
you