so good morning everyone isn't this an
awesome event right how many of you how
many of you have only come here for the
first time hanzo
all right this is awesome we're growing
it's it's been going since 2017 and it
is only going to get better but anyway
this morning we are going to have a
great conversation about cannabis in
technology and i think the first
question that comes out of this is is
our panel named the right way or should
it be in reverse and why
go for it guys
anybody what so we uh right for
preparing for this conversation we think
it should be reversed so i don't think
it should be cannabis and biotechnology
we agree that it should be
uh biotechnology in cannabis
if that's okay with everybody and why do
you say that why why why are you all in
agreement with that
and in the biotech world is the rules
have been formed for quite a long time
um and we came into it and we want to
change the rules towards
what we wanted to be
so i'm a medical doctor for education
and through algeria algae we care for 10
000 patients and i think at that scale
you look at things differently you're
looking at the research that's coming
out but you're always in you're in the
back of your mind thinking
how is this going to be applicable to
patients how is this going to be
available to patients and i think it's
interesting also
we did a little poll
before
the session and just asked
participants of the session does your
doctor right now
actually know about terpene profiles and
does he or she
you know use that information for
treatment and we saw that only a third
of the people responded hey my doctor
let's that influence the treatment so
just for me it's gonna deal with
advocate from a medical perspective i'm
always thinking about
okay biotechnology and we're seeing
crazy technologies coming out that we're
gonna enhance and prove the effects of
cannabis
but we're always looking at okay when
will this be applicable and let's look
at the data well i think that brings up
a really good point right so actually
just like the pharma pharmaceutical
discussion cannabis was banned as a
plant and a drug right around the time
that the formal pharmaceutical industry
got going in the 1930s
so
how do you guys think from a medical
perspective from an investment
perspective from an extraction
perspective
that this plant is going to impact the
biotechnology industry and or vice versa
i know that's a big question but you
know highlights
i think we actually have a unique
opportunity here from medical
perspective that through cannabis we can
offer more personalized treatment so we
have so many
access points basically within the plant
to say we're gonna do re you know kind
of cannabis dna based treatment and
that's how we look at it so we are
completely data driven so we can plug in
actually you know starting with terpene
profiles but also look at other
biomarkers within the plant and plug
that with outcomes of patients so i
think we're just getting started
actually
you've thought something like yeah
definitely
this is just the beginning from a
scientific perspective uh currently i
think we have a 1200 1300 studies
trials going on right now with cbd
with thc 250 300 different trials um you
know they're looking at multiple
different indications different delivery
methods um you know to bring that
medication in and that's just the
beginning now
um you know that's only going forward
much quicker especially uh since the u.n
voted to to prove this to be a medicine
and as more countries come on
that's going to open up the capital flow
for people to to make these larger
investments
into the future and looking more as a
biotech rather than a recreational only
space
that you've seen in other markets well i
have to say i mean as an american german
sitting here
it is very refreshing to hear that the
doctor on the panel talk about terpenes
i mean that concession even a couple of
years ago was almost unheard of you
didn't hear that so i mean i think
there's going to be other discussions
and i wanted to get into one of the
topics that we raised in agreement which
was
what about all of the delta eight and
the delta zeros and the delta tens that
you're about coming from the us
when is that discussion gonna start to
hit here and how is that going to fit
into a more formal
biotech
structure than say just the wild west of
recreational yesterday
that's the classic
answer to almost anything when you talk
to any company you know when do you need
money or when's this going to happen
it's always yesterday in canada's right
uh real quick though a couple numbers
you know there's a reason why there's an
investment banker on this panel
just a couple couple quick few numbers i
have two undergrad degrees in science
i worked for 15 years in biotech
companies and veteran on three u.s
patents
i worked in investment banking 17 years
now
uh we've worked in cannabis in the u.s
and north america for eight years we've
worked internationally in cannabis for
six
and then also i've been
for the last two years chairman of the
scientific advisory council for athletes
for care which is composed of four
leading scientists ethan versailles
guillermo moreno-san sans from spain
um raquel perube and deb kimlis
but yes
we've worked with a client that's uh
making uh we actually talked to a client
yesterday he's uh making hhc
so i don't know if you guys have heard
that but instead of tetrahydrocannabinol
it's hexahydrocannabinol
so that's got a whole different form
factor to it and then you have acetyl
groups being added to the things and
then also in europe one thing to bring
up that's interesting
the united circuit court of appeals
about two months ago allowed and came
out and said that delta eight thc is
actually now legal nationally under the
farm bill
so
yeah to your question
where is this all going and frankly i am
you know i i don't know
i mean this is this is one of the big
problems right so if you have a let's
say a delta 8 which is also being made
from cbd right now in the united states
once you get into a much more formalized
environment which is europe and the
medical discussion
how do you see
path to market market authorizations
happening
in a situation where again it's even
more unusual than the drug cannabis or
do you see as this becomes more accepted
within the biotech and pharmaceutical
community that will flip any thoughts on
this
i mean it's an interesting perspective
when you you have like the u.s
perspective
you juxtapose that to the uh the way
europe is looking at it
i'm sure the us and producers you know
what they're pushing the limits
um and you know the politicians
you know are either embarrassed to
address the issue
or some of the stakes are addressing the
issue and combining these new uh uh
semi-synthetics um you know either under
cannabis or allowing them to uh to
proliferate
um
you know but
you're very limited uh from the european
perspective um you know these kind of
advances would require in my mind at
least uh clinical trials and more data
in order you know to bring these to
market or bring these to fruition and at
this point uh you know uh you know we
for sure are gonna be making for our
indeed purposes semi-synthetics um but
the usage is is not yet clear uh in the
market and even the terpenes uh you know
we're we're registering those as
excipients uh flavor you know flavor um
you know we're not making claims as to
what their positive or negative effects
may be
um so you know it's fun to watch it from
the u.s perspective they're
way out there you know on these products
and in a good way i don't mean it
negatively but you know we also have to
find out what is the exact science
behind it to make this a reality for
europe in my mind
well my that's my next question is the
biotech discussion really only limited
to the medical discussion or is it a
broader
spectrum of discussion and it would be
interesting actually from to hear from
me from europe okay you know us being
advanced let's say somewhere between six
to 20 years i guess some ballpark number
but what does it actually mean within
the country so all the new research all
the new applications all the biotech
innovations in the us are they being
applied in the u.s or is it still kind
of you know lab benchmark
but you guys
that's a good question
i think one thing that's interesting
that we've been trying to do and i think
everybody in this audience would agree
that
everybody knows somebody that's used
some kind of preparation and it's really
helped them out so there's a lot that's
the problem is there's all this
anecdotal data there's no doubt this
plan works i think the one thing that
we're trying to do we've always tried to
work with companies and provide capital
so they can do the right experiments to
get the right data whether it's in a
clinical trial or something less
i think everybody would agree our
perspective is the entourage effect is
real
but i think in order to really get the
value out of this plant we need to do
another molecule by molecule basis and
kind of deconstruct you know there's
over i think 600 compounds in cannabis
sativa so i think that's one thing that
i think everybody in this room and
probably everybody on the panel would be
agree we need to do the work whether
it's under stringent conditions or even
maybe less changing conditions to find
out really what is the value of this of
this plan and on a molecular basis well
when you get into delivery issues and
delivery discussions and the technology
that goes along with that i think that
that's also going to have a much more
i guess a greater impact on this
discussion but here's i'm going to flip
this back to you do you think that in
europe there's going to be more of a
focus on this discussion from the
biotechnology discussion first on the
recreational side and i'm going to throw
that out there in part because for those
of you who are not german or don't live
here the vast majority of medications in
this system are generic i mean most
germans are used to going to a doctor
getting a prescription going to the
output or the pharmacy and getting it
for 10 years because the government is
allowed to pre-negotiate contracts
is that kind of discussion going to have
an impact on this
plant and the legalization of it so far
and do you see like the united states
perhaps
more of a discussion of the
biotechnology happening in the
recreational side first because of the
regulatory structure here and the
difficulties of getting a mainstream
drug into the system
like nano for example or patches or
i think that depends a little bit on how
it all plays out so what they're ready
to reframe before legalization
recreation space will really
look like
um again i think we're in a unique
situation where we have had five years
of a medical market in germany which was
a very advanced law um especially in the
european space
and when looking at also the pay phone
we found results like a
supervisory study the results are not
great there so i think from a
politician's standpoint uh with all the
different lobbyists involved there
you're gonna look at data you're gonna
look at hard fact data which sounds a
little bit boring but
we have again also looking at new types
of applications and new types of you
know biotechnology innovations
we can apply that already now in a
medical space
you know have
have regulated results have results of
ricky ryland then applied over in a
recreational space
you're an extractor so so i'm going to
throw this back for a second
um
how do i say this
i think that the biotechnology
perspective for me is at this point is
like how do you separate the
cannabinoids out how do you make them
effective and how you bring them to
market beyond the technology itself but
here's my question to you is in the
united states right now i mean there's
probably better people out there to talk
about this but for example delta 8 seems
to me to be still a narcotic even though
it's coming from cbd so just because
you're submitting it to a process
chemical process or whatever does that
fundamentally change the nature of the
cannabinoid
i mean there's a lot to unpack there
you know from one point we're
manufacturers you know we're not
necessarily confined to the beginning
stage
of extraction so we're looking to bring
uh finished products to the market and
bring authorizations uh to the market
and germany is a little bit different in
that respect uh you know they've kind of
made their own rules you know to to
circumvent you know the herbal medicine
rules
and
that's quite complicated you know
they're they're they're stuck to a
singular molecule dronabinol
um you know and they're looking at
compounding the magisterial prep um you
know and this is fine
you know for advancing um you know at
least the beginning stages of the
advancement but when you look at market
authorizations for herbal medicines um
this is these rules have been set well
before cannabis got into play uh in
europe and you have to
think in those terms when you're making
whatever medicines you're making and
you're confined to singular elements
a thc distillate cbd distillate thca
and these ones like cdn which you're
seeing popping up in switzerland
and the uk and
these don't exist in the monographs you
know currently so you know there's a lot
of there's
there's a nice building blocks in the
beginning uh you know for us to develop
medicines and there's a clear pathway
with some countries uh to get these
authorizations and as other countries
kind of you know develop their rules and
even if germany let's say goes
recreational what does that mean
maybe that'll be a flourishing flower
market and at the end you know the
doctors will be looking for innovative
products um you know more along the
extractable basis would be my guess i
mean who knows
so i'd like to go back to your question
i think margaret you had on on wreck or
don't use whatever you want to call it
biotech
so one thing i think that's interesting
for people to note is so uh back in 2013
2014 i was chief business officer of
serna which is one of the first public
companies
in the space there's a company at the
same time called ebu
heavy was in colorado and they had these
four or five formulations that you know
this is going to make you calm this is
going to make you creative
so i was lucky enough to work at a
company called a few metrics in late 90s
leading generics company and they
essentially came up with the term
pharmacogenomics because of their
technology
and that's one thing you guys ought to
note is that even on the wreck side one
thing we need to do more of is the human
genetic side so if my wife even takes a
small preparation of any kind of
cannabinoid she's gonna she goes off the
off the rails right so that's one thing
even on the rec side that we can do
better on
characterizing the human genetic side
the snips the biomarkers because
everybody most people will
will react differently to these
preparations and also for medicare so
that's actually my question in return
maybe looking at
both personalized treatment but also
personalized consumption maybe in a
recreational space again i think there's
opportunity maybe looking at dna looking
at other biomarkers
to
create products that kind of plug in
there so from a from a creation from an
extraction standpoint are you looking at
what type of data would we need from
customers patients
to then formulate something but still be
able to scale or how are you looking at
the market
okay so so we had this conversation back
in the green room as well is this plant
fundamentally different to begin with
and say
poppies why is cannabis so different
from that and what is that
going to have what impact is that going
to have on this discussion as well
well
one thought and i don't know a whole lot
about heroin and poppies but my guess is
that you know really they do try to
concentrate down heroin to the point of
uh you know that's the only active agent
but mentioned before there's over 600
it could be 600 active agents i mean
that gets back to the point of you know
are all these cannabinoids and terpenes
have some value to some indication or
i mean my guess is suddenly have no
value at all but then maybe do they have
value in combination so i think that's
one thing getting back to the entourage
effect that that's the magic uh i think
of cannabis
um are there any questions from the
audience at this point
there's one over there
well we already
[Music]
there are a lot of experts in the
audience also so there are a couple of
questions right we're all experts in
this audience let's hear it again for
margaritaville
[Applause]
i would like to know your opinions about
synthetic
well there are a number of ways using
biotechnology to produce cannabinoids
one is through um
synthetic chemistry some is by
biosynthesis using hosts like algae or
yeast or bacteria and then there's the
system that we use which is growing stem
cells of cannabis um it doesn't produce
the whole entourage effect it produces
specifically a group of cannabinoids but
this is the biotech for the production
of cannabis how is that going
how are these systems going to impact
the
regulations in the market
i think just medically speaking
as a doctor you're pretty much open to
every type of application that you know
is safe in a patient's hands
so i think
a little bit boring but also down to the
point depends on the data depends on the
results that you get of it i think what
it's interesting at these panels also we
were looking at maybe two to three
hundred thousand cannabis patients in
germany which is still tiny i mean still
by a tenfold at least so many more
patients in germany could benefit from
cannabis which also means it needs to be
more standard and it also means types of
needs to be more centered so i think
synthetics as also margaret said when it
comes to regular medication germany is
one of the ways to go
and also i mean this has been a war
waging for a long time hundreds of
millions have gone into biosynthesis
you know
you know they're trying to get
to a more economical format
you know clearly this is this is very
attractive
from the biotech industry especially
places like usa where the fda is more
guided on a synthetic basis as opposed
to an herbal medicine basis um you know
and you have to keep a global
perspective um you know you have a lot
of countries that are going to be coming
on that have more herbal medicine
you know results like india as an
example and and europe they're more
accepting
but you know clearly all of them have a
space and if you can reproduce at an
economical rate through biosynthesis
semi synthesis you know biocatalysis
whatever your process is
you know there's a market for it
one quick thing to add to that michael
is i think the interesting thing is we
have so many indications potential
indications that could be solved and you
have so many of these
these molecules in this plant that
matrix that you combine to try to find
combinations thereof it's to deconvolute
that it's it's going to be a big uh
issue but one last thing on the we don't
like to call it synthetics we like to
call it alternative production methods
but you know what we believe is we have
no idea if it's going to be used e coli
chemistry or some combination of fido
and whatever
but one thing we do believe is the way
to do it the cheapest with the highest
quality cannabinoids is probably going
to win over can i say i mean i think how
it's produced is one issue and also then
how it's absorbed by the human body if
you think about for example a technology
like nano
and if you know there's a synthetic
versus natural discussion there as well
that's getting into some very other
long and involved questions do you have
another comment to make or
i have just a question uh my name is
amig i'm impressed from falling and
representing also the medical cannabis
division of
the association the german one i think
what you're addressing is i think these
purely pharmaceutical development
questions starting from the extract
that's the biotechnology part
with the very clear guidelines on how to
to be to get a product or an active
actually approved by the authorities
and if you talk about the terpene
characterization do you really see the
chance that this can be characterized so
that it does fulfill the guidelines and
that that can
will allow an approval of
this kind of an active material
and also you're addressing uh delivery
systems nanos or whatever which is again
purely pharmaceutical questions
and i'm i still feel that the
pharmaceutical industry this audience is
a bit underrepresented and maybe my
question now to you is how do you rate
the complexity in terms of timing and in
terms of players in that area so that at
the end there will be a product that me
that does meet the market
both with full characterization of the
terpene levels and the actives but also
with delivery systems
from your background now and for your
experience from the u.s market
one thing i'd add to that
with regards whether it's the ema ema
here in europe or it's the fda
you know also i'm since i'm an
investment banker we deal with the sec i
think everybody in this audience would
agree the regulators are always behind
the curve whether it's crypto or
cannabis
and a matter of fact somebody wants to
talk to me later we've heard some recent
stuff from the fda i think that's one
question getting back to your
thought on the pharma side is the
regulators one question we need to
figure out is how to do this better
because the regulators are probably
going to screw it up
they're already screwing it up the fda
should have done a lot more than they've
already done in the u.s and the ema
supposedly you know they're sitting on
their hands too so i don't know if that
really answered your question but i
think that's yeah i think that that
describes the current situation because
regulators are really they they
you can build into this as much as you
want on complexity on the other hand
that would limit finally an improved
product but how do you rate it and how
do you see it maybe different in the u.s
go ahead
yeah
from the u.s perspective you know you
have to realize that you know from a
recreational point we can make a product
tomorrow put it right on the shelf and
sell it
and so you can make a you know hot
seller right now for you know who knows
if it's even the the efficacy is there
but it's cbn and thc for a nighttime
sleeper now is that product tested and
has that product does that product have
results uh that are tangible from a
medical perspective absolutely not
and and that's for sure um you know from
the fda perspective they turned a blind
eye to all of this and you know they're
more concentrated on the epidiolexis and
those active x's and uh and a million of
trials like i pointed out at the
beginning you know there's hundreds of
tac trials and thousands uh in the
thousand plus of cbd trials and you just
oppose that to europe uh you know and
you have you know very very strange
regulations in germany
you know that's another debate for
another time but then you have you know
countries like portugal which are
adopting the herbal rules um you know
which is a path to the acm which is a
path into the european market but these
you know germany would you know thumb
their nose up at that and say no this
isn't going to work you know but you
know we'll let a a pharmacist compound
this you know in a completely unsanitary
environment you know and that's great
you know i mean you know you have to
look at from a country to country basis
and how they're developing these rules
and are these federal regulators
overworked it do they want to deal with
this and they surely don't want to deal
with thousands of cannabis people
pushing the limits
yeah thank you but thank you oliver i'm
sorry to cut everybody off we're
running out of time let's hear it again
[Music]
[Applause]
you