[Music]
hey how's it going guys I'm Marcus
Richardson aka the bubble man help
popularized a Pioneer waterash back
about 25 years been in the industry for
a very long time hemp activism medical
cannabis and of course recreational
Cannabis I've been coming to ICBC pretty
much since the beginning uh Alex is a
good friend of mine I've known him since
back in the days of Amsterdam uh 25 plus
years ago and I've always found that
Alex has done an amazing job with ICBC
bringing together the corporates and the
Legacy you know helping push regulations
helping uh inform and educate government
and different groups that are going to
you know obviously be requiring to
understand what this industry requires
and what this industry could look like
if we all sort of got behind and and
pushed it through the way it needs to be
pushed through very different from shows
in Canada um in the sense that you know
Berlin is you know second to none for a
cannabis show the amount of companies
and people that that arrive from both
the corporate entities the Pharma
companies but also from Legacy seed
breeders and Growers and uh without ICBC
there would really be no platform for so
many of us to gather uh and it is truly
the conversations that happen at ICBC
are the conversations that will shape
the future of the Cannabis world that we
[Music]
know
oh
yes oh
[Music]
yes let me know if y'all had a good time
tonight make some [ __ ]
do bless
y'all
up