well uh guten morgen um nick easley
managing director multiverse cap also
ceo of 3c consulting been in the space
for 15 years
so from the legal industry in colorado
everything i'm going to say today is
from the trenches of the industry from
working with thousands of companies
first quick little disclaimer though
[Music]
interesting um not a lawyer i'm not a
cpa
you have to use these professionals as
this isn't like 2006 2010 in california
setting up weird businesses
you must seek out very good counsel very
good like
everything when it comes to this because
this industry we've been doing this for
now nearly two decades legally
and without these professionals all the
businesses that we've seen fail had crap
illegal didn't understand tax structures
and there's very unique tax structures
in the united states based on irc 280e
just like if you have
companies in the netherlands like bbs
here that are doing investments here how
companies are structured
matters as all of you individuals know
most of these companies this is a
startup industry full of startup
companies so there's high levels of risk
just make sure you use those
all right a quick little bit of
background
um
originally from farm country in
wisconsin you know kind of poor farm kid
area
was in the united states air
so i force languages to the military and
which is actually really helpful for
when you go from enforcing the drug war
in south america to now actually like
being one of the largest producers in
south america and working with those
organizations
um i got hurt in the service and went to
colorado to be a ski bum big fan
and
tried medical cannabis it was a really
big help for me so in 2006 i got a
medical card
and started using medical cannabis and
realized how people were growing it they
had no idea now colorado was the first
legal medical commercial program in the
world
where you could actually sell it granted
next door in the netherlands 2005 the
challenge
like they started but
realistically like for sanctioned legal
sales colorado is where we started also
first the w's market regulated marijuana
like alcohol in 2012
we passed before washington for the
first recreational cannabis in the
history of the world
next year in the netherlands not so much
legal kind of happens gray area which
we'll get into
but having worked down the united states
through over 36 states from a medical
standpoint we have 19 adult use states
11 of which have current sales
close probably i had 30 billion in
revenue this year in the united states
alone canada like 2.5 billion
you know make fun of canada a little bit
but back on that disclaimer just make
sure everything i'm going to share with
you is like truth from the industry if i
offend you your country your investments
you can't fix stupid
so i'm not here to offend them it's just
like the truth and when you fight the
truth you lose so a big thing um that we
learned you know
medical cannabis has been expanding
internationally there's a very big
difference in medical campus in the
united states
canada and uruguay compared to the rest
of the world the same with adult use
adult use in canada
legal from the from the government
everything we do in the united states is
federally illegal like i might violate
federal law every day you think pablo
escobar that's what we do in the united
states but we follow state law like i
never have broken a state law for campus
and uh federal we just try not to think
about that much but we're kind of like a
little big now so it's kind of like
happening there is like schumersville
the morax care act none of those are
going to happen so from a federal
legalization standpoint in the united
states we're always away and everything
on the table is not going to happen but
on a global standpoint it's a
compassionate use medical program under
the 1961 single treaty on psychotropic
substances from the united nations which
currently the united states and many
countries are in violation of because
some very big news happened this last
year
so there was a delayed vote with the
commission for narcotic drugs under the
international narcotics control board
for the u.n so the cnd the commission
for narcotics drugs
kind of quietly this last december which
is supposed to be march before but then
run up
um
we rescheduled canvas internationally at
the unl
so canvas is no longer the same as
heroin
like it was forever so it went to a
different schedule schedule three
knowing that it actually has additional
value
needs more medical research
so that's a big deal for investors to
know like we're not talking about heroin
anymore and we're single trafficking
cannabis yeah there's all these new
psychedelic kind of industries i think
personally and the agents are going to
be great for the mind for the body for
scientific research we're
single-tracking campus only do one crazy
thing at a time don't
you drink and drive and see
drinking driving
one weird thing at a time
if you're gonna do cannabis don't do
cannabis in cryptocurrency like one
weird thing at a time
but as you invoke it change things
and it's freaking ukraine
out of the blue or when they were doing
that vote it was like two in the morning
my time ukraine was gonna sing and he
looked forward he's like yes
he was like holy
it's like it happened by one vote and it
was ukraine seventh and ukraine didn't
then like pass them out of the bill
about a month and a half two months ago
but ukraine
yes ukraine they changed it big time so
the little thing happened this last year
growing up kind of unfortunate when it
comes to like cannabis investments and
what happened massive supply chain
eruptions
all this massive proliferation of
international expansion that we've been
doing in the united states international
security market sharing all these places
have changed the cost of construction
balloon steel packaging everything is so
much more delayed so for investments as
you were securing all these positions
and then we couldn't fly and actually
take care of these portfolio companies
got crazy like when the one
caps away the mice will play i see a lot
of faces in here who know like i've
worked with you in africa and south
america in asia and it's like what's
going on in that country
we don't know we can't get there like
they're spending crazy money how do you
do a hospital takeover in a country you
can't even get into
so this was an opportunity it was like
warren buffett said like never let a
good crisis go to waste this was a
crisis of attrition and it was literally
the moment that no one realizes now what
happened in march last year on march
21st when the stock market was like
its hands
we were doubling i didn't sleep for four
days like i was buying companies on a
public market that i normally think of
garbage that i wouldn't touch i hate
their executives i've known them from
their starts when their stock was going
from like 25 to 19 to and forty cents a
share was like
like
crazy deployments in capital also then
during this time a lot of these public
companies had no good liquidity on the
books
so they were massively unloading assets
like things that can't be did in spain
for example spent 50 60 million euros to
secure some of these positions these
initial things and they're like we were
buying stuff for pennies on the dollar
and like now like that 240 cent share
that's up at like 15. so
sadly even though many of you if you
know me i talk a lot of crap on canadian
public companies
and then some of the shell-listed ones
on the csc and the tsx that actually
don't invest in the united states and
our companies are listed up there
because it's federally legal in the
united states
but that's where the money is and that's
where the change is happening and
there's still a moment to get into some
of these huge things here
so in companies as they're raising the
capital which when you think of your
vetting investment opportunities here in
europe there are not many and most of
them are garbage there have been a few
with kenobo and a few others like on the
london exchange you're going to see more
starting out frankfurt exchange
television
canada has been where like most of the
action is but canada with 40 million
people
already a very illicit market that's
been happening it's not where
international campus is really going to
take effect so a lot of people lost
their asses in canada investing in
massive big things
compared to like small private companies
that were scaling the united states when
it's federally illegal in the united
states we have this tax code irc
very important because the united states
is where we're going to talk and make
it's where we make all of our money that
allows all of our international
expansion all i've done is spent
hundreds of millions of dollars around
the world securing positions nurturing
companies because we don't grow
pineapples in canada in warehouses
to like have pineapples there it's like
they come from other countries the same
with coffee the same with other things
so you have to think like longer term
and as investors you know you've got
like your short positions your mediums
your long what are your long-term
strategic visions and sometimes just
like a short squeeze it'll kill you if
it squeezes you for too long and that's
what happened with canopy and tons of
these other companies they held all
these positions had all these shorts and
they just had to like
massive shitty in their books to get
things and then you would see like
tillery buying like national the harvest
long established like hemp seed company
just because it does gravity like
they're buying all these other companies
just to look like look at all this
revenue we're making just to trick
investors to keep their stock prices
high but it's very hard to raise capital
from these small-scale and private
companies we really multi-restrain but
we structure and really focus on seed
stage series a series b getting those
little baby unicorns catching them
feeding them taking care of them and
then getting them ready for like future
exits or acquisitions which has been a
big strategy but like i said in the
united states irc 280 this tax code from
like you normally know your cost of
goods sold for that what your deductions
are appreciation a little thing no one
understands is this thing called ebitda
you know maybe some of you have heard of
it you know based on your backgrounds of
course campus operators did not so an
imc 280 when you cannot deduct your
normal cost of goods sold you can claim
your depreciation you can't insulate
assets you can't deduct your interest
expense nor your tax expense you're like
net at the end of the day might be 30 to
40 percent less than a normal business
now the thing that's crazy
irc 280 is only applicable in the united
states
and it's only applicable to companies
that deal in the unregulated controlled
manufacturing distribution of schedule
one and schedule
two narcotics
remember that whole thing i said about
the u.n how we rescheduled that the
united states were members of the united
nations
we're in violation of u.n drug treaties
which we actually pushed like
to write back in the day to like really
kick him in half
to go against that so we're actually in
violation of that policy the moment that
the international air house control
board and the cnd wh
which we were members of until like that
last president which we don't want to
talk about um so i didn't believe the
wheel during the global pandemic
that's maybe why this didn't happen but
the moment the united states starts to
follow u.n drug treaties irc 280 e goes
away
it's not the care act more act it's not
schumer's bill it's kind of like oh no
institutional capital banking can come
into the states
when we follow that accuracy 280 out the
window companies now for their ebitda
taxes interest expense appreciation
cost of goods sold deductions we get it
that's literally the silver bullet to
companies in the united states
especially the ms espresso truly
purely harvest on like forefront
that's when if you're in those and that
happens you're going to see a bump not
giving them securities advice here but
you're going to see a bump in like
30 40 50 on their stop by pretty much
day one to that
so just watch and know that that's a
very significant day
now in the united states you know where
i'm from
up there by canada that gray one up at
the top and sorry i realized actually
this one i forgot to change it at the
end we also have virginia on there now
mississippi happened for medical but
their supreme court said like oh the
voters didn't understand what they're
willing for or stopped like voters don't
know where to stop that and then south
dakota actually passed medical and
recreational in the same boat but then
their governor is kind of
kind of like the governor of maine used
to be and didn't allow that to happen so
when you look at this patchwork from
when it was like california in 1996 with
the compassionate usap first medical
cannabis
compassionate use act in the united
states they didn't allow commercial
sales it was like i'm a non-profit i
build plans for people i sell plants
with people but we don't make any money
colorado is the first when you think
about what's happening
only a matter of time
and you know texas giant place it has a
medical program but only for the
childhood epilepsy
so this is really where to watch
companies and grants that start we have
a very illicit medical market
all those medical states originally we
call them the dirty seven california
oregon washington
um
michigan maine
they had a medical program where you
could have like this piece of a drop on
the wall it's like i can have 90 plants
for jamie and nine plants for thelma and
90 plants for steve
we're not selling it of course but then
you have states like oklahoma in a way
that are growing copious amounts of
cannabis
and it's kind of like leaving those
states now a big thing um under
president trump passed president trump
thank goodness um
he put in uh jeff sessions that's the
attorney general that little keebler
alphabet guy
got
he was like hey there's this thing from
james cole you know past you know he's
like this whole memorandum had eight
rules that states had to follow in order
to have a legal medical cannabis program
and he's like this doesn't matter
so pretty much that's the only guy who's
getting followed and then he said it was
garbage
so when that happened it's like let's go
follow that because what's gonna happen
it's that fear that's the moment of
opportunity we are we are definitely too
big to fail this isn't like are people
going to buy shoes online i don't know
those apples might not be a good
investment uber who's going to use that
there's taxi cabs
cannabis is already a bona fide market
and the united states doesn't want you
to know this
nor the dea which has a beautiful logo
like that flying eagle but like the drug
enforcement administration
sorry guys
[Music]
our elicit market in the united states
is close to 200 billion dollars
200 billion they say it's about 50. they
don't want you to know this from
thumbnail a lot more people use canvas
than actually admit on their little
surveys let's just say on government
survey are you going to admit to like
breaking feather law probably not
but this is really rare to watch and
there's major things happening now also
with these new states that are coming
with like so connecticut actually
already happened
good to go on that new medical states
like alabama south dakota did happen
it's only a matter of time in the united
states until this happens and we were
the that made this kind of
illegal all over the world back from
william randolph first you read that
book the emperor wears some clothes jack
herrera back in the day this was nothing
to do with like smoking cannabis it was
all about like paper industry cotton
industry petrochemical industries being
like
we don't know the forests and the
paper mills and it's like way better
than all our
we should like make that sound bad so
then they use their journalism yellow
journalism to like write about like
reefer madness african americans raping
white women like devils lettuce scary
stuff
just to really make propaganda about
cannabis and we did that and now it's
kind of weird that we're going to be the
first ones to like make 100 billion a
year
from this industry so
sorry about all that but i'm working on
making that better now but every
every day especially based on corona
virus states lost so much tax revenue
and jobs
they don't care about cannabis anymore
they're like hey
george floyd like all the things that
happened this last year like social
equity minorities united states alone
there's over 1 million african americans
or latinos that go to like private
prisons every year for minor cannabis
offenses
and the private prison industry is also
one of the biggest lobbyists against
legalization in the united states
because that's their revenue which is an
absolute way to make revenue and i'm a
big triple bottom line for people of
planet profit you steal from the
environment or you steal from people
your profit is not generally it's not
genuine it's a bandana principle
and when you think about like what
profitability is possible in this
industry especially in the united states
epic now foreign nationals don't invest
into something federally illegal in
another country kind of bad idea
homeland security not a good idea
ancillary which we'll get into is a huge
opportunity
now
here we go there you go so i was making
fun of canada before yes they were the
first on like a national medical program
other than uruguay that you're ways down
like little anybody don't care even
though in the beginning we were really
terrified the new international
narcotics community board was going to
like cramp down on uruguay same thing
for their adult use program we watched
nothing happen then you have a g8
country like canada be like legal good
medical we send it in the mail
we like poutine
good and then they legalized adult use
and then we're like
is this are they going to go after
a g nothing happened
so i feel like we're pretty good trudeau
and everyone knows like we're pretty
good now especially since they've
already raised about 300 billion dollars
for some of those other companies and
more more that's undisclosed and private
but all those public companies was like
this is going to happen and it didn't
and i started calling on these crashes
very very early and everyone thought it
was freaking crazy
i love private companies that scale and
grow mergers acquisitions ipos normal
business dot com awesome but that bubble
burst because so many of them were
garbage companies the same with those
bubbles for
they're like we're going to grow
cannabis for the whole world because
we're the first ones to do it canada is
cold as
it's not where you want to have massive
greenhouses i've been buying greenhouses
in canada really fancy dutch ones
disassembling them bringing them across
the united states order and reassembling
them for literally less than 10 cents
when they started to close these things
it was like
maybe we're not going to supply the
world because our cost of production is
so high
and right now there's almost 800
companies in canada through health
canada you get your lpa original license
and then you have to build your whole
facility have an
then get your final approval license
there's 800 companies currently building
out more facilities in canada to like
make water just to put more water in the
ocean
like they don't need more cannabis
there's such an oversupply of cannabis
whenever year supply storages in canada
all lies also any public company press
release you read from canada 97 chance
it's pure
or actually they don't study about the
company
like this may
it was when they signed in
for a meeting
did a big press release stopping up 113
million dollars in market share in a
day
from signing in to have a meeting about
nothing
so just know that that's not the case
i've been trying to put in your own
business for years because like our
lighting company the sun i always say
this like it's the best lighting company
in the world i've been growing plants
for over a half a billion years biology
enemies
like the sun outdoor four season hybrid
greenhouse that's the way the future
indoor we only did it to go inside
behind so like if you're investing in
the massive like
you know
50 000 hectare indoor facilities your
constant reduction on a cabinet
standpoint it's about six times what a
greenhouse is and your opex is about six
times as well paying for electricity and
hvac dehumidification so humidor is good
for r d smaller scale not for growing
all the pineapples for the
world now you always want to think about
these things from a normal business
standpoint like what are the
profitability kpis for
whatever it is you're investing just
because it's a cannabis thing doesn't
mean it's going to be a good investment
in 2014 15 16 we can't it's great that's
not the only thing in the world that
matters anymore so you really have to
think about like what are their
standards
too many people say this is so divine
but like we are a compliance industry
and if we are a good plan we have the
privilege of cultivating manufacturing
and distributing controlled substances
if it's not compliant at high level
standards it's not bona fide in my mind
and i won't touch it there's a risk
factor for our investors even with
anything bad going on out even if it is
a potential uniform it's a unicorn it's
going to break its leg and die
so always look at those other sorts of
people and like what are the metrics of
this company true financial models
audited financial models so many
companies raising camp don't even know
what that is
so make sure to like evaluate cannabis
just like any other business opportunity
if you're new to this industry we've
done this for 15 years i've been looking
to say garbage and you're like i already
put 5 million
that was probably a bad idea
and like what can you do to get your
money have a change over uh it's just
improved
so another kind of big thing you know
with ham and cannabis there's like thc
which is actually kca that's the
psychological side there's over 260
known cannabinoids from like what dr
machine originally found out back in the
60s in israel
now there's this big one delta eight
right now that everyone's talking about
it gets you kind of up
accidentally had a delta eight candy in
north carolina last week at this
conference i was at they were just
giving away this like little goodie bag
they weren't labeled
i was like oh taffy i'm like sitting up
that night i'd probably eat five pounds
of food like two and a half
cdg that was cool
in 2016. if you're a cbd company now i
don't care
realistically i mean unless you're
getting your supply from a gmp producer
in romania poland colombia and other
states like if you're producing cbd in
california i probably don't care
or like you're some new novel safety
company the biggest snake oil industry
we've ever seen but it's also an amazing
disconnect that needs more research but
so many garbage companies got into it
and now so delta a is going to be
scheduled like that cdn just look and
bet these things just because it's novel
doesn't mean it's going to be epic now
in europe you've got some massive
opportunities here but not so much yet
we qualified for some of those german
tankers early on when they took that 2
200 kilo block away which was like i'm
like we got a license in germany and
then like to literally grow in a space
this big i feel like that was a bad idea
the beef i'd love to stop that like that
and now there's the new program too
profitable i mean i don't say german so
if i get your voyage like that last part
it's going to be good but cannabis
produced in germany would be so
expensive
compared to like portugal or some of
these other countries that we've worked
in now yeah greece is part of the
european union no offense greece i don't
know how they're part of the european
union
but
like greece was going to do this huge
thing they copied israeli laws which
meant that everything had to have a
standard deviation of zero
to be exported so like there are a lot
of opportunities there but you really
have to vet these countries just because
it's north macedonia and you've got this
new cool thing that you can do
doesn't mean it's going to mean eu gmt
standards
i just have to say one quick thing we're
not going to take a break after this
we're going to make up for time to go
right into the next panel and then we've
got a big great lunch for everybody
right after that you know i'll keep
rocking and trying to swear a little bit
so you know we won two of the eleven
licenses in denmark originally we've got
the first license and portion of the
workforce some of those in germany like
massive opportunities here in europe but
still it's so early and everything
international you have to remember it's
under compassionate use and that takes a
doctor to write a prescription
medical in the united states doctors
make recommendations not prescriptions
prescriptions are around the fda
which is federally illegal so they can't
write prescriptions other than for like
a few cannabis products like from gm
students which is now like worth like
for a very crowded 2.5 2.5 it doesn't
make any sense but they were first
this is a really important thing for any
international investors to understand
pace countries p-i-c-s
these blue ones are the only countries
that freaking matter if you want to
develop phased clinical trials or drugs
that are going to be able to be sold in
the united states and europe you're like
oh i have this cool license in zimbabwe
and we're going to make cancer our
products for cancer we sell all the
world no you're not if it's not produced
in a pig's country or your clinical
trials are dominant country it will not
meet those standards and you will have
to redo them all somewhere else
time is everything these things can take
up to 11 years and cost 562 million
euros
just to get a product to market
pharmaceutically so whenever people
start talking about pharma just know
money
big companies and it's not about trying
to be fizer it's about trying to be
bought by flies
so like you have to think in that kind
of capacity so when you think about this
map on top of where is production lab is
not unfortunately the biggest partners
like argentina and that's why i love
south africa and got licenses there
that's why cambodia even though it's
freaking crazy with thailand i'm
interested in that because it's a pixed
country long term same portugal the only
country in europe that has the most epic
climate
cheapest cost of labor
surfing
so if you're ever thinking about this
like clinical recently if you're
investing into pharmaceutical companies
it's not the cannabis companies right
now it's going to be their options on
these things and what's really important
as you go through this is know that it's
going to cost a lot of money and take
way more time
the ip of cannabis can be everything
it's not illegal to own the intellectual
property to do something
it's illegal to do the thing but owning
the intellectual property can be the
biggest value because that's what's
going to be bought by dupont and
monsanto and pfizer and modern and all
of these companies nature so you must
protect that intellectual property
through the right structures
latin america is definitely going to be
a world leader when you think about
colombia specifically i love how
the pastor of moore in colombia and now
like i put a plank outside flowers it's
12 hours of dark 12 hours of light big
three ounces get plants ready put them
inside boom
massive oil plantations columbia
literally could serve the entire world's
cannabis
and they just allow
export this last month which is huge
before it was just oil evaluations in
columbia are going to be great over 100
licenses
only seven of them
and i know three owners of companies
going to be a little weird that peru can
also change the world because it's so
close to the equator when you think
about where canvas is going to be grown
long-term
it's the waistline of the world
and the further away you are the more
expensive it's going to be to do it and
the more environmentally kind you're
responsible
asia has kind of been a big a bit crazy
with us china is great on the hemp side
about things that are kind of huge when
you think about cambodian passing
thailand through university
and their programs and what that's going
to be like
um kind of major philippines they used
to murder you from cannabis now we
should talk to
um
big big deal everything in africa is
mostly garbage
mine is hosutu and mine is south africa
if you know the king swaziland and he's
going to give you some exclusive license
to do something you're probably not
now there's gonna be some massive
opportunities not to on the whole
continent but like in south africa
they're like so this is africa
very interesting place to do business
and you're gonna have to deal with the
chinese when it comes to real estate
typically but their climates are good in
south africa you can get if you're doing
stuff in the northern hemisphere and
down here you're getting two harvests a
year massively actually four but just
know that a lot of things in africa are
very volatile and the exports can be a
problem
oceana the thing i put up here really
sad you know with rona like adult use
didn't pass
in new zealand which was really sad by
just a few votes
um
that was going to be a big change for us
but guam i've got the first i got the
first medical license on guam
there's 1.6 billion people that live
within a four hour flight long
so brands for recreational to be legal
there now which is starting with our
first companies that's where we can
start brands in korean and russian and
japanese and chinese and actually start
exposing tourists to dolphins for the
first time if you've ever played that
risk game this is how you get into
africa this is how you get into those
seven troops
ancillary is huge for you investors
foreign nationals i make 12
to 18
on real estate
i say that again i mean 12 to 18 on real
estate secured by
a fixed asset because the institutional
capital cannot give loans to companies
to build their greenhouses by their land
by their extraction equipment you can
invest into those things and debt is not
a financial interest it must be
disclosed and you can do that in a bona
fide way in the united states or other
countries so ancillary from all these
sorts of things just remember for every
dollar spent on a cannabis product the
velocity of capital in cannabis is
anywhere between four and six
dollars just think the united states if
we did 30 billion in revenue this year
that means there's 120 billion of this
going on and this is not federally
illegal it's structured
so when you're thinking about what's
going on in the future here that
opportunities well
know from people like what's real what's
not what can you do what can you not
do investment due diligence tech
services i had printed off a lot of
these things in the back for specific
for investors like what things to do
that deals and opportunities
look out seek advice all confidentially
basically is this a good idea or not is
this evaluation
or not because if you don't even like
deloitte even big big companies they
don't understand cannabis in the way
that the people who have been in the
trenches bleeding for a couple decades
happening
things look different when you've like
been in battle and you come back and
you're like whoa war is kind of crazy
and you're like war is great we're going
in you know
like run the front of the line so really
do your homework a lot of good people
here even though you might look left and
right you think like normal investment
these are my competitors no
in human history when we collaborate we
win
so like the collaboration i put five
million towards something you put five
in like the more that we pool capital
with your funds special purpose vehicles
and wise investment managers you don't
have to be an expert overnight so like
look around and make partnerships so
great that we get to be back together i
know it's been a long time since uh we
were able to do this again if you've got
any questions you know we'll be here
this next couple days such a big thanks
to alice in the icbc this is this
conference has literally changed the
world
and from a medical like disabled
veterans standpoint like getting
medicine to patients is our highest
priority and doing this in a responsible
way without conferences like this that
have been in the trenches themselves for
years allowing things to happen that we
talk about that are illegal in many
places
it's those risk takers that that really
the pioneers that made this industry
possible we've got a lot of experts here
from the united states from other
countries so if you've got questions
we're here we just want to like rise and
grow this industry together so absolute
pleasure to speak with y'all thank you
so much
[Applause]