what i'm going to do with you in the
next couple of minutes is i'm gonna
discuss with you what happened the last
five years regarding
this
what are the challenges
what are the pitfalls
and of course we're going to discuss
also
a little bit more in detail
what will be the future with regard to
the recreation market at least from my
point of view
which is the point of view of a lawyer
who is involved in the business since
i'm in the life sciences field for over
20 years 30 years contractors
and before i came here this morning i
had a radio interview with uh
attorney broadcaster
and the interviewer surprised me with
the following question
peter
we have a look we have a look at your at
the dentist's home page and we found the
following slogan
however you need to grow
then this is here to help
do you take that
and frankie speaker and now our
marketing people
but to a certain extent no surprise
because i didn't
know about that's wrong anyway
so
i try to answer that a little bit more
in detail and what we're going to do
right now and here's how the german
speaker usually presents the agenda
an overview of it
about the historical facts very briefly
because you all know what happened in
germany in the last five years how we
actually develop
the medical market for for cannabis
we're looking into the liberalization
process some milestones tell me very
quickly some some really headlines what
has happened in these five years to the
german market now we talked about the
pitfalls the market situation coming to
canada is as of today and how we
developed over the last couple of years
and then we come to the you are all
uh very very interested in the
liberalization
process for regulation cannabis in
germany
so if we look into
[Music]
the timeline
you see that we have actually
deliverization in 2017
uh in march
the decision of the federal
administrative portuguese triggered the
liberalization
was in 2016 and
of course then
we had a
whole concept of
a legal environment building up
regulatory frameworks for the respective
medical cannabis products
in april
2019 the federal institute for drugs and
medical advice which is the way farm
which you all know actually granted them
three licenses to
german cultivators which we all know of
with a very limited extent to cultivate
cannabis in germany it's 10.6
metric tons over the period of five
years
which is by far not enough to serve the
market as you can see later on in my
presentation but at least it is a step
forward
the question is of course why only 10.6
tons for four years
well the bee farm is actually purchasing
the flowers from the three
licensed producers
and selling it directly to the
pharmacists of course they are not using
own warehouses they have used an
appointed kansathima to do that for the
big farm but they have been extremely
conservative with regard to what is
actually the amount the quantity which
will be needed for the medical market
it is
definitely less than what the market
needs and of course germany will remain
one of the largest
importers for medical economies in the
next years as well
i'd like to make just a very brief
discourse here
which is a decision
of the
european court of justice
of november 2020.
it doesn't really have to do with the
medical cannabis market because it was a
cbd
and the european court of justice
actually
classified cbd
as
not being a narcotic
this has now to be implemented in the
but i think it's a big step forward
into
the legalization
of cannabis and cannabis related
products such i have mentioned that here
we will come back to that in a minute at
the end of my presentation
let's have a look into the milestones
which we have seen
in the last five years
[Music]
now these are the
rebate contracts
what are rebate contracts
pharmaceutical manufacturers and what's
common in germany
ground helps ensure certain remains for
dispensing and then expands and in
return get an exclusivity being the
supplier for these
uh health insurance companies what you
have to know
is
once a patient
has a right
with the brand of disposition for
reimbursement of the respective
treatment
[Music]
and as such the health insurance
companies having of course a very close
look into the expenses of these
respective treatments
so what has happened here
as at the beginning of
the
liberalization and you may
know that
the price on a paragraph basis in 2017
and 2080 was around 22 euros
for the patient
was around 10 to 12 euros from the
wholesaler to the pharmacy
and then the pharmacy had to
add a hundred percent surcharge
why because the product was qualified as
an extendress mixture and helped as a
ready-made pharmaceutical
with the consequence the price up
and that was of course an issue with the
respect of health insurance companies
and the association of health insurance
companies and the associations of
pharmacists have actually found the
solution they have kept the price from
the wholesaler to the pharmacy at 950 to
the euros
per day
now the surcharge applies and of course
there's a staggering process the
surcharge will decline very much
depending on the quantity of the
prescription
so that was the first time the real
price regulation mechanism
has entered the market here
what happened what happened as well
was that
due to the competition in the market the
price really went down on a per gram
basis from this 952 to
six seven euros very programmed even
below that over time for the medicinal
market
and then of course the health insurance
companies had the idea why don't we
apply the same system which you have
already made pharmaceuticals
also to the extent horrendous mixtures
being catalysts
that's why these remained contracts
actually came into force and of course
there are
some companies who have entered into
these rebate contracts with the
respective health insurance companies
and others may also join because these
are so-called open house contracts
another
milestone was the application of the
so-called amwat fault in canada
we are talking here about the
possibility of humiliation of the plants
in order to significantly reduce the
microbiology
in 2019 one of our clients has asked
what do i have to do
how can i actually import irradiated
cannabis flowers from canada into
germany so he went through the waveform
and says okay what should we do
if i actually said well you just find
the application for the importation
license for the specific lot with your
local authority or just mention that it
is irritated which we did
client actually imported in 2019 at 2018
this
cannabis irrigated talents was in
germany
all of a sudden in 2019 the bay farm
actually decided
well i think we have to grant a
specific license under the outlet file
which is the respective lawyer
um for the irradiation of the cannabis
which was totally new if you look into
the respective legislation to the
respective law it is capable for
regulators
not for extemporaneous mixtures well it
was actually applied one to one by the
bay farm everybody applied for it and
then of course the respective
licenses have been granted
what was the reason for it
difficult to say uh hypothetically well
the license is relatively expensive you
have to pay for it but the intention for
each and every product you should like
to report
let's go to the next milestone um
here are the various voices which she
just
listed which you need if you would like
to
enter the german market
of course you need to have a
manufacturing permit
experiment
import permits
uh then you have remotes in the
wholesale license advertising is not
really allowed because it's an economic
it's very very limited
and as i said
these
products are extensive
not early
so if you want to do business here
insurance you have to either establish
your own company and apply for these
licenses timeline approximately one six
nine months if you're lucky very much
depending on the local authority where
you are located
or you'll find a company who has already
the existing licenses from the import
and you're going to educate a respected
agreement with them
which is
for most exporters in your best way to
do it if you want to reach the market
quickly
what we are currently discussing
about a bit for are the quality
standards
so
this is a
relatively new but very intense
discussion for general companies
the precondition for importing products
from a company from a country outside of
germany is first of all
that the country
of origin
adheres to the 1961 u.n civil convention
which
stipulates that you have to have a
formal licensing process for the
cultivation and the export a controlled
process for the export for medicinal
canals
or for cannabis for scientific purposes
not for recreational i will come back to
that in a minute
once this qualification has been checked
then of course the exporter the
exporting
company has to fulfill eu gmp
regulations in the process
and of course the products have as well
so if you are an exporter from canada
you
may obtain
a gmp certificate locally which of
course is not recognized within the
european union of course and by the trip
authorities
that means
a german officer from the german
authorities have tends to do an on-site
inspection
in order to
see whether the
company in canada qualifies under the eu
gmp regulations
this is not necessary for all those
countries where we have a mutual
recognition agreement in place between
germany and of course the respective
country
which folks is for example
applicable for australia
any kind of gnp certificate in
australian companies
within the european union
what you can see right now here is the
overlap
of gacp and gmp and that's where the
discussion starts
usually
the respective
company the exporter in the third
country
has to
adhere to the eu gp regulations
there are treatments right now
that
they can actually export gacp
processed flowers for example flowers
into germany
which are then
gnp processed here and then sold to the
drill market
that is as
some of the representatives of these
years companies who are doing it
disruptive
disruptive new idea and the question is
is it covered by the respective
and legal framework here so no that's a
good question because we have an overlap
between gacp and gnp and the grayson in
between
the pre-drying process is definitely a
process which can be done on the pacp
a real drying process is of course gm
that must be gnp compliant
and the way from just recently in
connection with a clarification
regarding the unrightful permissions has
stated that as well
not as clear as we thought it would be
so however we are still in the
discussion whether you can actually
import into drinking or expert oxide
gacp presents flowers which are then gnp
processed furniture gp processed via
germany and then sold into the
pharmacies which is currently the case
for some employees
let's look into the online trade of
medicines
[Music]
can you sell
cannabis products online and pharmacies
actually
send the product to the respective
patient
by career services yes or no
the answer to that is in principle that
is possible as it is possible for all
our rx products pharmaceutical products
however you have to adhere to certain
preconditions
first of all the prescription needs to
be sent to the pharmacist you can't send
the product with my career to the
patient that careers collecting the
uh prescriptions bring it bring the
brings it back to the food pharmacies so
first of all the prescription has to be
sent by the patient to the pharmacy by
mail
which is actually the case multiple
other rx products
and then the pharmacy can actually send
the product to the patient the patient
does not have to appear in the pharmacy
which makes it easier for patients to
select
which pharmacy is going to buy his
product which
which has been prescribed by the
physician a very helpful tool and we
have seen that
currently
a large number of the respective
distribution is done by this online
training
where patients are acting ordering their
products sending the respective
prescriptions to the pharmacies and
receiving the package but of course the
career service has to fulfill certain
preconditions you can't send just any
bicycle career center with a package of
calories to a patient that's clear
but there are of course the
larger
forwarding companies like dhl for
example can provide these services
knowing what is in the package which is
very important
let's come to
the market situation currently in
germany
as you see in 2019 the
waveform awarded the contracts for the
cultivation
respective quality standards have to be
adhered
the first harvest by alfrea actually was
done in july 2021 because the small
extent was literally kilogram
then the first hundred of demi karma was
100 kilograms
back in april 2022 just recently and of
course and also aurora has made their
first house i was available
which is a distributing company
for the dfr in may 2022 so it's
slightly developing we are not there yet
because for various delays which are of
course also
caused by the respective pandemic
which has slowed down cultivation
processes
because didn't gather expected materials
which can be exceeded
which can be
increased by a 10 percent
for each
company
so where do we stand right now with the
medicinal
but if we look into 2017
the actual
the demand estimated by the federal
opioid agency was 10.4 tons
of course 2017 was the year that the
inauguration took place
only 1.77 tons were actually imported
2018 it did increase significantly
in 2019 of course in 2020 and 2021 i
think that was a significant increase in
2021 we had an import
of medical cannabis products of around
20 metric tons
which is
a market the largest market in europe
compared to other markets not in canada
or in the us it's relatively still
relatively small but not increasing
so the question is of course
where is this market going
i would say
we are looking into an increased number
of patients if we have a look into the
patient numbers
of the patient numbers
we are
from different sources you see it could
be around
80 to 100 000 patients per year
uh within germany which is far less than
the initial hopes
that we see
which we are actually uh
one percent
of the population which would have been
800 000 patients we probably will not
reach that fear
uh but we will have c we would see an
increasing number
and as i said it's currently my father
video creating this market in europe
compared to other markets like the
netherlands poland or italy
so
having all said that about the medicine
market which to a certain extent may be
more to you
maybe a little bit more now comes the
grief
how are we looking into
the legalization for recreational
kindness in germany
and let me look into
the respective process right now which
we have heard from this degree that is i
would say a relatively early stage
um
currently
cannabis is for non-medical purposes is
non-marketable it's a non-marketable
narcotic substance i think that is clear
so we have to change the laws with
respect to the
consumption for recreational adult use
what is the market size
that's a very good question we have
estimates
who actually
say that the market the illicit market
right now
is in the duration of 700 metric tons
per year
which in comparison to the medical
market is significant
and if you look at how actually the
market
for the liberalization would develop
then
if
let's say 50 of the total market
could be served by a regulated
market
for recreation recreational purposes we
are talking about 350 metric tons which
is significant in comparison to the
current market for medical calories
and as such
the
caution
of the lawmaker
in that process is understandable
the original
process for the utilization of medicine
cannabis wasn't really a
masterpiece it was done very quickly
we had a lot of grey areas a lot of
unregulated areas as we have seen for
example with the irrigation process but
other processes as well
and now the lawmaker would like to make
it right
and there is a certain reluctancy to
speed it up
of course the demand is there the black
market in this market is there as well
there are there is a danger for
[Music]
so what is the timeline
now in may probably autograph the
federal minister for health announced
the plan that the draft law
it doesn't say that it will be the law
it doesn't say that it has been agreed
by the by the parliament
it has been released therefore the draft
will
then be
forwarded in
the second half of
we heard this morning this plan is
already a little bit extended to the
beginning of 2023
uh probably maybe even
at the end of the second quarter 2023
and then of course the whole process
starts and of course there's a lawyer i
i like to and that was truck here
that's the legislation process
then it's not just we put the draft into
the parliament and then we agree on it
and everything is fine
no that's not the case
it very much depends of course on the
drafting of the respective
legislation
we assume
that this is a consent bill
this which means the bundesliga which is
our second checker
where the majorities
buy the
chris democrats which is the more
conservative side and very very
critical with regard to globalization
has the majority
so that means you may have another
reading
so altogether i would say
that we will not have
a final
law
for globalization of cannabis
for adult recreational purposes in place
before the end of second third or fourth
quarter 2023
that is kind of invention and the
natural process you can't do that
overnight
and then as
we have heard the first draft will be in
2023 well then of course this whole
process here starts and we will see how
quickly that will be done
uh and whether the google start of
course is giving its concept yes or no
very much give heads of course and mr
peter brought it out on the discussion
between the various parties uh and how
they actually uh
put life to adopt
the liberalization
which i would like to address here as
well
this is a summary of just what i said
um
what is
important
are the legal checks
[Music]
the first one is of course
germany is part of multiple
international trades and we spoke about
that i think through the last icbc event
the 1961 unc convention other two
conventions are restricting the transfer
of narcotics between its member states
over 180 countries have signed off on
those streets
which means that you cannot just import
cannabis from holland canada or any
other country for recreational purposes
you could be
immediately in violation of the 9661ux
but what are the theoretical
consequences of that
the international narcotics control
board which is the executive control
board for the conventions
is empowered to monitor the compliance
with the respective conventions
and last but not least they are setting
the quotas for the importation
also for medicine economists
so so far there was never a problem that
wasn't discussed at all though the day
fund
in 2021 actually has increased its
demand over the period of time in 2021
and has asked the incb to adopt and to
ground the permission to import the
larger amounts which have been
voluntarily
but without the permission of the incb
even for the respective medicine
journalists you are not allowed to
import these products
to a certain extent
so the practical consequences of a
violation
could be
that the incp
is going to
initiate a reforce mechanism which they
haven't done in the case of canada and
europe who would enter the recreation
park as well
but they are
uh
in the position to
reduce the quota also for the medical
terrorist of course
which they haven't done they have not
really reacted so far neither in the
case of canada or uruguay
but we'll see what they
may or may not say
about the
possible cultivation of love of
recreation in germany which was really
one solution that are coming to the back
development
furthermore
the shang convention
there is
the eu framework
which of course all the universities are
probably you know
in contract everybody talks about
sharing content when it comes to
words presentation and
immigration and whatever so we germany
if who has
a very small
cultivation for medicine economist at
this point in time
can not just without violating the
respective u.n conventions and the
shelling convention
import these products into germany
won't the government do that
good question
i would say they do
so we have to find a way
to solve that issue
which we didn't press this morning
where do we get the calories from for
the recreational market which is a
significant market
do we do homegrown
do we do
cultivation in germany
do we ask the three licensed producers
right now to significantly increase
their
their their quantities which they to a
certain extent may or may not do are we
inviting others to join
uh the foundation germany which would be
a possibility to say well we're not
tendering it up no more tankers sorry
the bay frontier was
really very difficult i would say but
invite
for respective
interested parties to cultivate
cannabis for recreational purposes if
they fulfill certain requirements and
get the license you may have seen that
happening in the netherlands where 10
companies have just recently been
granted the permission to part
to grow
cannabis for recreational purposes for
the domestic use
within the netherlands
i see here
one of those solutions
other solutions may be of course
the respective
change of the convention well i don't
think that you will get healthy
countries to
very quickly agree to a change of that
convention to
terminate the convention step out and
apply again for
with the provision that cannabis doesn't
come from it doesn't be applicable for
germany very difficult you never know
whether the other 180 or 179 countries
would agree to that
which is a possibility theoretically
but the more practical solution
definitely is
either we're talking about homework or
we're talking about domestic cultivation
and the respective increase then of
course we are talking about
end of 2024
because you have to do that process
despite the fact that you have also to
establish the respective infrastructure
in order to have
this
cannabis foreign creation purposes
distinguished to the
the infrastructure is you know it's
do we have heard about this morning
about licensed shops
yeah
so we need somebody who is going to
grant the licenses who is going to look
and control the respective distribution
centers so that is an infrastructure
which you have to set up
and that's a significant effort
and we should have started that a little
bit earlier probably if we would like to
look into the respective
results so let's see
her challenges
the question is of course how we attract
the problem do we do decriminalization
like an opponent or do we really do
legalization
with the respective
not
not enforcement
these are the solutions which i just
mentioned
the open violation i don't think that
the german government is going to try to
violate international treaties
immediately as well as the shang
contract
so let's have a look into another issue
which we have to
adhere to
which is actually the quality of the
product
so
if you look into the recreation market
from my point of view there are three
major factors in order to make a
successor
the first one is pricing
you have to have an adequate cost we
have heard that this morning
when i heard about taxation to a certain
extent of course that's an interesting
income for the government but it has of
course an impact on the price so prices
are first one secondly
is availability
the product needs to be made available
you don't have to should not drive 20 or
25 kilometers to the next dispensary
shop or license shop to get the bot you
would like to buy
so
the infrastructure has to be there
so product availability
and the last one of course is
uh quality
price availability quality should be the
other way about this
but i think that's that's the real issue
why we have heard this morning for mr
peanut the quality of the black market
is
difficult
to say at least there are lots of
products
which are mixed with things which are
definitely unhealthy
and of course that is something which of
course we should attack the
market but what is the right quality are
we going to gmp again
a
maybe good question
uh it would definitely be an
advantage
for for the recreational market if you
have the right quality in place
and gmp would be one of those
so if you look into the challenges
this is an example of how the canadian
market actually developed
relative to the
medical environment in the market
you see in the medical market
after the respective liberalization it's
declined significantly
and
the refugee economies
actually
significantly increased
we can't
actually transfer that
to germany as well
from my point of view and that's a
significant
issue in the german market you have the
reimbursement
patients get reimbursed if they
get a prescription
now that is not the same to the same
extent happening in canada
so for some patients what was much
easier to go to the recreational market
than who is going to adopt and get the
prescription
so what we will definitely see is maybe
a slight decline or a kind of a
steady line with regard to the
with regard to the
medical market and of course then an
increase of the
recreation market
if we look into the next chart here
which is the product price
you see that the product price
uh for the innocent
uh market actually went down the legal
adult use market went up
and of course the medical market isn't
to a certain steady line that's exactly
what i just mentioned whether this can
be transferred or to go to germany or we
have to be careful with that
so the challenges of the recreational
markets are there we have to work on a
number of
issues a number of problems which i
hoped might have been addressed this
morning a little bit more in detail
however it looks like that the
current discussions are difficult and
the current government may not
be in a position to
let us participate in those discussions
in more detail hopefully that will be
the case in the near future
before i'm going to end my presentation
by coming back to
two slides with regard to the cbd market
which is an interesting market for all
participants in that field as well we
have
these three segments for cbd products
cosmetics
which includes
the so-called food supplement market and
last but not least with our sugar
department
so the cosmetic market is relatively
easy to enter in comparison to the
secondary market why
the european
commission actually decided
that
any kind of food supplement which
contains cbd
is a normal threat and falls under the
normal food
convention or directed
with a consequence that you have to
apply
for the marketing of these products at
the european commission
so the european food and safety
authority is the one who looks into the
respective applications
we have to provide data with regard to
the
product it is hardness it doesn't hurt
at all
and that's what a number of companies
did
however
what happened is that the
european food and safety authority
earlier this year
decided
that
they will not proceed with any of those
applications for food supplements for
the registration
due to the fact that they do not have
enough safety data
that is
a significant setback for the market
whether this
is
justifiable probably yes
is it correct
difficult to say
is it helpful for the market deficitly
no
and as such
the respective applicants are now in a
position
that they have to
provide more than safety
data and they may not get an approval in
the near future
because the collecting production of
safety data is an enormous effort
just recently on 28th of june 2022 had
an official hearing which in which we
participated
and they actually pointed again out that
we
basically we are not in a position to
write any of this requisition without
again that is a setback for that market
it doesn't have to do anything with
medical implications
but i wanted to
provide you with that latest information
it is
up and down with respect to the
liberalization also in the cte market
and we see that as well as
having said that i really hope
that the german government is putting
significant efforts
into the
next steps
in order to find a way to open the
recreation market
i have to say that we
are to certainly
should not be too optimistic at least
not even too enthusiastic about the
timeline
it will come
definitely but when is the question
probably
sometime in 2024 we may have the first
product on the market if we are lucky
sorry for that bad news
but
i
that's that's more a realistic view than
what we have heard
so
far said that i would like to
close my presentation it was a pleasure
to be here it's a wonderful conference i
would like to thank knight gorgeous for
putting together this excellent
program
and thank you very much
[Applause]
[Music]