[Music]
yo yo yo ICBC in the
house just chilling legalizing cannabis
a the
achiever Time to Begin Again with the
news IBC with them rap reviews for 20203
Welcome to the annual break up the
manual the future is here but this here
rap recap now let's tap into a few of
the top happen of the year no wonder the
flaws in the laws whatever the cause
down under and all Elementary relevance
from relevant elements laid up the
evidence of patient and Common Sense and
we think it's Sensational that the
Australian Parliament introduced
recreational now that's just a start you
see this here charade is coming apart
and that's why Switzerland has embarked
on a mission that'll be marked as
historic pilot projects yes we adore it
and implore other jurisdictions to do
the same South Africa is way in the game
now it ain't no root yeah we speaking
the truth the National Assembly approved
at all use we come on y'all yes we
moving the ball Japan heated the call we
thought it might have a fall and here
comes medical and speaking of medical
like a delectable edible we're going to
turn up the level of De and put the
pedal to the metal you see in Germany
and soon off the lunacy in the community
will be Abad and what's greatest not
just Social Clubs grow in and drim
cannabis is coming off the narcotics
list now that's a Whopper way up high
like a fly helicopter we wouldn't be
here without all of the schooling true
this year we lost the great Raphael R
now I hope y'all catch this praise this
to the most high cuz every moment is
preious bless the spiritual Po and the
sence now it's time for a moment of
silence see policy is moving forward and
the world is choosing to go another rout
this has been the ICBC 2023 rap and
review and we out and we out and we out
and we out I
seec go set it free I CBC rap recap for
2023 I see
BC we going to set it
free I see b c rap recap for
2023 I see
BC going to set it
free I see BC rap recap for
2023 I see
BC go set it
free I bing rap rap of
2023 I see
BC yeah let me tell
y'all
[Music]
oh