I decided that we wanted to attend  the ICBC in Berlin specifically
because the European market  is truly coming online.
Germany is today the most important  market in the cannabis industry in Europe,
and so coming to the capital of  Berlin with ICBC was a no-brainer.
ICBC in Berlin - perfect match, it's perfect.
When I think of Berlin, when I think  of Germany, I think of organized.
I think of professional. I think of brave, and  ICBC delivered all of those things in spade.
I'm here at ICBC for three reasons:
the first reason was to get as much  information as possible from the people
that are already in the industry, hear from all  the success stories, hear from all the failure.
What ICBC has done is I've met  people in the finance industry,
I've met people in the legal industry, I've  met people in the regulatory framework,
and these people have been able to tell  us what's possible, what is not possible,
what would work for a country like  Zimbabwe and what wouldn't work.
We want to craft a national cannabis master plan.  I've met the parties that can make that happen,
and make it happen uh faster  than it would normally take.
ICBC, um, it is probably the best conference I've  ever attended, and I've been going to conferences
since I was 12 years old. The reason why i  say that, is the growth. I grew in three days.
I probably grew more than I have in the last  three years. The networking opportunities, uh,
are just unparalleled. I've met people that  I wouldn't normally meet. I've had a chance
to liaise with professionals in the industry  that there's no other way I would have had
to see these people. I have access to billions  of dollars in funding right now because of
coming to such a conference. So, I made  the sacrifice. ICBC is worth it for me,
it's worth it for the people of Zimbabwe, and  we will reap the benefits of my presence here.
the ICBC after parties are always always fun  - what you expect from the cannabis industry,
and always always elegant.
We always get exactly what we expect, which  is it's a sophisticatedly professionally run
conference, very rich attendance in terms of  diversity, as far as just people and cultures,
but also the areas of the industry that are  represented - always very intelligent discussions.