thank you guys
always a pleasure
ladies and gentlemen it's very nice to
be here
thank you to the icdc
alex and the team for putting this
together we had a great show yesterday i
believe
all of us been around it's an absolute
pleasure to talk a bit more about adult
use cannabis legalization models across
europe today
and my name is luke richner i'm from
switzerland i'm here to represent kind
of iggy but also to represent a bit the
swiss industry and some of the parts and
the
approach that we're having towards this
legalization
if we can call it at that already and
what do we do
kind of video is a compliance track and
trace software see to sale inspired by
what the us is doing
i believe you had metric earlier today
being one of the first in the industry
and we then looked at what canada is
doing with the gs1 integration with a
more standardized global approach in the
supply chain and we looked at different
standards out there looking at the ugmp
more consumer protection consumer safety
aspects
and and out of all of that we created a
new new
aspect a new basis of a software that
kind of taps into all those different
standards and
we're very proud to say that we were
able to secure a 10-year contract with
the swiss health ministry for the whole
track and trace of those pilot projects
the legalization models that i'll share
a little bit more about later but i
think that's enough about me to start
let's have everybody introduce
themselves and
thanks luke my name is jorgmya brenken
i'm with fluence bioengineering
um i'm heading the cannabis sales
department in the fluence in the emea
region so you're a middle east and
africa and we supply lighting solutions
to the industry for greenhouses as well
as indoor farms
and i'm based in germany but as i said
working in europe middle east and africa
i think i have a good overview of what's
going in the markets how they developed
what's the legislation in the respective
countries so i'm happy to talk obviously
about germany which is my home country
but also to
shine a little bit or to to shine light
on the on the other countries so
sunny
yeah so thanks for being here i'm sony
moon out managing partner of cultivators
we're out of the netherlands i always
say i'm literally born in the greenhouse
so all my life already in the in the
growing industry
what we do we help growers investors in
making decisions how to set up a growing
facility and also support them with a
daily business in growing cultivation
how
do okay thank you very much for having
me uh my name is aldo vidinia i'm the
ceo of stepwise farming engineering um
i'm
i'm a consultant
more on the on the pharmacy so i have 15
years experience in the pharmaceutical
industry i was one of the co-founders of
a second
jp license in portugal
and we provide
consulting to
pharmaceutical industry and the medical
campus industry were involved in 14
projects at the moment in portugal
and other countries
and we deliver basically turkey projects
from
an idea from an investor to get the full
deployment of the project and the
licensing process
um
we're happy i'm happy to to be here and
to discuss about the the adult use
models in here in europe thank you
thank you guys and basically what we
want to discuss a little bit today i
mean you've heard all about what is
happening in different countries we're
not going to go too deep into those
different models it's all over a similar
thing and but we'll do a little
introduction of just overarching what is
happening in the respective countries
and then bring that a bit closer
together and give some aspects where we
think uh maybe there could be a little
bit more thought process put into into
some of those
some of some of that momentum let's call
it like that uh maybe i'll kick it off
with switzerland uh what we're doing
right now we're in basically in a
consultation
mode consultation situation we call it a
pilot project it's basically a
nationwide study on how legalization can
be formulated so instead of having five
sessions and one of them being open we
do five years that can be cut short but
we have a five plus five year period
where anyone that would like to show and
think through a way of legalization they
can submit that you have to submit that
to the health ministry then you're going
to have all different participants of
the supply chain every stakeholder
involved and
through that after that through the
basis of hard data we then formulate a
basis for for a legal structure so uh i
think
what i think we'll talk more about later
in a little bit but why don't i give it
back into the round and share a bit more
about how it's how it's approached in
your area
so
we heard a lot about germany yesterday
already um i think we're
unlikely a few steps behind the
switzerland and germany we're trying to
find our way still
how can we make recreational cannabis
accessible to
um yeah to the people in germany it's
not defined yet
would it be through pharmacies whether
it be through dispensaries will it will
we even allow to grow plants at home
um
which to my personal opinion would be
great as a as a grower that has access
to a lot of knowledge
people like sonia could help me grow
grow plants but i think in general it's
a
yeah
it's a difficult thing to grow cannabis
the right way so i'm not sure if i would
allow to
for everybody to grow at home
but this process just was kicked off
we're hoping to get it to parliament
next year beginning of next year and
maybe have a decision end of the year so
we're still finding our way in germany
and and i think it's going to be an
exciting
path and we
have some kind of obligation to make
sure it goes or to bring our input as
insights from the industry to all the
politics everybody who has a say on that
so we can make sure it's it's going the
right way and looking left and right i
think is a good idea um because
maybe sony we want to take it up next
for for the netherlands there is another
model that's also interesting let's see
how that will go
yeah indeed it's of course tolerated for
many many years in the netherlands
like the backdoor policy we sometimes
call it
we have that distribution model
already set up for years with the coffee
shops and now finally a couple years ago
the government decided okay that's also
from the growing side the supply to the
coffee shops let's organize that
so they had um yeah like a they call it
an experiment a lot of people have
actually no idea why it's called an
experiment but that is because of the
single conventional 1961 there are two
exceptions medicinal and scientific
purposes
regarding cannabis and
they the netherlands don't want to be
like uruguay and canada
of course fully legalize it now we want
to be a brave kid within europe and okay
we call it an experiment so now
growers have actually got a permit they
can start
production soon when
actually they know a bit more about the
the timeline when they're gonna supply
the coffee shops
it's actually not all coffee shops so
10 municipalities in the netherlands are
part of the coffee shop
experiment
so it's not the big cities like
amsterdam the hague rotterdam and
utrecht now it's smaller like the bigger
cities in the south and the east
so the 10 growers can supply the 10
cities and all the coffee shops in there
and there will be a certain moment the
government will say to coffee shops
you're only allowed from now on to buy
from those 10 growers and that's a bit
how the experiment is organized
the the drawing as it was actually was
already in the december
2020 and still we have no
grower really
active
and yeah being able to sell and
last week i was hearing that the growers
themselves are expecting it will be
actually
q4 2023 probably
and
yeah
really looking forward when we finally
get there great for greenhouse
cultivation right another q4 to start
i'll
share them with that yeah
so i forgot to mention that portuguese
so um
we
last year we had some movements to
legalize cannabis there was a couple of
parties that submitted some
proposal of law in the parliament
it was not approved it was delayed for
further discussion
and with all of this situation uh with
the war and all of that so basically the
priorities are elsewhere
and everyone's expectations were that by
2023 um the general law would be
approved obviously
despite this general law may be approved
until 2023 and
there's actually no model yet we're
trying to find our way as in the same as
germany
and there's always time to
operationalize the law so you need to
need to give tools to your to your
police to check that everyone
has the
maximum amount of the limit that you
have when you're driving
there's a number of things that need to
be operationalized so despite the law
they came out in 2023
there's a lot of things that need to be
done afterwards um specific laws
specific limits to how do you test it
um
and all of this will take my expectation
would take at least two to three years
to make it actually uh uh available to
to to people in general when about spain
yeah
so
yeah we're trying to find our way
there's no there's no yet an idea
complete idea of if it will be through
pharmacies if it will be through
dispensaries if there will be a limit to
the number of dispensaries if we go that
way um
that for people to to to open a
dispensary um there's still things to be
done i think across europe it's not just
the portugal spain has a
has already a different model they have
the social clubs that were opened for
um
protecting people that consume drugs so
that's that's one step at least to
protect those people that already have
this
this consumption in place
now they're making movements for the
medical cannabis um
the next step will be the recreational
um let's hope it gets its get there
soon
thank you guys so we heard a little bit
more about the different approaches and
some of the different models and
i think our main part here in the panel
is also to channel challenge that a
little bit and we are in europe here so
we all have seen what happened in other
countries um i don't want to say they're
all failed models but let's say that if
you still have 80
black market consumption after five to
ten years depending where legalization
then it's not really what we're striving
for in europe
um we also have a different kind of
approach i believe we are the legal
structure first and then business other
countries are business first and then
legal structure
so it's a it's a great time for us to
see to assess what happened around the
world and and bring that into you know
into different formulations of how this
can work actually not different
formulations i think it has to be very
much a harmonized approach and this is
one of the things that i'm very much
missing right now in switzerland it took
us four years we've been consulting with
the with the government the last two and
a half years and we're able to finally
and again yeah it's also a study it's
not the full legalization because it
doesn't help anyone if you step outside
of the law so you better create a study
environment that allows you to then move
further once everybody else has figured
out their things
but what i'm afraid right now is that
we're going in the same direction like
some of the other countries yeah then we
just go okay business first some of the
big companies here in germany you lobby
in the bank this this and then in the
end you have a legal framework that
works in the short term and if it does
not work in the long term we had in
switzerland 20 years ago we almost
legalized and
that was then put on hold for another 20
years because we went too fast into it
now i don't want to say slow things down
and i just want to say you know have a
bit more of a wider approach a bit more
look at the different models what we see
also right now right malta multi is a
not-for-profit organization that they're
creating that does the whole
a system of malta under one roof and
then disperses the money which is also
one of the workarounds and
with all those different approaches
right now is that's what we discussed
earlier also that
if we do this now how do we then later
come to an actual industry in the end of
the day it's time it's our
the whole
way the european union works it's a
collaborative approach you should have
to know we have harmonized laws we have
country overarching systems and i see
now different standards right
switzerland the cultivation is under
gacp and organic which means soil bound
and so forth that was done for several
reasons uh you always want to have the
farm lobby with you you want to have the
big lobbies with you so you have to find
a stakeholder harmonized approach
throughout and
this is also one of the things that we
discussed what are the standards that
you think we should have
for like cultivation that side of the
supply chain of the earlier one that you
think would work across those different
jurisdictions
do you want to take this one out i think
it's yeah yeah
so there's
at the moment there's two licensing and
or two two approaches to guidelines to
cultivation
or to actually the the product one is
rather produced under gcp and product
produced under gmp
the gmp is applicable to pharmaceutical
standards so it's the approach that was
defined for the medical candidates in
europe
cultivation is always done under gac
it's the processing that is then
passes through
through gmp
for the adult use i would think that
probably gcp would be
would be more than enough to
to assure that we have a product that is
safe for the consumer
for the pharmaceutical for the medical
cannabis obviously we need at least no
additional assurances to make sure that
the product is actually as a therapeutic
effect and it's effective to to the
disease that is uh that is tackling on
the adult use we're not ideally we're
not you looking for treating a disease
we're looking for just a
uh having a recreational
effect so
i think
probably we're talking about
something somewhere between jcp and
ngmp
closer to jcp just to show that it is
safe for a consumer to to take because
gsp is used for
food uh products so
it should ensure that at least
it is a product that is safe and that
you shouldn't be armpit obviously
there's a complement in that which is
maximum amount of thc on product maximum
amount
that you need to have if you're driving
so all of this needs to be taken into
consideration in addition to the quality
of the product that is insured by the
gsp to calculations
maybe to add on that if you look to
growing uh vegetables or fruits it's all
about
global gap i think towards the gcp it's
just a step
further all because of consistency like
all those said safety for actually the
entities of the product now uh as an
example in the dutch coffee shop you are
you don't know what you're buying
actually and that has to change we we
need to go to a direction that just as
with your beer on the back side how much
alcohol
is in it that is where we need to to go
to and then
yeah your support helps as well to have
that track and trace i know where it is
really coming from the product and that
is what we really missing now in the
dutch coffee shops and i think if you
use
towards gcp you can track and trace it
back and you can be sure that you buy
actually
a certain amount of dt in your product
consumer safety right and also correct
protection and at the moment
and anywhere that you buy and be it in
whichever form cannabis you have no idea
what's in there and anyone that has
worked in the testing space anyone that
has worked with more standardization and
looking at the different chemicals or
the different
mold is a big one right i mean half of
the wheat has mold in it and
recalls is one thing you have to be able
to do and it's not even just going over
the top about it it just i think global
gap is absolutely fine but it can't be
that there is less traceability for weed
or for whatever than there is for
tomatoes in your supermarket or for uh
or for you know any kind of
natural product absolutely today your uh
your teacher this trace will write to
the source where it's been processed and
produced so
why should this industry be any
different from that and
and i think with all that also comes
accessibility right you said
they can buy the coffee shop so there is
an existing structure of where to buy it
from in the netherlands and and this is
going to be key also to fight the black
market if you're in a in a country area
not in a big city and you have to drive
25 kilometers to to shop or
nothing is available over the weekend
then we open doors for
the dealer that
might come just with a simple ping on on
instagram in 10 minutes of the backpack
to your house so in order to to make it
available we need to really think about
the distribution models
we heard yesterday whether it's be even
an online thing that you register i mean
you can do all your bank
transfers and and businesses online
after having registered and make sure
that's you doing the business so why
shouldn't that be possible with a with
an online candidate
yeah career or whatever the structure is
like so i think that's very important
that we think about that and make the
product really available for everybody
convenience i think is a big word there
right connections accessibility then
that can come in different models right
and then i'll take a quick side step
into what we're doing in switzerland
right now where yes it goes to the
health ministry it has to sign it off
but then it goes to the municipalities
and then you have you know the police
has to be involved in some ways then you
have identifiers for the people that are
actually consumers but they're not
identifiers there's pseudonyms so you
cannot actually link them to their names
and then you have different distribution
models right we have in one city for
example they're looking at
doing it the same way that there was a
government in switzerland if you're a
heroin addict you get methadone from a
government facility that is one approach
then there's the approach of coffee
shops of course coffee shops in
switzerland there they will also be
backed through at the moment the whole
uh
ordering and quality control is still
backed by a pharmacy not meaning it has
to be sold in the pharmacy but just to
have some kind of like quality standard
on that part and then we have the social
clubs that also the purchasing and the
guiding is done with the with the
qualified person and somebody that's
also you know somebody always has to be
in charge in the beginning in the
beginning right it can't just be a fool
or that's that's my humble opinion that
can't be full free flow yet
yet and then working towards that so and
then of course there's also the direct
distribution online that they're looking
at as you have you can order your
medicines online so with all those
different approaches there's not one
that works for everywhere and there's
not just okay you have to go and buy it
there because then you go to your
standard dealer that everybody's going
to or whoever you know
and
there i think this is one of the things
that i mentioned earlier with that
consultation phase there's not one model
that works across one country there's
even different models in different
countries so now going out and saying
this is the way it's going to be
will not help anyone right it will not
open it up it will actually more
isolate that one side and that's another
part we're coming to in a minute you
can't isolate one side you have to find
an approach that works for everyone and
bring the whole industry together and
have everybody that's in this room are
out there they have to state and they
have actually have to have a voice in
this because otherwise everybody
complains as usual in this industry and
nobody does anything and that doesn't
bring us further
we're also good complainers in germany i
love it
now but
maybe
i would like to give an example um
i work a lot in israel and israel
actually to me is a fascinating market
we know they do a lot of research and
have never
neglected the whole cannabis industry
we're always active and
i would say they have a semi-medical
recreation market so they have actually
more medical patients as we have in
germany right now but being a country 10
times smaller
shows how many uh
what the market size is or the
percentage of people having access to
let's say medical and safe cannabis
and what i wanted to say is
the accessibility in israel is amazing
you can subscribe to the pharmacy
when you have your prescription
obviously from the doctor and they send
you daily menus over whatsapp you see
all the strains they have it's amazing
it's it's available it's there you can
drive there right now or they will send
it to you if you're a registered person
person and and you look at 50 different
strains um thc 10 15 different strains
and cbd balanced oils fixtures whatever
and they send it to you every day so so
you see the menu you can just order it
and it's super accessible there is
transparency it's grouped in different
thc level groups so
this is something that
i know it's medical but i i think
it's a because they don't have
redeveloped the recreational program yet
this is some kind of a role model right
now to me how accessibility should look
like
and
you mentioned it earlier we don't want
to have kind of an american
model where every state does its own
thing and there is no overarching
let's say common sense and common rules
you travel from
portugal to the netherlands to germany
will that even be allowed in the future
if one of the countries has legal access
to recreation right now it's not you
cannot buy in the netherlands and drive
to to germany you're committing a crime
actually so
alignment between the countries would be
would be a very very appreciative thing
i i guess
for all of us here in the room
i think what you're mentioning the
different forms of products in israel
also in nolan the big thing is actually
the accessibility of
us for example because a lot of people
don't know that a big portion of what
the coffee shops are selling is actually
this product and the product is actually
coming out of morocco
often so
accessibility to this same products as
people are used to get needs to be there
and that is also a challenge for all the
10 growers where to get this experience
and
people are really straightforward we we
also want to buy future debt stuff from
worker
and that is different than what we know
what's happening in north america with
ice production that is not the same no
it's not the same it's a different
different profile and actually this
brings me to another thing that we
didn't discuss with drop it in anyways
there is a reason why it's only second
to your cities in holland at the moment
right the reason why they have the
second tier cities in holland is because
they're afraid of the gap that is left
in the market of distribute of supply in
the first tier cities now i think you
all can figure out yourself what i'm
talking about there and i think this is
one of the big big issues that also have
to be addressed and tackled before we
just do now okay let's make a model that
works we have big companies that make
big facilities they all supply everyone
yada yada and then after that you have a
vacuum and usually like you're with
people that need to do something and if
they don't have anything to do they'll
do something else so this is something
that has to be addressed that can be
addressed in different ways i'm not
gonna i mean there's there's different
you
know it
like
you give them a certain time you give
them a chance to come forward with a
chance to you know
self
in
substance
good question i don't know all right
like an amnesty program right we're
giving time to come from from stepping
out of the dark so to say come forward
in front of the law and say you've come
forward with that in the past and now
your record could be cleared back
exactly and create the point zero and
then move forward and then like that
have the part of the overall industry
and this is a big i think for me that's
something nobody talks about because
needless to say this has been a long
this has been around for a very long
time and i was very happy to be part of
the consultation process here in germany
a couple of weeks ago here in berlin and
the gentleman from from holland that
organizes all the coffee shops one of
the coffee shops association he was like
how can we bring the moroccan hash back
because the people will want that hash
if it's not there they will just go
around it so it's a there's a lot of
more homework to be done is what i want
to say with that not that i'm saying
blueprint or any one of us i don't want
to be the one that has to make the
blueprint but i'm definitely here to
speak up and put up my voice and i think
everybody should also do that in their
capacity and not just be one on the
outside and just say no no no this is
not good it's not good that's completely
open let's completely run around and you
know i
i just want to say there's a bit more
homework to be done in my
in my opinion and
we need to close these gaps all of them
right accessibility
supply chain
variability in the product is very
important
and although you said
earlier that
ideally people in the recreational
market
don't buy for disease treatment
but let's face it there are so many
people that do it right now and they
don't even buy from the wreck they buy
from their legal market and they may
have found their hush
that works for them so if you change all
that we know how
how important
the very transition of the strain is to
if you have found it for yourself for
your endocannabinoid system to be
received and if you change all that you
lose these these patients these
consumers yeah control over the supply
chain i think it's the
it's the key to all this and it doesn't
depend on the country to legalize the
other tubes it depends on
if there's a morocco ash that comes from
from this country then you need to
legalize it there and have the in place
controls that make sure that the quality
is there that you're because this is not
growing tomatoes we don't test the
tomato for an api for an active
ingredient we but we test cannabis we
need to have a specification in place
and having jc gcp regulations in place
doesn't mean lack of control
it means that you have a specification
that you need to comply with to release
the product in the market
there's this still applies it doesn't uh
it doesn't mean that you like lack of
control so if you have this standardized
across
the world ideally um
if you have this these standards
complied with each country and it is
regulated and controlled in that country
then we'll have better control over this
and well at the moment it's the one that
controls the whole
basically the supply chain in the world
and make sure that
we don't have loss of control or a theft
of controlled substance
so this is not one country to decide we
need to learn from each other i think
europe has a lot to learn from the
mistakes made in canada from what's been
implemented in the us i think there's
good things there's things that we need
to learn from and improve
and
we cannot shut our eyes to what others
have done because otherwise we will
learn from it and we'll make the same
mistakes
so yeah it's uh it's important that we
learn from some models i think
having the the adult use for instance
having
having some kind of description i've
been in a in a dispensary have just came
from came from from the u.s i've been in
a dispensary there and there was a
dispensary that had basically the
product was ordered on a table and a
tablet inside the the inside the
dispensary and there was description of
the product there was a valuation on
what it did for you from a focus point
of view from a sleep point of view if it
is energetic if it is something like
that so if you can have this
at least this information for the
program i think information is key for
this because you don't know what you're
buying because it's not just a teacher
it's the whole components of the of the
of the plant it's the the flavonoids
it's the terpenes and everything will
will come along and give you a different
different sensation and different
experience when you're when you're
smoking it or vaping it or whatever
we're doing with it
so i think it's important to give also
this information to the to the consumers
so that they know what to expect and
they can choose um what's actually their
their purchasing
that's
something that we're discussing
internally all the time is that
i mean we are all from the industry we
have a good idea what what product could
do to us but
um if we want to win
people that are not consumers that and
yet and we want we want to create
accessibility and transparency for them
is like with wines right on the back
it's written it complements with certain
foods it it has it has this that taste
and if you
yeah so if you want to make a wine
choice they give you some options and
hints what you if you're even if you're
not an expert what you
what you can choose and and i think also
we need
a kind of a
traffic sign or or or taste wheel
kind of easy graph on product or
in the stores that describe
the actual
power of the product let's go that way
right so
this is extremely important to open the
market for other user groups i guess
and create a standardization throughout
right i mean i think this should be the
same in every country
like sugar content in food exactly like
now we have sugar content coming up and
it's a big thing people forgot yeah we
had a lot of little sugar now there's a
lot of a lot of issues coming out of
that we have it with alcohol you have
beer that has a certain percentage it
has a certain tax on it you have wine
that's a high percentage of higher tax
that's how you naturally also can kind
of guide the consumer towards a more
[Music]
softer
consumption and then well outside of all
of that
what
for in you guys opinion now we've talked
about what europe has been doing we
talked a little bit about the outside
approaches and we don't want to say that
the u.s and canada did everything wrong
not at all not at all they were front
runners
a lot of pioneering a lot of a b testing
a lot of you know cowboy mentality and a
lot of business first approach which has
it's very rightful place within within
an industry i think
anyone that comes from more economical
background sometimes and without the
business first approach at the same time
we also like slow and steady and i
believe still slow and steady wins the
race
um are there in your opinions any key
learnings that we should take from
outside because actually this panel has
been put together a little bit also and
everybody that is sitting here has
explained extensive
experience outside of europe but they're
working
from europe to the outside and from the
different aspects of it what have you
seen outside that you think we should
take
and
and then that could work on our our
grounds
actually i want to dive back to the
cultivation side of things
because that's where it all starts and
if you look to
the with the coffee shop in holland we
have a way how to get product to the
consumers but
at this moment
you have like a vertical integrated
company they all need to be certain need
to have their own models propagation but
why are we so big in the in the growing
industry in the netherlands because we
have specialists for propagation who do
all the cloning we have growers and then
we have more towards poison harvest now
they need to do all so you need to
actually build a company with four
different companies within the company
and i think when
implementation of the everything
regarding recreational cannabis they
should not forget about
the growing part and may make it
possible that growers can buy rooted
clones from other companies because that
is what is lacking now as well in many
countries
they need to do all but yeah
it is something special and you cannot
do everything
really well
without me wanting to be too much
commercial at this stage but this is
exactly what
we are trying to tackle from my company
we looked at all these countries that
are the companies that are completely
vertically integrated and that's not an
economically viable system right usually
in any other industry you have
specialists in different parts of the
supply chain and then you have to work
with each other but because of the
hardship of the regulatory non-existing
or less existing framework you have a
lot of completely vertically integrated
companies which doesn't make the most
efficient doesn't make them specialists
so we believe through full transparency
throughout the whole supply chain you
can break that vertical integration into
what i would like to say more of a
horizontal integration you can still
have quality control you can still have
batch release systems you can set up
coas at every stage of the production
and therefore actually then also
consumer protection in the end but you
can allow the clones to be done by the
best clone
clone manufacturer cultivator
cultivation done by the specialist in
that then it goes to you know a
manufacturer that is specifically just
the big manufacturers in pharma are in
actually out of food products they're
contract manufacturers they don't
produce their own products they produce
for everyone else and this is another
big thing that i believe we have to
break up i see michelle stood up there
so is this the time michelle for us to
ask some questions from the audience or
yeah yes please
shot like always
let's hear it again for uh lou krishner
and your
[Music]
[Applause]
hi thanks a lot for the panel my
question is like about the supply chains
and the legalization process in germany
so right now the biggest community
pharmacy organization like the only one
who talks to the government actually has
as an impact says we can help you with
expansion if we legalize but only if we
do like in community pharmacies only
because that's the only way the only way
we can
we can save the track and trace process
and with your experience what do you
think about this statement about this
approach
i'm not 100 sure about the question so
that the the track and trace is only uh
applicable when there is certain
dispensaries from the network no no um
the community pharmacists in germany say
we can take care about the dispensing
but only if the dispension only works
throughout pharmacies because that's the
only way we can take care about the
supply chain well that is of course
because they want to keep their
interests and they have a strong lobby
group there which is their rightful
thing to do but then there are solutions
out there like for example mine or other
ones
that actually exactly are dedicated to
break this up you can move between
different problems between different
dispensing models and still have a full
traceability fully
you know integral supply chain without
any product leaving from one side of the
other or any product entering the supply
chain so this is of course a statement
that was brought in there from uh from
promoter strong lobby groups which i
believe very much are important to all
have within
and
not fight against this
next few stages because the more you
have all stakeholders involved and
happier behind it
the sooner we can move towards the next
station or the next uh
just just to add i think personally that
we shouldn't
neglect an existing network of
pharmacies that we have they're
specialists i think it's it's the lowest
hurdle to train these people
also on the consumption and application
of
not only medical but also recreational
cannabis so
it would be in my opinion not wise to
exclude that and try to differentiate or
make a hard cut between the recreation
of the medical dispension of cannabis
because that network exists it's all
over and it's even in small rural areas
usually you have a pharmacy so
so again accessibility and professional
advice which is part of the
of the proposal for law in germany that
you need a trained person
which i think is a very very good thing
and we should obviously do that so um
yeah
and i hope that answers your question a
little bit it's part of the convenience
right again
apps you started with at the end of the
day it has to be a model that's
convenient and the most
widespread distribution model straight
away available overnight is through
pharmacies now if the pharmacist trains
someone that is not a pharmacist to then
be the person in the dispensary that's a
different story there's many ways to
work with
and
[Music]
i'm interested to to see a pharmacist
help
someone that's new to cannabis
to show how to apply the cannabis so if
he's buying a flower will the pharmacist
help him or her
rolling a joint packing the pipe i don't
know but
it's going to be interesting
good morning matt dickinson from clarion
canvas we're doing indoor
small batch craft cultivation and
portugal a question for you guys and
thanks to the panel as we move into
legalization or adult use what do you
think we'll see dropped in terms of the
gmp to gacp
restrictions and do you think we'll see
any changes to that at all
the question
so
as we move from legalization we're
starting from that from medical or to
adult use do you think that we're going
to see some of the restrictions that we
currently have with gmp
dropped and moved more into a gacp model
or do you think those restrictions were
specifically with to do with
microbial accounts consistency product
registration
labeling things like that do you think
we'll see those dropped or relaxed
um
from an adult use point of view in a
consumer point of view
part of those restrictions probably will
will fall the specification side it's a
question of safety so i don't think it
will vary too much the specification
that you get from gcp from the gcp part
on the labeling on the type of packaging
that you can use eventually there will
be some variation but bear in mind that
cannabis is being used for
equivalent to food grade materials so
specifications on materials should be
probably the same won't vary it much
the only thing i see is the labeling
that can have different information
because you're not treating an illness
you're talking really you're talking
about the regression and use so i think
i think it will become much more
accessible and then all the
conversations that i was part of was to
to lower those barriers without losing
the quality control and the traceability
and all of those aspects so i think the
life for a craft cultivator and it's
going to become
easier than ever because it shouldn't be
easy i don't think it should be easy but
it will become
more accessible
thank you thank you so very much we're
actually out of time let's hear it once
again
[Music]