um so yeah i'm really looking forward to
this conversation actually and to kind
of around everybody and where everyone
is coming from before we tell you what
our backgrounds are and where we're
coming from just like a show of hands
how many people are actually
making a living from cannabis right now
some sort of revenue or something
awesome how many people are kind of like
just activists or
um
very few
clint of course of course
um okay yeah so we're we're mostly from
west coast of north america and i'm from
vancouver and british columbia
where i hope dispensaries get licensed
there before legalization and then have
been kind of slowly changing certain
laws and licensing classes and things
like that since legalization um we have
people from california from arizona
i think it kind of the easiest way i
mean obviously their bios are very
impressive and they are in the program
um but i'd like to just kind of start
off by saying you know who are you
advocating for and what are you
advocating
um hi i'm luna stower i'm with ispire
and uh who am i advocating for the
people and the plan i think that um you
know access purity wellness this is all
what we come here for um and this is so
much bigger than just the plant so as
we're seeing a lot of darkness in the
world right now we really believe that
plant medicine is our pathway to higher
consciousness and a higher way of living
it's not just about the buzz or the
medical benefits
it really is about liberation and
sovereignty and autonomy and that's you
know the human rights issue that we're
fighting for
[Applause]
hi i'm brigitte hennessey i'm with weed
maps
and who we are fighting for and what we
really dive into is making sure that we
have
an open diverse and transparent cannabis
economy around the world
and so we have really leaned into that
and made sure that we are fighting for
that every single day
and for those who are not familiar with
me max i should just quickly say we are
a tech company in the cannabis space so
we don't directly touch the plant but we
are here to power the industry with and
give the industry tools to perform as
efficient as possible
hi everyone my name is matt cumin i'm an
attorney i've been
in the cannabis space since the late
1990s in the bay areas where i started
we have office in new york recently
opened um
my advocacy
changed over the years initially i was
advocating for medical cannabis patients
we were
suing governments for you know
discriminating against patients in
california some
federal governments who
state
kent state county cities
then uh
i got very involved in political action
committee in california we advocated for
cultivators up in the emerald triangle
we were
bringing them together and formed a
political action committee in humboldt
county and other places when we brought
the pac down to los angeles and
essentially trying to organize
the business community that was going to
be affected by the changing laws
and uh
so all along the way we've been you know
the advocacy is changing and now
ultimately the advocacy is really about
fixing the broken laws that
we've seen you know canada and
california and other many other places i
know dominic's going to talk about that
a lot
and we're just trying to fix the broken
laws so that we can really make sure
that there is even more access
free
unhindered access to cannabis
throughout the world and that's i think
the next big
big advocacy for me
demetri downing i'm an ex-prosecutor got
involved in the industry in 2012
in a sort of general council role for my
brothers and my dad's dispensaries in
arizona
uh 2012 2015 i studied cannabis
regulations licensing market structures
uh came to some conclusions which i
found out later through my work with
normal were the wrong conclusions got my
head on straight
started the marijuana association of
arizona which is which became known as
one of the best ones in the state uh
interests of interstate siloed markets
of the united states and we evolved it
into marijuana industry association usa
and we've been developing that over the
last year
and um well we do a lot of different
things application advocacy education
business networking
but if i can leave you with one thing
we have to fight as an industry
as the future members of an industry
participants in industry employees of an
industry
fight the concept of limited licensing
because that is an economic abomination
that we have inherited
through the good work of mpp but
inadvertently not understanding
economics and market structure actually
they probably understood them
just to appease those who hate cannabis
limited licensing was created and for
most people that i have met
uh in the industry it um
it's just it's not a favorable result
and it's definitely not a favorable
result for the patients and the
consumers but we can talk more about
that as we go so to meet you
[Applause]
raises a point that i was referring to a
couple of years ago in an icbc
conference with with george worth and
burkhardt blind on the stage i said that
that lobbying for cannabis regulations
with politicians was like playing chess
with the pigeon it doesn't really matter
who wins they're still gonna knock over
all the pieces and all over the
board
um people took that as a little more
pessimistic i think but i it was very
interesting our conversation backstage
where we've all kind of talked about
we've seen such amazing progress in our
lifetimes and and
so many more people have access
although we've also seen things drop
like in bc for example you know there
used to be better access for a lot of
patients particularly poor patients um
when things were still illegal and now
that we've gotten to legalization those
things have gone backwards and so what
are some of the other things that you
see that have been frustrating and what
kind of keeps you motivated to stay
positive and keep moving
yeah i would say a lot of the
frustrations um for us definitely comes
from not having pathways for medicine
and that's not really a conversation
anymore right it's recreational now
we had to pass a senate bill 34 just to
be able to do what we were doing before
which is getting to ill people patients
veterans um so yeah i mean that's a huge
part of what we do
um ice fire works in the in the hardware
space so much like we maps we don't
touch the plan we just do the hardware
for the vape industry so we can really
uh be able to put our our resources and
our energy and our advocacy behind
certain things that other cannabis
companies cannot because they you know
all the limitations that they have
around banking advertising cash flow um
so that's been a really exciting thing
to be able to have ancillary be able to
come in and show up for the um you know
the consciousness raising side the
lobbying side the organizing side
because really there's no there's no pr
group or psa for cannabis no one's
really arguing in her voice it's either
industry advocates or patients who want
low pricing it's not really what's best
and what's in the nature of this plan so
i think that the thing that keeps me the
most happy and we talked about this
backstage too is you know just the
networking doing what we're doing here
it's a radical act during a time of
pandemic to come out and be around other
people and fight for medical autonomy
and advocacy during a time of medical
fascism in a lot of ways people are
controlling everything about our medical
passports and what we have access to
from food to medicine and beyond so what
keeps me feeling happy is seeing that
much like the way that the plant grows
in uh you know an interconnected way in
this environment we're doing that as
well making sure that we're staying
buoyant that we're connecting with each
other we don't compete it's not us
versus each other it's cooperation
there's enough for all of us here and so
i think that's what gives me hope is
that despite the obvious um tyranny of
you know uh of the government against
people being as autonomous and free as
possible we're still learning from this
plant we're still allowing it to open
our hearts and our minds and see that
this is not like other industries this
is not a consumer package good you can't
just treat this like alcohol tobacco
it's a magical mystical medicinal plan
when you start acting like it
yeah i would say that um when i think
about it i you know i feel overall very
optimistic because when we start seeing
legalization take place in new areas or
you know they're starting down this path
they are looking to the established
markets and trying to understand where
some of the pitfalls are i think one of
the biggest mistakes we've seen in some
of the early
movers was really
not bringing the legacy market to the
table and having their voice heard it
was a bunch of people that were trying
to learn about the plan or learn about
legalization from a very business
setting and so i think we're doing a
better job and i i'm very hopeful that
we'll continue down this path if
and the legacy market isn't an
afterthought we don't establish a market
and establish regulations and policy and
then think later like oh we should
probably talk to the people that have
been in this for 20 years in the illicit
market like we should be having them at
the table from the outset and i think
we're seeing states like new york that
actually got that and understood it and
are going to implement a law that is
just that so i think overall it's
hopeful it's slow
but hopeful i think that we're going to
get there and it's just going to take
time
um
and and
[Music]
hats off to weak maps and they put their
money where their mouth is and
that dovetails into one of the trends
that i've seen in terms of success
um it's businesses that
integrate the advocacy
that is still necessary in order to make
this
not only politically and socially and
culturally you know acceptable and get
rid of stigma but also to help create
their own markets
and if you bring legacy people in and
marry them correctly with your your
finance people your mbas and you develop
a working team uh then i think you
actually have massive success and
actually as a side note to that i went
to a
seminar it wasn't about cannabis but it
was about
um
someone was tracking uh
publicly traded companies that had big
budgets for lobbying and political work
and those companies actually did better
you know from a profit standpoint so i
mean if you're if you're a company and
you think well advocacy is an
afterthought or that we're not going to
spend money on advocacy it's a mistake
because you actually will help create
your markets and you'll build uh not
only build your markets and open your
markets but you'll also be able to help
the larger political and social cultural
goals that we're trying to achieve
yeah i'll go ahead and one trick tony
you know i'm incredibly
the world is upside down from where it
was back on arizona and california it's
unbelievable the amount of patient
access and consumer access and choice
that exists now that as opposed to 15 20
years ago
but i've always just wanted to stick to
the same basic point as a trade
organization you know it's everyone from
a bud tender with a dream to an owner
with an exit strategy and you have to
advance the rights of all those people
every employee and their ability to one
day be an owner themselves and limited
licensing barriers to entry prevent that
and that's one of the biggest things
that's happening in the cannabis
industry that we as members of the
cannabis industry need to advocate
against and educate against and germany
hasn't set things up yet but you know if
there's one thing i can leave you with
limited licensing means drug war 2.0
means prohibition 2.0 there have to be
civil and criminal sanctions in place to
punish these people that's not what the
members of this industry should want
advocate for and it's not ultimately
what's in the best interest of executing
their hopes and their dreams and it's
not what's in the best interests of
creating competition
innovation and better products for
patients and consumers so again being
the one trick prone i'm extremely
optimistic i'm an ex-prosecutor it's
incredible
what's happened
unbelievable amazing come to california
come to arizona it's beautiful
but
there's a lot of work to be done and
media usa is here to help do that
okay can i say something no i i
graduated college a long time ago i'd
become the old old guy on the panel here
a little behind me
and
um i immediately went became a labor and
community organizer and over the years i
fundamentally was trained and
fundamentally my passions are about
organizing
and over the years i've just seen what
happens when people come together
even a small group you know
have an idea
and then they organize around it and
it's amazing i mean
in the cannabis space one of the things
we did in uh
in
2009 the state of maine came out with an
ethical rule that said that lawyers
could
represent dispensaries in maine
and you know
i called up you know and then the maine
bar association went over to arizona
actually and we i flew to phoenix and we
met at the aclu headquarters and a bunch
of criminal defense lawyers i knew and
immediately started organizing and we
reached out to people in the main
and the arizona bar association we
organized like crazy and they
they ended up
arizona bar association wrote one of
those brilliant
ethics opinions that said lawyers you
know should be allowed and it was really
important and and because we organized
because we we wrote papers and we got
law professors to help and
it
is no question that you can advocate and
organize
to the positive results but it does
require you to you know to
sit down with people you might have a
disagreement with and work out how your
strategy is going to go but it's
absolutely possible we did amazing i was
in mississippi we organized black
woodcutters who had no money in power to
change legislation in the state i mean
anything's possible if you work next
that's basically my message
yeah what we've been seeing in canada is
sort of the industry bifurcating a
little um into two camps and and uh it's
interesting you know dimitri keeps
bringing up the limited licensing issues
that they're having in states and it's
it's it's a fundamental
issue of how you approach your
competition you know are they actually
competition or are they on your same
side in the long run and
how do you encourage that in an industry
that's filling up with people you know
in canada
in the last couple of months we've had
some stores starting to advocate to go
and arrest shutting down indigenous
stores
without any idea of what what their
sovereignty is like or you know anything
like that and um
that's
that's something that while we've been
seeing that happen large producers are
getting away without even getting fines
or anything it's like we don't want to
see anybody go to jail but if you're
going to have rules you should follow
the rules um obviously indigenous stores
fall under a different category because
we still haven't figured out exactly
what that sovereignty looks like but um
how does that issue strike you like how
do you how do you build those bridges or
do we just wait until they're all pushed
out all the people that don't want to
work with anybody else
i mean i think
in my role at weed maps we've had to
deal with this a lot because we
we were supportive of the legacy
and industry we've been around for 15
years
and so when
places like california started moving to
an adult use model and started to
regulate
we had really hard conversations with
our clients and we had to be open with
the fact that you know we are going to
push for a very open market and some of
you guys are going to feel really
uncomfortable with that because we want
to see everybody win here we don't want
to see just five or ten companies
winning the entire industry and we often
will be at odds with our clients
we're sort of unapologetic about it at
this point we treat it very
diplomatically we will go in and have
that hard conversation but and we'll
hear them out and hear their point of
view and try to explain you know we we
look at the data we can tell you that
the data is there to say there's plenty
of demand for the industry so
everybody's going to do well that we all
have to work together with one voice
it takes time and people have to start
building trust but i think the
relationship building having honest
conversations looking at the data you
can get there just it's a work in
progress all the time and
we will lose some relationships over
that but you have to be okay and know
that you're working you're heading the
right direction the whole time
and remember when i we were talking you
know government is the enemy government
deserves the black market it creates
through its restrictions and through its
limited licensing and we will it's
winning we're winning all the time
because whatever whatever we can't
organize well enough to create and and
get rid of these restrictions
well the consumers are going to go get
their cannabis in the black market
that's just the way it is it's going to
always be that way it's going to be that
way in germany it's been that way in
europe and it's going to continue to be
that way so we win
the plant wins either way
it gets out there
and i was always telling my legacy to my
clients up in the emerald triangle i
said you guys you know you you planted
the seeds of your own of your own demise
because the consumers saw that little
green bud from california and they went
crazy around the world for it and that's
you know part of what happened but it's
it's on fire now there's no going back
yeah to your point about northern
california exporting all of our cool
um something really interesting that i
want to mention too that makes sense in
europe because of the appellations of
origin for wine
you'll notice that you can't call
something champagne unless it's from the
champagne region bordeaux
so something that frenchie cannoli the
late great hashishin who is no longer
with us but i always was talking about
the terroir and
the place the spirit of the soil the air
the water the genetics and the love that
the people in northern california put
into it through regenerative farming and
the energetics of really working with a
plant that they know that they're making
for medicine and having decades and
decades and generations of people doing
that work um i think that that's
something that can really set folks
apart um you can't just put cali on a
mylar bag and call it cali and have
people you know believe that we i think
that that's something that can help us
as far as cooperation goes is really
finding other people that have the same
message you know with that is something
simple is when we do our dab bars we
always have a concentrate sponsor that
has a mission that we relate to
um you know we always have you know
another you know dynavap is another
partner that technically is a competitor
but we're partners now we use each
other's in you know induction heating
for their dynavap piece or the dip
device folks like it doesn't it doesn't
have to be limiting it's not we're
larger than the sum of our parts and i
think that once we start seeing people
come together and use common language
that's the one thing i really want to
say to the europeans out here trying to
legislate and trying to move this
forward is you know talk to each other
get on the same page
a lot of what happened with us in
california was we did a lot of sloppy
infighting right in front of the
legislators and it was really bad it
allowed vermont's uh philip morris and
some of these bigger players that the no
acreage caps came in and just decimated
us because they came in in their suits
they were really buttoned up they were
really respectable they spoke the same
language and we look like a bunch of
wild wacky hippies that were infighting
um so i think that that's the biggest
thing that i've seen is utilizing trade
organizations like me to um talking to
these you know people that you think are
your enemies like matt said you know
these people are on your side having
that hard conversation now is gonna save
you a lot of pain um from down the road
when you're trying to undo some of this
stuff so i think that knowing what you
have knowing that what you grow what you
make is really special and finding other
people that are in it for the long haul
not folks that are exit focused that are
just in here to make a quick buck green
rush it and bounce that's not what we're
here for so just be on the lookout for
real family and stick with them
[Music]
and i think that it gets a little
overwhelming i know certainly did in
canada where it suddenly was the mining
companies throwing around stocks and
millions of dollars and it it can get a
little discouraging especially because
then it makes it harder for the
legitimate people to
do money and raises and things like that
but
it's we're already starting to see that
kind of fade out like those companies
can't keep running the way they're
running not forever um and that now that
we've gotten smaller license classes and
things like that and people have had
time to transition that maybe weren't
able to transition right away
into the legacy and into the legal
market from the legacy market um it's uh
it does get better eventually but it's
it's hard you know you said something
backstage that is exactly is the
insulting injury of of telling the
jurisdiction this is what's going to
happen
and then watching them do it again
anyway and it gets very frustrating to
see that happen again and again but you
know on the positive side the more that
optimistic outlook is that we do come
through the other side eventually and
we're starting to get there in the west
coast for example i mean
you guys are going to have issues again
when you get to federal legalization
because it's
you know the more you try to appease a
bigger group of people the worst things
ultimately get in the long run for the
people that know what's going on um to
meet you i notice you've been taking
notes uh frantically i'm just taking
those for myself really i don't know
what what
no well i mean again you know i'm gonna
be a one-trick pony you have to do
whatever you can
to fight limited licensing it creates so
many of the problems
our friends turning each other in
we know the ruthlessness and the games
that are played it makes no economic
sense it's an abomination
even if you're opening up a nuclear
power plant you can go get a license you
pay for it and then if you break the
rules they take away your permit
limited licensing merit-based licensing
deciding who has the right to retail
manufacture dispense grow all that stuff
it creates a minority report reality
remember that movie with tom cruise
where the government is trying to guess
who's going to do things right or who's
going to commit crimes that's exactly
what we're doing and it's and it's a god
bless the mpp i love them
they inadvertently did this they should
have never attached manufacturing
cultivation that they had some sort of
economic theorist working with them they
wouldn't have but it's a tragedy that
we're repeating over and over again
and countries like you know maybe even
germany i don't know what's going to
happen here i don't know what the
lobbying situation is and the special
interest situation is but people look in
the united states and say how did they
do it there
and this this this devil
exists
that uh you know it's damaging all kinds
of things even the legacy market
okay the legacy market if it wasn't for
such restrictive limited licensing could
get involved
you know yeah sure they have to dot more
eyes and cross more teas and follow more
rules but it's impossible for you them
to even get started in social equity in
arizona we have 4 000 people go through
all right god bless weed maps for
sponsoring us i have to mention they
sponsored that program um four thousand
people get educated they self-identified
as social equity entrepreneurs that
wanted to be involved in the cannabis
industry they're competing for 26
licenses 1500 were determined eligible
through a series of state determinations
as to what social equity is okay fine
fifteen hundred paid four thousand
dollars
twenty six of them got licenses so what
does that mean that means about 4 000
people that were motivated to get off
their ass and do something and push for
their hopes and their dreams and
opportunity in cannabis is what cannabis
should be about not just patients and
consumers and therapy and all that stuff
but also about a free market of
opportunity
all those are crushed
all those were crushed because of the
concept of limited licensing i'd rather
see those 4 000 people go get a piece of
paper screw things up get their license
revoked fail that's what cannabis should
be about and we keep i hear over and
over again in different countries and
different states throughout the world
what did colorado do how did this work
why did that work
and the problem is
limited licensing this notion needs to
die
okay
you know in canada we had barriers that
ended up being
very similar to that that came about
just from oh you have to have this and
this and this in the facility and you
have to have this in the facility and
then because there were so many people
that were just saying hey we applied for
a license so were they enlisted on the
stock market by our stock there was so
much of that that right when we were
allowing smaller producers in health
canada said okay you've got to actually
have a building first before we're even
going to look at you so then all of
these smaller producers and people that
you know especially people from from the
former illicit market that didn't know
if they were going to get security
cleared couldn't necessarily
build out those facilities to that level
and um
take it a side tangent here because i've
been using the word even though it's a
pet peeve of mine as i hate the word
legacy market because legacy is
something do you leave to somebody when
you're dead and the black market hasn't
gone anywhere it's still here it's still
strong in canada it's still strong in
california right thriving
actually growing up so yeah so i mean
it's it's and it's an interesting thing
to kind of watch happen especially when
the government's you know in canada one
of their main approaches was well we
want to
transition the
illicit market but then you only saw
that in basically bc every other
province wanted to term wipe it out and
replace it right i mean so
um
i had a question in there somewhere i
think it was a bridge that you had
brought up before um about how important
it is to fight for equity and amnesty
and that kind of touches on on some of
these barriers and artificial barriers
that are being raised to the industry
yeah i think one of the things that we
everybody says you know where you'll
hear it again and again in states or in
different jurisdictions that are
legalizing and they'll say
they're doing it to write them wrong
from the war on drugs or whatever
but we're not actually doing that we're
i mean if you look california is a great
example of what not to do in this area
because they did a lot of talking about
social equity and making sure that there
was room in the market for people there
was no clear definition in the policy
it was every jurisdiction gets to decide
how they're going to define it and how
they're going to give out those licenses
and there's no access to capital so
we're going to give people the space
we're going to say you know the city of
los angeles for instance said
you have to have the property in
possession before you can apply for a
license
and then they took two and a half years
to go through the first phase of
licensing while people paid rent on that
property how does somebody who has zero
to very little capital even
get in there and do that so
we've been fighting for that we are
trying to call this out as often as we
can and
i do feel hopeful in places like new
york where they're leading with the
social equity licenses those are going
first they're getting a head start it's
still not perfect there's still going to
be a lot of room for improvement and we
have a fight ahead for us
but
we're finally starting to think about it
the right way and think about like
not only do we give them licensing first
like how do we help them build
successful businesses that can compete
with the well-capitalized that can
compete with the companies that have
been around for decades and their
multi-state operators are you know
they're operating all over the globe we
want to make sure that there's room for
the mom and pop shops to be in the
market so i think
we need to continue to call that out i
think limited licensing
on every level is one of those problems
as well and quite frankly you're just
propping up the illicit market by
limiting on any level of that so i think
we need to continue to call that out
make sure that people are thinking
through that as a design policy
yeah
these are law school habits i think they
write stuff down um
but uh yeah you know and you know
again don't
countries like germany and the
regulators i hope that germans do their
own thing and
invent a market model and say hey you
know what colorado you guys screwed
things up you guys didn't give enough
people opportunity
you guys left the legacy market out you
guys left social equity out by not
allowing for free market capitalism to
triumph and for people to succeed or
fail based on their own merits access to
capital is a huge problem
and uh there's other groups that have
come up with this it's not my route well
i came up with it on my own but they
come up with that on their own as well
you know there's an easy way to solve
the social equity issue you know less
barriers to entry allow all the social
equity whoever wants to self-define as
social equity to participate and then
create funds with the taxes that are
generated so that they can have access
to capital to take out low interest like
loans from sba type programs if you want
to help social equity uh status
individuals and that's great that you
know i support that but to have people
go through a merit-based process to
determine that they're social equity
eligible that that's that's really tough
i guess you know even in a capital uh
even an event in a in a loan structure
they're going to have to do that but
again if i can say one thing
let's kill
limited licensing in cannabis
yeah it's diversity right isn't that
what you want in any ecosystem is
diversity
the um
yes and a couple of points that i wrote
a short little piece
for that
interesting little soft word the the
dominic's you know
saw here which i agree with
completely
um the other thing just talking about
advocacy and how to do it um
maybe because you know i we're we're
david to goliath you know but david won
you know and and i know we're winning i
know we're going to win this and and
it's going to be painful and there's
going to be a lot of baton passing i
mean i you know i've got you know my two
daughters are you know activists and i
i've got the baton handing over to them
and a lot of young people that i mentor
and bring along you know
there's a lot of organizing tips out
there you know we you know when we went
it up to humble you know the cannabis
farmers up there were terrified and we
actually brought them in and they were
going to the pta meetings and they
couldn't tell their teachers you know
what they did for a living the kids
teachers and we brought them in by
creating a stakeholder process you know
so we went and we started we went to the
rotary club and can we have a
can we have your monthly luncheon
meeting be about cannabis up here and
and you know business people in humboldt
county and it turned out
we had allies everywhere
we have allies in so many places but
they're afraid they're a little bit
afraid because of the stigma but when
you start to create a forum
or forum whatever the plural is you know
for people to come into a room and start
talking and communicating it's amazing
what happens and that's what happened up
in humble you know we had a 16-month
campaign that was kicked off at a rotary
club meeting in october of 2014 and by
january of 2016 which was really fast if
you talk to political people we had an
ordinance in place that was progressive
that had environmental concerns yes the
state screwed up they allowed stacking
the licenses and they wiped out you know
farmers and
not that the farmers knew what they were
doing how to get into the space or
branding and that's all other separate
conversation but the point is that you
can organize using stakeholder groups
you bring in the you know you bring
everybody into the room and you'll find
your allies they will emerge they're
they're in the political world they're
just afraid but you give them a place to
speak as an organizing tool that that's
really powerful you know create places
that you wouldn't think to go
the rotary club the
you know the the whatever it is you know
they're out there there's all these
places and they're all
interested in cannabis we all have
veterans
every country has veterans of war and
all of them have ptsd and physical pain
and almost all of them are being
prescribed opiates right now so that's
one thing also just like as we're
diversifying our voices one thing i've
noticed is the only people advocating
for cannabis is usually business people
if i was a legislator and i saw business
people coming to advocate for cannabis i
would not trust them i would think that
they were just doing it to do business
unfortunately we've seen in california
is that the patients don't come out and
lobby with us when we go to the city
council meetings until one in the
morning on a tuesday night in the middle
of the night it's all business people
it's not convincing and i think that
that's something we need to really think
about is with these stakeholder meetings
how many business people in here have
actually held the stakeholder meetings
beyond maybe a focus group for early
stage branding market research like
who's really getting people together
first thing we're all fighting for these
people where where are these people are
they at the old folks home like in
berkeley you know or in the bay area we
had sue taylor who's bringing it into um
uh old folks homes and it was they were
able to get topical rubs with cannabis i
mean these are things that had to go
into the community um you know talking
to school teachers how are we doing this
work i mean really ask yourself like how
are you really talking to the end
consumer and having them talk back to
the legislators we cannot do it alone
there's way too few of us we're in the
minority the majority of people are
either neutral or uncomfortable around
cannabis um other business people we're
all busy right i don't know about you
guys but i've been working 90 hour weeks
for the last two years without a break
just with ice fire before that it's like
six seven years in the cannabis industry
with no breaks this is a crisis where
this is not a game to us like there are
people dying every day there are people
rotting in jail who are a lot darker
skin than me for doing a lot less than
what i do every day and get applauded
for so this is like we don't have time
we don't have many resources but we have
the love and the organizing and the
networking and leaning into that and
that diversity i mean they say this with
women too it's like having more people
in the business is not just a feel-good
move you actually objectively in the
data have better innovation more
disruptive technology um and even same
thing with like women and people of
color in the workspace it's not just you
can feel good that there's chicks on
your team women people of color provide
incredible insights that build out the
end result for your consumer and you
sell better love is lucrative that's
what we have to remember the love is
lucrative but how are we gonna actually
organizing it together to your point
stakeholders are rarely in the room with
us we have a lot of these conversations
in these kind of silos and it's an echo
chamber so you know i really invite you
guys to talk to the soccer moms go to
the places where they're focused on wine
and cocaine at the club when i'm out
there when i'm out in the back dabbing
and everyone's railing lines and start a
conversation be like this is what i do
this is my plant medicine this is how i
integrate it i talk about the cannabis
industry the people who are not in the
industry all the time because the best
way to stop the war on drugs from making
more veterans of the war on drugs is to
stop making the laws that criminalize it
and every person who's a voting person
has a voice in that so just like he said
this is not about industry this is a
movement a mass movement for medical
freedom and go through the world talking
like you are a a conduit of this social
and physical and emotional change that
we're all going through and you should
be very very very proud of what you do
and be very forward about what you do
i'm a public school teacher you know i
still have my credential in english in
california i could go back and teach at
any time i made a choice to openly be in
cannabis and i'm proud when former
students reach out to me they're always
stoked to see what i'm doing my parents
are proud of me it is you know it
doesn't make sense for someone with a
master's in teaching to be slinging me
at an international level maybe not on
paper but the change that i'm making in
my life and the amount of times that
i've been scared to move forward in this
space and the universe has shown me that
this is the right path and just we're
just here to show you that we've been
through a decade of absolute hell it's
like being in an abusive relationship
with someone you know that this industry
is only going to keep harming when you
show up every day loving it
unconditionally if we can do it you guys
can absolutely do it and we are totally
here for you every step of the way as
you guys roll this out all of our pain
all of our suffering that we've gone
through you're not gonna have to go
through it again if we have anything to
do with it
[Applause]
there's a ton of examples as to why
limited licensing is a failure and while
extensive licensing is a success anyone
who ever says the oklahoma industry
sucks that's just somebody who couldn't
compete and couldn't win and who
expected too much and wanted to keep
prices of cannabis too high but if i may
say one thing because we are in germany
and i am reminded that in 1945
the piece was made and they thought it
was a good idea to divide up you know
into four actually more than four
sections like five six seven but
famously four sections united states
france et cetera and it took until 1991
to unify and get that right
uh and let the people of germany come
together as one maybe they had to be
taught a lesson i don't know
but but we know that germany is a great
una united country uh now and think
about that 45 years so again if i can
leave you with one thing
i was listening to how the stakeholders
meetings were happening the
parliamentarians last the summer and
that work has happened already here
and uh one of the individuals was
telling me that there was not one
person
who was advocating for prohibition
that's great so we don't need to talk
about that anymore we need to talk about
let's kill limited
licensing
let's talk about that because it's about
the market structure and you do not want
to wait 45 years to get that right the
next time
yeah and i think that's really important
is you know we we've been talking about
talking um but the other really
important piece is listening and knowing
when to change your message because a
lot of the early success i had as i was
coming into these meetings where
medical cannabis advocates would be
expounding all the benefits of medical
cannabis to a city council
who doesn't really whether he believes
you or not it doesn't matter that's not
part of his job that's not something
that's going to get him somewhere once
you kind of show them hey look this is
what happened in all these cities in
california and these guys regulated
early and they've got no problems and
they're you know improving their
industry all the time and these guys
tried to fight it and got hit with 10
000 lawsuits and you know and then as
soon as they see something like that you
know that triggers somewhere so it's
like important it's important to know
your audience and the message and
speaking of which
are there any questions
in the audience hasn't gone over here
let's hear it from the panel yeah
[Applause]
lots more questions this year
uh i think this question is maybe
primarily for dimitri but maybe for the
whole panel um what do you think of
what's going on in new mexico uh your
your your neighbor which has seemingly
adopted the opposite of a limited
licensing framework you mentioned
oklahoma but just curious about new
mexico and other models what they've
done right and what they can do better
well you know
let me give you an example i think it's
great for simple questions great
anything that's better than anything
that was away from limited licensing and
more opportunity is better than not but
let me give you an example in arizona
what we have going on right now
we have brands that are migrating into
these intrastate models and right now we
have all these brands coming in from
oklahoma that have successfully competed
and worn against 300 other
gummy lines and the businessmen know
that these brands have shown some sort
of success with the consumers and
patients that is desirable so they are
uh more likely to take them in than a
brand from arizona who doesn't you know
just as competing against 25 other gummy
lines so anywhere there's better more
competition you're going to find a
better marketplace this is simple
economics it's just something that we've
adopted and it's been replicated over
and over again because people like what
are they doing colorado what are they
doing colorado what are they doing and
then they keep
up
so we need to stop this
domino effect at some point and
somebody's gonna get it right if i was
the german chancellor in charge of is
there a chancellor yeah if i was in
charge of germany i would say we want to
be the best we want competition we want
innovation we want to be known globally
as the best cannabis manufacturers so
cultivators i know it's northern europe
so a little different but at least
manufacturers product producers anywhere
we're going to create a free market and
we're going to teach the americans what
a free market is because you guys didn't
get it right over there in the united
states but we are going to get it right
so i like new mexico if you want to
can i just add to that one of the things
that i think new mexico did really well
while they were drafting their
legislation
is they
did a thorough scan of what not to do
and see they literally we had multiple
conversations with the legislative
members or drafting law
and they knew that we had a lot of data
around the industry and they just we
would set up these working sessions for
hours and they would ask us for data we
would dig it up we would find it we
would pull pieces of law that we thought
okay new jersey got this section right
we got this right in washington
they did they looked at everything and
then tried to do the best that they
could
um to start it out they also have since
legalizing have realized they made some
mistakes and they're already going back
to fix it next january so i think
they've gone in eyes wide open and we're
really open to hearing what worked and
hasn't worked across the united states
smart
and just the idea that
talk to the legislators let's go go call
them up they have staff people they're
good yes
they listen they really listen when you
toe up their offices they have meetings
about you cannabis people being loud is
the only reason you even know the word
california and bring them on a medical
cancer patient i mean you know i hate to
be cynical sounding but i mean every
time we did a lawsuit on behalf of
medical cannabis patients we put her and
we got someone in a wheelchair we put
people up right in front right in front
and made sure that the community and
that everybody saw what was going on
that this was about access for people
who needed to use cannabis for whatever
reason but we gave them some really
compelling reasons there's some nuances
that are really wrong as bridget was
saying with with new mexico but in
general heading in that direction is a
great idea
so it's not perfect
hi right up here
hey great conversation here in berlin so
great to be back
and it's very lucky to for the germans
to hear these insights because
it's all very similar to what they're
going to be going through so we didn't
have that when we started but i wanted
to talk about education because i think
a lot of the things that could be solved
because we did education much later
jamie knows uh we did a bunch of
education together
would it be nice if everyone just
consolidated education and i don't know
if anyone has any thoughts on is there a
way that we can just help educate work
together to make one bible of education
to share around the world which will
make all of our jobs easier uh any
thoughts on that
i'm gonna do a shameless plug right now
wmpolicy.com we've been gathering data
we have papers from different thought
leaders we have we have a bunch of
policy papers
um and you can also put in requests
where we are pulling as much as we can
from the industry making sure that we
have best practices there check it out
but this is something that has been a
labor of love for the last five years
and i think we have done a good job of
gathering a lot of the information of
lessons learned
[Music]
wmpolicy.com
weed match wm for weed masks
we're also seeing
you know actually when you talk about
education we're actually seeing some of
the community colleges and colleges and
law schools actually having curriculum
now and well where they really need
curriculum is in the medical schools
because you know they did surveys and
medical students aren't taught about the
endocannabinoid system so you know
there's there's a lot of work that needs
to be done but there's curriculum people
developing curriculum for actually you
know for higher education um they won't
they won't let us get into the
the grammar schools and the elementary
schools and the high schools but we can
go into the community colleges and law
schools and universities and and that i
think is you know again it's it's a long
process yeah and i think this is a it's
a piecemeal approach that alex is trying
to avoid because you know in canada you
know so i taught one of the first
courses um at a university level one on
dispensaries but then there was you know
multiple other ones that were written
and the laws were being changed at the
time and there was no no uniform
approach um and and you know we've seen
it particularly affect our pharmacies um
you know pharmacies were asked if they
wanted to be part of the medical program
before legalization and none of them
wanted to touch it and then after
recreational legalization all the
pharmacies wanted to jump on board and
started saying we're the only ones that
should be prescribing it but they still
didn't bother to teach anybody about the
endocannabinoid system and you know the
pharmacological colleges were still like
no you know doctors colleges that don't
want to hear it and they're still
anti-cannabis which is
mind-boggling but here we are in 2022
right here we are
just one one thing i would want to say
did anybody else know that you look
closely at those lights they're green
and red yes yeah i tried that too very
tricky that is awesome i thought i
thought i was like
one more time
[Applause]
you