[Music]
I'm delighted that people from many
different aspects working and cannabis
are here I spoke to people from many
different countries many of them grow
the cannabis others try to formulate it
make it into dress or make it into
edibles and I expect that all of them
will have to sit together in disgust so
there are many problems that have to be
solved in the future in such meetings
like this one will help understanding
and then cannabis will come into the
market with a much better background in
understanding of what's going on
hi I'm Sebastian from conception we are
a German tech startup and we claim to
pack the Sun so I can create sunsets I
can simulate daytime etc we've been to
quite a lot of trade fairs conferences
etc and I really think that was the best
speakers or the the topics that were
selected with very interesting and very
well organized so thank you guys hi my
name is Adan von interrupter I come from
Canada I'm really enjoying myself
talking to all the exhibitors of the
major companies international business
there's nothing like this in the world
there's everything you can imagine here
the first time in my life I can use all
my languages and use my cannabis skills
to be a part of something that is very
magnificent it's I feel like we are
creating history Rob comes from America
California great time here I've had a
lot of amazing people here in markets
awesome I'm so excited to help it grow
and create a worldwide market that
everybody is benefiting from the quality
ICBC is the best thanks to Alex and ICBC
and all of the sponsors and promoters
and all of the people that are here and
it's it's really been a great time even
the after parties were great
[Music]
this is where you need to be
danke shed