thank you very much and I want to thank
the National Council I also want to
thank
theki let me get this
[Music]
right
BL
today um but you know I came to Slovenia
20 uh 21 years ago um I fell in love
with Slovenia 21 years ago and then I
fell in love with a Slovenian girl and
so what how do you say uh mom stretch
stretch stretch
yeah and uh and now we live in Slovenia
after uh many years in in Oregon and we
came back here with our 12-year-old
daughter uh
anuka and uh we've been here almost 2
years now
uh and uh we're just having such a great
time here and it's a real real honor to
be here with you all and to live in your
wonderful country um so I'll get started
by uh
saying um I I'll start with some of my
successes um I'm in the Kansas industry
I've been in the legal Canabis industry
for about 15 years now I started what
people would call um non-plant touching
businesses in the Cannabis industry we
like to say there's plant- touching
businesses and there's nonplant touching
businesses and what that really means is
when you legalize cannabis and or
liberalize the laws or modernize policy
uh for whatever reasons be it human
rights be it compassion be it uh Common
Sense there is a a ripple effect in
terms of the industry and it's very
interesting I think a lot of people
don't understand all the benefits uh
economically uh for Canabis again
legalize under whatever opice is medical
recreational albe it so my so I'll I'll
start with just saying what my What I've
Done uh thus far and the first business
I started was 15 years ago it was a
medical marijuana clinic we call that a
nonplant touching business it's not
dispensary it was a clinic and I have a
a series a set of doctors who who I
hired to work for me and in the last 15
years we uh carded carded that's what we
call it it's not a prescription in
America now is it it's a recommendation
because it's not legal from the FDA so
we call it a recommendation we CED over
20,000 people and uh and so I not only
did did I create a business that made
money for me we were actually able to
change the dynamic of the community it
was a more prosperous community and it
was a safer Community because what we
did is we created safe access for
patients and we literally took cannabis
off the black market uh no small task in
a in a valley in southern Oregon which
was known for growing over a billion
dollars worth of elicit
cannabis that market got flipped over
and it all went into the the list market
so this is a very interesting time in my
life um I was able to revolutionize
medical marijuana in America um I'm the
first person to advertise on network TV
and uh make it mainstream if if you will
and that was also no small task because
uh I actually had to make this
commercial myself they wouldn't make it
for me I made the commercial and uh and
I made it extremely professional I took
the extra effort to make it professional
presented it to them and off we went
with this amazing uh business that was
actually helping the community at the
same time I was an activist 30 years ago
today I was on the corner of hate
ashberry in San Francisco I lived in
Berkeley and I commuted and I took the
Bay Bridge over to ha Ashbury where
Debbie goldsbury through a man named
Dennis Peron who's the Godfather of the
medical marijuana movement had a booth
on the corner and we sold stickers and
we had a jar for donations even though
we call them stations ha and we we uh
and and and we said legalize candidates
and we also had petitions and we were
there getting signatures for what would
then turn out to be proposition 215
which is the first medical marijuana law
in America from California which was
passed in
1996 so when I started into business I
thought I felt a little guil guilty I
thought man you know what this I'm not
an activist now I'm going to be a
businessman but my heart stayed the same
therefore when I acred for lack there of
a better term influence and Power in the
community I used it to the advantage of
the people to raise the tide because the
tide all boats Rise Up When The Tide
Rises up and I realized I'm more an
activist now ever as a business
businessman so I think I'll get to this
in a second so I think this is an
important thing uh for for Slovenia and
Europe in general to understand that
they business business and and and and
being successful at business it's not
mutually exclusive to somebody else uh
to someone else's detriment it can be a
win-win situation for for for everyone
uh my next business I did was the
international canabas business
conference which which is held in Berlin
every year and is the biggest business
B2B business event in the Eastern
hemisphere this is very this is another
nonplant touching uh business but this
is also another event that has helped
the community in fact some people have
come to me and said Alex without your
event which started in 217 Germany might
not have legalized as or being on the on
the trajectory as quickly as they are
right now I've had many people say that
to me and it warms my heart could I have
had an influence on Germany legal
Expediting their legalization well
that's a very nice nice thing while I'm
making money at my business conference
and helping the community at the same
time these are just two of my examples
of you know econom or you know business
possibilities that when cannabis becomes
legal under uh or policy becomes
modernized under whatever office is uh
because I think I because we're going to
get to what I think syia should do right
now now which seems very clear to me uh
that all these other ancillary
businesses are created and so for the
ICBC the biggest the international
canabas business conference the the uh
there's there's hundreds of different
ancillary businesses so you have
producers and processors and you have
Distributors and you have
wholesalers but you also have research
Labs you have insurance companies you
have lawyers who are representing other
companies you have tech companies
they're using applications uh for the
canab this industry I mean it runs the
gamut you guys would not even uh uh
believe all the different things that
are created when Canabis laws become
modernized in a respective
jurisdiction now what is slovenia's
Advantage this is really something that
I've been thinking about for years um I
knew I was going to move back to
Slovenia 5 six years ago the lockdowns
happening so that that delayed that a
little bit but my mind was already I've
already been living in Slovenia for 5
years probably in my mind you know
incessantly going to NE Ma and looking
at real estate on indala or sty in the P
or where or in luano of course you know
I was really I'm really infatuated with
Slovenia I do think it's the greatest
country in the galaxy and so now here I
am and I say well what can we do in
Slovenia here's what we can do look at
this room right here look how look at
the brain power in this room right now
this is amazing we we are we are
Slovenia we are the Revolution and it
really doesn't take much to make what
most people I think in this room want to
happen happen it's just a little tweak
because we have it already we have brain
power we have AC I'm so impressed with
slovenians how many languages got don't
you speak okay everybody speaks perfect
English I who's using their you know
nobody it's amazing you are a smart a
talented a responsible family oriented
country that's
clean thank
you
for for me I'm not because I live in a
lot of places I come from a big city in
America you know you know I've had
crackheads jump me in the middle of the
night okay it's like can be very
dangerous in America of course it can be
dangerous here also but no my
12-year-old girl daughter uh our daugh
she's now taking the bus public bus home
from school she's in new somewhere stop
Miss
leave it's great what an amazing feeling
so we're a special Nation we're a
special people and we could never forget
that so will we ever be the biggest
producers of cannabis in the world no
probably not will we ever be the biggest
producers of hemp in probably not we
just don't have enough land here right
but here's what we can be we can be the
leaders in research and development for
the world for canid an Innovative Tech
there's no question about it in my mind
and look at all the research in public
research institutions here today it's
happening we're coming together and yes
we should liberalize the laws and yes we
should have uh I think medical marijuana
is it's a easy decision we need to when
I hear Dr noow speaking and listen I was
actually crying when Dr noow was
speaking because you know there's how
would you not look at us what if your
kid was sick would you give it wouldn't
you do anything whether it was illegal
or not to alleviate your child's pain we
all would I think and we have in
situations I think a lot of our parents
when they get older our grandparents and
they die we know we we've helped them
with cannabis and some to alleviate
their symptoms to make their last days
better we know this this happens so
there are all these ancillary businesses
that will happen as as Slovenia
modernizes its Canada's policy but the
number one thing I my humble opinion
that I think we can do and Our poise to
do is again be the number one research
and development and Tech Hub in the
world for cannabis I thank you guys so
much again uh everybody it's an honor to
be in Slovenia and I know that I'm going
to do my part to do whatever we can to
keep Slovenia strong beautiful and
amazing and make it indeed the research
hub for cannabis in the world thank you
very much