wow what a day what a day
um you know had thought about
utilizing a lot of information up here
about being an investor in what we do
but you've heard a lot today and frankly
i learned a lot today because in
particular novel foods is a really
interesting topic that we're having to
discover what that really means here
uh throughout europe so anyways i wanted
to start by introducing myself my name
is matt nordgren founder ceo of arcadian
capital
um we're happy to be here because uh our
firm is moving into europe now we're
launching arcadian europe and borg we
couldn't be more excited about it our
investors really have encouraged us a
lot of support there
but the first thing i think we want to
do
um
talk about this industry this is an
industry where we create a safe space
for other people to thrive
no judgment wouldn't the world be a
perfect place actually if in fact we
didn't judge anybody for anything they
ever did
there might not need to be a room for an
apology even then because we're all
connected through a collective conscious
like this plant did you know back in the
time when the dinosaurs all were wiped
out from earth there was nothing left
everything survived through a fungal
network frankly through mycelium and
other plant matters and so if you really
think about it whether you believe in
god which i do or you believe in science
either way there's a collective
conscious so in this room no judgment
and this is a community that we're
excited to pour into frankly excited
about the companies here man downstairs
a lot of cool companies particularly and
here's our friend giada by the way you
guys should get to know her she's a hell
of a female leader in the space
there was one booth that was like a neon
i don't even know it was like a color
room or something felt like i was at a
spa
man you guys are doing it right over
here so many good people downstairs as
an investor we're not judging people
we're getting to know them creating a
safe space for people to thrive
one of our not even competing companies
i was talking with downstairs a little
bit ago
and you know there is no competition in
this space it hasn't institutionalized
yet we're all here to support each other
that's what we're here to do and i want
to start this conversation with that
type of energy
also thank you alex are you in here
you might be out running the conference
which is a good thing to do
but you've you've you've built this
community
i've spoken here before it's been a lot
of years been a lot of years for us to
do anything i guess wouldn't you say but
here we are
and the world's healing itself and we're
going to be a big part of that and thank
you all for pouring into it thank you
icbc for doing that as well
the first thing then i'm going to tell
you a little bit about arcadia and we're
going to play a video
and this is something we believe in
can everybody in here just do me a favor
i've been in this audience today been
walking around
let's just take our time close our eyes
if you can just humor me please
humor me with it
take three deep breaths this is
something to do in life no matter where
you are just to set your body bring the
blood in activate your parasynthetic
nervous system bring oxygen to the brain
just three of them
i've looked at this room it's a
beautiful room take one more
before you do your last one sex your
intentions what's your day about this
day is almost over there's one more to
go
thank you for that
okay i want to bring this community
together sorry i'm a bit of a roamer on
stage
arcadian what do we stand for
well we're an investment firm we have
about 55 companies today all throughout
the world in this industry and we serve
them
just like we're going to do here
arcadian is a firm that has operations
in america corporate out of los angeles
we also have arcadian latin america
pretty fired up about what's happening
in mexico these days are you guys
familiar that will be the largest market
in the world pretty soon it's actually
already legal if you ask congress but
supreme court but the congress and the
senators can't figure it out
so here we are with latin america and a
lot's gonna happen there and then we
have investments in china and the
largest operation in africa and
here we come to europe
okay so that's that's arcadian we're an
investor we like growth equity we want
to pour into you and build a company
and we've been doing that to a very high
level friend you know
look at that energy right there
thank you for that man
this room needs to be uplifted that's
what we're doing in the space coming out
of this sickness
is healing the world hope you don't mind
my energy but this is the way i choose
to live life
we work hard and we pour into people and
that's arcadian and to do a little
better job of that um randy
randy is going to play a video thank you
friend
[Music]
[Applause]
so
[Music]
[Applause]
is it working okay well that's a lot
better i think than having to have
somebody explain it
thank you so much randy i appreciate you
i know you said that was a large file
and probably the team got it to you an
hour ago so
um thank you for doing that and um
we wanted to do that because this isn't
about talking about us today you heard
from a lot of experts
but what we're going to tell you about
is what an investor is supposed to do
for an industry and as this one matures
what we're committed to doing here as
well
and so the reason i asked you to set
your intentions earlier is because do
you know why they call it a present the
present this moment mindfulness being
here
because it's a gift
[Music]
it's a gift it's the greatest present we
were ever given
whether you're a science person you have
two brains right one with which to think
critically and want to think creatively
and guess what you're designed to think
about both fifty percent quickly and
fifty percent creatively
there's balanced air your body it's
homeostasis that's why we're all in this
industry isn't it giada
we're here to bring
health and wellness to people
and so this is all about balance and we
wanted you to be balanced coming into
this to end your day we're gonna have a
little party after they say
um so hopefully uh you enjoy that and
some of our information
but now for some informative details
four things to pay attention to as an
investor right now that we are really
excited about
well the industry growth have you
watched the revenue in america i don't
know you do data better than me
uh but we have i think 25 billion
dollars in revenue this year and there
may be 30 in the world so you know this
is growing and through 2020 at a 60
revenue number is that right
in the year what's that
right and then the years before that
before coronavirus we were growing at a
23 to 30 in revenue number find me
another industry doing that with these
other things on top of that a similar
growth in taxes
give me much taxes we're paying places
that legalize this
a lot as you know
on top of that jobs
all these tech companies that are doing
great things not finding a tremendous
amount of real jobs there this is a
capital this is a consumer industry
built from a commodity so it's going to
require a lot of infrastructure and so
we're happy to report the jobs are
growing at a tremendous clip as well
on top of that
get ready for a bear market we're in the
longest bull market in history are we
not
cycles have to happen
there's no way to not have a cyclical
market it doesn't exist it's a test of
psychology and so it will happen
and so get ready for a place that is
going to be very excited for an industry
that is credit worthy when legal
think about all the infrastructure the
assets
this is an underwriter's dream in a bear
market we're getting calls already to
manage debt and credit because they
can't predict where they're going to
find yield
it's going to happen at some point and
this industry is only going to be more
interesting
assets credit worthiness banks are going
to need us more than they want
so these are four areas to really pay
attention to
that we're seeing be
very instrumental in bringing in the
institutional class
so really two groups we want to talk to
today and and frankly this is what at
arcadian we do really well
we serve our
investors resource providers so if
you're in this room and you are a
resource provider to this industry in
some way will you raise your hand
okay
well our friend nick of course
tremendous
to see you friend we've been doing this
for a long time haven't we
thank you for being a partner um anybody
else in here an investor well of course
chairman ceo of a public company too
and uh you bring a lot of resources to
this space anybody else
okay well of course bo and what a great
job bo did earlier we've worked together
at a number of places and encourage you
to spend some time with bo
if you are a resource provider to this
space
we'd love to hear from you
i are at arcadian cap or
arcadianfun.com and our commitment is to
serve you
it really is in this industry and if you
look at an emerging industry throughout
history
you need to be hedged
okay
there are a lot of amazing companies
here we've seen them all over the world
the interesting thing is
pre-institutionalization
you see a highly fragmented space
and so it needs to be put together if
you go back to the 90s and look at
google or facebook or apple or amazon
any of these companies that end up being
who they are today go look at the cap
table in the early days the a round the
b round the c round you're going to find
andreessen horowitz you're going to find
general catalyst you're going to find
benchmark
and so ultimately it's the investors job
to manage capital care about companies
invest throughout the whole supply chain
of an emerging industry and put it
together
see things from a macro level and so if
you're an investor here definitely pour
into these companies but i would
encourage you to reach out to the top
five or ten investors that have groups
doing this in the world and think about
that as an opportunity
but on the other hand our real job is to
provide return to those investors and so
if you're here and you run a company and
you're looking for resources raise your
hand
okay there's got to be more of you than
that so that means everyone else in here
is doing what
because you either have resources you
want to give to this industry or you
need them
and in either way it's okay
you come to arcadian and we're gonna
listen to you and figure out a way to
pour into your needs
but if you're an investor uh we have
several funds in several countries and
we would love to
offer those to you if you're an
accredited individual and believe in
this if you're a company well
um
that's what we're here to really do and
we do that through a multitude of funds
uh like nick
nick has called
his name actually is for multi uh
there's a whole bunch of what he does as
well but we're here to address each
opportunity individually
and so um
our investor team you can reach them at
investments at our
acadianfund.com which is not up here but
if you if you have a business and you
love our team to look through one of our
funds to partner with you
please call us please email us
investments.arcadianfun.com and the
reason we will never let anybody not be
heard i promise you that
never
and i encourage you to do the same thing
set those intentions when you come in do
this the right way we're building
something real special here if you're in
this industry to trade in and out of it
we're gonna find you
we found you before
and you're gonna be probably not too
happy with the result because this
industry is about community friends
i promise you and it won't be any
different here ultimately the winners
are going to do it together
we were just talking about that weren't
we
we have companies that are in the same
category that are trying to figure out
and they're public
and they want to work together
that's what this is about that's what we
expect our companies to do and please
reach out to us if in fact you'd like to
have our team a part of yours we would
love that
um
there are three main phases to this
industry and as this one develops here
think about these and that is
the fundamental aspect the core the
foundation and what we've seen in other
markets is that would involve
cultivation retail manufacturing
these are very sensitive in different
places and it has to be figured out for
there to be any industry and so we think
about that today in most places uh in
larger markets is credit and debt
here we're going to be providing equity
for that line of business so just some
more information about the capital we
provide and in this market it would be
equity if you're in the u.s or a larger
market it would be credit and debt from
our perspective those multiples on
valuations won't get any higher than
they did in 2017 and 18 probably you had
agriculture businesses trading at 100
revenue
i mean not just not the case even in an
industry growing 40 to 60 so
that has been corrected now and there's
opportunity for credit and debt there we
think in the u.s and equity here as this
one builds the second phase being
well the the b2b side uh this is the uh
picks and axes of the industry if you
will
if you're a gold industry uh analyst you
look at the value of gold the industry
that takes it from the ground to the
consumer and ultimately what the use is
for the consumer
and that's the third aspect which is b2c
so all these we see grow in a little bit
different ways
we're looking at all of them here and we
encourage you to reach out to us if
you're involved in any of those aspects
one of the biggest things i think that
we have to think about in this space is
the esg component
here here we are in a world where
all of these industries that are large
and scaled they're trying to figure out
how to reverse engineer how to think
about the earth how to think about
animal welfare how to empower women in
the workplace how to think about
minorities in the workplace
well the great thing about this space is
we get to do that from the beginning
and so as you build this space here and
as you come across other people in it
encourage people to think this way
it's an important topic for us at
arcadian we ask all of our companies
these questions in order to verify
certain operational procedures that they
have
and so please do
think about that aspect as you build
this industry and if you come to us
we're going to ask you about it and try
to track it it's hard to do but we're
going to try to track all of those
characteristics because we believe that
if a market's about psychology
then what you're noticing is the 70 year
old community in the 60 year old
community and 50 as these decades
continue to grow the thinking behind the
younger generation is not just financial
there's other things that motivate it
and so watch these markets change
throughout the rest of your lifetime
there's a third component it's not just
is it cheaper
is it better
the markets now the people that make
decisions with that capital that are
continuing to grow up and take over
their father or grandfather's
capital they're asking themselves is
this better for the world is this better
for me watch the markets watch the
psychology behind it that's why you
should be encouraged what you're doing
right now will continue to matter
the thinkers behind the people that
provide all those resources think
differently
at the end of the day
we don't want to take a lot of your time
the way we think here
is that this is about
moving forward and either fear or faith
that's the future
you realize everything that ever
happened in your life before this moment
only lives in your head
that's a fact
everything that hadn't happened yet also
lives in your head
in the form of faith or fear really
and so why not choose hope
in what you're doing
it's working
and so
in some sense you think about this as
it's not what the world does to us
it's about what we do to the world
as individuals
and so if you don't believe me just
think about how data flows right
through the pure medial cell into the
brain
the only way in and out and then
ultimately there's a chandelier cell
it's there to repeat look at repeated
negative data patterns and in the event
that it does it starts to close down
your neural pathway to enter the brain
and then ultimately once it gets through
and hopefully you're balanced and
mindful in which case your chandelier
cell will open and you'll have a little
bit more flow into the brain it then
goes to what a 80 to 100 billion neurons
to be processed
that could be connected with 10 000
other neurons creating a neural network
that's absolutely insane and so this is
why it matters to be in the moment
because it's the only place you can make
a choice
here we are in this moment we wanted to
just use this time to try to
get people excited
you've heard a lot of information today
be here
all of the answers you wish to find in
life are in fact in the moment
they're right in front of you
if you're gonna play pay close enough
attention to them
and the reason for that is because
that's where data is processed
if you sit with the past and future too
much
you can't take in data from the moment
everything in the past and future is in
your head again
and so we just asked that
you pay attention to the moment you're
in
pay attention to the people around you
pay attention to arcadian
we've done a great job
at investing in companies and managing
capital for other people and so if any
of this aligns with you
let us know
we hope it does and frankly
we feel blessed to be here
and that's our choice to feel that way
thanks for having us um
appreciate you on the video too
do you have time for a few questions
matt nordgren
are there any questions
all right let's all go home then
uh let's hear one more time for matt
norgren from arcadian financial capital