so hi everyone hi everyone so I'd like
to thank Alex in the ICB icbc foot for
this award I don't think of it as a
Lifetime Achievement Award more as a
tenacious miss of work and this it could
be an inspiration to everyone here if
you just last long enough eventually
they'll call you an elder states person
so that hasn't happened to me yet but I
think that it will at some point maybe
so anyway I worked long and hard on this
because I didn't want to do a Donald
Trump you know I actually have a speech
it's an hour and a half I hope you don't
mind did it it's my entire views of the
entire world and the situation and it is
dire but actually more of my philosophy
is one of a great 20th century baseball
player satchel paige and he's not
recognized a lot because spent most of
his time in the black leagues but he did
say somebody said he could turn off the
light and get under the covers before
before the light went out and he did say
don't look back they might be gaining on
you and you know you start looking back
to get scary about some of the things
that you did in the past and I'd never
do those things now so close Castaneda
who was a writer about spirituality had
a character in his books by the name of
Don Juan and Don Juan was this Indian
Shaymin from the southwest and he had
all the psychedelics in these different
different psycho phytochemicals and he
said
and his his said that his he had this
Ally plant that he would smoke and then
after I read that book eventually I
smoke marijuana not to eventually but i
did and i realized that i don't know if
that was exactly his ally but i realized
that marijuana was my ally and i
realized later on something that you
know the difference between marijuana
and politicians is that good marijuana
never told a lie so and i think that the
reason why i like marijuana so much was
described by aldous huxley when he
talked about psychedelics and he said
that you know we develop the brain the
mind in our brain as a filter and it
filters out we learned what to filter
out and how to filter it out depending
on what society were in and so we have
sort of boxed in and he said that
psychedelics alter the brain's ability
to be a filter so all these thoughts
that would be boxed in and wouldn't come
into consciousness because they didn't
fit the mold start shooting out and
that's certainly what marijuana does to
me and I'm sure to most people here and
i'll just give you one example of it you
know that obama when he first became
president had marijuana deficiency
syndrome which people used to laugh at
when I said that and then when when
physician started saying if they took it
more seriously for some reason but
anyway with marijuana deficiency
syndrome he was not able to make wise
decisions in the beginning and that's
why he was taken over the coals by the
banking industry and if he had only been
able to smoke marijuana and look at
things from both the straight with a
straight mind and all would somewhat
altered mind that what would allow him
to be creative we wouldn't have gone
through the
wrenching thing that that we did and a
lot of the people who were wearing
pinstripes would be wearing horizontals
now so if marijuana teaches you to think
outside the box then thank you somebody
said they agree so I consider that a
vast majority so if somebody they think
so if you start thinking outside the box
then you're going to change so you could
say marijuana is an agent a catalyst of
change and and we need a lot of change
you know recently I've been annoying
people who work with me at quick trading
with some songs from the 60s and i'm not
i'm neither going to sing them to apply
them for you but one of them was the
mothers of inventions called song called
trouble coming every day and if you look
at that on youtube and with certain some
of the videos as long as 50 years old
but it could be taking place it could
have been taking place this summer you
know on the streets except that most of
the videos show people rioting and in
this case it's cops rioting really and
then a second was is Donovan season of
the witch I should say the second is
really for the fugs kill for peace and
in that song from fifty years ago they
say if you don't kill them the Russians
will if you don't want America to play
second fiddle kill for peace and isn't
that what it's going on right now 50
years later different countries same war
and then the third was and this is more
applicable directly to what we're doing
now and why people are here it's
Donovan's season of the witch and in
that he has one line
beatniks out to make it rich well
hippies whatever right come on recognize
yourselves so the reason why I got into
marijuana is because I hate war and
marijuana is an agent of change and we
have not only Americans but the whole
world has to change and we have to get
out of war and anti the war on ourselves
in the war on environment and those two
things are really important and the only
way to do it is to change consciousness
laws don't do it regulations don't do it
it's a change of consciousness and
marijuana helps you get out of that box
so you can actually see reality and
that's why I'm in marijuana now you know
I wrote this marijuana users Bill of
Rights which you can just go on google
and google that in and it will come
right up and one of those is that and
ultimately that the questions or the
though that Bill of Rights brings to
mind some something and that is if it's
a question of freedom or profit what do
you choose now i would say moat many of
the people who are now in marijuana have
chosen prophet they don't really care
about freedom you know freedom is um in
let's close the door and I don't I don't
really think that that's a really good
policy for society I think it's a stupid
policy and I think it's a policy that
ultimately brings illegality and illicit
activities because if you can't get in
the door you're still
going to do it so how are you going to
do it you're going to do it outside the
door and I hate the term organized
organized crime as I understand it and
as I've seen it marijuana outside of the
system is disorganized crime totally
disorganized so if they want to talk
about organized crime and heroin or
something or oxycontin with the cartels
that are making all these opioids fine
but leave marijuana out of it I'm please
please when people say well we're
protecting society from organized crime
and all that that's they're
protecting society from people like us
ultimately come on so what I think is
that you know profits really great but
i'd rather have freedom if it's a choice
of profit or freedom I'll take freedom
every time every time and you know only
the people who really believe that who
are willing to fight for that they're
the only people who have freedom you
know I used to belong to the yuppies
youth in youth international party and
we had a saying when freedom is outlawed
only outlaws will be free and that you
know there are different like people are
saying well prop 64 it legalizes
marijuana yeah if you have under an
ounce if you've one of the chosen few
who gets it who gets a license that then
it then marijuana is legal but if you
have over an ounce if you want to grow
more than if you want to grow plants in
a county that doesn't allow plant
growing if you have if you want to sell
to your friend if you don't if you're
not within the system then marijuana
isn't legal that's why prompt 64 is a
farce and as much as people who keep
saying that prop 64 has to pass or else
marijuana will be set back
no no no we're not going to we should
not sacrifice the people of California
for other people's ambition 64 is just
when you read it when you actually read
it it's total you could be
totally legal in one County step over
the line you're illegal at
fractionalized it's California it's a
terrible law and the worst part of it is
it keeps the cops n who wants cops n
anybody nobody here wants cops in their
system they'd rather have civil
regulation well you better start telling
the people on Prop who are voting who
are campaigning for prop 64 what you
think of it because if you want cops in
your system and taking your money you
know one thing that Assad knows don't
feed your enemies that's why he's had
that siege at Aleppo all this time I'm
not saying I'm pro pro him but but prop
64 and the Oregon initiative both of
them feed the cops can you believe that
you're feeding your enemies I don't
understand it I don't get it that I
don't think that's legal action so I
wasn't going to I promise not to talk
about 64 month or so so you know I think
that marijuana is an agent of change and
I think that we really need this agent
of change because you know we're at war
with the world I don't only mean the
United States I mean people are at war
with the world there were war with their
mother they drill it they pierce it they
tear it up they break its skin they put
they fill it with concrete they make it
poisonous they toxify it how can we live
that is it so eat on musk and a couple
of others are going to go try and find
another planet but I don't you know
there's a difference between columbus
coming to america and us going to
interspace and the difference is he had
air to breathe and when he got here when
he got to the new world there was food
to eat big difference and you know and
there was intercourse back and forth but
between between the contents but we when
you go out into space it's a one-way
journey and you better take everything
with you oh we forgot a piano did
anybody take the Dylan tapes so actually
as bad as 64 is the one thing that it
will do is get more marijuana to people
and that's the most important thing and
the reason for that is it just what I
was saying is that marijuana is an agent
of change and being an agent of change I
think that these laws or any laws that
stopped the free market in marijuana and
what I don't mean a regulated market I
don't mean that you know anybody should
be able to sell any quality marijuana
just like they can food no I'm talking
about a regulated market that protects a
consumer but but anyssa body should be
able to get into it and anybody should
be able to get out of it and anybody
should be able to buy and anybody should
be able to sell as long as they have a
license in the zoning and everything
else in the state shouldn't be able to
say I like you but I don't like you
shouldn't be able to do that it
shouldn't be able to say oh we have
enough licenses so you let all the
stores that want to open open and you
know that most of them are going to
close right and people think Oh people's
people are going to have their life
dreams dashed of owning a store but
that's life but it's not the state doing
it it's a market doing it and when the
market does it it's okay for that to
happen for the market to say I like this
door I don't like that store but it's
not okay for the state to do that to
people because we're all equal we should
all have equal opportunity and it
shouldn't be who got here first we're
not taking any more applications that's
its demanding just talking
and and you know what here's the other
thing that I have to say about that is
that you know you could be a farmer
nobody says you have to make a profit
and what I mean by that is farming is
farming and it's a very risky business
and there's you know environmental
things there's all kinds of problems and
you know of course when you have a great
crop the price goes down because
everybody else has so nobody says
farmers have to make a profit but
everybody should be allowed to try to
make a profit in and if they want to
farm everybody should be allowed to farm
as long as they're on proper farming
land or in proper area anybody disagree
with that you know brendan kennedy said
the same thing it's it's I think that
there's rude anybody who's read
marijuana growers handbook and I'm sure
everybody here has if you know if you
haven't you should immediately go out
and pick up a copy and read it and in it
there's a there's a page about the
tomato model you know with tomatoes
there are large tomato growers there are
small tomato growers there they're
international companies national
companies regional companies local farms
and neighbor to neighbor sales and
everybody's doing okay with tomatoes and
I think it could be like that here I'm
not opposed to giant corporations I just
think that we should allow all
corporations and all people to do
whatever they want in marijuana as long
as it they're following the rules and
doing it legally and the rules should
allow them to do it anybody disagree
with that well that's what we have to
fight for and that's what we're not
getting and none of the laws do this and
all these state legislators who are so
in favor of capitalism except when it
comes to to to marijuana for instance in
in California but note profit-making
dispensaries are allowed no
profit-making dispensaries but it's such
a capitalist state could you imagine if
they had said okay no you know computers
are so important to society that we
shouldn't allow any of these companies
to make a
profit just think how far advanced much
further advanced we would have been with
computers now like we would have been up
to 128 not billion but millions no or
whatever it's how so okay so so I think
that marijuana has to become totally
civil and we have to get the cops out of
it and we have to get the legislators
out of it to the extent that they allow
a free market but on the other hand we
also have to make sure that that people
have the ability and the right to use
marijuana as a light so that we can
change society and become a more loving
group of people thank you Thanks a given
ed rosenthal in the house in the house
thank you and for all your service
brother we appreciate you man what