join us for the next international
cannabis business conference in san
francisco california at the hyatt
regency february 15th and 16th
it's a conference we're having here at
the oregon convention center it's the
international cannabis business
conference and alex rogers is putting
this on and just been remarkable a great
set a diverse set of vendors and a
fabulous set of speakers there's been a
great crowd uh great vendors great
attendees the feedback has been
extraordinary i've had so many people
tell me that this is the best conference
they've ever been to and i'm here to
learn how to tell the future
and i think
i'm getting a lot of great information
the people here are great
and it's not much stress
and they have free coffee
and someone's walking around with
sandwiches the beauty of icbc is meeting
all the activists lawyers
gardeners and people on the forefront of
providing medicine and good product to
people and patients very knowledgeable
people people from all over the world
it's been a great experience
i've heard some amazing things already
there's a
congressman here who was speaking about
where the industry is headed where the
laws are headed
federally which is is very important if
you're going to be investing in the
cannabis business
my name is ed rosenthal
and
it was a pleasure for me to come to this
conference
it addressed the needs
of the local people
of oregon
amazing the speeches have been
incredible i've met a lot of people that
have been great just making contacts
with different dispensaries and grow
grow houses and kind of perform
partnerships
we're here at this conference to
talk to testing laboratories and
producers and processors about
laboratory accreditation and what it can
do for them and what we're about is
about promoting organics
in the cannabis industry
don't magazine
stands for something
defending our patients everywhere
the magazine allows us to actually put
input
and relevant articles
out into the public
oh it's great this is
our direct target market really anybody
who's trying to get into the cannabis
industry trying to start a business
trying to make sure that they're doing
things right doing things legitimately
that's what we're here to do just to
help the industry and make sure
everything's done done the right way
give alex
mr rogers full
credit because
this is a really good event i like it a
lot we have got many good contacts
and i hope we will meet again they got a
stack of business cards here meeting a
whole lot of new folks that are just
getting into the business but also a few
of the business people and a lot of the
activists that i've been working with
here in oregon for the past 10 years so
it's a combination of family reunion and
kind of a speed dating session
and that is just some of the things at
the international cannabis business
conference we're going to keep this
thing rolling join us for the next
international cannabis business
conference in san francisco california
at the hyatt regency february 15th and
16th