hi icbc this is awesome right second day
third day for some of us um we're going
to be discussing for the next hour
uh cannabis and emerging markets which
is actually a really really fascinating
topic um because at least we were
discussing in the green room there is
really no such thing as a cannabis
market that really is not an emerging
market but i think that we have some
really interesting uh panelists today
who are going to give us a perspective
of what it means to be an emerging
market some of the issues that are going
on um and how to to work successfully in
your emerging market as well as
inter-emerging market so i think we we
have everybody's name is up here but we
have really really wonderful people to
discuss what's going on in the uk and
ireland in greece in zimbabwe and new
zealand plus of course we'd like to get
your questions as we go forward because
we'd like this to be an interesting
conversation so my first question to all
of you and you can
depending on you don't have to answer
this but i think it'd be really great
what is your definition of an emerging
cannabis market
any one of you jump in
okay great uh why not uh morning
everybody um
so i suppose in in in the sense of an
emerging market i would say um it would
be to a point post legalization where
there is actually implementation of a
of a of
a supply chain and access to patients or
patient access to certainly
qualified medicine on scale i think you
know
canada has it
uh certain states in the u.s has it
nowhere really outside of those
those locations actually have
so you can classify every other region
as an emerging market
for the for for the sake of this
conversation for the sake of this panel
to give it some context i think what we
are seeing in europe what we're seeing
in latin what we're seeing in uh in
in asia and in australia is really the
kind of the development in unison of new
access programs for patients all around
the world and because there isn't a
blueprint or certainly the blueprint of
what went on in north america isn't
exactly the one to follow when it comes
to these emerging markets you're seeing
new models being implemented across
across the globe and that's really
really exciting to try and
to try and cover and analyze but for
companies wanting to operate and
certainly scale their business is
exceptionally complex
well you're you're in in ireland and the
uk right that's one kind of emerging
market maybe constance you can talk
about greece because i'd like to talk a
little bit more about an emerging market
clearly in europe
what do you see is your definition is it
export focused is it a cultivation
infrastructure is it having a cannabis
agency what are the kinds of things that
are i mean your idea is is a definition
of an emerging cannabis market from
greece sure thank you margaret uh well
i think that the cannabis industry as a
whole is an emerging industry so even if
we talk about north america canada
there's still room to grow
in terms of people that have access to
the products
in terms of
cultivation manufacturing
and more importantly what i see the
biggest
bottleneck of the industry is the
legislation so there's room to grow on
every vertical
in particular greece i mean it was one
of the first european countries actually
that started to form some kind of
regulation to allow for
to allow for the industry to grow
and
most of the politicians saw it from you
know as an economic opportunity
and unfortunately that left patients
behind quite a bit and
20 2018 is when legislation started
big ambiguities and legislation in terms
of what could be
produced in the country
basically there was a very big
bottleneck that allowed only for
finished products so you could only make
side effects or dialects
and as you can understand that was
really not something marketable so a lot
of licenses started to go out i think in
the first year there was about 100
licenses we're about a little less than
200 right now three years later
and
it's really interesting because in
greece up until a few months ago
the um
we have both the ruling government party
as well as the opposition supporting
cannabis so greece did an amendment in
legislation a few months ago
and kind of tried to clarify as to what
can be produced under what conditions
and eventually
you know what how products will be able
to get registered in order to allow for
exports and primarily flower
well
you know
it's still not final so there's still
it's still an emerging market in what
sense right now legislation allows for
the cultivation of flower
and it's export as long as you're
manufacturing a second product that's at
least registered in the country you're
mentioning you're bringing up a very
very interesting discussion and i think
one of the the key aspects of emerging
markets is maybe
products are designed either for export
or you're importing them um i'd like to
kind of go down to boniface because
you're coming from africa right which is
a very cool emerging market not only
bringing stuff to europe but inter
africa maybe you can talk about some of
the challenges and and what it means to
be an emerging market from zimbabwe
indeed um i'm boniface i'm from zimbabwe
um
i can't see without these so i'm not
that weird i was trying to hide his eyes
and then
in zimbabwe we just exported our first
crop last month
we have more than 55 licenses and out of
those 55
less than six
producing
the challenge that we have right now is
from a regulatory standpoint
what we have is
we have a
cannabis industry that is still in the
fledgling stages
what i mean by that is
there is confusion in regulation the
regulation is not clear
so bringing in products and taking
products out is still a little bit of a
challenge i'll give you an example in
south africa
there's a
canadian company
that just
went through the process of cultivating
a lot of crop that they were not able to
export
so
some of the challenges that we're facing
they come from
guys like yourselves who are well
intentioned and then you come to africa
then you want to be a cowboy you don't
want to play with me you want to do your
own thing
it makes business difficult
in in terms of
just getting what you want work with the
locals and you get what you want
and
uh secondly in terms of uh
how we're working there's a
i think an issue with regards to the
work that it takes to get uh the
cannabis to be exported or to be
imported
i mentioned to my friends here that
everyone likes to eat sausage but no one
likes to make sausage it's a very nasty
process
so
you come to africa i'll do the nasty
business for you
we will do the nasty business for you
together we'll get something done i'm
here to talk about zimbabwe i'm here to
talk about the opportunities that exist
in zimbabwe we have great factor
endowments you can come
we have land we have sunshine
we have a lot more
to offer than what you traditionally get
down here bring your expertise to
zimbabwe and you make way more money
than doing a business here
paul this is this is my next question so
with that advertisement for zimbabwe um
how would you say the emerging market in
new zealand is developing in terms of
both the creation of a domestic market
and of course exports which are now
starting to come to europe
thank you margaret uh yeah so even
though new zealand might not really seem
like a an
emerging market from the outside because
they have really modern regulations in
place already have the cannabis agency
that is also cooperating with the german
cannabis agency and
it is really that they came up with this
medicinal cannabis scheme just in april
last year and the goal of that was to
really supply the market with some
domestic high quality product because
all that was available until then
was just really
like prices were really high and
everything needed to be imported so what
they tried is they
awarded around 40 licenses so around 30
for
cultivation and 10 for distribution and
manufacturing and now
with this emerging process and still the
new zealand government realizing that
maybe some of the restrictions they put
in place because they wanted to go
really really strict so they looked at
the german market which is obviously for
most international companies the most
relevant market they they took germany
as an example and added some more
challenges to it i would say so that
means they added some extra testing so
for example to be registered in new
zealand as
a medicinal cannabis product you have to
comply with or
they will test your product for six to
nine pesticides and have some additional
micro microbial testing applied to it so
this is really really hard and they
realized that some of the other
bureaucracy around it maybe they went a
bit too far so now they're that they're
going back a bit as well on that so it's
still emerging so and this is like in
other places around the world this is
why it takes a bit longer for the new
zealand companies to actually have their
first harvest and comply with all these
regulations well this is really
interesting let's let's get to that
point right so i think several of you
here are from company countries that are
really thinking about exporting right
obviously the uk and stephen is in the
uk and ireland that's more i don't want
to diss the weather but that's more of
an import market how what would be your
recommendations to people out there
about
you know minding the gaps so if you're
an emerging market and you want to
export to germany or you want to export
to another country how would you
recommend that that process begins to
start especially
you know from a company perspective
especially as regulations are also
evolving
to your point because it's just about
everywhere
yeah well like i think 99 of countries
and locations should be import
you know i think we as a as an industry
are so caught up in
the site of cultivation we forget about
the rest of the supply chain
and countries ultimately forget about
the rest of supply chain so great wave
product but how do we actually get it
implemented into the hands of patient
and once the process behind
reimbursement and so forth and
there is so much talk of cultivation
cultivation and product and yes
obviously it is exceptionally important
but there's one or two facilities in
europe alone that can cater for the rest
of the demand that europe will need for
the next five years and you know nobody
talks about that elephant in the room in
terms of how much cultivation actually
happens we only need to look at canada
there was a great article um two weeks
ago by matt lammers from mj biz who
talked about 80 of of cannabis being
produced that has been destroyed too
early down to uh pure uh purely down to
kind of ignorance when it comes to
mapping the forecasted demand and also
the understanding in terms of who the
customers were and what they wanted
so
you know the the focus of import and
export and the rush to cultivation
i think is is is is overvalued and
certainly uh over forced by the hands of
the investors who want to see
significant capital returns because that
is ultimately where you know you are
seeing the the large multiples
traditionally come from um but you know
i i do think that there is sufficient
supply
in you know in production or in
production cycle to cater for
cater for demand in europe for the next
10 years easily
so you know there is there is there is
obviously um
a benefit of having domestic supply and
not being reliable reliable on you know
reliable on on on anybody else but you
know this is just another this is just
another supply chain just another
product at the end of the day so why
should it be different to anything else
that that exists and there's no other
industry that takes this i suppose
domestic first approach where everything
needs to be integrated in the country
uh to in order to in order to you know
achieve growth
so
the uk is the uk well the uk is
is is import and export but it's export
for for for a very
specific circumstance and it's only
starting to emerge in terms of
providing domestic cultivation
and licenses and you know there is huge
risk associated with cultivation and
whereas what the uk has probably
benefited more from is looking at
innovation around the plant so the
science around the plant but also the
the supply chain so everything from
delivery services to
clinics to doctor education and they
have kind of built these elements out
that has benefited the patient now
there's obviously still issues around
pricing and still issues around um
around consistency and supply but that
is i
that is probably common
and common in every emerging industry in
every emerging market so these are these
are kind of growing pains that exist in
the uk i don't think
it's it's as a result of not having
domestic cultivation i think it's just
as a result of you know capital being
exceptionally tight in any emerging
industry well i i'd like i think the uk
at least in my opinion i think the uk is
a little bit of different than say
greece or new zealand or zimbabwe i'd
like to come back to costas for a second
i mean i think one of the issues in
greece is obviously there's a clear
focus on the export market but there has
also been i think going forward a real
focus on trying to also make sure that
greek patients can get
you know cannabis themselves maybe you
can talk a little bit about that yeah i
think that there's quite a few more
european countries that
don't allow patient access it's not only
greece
but what was your question i think i
think what from your perspective what
are some of the challenges that
companies face in greece obviously they
want to make money they want to satisfy
their investors and they want to export
but a lot of people that i'm talking to
definitely also want to help patients
and develop the local markets how would
you how would you suggest that you know
well i would say what is your opinion on
how that is proceeding in greece what
are the challenges and how do you think
that the industry itself can rise to
that i think most people want to make
sure that patients everywhere get stuff
not just if you're exporting to
another country well it is uh
you know cannabis has always been
political so i think that uh the biggest
issue for
the european union you know in its
respective countries it's country
members uh
you know the political risk of
applying
some form of you know cannabis
legalization
and allowing the you know intro-european
trade
it carries a lot of risk
and a lot of the political parties are
very uh afraid of house that is going to
interpret to their uh
the voters however i think that we're
getting more and more evidence of um you
know with what's happening in the united
states what's up you know what happened
in canada uh mexico that
there's a lot more pressure now that
this is a real industry and more
importantly it's an entry that affects
you know sick people
to one extent but at the same time you
know it's about a well-being of the
citizens so
i think that what we're going to start
to see in the very near future is as
people you know as the industry becomes
more legitimate and legitimate mean
meaning you know there's actually uh
because the first couple of years year
and a half there was a lot of wishful
thinking a lot of licenses and you know
it's going to be a you know half a
billion and you know trillion gazillion
million dollar market
you know it's still yet to come to that
so
another big challenge that i see is that
people did not really understand how
much time it takes from the time that
you you know you you get your license or
even before that till the time you're
able to have product to market so
there's been companies that two years
ago three years ago started to
you know to incorporate and apply for
the licenses and we're going to start to
see the fruits of those
you know
those tries
now three years later so we have a
specific market now that is growing at a
certain pace
and yes you know i will agree with steve
that more product is going to be coming
into market so now we're going to start
to see a competition in you know in the
product it's not about just having eugmp
flower it's going to be okay
patients and you know the the the people
in germany are going to have a selection
so we're gonna start to see product
differentiation we're gonna start to see
um certain products to be preferred over
others
and at the same time as more product is
coming to the market it's gonna be a you
know a price war so
those companies that are able to uh to
cultivate at lower cost we're going to
have a greater profit a greater margin
to reduce their prices so
we're starting to see a shift in the um
the criteria that people are you know
selecting their products now at the same
time when it comes down to greece
there's probably going to be not you
know most likely we're going to see at
least one company rolling out product
within 2022 i should say
companies
local partners with israeli expertise
and
everybody's paying close attention to
them to see how they're going to be able
to navigate the local uh you know
regulatory authorities in terms of
registering their parties and exporting
it to germany and other jurisdictions so
i think as far as greece goes within the
next six to eight months we're going to
come to see exactly how the system will
work right now we're there's a lot of
ambiguity
and there's people that still see a lot
of challenges but that's going to clear
up within the next few months
that's okay so i'm going to actually
skip down to the end here with with with
paul and and boniface because i think
that the certainly greece most people
are looking at european export but
within africa there's like an africa to
africa trade and then yeah i think also
paulieth can talk about maybe not just
coming to europe but maybe looking at
other markets like israel
right
within africa we have not
developed a domestic market i could tell
you for example in south africa
you can cultivate but you cannot extract
so you cultivate
you send it out then you import your
stuff back in
how ridiculous is that that's very very
ridiculous such inconsistency in
regulation
is what keeps investors away
but in zimbabwe
we understand the power of political
will
so cannabis is right at the president's
desk
the president
himself is in charge of cannabis
i'll give you something here
we've got a five-year tax holiday for
anyone who will come and farm cannabis
day
five years you don't pay tax
you want to bring your money back to
germany you want to bring it back to
america you can
expatuate all your profits
bring them back
um i'm sure by now you can tell that i'm
fighting for zimbabwe
uh unashamedly because you guys are all
here for your own agenda my agenda is
cannabis and zimbabwe and
i i would like you to know that we are
open for business for cannabis we want
zimbabwe to be like how brazil is for
sugarcane
we want that silicon valley type of
recognition for cannabis in zimbabwe we
want to raise the floor
for our standard of living we come here
to europe you guys live so well you have
electricity your trains run on time
guess what cannabis has got the
potential to unleash a good sustainable
industry for my people so that our floor
is a little bit higher
we don't want to be in the bush
but
i'm sorry to interrupt the commercial
here but i mean are you looking at are
you for example are people in zimbabwe
more looking at an inter african trade
or are they looking more at europe or
well first first and foremost we're
going to look to export everything we
make in africa
in agriculture especially is for export
purposes
you have made it such that we rely on
your foreign currency so we cannot live
if we don't sell you this cannabis we
want to sell it to you first
and then after that
maybe we can educate our people
on how to use this lovely plant because
we were using it for thousands of years
until uh some propaganda came
and we stopped so
so so clearly though i mean there is
already african cannabis going to israel
so maybe paul you can talk a little bit
are you from the new zealand perspective
how do you see your emerging market
developing with sort of a diverse
uh export ideal not just coming to
europe but also going to other markets
like israel
of course those regulations that were
passed last year they aimed at the new
zealand market just um
decreasing the dependency on those
exports as steven said i mean and this
is the this is the main goal that new
zealand currently had since they were so
dependent and they had those super high
regulations which of course are now
helpful if you're looking to export
because new zealand has already some of
the highest regulations in the world
which will allow us to export but of
course this came into place to decrease
dependency and
given all given the number of companies
in new zealand and the really i mean if
you know new zealand it's a very it's a
beautiful country but of course it is a
very small market and we're not just
talking about cannabis market we're
talking in general for any product that
a new zealand company makes a lot of new
zealand companies are looking to export
like
they're basically basically important
global no matter what they do those
really high standards allow the new
zealand companies to then export to
germany so this is currently i would say
the highest priority for new zealand
companies but of course there are
they're also looking to to australia and
of course israel would also be in those
top three markets to to look at foreign
companies well i think i think what
everybody is is kind of getting a sense
of if they didn't have already is you
know going country to country with
cannabis is a bit of a risky proposition
to begin with so i'm going to throw this
out to all of you what would you say are
some of the best
risk mitigation techniques um that
companies can start to think about it
could be hiring local it could be
looking at say reaching an eu gmt
standard what are the kinds of things
that you're seeing in your own markets
that are helping cultivators and
producers meet the challenge of
basically being a developing market and
then exporting to another developing
market
um oh i'll take a step
i i think that the days of
the investment decks where companies
have flags planted all around the world
uh are kind of outnumbered thankfully
and that's really as a result of the
realization of just how difficult uh
executing international growth and
international business development can
be um one of um you know we have worked
in probably around 40 odd countries
over the last of the last five years and
really on when we work with clients one
of the key things is on local
partnership and that is you know local
expertise who understand not only the
legal system and have legal partners but
also you know can develop the
commercial interests
when you know when um
you or they are not there to take care
of us and that could be everybody from
you know in for instance in germany it
could be anybody from a distribution
partner all the way through to um
medical and science and it's it's it's
that type of
um it's that type of partnership that is
critical for any business that wants to
flourish trying to come in and employ a
brand manager or a country manager and
have them execute
organically is exceptionally difficult
exceptionally exceptionally difficult um
because i suppose what you're missing
out on is is the years of experience and
in such an early at such an early stage
of the industry
there is it is a race you know it is a
land grab
to to to acquire market share or
certainly first to market in a certain
in a certain sense and
kind of market ownership and that is you
know from patient access that is from
owning areas of the supply chain because
if you can own them and lock them down
it is very hard to disrupt them in a in
this period of time so having local
partners i think has been exceptionally
helpful for
you see some of the companies and
certainly some of the clever companies
who've made quite strong strategic
acquisitions now i think there is
you know there is a little froth in the
market but nowhere near what you see in
in north america now
i think we you know the last icbc was
here in berlin in 2019 and there is
there's probably a kind of a
a cap on company valuation european
company valuations probably in the let's
say 30 to 40 million was probably where
the the top european company was now
fast forward around a year and a half
and you're around 200 250.
it's a that's a
phenomenal growth for for for for strong
european assets but it's pennies on the
dollar when you realize just how big
this market can be and the potential
size of these companies in comparison to
what we're seeing in north america
i think that was a very very thank you
for that that very comprehensive
response so i'm going to actually throw
this out to everybody else can you tell
the audience or entertain them maybe
with any uh either success or horror
stories that you might have come across
about companies that you know sally
forth and either get into trouble or
have managed to overcome some of the
challenges that i think everybody is
talking about and referencing
i mean talking about success i'm really
happy that we now have two of those new
zealand companies i'm working with and
supporting in the market they have
agreements in place with german
wholesalers and importers which was of
course a really big step for them so i'm
excited so i would definitely count this
as a really great success story for new
zealand and for the local industry and
of course there's way more company that
now take this as inspiration to also
look for partners here in the market and
additionally i think
in general if you're looking at the
industry it is it is a success story for
the country because if you're looking at
new zealand
a lot of the land is owned by the maori
population and so new zealand puts a lot
of resources and support in that to
support the local industry that is that
is partly run by maoris
and the great thing is we already heard
that yesterday in jamie's keynote i
believe that she said
we're moving away from money i mean yes
money is still very important but we're
looking for well being for
sustainability and so on and i think
really this is where new zealand has
done a really big step because if you're
looking at those maori businesses that
that grow the cannabis there they really
put the money into into the local
community and really help the region the
rural areas grow well i think that paul
you're bringing up a big point that we
were all discussing in the back room
which is you know cannabis as a tool of
economic development
maybe costas and boniface you can talk a
little bit about you know the emerging
economic and incentive environment
that is allowing the industry to grow
when we start with costa
sure i think that most of the
european countries they're already
offering european
grants incentives that are
in most cases i know for a fact it works
for portugal it works for greece i'm not
familiar with any other country but i'm
sure it's the same mechanism that
gets implemented
they're able to provide grants with uh
specific percentages up to
uh like 30 40 of
construction cost or you know greenhouse
construction depending on how far like
you get more money the further out you
are from major cities
so that that is a great financial
incentive uh you know where you're
looking at putting together like a 10
million year facility you could get a
you know a couple million two three
million uh based on the location however
that that creates another potential
challenge which is okay if you're going
to go in a remote village in greece that
you know nobody really wants to go and
live there or you're going to find your
workforce so
although the father you know
and i'm going to go back to a little bit
to uh the risk mitigation question that
you said and i think that one of the
most important uh aspects a lot of
people miss in the industry is that you
know you need to you need to educate
yourself about the industry you need to
learn and make sure that you have clear
and
real expectations as to where the
industry is right now where it's going
to go because
right now
you're looking to
put a facility together that's going to
have product ready probably in about two
and a half to three years from now so
how are you setting those expectations
you know and you know looking at those
uh strong partners i mean i work for a
company that we manufacture eugmp
equipment
and
i have people all over the world
reaching out to us and like well you
know we want to get into extraction they
want to buy equipment and
talking about those horror stories i i
come across at least three different
companies that had already paid
you know
three four hundred thousand
euros worth of equipment that didn't
have a ce marking and could not cross
the border and get into border and get
into europe so
and it's funny because the people that
actually ordered that equipment were
based in either canada or the united
states so it wasn't people that are
outside of the industry they knew what's
being used
but they seemed to have missed this
little piece of information uh eugmp has
been another uh big challenge for many
it used to be a challenge up until a
couple of years ago until we came to see
how companies came to overcome that
and
i think that
a common practice in europe has been
to bring people in from the pharma
industry
work closely with them
and there has been a lot of people that
were you know promising eu gmp yeah we
know it we can do it et cetera et cetera
but
the only people that were actually to
pull it off were people that
brought the people in worked with them
and actually kept that
you know that knowledge in-house
developed it and they kept it kind of
you know secret so to me uh in terms of
mitigating that risk is
work with people that have proven
results as well as passion right i mean
vanase was talking about this is one of
the greatest things about working in an
emerging market there's there's
youth there's there's activism there's
passion what would you say that's that
the role of that and the importance of
that is in developing markets like
zimbabwe for example uh i think it's
it's very important uh where we are
today is probably where the rest of the
world was five years ago
we have a lot of optimism when i came to
berlin
i thought i was going to be the next cbd
smokable flower king
but after one day
i grew from this big and i feel this
small right now
but it's good because everyone here that
i've had a chance to interact with has
taken the time
to teach me what's going on in the
industry to allow my expectations to be
more realistic
i not only represent myself i represent
a nation
and the hopes of a nation lie with
cannabis the vice president came on tv
the other day said we have 1.5 billion
dollars of cannabis that we're gonna
sell this year
we haven't even sold two million dollars
you understand so that optimism uh i'm
sure everyone here has had it before
with cannabis it's a new industry
it just needs to be checked we need to
be practical about what to expect and
when to expect it and how to expect it
but
to speak a little bit further
on the opportunities that exist i think
before we address the opportunities we
need to look at education and regulation
people
in my country need to be educated on
this it's not the same as europe and
north america there's a huge stigma
uh we need to educate our doctors our
pharmacists we need to create a local
market sounds like germany yeah we need
to make sure that
uh before
we even start talking about the bigger
things
the the basic foundation to allow there
to be
a cannabis national master plan so to
say we're trying to make a national
master plan where we're putting cannabis
in our curriculum to get kids learning
about this plant because we understand
the value that this plant has
and we want to unleash its potential in
zimbabwe
so i'm actually going to come back to
paul here for a question
how important is it
to network
ahead of time and know that not only
you're going a crop in your own country
but figuring out
where you have to go right and where you
want to target why is it so important to
find international partners in that
process
uh i think very touching on there is
kind of like going back to the
mitigation risk because i think it's
it's really crucial to have this partner
who understands
um the local market and this is why
networking is is more than important
than ever even though
um if you're looking at the new zealand
companies they're all like they haven't
exported really like a big quantity yet
we're still in an early stage and all
they have shipped is samples so far
but it's really good for also the
economic stability of those companies to
already have supply agreements in place
which they have domestically but also
internationally and this is why
networking is very very important
steve i'm actually going to come back to
you for a second because the uk actually
is a very very interesting case i think
it was a couple of years ago still that
the uk was the major that's the biggest
export country for cannabis in the world
not canada or anything else um what does
that kind of dynamic create domestically
what is the tension there
uh it's i suppose it's it's quite um
elite and and controlled um the uk
has been producing cannabis
near near about 20 years
and um what you have had is you have had
this cut off from actual patients while
it's gone through i suppose a a pharma a
farmer root
so there's been i suppose
within within the the cannabis industry
and certainly within the the patient
community there's been a lot of friction
between um the
the types of groups who have gone down
the farmer route and you know it's
understandable going down the farm route
it does take significant time investment
and you do want to protect that
investment as much as you can but it it
there's a contrast in so far as well um
if you look at
the basics of us in in the early stage
of cultivation there is a product there
ready for ready for patients to to to
use and consume and there is i suppose
friction that
the decision hasn't been made to allow
that access early days now that has been
rectified and patients are getting
access under you know under under a very
still strict uh manner and protocol
but
you definitely have um tension in so far
as why you know why is this elite group
allowed access and it is cut off you
know and why is the government not
engaging and
on this dialogue and a lot of that is
obviously down to
um cannabis has to be the most
politically friendly conversation of the
last 20 years now thankfully i think
every single
every single country is adapting their
tone and openness and transparency
around discussing cannabis now there's
the broader education that this isn't
something that kills and this isn't uh
reefer madness so i think we've seen
sweeping changes across uh across the
globe that cannabis is no longer the
political hot potato that they used to
be and you know
a kind of
a politician can come to a cannabis
conference free from the stigma where
you know uh most of us uh where we're
we're sharp suits and uh you know we we
where we speak in a very professional
manner and that's you know that's
relatively new this this this b2b side
where we talk of we talk of
implementation of a proper um a proper
commercial and responsible industry
and i think you know it's the industry's
just it's it's been hampered if you will
by a lack of collective
collective individuals who are informed
on the topic you know i think when we
started prohibition partners a couple of
years ago like i i wanted to actually
invest in in the space invest in
european opportunities but there was
very little information out there as to
what was happening
and you know and i think events like
these are absolutely critical for us to
come and share ideas now we may disagree
or you know we may think that there is
certain better ways to do it but that is
all part of the process and certainly
something that you know should be should
be welcomed
okay so i've got another i've got
another question and i'd like this to be
around robin
what is your favorite developing market
that's not yours and why start with
costas
well you know have to love germany of
course because it's by far the
well you know
and to be more specific on the patient
access only uh
it is really surprising how germany a
country that always focuses on exports
you know has only granted three licenses
i i have a feeling that this might
change uh pretty soon just based on you
know previous track record
but uh we'll get to see that however
i mean malta has been doing a great uh
job you know
both
government-led and you know
multi-enterprise has been doing a great
job promoting the opportunities in the
country and i think that there's
there's been
although a small country but they have
created a really interesting uh scheme
of how they can work as a hub
although not a
european union country but within the
european continent i think that north
macedonia has a lot of potential
um
why do you think that north macedonia
has such so much potential well there's
you know the if i were to compare it i
mean there's pretty similar climate you
know with greece and portugal so uh
when we when we say when we speak about
climate it's not only i mean when you're
you know cultivating in an eu gmp uh or
jcp
environment i think that the climate
does play in you know a certain role but
not that big of a it doesn't really make
that big of a difference however
it is uh it is a you know low
electricity you know low labor uh costs
um
if you're able to overcome a ugp and i
think that they have a government that's
really supportive of the industry
from what i spoke with a few people over
the last few days there you know we
should be expecting some changes in that
part of the world as well
uh i mean portugal has been i think the
leading uh country in terms of you know
cultivation and
2022 is going to we're really going to
see a lot of cultivation a lot of flower
coming out of portugal
um
[Music]
but yeah i think that you know i mean
denmark of course is you know is a more
established market in the sense that you
know exactly what's going on a lot of
transparency and uh we've been you know
as vitalists we've you know already
deployed equipment there and there's
been companies that are really producing
you know
pharmaceutical grade extracts let's say
so
i really like countries that there is
stability but at the same time those
countries with great potential
there's the risk might seem to be there
at the moment but i think that
if you're working with people that you
know
local people that have been in the
industry you can kind of safeguard uh
your investment
but yeah you know those are the
countries that beyond here what about
what about down down towards
non-european countries within africa or
thailand or you know further afield
china
i wanted to go with germany as my
favorite emerging market besides new
zealand but since kostas claimed that i
would go with israel
because i think there's also definitely
still a lot of potential for companies
exporting there because as i understand
there's a domestic there's a domestic
production but of course there's still
some room for some high quality products
there um and of course there is this
this taste in in israel that or this
this preference for for for flower
rather than uh just uh processed
products so i think this would
definitely be
very interesting but you just mentioned
thailand i mean i don't know the details
but i know that some of the new zealand
companies are also kind of looking into
thailand and the current developments
there i've actually got a question for
boniface i mean for example morocco has
got changing you know legalization laws
etc and cultivation
from your perspective just within africa
where would you say or like the hot
countries besides south africa and and
um besides south africa and zimbabwe i
was actually surprised that the lady
from new frontier data didn't mention
lesotho that sotu is producing and
exporting more than zimbabwe and south
africa put together
do you know what we call the tsutube
back home
we call it the kingdom of mischief
yeah they just
legalized psilocybin
they're legalizing anything and
everything in lesotho so i'm excited
about lesotho check it out too
okay so i'm going to throw this out does
anybody have any questions for the
panelists here would you like to ask
about any regions no i got more
none
okay i have a question okay
is it all going to be just commodities
is that the future
right because i feel like
cannabis in this global marketplace is
moving really more toward a cigarette
style of production as opposed to say a
wine or a beer style
right and it seems like everybody's
looking for that for like giant mega
farms and
huge amounts of exporting but where's
the craft is there space for that in any
of these countries in any of these
spaces
yeah there's definitely room for that in
new zealand because if you
a lot of the companies there are
actually really really small so with all
these cultivators and producers of then
uh products from the cannabis it's
really we're not talking high volume
it's going to be very specialized and a
lot of us come a lot of the companies in
new zealand that actually the people
behind it they all have a very strong
pharmaceutical background so they're
actually looking to not just export
flour but moving into into a value-add
product so we're talking about extracts
and other things and because this also
let's say kind of kind of
from my perspective saves your business
um in in the medical space if we're
talking about legalization in other
countries because then you have this
this extract
this liquid and because you know that
a lot of the patients or some of the
patients they would not necessarily like
to smoke or vaporize it so this is why
actually new zealand companies
definitely focus on the value-add
products and in the long run and not
just exporting flowers and mass but just
like small quantities right now but high
quality
see i was actually hoping you might talk
a little bit about the cbd craft
industry in in the uk a little bit or is
there one yeah
craft is a is an odd term when when you
put it to cannabis because ultimately
what it just means is uh consistency and
what's what we what we what we continue
to lack in this industry is consistency
so the small batch producers who have
been provided who who've
i suppose
who have been able to produce
consistency are now termed craft and
there is a nice premium and sound about
that but
i think in the stage of of the industry
the level of craft is still a little bit
far out i am you know you have consumers
who are only just starting to understand
what they want and what they like and
the volume of and and i suppose
frequency of products in the market is
is still quite minimal especially in
europe in terms of what choice you have
and and product availability you know uh
cbd craft markets uh
uh you know i
look rightly or wrongly i'm i'm
i i i'm quite skeptical of of the cbd of
the cbd market
i think you know you have a number a
large number of players who are
promoting these cbd craft brands that if
you look at the production chain they
all come from the exact same contract
manufacturer and you know you you you
you have this right across europe and
these are fooling the consumers and you
know it is not building any sort of
uh true education and true brand
credibility uh with either the product
icbd or the the brand itself and that
obviously comes from early stage
industry and misconception on both sides
of the field but
the
you you will of course have consumers
who want differentiation who want
personalization and and different
experiences you are seeing um
brand masters from you know from pharma
from food and drink from retail move
into the cannabis sector and there are
uh spicy looking cbd brands and products
out there all from cosmetics to beauty
to health and wellness and food and
drink starting to emerge now
whether
there is a big enough cbd market uh in
the uk under uh under the existing
regulations to maintain that is still up
for up for debate but you know they're
all hoping you they're they're seeing
what has happened in in north american
market where there is a thc opportunity
and you know that transition to chc and
consumer demand for those type of
product variations is obviously off the
charts so uh it's it's it's an exciting
testing stage but it comes with a huge
and huge huge amount of risk
customers you want to add to them yeah i
just want to uh you know will this
that was a great question and uh i must
say that for the longest time that i i
always thought of i mean we're an
extraction man you know equipment
manufacturing company
um so i'm very less familiar with
cultivation however it's something that
i'm i really enjoy talking about and
listening it's about and
um i want to thank tyler yesterday we we
had a great discussion from valeos and
the craft industry you know he made a
really nice comment that the size of the
craft industry you know is between you
know three to ten metric tons production
of you know per year i think that this
is what we're seeing in europe so
i i thought it was going to be much less
but i think that you know this is
substantial uh i mean
it fits perfectly the
european cultivation model of the
facilities that we're seeing being built
now and
for the longest time i thought that yes
of course you know cannabis similar to
tomatoes or whatever there's going to be
commoditization and
i don't think that is true
i think that the cannabis consumer and
you know let's let's call the spatial
spade i mean it to me it does not really
define
where this uh
adult use and where does medical use in
terms of you know specifically for flour
where you know how many people are you
know purchasing cannabis in germany for
medical use and how many for adult use
now i know that there is a lot of uh
overlap but
you know we're starting to see over the
last year at least that even the demand
in germany is increasing primarily for
you know people that are uh paying for
cannabis privately
so i think that over the next year year
and a half we're gonna start to see a
significant increase in the quantity
that's been
in the market in germany
for people that are you know using both
uh you know for for both usages so
always assimilate the cannabis consumer
as like you know the coffee consumer or
the wine consumer and yes you can go to
starbucks and get an espresso but i
really like you know an espresso from a
little you know italian coffee shop and
you know or or somebody that's you know
a colombian coffee shop so
it doesn't mean that i won't buy coffee
from starbucks but if i if i you know if
i have access to that other product i
would much rather enjoy that coffee so i
think that this is
it's harder a lot because starbucks can
afford to have all the nice locations
and so
you know the little mom and pop they
can't pay the rent on the gentrified
neighborhood anymore and now where do
you go to get your little fancy yeah but
here we go
the cannabis has been distributed
through pharmacies so you know the same
pharmacy could have the same products
and you know
this is where we're going to see the
the product differentiation come into
play really strongly so when you know
when when when tyler is cultivating you
know this uh uh
you know this product that he's been
cultivated in the united states for the
last 10 years and you know it's right
next to uh you know a large
canadian company that you know has a
like
i'm not going to even get into the
potencies but the real there is
differences in the cannabis
flowers so
if i had to choose i would much rather
go for a you know a a product that has
come from the craft industry versus you
know the big names let's say well that
you actually raised an interesting
question here because we're all talking
about international exports but no one
has really talked about developing
countries exporting into the united
states
maybe i would start with boniface is
that is that something that is on the
drawing board in zimbabwe or throughout
africa or is it just too difficult
it's it's difficult because hemp is
really cheap in the states i mean in
california i got buddies who stopped
growing hemp i'm convincing them to move
to zimbabwe
so
that's that's difficult but
going back to the previous question
about the products um what i see the
future of uh
cannabis and cannabis products i think
of uh if you go to a restaurant and you
look at a table there's a salt and
pepper the sugar well would like to have
you know cannabis products right there
just like salt and pepper and sugar
are there any questions because we're
sort of getting to the end of the panel
no questions out there
hi um nim from israel
um everyone's speaking about cannabis as
a commodity
as a commodity
and um in israel we're
importing around like just our companies
or importing 1.2 tons per year
of medical cannabis and it's a
connoisseur product
like the market is looking for
more um
quality than quantity i mean they want
quality and quantity now everyone here
is speaking about cannabis as a
commodity sugar
tomatoes it's not i mean hemp is a
commodity cbd
is a commodity
a cannabis in my eyes of course
and in the israeli market they're
looking for
premium premium premium product
and
i i haven't heard anything about this
the quality
and the
of these products and importing and
exporting well i think you're asking
about the eu gmp issue or or producing
for gmp for export i think everyone go
ahead once you go to um the regulations
eugmp or control union
um you lose a lot of the quality for
because of the regulations
that's what i've we've been seeing
because everyone's
growing their capacity if you have eugmp
it costs you a lot of money so you have
to have a lot of quantity
to um
let's say for to pay for that
i can't see how um
you can have an eu gmp or uh or for
import and have also the the quality of
t20
and terpene profiles of like three and a
half percent with these huge uh
facilities
well i think that what you're talking
about actually is is the dichotomy
between having a regulated certified
market which is gmp standard versus the
other stuff and i think certainly there
was a little bit of disagreement up here
that you can't have that in in a gmp
environment would anybody like to tackle
that one
no i'm not a cultivation expert but but
i i strongly uh suggest that you speak
with some of the and if you don't know
anybody i can introduce you to a couple
uh
but to you know dive deeper in that but
from my understanding you're able to
cultivate quality under eu gmp
uh
you know the trying process is where you
might be losing some because
is gacp
so you know it shouldn't really affect
the quality of the product you write
about the incentive of certain
cultivators to cultivate high thc potent
plants because they can get more money
for it because actually
you know you're getting paid
based on the thc potency and cbd potency
versus the rest of the you know the
flavonoids and the terpenoids so there
is an incentive
to get a higher price for other products
but this is a decision that the
cultivator should take when it comes
down to okay do i go for a product
that's 18
ph. get a little bit less money for it
but maybe get larger markets you know
market share in the market
so i'm not quite clear if i answered you
i think we're out of time do we have
time for one more question or we do not
okay well thank you so much can we have
a round of applause for our
distinguished panelists
you