[Music]
hey Alex Rogers the CEO of
ICBC we're here at the first Barcelona
event and we're teamed up with spannabis
it's awesome it's great we've got Berlin
Zurich Vancouver and San Francisco come
check us out we'll bring it all around
the world
[Music]
and today in Barcelona is absolutely
refreshing because it's great to bring a
b2b element to Spain this is the biggest
b2b cannabis industry event ever held in
Spain come join us
[Music]
and I think that there's a space for
everyone in each each sector it's just a
matter of what
do you want to be big you want to be
small what I you think that there's room
for everyone in this basis
[Music]
please drive safely and enjoy your stay
[Applause]