this is international business
conference and many people who came here
kind of took a chance bought a ticket
wasn't sure what to expect right and the
feedback I'm getting is I can't believe
this I didn't know what was going to be
this good what they mean by good is
information and networking and just the
general attitude of the people here just
want to thank Alex and the dial for
putting on it and that really blends
activism and business in a really really
great way and I believe in karma I
believe in community I believe in love
and understanding and I actually believe
if you hold true to some of those
tenants and precepts that you're only
going to benefit yourself for so many
reasons and in my case it's actually
helped me make money also so it's this
new win-win situation that's happening
with the cannabis industry in particular
and I think that's what people are very
surprised about that that they can make
money they can be successful and no one
else has still to lose we just wrapped
it up here at the international cannabis
business conference on a fantastic time
steve blum from celeb stoner and freedom
leaf magazine was here Steve DeAngelo
was here Ethan Nadelmann from the drug
policy alliance gave an impassioned
impassioned speech about what we need to
do with people are actually overly
excited and happy that we have decided
to dedicate so much of this to culture
politics and advocacy and I'm
tremendously happy with the feedback
never doubt a small group of concerned
citizens can change the world it is
indeed the only thing that ever has
thank you