good morning
my guten morgen meine darmanon heron
my name is jamie pearson ownership and
ceo from bang inc
fulfillment swansea
for those of you who don't speak german
25 years ago i took a german class on
the at the university of weberton
i speak a little bit of german like alex
just said i don't get enough practice so
i'm going to spare you
my my german today
but i want to thank alex and the icbc
team
for giving us
a chance to be here together and also
for putting this amazing conference
together i think this is probably my
15th icbc conference i've done them in
zurich in berlin san francisco kauai
and barcelona
i've been on many panels and had the
opportunity to see
what this conference has done for
cannabis around the world and it's
really remarkable and what i'd really
like to have everyone do is give the
icbc crew a hand
and then what i would like you all to do
is really look around this room
look at who's in this room it's a lot of
a lot of men i i guess i shouldn't be
surprised there's a lot of men here but
i want you guys to look around and see
who the people are that you're working
with that are changing the world because
that is what we're doing here in
cannabis
all right oh clicker
there we go
randall
bang went public in july of 2019.
in december of 2019 bang's founder and
ceo stepped down and the board asked me
to step in
and accept the permanent
president ceo role having been a real
estate investor for 25 years i'm really
comfortable in the investment
environment
i'm comfortable with deal flow i'm
comfortable sitting around a table full
of men
talking about finances looking over
balance sheets and p l's
so i didn't have any problem saying yes
because i also had been working at bang
for about five years at that point and
i'd been in the cannabis industry for
about seven years at that point and
really felt comfortable in accepting
that role what i didn't have was capital
markets experience
wrong direction
what bang has are some really great
partners
one of the partners i have is here with
me today his name is sean connecker he's
over there
he's with plant-based investment
corporation which is a publicly traded
company on the cannabis the canadian
stock exchange and they are an
investment company that puts investments
together for
plant-based and actually fungi-based
they're doing some mushroom stuff too so
i was fortunate because my company had
the backing of a really strong partner
and then in the in the meantime i had
been putting deals together with
companies like true leave they're on the
csc how many of you raise your hands
have heard of true leave
they're one of i think they're the
largest north american cannabis company
and they're one of the only profitable
ones
we have a deal within diva in canada
and i am here
doing this conference and zurich because
i'd like to bring bang into europe with
our thc products
so we started
11 years ago we were born in oakland
our founder was a master chocolatier
european trained chef to cuisine and the
chocolate that we've been putting in the
marketplace
is european quality now i have some some
swiss people out there that want to
challenge me and i brought some
chocolate i smuggled it in and
you're on here we go
this is where i'm from this is absorkee
montana
right now it's got a thousand people but
when i grew up there it had 800 people a
little small town about an hour from the
next we we had a grocery store but if we
really wanted to go shopping we had to
drive an hour away
and that's the view from my the ranch
where i grew up and my parents still
live there
so i was really lucky to grow up in a
place that's so beautiful
and also i have this affinity for
germany and this connection to germany
um
and i work for this great company and so
life is pretty good but i'll tell you
it's really good to be bang because
after i took over two years ago we
cleaned a few things up we got a really
strong balance sheet we've got great
financials we've got amazing products 11
years of history putting millions of
chocolate bars in people's hands
and
people then say to me how did you get
into cannabis
and i say i was born
i'm 52 my dad's 71. he's been growing
cannabis for 56 years that's him in his
outdoor grow i don't know if you can see
my face that's me and his indoor grow
dad dear old dad he's a vietnam vet ptsd
doesn't drink but uses cannabis it makes
him feel better so i grew up in an
environment where cannabis was normal
and then my first cousin on my mom's
side is dj mugs from cypress hill
and that's him getting the star on the
walk of fame a couple years ago
also the cannabis activist how many of
you have heard of cyprus hill
yeah
insane in the membrane
he and i are the same age we raised our
kids together
and he asked me to do a deal for him in
cannabis we've been investing in real
estate together
for about 15 years at that point so when
it was time for can for cyprus to get
back into the industry he came to me and
said would you help us find a deal that
is good for cyprus so i went out and
that's what i did that's when i jumped
into the industry but these are my two
kids jens and alicia we call her lisey
lisi's here right now she's going to
spain for her senior year of college and
she thought she'd stop and watch mom
give a talk um
and yeah
that was skeet shooting so
she's like do you think they'll be mad
if you're if they see me with a gun i'm
like no nobody's gonna care
my kids are jenzenials i don't know if
you guys know what that means but they
were born in that really weird spot
where
um
they know what a phone book is they know
how to dial a rotary phone
and you know so it's the analog
world that they were born into but the
digital world caught up to them and now
they're in the digital world they're not
quite millennials um they're not gen
zers they're they're right in that
middle which gives me an advantage
because they teach me a lot
so
muggs asked me to get into
cannabis because i was doing real estate
and i came from that little small town
and what happened was i have these two
athletes
and
i didn't want to tell anybody i was
working in cannabis i was
scared that there would be blowback on
my kids how many of you in this room
have a little bit of doubt or or
sometimes take a beat before you say i'm
in cannabis because there's a stigma to
it
a few of you yeah i mean it's it's a
little bit uncomfortable because we work
in this world where
we haven't quite as a world accepted
cannabis we're still in prohibition in
the united states and so i was careful
about what i would say or so that my
kids didn't have any um
any blowback
but it's the really interesting thing is
from so that's them that zenial thing
but
as you get farther on into this graph
what you'll find is that
not only are the kids growing up with
technology
but they're growing up in a world where
cannabis is normal
for this generation
there is no stigma and they wonder
what's wrong with us because we're
fighting about legalization because
we're we know that we've been using
cannabis for millennia literally they
are finding elements of cannabis in the
pyramids of egypt
and we just had the fda
skip phase three clinical trials and let
pfizer
have approval on that vaccine but we
can't get cannabis legalized and our
kids are wondering what is wrong with
you adults
our world's on fire
the planet is
shaking us off like a wet dog because
we're we're ruin i mean we've not done
this very well for them and i think this
generation is
wanting us to wake up
and that's why i think my kids make me
better at my job so i get in the
cannabis industry seven years ago
and
i didn't tell anybody what i did and
then high times outed me
and they named me the most influential
woman in cannabis um one of them in 2018
and the most influential woman in
cannabis in 2019 and asked me to give a
speech and it went viral and the next
thing i knew everybody in my little town
knew what i did
and when i go home sometimes
some people cross the street when they
see me coming
it's interesting cana phobia is live
alive and well and that's what i'm here
to talk about
because i shouldn't be afraid to tell
people what i do
bang has been putting we've put millions
of chocolate bars in consumers hands in
nine u.s states
we are the number one
chocolate in canada
and in 2020 last year
we were the number one sku in ontario
meaning bang chocolate bang milk
chocolate
sold more units than any flour or
pre-roll
in the country in the province of
ontario now flour and pre-rolls sold
more than edibles so as a
as an um
what do you call it
you know
basically
flour and edibles flour and pre-roll
sell more than edibles but not one
flower and not one pre-roll sold more
than bang chocolate so we're we're out
there kicking butt
we're out there doing deals with true
leave and we're putting
people
chocolate people's hands and they feel
better when they use our products i get
emails from people saying i haven't
slept like this since i started using a
product
people are using it for seizure
disorders for
anxiety and i've got a product that
actually improves people's well-being
and what am i worried about when i stand
proud and say i'm the ceo of an edibles
company
and it's because we've got this stigma
that we're fighting
and i think
improving people's well-being is
something that should make you feel
important
and everybody in this room should commit
to feeling important that what we're
doing is changing the world
so i had an epiphany the other day which
is why i chose this talk
i went to a conference and i heard every
single in fact i was at the
um global investment forum yesterday and
what people were focused on was money
oh this this company's doing this many
million dollars the you know germany's
the third largest cannabis market in the
world 30 billion dollars is the size of
the u.s market 200 billion dollars is
the size of the u.s illicit market so
there's this big gap between what's
actually happening
which is lots of people are using
cannabis and what we're really willing
to talk about what we're really willing
to talk about is money
that's what we prioritize
and i'm thinking wait a minute the
products that we're putting in people's
hands are helping veterans with ptsd or
helping people with parkinson's they're
making the world feel better
and we're talking about money and it
brought me to the realization that
that's what is wrong with this world
that's why our world is on fire we know
that hemp cleans the soil
we know that it takes
2700 liters of water to make a single
cotton t-shirt
when it doesn't cost that much water to
make a hemp t-shirt but what we're going
to do is keep making cotton t-shirts
when we're sending pallets of them to
africa we don't need any more t-shirts
but we want to make more money because
that's what we value and
my kids and that generation
we're going to cost them this planet
we're costing them this planet so i
think the people in this room need to
understand that this isn't something
we're doing for money
this is something we're doing for money
and it's something we're doing for
well-being
and what i'll tell you is that the
conservatives in america i'm sure you
guys all
from across the pond look at us and
wonder what are we doing we we put that
he who shall not be named in
to uh the presidency and a whole bunch
of weird stuff happened after he got
there
but
what we all knew and what we all
expected is that he was going to put a
focus on the economy he did not put a
focus on well-being we're trying to do
that now
cannabis is a gateway to wellness to
vulgar fool
to well-being it's going to clean our
air it's going to clean our soil it's
going to help our bodies it's going to
help our communities so i'm here giving
all of us a call to action to start
prioritizing well-being
versus
money
in germany
you guys are in the greatest position to
do it
yes these this is for 2024.
right now germany is still the second
largest cannabis market
or excuse me the third largest cannabis
market by spending which is amazing
because you don't have recreational
cannabis yet imagine what's going to
happen with the population density of
europe when recreational cannabis is
passed
and look we already know everybody's
using it so all of the politicians here
let's stop pretending that this is about
money your citizens are using cannabis
but you people who i love so much i came
over here and studied your language
i have two
children that are dual citizens of
germany they hold your passport i come
here i have family here i love this
place and what i love is how
you when i was here and get a sinus
infection the doctor says oh no you
can't have antibiotics you have to try a
plant-based medicine first you need to
get your nutrition in order you need to
get your exercise in order there's this
focus on volgoful here that we don't
have in america you have mutual kindcore
you can go to a spa if you're feeling a
little stressed out i love that i love
your culture and what you guys can do is
help us make this type of transition
because you
can be the example for the world you
already are we already talk about german
engineering we already talk about
precision we already know that your
politics are set up to not be played one
party against each other
you guys are
really poised to come in and be the
example of what's right
and if anybody wants this slideshow i'll
i'll just come up to me and i'll just
give you a copy
now we've got a model
already that exists and it's the sin
country scotland iceland new zealand how
many of you know what i'm about to tell
you about these sin countries
nobody okay well here we go
the sin countries
formed a union in 2017 and they agreed
to stop using gdp as their measure for
the success of their economy
what they use is the well-being of their
citizens
and so what they have done is created a
measure
of how the economy is doing it's not
just the gold and silver reserves
it's not just the output of work or the
goods and services that are being
produced it's things like access to
green space the happiness of children
access to housing none of that's
measured in gdp
they do measure the illicit drug trade
they don't measure unpaid care
in gdp
but these countries decided wait a
second we're confusing activity with
results
the results of the economy should be the
well-being of its people would we not
agree that that's pretty basic but none
of us do it
i don't think it's um
a surprise that the three prime
ministers of these countries are women
they also happen to be crushing the the
coveted
response
the the death toll in these countries
has been very very low
because they're prioritizing well-being
nicholas sturgeon gave a viral ted talk
and she said you know what we choose to
measure as a country matters
because it drives political focus
politic public activity
and it in the end
if the activity of the economy is
killing the earth
oh well
we created more money
and she's saying look what we have to do
is we have to do better for our people
and the well-being is the measurement
that matters
so we're gonna take a poll here how many
of you know who robin hood is
oh this is one where almost all the
hands go up okay great so i have a
question for you we're gonna say
do you think robin hood is gaming or do
you think it's democratization
raise your hand if you think robin hood
is gaming
the investment system
and you know there's no right or wrong
answer because it's kind of both and how
many of you think robin hood is actually
democratizing investing
okay can we try this again because i'd
like to see all of your hands go up i
want to know one of the other
do you think that robin hood is
democratizing investment or do you think
that it's
teaching kids how to
gain their money so all in favor of its
gaming
a few of you all in favor of
democratization
okay i guess some of you are still
asleep um
robin hood has 20 million users and the
average user
has a 3 500 worth of assets under
management the biggest online trading
platform is e-trade they have 5.2
million users users with an average of
100 000 assets under management so
obviously e-trades doing 420 billion
dollars worth of trade that's just
retail whereas robinhood is doing about
80 billion
but what i will tell you is 20 million
people are involved in the trading
platform and how many of you saw what
they did to gamestop
what all these kids what my kids did to
gamestop because believe me my kids got
into that
they were re they were all about it
and what this generation is doing
while i was playing pac-man and cruising
that little main street that you saw my
kids are on their phone talking about
their cryptocurrency and they're talking
about oh should we get into the amc play
i would say that's democratization but
what's really interesting and what i sat
back in my minivan while they're in the
back talking and they're talking about
reddit and they're talking about twitter
and as a ceo of a public company and i'm
supposed to be running an irpr
uh campaign and i've got these big
companies like you know stockhouse and
um
you know the the places where you all go
to learn about stocks want me to write
25 000 a month checks to get my stock in
front of you
and what i realize is if i go on reddit
or if i go on twitter and these kids
start following me i might get 20
million kids
invested in my stock and believe me they
love cannabis
they're gamers
they're cannabis users and cannabis is
normal for them
so i'm thinking to myself i gotta engage
with these young people they are our
future
the median age
of our citizens on this planet right now
is
28.9 years old the median age that means
the majority of the people on this
planet
have cell phones
they get their information from
technology
this group of youth that are coming up
that we are now building an industry for
they have some expectations
they have watched us prioritize money
over everything they've watched us send
to
not us but two billionaires to the
space
we know what technology can bring us
imagine what would happen
if we prioritized as adults in this
world
the pursuit of well-being over the
pursuit of money what would we come up
with
because man we're capable of anything
and i'll tell you what the future what
these kids expect from us
and after watching gamestop
where they took a company that had no
fundamental value and they saved it and
then they crushed the capital markets
people that had put positions or that
were playing that short
they know how to do that and they did it
and what they're going to do
is they're going to figure out how to
talk on twitter and
reddit and twitter and they're going to
figure out how to get what they want out
of us
and i say why don't we just engage with
them why don't we join forces with the
youth here's what they want they get all
their information from their phones and
their computers and they have a
fundamental distrust of the government
what's the government doing for them
what's the government doing for any of
us really
and i'm curious to see how they're going
to hack the government because i i don't
mean like literally hack it but how are
they going to make things happen the way
they want them and what they're doing is
cancel culture
if you know if they don't like you or if
you are not authentic or you are not
telling the truth they will out you and
you will be done
so how about we start listening to them
and start telling the truth start being
authentic and start prioritizing
well-being of
the humanity and the planet
and we are we are in the right industry
for this because we are operating in
prohibition we can make this world look
any way we want
we can do things like
demand that the stock exchanges require
women and people of color be on boards
and young people for example we can
require that in one swoop of a pen
we could change the way the world works
authenticity
my kids have been marketed to since they
were born think about
when they get on a program and they see
somebody put product placement they know
they're getting paid for that what they
want is to hear the truth they want to
follow interesting people and they want
to follow authentic people so if you've
got a brand or you've got a company out
there make sure that you're
communicating to the world in a way
that's very authentic
you'll make it if you are they want us
to be planet friendly
they're watching us and they want to
know what the impact on the earth is of
our products the good news is if we're
in cannabis if we're not trying to grow
cannabis in cold climates which i think
is weird
you know you don't grow corn in
warehouses in canada to make candy right
the sun is going to be the way we make
cannabis and once that becomes the norm
because most of the cannabis
that is being sold in america right now
what's really hot is all the
concentrates
well it doesn't matter what the cannabis
looks like and ultimately fluffy buds
are the better ones anyway but they want
to know what is your impact on the world
and they want to know are you being
innovative are you up cycling they don't
want to see the landfills filled with
plastics anymore they want to they don't
want to see the oceans filled with
plastics anymore and we shouldn't be
doing that anymore so i honestly as a
ceo of bang i do things like
i have people of color on my board i
have gay people on my board my executive
team is diverse we only use sustainable
packaging we're making decisions because
i feel like knowing this and that this
is the people that are coming up to buy
my products it's malpractice when i
don't do it because i'm putting my
company at risk because of people coming
into the cannabis industry that are
going to be buying our products they
care about this stuff and we should too
so i have been asked that's me up in the
top right there um i'm part of this
group of women ceos in cannabis and we
call ourselves jokingly the female
cannabis mafia
and kirsten gillibrand is a friend of
one of our our cohort members and so she
calls us we have a call and they ask us
to give them advice about how to make
this legalization happen the democrats
really believe that cannabis legislation
is going to be groundbreaking for a
couple of reasons one is the way
politics normally works is monopoly
money oh we got this big budget over
here for military let's steal some of
that budget and put it over here for
education
and then the republicans come in and
they give the money back to military
right cannabis is a new bucket of money
and we can pull it out of the illicit
market and put it into the economy here
i am talking about money but we can do
it in a way that's responsible so i'm
telling senator gillibrand you know what
i think you guys should be doing you
should be talking to young people
don't underestimate them
this one says hi mom and dad they're
forcing me to write but they can't make
me tell you anything this is a little
girl writing from
from camp
this is the mentality of our youth
they are not to be
underestimated so here's my
calls to action for the germans in the
room for the europeans and for everybody
in cannabis
number one let's change the narrative
from money to well-being
let's talk about and if you can't stop
talking about money that's fine but add
well-being to your repertoire
cannabis makes people feel better second
of all
when somebody is spouting
fat things that are not facts oh it's a
gateway drug oh people get psychosis all
of the things that we know are not true
and you sit there and bite your tongue
don't bite your tongue
challenge these inaccurate narratives
and these untested assumptions
be brave in public be bold be courageous
and here's the one thing i want to say
to the germans you all know who our
brands are
people say to me oh bang
i know your brand i don't know a single
german brand
the third largest market in the world i
don't know if you have brands if you're
building brands but if you are start
buying american cannabis media start
going to places like cannabis now and
weed maps and let us know who you are so
that we can start watching you as an
example
because i believe you can be a great
example of all the things i've talked
about
i love this country because you do
prioritize wellness
and then i'd like to see
all of us
engage our youth we should all have a
young person on our on our advisory
boards we should have young people
telling us what they want and we should
be listening to them
thank you
jamie pearson
one more time for jamie pearson that was
great it's fantastic
[Applause]