welcome guys
um
yeah just uh i just want to give a big
round of applause to icbc i mean it
blows my mind that we can all sit in
this room and talk about weed you know
i come from a developing market from
south africa and it's still fairly new
to us in terms of the commercial space
but um
it's just fantastic to be able to be
with like-minded people who are really
trying to change the world let's not
forget that cannabis has the potential
to have a seismic impact on the world we
live in which is not in a good space
right now so we all carry a great
responsibility to try and make sure it's
as clean effective as possible and can
help move our planet forward so just uh
i'm going to very briefly introduce
myself um i head up chiba africa we are
africa's first cannabis education and
trading company i also run a consultancy
uh very involved in trying to push the
whole market forward you know we've run
to the 45 50 webinars in two years and
so we're quite at the front of the media
so i represent obviously south africa
and from that perspective we'll be
sharing some of the insights into what's
happening in our territory but before we
start i just want everyone to introduce
themselves so they're going to choose
and give us a quick quick snippet of
what's happening in your land right now
over to you well hello to everyone i am
daniel guesta i am a lawyer from uruguay
south america
and my expertise is in licensing
authorization and
corporate matters for companies
and also ipos contract and all that
i have also
collaborated with the government my
government in
drafting some regulations
so i'm here to speak about uruguay and
the south american market
cool elizabeth
hi i'm elizabeth
i'm from australia um
ceo and founder of lincan group and i'm
here representing australia specifically
medicinal cannabis industry australia
and austrade and
big gov so
lovely to talk to you and have the
opportunity to talk about the amazing
opportunities we have in australia
good afternoon everyone my name is
carmen darin i'm the ceo of helios
therapeutics new zealand's largest
vertically integrated licensed cannabis
producer
i'm here to share our stories from new
zealand
helios is a medicines company we
achieved our eugmp certificate in 2021
and entered the market a few months
later and we're here as well to bring
new zealand cannabis to the world
thanks for that um before our next guest
speaks um i would just like to give
thailand a round of applause for
everything they're doing at the moment
[Applause]
at the moment how you guys have just
completely embraced cannabis and just
taken the world by storm so well done i
look forward to hearing more about the
market but please introduce yourself
hi
my name is
i come from thailand
i am ceo in the iftc
thank you
hi
[Applause]
we are affiliates and you probably
learned that beginning of last month he
kind of delist
cannabis from the narcotic act
so he's created a new poll right now
so it's
you know become
a lot of smart
so now people can
can do whatever they want in about
canadians right now
but we are working on the new act is
under a draft period
he is one of the members of the
committee
so
within 30 days from now i think the bnu
act to control the cannabis
all right
thanks y'all it's fantastic everybody
embrace this
um i want to just get a quick snapshot
of how everybody's territory works uh
one of the things i when i first got
asked to facilitate this panel on
developing
cannabis industries i was expecting it
to be the uruguays and thailand and
mexico's unfortunately
ralph could not make this session from
mexico which is uh unfortunate but i
kind of perceived it to be
all the developing economies not putting
two together that you know from
developed economies but still developing
cannabis industries so just quickly from
a south african perspective at the
moment uh we can uh you can grow medical
cannabis for exports we have a very very
small
local patient market that's developing
through what's called a section 21
and then from 2018 you you're allowed to
grow and cultivate cannabis for personal
consumption
you also have a cannabis club on
but our legislation is a bit all over
the place and we're kind of trying to
figure it out as we go along
but from a commercial perspective you
know for those of you don't know south
africa has a very uh deep pedigree with
growing cannabis we've been growing it
for hundreds of years we're one of the
biggest exporters already on cannabis
very similar to mexico we've been
exporting illegally into europe just the
same as south america has been reporting
into north america and there's a lot of
conversations around south america
becoming a sort of official great basket
of cannabis into north america and
likewise africa to europe you know just
because of our growing conditions um and
the whole number of things we've
unpacked so that's kind of the stages in
our country at the moment so you know we
are here for business if anyone wants to
buy any weed come and speak to me um but
i want to just get a bit of
understanding of where the legal
framework is in uruguay at the moment
because you guys obviously were right in
front of opening legislation what's the
current status
of course thanks trenton um
let's see uruguay was the first
country worldwide
to legalize the cannabis for all areas
when in
several areas is recreational medicinal
and hemp
a legalizing the economies for
recreational purposes for uruguay
for being a small country between
argentina and brazil with just 3.5
million population
it was very difficult yes and
it was very encouraged from that in that
moment from the
development
we were called pirates from the
international country board
that was it's an interesting
story
but uh moved forward and has developed a
three ways of access to recreational
academies
that are
very
democratic
because you have the self cultivators
you have the clubs
and you also can purchase in the
pharmacies yes so you have the whole
spectrum of possibilities for you to
access through to canons also
you can grow cannabis for medicinal
purposes
where there you can make a thc with high
level flowers of course if you want to
export you have to be certified
you can make extracts pharmaceutical
products and there is also a hemp market
yes and production
of course as a literal country all the
companies have the aim to export
so all the companies are focused in
export
so
exporting to to europe
us but also south america because south
america it's a
440 million people in south america and
uruguay
is ahab yes it's between argentina and
brazil and gives companies a lot of
possibilities for that
it's very progressive that you've
managed to cover all the models so that
you know you've got this adult use
market as well thanks for sharing um
talk about australia we hear lots of
good things i mean i heard there were
200 000 patients a few weeks ago and now
you said there's almost 300 000 patients
you guys are moving very fast yeah
thanks so um it's a number of scripts so
the the
statistics that we're getting from the
therapeutic goods administration and the
office of drug control around the number
of scripts that have been written to
date or authorizations and
while we've had a bit of a movement from
people on special access moving across
to authorized prescriber in recent
months as that became easier something
with gp's under authorized prescriber
prescribing the total number of scripts
is heading towards 300 000. now
australia had a very slow start from
2016 when medicinal was legalized uh it
really was only towards the end of 2019
that we started to see a real change in
prescription patterns and authorizations
being improved and a huge amount of that
work comes down to
organizations especially like the
medicinal cannabis industry australia
which is the representative body for the
industry that just works so hard to
develop a relationship with the office
of drug control and the tga
to ensure that really sensible
legislation got through and that
we really would discuss with the office
of drug control the impact of that
legislation unintended consequences and
our industry had more knowledge about
cannabis than the office of drug control
did you know we were all out there
working with with the plants and working
with design so that really helped us to
then see a shift in
legislation
and a reduction in red tape for patients
and so from really late 2019 we've seen
a continual acceleration of prescription
much more ease of getting products for
patients
much greater volumes of product and
therefore the prices come down and this
is the thing that i think many other
jurisdictions can learn from australia's
you know 25 million people we're not a
massive population a really big country
but what we've been able to do by having
a steady consistent and evolving
evidence-based
regime
we've enabled the price to come down
more people to get access now it's not
perfect we've got a long way to go
but i spend a lot of time
in europe now and when i see the
struggles that are happening in the uk
where there's sort of nonsensical
application of legislation compared to
what we've been doing in australia
i'm actually super proud of our country
and i think the other thing that's been
useful is that we've aimed to establish
a strong
industry that could produce high quality
gmp product because that's the standard
required
and therefore we can export that high
quality product we're now getting the
volumes and the scale to make the
product cheaper
and we're also then investing in
research and that's really important so
australia has a very good research
environment we have fantastic
opportunities through r d credits and
and
refunds so it's actual cash in your hand
as a company that money you've put into
research you get a large chunk of that
back which you can then reinvest into
research so we have a lot of clinical
trials
that's what doctors are requiring and i
think that's the strength of
our environment and then there's
industrial hemp which doesn't have any
access to licensing for cbd cbd strictly
strictly within medicinal
it sounds like you've advanced really
quickly i'm interested to know more
about the local market versus export
we'll get to that in a second uh tell us
about your land what's happening that
side yeah so in new zealand the
medicinal cannabis scheme came in in
april of 2020 with a 18-month transition
period for
importers and local producers to be able
to meet the requirements
so
for producers in new zealand you need to
meet the gmp requirements
our gmp certificates are mutually
recognised as eugmp
you also need to hold a medicinal
cannabis
license as well for the steps in the
process where you're producing or doing
doing that research
new zealand is a small country we have
five million people our patient
population is growing quickly
so
we've seen a patient population of 30
000 and growing to 50 000 in the coming
year
so we're seeing month on month
uh six percent growth in patient numbers
so it's small when we compare that
patient growth trajectory to australia
which is a few years ahead of us the
trajectory is really similar so we look
from new zealand to australia to see how
the market is developing but also look
at what is happening around the world
and i think that while we are one of the
newest countries to enter into the
medicinal cannabis scheme there's a lot
of learnings we've been able to take
from
other markets around the world bringing
some of that talent into new zealand to
support our new zealand market and our
ramp up and that's been a really great
way to accelerate
um interesting thank you for sharing um
in terms of your your plans in thailand
is there is there a real focus on export
or are you trying to stimulate the local
market first what's what's your strategy
obviously you flooded the market plants
really kind of opened things up is there
a long-term strategy is export a big big
thing for thailand
yes uh
basically we are growers so
we
grow a lot of
candies in thailand
we did for have been doing that for a
year right now
so right now the
primary market is local
the buyer is the public hospitals
we haven't done anything in
recreation recreation yet
and we don't plan to i mean our company
so we're strictly
moving into uh medical cannabis
of course uh export is our
next top hit
but we are looking so
we need gscp we need gmp and so on and
so forth in order to export
we're working on that right now so gacp
should be around the corner
we've done sop already
so
i would say probably
will be in this year
and the next step will be eugmp
add a little bit because you talk about
the medical cannabis
we in thailand we have one department
for you know that goldman has for a long
time
they
use herbs
as medicine
so now cannabis
is one under the
the kind of herbs
we have a significant amount of
doctors
who use or utilize those
medicines
number of cannabis patients
still very low i think
a few thousand will be
but
hopefully that will grow up
in terms of your export markets so you
know from an african perspective we're
focused on europe south america is very
much about
the northern part of the hemisphere do
you guys have a specific region that
you're focused on trying to export your
cannabis into a particular place that
you've gotten by
um obviously europe yes because it's a
growing market
our advantage will be our cost
we
presented yesterday in the investor
group
i think our operation cost is about five
usn per
gram dry flour
so that's very low this is indoor okay
the main reason because of the
relies on the equator
so a lot of effort then just like
temperature like some nights
our daily sunlight is about nine hours
so you're talking about 12 12 is that's
three hour difference something like
that so we yes we move into
uh
target of europe we i don't think you
can export to u.s right now
so you the european market will be our
first goal yeah i heard yesterday you
said that you know one of your usps is
you have lots of sunshine and cheap
labor and i was like that's the same
thing we say yes i think so there's
obviously the competitive space that we
we need to and i want to talk about usps
across each territory in a second um
elizabeth just give me some insight into
is australia open for i mean i know we
are from south africa perspective
already exporting into australia um but
and you mentioned before we came on
stage that there is there's been a big
import market but now as the local
market is coming online there seems to
be a balance do you think that
eventually australia will have the
capacity to create all their own
medicinal cannabis or is there still a
market for developing countries
so looking at the licenses and the
production capacity then yes over time
if all of the licensed uh square
meterage gets built out then australia
absolutely would have the ability to
produce all of its own domestic animals
and also export so just to know a lot of
people don't realize that australia is
the largest exporter into the uk and
into germany so large amounts of
medicinal cannabis come from australia
and it's because it's gmp
it's ready to go
the certification process is
the same the standards are the same
they're recognized we don't have to have
german inspectors come out to australia
because they trust the inspectors that
we have in australia already so that's a
real advantage and we're seeing a lot of
diversification into dose forms because
there's so much research one of the ways
that companies because in australia you
can't advertise your medicinal cannabis
to patients
you
the differentiation is coming through
unique dose forms
rather than you know kind of branding
and
important feel
and so we're getting a lot of innovation
and because of our really good um r d
tax system
that means that you get a much better
return for your investment dollar in
australia than in many other places in
the world and you guys are importing a
lot of um you know gacp cannabis and
flipping it into gmp because uh you know
for for developing developing economies
if you look at eu gnp it's completely
out of our spectrum it doesn't make any
financial sense
so so that has been to start with so if
you can imagine when australia first
opened up medicinal cannabis there
weren't you know it's going to take two
three years before anyone would have a
license and be producing and so the
government allowed imported products to
not have to meet all the arms of the
therapeutic goods order 93 and 100 and
so you had products that were being made
under gpp or gacp in other parts of the
world coming in to meet that unmet need
but we're getting close to a position
now where that's not necessary and so um
the federal government announced um a
couple of months ago that from
july 2023 all products entering
australian month must meet the same
standards as products made in australia
so there'll be no more of this slipping
product in that is
made at a lower standard and then
upgrading it in australia or packaging
it or whatever to make it gmp
and that's really important because one
of the things in australia sets itself
apart not just in cannabis but if we
talk about food or we talk about other
medications
it's that you know uh ability to have
very high quality trusted products so
when other food products and medicines
going to asia or europe coming from
australia they're well regarded and what
we don't want to be seen as a place
where you could repackage things to make
them look gmp and get them out into
another market that's a shame we're
quite enjoying our relationship with you
so i'm so sorry
but fair enough you know i mean what it
means is developing economies that are
trying to get flower or whatever it is
art need to just up our game
um in terms of uh your do you have a
specific target region that you're
trying to push your canvas into and how
is that going well uruguay actually is
exporting
it's exporting to germany portugal
israel
and in hemp also it's exporting to
switzerland and started this year
exporting to ecuador
so mainly uh is focused as a
country with just 3.5 million is focused
on an export
and as a very qualified workforce
and it has companies with the
certification and
it's
it has done all the homework yes to have
a good product
but this is
the aim of all companies is export
do you think you know there have been
talks in certain regions of quotas that
are being said because obviously to some
degree you know as countries we protect
ourselves you know i mean there's no way
you're ever going to export into canada
right now you know they've got like tons
of stuff sitting around so do you think
that we're going to have to this
developing country is going to have to
really fight for our place um in these
uh these developed markets which
obviously are a lot more lucrative than
the last
historically has been an exporter of
commodities yes
and
we are seeing that in this case it's
happening more or
less same is exporting raw materials and
will be reporting finding finest product
yet also has developed pharmaceutical
products yes
but
in that way
we see that the euro will remove for for
for that for exporting raw materials
flowers
and
all of that for the countries and we
have a
we have potential to fight with the big
ones yes because i was saying that we
were the first one
so we have learned a lot in the way
yes and we see some countries that are
going back and forth yes with its
regulation and ui has
manually made
the homework very well in
that
my opinion
so
we have all in place to to to compete
with the business we've really
capitalized on your first group of
advantage i think it's very important to
know it was in the suture two weeks ago
which uh
as uh our american friends call it and
uh i was with governments and they were
just saying that they were first markets
in africa uh there was a huge buzz about
lesotho there's some amazing growing
conditions etc but then they didn't
capitalize on it at all so they've
completely fallen at the back of the
queue and they're trying to figure out
how they're back there so it is it does
take sort of a certain amount of
aggressive business to get out there and
build those channels and you guys always
had a great fun way to do that yes
of course the company always the
companies want to move faster yes
but
there will be regulation and the market
has moved maybe
not as fast that the companies expected
but safety that is very important
thank you carmen is there a market for
other countries to be shipping products
into new zealand or you're going to get
all from australia
so
in new zealand we do have some imported
products at the moment
those imported products actually are
much more expensive than the locally
produced products so prices
i
couldn't possibly comment
we'll take that as a yes okay so one of
the one of the earliest goals when we
entered market was to improve access and
affordability and we've been able to do
that compared to the imported products
which we're really proud of for our
patients
um but yeah there is an opportunity to
import into new zealand
our standards are relatively high from
those that have been trying to import
products already uh products that are
being accepted in australia or in
germany haven't been accepted yet in new
zealand
uh so it is something to look into and
really understand those regulations if
you did want to import
thanks
uh in terms of the thai markets i mean
you know you guys talk about medicinal
and that's obviously a focus
we all know that you know it's been
completely mind-blowing to be honest i
was at mary jane a few days ago and how
this cbd flower market has just
completely exploded you know with a very
well crafted flower
hash
and i'm also gathering that it's an
entry point so that most people do want
to go thc the reality is that we all
talk about medical cannabis but we know
the recreational market is huge and is
going to be massive you know um have you
guys considered that that there will be
a recreational market in thailand if
you've got models you know have you
looked at the club model like so so the
responsible apple use is there any
narrative around that at the moment or
are you just focusing on on medical
for company we're just focusing on the
medical
but for the country
i cannot
really
give you the
perfect answer
but for my opinion right now
this
is from this psychology
[Music]
so they will probably
already approve for the
medical cannabis
um
okay
so that's that's that's what i'm
explaining to you
on top of that what what internal
markets i think we
expect a lot of countries in asia
that will open for medical cannabis but
not open for growing
in the near future and that's a big
market for example like japan
and china
they have a movement to allow a patient
to use cannabis but not growing so
that's a big big opportunity for us to
move into it
and what do you think your your unique
selling point what are the advantages so
if you have to stand there with a whole
lot of other countries why should the
cannabis industry be interested in
catholics about product what are the
reasons how would you sell cannabis to
the to the general world
well i i think
i still
look at cannabis as a normal business
it's not totally different from other
businesses
according to my my opinion
so
first of all the quality of the product
we
doesn't have to grow
international strength
we have our own uh strain address yeah
and and
that
very high txt also
so we're talking about 20 25
if we do it properly
so that's how
our advantage
the second one is cost
so if you have good product with a lower
cost you can save anything
yeah absolutely i mean that's been the
word on everyone's lips is the cost you
know yeah and you guys obviously have
the sun so you can grow outdoor or
hybrid tunnels which is a lot more cost
effective um what are you guys growing
predominantly outdoors
no no for medicinal purposes it's a
greenhouse or indoor the
two possibilities you can grow also
outdoor but the companies have decided
to use that two months so what are some
of your u.s pieces of territory why
should you care about cannabis with your
mind well first of all
uruguay
is a hub it's between argentina and
brazil so if you want to enter a south
america yes as i said a continent of 440
million people yes you're why it's a
very good option first of all
second it's a
country that in south america has a
stability institution and it's more
important it's the
the country with less corruption
levels
and it has the investment grade but it's
also very important
also gives tax exemptions for the
company and have for the companies and
has qualified workforce and is the
second country worldwide yes in
renewable energies
and we also have the government
supporting yes our sector
in fact they would stand here the
uruguayan government yes they stand in
this expo to
invite investors to come to ui and
producing in europe
tell me when we come we talk about
developing economies we often talk about
the financial benefit of cannabis to the
people on the ground uh it's a big
challenge in south africa at the moment
you know we have um we have farmers that
have been growing campus for hundreds of
years who are still criminals who have
been growing cannabis to feed their kids
and to send their kids to school
who are to serve our technically
criminals and then we have big farms
that have a lot of capital invested into
them who can grow cannabis legally who
are not criminals so we have this
complete justice position between you
know the people who have actually put
cannabis on the map and are still unable
to do that so our licensing situation is
very very complex
does the uruguayan government recognize
that cannabis needs to be able to filter
down to build the economy and to also
filter down to the lower levels of the
economic spectrum or is it just really
focused on bringing as much cash in as
possible no no
[Music]
from
the
2013 14 and 15 and over i would say
a has seen the the kind of sector as an
industry yes that
brings possibilities for
all the spectrums of the society not
only for the big companies yes you have
also
a
two or three accuracy for example family
owners yes that invested 20 30 000
for
cbd flowers for example for for
exporting that's accessible exactly yes
well what about in thailand no i mean
you do you have a strong
mandate from government to make sure
that the people on the ground also
benefit from cannabis
yes they do um
i would like to classify it to treat
categories right
so one is a major player big player like
what we are doing
and the second one is the
they allow any household
to grow up to 10
plants
per household
but again you guys know better than the
growing cannabis to have flowers not
easy at all
so
in real life i don't know that they can
do commercially
you know and what can they do with those
ten classes they can do they can do
whatever they want to sell it they can
they cannot sell it they can consume it
okay
um and then there's a
gap in between which is the like the
underground who used to
have experiences to grow and now they
are legal
so that that can be like sme for me
you know who
who grow cannabis
a small amount but they can they know
exactly how to do it and
and sell it so we have three categories
right now so it is filtering down and
trickling down those opportunities
government even
announced to give away a million plants
[Applause]
where did you get a million clocks
because the government yeah nicole no
they they have seeds
but again it's fantastic as you guys
know growing cannabis is not easy so it
depends on but be interested to see how
many of those million plants actually
survive and go to flowers
[Music]
you guys are in completely different
economies so i guess the narrative
around the bottom layers of people is
not such so prevalent but but is there
access is it an exclusive kind of
industry where you need lots of dollar
to get in or or can you find that
there's a general sort of access people
have access generally so from the
industry the commercial perspective yes
this is an industry that requires uh
expertise
understanding of both agriculture and
gmp
and the costs of facilities uh you know
are very pricey um and then they're
long-term investments um the one thing i
will say uh from australia is that under
our constitution
uh things like personal use of something
like cannabis actually falls under state
legislation isn't in the remit of the
federal government and any time that
representatives federal government are
asked about this they'll say well it's a
matter for the states and so we've seen
the ict
has
legalized personal use personal growing
of cannabis for personal use they've
legalised that
a number of states have decriminalized
and i think
last week or might be this week in
western australia they're having a
debate about it in parliament
and so there is that kind of harm
minimization
and
um
kind of recognition of
kind of the ubiquity of cannabis within
australian society i think we actually
have almost the highest personal usage
of cannabis of anywhere in the world
um so you know a bunch of stones
well i i
i can't comment but you know maybe maybe
that's why we're so easygoing
[Music]
but from the from the medicinal
perspective um you know even our
supplement industry you know has very
high standards and so our nutraceuticals
and our food supplements
uh vitamins and minerals are always
produced are really high standard and
they're recognized around the world as
being you know really high quality
products and so
from when the law was changed the law
was changed because there were patients
in need who were dying or in severe pain
really suffering and their families got
together to really lobby the government
and got into the media and so we always
remember in australia that
we were begun by patients and
the whole idea of strengthening the
australian industry is to get that price
down and certainly why i started my
company was to do whatever i could to
help the industry to get to a place
where it could compete with the
non-regulated market and the floor price
for
licensed medicinal cannabis in australia
is now the same as the
price of the black market
so i think we've done extremely well
there now there are more expensive
products there's a whole spectrum but i
think we have almost the widest choice
of products in medicinal
medicinal varieties that don't when we
don't have a commercial recreational
market so there's a lot of choice for
patients lots of different ways they can
take the product
it's becoming much more personalized and
we're starting to see interest now some
of the work that um the medicinal campus
industry australia's been doing has been
to reach out through healthcare
practitioner and patient groups
to talk to the colleges of general
practice and specialist colleges and
we're starting to now see movements
towards education being developed by the
colleges specific to medicinal cannabis
and that's going to that's really what
we're going to see a lot more doctors
feeling comfortable prescribing
obviously you've always got the bleeding
edge doctors and the leading edge
doctors
but the more mainstream doctors will
require that education and so that's a
real focus of the industry
and the industries organizations and the
various patient groups in australia to
get really well educated doctors at the
end of cannabinoid system recognized you
know within teaching schools and and
continuing education programs i think
that's essential everywhere but it's
part of the evolution as the market
matures
and you know at first australia was
pretty much just all oils and sublingual
oils
now there's you know i think 140
different
methods of taking the product in
australia and we've also shifted from
being predominantly processed products
now to um high quality flower products
um taking more and more of the market
share
thanks for sharing that um in terms of
new zealand there are
in developing economies you've got lots
of parallel industries you know so if
you've got a developed pharmaceutical
industry or an agricultural industry
it's a lot easier to pivot and bring on
these new sort of uh
areas um how does that mean an advantage
in new zealand people capitalize on that
as an advantage yeah one thing that's
great about new zealand is that we have
a really really strong horticulture and
agriculture background
we have a lot of innovation in this
space that is being able to come across
from other crops so from kiwi fruit from
pinus radiata around tissue culture
around light treatments
so we're able to use that right now
as we're entering into the industry i
think that collaboration and that
opportunity is really exciting for what
we're building in new zealand and a key
way of us being able to accelerate our
pathway
one of the other things that you were
speaking out about before as well is
just that licensing
raging and how it filters down through
so we have some of the
larger companies like helios um
which are vertically integrated but
there is also over 40 cultivation
licenses in new zealand
and that can range from very large
cultivation spaces like we have a
strategic partnership with puro
who grow on the beautiful kaikoura coast
two very small boutique
cultivators
and we partner at helios with some of
those small boutique cultivators for
their
biomass which we then take through our
extraction process to get the unique
terpene and full spectrum profile
so i really like the fact that we're
able to work with small boutique
cultivators large cultivators we also
have our indoor growing space
at the site that we can use for high
quality dried flower so a real range and
a lot of that through the collaboration
and the focus on innovation in
horticulture using existing
infrastructures essentially
yeah absolutely existing infrastructure
also existing research at the
universities so we have some strong
agricultural
universities that are doing research in
this space that
can see the opportunity for the industry
for students who are graduating and so
those students are doing research and
then feeding
not only our product pipeline but also
our talent pipeline as the industry
matures
thanks for that i mean in terms of the
the thai market you've obviously got
certain industries that are more
developed than others
have you identified industries within
thailand that you think will embrace and
help the cannabis industry move forward
you know whether in pharmaceutical or
agricultural or you know product
development
right now there's a few big projects
going around
which i can
give you information for
some of them one of one of them who
plan to use
part of cannabis plants
to be become a chicken food
they have research in thailand and they
found that chicken after they have
that probably cannabis leaf
the chicken
become more calm and lay eggs
so that would be
the other one also comes from the huge
company
they plan to open satellite cleaning
using canopies
that's why i love it so much i mean they
plan to
become using like csr for the one who
cannot you know afford for price
that's a good project moving on also
and i i think i agree with her that
to educate market is very important
not only in school but you know
country-wide because
i almost believe that in any every
country when you announce
legalized cannabis they'll be pro-income
i mean against
a lot of people will say no
but if we can educate market and let
them
realize the benefit of
this
education and educate markets
[Music]
um thanks for that i just wanted to
quickly uh i want to take some questions
out of the time i just wanted to quickly
go through the the panel um where is
industrial impact in your territory
[Music]
are you growing industry
yes
an industrial hemp actually is grown for
cbd flowers yes and the market for the
grain is under development there are two
or three projects big projects under
development but the industry of camp has
developed
in the market of the city
australia
yeah we have a strong industrial hemp
sector in 2018 australia new zealand
under the food standards australian new
zealand act
allowed
hemp seeds to become a food
and
that means that you know health food
stores have all sorts of hemp products
we don't have an mcbd
market cbd is either a schedule 3 or
schedule 4 product in australia but the
separation's actually worked really well
because there's been no confusion for
hemp farmers they know they're building
either for industrial purposes or for
food or for food for animals or for
human consumption fibre fabric etc um
and so there's been the farmers haven't
kind of been lured by the promise of cbd
flower and then forgotten all the
fantastic environmental benefits of
industrial have
yeah absolutely and
yeah so in new zealand um industrial
hemp is available for food and fibre
yeah
that's good to hear we do have him also
yes okay
what's the focus for him today is it
textile because obviously you've got a
good industry style um
maybe it takes time right now yes yeah
because i mean you know we obviously
will talk about the sort of you know thc
cannabis which is more the sexy side you
know but at the end of the day you know
what as i started to learn more about
hemp a few years ago the the the ability
for all the the capacity for him to have
us a positive impact on our environment
is completely mind-blowing
so we all we often get stuck in the in
the high thc conversation but i started
to touch and see where each territory is
at so it's really encouraging to hear
that there is hemp running in parallel
to that guys we've got five minutes left
so if there are any questions
if you could put your hands up and this
gentleman here will bring you a
microphone
going once any questions there we go
there's a gentleman over
thank you so much i'm dr shakesha campus
condition from south africa well done
friends and my brother
and for the panel so my question is
there's an emerging markets guys what
are your views
on regulating the plants okay so we
don't regulate poppy and we make more
feed that can kill people
we don't regulate tobacco and we don't
tell the doctors don't tell your
patients how many cigarettes to smoke
but we don't regulate that either i just
want to know as coming into the industry
what are your views on regulating the
plant instead of the end products are we
looking at changing the narrative and
looking at things differently i just
want to understand what your views are
thank you
do you want to start yeah so in
australia we do regulate the plants so
we do regulate poppy and we do regulate
tobacco so we don't just regulate the
end product so australia was a big
producer of
opiates at least the the apis that went
on to be become other things
and especially down in places like
tasmania and so
it is a controlled crop so it's not that
there weren't any regulations the other
thing too is that when you look at
a poppy um it's not so easy to take that
popping yourself in in your kitchen and
turn it into a drug and most people who
do die
and so it's quite different to the
ubiquity of the uses of the plant
growing in the fields and growing in
someone's backyard
but
taking off my australian hat and looking
at you know from my international
relations background harmonisation is
really important and the use of
regulation to impoverish and imprison
people is a global shame
of this period and we need to do
everything we can to remediate that
situation and also to to ensure that we
don't put people into health poverty
that's one of i was born with a really
rare disease my parents sold everything
to keep me alive
and so i'm here again 57 years of age
when my parents were told
at two that i was going to die and there
was nothing that could be done and they
spent every cent they had ever since
they saved every cent they could borrow
and took me to italy to get surgery that
saved my life and then at 12 i had four
strokes and they were told again so
for me health poverty is an enormous
issue
and it's not you can't fix that by
saying grow your own plant because
families with very ill children
can't make the medicine that their
children need in most cases not all
cases
they need to trust supply that's high
quality
that is consistent that they can trust
that is and that isn't going to bankrupt
them so that's why i got into this and i
i know a lot of the other ceos in
australia and they all have similar
stories of family members and and really
compassionate reasons why they got
involved thanks for sharing that story
um it's uh it's very interesting how
many people are in the campus industry
who have stories to tell ultimately and
what's incredibly important prohibition
partners uh the recent global report
they put out and we were quite
disappointed because africa got quite a
small mention but one of the things they
talked about was the fact that
the african uh markets are purely
focused on export um so getting our
medicine to other people but not looking
after our own people uh and you're quite
right i mean if you look at the cbd
market it's completely for our populist
unaffordable you know it's a tiny tiny
segment of population
and i think that is a massive massive
issue the other thing is about
regulating when you regulate in an
advent developed economy you know
there's an argument to be said that you
don't regulate your cultivation in
regulator processing and distribution
you know because we've been trying to
stop people growing in their backyards
for decades and decades and never worked
so there's all these models that i think
are needed
in different countries for different uh
different different dynamics you know uh
any other questions i think we can
probably tell you one more yes sir
darren get in here
hear me
um
or i can speak with that
i can hear him now
how do you hear me i'm darren edmond
here from africa as well
thank you very much for a great panel
jordan good to see you again thank you
great job i love you candace um
my question is actually for you or my
comment um you said something called my
attention in reference to
can you unpack that a little bit more so
so ultimately one of the usps of a a
developing economy that has good
sunshine is obviously our light you know
so if we if we start to grow indoor
uh the cost of processing is is
similar to growing in canada or europe
you know because it's indoor uh yes we
have low low cost in electricity and low
labor costs um but as efficiency in the
international market increases and the
cost per gram comes down because of
economies of scale et cetera
the opportunity to compete price point
wise on an eu gmp level is i don't
believe it's long-term sustainable we
need to i believe in our territory to
grow medical cannabis that growing
tunnels hybrid tunnels is the best way
forward because you get utilization of
the sun but you also will growing in a
controlled environment so i think that's
one of the biggest challenges is we only
can't sell light for light we need to
look at the strategic advantages we have
from our territory from our sunlight
and all those other elements we need to
figure out what the best thing is the
other problem at the moment
from a south african perspective is the
tail wagging the dog so we are being
dictated and converted to commerce by
the international markets who want a
particular thc level or particular
strains growth so i would like to see
developing markets you know like
yourself as uh being able to come to
events like this and go this is what we
grow this is how we grow this is our
cost per gram and and sell the cameras
based on what we are developing as
opposed to being told
the other fear we have is you know
exporting raw products uh and then
importing product back into our
economies which we've been doing for
decades especially in africa you know
and that just can't happen because that
makes no commercial sense so i hope that
answers your question
all right i think you have time for one
more question
one more question guys one more question
anyone have any hands up
no all right everyone
[Music]
[Applause]