hi everyone and welcome to the
successful investors financing european
and international project funnel um my
name is david templeton and it's a
pleasure to be joined in today my
four real sector leading experts in the
financial ecosystem who i think all have
really unique and international
perspectives to share today
um in today's panel we're going to be
covering the current investment
opportunities in europe
we're going to be taking a look at the
sort of professional investors that are
actually active in the sector at the
minute and then also diving into some of
the
blockers and hurdles that we need to
overcome to get wider kind of adoption
um
and now that's kind of hand over to our
parliament
introduction to themselves before we
kick off
so my name is marcus mozar i'm
around 25 years in the financial sector
i started from university as an analyst
and then i was running for 12 years fund
for banks in switzerland germany and
luxembourg
and the last 50 years i concentrated
mostly on metal resources in the last
two years because of lockdown i looked
for new industry so i looked over
cryptocurrencies and canadians and then
i found out that cryptocurrency is a bit
too complicated
and greatest is more easy because you
can
consume it
you can
touch it and
then the last two years i spent
exploring
companies investors mostly in europe and
yeah that's the reason i'm here
fantastic
um and i'm as as mentioned i'm a
consultant at henry we are europe
leading canvas sector advisory fund we
specialize in new market entry import
for an investment strategy offering
licensing support to our clients and
also helping them to build their brands
and supply chains across europe
um this topic particularly is really
well for us through first wednesdays
we've recently published a report
opportunities in history in europe so if
you'd like to dive into the data and
some of the interviews and case studies
you can
[Music]
i'm download
thank you my name is
i'm mostly known in the industry for my
previous job at lgbt but now i'm working
as vice president of investment analysis
at seed innovations and we are london in
any stock exchange for the investment
fund we are probably the largest
european investment fund in the sector
judging by the amount of investment and
particularly
[Music]
good day everybody my name is matthias
meiner
thank you for having me i'm the chief
financial officer of canterbury
we are a
division of vienna based ring
international holding
i've been in the cannabis space for
three years and we're running a cbd
operation in
europe
that is
austria out of which we're catering to
the european market and we're running
canvas operations in canada
catering to the canadian brand market
and the german medical market out of
that
hello together my name is
[Music]
first i would like to say thank you for
having me on that tremendous time here
together with alfredo matthias
and thank you also for calling me an
expert at something because that's just
cool and
we go as a company um focus on medicine
accounts and we are rationally active
currently in the united states of
america
denmark and germany and since the
beginning of this year we expand our
activities
and invest currently in switzerland
[Music]
fantastic thanks guys
so the first kind of topic that i think
would be really interesting to dive into
is the current actual opportunities to
invest in european cannabis companies i
mean the focus to date has often been on
north americans especially in terms of
uh publicly traded companies but we've
really really seen the last few years
that i think the parliament will test
a lot of interesting opportunities now
coming in for european players and
european investors
markets i guess from you
[Music]
generally open and
maybe i mentioned that last year i did
the large research about european
canadian startups mainly in the
german-speaking countries germany
switzerland and austria
and the big private equity company as in
selling dutch in the world was looking
for opportunities in the canadian space
it was very difficult for me to find
the companies
which still to them because most of the
companies are too small and for myself i
don't care about the size but most
investors looking at companies who have
already a certain turnover
as earnings some positive numbers and i
think that's a bit difficult at the
moment to find because we are very early
spanish i invested personally a couple
of weeks ago in a tissue cultural
property out of canada they do mostly
business in u.s in my idea is to bring
them over to europe because it's a new
technology and tissue culturally i think
it's a very interesting field
for sure does anyone ask any thoughts
any specific areas that you think are
particularly interesting and the work
people keep an eye out for
answering your first question as well um
we tried to have a balanced portfolio of
liquid and non-liquid assets so we've
invested for example in youtube which is
listed particularly in connection with
the position of the economy subsidiary
in denmark and then we also have more
like vc type of fields we recently
invested in an equal amount in europe's
farmer here in germany
and in terms of restrictions i think
it's important to mention being a uk
regulated fund we can't invest in the
recreation sectors that's obviously the
implementation that we have
other than that we are open for
opportunities of course but i would say
that at these moments in 2001
uh
[Music]
yeah for sure and i think revenues are
something that we haven't always seen
today but we are finally now seeing
players coming in and really getting
those weapons up
and i'm telling the only kind of
investments you're currently raising for
yourself or any kind of opportunity
and yeah i think our general
investment approach is when we look at
the canons industry everything we see
here in europe currently in germany for
example as a new and emerging and
medicine campus market is not entirely
new yet
and if we just take a look into north
america we see that there are more than
50 new restrictions basically but
legalized medicine accounts in some
shape or form in the past
so what uh what rico is doing what we
are doing and
we are operating actively in those more
mature
markets like the united states we are
in our retail operations when you guys
we are processing 16 000 patient
contacts a month
and looking into those more
new and emerging markets we are
investing the preliminary
in
infrastructure
and then basically what we are doing is
we
collect a lot of data points in the
united states and try to identify
certain parallels or patterns basically
what we then can assume
will
take place in a new and early market
like harmony
[Music]
when we identify a product or a concept
what fits those requirements
we are focusing all our efforts on
timing
to find out are we basically are we
too late for that concept are we maybe
too early
or are we maybe just exactly right
and
when all those
check boxes check and we all come to the
conclusion that it's work we work it
then we incorporate spinners in
for example in germany or denmark and
will go to them really quick to revenue
and also really track to profitability
fantastic
and matthias you've spent quite a lot of
time both in the north american and the
european sector and got to know the
investors that
do you have a lot of advice for people
the professional uh institutional
investment we have
we have a
20-year history of investing into
certain industries to grow kind of the
divisional players
and
we have a tradition of always moving
into businesses with our own funds grow
them to a certain stage and only then
reach out to the capital markets and
seek for kind of accelerated
investments
um
we've this has worked out fairly well
and successfully for the move in the
past admittedly though our past focus
has been on more
conservative and mature industries
than canada is
today we've been in canada space for
three years uh we've grown into a
reasonable size and what we consider
sustainable uh position in terms of
operation and financial performance in
our own funds and right now we're just
at a point where
looking into the capital markets uh for
potential accelerated investments we're
looking at both sides of the ocean but
in europe obviously there's a lot of
feedback that the uncertainty
concerning the regulatory framework is
made like there's no visibility it has
to revert forward
which is a key model for investors to
pass on opportunities
as a quick speaks to that go to the us
but if you go into north america we
sense this is a lot of baggage from the
first wave of the under the president
where a whole lot of cash was burned on
early stage benches that
i think just tried to become a little
too fast and
just overpaced so they are one of the
key challenges obviously is to convince
investors of your business while being a
solid one you're approaching
one and they uh
that's the key challenges that we're
facing today on either side of the ocean
great and i think there's quite a lot of
yes you mentioned european companies
being acquired by either canadian
producers or usns and
to my knowledge we were involved in the
largest transaction of our european
company being sold to the canadian lp a
couple of years ago that was the new
veda afria deal we were early investors
there and then more recently and
wildlife sciences being acquired by
curative again we were investors in our
life sciences and there was management
crossover as well i think that was
by the way these two transactions
combined were for a total of one million
which
in industry is quite meaningful and i
would say that
that signals the importance of having a
good strategic investor early
on uh that understands the industry
right because i mean it's fine obviously
it's startups fine i don't know tech
is investing in them that
is but these investors probably won't
understand the industry in the same way
specialized investor good and that may
help down the road for example
negotiating an exit opportunity with a
large canadian or u.s company which was
the case for us
[Music]
uh
um in terms of raising them with
strategic support but in terms of
understanding the business model of
things
[Music]
is understanding the possibilities for
liquidity or exit opportunities which
maybe are
being acquired by a north american
company or more recently involved in the
london ipos and for that it certainly
helps another investor that understands
the industry but not just in terms of an
exit opportunity but also in terms of
growth right um i mean we've been in the
industry in europe since
inception practically and uh part of our
our strategy as a fund is not simply to
invest money but also support our
companies and but
i mean the ecosystem is not so big in
europe everyone knows each other but
certainly helps to have an investment
and moving on to kind of the
institutional players the investment
banks and private equity funds
we've discussed a lot and we've heard
that kind of the current ticket sizes
and market caps are still quite small to
prevent people getting involved
any of you have any thoughts on what it
would take with the kind of
consolidation needed
to actually make a private
industry this year at the medical campus
industry
level this year will be below 500
million euros and yes it is lowering but
still this is very small for large
institutional investors
if you're trying to affect the largest
easy funds
i think everybody in the industry when
the financial industry is aligned that
there's no doubt that cannabis is going
to make its way
[Music]
by and large
obviously the uncertainty of the
timeline of the cannabis industry
is something that doesn't play well with
their financial models and that i think
is one of the key challenges we need to
overcome before
[Music]
yeah i also think um kind of advanced
projections per pins and decks is a
other reason to kind of back up that
you're going to become big uh we've kind
of passed the days of that so yeah don't
you kind of have any thoughts on
what kind of um
the cultural differences are between um
north americans and european companies
do you sometimes
see childhood speaking to investors
economies just because of the kind of
disconnect there and the
kind of non-land understanding
i think there's a big problem in
cultural differences because
the sinking in north america is very
different
also i think the canadians market in the
europe is different to the u.s market
and a lot of companies have come over in
the past so that europe is developing
much faster but they didn't thought
about politics and i think the legal
frame is very important that we get
faster to larger entities to larger
companies and attracting more investors
and that's a little problem because
politics are very slow
and
i think it will need times our
government i expect more merchants
also acquisitions so that larger
companies will exist and then we'll
attract also investors because if you
have a 5 million
euro
turnover or 20 billion a journal it's a
big difference and most of the investors
start from 10 million
and at the moment we have maybe a
handful of companies over 100 in europe
exactly
and then you can't have
[Music]
um yeah i think one major struggle every
investor's person who's entering the
kent's
field for the first time
is the regulatory challenge
like cannabis
for every investment experience with
cannabis it's a super high regulatory
barrier
and
regulatory and compliance has to has to
have a constitutional
uh
basically
an acceptance and priorities in these
companies
i think that's one big struggle every
new investor is facing
and when you look a little bit deeper i
think what's also a huge challenge for
the industry is that
the um the real cannabis culture or the
people who carry the real knowledge in
the industry
basically come from the cme legal
industry they live they work for over 20
years in the de facto illegal industry
so and and that that basically
made them
loyalty
secrecy
and and that is in total diametry in our
eyes towards a corporate culture where
it's about transparency quality
management
and i think that is a huge challenge
that all of us are facing in the next 10
years and we are convinced that the
companies who can
merge those titrates basically and
that they will be the most successful
operators
about that i think as these things are
improving right and yeah and you
mentioned that very well in the report
about investing in europe in the case of
the uk that the financial majority
guideline finally clarified
investors to invest in the european
industry so that was great and it
certainly boosted
the investment space in the past year or
so in you yeah for sure i think we've
had we have a lot of companies coming up
to us now and really buying the ipo and
um really kind of uh structuring their
plans for the next few years based on
the fact that they now can rest on the
as the main exchange
um i'm kind of diving
[Music]
you mentioned earlier that you're unable
to invest in recreational assets for
companies with any vocational exposure
but
when we approach investment
opportunities we have this very clear
limitation that we can't invest in
recreational even if that is federally
bigger in the country where the company
operates so let's say canada uruguay
whatever it is some people think it's
about the u.s federal illegality but now
it has nothing to do with that even if
federal illegal in germany tomorrow he
is a uk investor could invest there
because the activity would be
illegal in the uk and that is certainly
a restriction there that we have then
the lower school proceeds
is from 2008
oh yeah this is definitely a key blocker
that i've heard a lot of people saying
they're watching the recreational space
but they're unable to act and strangely
well i guess it's not really too strange
but i've also heard that a lot of cbd
companies are being affected by this as
well particularly with
but i also say that
i mean some companies don't like that
for example when we are negotiating with
them and we tell them okay but if you
were to operate in the recreational
market then you would need to exit
and then all of these components that
want to operate in the recreational
sector would be
[Applause]
[Music]
the problem is also that every company
europe has different laws and so
it's very difficult for companies you
know to go to other countries
and i also realized that investors
prefer their hometown
so french investors mainly invest in
clients germany western germany or
german-speaking countries and
that's yeah i think that
should be a bit more open and
i think the regulation
should be
similar in europe and hopefully we can
get there
for sure
yeah he reminded me of something that i
also see on companies that want to list
in a stock exchange of their country
like
stock exchange patriotism i would say
and maybe that doesn't make sense right
because we've seen that has been very
successful today at least with the ipos
so even if you're a german company it
might make more sense to list in london
than
foreign exchange and
yeah maybe a lot of this in germany
would be nice but i mean my advice is
don't think that because you are
operating in denmark a danish exchange
is the best way to go maybe i'm not
saying it it's not but not necessarily
yeah
i can ask because i have a danish client
and
they
now
think about to listen to germany because
denmark or a lot of countries are too
small and also stock shades are very
small but to go through ipo is a very
difficult process and i realized that
maybe sometimes a shell transaction or a
kind of respect deal is maybe the better
the better idea because i spoke the last
six months with five stock exchange in
germany and they're open but the
knowledge is very limited and so you
have to explain the laws and they are
not afraid you know uh to list latest
companies and we know there's a lot of
retail investors in london i don't think
anyone can guarantee to me that there's
a lot of written investors in germany
for canada
[Music]
yeah i was just thinking uh marcus
mentioned
back deals and the like
we're in an extremely young industry
it's a buzzing industry and we're just
everybody's struggling to keep up with
the pace that the industry is taking
operationally
as a businessman day-to-day business
operator
my thinking actually is i
shouldn't have to worry about complex
listening structures to circumvent
whatever burdens or hurdles we may have
along the way the industry's growing
market is growing people want the
product
all that complication around it is
kind of slowing this down a little bit
and
that's what i wish that at some point
we'll get we'll get to a level where
access to capital is
maybe a little bit more serious a little
bit more trustworthy
overcome
past
past mistakes
i'm on the regulatory financial side
i seriously wish for a little bit more
simplicity
yeah 100 percent and that's why the kind
of how to educate all of the
accommodation financially because the
stock exchanges really about us and
hopefully we are gonna be seeing um that
awareness come on over the next years
um
of regarding that emac and uh
transaction for 286 million
can you take a run at breaking down how
do you ask that valuation and are there
a certain number of like golden tokens
that a company needs to amass in order
to accelerate that value from you know
more reasonable 50 60 ml valuation
of the right price to that 286
so the short answer is i cannot speak on
details of the transaction but i would
say that for us as an investor our whole
strategy was to create
a
package i would say for a north american
company and even something ready to
potentially develop here in europe which
included a vertically integrated company
from cultivation in portugal to
practical distribution in the uk plus
other assets in germany switzerland et
cetera et cetera so i think the value
comes not from
some of the parts but from the package
that is being sold to a north american
company and the largest one in the us
that if that company were to create that
in europe it would take them very long
they would probably make
anyone else
fantastic remarks thank you
thank you um yeah thanks for all your
time today and your interest um it's
been a great time i think and yeah
really looking forward to hopefully meet
some of you after and chatting through
some of the key points from our report
and also um chat to you about one of the
yeah
[Applause]
you