so you've got an attorney and then
you've got an economist my God
okay so my name is Bo Whitney I'm going
to talk today about kind of the
economics of cannabis
um
I have a
let's see here
oh I have a presentation
there we go so I'm going to give it a
broad overview about what's going on in
the market globally the U.S just people
are always talking about the US and then
narrow it down to Europe and then uh
Germany in particular
um now a little bit about mini economics
we're a global data and research firm we
do Consulting pretty well known we have
clients all over the world we're based
out of Portland Oregon and the United
States
so as Bob mentioned there's this growing
expansive of countries that are
legalizing either hemp or adult use or
medical
this is just growing day-to-day
um a lot to keep up with
um the I think the key message here is
that even excluding him you've got a
large Market got a large number of
consumers in the way
so in terms of the U.S
so what my firm does is we gather data
on all these markets we look at Trends
we look at ramping scenarios from
country to Country state to state and
then we put out protections and so our
projection for
20 to 22 is about 29 billion dollars in
the US and it's growing up to about well
81 82 billion by 2030. now uh in the U.S
right now uh this whole covid surge in
demand is over there was a lot of
working from home or as I called it
working from Stone and they were able to
consume uh more and more because they
didn't have to go to work and so they
could work well under the influence
now that surges over and so these the
pattern the growth rates and all this
internet since are going back to the
growth rates that you saw in 2019
pre-coded and so it's kind of
normalizing where the growth really is
in the market is in these new emerging
states such as New York New Jersey uh
the the more mature markets like Oregon
Washington Colorado
that peaked their now just basically
steadiating a lot of the growth is based
upon population growth and so of new
markets are coming online
and that's where the growth is that's
where the opportunities are now not
every state has the same opportunities
of course but right now there's this
talk about will inflation in the United
States will that impact demand we're not
really seeing that we're seeing more
deflation in products that are going to
Market where we see inflation's impact
on the market it's when in the startups
so deflation product pricing
softening of demand due to coveted
returns but inflation 25 to 40 percent
inflation for construction for breaking
up in dispensaries and in in that life
so this will have an impact on
new markets like New York New Jersey
Pennsylvania and like just how much of
an impact not quite sure yet but it's
definitely a present something to be
considered
so EU so
um
like I said we've we've built this these
models there's uh the total Market
having Hangouts for a second
thanks
um the total accessible Market in in
Europe is right around 63 billion
dollars now that's illicit and legal
combined
um most of the countries are starting to
reform or they want to reform and
they're really looking at Germany to
um to be their guide throughout this
whole reform process but I think the
reform throughout Europe is inevitable
um now
who will supply into these reforming
countries while our models indicate that
the countries that are on the outside
the fringes of Europe will be the
low-cost suppliers into the European
Union once Things become regionalized
right now every country seemingly wants
to supply into Europe so you've got Asia
you've got South America you've got
Africa but there's only so much Market
to go around so
um so when you're contemplating
supplying into Europe be very very
careful about oversupply
now there's not a whole lot of data
um about the European market but there's
more and more
insistence by Regulators by members
States younger countries to start
Gathering data so that we can do a
better job of predicting what's going on
in the market
and so data is a key issue throughout
every Market signaling um in the world
um so five countries make up about 62
percent of the total demand
in Europe have listed the five countries
here Italy France Germany UK expand
but these uses remedies this total
Market is rather underreported because
there's this Latin data
so for example my firm is estimating
that there's about 37 million consumers
22 million is being reported by the
United Nations and it could be as high
as 150 million if you include a lot of
these periphery uh European countries
so pretty substantial Market it's the
second largest market
for Revenue purpose right now in the
world
however Asia and Africa have the most
consumers in the world so it's important
to make that distinction
so I want to give a little bit of time
on the training
um
that
post-legalization ramp will capture a
greater percentage of the legal demand
so
it'll capture more of the demand in
Germany than in the U.S but less in
Canada and what I mean by that is that
by mapping out these ramps and seeing
how the structures are evolving and the
like the demand is rather predictable
and the conversion from the illicit
Market consumer to Legal Market consumer
and so if you look at it just from a
first year second or third year
Germany should do a better job of
capturing the legal consumer than the
United States but Canada was really Off
to the Races and so they did a
reasonable job even though they're kind
of peaking and stalling right now and
then ultimately
um
you know where it goes in terms of
Germany and how much legal capture how
much consumer demand it will be
supported by the legal Market that will
really depend upon the rollout of the
regulatory structure and that's still on
the same flex but right now you know by
there should be about 5.4 billion
dollars in legal sales and so that's
pretty significant
um you know 2 billion or 2.1 billion by
2025. now this incorporates the delay in
the rollout that 2024 starts it seemed
we're predicting that it's going to
alter a little bit out of the day of
2024 and then really take off by 2025
but
you know 5.4 billion dollars it's a
pretty sizable market and that that's
not even including some of the demand
that's going to come in from Canada
tourism
um but the key to a successful ramp
is based upon access the more people the
more access they have in stores and
retail outlets and the like uh the
better
um and it's easier for consumers to
participate if they can go down the
street rather than drive 25 kilometers
and price price plays a real important
role in the amount of capture because if
the consumer feels as though they're
paying too much of a premium relative to
the illicit market then they just won't
participate or the level of
participation will slow down
dramatically so it's going to take a
while to ramp in Germany it always does
but then eventually and they'll gain
some traction
so you know my firm not only looks at
the ramps and that's demand looks at
jobs looks at taxes but we also have an
office on Supply
and I think one of the often overlooked
parts of regulatory deployments is
sizing the supply appropriately it's
been mentioned multiple times today that
the supply is actually too little even
to support the medical
marketonius Market but based on the
total addressable Market that's solicit
and legal the total Supply that's
required
is about 950
000 kilos that's
you know hundreds of metric tons versus
the 10 to 25 that are in place right now
so as it comes to
regulatory deployments it's really
critical to make sure that
the the country stays ahead of the
supplies so that it doesn't constrain
the market unnecessarily
and so if you under Supply
it can really harm the market by keeping
prices too high because it's supply and
demand
if you over Supply prices crash and then
it doesn't help anybody that tax
revenues are
sub-optimal the profitability of
companies sub-optimal and so it's really
important to strike that balance now my
models can predict at any given stage
how much Supply you need to support the
demand and support the rent so you don't
need to supply all of this Supply
immediately you have to just you know
grow as the market grows evolve as the
market evolves
and so and I don't think there's ever
been projections and requirements uh
presented on the German Market
especially going out to 2025 2030 so you
know this is some you know revolutionary
data right now and so we're going to be
refining this as we get more and more
data
so key considerations for
German regulatory
access and price is key I can't stress
that enough
uh and collecting and Publishing data is
also very very important
often Regulators don't know much about
their money
that's behind firewalls
of good businesses
so the more data that can be provided to
the market the better because it helps
shape policy and help shape business
decisions
um and it's important to remain flexible
from a regulatory perspective because
there's a lot of unknowns as these
deployments take place and so
understanding what you know and what you
don't know is really critical and being
flexible enough to say okay this is a
working let's change it
um I think Bob mentioned about the
regulatory that you can change things
quickly and I think that's what will
happen in the German Market
um for a period of four or five years
after that
um and I mentioned the importance of
gradual Supply
um and I think that the model where they
the Germany allowed for imports that
they had some basic domestic Supply and
then supplemented that uh with Imports I
think that's a good model
um there just needs to be a better
balance between domestic production and
imports
I mean keep in mind that for Regulators
that there's an emboldened Melissa
market and so they already have the you
know they're already ahead in the game
relative to what's going on in terms of
regulatory deployment
um and so for those that are in the
industry education and communication are
really key uh constant Communications
with Regulators is helpful for them
because they don't know how to regulate
this so we've never been doing it before
they may have done it on a small scale
with medical but that delegates is a
different piece to say the music
um and as a business operator a set
realistic expectations with their
business don't think that you're going
to get 10 of the money to the 20 of the
market when it's more realistic to only
say get two and know your cost structure
uh Bob and others mentioned how there's
going to be price declines as the market
for tourism becomes more saturated we're
seeing this in every Market
um what we're also seeing is a high
level of business failures in markets
that
um where they get over extended in their
cost structures turned upside down
relative to the market price and so it's
really important to be to understand the
cost structure understand where the
price is and where it's going you make
informed decisions on that and nowhere
when and where you have to get out if
you can't support your business because
prices are declined so much then it's
important to know that too and to make
that tough decision
and then it's important also to uh at
Global it's a local issue it's cannabis
is generally a very emotional issue
um it's important to act local but it's
also important to think globally now you
know five cents a gram in Thailand I've
seen instances where it's opinion Ram
I've seen wholesale prices in South
America and opinion around in the United
States production costs are 25 to 50
cents a gram so there's this competitive
disadvantage in the United States and it
could be very well in Germany as well
but so it's important to understand the
role of competition on the global scale
when you're operating locally and just
be cognizant of that so that you're not
surprised
um we've talked a little bit about him
um I presented some of this data before
on the hemp site
uh hemp is a pretty amazing industry in
and of itself and it's actually larger
by our calculations than the global
cannabis Market
in this example up here there's the
global demand total adjustable marketing
around 250 million dollars for cannabis
but just in 10 product categories taking
minimal market share
for him this is a 350 billion dollar
market and so and that's just those are
reasonable assumptions there's already a
presence in automotive there's already a
presence in Plastics there's already a
presence and animal feed and these these
industries are expected to grow
exponentially over the next decade so
um I think in some countries
hemp is viewed as a competitor to
cannabis but I see it more as a partner
or a compliment to a higher THC cannabis
and especially when it comes to the ESG
side of things environmental social and
governance on the environmental side
cannabis is a real dirty industry but
there's a lot of plastics a lot of
energy consumption and light and so him
can help complement and support the
higher THC cannabis industry by
providing environmentally friendly
products to help bring those products to
Market Plastics is a is one prime
example
um and there's all sorts of demand I
don't need to belabor the point but
um you know there's big Industries in
hemp and it's a compliment to hire THC
cannabis so in terms of predictions
um Germany is one of the first major
markets
um out of the gates here but it's that's
additional acceleration of legalization
throughout the EU and Beyond
um look for a spike I mentioned this
about piano tourism it'll be a novel
um industry it'll be a novelty to go to
Germany to buy adult use but eventually
that will Decline and that will go away
as more and more countries deploy their
legal systems as well and prices will
remain high at the start mainly driven
by lack of access and under Supply but
prices will eventually normalize and
Decline and so
the normalization I think is something
that people really need to build into
their business models
so
um I think you know that's
about it I mean you know
I think the key message here is it's a
exciting opportunity
but businesses need to be disciplined
Regulators need to be disciplined there
needs to be an understanding not only of
the demand but the supply as well and
plan accordingly and if
and it's not an easy nut to crack it's a
very difficult process to go through but
eventually there's plenty of opportunity
for successes not only in Germany but
throughout the EU and Beyond so just
wanted to say thank you for this
opportunity to speak today there's some
data here for you we're happy to share
it and I'll take any questions if
they're let's hear it for both way
s
[Applause]
anybody
someone's got to have a question
no how do you think Bayern Munich is
going to do this year
that's one upstairs
[Applause]
is there talking about the potential
markets what is the reason that Italy
like with last people does have such
more potential than for example France
of Germany
yeah so the question is why is Italy so
much larger than some of the more
populated countries and it comes down to
usage rates so
um based upon the UN numbers and others
there's a higher percentage rate then
there's more and more consumption and so
that's what drives the large Market
but one thing to note is that these are
pretty conservative numbers they come
from the U.N they come from the EU
through some of those studies and but I
think that they're underreported so I
think that this would be a good Baseline
to go by but the market is actually
substantially larger and and the demand
and consumption patterns are uniform
from not only state to state but the
continent to continent and I'm seeing
this especially out of some recently
published data at Uruguay where you know
31 of adults have used cannabis in the
past year now this is well in access to
what's being imported by the UN so I
think like I said
the uh the amount of consumption and the
amount of Supply here is very very
conservative relative to actually what's
going on in America
I don't need the mic
with what experience we have to learn
from from other countries what is one
hope that you have for Germany to
improve the process here
so the question is uh
what is the one hope that
Germany has for that would spell success
in in the deployment yeah what do you
think Germans can do better
um well
I think they're
they've done a reasonable job in terms
of deploying uh their medical program
um but
where they have the opportunity now to
build the infrastructure from the supply
all the way up most countries build
their models and their regulatory
structures on the top down regular their
retail and the taxes and all that and
then they go oh yeah now we need to
supply the market I think Germany sets
up the market to to where they
our common sense of the supply and a
pair of the supply then because that
takes the longest then from there
they'll set themselves up for success
and they can maximize the revenues they
can support the businesses I didn't even
talk about job creation but I think that
it all starts with the plan
it's a good question
all right that's fantastic
[Applause]