i was right there to help companies
start getting licenses
we were also the first state to allow
adult use
prop 64 regulate marijuana-like alcohol
we passed that in 2012. first store is
open january 1st 2014.
it's almost a decade ago that we've
owned recreational cannabis stores in
colorado
did everything go to uh colorado's
still awesome we have more jobs less
minorities in prison less problems less
alcohol consumption
so we've definitely learned some lessons
of what not to do by 2014 then seeing
that the feds didn't rate us we started
working in many many other states and
then by 2014 with canada
started working there then germany then
denmark and now over 40 states 40
countries we've worked in
so i've been around seeing lots of
companies from cultivation to
manufacturing retail the internationals
that have eu gmp compliance and gacp
compared to state regulations in
oklahoma which
let's just say some of those aren't the
best laws state by state
so
blades of glory
two rivals that were skating and they
got in a fight that got kicked out of
the olympics in their class of skating
male single skating couldn't do it
anymore
one went out to be a burnout the other
was tying some shoes
and all of a sudden they realized there
was a little change in the regulations
that would allow them to compete in
another category
like paired finger stating so they they
launched to be the first male paired
figure skaters in the history of the
world and got to get to the olympics but
one was like you know pretty boy
uh jimmy the little blond guy
he was like raised to do this i see him
as like the canadian public companies
like i went to work and i know about m
a's and ipos and all these evaluations
and it could be for a chicken farm or
cannabis it doesn't matter but they came
from the pedigree they were raised to do
this
and then you got these outlaws like chas
michael michaels
who is pretty much ridiculous in doing
whatever those are like the legacy
operators like gangster power by any
means necessary didn't have the
resources in training but they they both
do beautiful things however
they bonded together to capture the
dream which was a very beautiful kind of
sentiment to go on and like actually win
the world olympics as the first
not even ambiguously gay duo but like
blatantly awesome duo of skating so when
you look at some of these parallels at
least in my mind three months ago when
they wanted this presentation topic
um it was like right now everyone's just
freaking dreaming
dreams don't happen unless you
do something about it if you have a
great dream to do something you better
read the rules about what you're gonna
do put a team together have a plan just
because this is cannabis doesn't mean
you're going to be a millionaire or a
billionaire i mean i see companies that
do hundreds of millions of revenue that
are like losing money every month
canadian public companies msos all of
those and even private companies
there's all these different tax
regulations that you have to follow not
only in the united states where it's
federally illegal we can't deduct our
business costs our ebitda should be like
5 million it's like 1 million
so understanding all of these parameters
if you've got a dream how to take a
dream and a vision and make it something
is what i love to help companies do but
i see that most companies fail because
they're always like dreaming i could do
this or that and they don't have a focus
the focus for the companies is most
important
so when we look at the global
cannabis market it's constantly evolving
a couple more new colors there it's
happening time by time when we're
talking about like the entire us and
global industry of legal cannabis last
year about 35 billion us dollars in
revenue when you think that 88 of that
was in the united states
which is federally illegal and state by
state it's like we're almost different
countries
you got canada doing 90 is a legal
medical and adult use industry
interpol
nobody mess with them no one's messed
with uruguay yet
and then the rest of the world this is
of you
medical adult use
less than one percent i mean even
germany last year almost 350 million in
medical cannabis that's freaking awesome
helping patients have less suffering
healthcare's covering it's incredible
it's like testing the waters on a market
but colorado 6 million people close to 3
billion in revenue
germany 90 billion 90 million
like 350 million in revenue we're all
people and things are going to start to
change especially as the rules start to
allow to change but when you're in the
united states every little state is a
country and i can't grow things in one
place and move it to another so it's
super inefficient i have a different god
or government i have to serve in each
place some states will allow hundreds of
licenses some will give five but getting
market share in these new markets just
like international it's a real estate
land grab because commonly for your site
master files or for your qa qc programs
you have to have real estate that's
compliant that the owner will allow in a
city that said yes that's not too close
to a daycare or a church that's going to
have to have power and water and all of
these different services
but real estate is one of the secrets to
like finding these little places to go
because you could grow cannabis anywhere
it's a weed we've grown cannabis and
greenhouses all the way up in alaska all
the way down to south africa
middle of the world
you can do this anywhere but how much is
it going to cost you to do it somewhere
how much environmental and social
benefit is going to happen there and
what are the tax treaties and
regulations between countries from where
the money comes from where the money
goes how you bank it
these are things that are not as easy as
most people think
now the united states you know from
wisconsin
sorry just in advance
not everyone in america is like you see
on tv nowadays you know um there's still
some good ones left
we can still have women vote they can
have credit cards still you know there's
still some things
these can still get married uh
you know we'll check in on that in four
years fingers crossed but with weed
um
no current federal bills axe attempts to
do anything in the united states are
going to pass now it's really good for
stock prices when it's like oh the
moraps move forward great not gonna
happen
so more acts care mace
safe banking like they're all needed i'm
not against any of that but right now we
have such a divided house
and when you think about the economy uh
linguist background like economy is uh
oiganomos from greece like i know most
of the rules of the laws and
uh oikos is the house so the rules that
govern the house it's like what economy
is and our economy allows these little
state light things similar to the eu but
we don't have like weird sanctions or if
one state does something naughty we're
gonna like remove them from swift
banking or something like that
um that'd be interesting actually
but when you're thinking about all these
states and when it started with a few
there's only a few holdouts we've got
over a thousand bills nearly to legalize
in different programs it's going to
happen but we were the ones that caused
this show around the world in the
30s with some of our corporations that
were paper oil cotton
they're the ones who kind of work
together to make cannabis illegal just
to go after him
which is you know we've only been able
to do hemp in america since 2014 and
that was a show of a program the
first few years
but state by state is it's coming like
california you're going to do 5 billion
in revenue this year colorado probably
three oregon and washington a billion
and a half each some of these new states
like new york new jersey coronavirus we
went from 10 adult youth states to 20.
because they're like tax revenue jobs i
don't care
it's like this is going to bring in so
much more new economy and it's the right
thing to do like on a social justice
standpoint but we've gotten to be guinea
pigs in each one of these states
different departments of agriculture
departments of health telling us what we
could do what we couldn't do
we're trying to figure out that right
thing but we already figured out what do
people like and there are people that
are different in europe from like the
things you like like you like good bread
americans don't like good bread because
there's not any good bread in the
country i don't know how that's the case
but
you know there's different taste
concerns in countries when it comes to
it's not just flour anymore it's not
just hatch with tobacco but consumer
packaged goods are changing the way that
this industry is going to be it's gotta
have a barcode
so the companies of ours here that do
soil to oil cultivation and
manufacturing co-located we don't sell
wholesale pounds 500 kilos here 500
kilos there everything's in a single one
gram three and a half gram seven gram
package every edible is child safe
and then that's where you make the
massive revenue but what you can learn
from the united states what products are
working and not when it comes to
beverages and others what will your
countries allow in the future
or you're gonna do a giant vape line in
europe well europe's based on the api
and medical right now other than the
swiss path program you couldn't even do
a product really so you have to know
those rules and what you can do
so what can we learn from the united
states and canada
canada um
long story there
like to actually do this well and like
jimmy you say it's like if you can dream
it you can do it well that's not
actually the case it takes tons of
people to put this stuff together tens
of millions of euros of times to do this
stuff and that's sometimes just to get
started
so when you think of what products
worked in america what's worked from
regulations what pesticide testing
packaging what were the problems we had
in a poll in europe for adult use the
biggest concern is about child access
we've actually seen
teen access go down and consumption go
down in legal states because it's not
cool anymore like in america
i could get shot from my country i could
buy a house have a gun
get married pay taxes smoke cigarettes
buy porn
uh can't rent a car until you're 25 but
you can't drink beer alcohol or wine
until you're 21.
so then here it's like 18 is different
16 is different for beer but like
drinking is so cool to teens in america
because they can't do it
but then once it's like your parents are
smoking weed and you're like oh it's
not that cool anymore there's no folks
do it
but it still does happen so
no matter what you do in europe really
good educational programs for like youth
access substance abuse education you're
an advocate in this industry you're no
longer just like i got a business
everyone looks at what you do from your
packaging your labeling the messaging
that you have for this
you know who you support from substance
abuse education the trainings that
you're gonna do
so so important also like you don't need
pesticides to produce this even if you
don't have to follow a standard if you
do like gmp or eu gmp or gacp for
cultivation you're already setting them
like doing all this risk mitigation
less risk is better for the investment
and you're higher likely to succeed so
do the things even if you don't have to
do them right away because it will not
limit you from selling to another market
so you know i went over a little bit of
this the other day but internationally
the big problem with international
medical cannabis and as a medical
cannabis patient myself is that the
united states doctors write
recommendations they don't write
prescriptions for cannabis because
that's through the fda the food and drug
administration they're a federal
organization this is federally illegal
the only prescriptions that doctors can
do there for like apodex
satellites dronabinol
the synthetic cannabinoids that are all
poisoned
but they write for like recommendations
based in some states it's not everything
california anything your doctor thinks
cannabis could be helpful for you can
get a medical card i broke my wrist when
i was 14 skateboarding it hurts i can't
sleep oh here's your medical card others
like do you have a weird disease that i
can barely pronounce
and two doctors that say you haven't
okay now you can have medical cannabis
but only five percent thc oil here or
there like each state's so so different
but we need doctor education around the
world we've been stigmatizing this plan
for so long so no matter what you are or
where you are don't ever like
go so flowery to sales like canvas cures
this and that like
cannabis has been shown to
and we need a lot more medical studies
and a big thing that happened through
the commission for narcotic drugs the
world made um world health organization
and the u.n that re-rescheduled cannabis
in december of 2020
to be similar to the us's schedule three
like has medical value needs more
research in america schedule one
narcotic we're heroin cannabis is the
exact same no medical needs no more
study needed just the devil so
internationally cannabis isn't the devil
anymore
it has medical efficacy needs more
studies if we change that in the united
states irc 280 that tax code that really
kills our industry
goes away overnight because that's only
applicable to schedule one and schedule
who narcotics when you see that happen
by every single
mso that's in the united states in a
public company standpoint
we've got to do education we've got to
get more doctors understanding the needs
for this and trying this and using this
that's why patient counts are so so low
adult use is starting
you know it's happening in canada
happening in america happening in
uruguay
other places in europe are starting to
allow this why hasn't it happened yet
and one of the big issues here is
standing in germany deutschland's
biggest gdp in the eu awesome
almost what four trillion
pretty gangster almost 90 million people
like what you do here europe will follow
and now that you're not competing with
the uk so much like whole brexit then
we're not going to get into that
but um
germany you have the ability to be like
the trendsetter like the prettiest girl
at the bar
if you figure this out right are you
going to most likely not
because bummer it's not your fault it's
just
who your parents are aka the eu so we've
got all of these international drug
compacts that bob hogan and others
talked about yesterday the single treaty
1961 from the united nations on
psychotropic substances
indian pharmacies act all of these
different things
canada is in blatant violation of that
uruguay is in blatant violation of that
all of the medical programs under those
are doing compassionate use programs
which means it can only be medical api
active pharmaceutical ingredients flour
oil compounding happens in pharmacies
you're not selling cookies or vape
cartridges you can do part a part b you
know
standardization but when we think about
like what are all these things can be
these are a lot of questions that we
normally typically try to figure out and
answer but the issue with germany is
that you're in the eu and the eu has
different sanctions and provisions from
member nations so you can pretty much do
this to the uh everyone's doing that
right now no one's doing minus
russia but that's different thing
also very unfortunate
um
but then you're also gonna have to think
of what's gonna happen not only in your
country in some of the cantons like in
switzerland or within certain
municipalities and what's going to
happen and the easiest way they see it
to do this is through like
the home grill which as a farmer and
being in this space like something's
legal people should be able to grow it
are people going to make moonshine yeah
are people going to make extra beer and
salad yeah is it going to be significant
abso literally not it's me like
this much how many you all could brew
beer right now and grew wine how many
people have carboys at home
wash those put the priming sugar in you
know yeah not many but how many people
had wine last night
we're lazy cannabis is it takes four to
six months to grow it you gotta dry it
you gotta cure it you got all those
things and it's great that people do it
and it's medicine you've been growing
and seeing a plant and helping that i've
seen that massively helpful for veterans
but
if we legalize it that way it's going to
start a program of more illicit market
and then it's going to be harder to rail
that in later so if they do the right
thing early it's going to be very very
nice
when you think about it i threw on the
team america world police on this one
too just you know
america but we've got stuff we've got to
deal with like the united nations the
commission for narcotic drugs the world
health organization the eu eu then with
europol oh we got interpol we got all
this money sitting up in london we can't
do right now even though they went
like rage and pillaged the world for
like
half a
thousand years and then now of all it's
well sitting there that they can't
actually invest into like things because
the proceeds of foreign crimes act in
they can't even invest in real estate in
america that we lease to a cannabis
company so they can only invest certain
proceeds into like other legal things
that are legal in their country which is
mostly cbd type things
but when you think about all these
regulators and things you have to worry
about not that team america is a
regulator but
you know
they like to act like it but since we
were the that did this whole
thing internationally we're not going to
be the first to say like we're sorry
cannabis should have never been illegal
well we're gonna do this right we're
gonna take the ip and companies will be
leaders from the us and what they've
done but we will be one of the latest to
adopt this
and always that crystal ball question
how many years until federal
legalization of the united states
five to nine years
i've been saying for five to nine years
and based on who our last president was
which he shall not be named um nothing's
gonna happen current administration just
a great bill from biden the other day to
actually like take certain people out of
jail
but not about not putting more new
people in there
international
narcotics control board is definitely
pissed about everything that's going on
especially when it comes to like all
these vape cartridges new cannabinoids
people doing isolates isolating
something from nature versus just like
full distillates if you isolate
something from nature and you try to
make an api that's 562 million dollars
of clinical trials to get a standardized
drug
even if i took beta-carotene out of a
carrot and i was going to make a
supplement or something for that or a
pharmaceutical drug half a bill
just to do that so always use the word
distillate not isolate
um there's yeah we're in this gray area
where there's all this new learning all
this new science but there's no
regulators really cracking down other
than on the blatantly illicit market
and when you're thinking about what are
the possibilities in this place like are
people going to like wheat in europe
it's going to be a whole different roll
out for how you live here or when you're
thinking
467 billion in 2022 in alcohol sales
that's almost half a trillion euros
and normally that'd be like a lot more
but like the dollar in the euro you know
about the same right now which is
awesome for us sorry for you
you
know normally they'd be like i'm like oh
god 467 billion euros oh my god it's
like 600 650 million dollars oh my god
it's the same now but
that's a huge market share and that's
not something that's poison
we allow alcohol but we don't want
cannabis anybody seen a drunk person in
a stone person not saying one's better
than the other but
damn the problems that alcohol causes to
society over what cannabis like helps to
like treat and make better
alcohol and then you've got tobacco
almost a quarter trillion
dollars a year and smoking's cool here
it's not in america anymore it's really
bummer but like all these new things
jewel got banned by the fda like those
little vape cartridge type things like
tobacco is still this weird thing it
built our country but also like kind of
killing the country when you think about
this market share and what's happened in
colorado
most of our data there's a lot of data
companies out there but long term we
project that there's going to be one
billion in revenue from every million
people
for cannabis and for every dollar spent
on cannabis there's about five dollars
of velocity of capital the real estate
the consulting the legal the packaging
the electricity the plumbers putting in
things like manufacturers in china
you buy cannabis you're contributing in
this whole other industry so even if we
say colorado's doing
three billion in revenue we're probably
doing like 12 billion of additional
economy 15 billion what would that look
like here because eliza cannabis exists
here now it's just not being taxed
tested regulated that's what creates the
problems with this
massive opportunities will be the second
largest adult use market in the world
within five to ten years closer to the
10-year side when you think about
thanksgia for you know some slide but um
you know the eu with all the medical
it's really been happening well portugal
did something awesome by decriminalizing
drugs back in the day
not only did it allow you to buy a lot
of fake drugs in lisbon on
accident you know happens whenever
there's like oh people think that drugs
are legalized but there's a big
difference between decriminalization
legalization
you know rescheduling descheduling but
the medical programs have been starting
here but mostly i've let you down as
businesses because we don't have tons of
doctors writing prescriptions all over
the place that create the massive
demand that we need to actually
fuel these businesses that's why canopy
aurora all of these companies are
willing to take over the globe same time
we were working they spent so much money
on things that thought they would
generate revenues and returns two three
years out those were all four to seven
to ten year plans and they just got
burned like short squeezes
when you think about that and don't use
in europe kind of awesome you got the
netherlands you know coffee house thing
since the 70s that's gone through many
iterations it's not actually even legal
for non-residents to purchase their big
shout out to the dutch though because
like without them and they're breeding
back in the
70s we wouldn't have a lot of the
genetics that we have and it's sad to
see those companies aren't like
massively profitable like driscoll's
right now because they didn't do brand
licensing and like genetics breeding
rate stuff
but you know the netherlands had their
program and you've got this has the
program and the wheat experiment to
allow 10 to produce for 78 coffee houses
a few more there's over 500 coffee
houses in the netherlands each one on
average does 1.7 million dollars a year
i mean pretty significant and it's in
the country
for that spain has their club model with
like the medical club model also like
grey area ambiguity but it's
proliferating it started more and more
luxembourg introduced full legalization
all of that's gotten shot down and how
that's going to happen
germany how we're going to do it awesome
but like way to go otto way to go like
greens the social like everyone who kind
of made that happen gangster to
say that like this is amazing i'm
surprised jeremy was first i figured
malta would be
you're just the big one everyone's gonna
look at like portugal it's not legalized
it's decriminalized and that's all drugs
and they've had so fewer drug problems
with all drugs in their country because
they treat it as like an illness and
they help people instead of like put
them in prison take away their children
it's a really good model of drug control
malta's got that on their books in
switzerland has this pilot program for 5
000 patients people to consume in little
like club settings but they allow
products not just flour and oil it's the
same thing the netherlands the weed
experiment it was only flower
they didn't have like the edibles plant
yet we're going to do like netherlands
1.0 2.0 similar to canada but these are
the countries to really look at and pull
things that work from some of the others
but germany's got a lot of work ahead
so always like i'll say it's like to get
into this thing if you want to capture
the dream you got to know the rules to
play the game there's a lot of reading
to do in a lot of languages but the main
thing you wouldn't
like go to a casino with a million
dollars and like go play blackjack if
you didn't understand the rules or how
you would double down on things or i
don't gamble it's a tax on people that
are bad at math
but if you wouldn't go and like put a
bunch of money down and like do that
also what gambling legal kind of crazy
to me too
and gambling hates cannabis because we
don't make good gamblers like we get
distracted and we're not like yeah baby
like getting hammered like that's why
there's been so many problems in las
vegas getting this legal on the strip
but when you know the rules of like
what's the law allow what are the
standards i have to follow what are the
outside industry things that i need can
i even do my business plan where i'm
thinking about doing that business plan
does this country allow it
just because you have the idea that
you're gonna like get an extraction
license in portugal and make vape pens
and sell them all over the world
well not necessarily going to happen
unless it's a medical device compounded
and so forth but it's always from like
almost hindi meth like mythology you
have multiple different gods and you
gotta serve them all it's not just like
christian santa claus god just wanted to
keep him happy like you got national
international law your federal your
state or country municipalities your
counties all the way down to like little
boroughs and burgermeisters and it's got
to be compliant top down bottom up and
that's not just cannabis loss the
biggest thing i see having done
thousands of applications and businesses
winning the licenses i focus on because
it's number one but getting a license to
a building permit a certificate of
occupancy and starting the business
that's capital raising pre-construction
site planning engineering like oh
expensive and time and little things now
coronavirus has changed so many things
for supply chains everything you're
going to do
is going to right now two times as much
money and take twice as long
so in the past we used to just do new
buildings for everything but retrofits
are really starting to be much more
important
cannabis stocks are as low as they've
ever been right now some of them are
undervalued some are still overvalued
but
on a public or private standpoint this
industry we're out of gas even though
we're doing 35 billion in rev and all of
this services i can't get traditional
bank loans i can't get other things
so since we don't have institutional
capital how you raise private capital
how you deal with public capital we
manage funds do a lot of spvs i've seen
over a billion dollars of capital
deployed in the space some good some bad
but now more than ever
is like if you're thinking about getting
into this starting a business we have a
very short timeline that's like within
the next 10 years that this is all
established whoever gets those first
early market positions those are the
ones that are going to get the exits
that we hope for
a lot of them will stop though costs are
really high we have weird tax provisions
people are trying to figure out r d and
things on things that are already known
big advice
just like bob said this is an
agricultural commodity this is a
value-added product from consumer
packaged goods supplements
don't just think you're reinventing the
wheel on everything you're not going to
come up with some amazing new way of
cultivation the dutch with their
greenhouses and the venlos have figured
all this out a long time before use
their technology don't develop a new led
light that you think is going to do this
magic and your no
agriculture been around for like what 10
000 this year has been working pretty
well for us
pull from that you know indoor i've been
trying to put indoor out of business for
over a decade
it's so environmentally catastrophic
it's cheaper to build big four season
hybrid greenhouses that can still be
gazp and gmt and outdoor is where all
oil will come from in the future
tons of due diligence is needed if
you're an investor an operator do your
homework before you jump into this if
you don't you will be lost and all of
your dreams will not happen there will
be nightmares and you'll work at
mcdonald's someday
we've got more startups than we've ever
seen they're failing how many new
companies are here this year that
weren't here last year the year before
that we have to literally be mindful of
that when you've got these companies
going public and thinking they're going
to take over the world be careful anyone
can write a good press release and
that's where we are right now in publix
that's not true value but remember a lot
of those dominate market sharing you got
new ipo's that are happening here
hemp just the last thing don't go play
with the woodland fairies after you know
he was kicked out of the olympics that's
delta eight that's cbd novel cannabinoid
right now hemp there's industrial hymn
and you've got novel cannabinoid extract
like extraction almost a two billion
dollar sign in cbd and cbd
very good medicinal compound awesome
90 95 snake oil garbage industry being
sold in gas stations once hemp didn't
make them billions of dollars and then
cbd market bottomed out what new
cannabinoid can i do with this license
and then delta 8 delta 9 thcv all these
others still all be scheduled similar to
heroin in the united states in this next
year even though some farm bill stuff's
happen so don't just jump on random
bandwagons
main thing just uh
gotta show a panda at the end
if you practice and you do your
homework you have the possibility of
capturing the dream but in this room
you've got less than one percent chance
of doing that on your own so like who's
here left right of you don't walk by
people look them in the eye like your
partners your future investors they're
all here and we're in this together and
we only have so long to put this
together right before like this whole
industry is pretty much like dominated
by a bunch of bag
philip morris all the others they're
gonna buy a lot of our companies it's
great but if we embed good ethos into
the company now
we can literally change the world it's
the most important thing we could be
doing with our lifetime with your
capital with your with your money with
your minds everything else is boring and
established but this is revolutionary
what we get to do at this time
thank you berlin
[Applause]
you