[Music]
my name is Kai nman I'm the founder of
the kfn plus law office here in Germany
we the ICBC 2024 Berlin and yeah what a
journey this new legislation which means
that cannabis in no is not a narcotic
anymore it's a regular medicine which
can prescribed for almost any indication
this will mean that we will probably at
the end of 2024 we will have 1 million
patients in Germany which is a huge
success this is a place where people are
looking to do business and there's new
markets opening up and they're coming
here to learn about it so if you come
here and you have an international
business as long as you have the right
product the right price and the right
presentation on it there's no way you
can't be successful here
I'm Bo Whitney the founder and chief
Economist at Whitney economics Germany
is just the beginning of a global
phenomena a global movement of change
and I'm I'm confident that German
legalization will lead to an
acceleration of Reform not only
throughout Europe but throughout the
[Music]
globe hey guys it's Andrew fredman the
Cannabis Somalia here with cannabis
tolling Solutions we're at ICBC 2024 in
Berlin they just legalized cannabis what
an awesome show the energy was electric
people from all over the world getting
excited about cannabis culture and look
we can finally have a puff here in
[Music]
Berlin who would have thought happy ICBC
I'll see you next year Berlin
[Music]