thank you thank you very much um good
morning everybody
uh
and thank you for for having me here
as well my name is i'm based in brussels
i work for a
public affairs and communication
consultancy called hague corporate
affairs
and my job is eu public affairs which
means
shaping and influencing the development
of
policies and regulations at the european
level
i do it for in many areas among which
medicine and cannabis
via what we call the multi-stakeholder
approach which is represented by
medicine at cannabis europe which
is the association that uh hague set up
back into in 2019
and in this presentation i'll just just
uh go through with you
on the uh on our
the the role of national cannabis europe
our goals uh what we have accomplished
so far especially in terms of uh
political engagement
um and also if you're interested
you could uh be part of my sentence
so when we uh started back in 2019 and
in general when
when we
look for uh projects or uh ideas in
in eu affairs
we always look at what's uh what's the
status quo
in this case what what was the status
quo of
irregulation in terms of medicinal
cannabis
which i'm sure you're all very much
aware and that i would uh
summarize with awards which is a
fragmentation
i will go very quick on this as i'm sure
you're uh all aware uh medicine cannabis
regulations are quite different across
member states
so there are many states which are more
advanced on one part of the medicine
economy supply chain and others uh are
advanced in other parts of the supply
chain
however the european uh europe is
becoming on the way to become a leading
market in medicinal economies
and a lack of a new regulatory framework
for medicinal cannabis not only poses
hurdles to
the industry cultivation of our pharma
but also to the other
aspect or segment of what we call the
value chain uh which are for instance
the scientific and medical community and
the patients
and
all these segments are strictly
interlinked so if the uh if the industry
cannot develop in a smooth way then also
these affected so patient access to high
quality and safe medicines
so we said okay
we have this these hurdles we have this
situation there is a gap at eu level
representation of these
interests if we want to say photo call
it like that
how can we address that
and that's how we set up medicine
cannabis europe which is the only human
disease coalition
that was mission is to
ensure patients for access to medicine
cannabis in the eu
our why is of course because of the uh
therapeutical benefits of medicinal
cannabis in the application on the
treatment of different conditions and
diseases
but at the same time the lack of a
framework that can ensure that patients
can have
fair access
of to these medicines across europe
and how we approach this jointly uh with
the balance on the cannabis value chain
so
what do we mean by multi-stakeholder
approach uh it means that so
cannabis europe is a membership based
association and in our association we
have
all the the three main segments that we
identified of the canopy very medicinal
cannabis value chain
so we have industry we have the medical
and the scientific community and we have
the patients so we have a big
pool of patients association from
different
member states
which
we will see afterwards uh is also
what allowed us to gain the political
support uh we have now and it's also how
what we saw lacking at eu level so we
saw a lot of representation of uh
medicinal cannabis patients or a
coordinated representation of incidents
so when we start data
we started we had this idea of
multi-stakeholder approach uh different
segment of the cannabis value chain
and so okay how can we put that in
so we asked ourselves we want to ensure
patients for access to medicine cannabis
what do we mean what do we need to do
that
and we identified
three
pillars
one
is of course from a regulatory
perspective so uh ensuring that there is
a regulatory framework organizational
framework for mexican cannabis in the eu
we are i'm sure you're all
well we're aware of all the different
hurdles that exists
these are just
few of them of course when it comes to
motivational production
organizing standards when it comes to
affordability of medicines that patients
what patients if medicines are not
affordable for patients they don't they
won't buy them or they will resort to
other roots
to get
the treatment and the medicine they need
and also when it comes to uh free
movement of people so we have issues uh
well there are issues of of patients for
instance moving from a member states to
another with a completely different
approach to medicinal cannabis and maybe
a patient who was uh who legally use a
medicine and based on cannabis in one
member state will not be able to use it
legally in other member states and this
is also
another hard rules but there are many
more i'm sure you're aware of it
then we have another pillar
which is research research and
innovation one of the main hurdles
especially for for the medical for the
medicine economists
is the so-called lack of scientific
evidence
that is that we have and we hear hear a
lot also from policymakers
and so another point another pillar of
our advocacy is to really
promote
research innovation so european in
europe in europe as well as a national
level there are funding schemes i'm also
sure you're aware of that such as a rise
in europe who allocate funding for
reserve generation of specific areas
among which
health
and we are pushing in that direction to
allocate funding for medicinal cannabis
research
in different and in different ways it
can be
research projects on the application of
medicinal cannabis on specific
conditions
in this case well we are we are focusing
especially on conditions which are also
a priority in the eu
because
when you do advocacy uh at all levels i
say all i believe was at national level
you
you know what you want to say what you
want to convey what is your message but
you also need to know what the other
party and your interrogator is willing
to listen to and is really interested in
knowing so
as a first step we
focus on
in this case conditioned diseases which
are also priority in at the eu level
cancer rare diseases this is something
that
is already work which is ongoing at eu
level and
it's work where we see a role for
medicine academies and that's the route
we take to advocate and to try to
allocate research resources and funding
for medicine economy research at this
stage
and then we also had um well of course
clinical trials um
that are useful and needed to build up
the real evidence and then would allow
and first accelerate the uptake of
of medicine cannabis
and then we had a third pillar which if
i would uh prioritize would be the let's
say the foundation on which the other
two build
and it's
the narrative around medicinal cannabis
which we are seeing and i think we also
this was discussed in the previous uh
panels
we
we are seeing it developing i think uh
since we started uh three four years ago
uh this has already been developed in
the in the in the right direction but
it's not uh over so this is uh one of
the pillars that we uh we work on and on
which we started
with our policy maker engagement because
not only need a social dialogue but we
need a political dialogue
because when we started back in 2019
medicine economist was
barely in the political discussions at
the new level barely and when you do not
like the topics you want to advocate for
it's not in the agenda and you have to
put it in the agenda you have to push a
discussion on it we have to make sure
that the topic is
in political discussion and that's what
we what we did first
and one thing that we got in our
exchange with policy maker is the
importance of a clear distinction
between medical and recreational
especially at eu level
so that's where we focus we focus on the
medical side
we promote multi-stakeholder dialogue
and of course another another
point is not only educating
policy makers externally to the value
chain but also educating the segment of
the value chain that's also another
hardware that we encountered and that
were also was also mentioned by the
panels before is the education and
knowledge of ethical professionals
doctors nurses pharmacists which
which is important for which
there is a new angle that can be
explored
so these are the three pillars of our
advocacy
but it all it all bases on a let's say
a prerequisite from our side which is
understanding what we mean by medicinal
cannabis
and trying to have an harmonize the
understanding as possible of medicinal
cannabis and this is what uh we're
pushing for at the moment and this is
also one of the first uh actions that
the eu is starting doing uh you cannot
cannot develop a binding definition but
what you can do is providing and
suggesting a harmonized definition as
much as possible
so this is the bulk of our advocacy once
we had it in place we said okay
how
to whom we address our concerns so in
the eu you have three different and main
institutions you have the commission you
have the parliament and you have the
council
and naturally uh the the first
institution we went to was the
parliament why because the parliament is
meant to represent new citizens we were
going there with the perspective of of
patient with a value chain but with a
patient-centered approach which
resonates very well with policymakers
we presented the policy pledge
it took some time but we managed to
build some support and in the second
half of last year we facilitated the
setup of
a european parliament interest group of
medicinal families
now an interest group is an informal
group of amitis
meaning sorry this is the eu jargon
members of the european parliament which
are shortened amenities
a group of amethyst who informally
gathers
and focuses on a specific topic in this
case is messenger cannabis
we have so far 36 energies from
different political groups
and
why this is important it is important
because
we don't want the topic of medicine like
cannabis to be polarized in the
discussion we want it to be a broad
political support
and so far we have it we will uh we will
continue to uh to increase and to
broaden the support
but that's a good start and uh nmeps
represents 20 countries which out of 27
it's it's quite a good it's quite a good
number
um
now you will ask me what what how can
what the parliament can do what what
they can do to help
our cause well there are three three
main things that they can help us
one is facilitating multi-stakeholder
dialogue what do we mean by that it
means that as i said before
to put a
topic in the political discussion you
need to create the conditions for this
topic to be discussed
and
one of the conditions is to have the key
policy makers involved in this
now
if
medicine has cannabis europe just
reaches out to uh member states like so
that say that the chances of success are
much lower than if a another institution
reaches out to look for events
discussions front tables and so on
so this is a
a an important role and this is also
what helped us we will see in the inside
afterwards making the first step towards
this movie stakeholder and policymaking
discussion
then they didn't support our advocacy
so the department has its own tools
instruments to
push a topic towards
the commission and the other member
states so they uh they also have side uh
all possibilities to to advocate
directly and to support our our cause
and our
uh and then i can broaden our uh
our social dialogue and enrich a broader
range of audience uh that can be also
fellow mbps or their constituencies
uh and so on so uh these three uh these
three elements uh are very important to
push our goals further
and one example for instance is the one
of the first activities we did with them
was to organize uh an event in the
parliament it was uh last march at the
end of march
uh which uh
where when we feature the different uh
representatives from policy makers so we
had the parliament of course the the
interest group all the mps and in
particular two mps who
participated in the event we had the
commission
we had representatives from
two national authorities france and
czech republic the choice was not random
the choice was on purpose because at the
time
france was leading
the council so the member state work and
now it's czech republic so it's also
through these opportunities we also
create a network at eu level with the
member states
and then we have representatives from
the medicine cannabis value chain which
also are members of medicinal cannabis
europe so we have our vice president
jacqueline potratz uh for mamaka
from the patient association dr
babakbaban who is one of our scientific
advisory board members and we have uh
finance who is from tiny christianity
group who is also part of our board
so this is uh our advocacy at eu level
it may be a little bit different from a
more technical advocacy but the
technical and what we call the so
more political advocacy both are
important to push a topic forward
because at the end is the
to say is the political
the more political level we give the
directions to the technical levels
that's not that that's how it goes so
there needs to be a push from both sides
and well
uh
as i said can basically cannabis europe
is a membership based association so we
invite uh and we invite everybody who is
interested in
in
participating in medicine cannabis
europe um
to to reach out to me uh we can we
welcome every segment on value chain so
cultivation pharmaceutical uh
medicinal doctors
and patient associations as well
and well just a wrap-up of what we do uh
of course we contribute for raising
awareness and shaping the debate on
medicine economies
also with policy makers patients and and
public
of course being active in brussels and
having a food in brussels allows us to
have intelligence on what's going on
when it comes to cannabis in the eu
uh we are a part of a good network with
with patients with the medical community
and with other eu associations as well
and of course our final goal and
ultimate goal is to shape the policy
developments on medicinal cannabis
i hope that was the
that was a interesting uh if you are
well if you are curious and wants to to
reach out to me and to have more
information don't hesitate i'm here the
whole day and if anybody if we have time
yes we do oh that's amazing one more
time
any questions
um
so i i think there are no questions at
all
okay
sorry i wanna saw that
hi um nice presentation um i was
wondering if um you're hearing sort of
anything
among those
emps uh about the prioritizing of
medicinal cannabis with everything
that's going on right now uh
in europe
uh you mean on the on the other urgent
issues yeah um
yeah uh let's say that
the
path and the work with the political
level of medicine at cannabis it's at an
early stage
what we are now focusing on and also
what we are focusing on via the mpps and
with the meps is on
as i said building this political
discussion making sure that this is
something that is discussed
um and in the in currently we also
following that the developments uh more
from a regulatory perspective uh
european uh european medicine agency
this is something that has been going on
um
yes of course the current the current
topics are very important and are
technology but i'm not talking about
mechanical taking over many other topics
also other topics i'm working on
but
let's say that the early stage of of the
of the discussion of medicine cannabis
allows us
still to have room for
to do what we what we have to do at this
stage
hello
i have a question what is your personal
view on extracts
and is
shared between flower and extracts to
what is regulatory
view on
what the
medical cannabis would be only should be
[Music]
now the commission has been uh
i was wrapped up and published
a cloud of glossary where they also put
down all the different definitions
including extracts
uh if interested i can share with you
um
but this is where we are at this stage
so
what is your current this
like advisors to regulators this is your
current review on
this issue cutting flowers and textures
are you doing something in this area
like trials
with overall thinking the visionary
are you doing any research on this
uh we are doing partially with our
scientific advisory board but that is
more on the rni side it's more on the
research and innovation side okay thank
you not on the policy regulator
and before we come to an end um let me
please ask you a question
um
because
when we look on the international laws
it comes to the point that any country
uh having a
medical cannabis program actually needs
a cannabis agency how many european uau
countries uh you deal with have a kind
of a cannabis agency
sorry again how many eu countries have a
cannabis agency as a basic for medicinal
cannabis so far
not many not many
because
because member states are applying the
topic of economics in a different way
you will have member states which are
implementing the so-called pilot
programs
we have france for instance we had uh
ireland we had denmark
which is a completely different approach
that for instance
czech republic
which has a drug coordinator or
the netherlands which has an agents and
so on so
also the way member states are
regulative medicine of the
way the structure the governance of
messaging economics in member states is
structured is different
so that of course contributes but this
is something that at eu level
the eu has not the competence to tell
member states
so let me please ask an additional
question that due to the u.n treaty
on
drugs
any country that
has a medical collapse program has to
have a caliber agency just as an open
agency so how come that country is
implementing a medical cannabis program
do not open up canonization because i
remember in germany before anything was
dealt with medical cannabis here we had
to open up the cannabis agency that was
always a delay was always the reason
that we do not have this agency on
federal or general level so uh how come
that countries implemented pro programs
just about such a thing
that's a question i cannot i cannot
answer but i think there are also
like
there are always sideways on which you
can you can deal with a topic like
amazing cannabis okay i've created a
special
program
only a
trial program and then if it works then
we can see how to move forward that's
for instance the approach of
thank you very much
[Applause]
you