[Music]
what we do is very simple if we only
want to be prepared inside of um
a conduction container and the unit
that's what we do nothing else so very
very very very niche
and there's always one regulation in
every market that hits us you know for
us no america is cool europe is tough
because
you can see in europe
okay so um
you know
everything but
these guys they're on a they have a
different perspective from a much larger
um view
out there so let me show you um my two
guests with me and louisiana
why don't you choose yourself
as uh
well hello
[Music]
is
thanks luke who is koski the chief
operating officer for a company called
metric and trc fbi
metric
i've been with the company for two and a
half years i came to accompany my way of
being a government regulator so i do
love regulations i'm sure you know you
do that good
good government
like comprehensive regulation and
official government is something we
don't hear in the same sense but
hopefully you have to talk a little bit
about that today and talked about
some more things that are happening in
the u.s but metric is a company
think of it as a centralized database
that the government uses
licensees report into that system
all of their
inventories how inventory is moving test
results
pull the sales information
that goes into that and then governments
can use that information to help
confirm compliance of licensed
businesses
in the industry so open software if you
all bought in something like this
well it's because it's interesting
because the united states is
probably the well the most advanced or
is the
oldest um professional cannabis market
that we have right now and uh in the
production campus space so if you just
write us some of the regulations that
you guys have on it and then we're gonna
talk about europe and i'm gonna mix it
all together and see what comes out
yeah so so just talk a little bit about
the u.s and big picture um our
regulatory framework across the us
is really kind of formulated from what
the government at the federal level has
done so way back when i first got into
uh canada's policy back in 2010
the federal government basically said
we're going to start enforcing
less
canvas violations by people that are
using it for medical abuse just by
looking at small comments publicly about
uh how they're going to take course in
action or not take for enforcement
action entire industry in the united
states started to formulate first with
medical uh frameworks and then later
with with adult use so that was kind of
the first thing the second thing that
the federal government did to do
anything which is regulate they can't
say on one hand this is completely
illegal federally we're not going to
prioritize enforcement we're certainly
not going to regulate the uh an illegal
substance that's a food product or
agricultural product so
they didn't do a lot of that so a lot of
regulations that formulated in the u.s
formulated by a state-by-state basis
with each state
interpreting what they think the federal
government would want and so as a result
we saw a lot of different regulations
based on whatever the important
priorities were for that state so if
they were more of a public health focus
state the rules really had to be
reflected in public health focus if it
was more of an enforcement or a law
enforcement type of posture the rules
tend to be a little bit more restricted
and reflect that and it was it was a
more of an industry-focused type of uh
environment while the rules tend to be a
little bit more permissive and reflect
that so across the country 35 states now
regulating cannabis in some way shape or
form
it's a
patchwork of different approaches
that have some dissimilarities and some
uniqueness to each market
but also some similarities as well
great interesting so
so every state is the cannabis industry
in itself
so can you is there like an interstate
market or is that
not legal
yes there is a interstate market it's
called the illicit market
cash regulated
itself all right then so um that's
that's that's the that's the u.s so
let's talk about europe
well in europe i think uh we do have a
chance now to make it a little bit
different and then the u.s is
not a federal government per se
we do have a federal government without
the european union now media is
so i guess it is up to us to actually
learn from what's been happening over
there uh and move closer together and
make sure that we find an online system
that allows us to then actually build
sustainable economics
then we have the whole situation in
europe we have all those different
standards and kind of at the end of the
day and that's the beauty of what you're
doing i think what we're doing is
through taking converts those gaps
between different kind standards
actually make something out of it that
is for everybody out there and through
that and kind of build the framework to
allow for industry
so
let's say here for a second so what
would you say are like the most
important
regulations that they are so if you were
if i wanted to i'm a cannabis grower not
from the listed market you know i want
to make some
i want to pay taxes on my team i wanted
to do that i wanted all things
um
i want to do it in europe so what are
the top
things that i have to look at
define europe
i want to sell here in germany now go
well i get a medical license you go
through the whole process in that space
and everything else is listed at the
moment so yeah it is
actually the end of the day medical is
the easiest because it's the one that's
most defined it's the one where you have
clear processes clear steps and you
follow those steps you actually have a
framework to put your business on where
in all the other markets that you work
with cbd is
0.263 united states this isn't that one
percentage
etc etc so all that confusion is
absolutely unnecessary that's not how
you look in this room
i agree um and i feel like one thing
that takes a um
for everybody makes everything much
easier is technology right so this is
for now since we're in an interconnected
world we have access to data and youtube
companies are based on data right that's
that's what makes everything more
transparent and easier
um can you can you like from from your
perspective
um what is
how does data help
you know in bridging like a business or
making the business more transparent
like very very concretely um but also in
when we talk about like across markets
you know how can data help and achieve
i think you appreciate that that
question so i think um when i when i
think about uh regulatory frameworks and
what makes them work really well first
and foremost you really have to have
some
cooperation from
all of the different stakeholders
they're going to be putting input
putting data into whatever the system
sounds like so
i recall very vividly in the u.s we work
very closely as a government official we
work very closely with a lot of
stakeholders from law enforcement from
local
government state government
federal government i mentioned earlier
was absent even though we liked them um
and we also had many industry members
and so we were able to collaborate on
what the
advocate amount of regulations was going
to look like so there's a lot of input
and a lot of insight into those
regulations i think most people felt
like they influenced some of the
probably people here that are spent time
in colorado they could verify that for
you in some way perform that said and
you have to have the right technological
structure to be able to collect the data
and what government chose to do in the
earlier years is to really
uh carefully monitor
all of the inventory that was coming
into the system
so as his plants were the immature
plants they started up in track and all
those inputs were collected along with
moving from one room to the next room
and um and then subsequent to that and
that would get harvested and start
moving its other products out to other
licensed premises and also ultimately
the consumer
and what we originally did that because
we were concerned about inversion or
diversion of
a product out of the
regulatory structure you start talking
about you know especially what we're
seeing in europe there's likely to be
commerce between member states the eu
etc um there's gonna be a lot of
interest in knowing what the profits of
that product is so you know where it
came from
hear your
data health be able to determine whether
or not that product that's coming into a
country is coming from another authentic
and well regulated uh industry
makes sense um
you're okay
well
data is one part of it
they are systems of building processes
and uh
[Music]
forward
combines only sounds like such a
daunting thing if there's an actual
framework behind it it can actually be
made in a very straightforward easy way
and uh
[Music]
another aspect of that for admission and
that is that
if government can lead the way and help
uh develop the right data framework it
gives birth to a lot of other commerce
[Music]
all of which use that data
um because it's collected you know in a
uniform way there's a single source of
truth that everybody can access
um with invitation but they can they can
access it and be able to utilize that to
run the
data companies compliance companies all
um integrate in with those data sets
that government have led the way in fact
in our system we have probably close to
500 companies that integrate into the
system and use the governance data
in some way shape or form
okay so you're saying that
as
do you customers have
access to
other companies data as well through
your system no
no okay so uh um even though the data
privacy those are different in the
united states obviously they haven't
been endured so you're not actually your
system is very secure when it comes to
the data um what happens though is like
take a point of sale company uh which
probably uses one of the economy in
terms of third-party
companies that agree with their system
and they have a business relationship
with dispensary aid
cultivation bee and manufacturer c
they would be able to with those
companies permission be able to exchange
data
from those systems so that the campus
businesses do not have to put the data
in twice and then make it more available
for the business systems that they use
on a day-to-day basis you wouldn't be
able to see any other data from any of
the other licensees unless you had that
relationship yeah okay so it's really
so
end-to-end
integration
you own that data so you collect it and
you can do something with it as a
company not we as a software company
like you as a competitor or
manufacturer's computer if you do
certain things in certified way you want
to be able to share that either with
your
client be made to decline or be able to
see clients so that having the power to
actually work with that data
school have been marketing so in the
class
and one
example that i'd like to kind of take is
in the beginning everybody was talking
about vertical integration vertical
integration with the whole supply chain
from 80
now we've seen in a couple of different
instances that might have been probably
the most successful business model and
specialization in different parts of the
supply chain basically become a very
daunting part of you every time you have
to completely move
all the all the traffic racing
everything that happened
[Music]
like businesses like ours allow
companies that basically are not
virtually integrated in one company or
horizontally integrated but that have
some complete
face different state standards and with
different country standards now and
we're currently working
you know
something that might be
the european um
medical side so you know
from your perspective and maybe also
from the certain customers if you want
to really become a globalized industry
what are the next steps so if you look
into the future what needs to be done
next in order to come you know from a
regulatory body well i mean we all have
to wait for
um
for governments to put their ads
together and do something about it sure
either the best in doing that probably
not
um but they have to do it at some point
but i mean
i think i feel like it's the industry's
agree um like the job
to steer them in the right direction
because we're the experts so to say so
what are the next few steps that have to
be taken away
and well it again it depends on the
different countries
[Music]
pilot projects which is i think a very
exciting approach to how communities are
performed we basically disorders this
government just opened up and said look
proposes something
come with an idea this is a study you
can propose
you can donate it has to be swiss
organic which is a different story but
at the end of the day it really allows
to study how can it actually be formed
how can it be brought out of the black
been cash collections as you mentioned
before how can different consumer
protection
safety standards and so forth also how
can people right with that market how
can you do that without just blocking
your
basically i think the next step is
now for countries that are allowed for
the industry to create social studies or
studies we're getting within a different
conference at first and then hopefully
studies
i really feel strongly that
industry participants
have a really significant role in
working hard to establish a credible
regulated framework and i'm hearing that
today from a lot of the speakers on how
important that is on a member state by
membership basis
so it's really it's kind of encouraging
to hear that you know i think some of
the more well regulated states in the us
have really um
lend themselves to that especially the
government side has
given that space for industry
to innovate and move quicker without
question having been both in the
government sector
and
now in the private sector the private
sector is much more capable of moving
quickly
and they're much more capable of really
kind of setting the standards
and so i think um to the extent that the
industry can really embrace a strong
regulatory framework um that allows for
competition that
allows for
some comprehensive regulation with some
efficient governance which i know again
is not
intuitive it's kind of much
counterintuitive in fact but to kind of
position the industry in such a way
where they can really help the
government lead
everyone to the balance of the policy
you can protect public health you can
protect public safety while also
allowing for greater business interests
to thrive within that regulatory
framework but the industry itself really
has to have saved what public health and
safety is too and typically historically
what we see in regulation on many
different regulatory frameworks i uh
study this as part of my doctoral
studies was was trying to
come up with ways for industry to help
determine what public health and safety
is rather than distrusting their
private interests suggesting money and
i'm hearing today it's really
interesting on a couple of the uh
panels where we were talking about
really focusing on patients or really
focusing on consumers rather than having
them
i agree this is why i think
what the acm is doing with the meetings
with their brain being experts from all
fields
in order to forge they're not i mean
it's not a regulation
it's more like standard it's not it
might be
a part of the law because a lot of like
lawmakers they refer to companies or
organizations such as astm when it comes
to creating regulations
um but i think initiatives like acms
doing will really help to to move this
and industry to really into a global
future
so i think we have just a couple of
minutes left i'm not mistaken are there
any questions maybe
[Music]
yes
hello thank you for sharing with us my
name is
and executive chairman from chilean
obviously following the work of that
metric
and this question may be particularly
for you
what do you see
the greatest opportunity and challenge
for europe
when it comes to this idea of
[Music]
crafting
uh this regulatory infrastructure so
that it can lead
to better information sharing when we
look at the us
and the opportunities and challenges
that we have there
thanks for the easy one i guess it was
hard i was going to refer to luke
because he knows the european market
much better than anybody so so just what
i'm learning because i think one of the
biggest challenges is that
member states within the european union
obviously system in the uk they're gonna
be more they're they're gonna have their
own
public health and safety priorities and
i also have their own priorities with
the reflect with prospective type of tax
revenues that they want to bring in so
being able to find some common ground
between all of the member states that is
going to be a challenge when i start
thinking about how different countries
are approaching it
just assume that i'm right about this
but i think there are some countries
that are more interested
in exporting cannabis
outside their boundaries or others are
maybe more interested in a tourism
type of uh
business that customer type conversation
criminal disease i've been trying to be
able to harmonize all of those
and create systems that allow for
uniqueness of public policy priorities
but also
allow all of the member states so people
to work together really closely again
and i think
i don't i don't think really well but i
don't need technology data and
those types of companies really have the
potential to help bridge that gap and in
a lot of ways i think government has the
right could have the right ideas but
maybe not the ability to execute on
those uh high level data and technology
needs and so companies like ours
can certainly help bridge that gap
i think another big part is that
systems are standards
[Music]
just choose one of them that is out
there it works for every other
agricultural good they train that all
around the world in safety health health
safety standards consumer safety it's
all guaranteed just basically choose one
of them they're all the same more or
less
anyways
[Music]
the day a lot of it is there
to mix it together and
create something that works for all of
you and uh
well
i would doubt that the regulatory body
would try to be
usually
what's up there already
yeah sorry about this
um i i agree so any more questions yes
right here
beautiful um specifically lewis uh you
mentioned it's very helpful to have
states that are already on board and
stakeholders involved in the process to
implement attraction what do you do with
the oklahoma's world where resistance is
going to equal persistence and how do
you get those uh maybe traditional
american markets to
get
and
you know catch up to the standards that
are out there which almost happens like
for your brains mentality
i mentioned earlier that there's there's
some uniqueness to all the states the
u.s states happily approached it
one thing that i also feel strongly
about when it comes to differences is
that there isn't just one way to
approach this i think it's more about
how
good
getting all the government
stakeholders engaged so when i think of
states like oklahoma i mean
they decided to take an approach where
there's um less barriers to creating so
they have a large licensee base so that
will take some time for it to evolve um
into a more mature market
all right do we have time for one more
let's go for one more maybe is there one
more
one more here we go
what are their thoughts about
fda establishing grandfather products in
some way
maybe for july 2009 when they said well
the deadline in 2007
and and everything from that point on
will need a submission do you see that
happening
[Music]
i would have to say probably not and and
probably more because the variety of
product is so great right so for example
you have chocolates you have
um cookies you have
other confections those are
not likely to just simply get a pass
because federal legalization comes
around but they did something that
everyone's really concerned about i
think there's a lot of things
to consider when we talk about federal
legalization how great it is
perhaps
you start talking about others that have
you know various regulations um you
could essentially be giving
cannabis
licensees or businesses a competitive
advantage over other businesses that
have to live up to that regulation
that they've been
working with for years
all right all right thank you very much
you