all right all right all right how's
everyone feeling out there y'all feeling
good
today no hey y'all glad to be in Germany
while we had just legalized
it y'all feeling good in Germany cuz we
just legalized it
make I see BC yo I'm going tell you
something y'all I came here in 216 and I
had a dream and a vision to bring B2B
cannabis to Europe because we know that
the market fuels the politics the policy
fuels the market market so here we are 7
years later under legalization but when
I came in 26 everyone thought I was
crazy okay and I remember I remember gor
V saying to me Alex I'm very worried for
you $500 a ticket we are very how you
say gtic people I do not know I was like
well GE gorg I'm worried too but what
happened we built a whole movement
around B2B cannabis in Germany and here
we are today in 217 we had the first
ICBC and I guess I got lucky SCH
hopped and what happened was medical
marijuana uh uh basically was was
legalized just before the first ICBC in
217 and that was great and I knew that
eventually cannabis would be legal in
Germany I had a feeling it would be the
first real Market that cannabis would
become legal in now I know there's
ambiguity or semantics whether it's
legal or not now but it has opened up
and we know it's been decriminalized now
we know cannabis has taken off the
narcotics list in Germany which is one
of the greatest public policy
achievements regarding cannabis in world
history so we only we have the Social
Clubs phase one phase two but we also
have that uh uh medical marijuana is
going to get a huge boost now in Germany
and uh one of my favorite things that's
happening a lot of people don't know is
that criminal penalties have been
reduced for cannabis also so this is the
this is where you have a a truly
Progressive Society where we understand
that prohibition doesn't work stop
locking people up for using an
herb it's about time and there was then
one thing I said when I got on stage in
217 at the mar Time pro some of you out
there I know were actually there who was
at the first ICBC in
217 awesome awesome awesome so was I um
and uh uh I said there's two most
important things when it comes to
changing cannabis policy and this really
comes from an activist perspective not
from a business perspective per se and I
said well this is what I said I said the
policy makers are going to things
up that's just true that's just what
they do that's the nature of the
bureaucracy that's the nature of
politics I said but what's most
important is that we end criminal
penalties towards cannabis and everyone
can grow plants at their house because I
believe growing cannabis at your house
is a fundamental human
right jack ha was my mentor in 1993 I
met Jack Jack ha and he um the gruff old
bastard was pretty much right about
everything and he said hemp could save
the planet well I wasn't sure if hemp
could really save the planet then I knew
I like to smoke hemp back then and I
knew I like to hang out with Jack ha and
kind of the the band of Rascals that he
was touring around um but 30 years ago I
was on hate ashbery with my dreadlocks
telling everybody to legalize cannabis
cuz it would save the world and
everybody was laughing at us but
nobody's Laughing Now ladies and
Gentlemen please give yourself a big
round of applause because the ICBC is
nothing without you
guys I'm Alex Rogers I'm the owner of
the and founder of the ICBC without
further Ado I would like to bring up
the our longtime MC every single ICBC
show my friend for 30 years please give
a warm Berlin Welcome to our one and
only
un buen Morgan Venus Diaz
bour I don't know any other languages