From the beginning
[Music] So I think for ICBC, what you can expect
to see at a show like this is a good connection
between distribution, packaging, um, I want to say
regulations, compliance, retail, wholesale...
It's great to have
all of these people all in one room and all in one space so you can kind
of connect the dots and figure out how your business can really excel within the industry.
[Music]
Really, what I love about this show is the interconnections between businesses
to businesses having meaningful conversations and relationships, uh, to figure out what's
going on in the industry. Whether it be in Germany or whether it be an entire EU or from
different countries altogether, different continents altogether. I've had great discussions
here. I've learned a lot here. This is the kind of stuff that I come to ICBC for. So,
having a
great time with it. I would highly recommend to anyone looking to exhibit at a show like
this - do it. Don't even second guess it. It's a great connection point.
[Music]
It has been so great to come to ICBC.
What an incredible networking opportunity. I have met fantastic,
smart, successful people from all over the world. And some of them I'm really keen to
want to work with.
[Music]
The one thing that we know is for sure, is we love you.
Thank you, everybody! DJ Goran in the house taking you out y'all!