all right good afternoon everyone
so as in gail sid we are here to discuss
the future of cannabis
and the impact that the stigmas have
so we have
here stephen martin mayor from fido flow
and he's an expert on the colombian
market
we have viola brunette
who's from cannabis schizo
and
i probably pronounce that incorrectly i
apologize uh who's an expert on the
italian and swiss markets we have
rebecca allen tap who is from agi
who's an expert on american and uk
markets
and then we have stefan roll
the ceo of hemp group
and the president of gushi culture ibiza
and a specialist on the german and
spanish markets
so we're going to open our question with
we're going to open this panel
discussion
with
[Music]
from the countries that you're in
what types of social stigmas have you
experienced
so
i actually grew up in europe so i'm not
colombian i had
more than 15 years working in spain but
the last four years i've been working in
colombia for a company called plana
global
columbia is very interesting when it
comes to stigma because obviously the
first thing that comes to our minds when
we think of colombia is probably netflix
the narcos series right so
and we
before you you fly there the first time
that's the feeling you get is i'm gonna
go there and maybe pablo is still alive
the truth is um in the last ten years
there's been great changes and that has
also been a strategy of the government
is that um
since drugs are there and they are being
consumed and you can accuse colombia of
producing cocaine but somebody is buying
it and somebody is consuming it
apparently so why not try to make a
legal market out of that and
kind of refresh the image of colombia by
also bringing economic opportunities
which are legal so that has been a very
interesting
experience for me to go and be part of
this
of this experiment so to say though you
still really feel when you say that
you're working with cannabis in colombia
the first reaction is so why are you
here why are you talking to me
call the cops and then you explain there
is a medical legal market and things
change
so rebecca what about the u.s
so the us has continued to evolve um
when i was growing up it was very much
the i lived in california so it was very
much like the snoop dogg um kind of you
know chichen chang that's that's really
what you saw a lot of um but as it
started to legalize we saw
that it just completely changed you'd go
into a dispensary and you'd see you know
your neighbor's grandma you know you'd
see you know your your co-workers you'd
see every person there so i think the
legalization has really helped to
to change the stigma and shift it but
the interesting thing is is now because
it's so
political we're seeing that shift again
so recently in the us i'm sure you all
know there's an epidemic of gun violence
and there's been plenty of school
shootings and now those are actually
being tied into cannabis use so it's
it's a whole we're seeing a whole new
manifestation of a war on drugs
happening and stigma is the driving
force behind that so like everywhere
else i think it's just continuously
evolving
yeah
i would say in germany and since the
talk of the legalization it's getting
better but
still when you talk to people and say
that you're
a cannabis
consumer the most people think you're a
lazy pothead
and that's
truly not not true that's none of the
truth
but uh when i compare it uh to spain
their uh cannabis is more part of the
culture there we have the cannibal
social clubs and
like
smoking cannabis for recreational uses
they're not a big deal
[Music]
this is what my art is coming from
hi everyone thank you for being here
after lunch thank you digest with us
i come from italy i'm working currently
both in italy and in switzerland
uh in italy we had a legal medical
cannabis for now 10 years almost 10
years
and
although we were just discussing this
one thing is changing regulations it
takes time but it doesn't take as much
time as changing a culture so
one of the things for example that we
still notice is the choice of words that
still are trying to in some ways feel uh
less
aggressive so many even many doctors who
i train healthcare professionals is what
we do with our company
and often we have
you know our students and our medical
doctors that instead of using the word
cannabis they still say can happen which
is a medical hemp because in some ways
it feels less dangerous
it feels less of a drug because what
they heard for so many years is that
cannabis is was just associated with a
narcotic and with something completely
illicit so the moment that they find
themselves actually having the
possibility to prescribe it legally in
their
in their in their office in their
medical practice they need to find ways
to feel better about that and and so
changing a culture it will take way
longer so i would say it's a sort of
like george orwell 1984
idea so if you don't have the word you
don't think about it and so um for
example i will assume that in the states
that there is still very strong this
idea of the marijuana world still used
for a very strong stigma around it and
the type of consumers actually or the
type of people around the marijuana
world right so it's actually being like
taken out of what like some of the the
like the regulation work so like
washington state actually just made it
so that marijuana is no longer a
terminology used um in any of their
their compliance or regulatory policy so
here's a question then and this is
it's actually just listening to you guys
it's governments and large corporations
that are
creating stigmas as well now or feeding
into this which is causing confusion
because as you're pointing out hemp
versus cannabis
is is not the same thing
yeah it's um
we i work and i have a cd company and
when you speak with people outside of
dentistry and you tell them yeah i work
in the legal cannabis industry in cbd
the most people start smiling and saying
yeah it makes you happy and it's not
about this
it's more than
making you high and this is a stigma in
the industry
and then that's an interesting thing as
well because
cannabis does make you high
but people when they want to talk about
being a patient it's about easing pain
and nobody wants to acknowledge
the high part of it
and and again that's a stigma what's
wrong with being high
yeah i would like to add that often i
mean from a medical perspective you can
see euphoria described as the side
effect excuse me but i think afaria is a
pretty decent effect to be given to a
patient to be honest with you
okay so as a patient
that i hate that stigma i hate that i
have to feel uncomfortable about my
cannabis use especially like if i'm
using it and i'm just trying to use it
to relax i'm not using it for
for whatever i would typically use you
know i'm using it because
sometimes i'm out i don't want to drink
so i bring my own my own stuff but i
feel i have to kind of hide it because
i'm like almost then like okay well i'm
not helping the patient cause if i'm if
i'm using cannabis outside of medicinal
use you know because it's we have
everything has to be in a neat box
you know cannabis hemp patient
recreational medical it's we we have to
have these clear defined boxes and i
think that this is this is something
that's not going to easily fit and i
think that we're finding that well and
it's interesting and and you can ask
yourself this question
uh
if you use cannabis how do you say you
use it how do you categorize yourself do
you call yourself a patient
because if you are
do you have a prescription
if you do where did you get it from
yeah it also opens up a big
conversation here or a big issue to
understand also when wellness ends and
medical starts because if i go to the
spine and get a massage maybe that's the
reason why i'm not going into surgery
because i have a real issue
with my back you see what i mean so that
there is a there is a certain um
preventive action that wellness does and
and and in that direction i think it's
important to understand that it's not a
defined um
defined concept and and around this
there is a lot to do with uh what do you
do you know
you might not be sick but you you are
absorbing a lot of stress on the
workplace no and so it is he's having a
little uh smoke at night uh something
that is just recreational adult use or
is it maybe something that prevents you
then to get into serious anxiety and all
these kind of you know more complicated
sleep better exactly sleep quality very
important um so so there i think there
is a lot of confusion that this
confusion we tend to try to put into the
same categories okay yesterday was
having a conversation with the doctor
and said yeah but you know with morphine
we have morphine and there's a scale and
you can yeah okay but this is not
morphing you know i understand those are
true morphine you want to be very
careful or it might be the last thing
you do but with cannabis you can self
train and you probably uh almost
certainly won't die you know and just
like
riding a bicycle you have to find your
own equilibrium but then you you will
understand what is the limit right but
that
is making people accountable for their
own behavior
and every society struggles with that
yes
so that's why i'm gonna jump in
we've all talked about this the
importance of setting intention with
your use regardless of how you're using
it you need to have attention intention
and set in setting is not just for
psychedelics and i think that we should
really incorporate that into it to
cannabis use as well and really getting
into the mind of why am i using this
what is my goal what is my intention and
what do i want to get out of it and i
think that if we just took that time and
put space between action and reaction
and really like thought about what we
were doing um not just with you know
with eating you know so just putting
food in your face same thing with using
with using any kind of you know
recreational or medical drug why are we
using it and how long was the intention
behind it
so then
that's a very good point and again i'm
going to say that's accountability that
people don't belong
[Music]
what about let's talk about the illicit
markets
and the stigmas behind that
[Music]
all right so i'll take that um
i came from the us obviously so it's no
our our war on drugs has influenced the
world um which we are i'm the first to
be here and say sorry everyone for
problems
on behalf of my country um
so it's challenging because then then
we've kind of taken this other stigma
direction which i think is interesting
where you hear so much about the illicit
market in the black market right and
they're like demonized thugs
uh
whereas yeah but my experience is like
one of my i have you know i i've
definitely sourced illicitly plenty of
times with them and i would get things
like um
special strings for what i'm looking for
they would do more testing than some of
the uh some of the producers that i
actually can purchase through on the
prescription drop i can actually get a
coa
from my illicit source easier than i can
get one
from a prescription pharmacy in the uk
um they also will tell me kind of what
to expect here's the terpene profiles
and give me more information on it
here's what it will feel like my doctors
can't tell me that
so there's not a lot of incentive i
think that that's another way to push
people into
you know more of the standardized uh a
format is by demonizing uh the enlisted
market because there's also that
caregiver model in california you know
in the in the 90s when medical became
legal there was the caregiver format
where people would grow in a community
for patients in their community and i
think that's something we really need to
explore but that that's they're really
making it challenging for for individual
growers and and do you feel that
when it comes to quality illicit versus
the large corporations
yeah it's i mean at europa we were like
opening up our flowers smell this almost
you can you can tell the difference i
mean the nose knows um it's it's a
completely different quality but that's
also
building a relationship there's a human
relationship factor there as well i
don't know my producers if i go through
the prescription route it's picked for
me but if i go through my my local
grower
i know what he likes his interest his
what matters to him so i know how he
cares about about growing the plants and
and the people he's caring for so
there's just that relationship there i
think that's something we're missing
all right um what about let's talk about
what do you see
in the near future what changes do you
see coming when it comes to stigmas and
the impacts it's going to have
yeah one thing i i
really
[Music]
feel should be addressed is especially
even the mainstream media speaks about
it all the time is that there is this
feeling that cannabis will be consumed
once it's legal you know and you know
the hundreds of millions of consumers
yesterday night i don't know if somebody
was here at the smoking area of the
concert it smelled familiar to me so
cannabis is already being consumed the
question is what will happen once it's
legal and the the feeling is also that
once it's legal all the problems are
solved but you've seen that with gay
rights for example you know now we have
gay rights in europe but you can still
go to rural areas and walk hand in hand
uh same sex and probably they'll throw
stones at you so
it doesn't change with the legality the
legality is not the beginning and it's
not the end the legality is a change in
compliance it's just changing how the
legal system and the society processes
uh whatever your personal consumption is
but
the fight goes on and i think it's very
important as an industry we also get
together of course we are all working
for competing companies but we get
together and realize that tobacco and
alcohol have strong lobbies they work
together to get the best rules so then
they can play the game of
i sell more than you but before there is
a lobby and i have the feeling that the
economy's industries he still has to
mature a lot in that in that aspect so
that the fight will go on and the
changes will occur also after big
changes like in germany occur this is an
ongoing process and especially to remove
the stigma i was giving you the example
the other day very quickly uh if i was
at a graduation uh someone getting you
know finishing university if i bring a
bottle of champagne i've seen as
as a very nice person if i bring a bong
um probably i i'm going to be looked at
who's this weirdo you know call security
and that that really shows you the
stigma because at that moment we should
be allowed to you know party or
celebrate in whatever form or shape we
feel is the right one right
yeah and when you come to conferences uh
you get drinks for free but uh why don't
you get drugs for free
now you're pushing it
you actually get like in trouble
this is a cannabis conference don't
spill that out right here
maybe this idea for the next icbc
there's a suggestion uh so then uh
another stigma uh tying into this the
whole the legal side of it
if
the fear
is behind
getting
like charged
yeah this is uh i would say uh for a lot
of uh chemist patients and in germany
right now
the only reason there are patients is
that we don't get fined from the police
because as a cannabis patient
like me
i have some pain but this is
my most reason to be a patient is to
don't get in trouble with the cops when
i have my weed with me when i travel and
when i smoke
um and there's also okay so so you
called yourself a patient yeah and uh
the whole thing is that when germany
when everything is organized and legal
wreck site medical side will you still
call yourself a patient
it depends uh on the laws but i'm
hopefully not i'm a recreational user
and i know the benefits for me cannabis
is like a superfood
i use it in my daily nutrition i use not
just thc i used cbd cbg all the very
priority of a cannabis it's not just
to make you high like i said before
if we are
able to talk more openly about cannabis
that can give us much more
that's true
maybe i'm gonna have a slightly
different opinion on this for example in
in my country in italy um i would say
probably around max five percent of the
patients
are there because i have a prescription
because there are recreational consumers
however you want to call a recreational
consumer i really like stefan's wellness
concept because i think
it really makes a good point
for several reasons i mean the
prescription process isn't really smooth
like in most countries still
the black market is still cheaper than
going to a pharmacy
so actually
my art i would say that 80
75 percent of the patients
patients that we have for the medical
market in italy are naive
to economies they never tried cannabis
before
what i'm fearing for the future in
europe
moving towards the direction of
recreational market which of course
we're all looking forward to is that
this is going to happen before a true
maturing of the medical markets what do
i mean with a true uh arriving to a true
mature point what i mean is at least
getting
free healthcare
meaning it totally remorse medication
for the medical market so in that way i
can ensure that patients actually are
still getting a product that is at the
highest quality
possible
and then of course as much as we can go
to a store and buy one or go in a bar
and get hourglass
of course i'm looking forward to a
recreational market but if we implement
it now
in which our medical markets are still
not i mean the majority prescription
both here in germany in italy in the in
the active medical markets that say
they're still private so this is going
to create a huge issue because of course
the moment that you have a smoother path
through a rock market than the medical
market anyone is going to anyone i mean
any person that needs cannabis even for
medical reasons it's going to go through
the market and what's going to be the
guarantee for the patient
very very little so i don't i don't
i mean i'm looking forward for
everything to lose fast but mainly for
insurances and
public health care to really take this
on board because otherwise we are not
creating a really
good scenario for patients to be honest
it's very good points
um and and then i'm gonna touch on um
the pros and cons of growing your own
so as a patient if you're able to grow
your own flower and consume it at your
own risk if you know what you're doing
um but where do you see that going what
are the pros and cons with growing your
own flower then
maybe here
i have a little bit of a controversial
usually opinion because i have
i was once in in uruguay and i had quite
a few mothers running after me in that
case it was a an association called mama
cultiva and it was matters growing for
their own kids which were affected by
epilepsy and i gave the negative opinion
on that
kind of uh situation because i feel
this is a very serious condition and um
you need to know exactly what dosage
what what exactly the kids are getting
and especially you need to go through
quality control um
intentions are not the only good thing
that you can do and it's a good thing to
have good intentions but contaminations
they come also with good intentions so
if
the cannabis absorbs a contribution from
the soil from the air you can do a lot
of bad things a total quality control of
a batch would cost you i would say
between two and three thousand dollars
if you want to go and see pesticides
heavy metal all the
microbiology and and so there i
you know depending on the condition i am
not so much in favor of uh people
growing for themselves like on the other
side i met adults in canada which were
on a wheelchair because they were
actually you know a traffic accident
actually the driver in this example i'm
thinking right now was a drunk so so he
was also the victim of um of a drunk
driver and he was growing his own
cannabis but now it was for a condition
of chronic pain in this case i justify
the the the consumption much more than
in a kid with epilepsy because
first of all you know
there was also the beautiful experience
of growing your own medicine which was
you know he was really proud of his own
plans
but you know adult use
chronic pain you find also what's the
right genetic for yourself that is much
more of a
easy to accept personal consumption or
personal growing that's a little bit my
own opinion
but um i wouldn't think that there's a
problem with the pesticides and stuff
that is because uh right now everybody
uh allowed to grow their own tomatoes or
fruits or stuff and people do it and
they
they know what they do they want to have
it like a hobby and want to do something
special
totally organic stuff like this and i
think this is the direction where home
grow goes it's
when you look at alcohol it's not
forbidden to to make your own but who
does it
just a really few uh for have something
special for for a special night for for
friends and i think it will be the same
with cannabis sure there will be some
guys who are growing their own cannabis
right now and they will do it in the
future for their friends they just don't
have to fear about
the police anymore
so even even like uh in the u.s like
some of the stuff that's even grown
that's just sold to dispensaries you go
in and you think oh it's safe it's been
tested for everything but that's
actually not the case like even going
through and buying something that has to
go through like a rig of roll of rules
and metric system and all that bs
there's
still not good testing standards for
things like microbials
and heavy metals and pesticides and each
state has different ones so it's kind of
like looking at that model and then
exploring the home grow it's it's
i don't really know what's where there's
a good
satisfied model already in existence
because even what you're buying and you
think is safe isn't it isn't safe and
there just aren't proper standards for
testing out yet
and at the same time let's say everybody
is able to grow the best flower ever
this is also very disruptive for the
large corporations
so what type of impact do you think they
would want to to impose
on a stigma
around
the way you're going to grow your flower
you know i wanted to just continue the
conversation on self on homegrown and
the direction it probably will go
i i tend to agree with what stephanie is
saying i don't necessarily see it as a
solution for medical absolutely but at
the same time there are there is a lot
of untapped potential in cannabis we are
all thinking about
decarboxylated
cannabis and when i think about
homegrown i actually think about
wellness and getting my own fresh
raw juice or
acids
and flavonoids and a lot of good stuff
that i wouldn't be able to get
anywhere in a shop whether that's a
recreational market or a medical market
and and really from
using the roots of the plant to the
sprouts there is so many compounds into
interesting tree terpenoids and
a lot of stuff beyond cannabinoids that
is incredibly interesting on a wellness
perspective so
and also i mean to be a bit uh the crazy
neuroscientist um i think it's also
important to really to think about
let's say the manufacturing process as
in the the growing process and the type
of energy that you put in it and of
course that's uh i mean very
up in there maybe but for a lot of like
ancient culture it wasn't because if you
think about how for example ayurvedic
medicine are produced people pray before
starting to to to take the roots and
then manufacturing them and so on so
yeah then you make your little batch of
let's say your home instead of your home
grandpa or whatever you have your own
homemade
special things that you can make your
friends try either for fun or for or for
wellness and that's great but is that a
solution for the mothers in
uruguay no but no also because i don't
expect everyone to have the time and the
tools and the capacity or even the the
clean soil i mean you can be as
strict as you want on your own way of
cultivating but i'm thinking for example
i come from north of italy where it's
there is a lot of growing and completely
non-organic so you can be as organic as
you want but then you will have to put
so many bushes to protect your land that
basically the patch that you have
available is super tiny
so yeah it can work like you need to
basically reflect to real life and real
life it's not like we all have this like
massive land of organic and irvana and
everything is going to be great because
you have great intentions behind it
very good points
and now i'm going to bring up the
obvious stigma
uh the stoner let's talk about stoners
when you hear the word stoner what do
you think of what comes to mind
and i'll i'm going to share what comes
to my mind is it's usually a man
it's true
sorry
but it's true but that's that's it's
really an image that comes to mind so
what do you guys think of when you hear
the word stoner and why are we so afraid
to be called a stoner
i think stefan
stefan just said it
i mean he just said it before exactly
that image of the unaccomplished too
lazy
it's measured with productivity
absolutely i mean and unfortunately i
think still in the type of world we live
in a success
of a person is based a lot on the
ultimate goal of their productivity
which also i find pretty strange but
that's for another topic probably
[Music]
go on what comes to mind
i mean you guys made some great points
but it is true i really think about like
productivity at the stereotype of the
lazy stoner
um
uh
the thing that i think is interesting
too is that
i feel like there's this culture too
with working cannabis is that
we can work and go to these conferences
but i don't know that everyone is like
it's acceptable like socially admit that
you're using cannabis you know either or
even if you're like medicinally using it
using it before work i think that
there's still a lot with that and it's
seen as like i know we were talking
about
a colleague that
can can use cannabis at any time of day
and and it actually calms their mind and
they do better whereas i think that the
intention and when people look at you
you think okay well if they they use it
they're not gonna get anything done
they're just gonna sit around smoke and
eat food and clock out
and i think that that's you know
perpetuating that because a lot of us
are here fighting for it and i think
that it should be more acceptable in the
workplace as well within within bounds
with boundaries
well that's interesting because yeah you
go for a few beers for lunch you come
back to work and that's okay
but yeah but what are people going to
think of you if you go out have a joint
come back and you're high
well i think it's about amount to like
amount amount of use you know like um
like for instance i talked about people
making their own stuff i'm a big fan of
people making their own stuff i do my
own coconut oils and i put that coconut
oil in my coffee and i do only like a
quarter of a teaspoon and i take it
every single day and i do it before i go
to work but no one can know that's in my
coffee i mean now obviously because it's
out there you guys know my secrets
but
it it makes me better at my job because
there's so much going on and there's so
much to do in this industry i bet
everyone this audience is doing 15
things right now while watching this
panel you're probably posting talking
about it like figuring out you know
content and scheduling meetings we've
got so much work to do that helps me
close some of those tabs in my brain and
i don't want to feel like me using that
to help me get work done it makes me any
less productive in the eyes of my
employers
just like stoner is a stereotype that we
have to try to get rid of but
stereotypes in general are bad you know
we don't we all have a different phase
we all have a different dna and we all
have a different cannabinoid system so
some people react to cannabis in a way
which makes them more productive and
others become couch potatoes or whatever
you want to call them and so everybody
has to find their own
inner balance you know the famous
homeostasis which is the basics the
basics also of what the endocannabinoid
system does and
at the end your productivity is
something you have to see whether you're
productive or not right so
too much coffee also makes you too
nervous and you're not productive but
nobody's going to tell you they don't
don't have another coffee but ultimately
those are really personal things i think
if you really want to take away the
stereotype yeah for me it's dollar some
one who misuse cannabis who use it way
too much um for some people it's it's
the best to use cannabis in the morning
to to start the day
for me not and then i get too lazy but i
know it for myself i know exactly when
it's good for me to use cannabis
and i don't use it every day but some
days i start earlier some days i start
later but
every day is different so you're an
accountable stoner
yeah like
i would say sure the misuse of cannabis
refuses too much it happens for
for a party like last night or the night
before but not on a ripple basically but
that doesn't mean i'm a stoner for me a
stoner is somebody who
who uses it on a daily basis for me like
almost abusing it yeah
i think that's his intentions
yeah exactly
i think it's important we
also i mean we are the industry so it's
really important we check our own bias
at the door i remember once i was
visiting uh stefan mayer at the place he
was working there so i was just passing
by behind one of his several calls and
he was on a call with some colleagues
some of them were from canada
and for me it was very
peculiar the fact that
without taking off the screen camera so
like oh sorry now is my camera isn't
working oh no they were in front of the
camera a couple of them took it up
and for me i mean i've been working in
this industry now 11 years and
so i should be totally okay with that
but i was like
it's just like the corporate world for
you you know and so and then then i
realized that also i might be part of
the problem if i find that shocking
because we might i might not have
like the little foreign of panache or
rattler as you call here so
uh i think it's important also
i mean this is the reason of this panel
like where is our bias and i think you
for you that we're mentioning as well on
employing point of view do i want to
employ someone that clearly looks like
someone that is a massive consumer but
then the point is that one
i
as we all mentioned there are some
people that if there aren't consumers
they're not going to be as good workers
as they could so um i think it's to keep
this uh point uh always in check
and and that's the thing it starts with
us as as as an individual for yourself
and how you perceive things
and it's an awareness right
um
let's talk about women
and stigmas
with cannabis
i i would like to start sorry
yeah since we where are the women right
i would also like to the men the men can
accept mansplain
if they would like
i understand i work in the american side
and health care side so one of the
toughest part is always when it comes to
the point of the mother or the woman
that wants to become a mother or
the the doctor that has to what do i do
with shall i take off this medication
i'm talking about a medical patient so
let's say for example a lot of
conditions may be crowning a few a lot
of conditions that we considered
deficiency the result of the deficiency
of the endocannabinoid system mainly
they are
the incidence is way higher women so
then it comes to this point of the life
of a woman that she might become a
mother and there it really is struggling
for
pretty much any doctor what do i do with
this because cannabis was working so
well shall i take her off
or shall i
keep her on it because then there is a
massive stigma from the other colleagues
some weeks ago we were at cannabis
europe in london and there was actually
a panel on on women's health and that dr
dani gordon was talking about the fact
that she was completely agreeing on the
importance for women that phone their
balance
for treating their pathology with
medical cannabis
but at the same time she wasn't feeling
brave enough she said i'm just report
quoting awards to
make a prescription to a woman that was
either pregnant or breastfeeding i think
here it really is important then to
and i'm sorry and on these i work in
education so i'm gonna i'm gonna repeat
this but it's really really important
the education silence for example there
are different is different the
metabolism in terms of
tshcoh and so on
between
a product that has a pharmacokinetics
for example through inhalation or
through an oral consumption
and this is a important difference in
the rate of penetration for example in
the in the fetus
so then it's really a matter of what
type of product it's gonna
be best for this state of condition
another another situation is that with
that of breastfeeding because of course
as
some of you may know in in our in our
own human milk also animal milk
there are endocannabinoids there's a lot
of torah
glycerol so so um it's actually a great
matrix a great tobacco for cannabinoids
so usually muscle time is breastfeeding
is one of the most difficult moment for
you know as a an administration of
cannabis rather than actually pregnancy
and and then you need to take in
consideration the quality of the life
not only of the matter but also of the
child because i mean the
past part of depression it's a real
thing so if you think about a patient
that so far was
balanced with her medication you remove
her medication so you're unbalancing her
and then she's also going through a very
crazy and balancing moment of their life
i mean the day of giving birth is the
highest amount of neurostar steroids
that anyone can can secrete
then what do you do and then we have on
the other side
a very well designed and very nice
protocol on benzodiazepines
is that you know is that a good solution
i'm sorry i bring this up because we
often have this conversation on the fact
that even um you know our in our medical
community of of cannabis doctors or
doctors that have been prescribing for a
long time but because cannabis as you
all know it's not a first-line treatment
then they feel safer especially in the
situation of a woman over planning a
pregnancy to use stuff that actually if
you look at has a much shorter
window of safety because you can die and
you can have a pretty bad addiction with
for example benzodiazepines
okay so i'm going to add in my own
story with my own experience based on
what you said because we have like the
clinical point of view and then the
patient point of view so
um i had that i have a four-year-old and
i was pregnant while i still had cancer
so i was still a medical patient using
cannabis in in the us where it was
recreationally legal
um
i
was
carrying they decided to let me continue
on with it i was very open about it um
but i was also intentional with my use
you know i wasn't aiming to get high i
used very little um i worked on weekly
using tinctures and tried to do as best
as i could
and uh but it didn't stop them from um
sending in a
social worker once i gave birth and i
cannot tell you how terrifying it is to
go through a 20-hour labor an emergency
c-section to have someone come into your
room then and interview you about your
medical cannabis use
um with a social worker right there um
you think you're going to lose your
child and this is something that's a
really big issue whereas they didn't
touch on us being at all for me that was
not everything so you said it's kind of
like a focus point whereas
it was not even a concern the concern
was you used cannabis during your
pregnancy you told us you were using it
we're going to test you in the kid if
anything comes back positive
we're going to have to take this and and
see it through and i mind you i was in a
legal state so and with doctor's
permission so this is definitely a topic
we need to touch on uh we need to
protect our mothers out there because
it is it is not easy uh to switch
medicine and then mess up the
already
road raging hormones going on during
pregnancy and then afterwards so um i
think it's an important thing to
highlight yeah and i want to know what
the men think
yeah well you know this this is
absolutely uh you know
when you listen to these stories it's
it's a little bit uh it takes away your
breath it's like why would you have to
speak in front of a social worker after
you gave birth when
cannabis was helping you
this is still part of the stigma is a
part of the things that have to change
and and again as
viola was saying if the alternative is
means of the hazard then we should
really have a serious conversation i am
totally in favor of you know defending
and supporting women for their use
absolutely
the crazy thing to they've had to add is
that
both tests came back negative so they
only had my admission so that's the
thing
they used my word against me so i
thought that was pretty interesting for
science sake though that nothing came
back with positive
did you guys want to add any last bit we
have about four minutes
do you well i think we're not going to
ask questions does anyone have a
question
all right well that's one question
let's hear
yeah so just a quick question is
in your opinion when it comes to germany
how long will it be before you'll see in
culture it becoming more accepted
and i don't think that we will uh
we will get it in our lifetime
that we will sit it takes
longer
much longer
yeah i can maybe share a quick
experience in uruguay i was there in
2015 so one year after they legalized
and at that time even the people in the
ministries so people working for the
ministry of health the ministry of
agriculture they were fighting it who
had to sign
the licenses because i you know it's
legal but i i don't know maybe i lose my
job
and that takes a long time to to to to
kind of change
the good news is that nobody lost their
job nobody died as we know cannabis is
not going to kill you uh and so slowly
there is a process of normalization but
that that's what i was saying before the
importance of getting together as a
lobby you really look at alcohol and
tobacco and they have hundreds of
lawyers paid to go and defend the
interest of the market the interest of
the sector and we are still a little bit
sometimes fighting against each other in
a in a kind of too competitive way
that's really one of the issues also so
if you really want to change you have to
go together
convince the media convince the
institutions uh you know break down all
these issues like a social worker should
not go and visit a mother the same day
after she gave birth that's that's
really that's human rights in my opinion
that you're going again so that really
is a little bit the
the the soul of the problem i think
and in general change comes because we
talk about things so just
being more aware in general these
conferences
add so much value in that sense
yeah for example just um just an example
from italy
uh okay we have a medical law now almost
a decade
we the majority of doctors that we train
there are over 50. why why is that
because they are already in a safe place
of their career
okay the young doctors they don't want
to know anything about cannabis
so
i think this
it will change but it's a slow process
and i and again the consciousness in my
opinion comes from very different things
one of these is education another thing
is working this happens a lot in the
czech republic for example you walk in a
store and you see from the shampoo to
everything with that cannabis leaf you
know this starts to give different
images so the grandmother starts to not
completely go
crazy if then the doctor is starting to
talk to her about cannabis but yeah it
will take a while and again the
commitment of all of us as a united
industry from all different aspects
great thank you very much we're out of
time let's hear it once again for
fascinating