so one thing to be clear right now
cannabis is highly complex the
regulatory environment
is
ever changing and we need to be
differentiating our products against it
and success is most likely to achieve
pipeline by being meticulous
about identifying potential risks and
opportunities and by being
always up to date with the latest
regulatory developments and this is
something we're going to talk about
today the three acknowledged experts on
those right hand side we have
um he's a specialized lawyer for hampton
cannabis kyle's
the
association an association for the
campus lawyers and working with cannabis
companies across the globe
and kai puts his energy to
to uh sustainably establishing the
cannabis industry as one of the most
significant industries um in the future
then we have alexander riek as uh was
one of the first entrepreneurs in
germany to get active in medical
cannabis he
farmer in 2017
and he was also a founding member of the
germany association for um
for pharmaceutical cannabis the bbc
and then we also have uh he's a partner
at dentons and focusing on life science
with more than 30 years of experience
and
he's the head of the european cannabis
school at dentons and he's one of the
most renowned lawyers in germany but in
coverage
especially in regard to medicinal
capitalism
so peter let's get started with you
what are the biggest regulatory
uncertainties and challenges producers
and workers at wholesalers and medicinal
cannabis face
and can you give us a quick update on
the medical cannabis ecosystem what are
the latest changes in legislation in
jurisdiction
services medicine cannabis
thank you so much for your kind
introduction
this is a very long question and i can
actually speak for the next three hours
about the regulatory environment within
germany and europe
but i would like to touch on just three
through theirs uh
just i would say in the last couple of
months
the first one is with respect to the
production producers there are a lot of
new producers coming up
in particular
we have heard that this morning already
producers coming from the european union
like in spain
greece
and other countries
but there are also cultivators
in other
countries outside of the european union
who would like to get
their products exported into europe and
to june
they are currently facing a significant
issue which is
receiving their
certification for their performance
those who are outside of the european
union need to have an inspection
off-site inspection of the facility in
order to get the eu gp certification by
the respective authorities
in germany
as
you to call it currently we have trailer
restrictions we have a long list of
different
producers in countries outside of the
european union who are waiting for
officers coming over to their side and
to get respective eu certification and
we will see
hopefully what is
to a certain extent overcome
these
for our clients is that indoor growing
is
at least the basis for
a steady quality
which can be much more easily achieved
under these certain circumstances of
indoor growing than in greenhouse or
even outdoor
and with respect to the
german monography
with
quality
provisions regarding
cannabis the thc content should not
deviate more as times 10 from division
which is a challenge for producers and
even some producers who are currently
exporting them to germany may have
difficulties to really
reach this plus minus 10 percent and
last but not least the wholesalers we
have heard of this mod already
they are under are confronted with the
price
erosion
is a price reduction and another price
fight right now
the
respective agreements between the
health insurance association and the
pharmacies to fix the price to a maximum
of 952
for per gram of flowers
it was an indication of certain price
control
and we see that this 952 program
from the wholesale to the pharmacy
which have a significant impact
and
reduced pricing significance
in 1996 there were the last reform um
and then we had a still literally until
and 2017 germany legalized medical
cannabis but only due to a personal to a
private patient
litigating his right to foreign
and the court accepted this right and
provided him
the option to drop this all americans at
home and then the federal government
said nobody doesn't want that we don't
want the patients about their own
cannabis it's too much of a
distress for society for police
lot of foreign medical cannabis that was
a milestone of course
but in regard to hemp and recreational
cannabis there's still sales that until
we had 2017 the last elections
the last elections and the green party
were negotiating with the liberals and
the conservatives
for a coalition
for
for the support of micah coalition this
coalition negotiations lasted four weeks
and then the liberals said no we don't
want to
govern
because we might put government falsely
so
at all
and then the main coalition came and
another skill set
so that's four years
but then you saw two important decisions
by the courts by the ecg in november
saying the kind of web case
at stake was cbd eliquid and
the
ecg said
no cbd has no psychoactive properties
and the french government couldn't prove
any
health risks for the
population
so they said it's uh movements of goods
the principle applies here it's legal in
the czech republic and has to believe in
france as well that was also a milestone
from the god and then
in march
this year
because law enforcement said you can't
give away any head product to their
consumer for consumption purposes
the federal court of justice said then
okay you can give it to the head
consumer which is a very big change was
a very good change but still the
question of
the misuse of interpretation is not
clear right now so that's why we decided
to start a procedure on the principle of
removal of goods
we applied for a general decree for
clients of us
because the cbd flowers are very popular
in germany flowers they are legal in
luxembourg austria
and
belgium
so if they are in these eu countries
they should be eaten in germany too and
we applied at the
federal office of consumer protection
for this general degree
this was dismissed in this application
and so we started
yesterday two days ago
we filed a lawsuit to the administrative
court of contract
helps me that the court will say okay
it's
it's a matter of you being not here
but
he may have would be if the next
election outcome would be that
we had another before and liberalize
these regulations
thank you man
and let's get a question to you um
what do you think what are the most
important questions farmers should ask
themselves before entering the german
industry from a regulatory point of view
can you tell us something about the
ecosystems that are in place here of
course
i think it's very important to
understand
that the end market and the medical
economics market are totally different
so you should always be aware that you
have to prepare as well as you can
before entering the markets
because there will be a lot of struggles
or there are still struggles
entering the market and i think
it will take some time to regulate
everything
it's getting better and better since
2017.
now we have a regulation and you should
be very well prepared
because you need a long breath and it's
not like running a
sprint it's more like running a monitor
entering the market
and
yeah for example the medicine market you
you also have to
to face a lot of uh
questions regarding or from your local
authorities opium shelter
and registering the products and
i think this is now more regulated than
the end market in my opinion and
yeah so you should always think about
that it takes much more time than you
expect
and
yeah
so
there are two um things there's hemp
against cannabis and within all of that
there's cd peter
cbd lifestyle
well
if you look into the cbd market
and into the regulatory environment
regarding cbd products
and you can actually sell cbd products
in three different sections
one is cosmetics including
gts
the second one is good sound evidence
i'll come to that in a minute and the
third one is
so with regard to cosmetics the
respective
[Music]
rules and regulations of the directive
for cosmetics of the european union
deployment which are not that stupid
however you have to be careful with
regarding the cbd to be implemented into
the cbd product because the german
economics act sees it is much stricter
and currently put that in comparison to
the european directive
and here
the european court of justice decision
which my colleague just mentioned may
help in the future
as we're clearly stating that cbd is
with respect to the fruit side event i
think there's an european commission
very clearly
confirmed that these food supplements
which contain cbd need to be registered
under the global food directive of the
european union so
we have currently about 40 or 45 maybe
50 respective applications for student
supplements
pending
to be recognized as
which
includes cbd and last but not least with
regard to medicine products containing
you need as you discussed this morning
in the first place
authorization about the authorization
for these drugs
so you have to be careful if
the ball alive between supplements
cosmetics and medicine products is the
medical claim if you have a product
for example which is a nicer supplement
you have
[Music]
improving your health condition to a
certain extent like
it's helpful for skin inflammations that
would qualify that prolapse medicine
product
and definitely
so the cbd market
difficult is moving forward with the
help of the european court of justice
and this
is an advantage
thank you kai what would you say
in all this
regulatory crazy
[Music]
as we say in german what will
the
elections play in terms of cannabis
reform and what factors could limit or
destroy the success of ongoing cannabis
reform
yeah the the elections will play a bit
well this year we are at a decisive
point in time here in germany as i
mentioned before
there were still some still there over
two decades almost
and this year germany has the chance to
start reform in all three areas
of cannabis
and at the moment it looks like that
this reform will take place because when
the
final results of the federal elections
will be clear at the 26th of
september so in four weeks time
we will see that we will have a new
chancellor a new government a new
coalition new parties and in every
constellation at least one party
probably two parties for complete
legalization of cannabis for
recreational cannabis and all parties in
the cbo agreed at the end of
because we see the law and we saw law
enforcement actions since january really
strict and
powerful law enforcement actions even
against handily key trailers and he has
been on the shelves in germany for
decades and
law enforcement decided early this year
also to go after handy
because it's canvas and it's
not possessed and
from that
point it's comprehensible to
is a great product and we see that with
everything every we can make a
discussion of everything is a cbd
product it's a supplement is there is
phd in it
is the cfg called enough to be uh
then we have the uh
ecg ruling which which helps but that is
a strong need for cannabis reform and i
hope that the
new government will also take early
steps right after
the new government came in place
for
decriminalization it's very very
important point that should be the first
measure of a new government and then we
can agree on the rules for recreational
uh in the next two years but the
accumulated immunization would be a big
advance
step
and then we can talk about modern
projects
and and how the rules will work on
that
okay just add that right here
we have to use
currently on the spot we are
representing one of the largest
producers in germany and they had a
wonderful team in that portfolio
system also believed to study
for two reasons reason number one
it is against the law to insert b
to c
uh and secondly it has exactly an effect
so it was from pure help
no thc definitely not
what actually happened
what really happened was uh the
federal court uh actually decided e2c is
possible oh my clients thought oh that's
fine
but then they are using an expert
witness
who actually
stated that if you use the hemp tea
leaves
and put that into
cookies
and bake it
[Music]
but that is something which
is kind of strange
we hope that this is going to change in
particular with regard to hemp because
industrial hemp as we all know has been
on
on the shelves have have been sold
for a long time
so
this shows this hatchery heterogeneous
environment which we're facing in the
different areas of cbd products and
products
so let me just quickly back to
how would you say
if we get cannabis regulation for
recreational cannabis in germany how
would this affect medicinal cannabis and
products here
of course this would be uh it was called
this was would cause a boom the green
rush
[Music]
hundreds thousands of companies
only dealing with irrigation kind of
thousands of jobs tax revenues
and
engineering businesses taking care of
the product quality
and consulting services uh
yeah that would have a great impact of
course
as
our
panel before they discussed already the
american campus industry will
probably get not a problem but
they always have a natural advantage in
the market because of the option of
reimbursement
the public health providers
so but then we have to focus on really
medical uh purposes
and the studies and then we need more
evidence and more uh more painful twice
clinical studies
designation areas where patients can
rely on
the the normal patient probably would go
up to the recreational market and
get their medicine for
their own therapy therapy there
so
but the market will open up we have 600
to 800 tons of dry flowers to the black
market in the regression black market in
germany
so there's lots of potential for for
that if we have
but i think that
both markets
can coexist because the first one is the
regression market and then it is
regulated in another way and the second
one is
that the patients get the costs covered
by the public health insurance so maybe
the medical market will
be a little bit um
smaller
but i think both markets can work
for sure yes but then of course the
public health insurers probably ask
why should we pay such a
such a expensive therapy they just go to
the next uh
yeah
still i think like we should not
underestimate the need for a doctor when
you're a sick person so
i definitely also think that medicinal
cannabis will still exist even though we
have a regulatory environment for
recreational cannabis
let's talk about regulatory environment
in the european union basically we have
a free trade union here in the european
union unless we're talking about
cannabis peter um
what possibilities do you see for
regulatory organization
level
yeah i think we need to go back a little
bit in history
and you may ask
and this is a resolution
of the european parliament dated on 13th
february 2019
which calls the european commission
to harmonize
the european
legal environment for the use of
medicinal colors
it has not been re-recognized
this is the initial step forward for
creating a new directive which needs
then to be implemented
in the respective legislations of the eu
united states
and it has been that it was published
celebrated by the chambers yes yeah we
are going forward
probably nobody has read it completely
but if you look into those 18 different
points
i would like to cite just two points
to make you understand where the danger
of those resolutions the point itself
reads as follows
calls our member states to reconsider
the relevant legislation of the use of
currency-based medicines
scientific research proves that the same
positive effect can be achieved by using
ordinary medicines that do not have
addictive effects
oops
that is something which is totally
contrary to the development which we
have earlier in the market and the
number 14 is the universe
calls on the commission to work with
member states to ensure that safe and
controlled cannabis used for menstrual
purposes can only be in the form of
cannabis revived products that have gone
through clinical trials regulatory
assessment and approval
which is not yet the case as you all
know who is
the pharmacist is going to do a hand
manufacturing thing before he hands it
over to the patients so there is no uh
relationship approval necessary no
marketing improvement
and as such uh you know this is is kind
of dangerous if the eu commission will
follow and implements the respective uh
direction
so the industry has to work against that
has to work with the information in
order to
have an environment a regulatory
environment throughout your
establishment
for the industry and not against the
interests of things
when this will be implemented while
nobody else corbit has of course uh
slowed down each and every process uh
for the year in commission and they are
not as quick as you know
in general
but
there's a process going on and we have
as an industry
to to
put forward our interests
and to lobby the interests of the
respective
only agree uh it's in each and every one
of our responsibilities to lobby for
policy and to be there and to
work together as an industry so we can
get a more harmonized and also
operatable regulatory framework where
our interests are reflected in and we're
not there taking decisions that we have
to work with that in the end
so we're always at the end like i have
one last question for all the speakers
what is your personal message to our
founders and investors having a look at
the cannabis regulatory environment many
times
yeah look at the rules the state of line
but don't let them
over value
if it's too
confusing or it doesn't make sense
and i think
you should have a very long breath and
you have to fight
make yourself available with the
heterogeneous
regulatory environment not only within
europe but also within germany different
states has different views as you heard
this morning on what kind of products
are it has an impact on your on your
business
and of course how any of the investments
and as such make yourself familiar with
all these different and
heterogeneous regulations
okay great um
yeah
yeah do we have time we have science
there's a question right there look he's
so excited
here
[Music]
market here as in
non-champions
has anybody heard about any
conversation landing or if that's moving
forward
yeah we have indeed currently a route
of colorless products which are just
gacp processed into europe and into the
german market as well
products are then here we've refined
under eu gop certification and then sold
into the market the authorities are
looking very closely into discipline
because of patient safety of course is
something which
is top on that is
and we'll see how the authorities react
but they are watching it very very
closely and
also whether these products which are
important to the european union and into
their data to germany
we know one
producer from ui via spain into germany
has been the only
ghcp process there is a kind of a great
zone between regarding the trying
process free trial is allowed under jcp
really a further driving process is gnp
and would then require gdp certification
so and if you have a product which
arrives in europe which has the ability
of maybe 20 or less
that might not be gacp process
and so
only in gsp process this may be also a
gmp
process which of course would
lead to certification it is not entirely
useless
currently the night of the german
authorities are looking into that in
particular some of the lower
pharmaceutical authorities in the
various states
where the importers are located
thank
questions
you're so informative apparently you've
talked about everything
for the whole panel
[Applause]
you