so welcome everybody to the novel food
panel novel food is a regulation that is
specific to the european union still
across europe there are countries that
are not part of the european union like
the uk and switzerland those countries
carry a different regulatory framework
even though they're dealing with the
same ingredient
i'm happy to introduce to you three
knowledgeable speakers from slovenia
germany and switzerland who will give
you great insight in their personal
experience with novel food and some
long-term prospects for europe
so let's start with dr marietta chesan
marietta works at farmerham since three
years her current position at farmerham
is chief regulatory officer
she's an expert in the field of global
legal requirements for cannabis related
consumer products such as cosmetics food
supplements and medicinal products
and she's the responsible person author
of farmer hemp's application for the
authorization of novel food that were
successfully submitted to the ec and uk
fsa
then we have mr kaifri de nirman
kaifritri is a specialized lawyer for
hemp and cannabis kai is a member of the
international cannabis bar association
and working with cannabis companies
across the globe
kai puts his energy into
sustainably establishing a cannabis
industry as one of the most significant
industries of the future and kai is
working with different clients that are
in the process of the novel food
application
and then we have dr francis garland and
he's the founder and managing director
of cloud 9 in switzerland a life science
company
based focused on the development and
commercialization of pharmaceuticals and
nutraceuticals based on medicinal plants
particularly cannabis and his vast
experience in fast-moving consumer goods
tobacco fuel
future pharmaceuticals flavors and so on
so forth
so let's get started uh kai can you give
us maybe a quick overview on what novel
food is and what the process of the
applications are at the moment
yeah sure so last time i sat here at
icbc was april 2019
three months after the novel food
catalogue has changed and we predicted
at that time that strict law enforcement
measures will take place and guess what
that took place until now
but
the whole story so
before january 2019
the novel food entry was that
cbd
is not a novel food unless
it doesn't exceed the natural contents
of the plant
so this was a very broad definition not
very precise
but the industry could live with that so
if you had a 2.5 5 cbd oil it would have
been marketable by that time
but then intense discussions between
several european member states it took
place
spain started that in august 2018 and
removed all cbd products from the
shelves
it went
on with austria in december
saying that a
general decree issuing to the governors
of the municipalities
saying that they should um enforce the
novel food directive because all the cbd
oils were deemed as novel food and then
we had the
change in the catalogue in january 2019
addressing now all extracts of cannabis
all extracts of cannabis
and it doesn't matter which kind of
cannabinoid it can be cbd cbg cbn
so all these extracts of cannabis
from then on
novel food
and then we had in germany the
the the public announcement by the
federal protection by the federal office
of consumer protection um saying that
there is no constellation possible where
a product as food
is marketable when containing cbd
and that was the end of the cbd industry
we helped to know or we had known so far
to that point
and then i had the european industrial
hemp association decided in june 2019
to start a joint application procedure
ir by now has
over 300 members
taking part in this consortium in this
novel food joint application consortium
and every company can take part in this
consortium so
um the aim was to collect uh 3 million
3.5 million euros
for conducting several tax studies which
are necessary to get the approval by
efsa
for these
joint applications
for these joint applications
and
ir has achieved that so we are
one third of the way right now
um and um there are four applications
for for this novel food joint
application it's isolate it's a raw
product it's a gold extraction and it's
a raw product they are all
decarboxylated
but not the war one is not destilated
information you can see on ihr webpage
and
the
procedure started so the the top studies
are prepared and i are starting now in
the in the concrete phase
of really
doing the the talk studies starting with
animal later on in the later stage also
with human exposure
and uh yeah that's the that's the status
we have seen a couple of circumvention
strategies in the market
uh from labeling as cosmetic as aroma
extract as a roma product
but the next two years will be very
difficult for the companies to stay on
the market to keep their products on the
shelves um and
after that
the the the fully potential of the cbd
market will will unlock with the
with the with the uh
yeah approval by by efsa for noble food
and um
until then yeah let's let's see how it
works
okay thank you um francis you're a swiss
company but you're also looking at the
uk market can you maybe give us an a
quick update on what is happening in the
uk um actually i was calling
some friends of mine this morning to
find out and i was checking also the
website of the fsa to find out if there
was anything new there hasn't been
anything new since april 26th when they
published a document listing the
i think four different companies that
have had
their applications
validated
and i make the difference between
validated and authorized because to date
no products have been authorized by the
fsa in the uk
and we still seem to be quite far away
from that
of the products i think there are
there weren't that many actually most of
them were a synthetic cbd
and from the echoes that i get from the
uk market it's it's looking that
authorities are very more favorable
towards synthetic to to any broad
spectrum
extracts or anything distillates like
that
i also heard that uh in terms of process
and we were talking about it just before
normally the fsa they said they were
going to publish the list of companies
that have had their
applications validated
however that list hasn't changed since
april 26th so it seems to be um
in delay in terms of the publications
they're not the fsa are not
keeping to the process that they they
wanted to engage with and i think i can
understand that maybe there are some
legal implications as well
in terms of when the authority is
publishing a list of companies that also
has implications for business and
commerce right so
um i can understand maybe the fsa are a
little bit hesitant to continue down the
road and and naturally they're probably
in communication with the with the
people in brussels as well to try and
maybe harmonize actions so there's no
real news
from the uk side of things
now i'm a swiss company i make chocolate
i make swiss chocolate with a broad
spectrum extract and a cbd extract that
i can only sell in jurisdictions where
novel foods authorization is not
required so we're we're doing that
and i'm waiting actually for my
suppliers to get their authorizations so
then i can make my application from my
chocolate to the authorities and get on
the market so i'm at the end of the
value chain so i'm the customer of
people like margrethe here who
are really at the at the call face uh
tackling all the issues with the
authorities
thank you
you have submitted applications to both
authority authorities in the uk and the
european union um what is your
experience with that and are there many
differences and how the applications are
hello everybody yes that is correct we
have applied at farmer hemp to
different applications now food
applications to boat authorities it's
been over half a year now since that
and what regards the the approaches that
both authorities are taking
basically the rules that apply with
which are pla which do apply are the
same they both follow irregulation and
novel food they both follow eu guidances
for the novel food
however when it comes to the cbd
products there are slight differences
that we have observed
um
one of them is definitely the approach
that fsas of food standards agency in
the uk has taken
they basically left on the shelves the
cbd products that are at the moment
related to the novel food applications
that were submitted
before the end of march this year
this rule has slightly changed as you
probably know the first announcement of
the fsa was that the valid that the
novel food applications have to be
actually validated
in order to have the products legally on
the market this has changed in the
middle of march
i guess the authorities didn't cope with
the amount of applications that they
were receiving by that time
so they've changed it to just submit it
and as my colleague here says before
this is kind of related probably to the
to the fact that it's just too many
applications over there and um this is
one of the main changes i would say that
when we compare
ec
or efsa to the uk food standards agency
the next one is the public list that we
also already discussed this is something
that ec hasn't considered yet and
probably won't consider
but in the case of uk authorities try to
be more
market oriented to how to say and the
list indeed hasn't changed till now
there are five companies there
it's about 50 products that have passed
the validation
the public list contains also additional
lists with the on-hold applications
but also that part hasn't been updated
basically it's empty since the the
announcement of that public list so
it looks like
something is on hold
by by them not by by the applications
themselves um
another one which i found quite
interesting is the fact that
the rapid alert system for food and feed
which is a
rasff system in europe
if you check the notifications on that
portal you can see that unauthorized use
of cbd products is relatively often
on the list
so authorities in eu members are kind of
dealing with the cbd products on the
market
but i've been certain i've been
following also the fsa list or their
announcements and there hasn't been any
recall or any unauthorized use published
on there on their web page so this is
another
thing that we can say that that's
different in the case of uk this might
be again related to the fact that they
are putting everything on hold i think
because they are not really
i think they have a lot of other things
to do as well because of the brexit and
they are basically
quite busy at the moment so yeah
thank you um so
we see there's apparently there's a
delay as well as in the uk as well as in
european union kai what are the biggest
important factors that uh or that can
delay
the process when it comes to novel food
and do you know how many applications
have been handed in in total with the
fsa in the european uh commission and
what the current status is there
i don't know the exact number it's hard
to find the exact number it's about 50
probably
you ask about the delay that's a good
question i'm just a lawyer not a
scientist but
the the talk studies will be the crucial
part of this uh these this process and
it's the biggest stock study on thc
commissioned by iha which there has ever
been
so i assume that on the way on these
talks studies they will pop up problems
which no one expected and which have to
be solved then and which maybe can
delight the the the process um it's not
only about cbd this this this novel food
joint application it's also about thc uh
which is um
is just as important because we have
these strict thc thresholds for food
in the european union
the the so-called ar fd
by by efsa the acute reference doses and
these reference doses is so low
that you hardly can put a
product on the market um without
yeah having to fear to to to break these
threshold
and to have a call back by the
authorities etc and the aim of iha is to
increase this threshold by seven times
so that you have seven microgram per
kilogram body weight uh as a daily
intake
and then you can work with these
threshold and what pops up in this
process in these toxicological studies
uh maybe mageita knows about that as
well uh this we don't know that yet we
are all confident that
the the the they will be conducted
successfully and and on time
but you don't know what efsa comes up
with and no that's not sufficient please
do some more
add something on there we have another
problem do this do that we can't we
can't tell that right now but we are
confident that the process will be
finished within 2023.
thank you so much
what do you think are important factors
that will help to get a successful
approval and maybe you can tell us a
little bit what you've done for your
novel food application and what steps
you had to go through
yeah so
rule number one followed essa's
requirements i think this is the most
important important one uh with all the
notes that they put in the guidances um
they really want to know everything for
now we've been in communication with
both the fsa and efsa and they really if
they say you know preferably five
batches you need to do the analysis on
all five batches it's it's as that
simple
um
another thing yeah regarding our status
we have both applications in the
pre-validation
step and if so suitability check
um for the that one which is now in the
phase of if so suitability check we are
basically we are having a tc conference
with afsa authorities they will give us
some further clarification on their
requirements that have been submitted to
us in august
so i'm having this conference which is
part of asa supports supporting
initiative in september we'll see how it
goes but usually they are quite uh
they do respond to our questions they do
try to answer also our questions so it's
a constant communication with them
the same goes with fsa they do respond
thank you so francis let's say um
in the uk
novel food applications go through like
if any but will this do you think if it
will have any impact on the european
market if the if there are products
approved with a novel food in the uk i
don't have a crystal ball
but i would imagine absolutely yes
because
i mean they're the biggest trading
partners between the uk and the eu
anyways so there's going to have to be
some sort of a
harmonization there between the two
systems probably the fsa will come first
before the eu because the eu seem to be
i don't know on life support there
there's no nothing coming out of
brussels you say you have good
communication that's great but they
don't seem to be making much progress
right at the eu level and i mean last
year you remember they put all the
dossiers on hold the 50 years old
dossiers back in when was it march last
year because they had the preliminary
review remember the legal review from
the
digi-sante and they said that it was a
narcotic
remember that and then we had to wait
until november when uh it came out that
from the european court of justice that
okay it's not a narcotic and then what
two two or three days later the european
commission came out with their statement
saying okay all the dossiers are back
back in progress again but since
november
nothing
right so um if
if the uk
get ahead in the race to actually
develop this market in europe for sure
there's going to be a consequence going
to be an impact do you think we we
should be more pushing from the industry
side that we get some results and that
there is more progress do you think we
should push more
uh at the european level
general
i think that's being done by your
colleagues in i i have eiha they're
doing that and there's some other
associations very active in brussels and
companies also in private comp you know
canadians they have offices set up in
brussels and they're doing a lot of
lobbying uh in in the
in the brussels corridors so i think
that's happening
i don't know if anyone's listening
that's where i have most of my doubts
yeah and then you know i think the uk
their authorities fsa like i think they
received something over 800 applications
a lot of them didn't even get past the
rf number when they registered you know
when you register online your
application you get an rf number and
then you go to the next step but a lot
of the companies didn't get to the next
step because they didn't have their
applications done the right way like you
guys
so
um
i can't really say any more than that
thank you
so
let's jump a little bit to another topic
but that goes to the same authority um
let's talk about health claims and false
advertiser advertisement kai
what is the problem with this from a
legal perspective
yeah this is a the third obstacle of the
cbd business
the the first is a novel food the second
is thc and the third is health claims
so
i started to work in the industry 2017
and by that time i didn't know what cbd
is at all
and everyone asked me what is that
how is it legally how can you see that
and then the work started and we jumped
in as lawyers and to gather and to
collect the legal framework what's
what's going on
and
then you saw the boom the cbd boom
so
numbers skyrocketing the sales numbers
and
why is that because this product is so
popular so many people having so many
expectations for their life for their
well-being for their homeless studies
i don't really can't i can't explain it
to myself
today even today that is so so popular
uh by
but by by that
by that expectations you have that
at this product
it's just one step to have a health
claim
it's good for your homostasis is also a
borderline case and if you start it's
good for cancer it's
it's good for even covet 19 maybe
it's a clear health claim and by that
you need to have an authorization for
that product according to the medicines
act in in in the european union
so but then the marketing departments
from the companies coming and asking
what can we say we need to say something
our ceo
needs some bullet points and
then they set up on their web pages
like cbd
question q question answer
areas and uh
yeah describing the history of cbd the
proper the possible
designation areas
and
that's all wrong that's all wrong if you
do that i can tell you if you get
in the eye of the
authorities and they find these
these
questions and answers these
tips these
these areas on your web page they will
designate your product as a medicine and
you have a problem um so that's the big
problem of the of the whole business you
have a wonderful product
people love it but you can't tell why
and you set up a nice brand and nice
graphics and you have a nice
shop in in berlin or
what is it a flex store and everything
looked nice and the people coming in and
you can tell them what what this is
about this is a this is a problem and
will only uh
be solved if there might be a health
claim accepted
and um and
in the we
we will be
accepted by the eu commission and will
be listed in the u health claim
catalogue then might be one day this
problem will solve but it doesn't look
like like this right now
thank you so much how are you dealing
with functional and health claims and
what is your opinion on the issue of
false claims
so i think this issue is a bit more
general it's not related only to the cbd
products it's basically related to all
consumer products that can be purchased
nowadays
the kind of new miracles that cure
cancer appear almost every day and i
think this is a common problem of false
claims for the whole industry not just
the cbd industry
um in the eu like it was mentioned
before we do have an established system
of nutritional claims the claims that
you know like low fat low sugar claims
which can be completely legally used for
certain products under certain
circumstances and the same goes with the
health claims there's a register
you register of
authorized health claims such as the
claims that are used typically for
vitamins for minerals
which can be illegally used so without
breaching any law
when it comes to the cbd it's true
there's no
authorized claim for the moment
available in the eu but we at pharma
hemp have decided to go a step further
and start with the project
another application for the
authorization of the health claim that
will be related or is related to the
certain condition
i'm personally involved i'm going to be
the author of this health claim
authorization dossier and i must say
that this is even more complex project
and even more demanding tasks than the
novel foods to be honest
um
partially this is related also to the
fact that the new transparency
regulation came into force this has
happened this march and i think that
the whole process because of that new
regulation is even more difficult and
even more complex but yeah we will try
to do it i'm working on this project now
for a few months
it is an interesting new thing a lot of
clinical data has to be reviewed but
we'll see how how fast will i be
hopefully we'll
submit the application by the end of
this year
and francis how are you dealing with
health claims
we don't make any health claims
simple we we comply with the law
and i mean when i started my journey
also back in 2017 at the same time the
first thing i did was i went and met
with my local authorities in switzerland
and i said what do i need to do to
comply with the law so they said things
like well it has to be a eu certified
hemp it has to be a traditional
extraction process can't contain any thc
because in switzerland we actually have
a regulation in the contaminants direct
ordinance for contaminants and food
products
uh specific levels unlike the eu i mean
we actually have a regulation in
switzerland uh for that and um
and basically it's it's
zero with a lot of decimal points okay
um
and um and no health claims that was the
final thing they said to me they said
you cannot make a health claim because
it's a food product falls under food law
so that's it simple
thank you
so um can i add one more thing though
sure because um
to follow on what margarita was saying
about the category of like vitamins
probiotics because that's a nice
category where
if you do get a product approved and we
are actually in the process of doing
that in canada at the moment for our
chocolate
not the cbd one but using hemp seed oil
so we're using the nutritional
properties of hemp seed oil as a
superfood to also get it approved as a
as a natural health product because in
in health canada they have that category
of nhps so then we can also sell our
chocolate in pharmacies or power
pharmacies or health food stores and
make health claims
that's very interesting
so um
maybe again to you francis um
maybe you are brave enough to look in
the glass bubble um so how long do you
estimate will it take to get the first
approval of cannabini cannabinoid
related novel food ingredients and how
long will it take to bring those uh
market products to the consumer and what
which products do you think will be most
likely
yes
authorized
we've been waiting two i know i i my
supplier has been waiting two i know a
year and a half years since they they
made their applications to the authority
they didn't wait till march to make that
they made them already a year before in
the uk still waiting uh same with the
european commission still waiting in
brussels so i don't know i mean i really
don't know i and i don't think anyone
knows yeah
wait do you think any products have a
better chance of getting faster approval
over others
yeah this is what we've discussed before
maybe the synthetic cbd is the most
prominent one however
also with what regards natural hem
derived products i think that
the isolated forms of cbd might be
a bit faster than than the full spectrum
or broad spectrum extracts but
again this really depends on the
application itself if it's
good quality application it might be
faster
and not rejected at the end
thank you so um another question kai
what do you think if there are approvals
of
novel food applications how will this
affect all the other companies who don't
have approval
yeah so we at i have we
are assuming that
by these talk studies which are
conducted now
we will get or this application will get
data protection
according to article 27 of the novel
food directive
so no other company can refer to the
results of these talk studies
only the licensees of iha of iha project
gmbh can refer to these results for a
period of five years
so uh
all members now who joined the
consortium have a have a clear market
advantage
in this time
this is for sure
and all the other companies which did it
on their own as well so probably you
have to have a lot of data and a lot of
stock studies and this data protection
will be granted we assume that very very
strongly
and all others companies which are not
licensed but don't have any any um
we are not affiliated or associated to
any of the licenses or of these noble
food
authorizations will have a problem
and not i only i have will
kick them out or we'll send them the
cease and desist letters
for stopping distribution
the authorities as well so
it's still time to join iha
it's maybe i can tell it's a
2 500 euros for the membership
as a minimum fee below 1 million
euro revenue and it increases the more
revenue you make it stops at over 20
million revenue per year it will be
actually 190 000 euros
you can pay that in three um
three parts
and um
yeah so
it's
nineteen thousand
and two thousand five hundred below one
revenue that's the starting point uh and
uh the fees will increase every half
year
and uh aya is still open for uh for new
members in this consortium
i can only strongly recommend to
to to to organize something like this
okay thank you
so
we're basically through with our
questions but this will leave us a
little bit more time for taking
questions from the audience
if there are any
that's fantastic let's hear it for lisa
in the panel so far
thank you to all the panelists also
so i've got a question actually this is
an issue that kai brought up and i think
maybe francis will be facing uh
obviously novel food is not just cbd
right it's anything it could be thc
what's going to happen in switzerland as
of next year how is food going in in you
know with thc going to be dealt with or
etc and what if how
if any way do you think that path is
going to be different
i'll start to answer that because i what
margarita is referring to
is since may the 15th in switzerland our
ministry of health has opened uh to
receiving applications
for a new swiss pilot program that has
been approved by the government after a
couple of years of going through the
legislative process to modify our
narcotics law
allowing for a study to take place
so it's a study a minimum five years
to evaluate um
and to collect data uh on whether we
want to legalize uh recreational
cannabis in the country so you know
switzerland loves to do referendums
we're always doing referendums every
three months practically
so probably in five years time there's
going to be a big referendum
the nice thing is that in order to
change just to modify the narcotics law
actually all a lot of the stakeholders
in switzerland
were favorable to it they they allowed
at the political parties and
representatives the the medical
community so it's it's interesting
because we realize that in switzerland
we have over 220 000 uh consumers of
illegal cannabis
in the country so it's not a drop in the
ocean anymore you know for a population
of 9 million so so there's a consensus
and you know this also falls in line
with switzerland's more progressive
attitude uh for many years um on
on
drug drug laws so um
the idea there marguerite is that
it'll be under uh the protocols of a
study so it's a scientific study so
that's how we are being allowed now to
uh put products into the market and and
the thing is the participants of the
products now will be recruited by the
study organizers 5 000 participants per
study in all the cantons we have 26
cantons so you can do the math and you
can see what the potential market will
be for this particular study
so under that under that framework of a
scientific study it's been approved it's
been allowed okay so from next year um
we'll be able to put into actually i'm
starting now actually because we have
our we have our application i got nice
news a few weeks ago that our
application to do
a chocolate containing thc is now into
the database and made available to all
the study organizers in the country so
we'll be able to do a nice swiss
chocolate with cbd and with thc for your
pleasure and enjoyment
[Applause]
i got the cbd ones for you
any more questions
no one has questions
at all not even for like maybe the
recipe for the swiss chocolate with the
cbd how much thc should i put in it
we're allowed up to 20
up to twenty percent well let's start
let's start with that uh i don't know
i've become a lightweight now so like
five milligrams per serving so ten
little squares on our bar
five migs per little square you should
almost do like one big for little square
because who's going to eat half of a bar
yeah exactly you're going to eat the
whole bar maybe some food but might get
better
than your 83 more so yeah
you know that's how it goes no no
questions at all
closing statements
sure i wish everybody success who has
applied for novel food so
that's the right answer
well all right we'll just play bingo
let's hear it for everybody then thank
you