welcome to our panel
doing business internationally
and i'm proud i'm glad to have two real
experts here on stage
on the right on the very right we have
uh
rudolph
ruffier
he is
for he's
working for the
one of the biggest law firms in the
world for clifford chance a london-based
law firm
and
they
also
are now
consulting cannabis investments
and on my right we have pete paterson
from welkin medical who is the leading
then the leading
danish extractor for medical cannabis
products
and they are licensed
since 2018 in denmark
no incorporated we just got licensed
this year uh sorry yeah they
incorporated uh since 2018 they got
licensed this year
and i think uh
you just tell us a little bit about your
activities in denmark
is this on oh there we go
uh so yeah we are extracting in denmark
taking some cannabis flower from the
various cultivation companies that are
there there's some phenomenal quality
that's being grown we're turning into
oil and
that's heading to places like here in
germany
and we're eu gmp
certified
for real
rudolph um cannabis is uh not so long a
topic in your company i think not such a
long time how did it come a big law firm
uh is uh
interested in the cannabis market right
now thanks michael well cleve
as you said a very large law firm we're
a full service business law firm we're
based in london but we have offices all
over the world i'm based in australia
uh and in europe and i do international
disputes our cannabis practice has been
kicking off i'd say five to six years
ago and interestingly it started off
here in germany in dusseldorf frankfurt
and munchen
we do mostly regulatory matters
corporate matters mna in our cannabis
practice
out of germany but i take care of the
divorce side of things i'm afraid the
disputes
that's why i'm here to talk to you about
today
thank you very much um pete my first
question to you um
you're you also have experience in the
canadian cannabis market
what's the main difference to the
european cannabis market
i would say
the commercial flexibility uh i think we
know that the canadian market is much
more mature
um while we see the european market
really just starting to develop its legs
right now trying to figure out um how
patients are going to be granted access
in canada there was a wonderful program
with mail order cannabis
for access versus here you know seeing
in germany they actually have cannabis
going through the pharmacies right so
yeah it's just maturity i see it
following a very similar path in terms
of how
um cannabis
industry has been maturing from
say the north american markets and over
here and watching yeah it's almost
almost like watching it happen
in the future right like we can we can
we can see how it's been evolving and
it's like it's already been mapped out
for us everything starts with
cultivation then we start to see lots of
extraction happening then we see more
focus on brands and distribution and
access
and
would you say it's
or let me ask let me ask something
different um why didn't you not come to
germany and grow because germany on
growers grow cannabis or extract
cannabis why did you come why did you go
to denmark because the law in germany
was implemented a lot earlier much
earlier than in denmark was it harder to
apply here or
well i didn't want to commute compete
with the demi can guys they had such a
great proposal that was the first one
but no on the other side of things like
we took a look at the german market
great market
but
we were looking for something with a
little bit more commercial access
denmark didn't have any restrictions on
how much we could produce
where we could send it what we could do
so it was really that just that
commercial viability
also on the danger side of things
just kind of you know doing business
internationally we took a look at the
government infrastructure and how much
support was at that government level and
how stable
that program was and that was another
big indicator because we were looking at
portugal or greece or or germany and it
just it just made sense in denmark it
was like an eight out of nine vote um to
be passed through by law so if the
political regime was to change there was
still majority favor for that um
so it just it just made sense for us for
our investment
rudolfi thanks a lot um
as i you know in europe we have
a very lot different regulations on
medical cannabis europe based in
australia australia is also important to
the german market
as a lawyer what would your as a as an
investment expert what would you
recommend somebody who wants to make
canada business in europe how where
should he go because there are a lot of
countries who announced that they will
have a medical cannabis program i
remember like greece for example
some work in portugal some work in
denmark
some work in australia what would you
recommend a strategy to enter the
european market okay thanks michael
actually i would like to second what
pete has just told you guys a couple of
seconds ago
i would first and foremost recommend a
stable country
politically stable
cannabis stable
uh cannabis and it's not unlike other
industries frankly i mean i do a lot of
mining and and oil as well so
big dirty stinky stuff that is quite
controversial right
um and the attitude toward those
industries is fluctuating
cannabis is the same you've seen
countries that have announced in europe
take greece that yeah it's going to be
kind of this party we're going to
liberalize and create a real market
government changes because there are
elections like in any democratic country
and in non-democratic countries boom new
government now you know what canada is
not so sure
you don't want to end up in a country
where that's the case especially if it's
not a very cheap country you know i mean
there are plenty of countries in other
continents and i'm thinking latin
america sub-saharan africa um and
southeast asia where you know high risk
but high reward it's so cheap to grow
stuff there that it might make sense to
take the risk but europe is not cheap
right um so you want to make sure that
the first thing you do is to set up shop
in a country where you know your
operations are legal
and second where you expect they will
remain legal in the years to come so i i
totally get what you've just said pete
and i can only encourage you to do the
same uh of course germany i think is
rock solid frankly uh there's little to
doubt from germany
i'm
spain has been very vocal
i've got some reservations again based
on how they behaved with all their
industries think renewables at the turn
of the 2000s you know they were like oh
yeah we're going to go green so all
those companies you just come make
electricity here with those nice wind
farms and solar panels it's gonna be
expensive but don't worry we will
subsidize you
what do you know six to seven years
later government changes like oh you
know what it costs me a lot of money
this so just forget about the incentives
yeah but i've invested like hundreds of
millions in that country already and you
told me it's based on incentives in my
business model of revolvers and
instances yeah sorry man i can't do
anything for you anymore so that's what
you want to avoid right when you start
uh setting up shop abroad generally
speaking and that's my thoughts on
europe particularly
thank you rudolfi and let me just ask
you
in addition
because
in germany we just got the first
deliveries from south africa and from
lesotho and when
when you normally hear that you also
think or when they announced it i
thought okay this is one of the country
that announced to a grow medical
cannabis which will never come to german
pharmacies and i was quite surprised how
come that that that there's a difference
in results in south africa
um
i think
you know and again
i'm gonna say the same thing
this is new cannabis it's a new industry
now we're at that euphoria stage where
everybody wants to do it because
everybody sees you know there are
billions in in the industry just waiting
up to be made right
and of course african countries are no
exception uh they have seen the
opportunity just like what they have
before with mining and oil they don't
really have the know-hows and financial
capabilities so right now they're
attracting a lot of foreigners and want
to attract a lot of farmers to help them
develop their market and obviously they
know they're not so much a consumer
market but rather an export market for
consuming markets consuming markets have
we've heard earlier from jada it's here
in europe and it's in the u.s so that's
that's why now you've seen those
shipments coming up and there are
companies from canada from um england
and even australia now heavily investing
in south africa lesotho and even
zimbabwe
because they have seen that there is an
opportunity to grow
very good quality hemp and cannabis for
cheap
and then process it maybe in europe or
processing back home in australia and
then export it to consuming markets yeah
thank you rudolfi um my next question
goes out to pete as a canadian
or a canadian based
salesmen and you also know the us market
probably
and everybody is waiting for federal
legalization and
yeah
and
because then first u.s companies could
export to europe as well
and that would be a game changer i think
how do you expect the chances for this
scenario
oh man that's a good one um
so with federal legalization it's in
discussion right now i think the safe
banking act is going to be a good bridge
uh
towards that discussion even further um
i do think uh with the democratic party
that they're gonna
they're gonna use it as a platform for
the next election
that's what i would do if i was in
politics
they don't really have any promises in
their current foundation to say look
we're gonna legalize it during this
four-year period
so why not use that as another
indication to say let's bring in some
votes
it won't be biden because i think he's
going to be too old for the next
presidency but
whoever is the next democratic
leader
using that as a platform to yeah drive
additional votes
so it's a possibility
so
a little patience it's a little patience
i think it will be a game changer it's
going to drive a lot of investment
capital into the business
a lot like a lot of institutional
funding will continue to come in um and
since it's federally legal um and you
know you can expense stuff properly i
think that'll be a pretty big game
changer
and then we're going to start to see
yeah even more capital flood into europe
like we did when it happened in canada
right so uh it just depends on what they
decide to do with that wave of capital
and what types of business decisions are
made in this
international
expansion
thank you
rodolfi
safe banking is a good keyword he just
mentioned um
what obstacles
can cannabis
investors face when it comes to safe
banking which is a very very big issue i
think
right so um
the problem with banking is that and i
think you know the u.s is a very good
textbook example of that
um even when you set up domestic
operations
um banks are super hostile to lending
you money
even if your business is just going to
be in colorado
you say look i just want to set you up
in colorado in colorado i have potential
customers in colorado
business partners in colorado you go to
banking colorado and they're like um
yeah we're going to think about it and
the reason for that is it's not legal at
the federal level you can only imagine
what a bank is going to tell you if you
go to that bank and say hey
i'm going to explain internationally you
know what i'm going to sell my stuff in
say europe in germany it's like whoa
whoa whoa i mean if you told me i'm
going to sell it you know in boulder i'd
be like maybe
dusseldorf
not so sure
um so that's one of the big issues that
i think companies have to cannabis
companies have to solve right now is the
funding
but there are perspectives of hope
because you can see in europe
that um even the eu now is pushing hard
toward legalizing at least cbd
and from the moment you have a
harmonized regulation that covers an
entire region then banks will feel a bit
more comfortable to do that
certainly clifford chance i
historically i gotta say we're not
disputes oriented we're more regulation
oriented and transaction oriented
for the past two years we've had at
least four or five big banks operating
internationally coming to us and asking
all right i think i'm getting ready to
you know start opening the
green gates not not you know cannabis
but the dollars
i want to know
if i can do that and i want to know on a
country per country basis
how exactly i can lend money to cannabis
businesses what kind of businesses and
what conditions and then next step would
be
if i lend money to fund you know
cannabis operations in germany
then can i lend some more money to fund
that business internationally
and and that's how we see at our own
level
that there is a shift that is occurring
right now and that's thanks to you know
that those politics that are taken at a
broader eu level as opposed to country
per country level it still makes it
challenging like being a business
in this environment and dealing with
banks like it's one of the things if
you're looking to expand into germany or
open up in denmark or whatever it may be
um how many north americans do we have
in the room today
okay so a few like i so as a canadian
like i had a canadian business sold
but while we were operating that
canadian business
it i was kicked out of cibc uh rbc
uh
like and this is legalized federally and
we were still kicked out of the banks uh
it was incredible even here in denmark
or here in denmark we're in germany
uh in denmark uh donsko bank uh didn't
want to work with us so we had to go to
one of the smaller banks uh jessica or
i think that's what it's called
the danish friends in here are nodding
at me so i got it uh so yeah banking is
banking is a challenging one um even
though they might be given the thumbs up
they have to do the internal checks and
know your customers and not even just
that just do they want to deal with
cannabis so making sure that you've got
backups
backup banks just in case you get kicked
out
all of a sudden you have nowhere to put
your cash to pay your bills and
collect your customer invoices
um
do you think
that may cause further problems in the
future because uh
cannabis money is already there a lot
and
if you cannot invest with it or deal
legally with it what are the dangers for
the future if that
is not solved within if within a certain
range of time
all right let me say this then and i
think it expands again on what pit has
mentioned and what we have touched upon
a bit earlier in our discussion
it's one thing
to have a business plan
you know contemplating in what
jurisdiction you're going to set up shop
and expand your operations you know
and then take greece you have plans for
greece and then three months later oh
man change of government they don't want
to do cannabis anymore
you know i need to find a new place to
expand my operations but hey at the end
of the day it's fine i've not invested
any money yet it was just a plan
problems arises when
you have already poured your money into
a place
you have applied for a license or even
you have a license or a permit to grow
the stuff or to manufacture it or to
export it
and few months a few years down the line
suddenly then there is a change of
government
um
and suddenly oh wait uh my license been
taken away or i had applied to renew my
license and now the government won't
give it to me problem is it's all
license based right so if you don't have
a license you don't have a business and
you don't have money anymore
um
i'm not here to give investment advice
in that or what are the alternatives for
you as a business to invest in
i'm here to tell you there is a way to
get that money back
or to prevent it from going away and
it's quite simple
it's just that you don't know about it
but i do because it's my job
there is a network
of international investment treaties
they've been developed after world war
ii because everybody wanted to do for an
investment to rebuild europe rebuild the
world so boom 3000 treaties in the span
of 50 years being concluded by countries
on a one-on-one basis on a multilateral
basis but like in the eu right
those treaties are free by definition
there are treaties
but they don't only concern states and
like most treaties they concern you as
businesses why because those treaties
give rights to businesses and those
rights are fairly straightforward my
right is not to be expropriated you know
my company taken away by the government
my license taken away my ip taken away i
have a right to be treated fairly you
know my investment not only cannot be
expropriated but can you just play cat
and mouse with them you cannot tell me
one day here's a license the next day oh
yeah i don't know if i'm going to give
it to you right
and lastly but most importantly you have
access to an alternate judicial system
and if i may just expanding on that
thought
say
you invest and you know i want to take
example of spain it's a bit unfair if
we've got spanish friends here today but
again it's based on recent very recent
history you invest in spain because they
live liberalize the cannabis market they
even give you incentives to grow stuff
there because you know space is nice
nice sun fertile soil there we go
you do that for five years or invest
dozens of millions or a bit less or a
bit more you know depending on the
skills of the operation and then one day
spain's wake up and realize oh you
know those incentives they cost me a lot
of money and at the end of the day i
don't make that much money out of it so
maybe it's time to let them go right all
of a sudden your business model
collapses because it was based on those
incentives
now you could go to spain courts and you
know the spain judicial system comparing
it to the french one say is roughly
similar it's fine we have independent
judges
but it's very slow
and on top of that
cannabis is political
i can see in my own country you know
home country france
that not everyone is very happy about
the perspective of even just legalizing
cbd right
you've got people and and not just a few
like half the people really in france
like i don't like cannabis i don't want
to do any of that and
you go to local courts and of course
you've got local judges you don't pick
your judge right so
you just have to pray that whatever
judge is going to decide your case is
sort of okay with cannabis
alternatively
with that attended judicial system it's
called arbitration
it is designed for businesses to pick
their own judges internationally
and that's the you know one of the most
important protections you can get under
those treaties
thank you
of was good explanation
my next question goes out to pete
despite we have those problems um
cannabis other medical cannabis stocks
are already traded on german stocks they
are detained in luxembourg luxembourg
even changed the medical cannabis law
so they could continue to detain the
stock so we
something moves also
and as it seems recently in my eyes
germany is becoming the trading place
for
european medical cannabis the main
trading place
but the german government does not allow
a lot of companies to grow a lot of
cannabis so
my next question it goes out actually to
both panelists what do you think which
will be the or where will be the main or
which countries will be the main
production countries within europe over
the next years because it's not going to
be germany i think
no germany's
going to do a high quality product
probably a very pharmaceutical product
but let's look at portugal spain greece
like when that does get into but any
anybody that's close to the equator
where it's much much cheaper to grow it
just makes sense right um
that's what i see
yeah
um i'm sorry it's not exactly the answer
you expect i guess michael but my answer
is maybe
europe is just not going to be a place
where you're going to grow the most
stuff
and and again it's part of that evolving
cannabis game
it's not just you may want to seize
opportunities abroad outside europe it's
just you're going to have to probably
because again you know colombia and
latin america south africa even morocco
thailand
those places have the ideal climate to
grow the stuff
it's where is the cheapest in terms of
labor
the only problem again is a matter of
country risk but we've just addressed
that there are ways to plan ahead of
that but frankly if i if i had to tell
you what country i think will be growing
the most stuff in europe i would say
morocco
probably
okay
thank you
and my next question also goes through
you because uh you are australian based
and we never talked about the australian
medical cannabis program here is it
worth to invest in or can you invest in
the australian medical cannabis program
how is that organized there yeah well um
australia has made great strides over
the six to seven years to liberalize
their medical cannabis market so right
now it's purely medical and industrial
no recreational just yet even though
there are voices already even at the
government level that are trying to
advocate for that
it's it's i'd say a major
market in the making
um we have a few big companies based in
australia i'm thinking of can global uh
little green pharma that maybe a few of
you have heard about because they have
they're making great strides in europe
i'd say at the moment what we are seeing
is more like australian cannabis
companies investing outside australia
primarily
in southeast asia so thailand
uh africa and and europe than the
contrary it's possible but i think the
trend is going to be just a bit like you
know like canada and the u.s like big
local companies doing their own stuff
and then trying to export their
operations abroad
pete do you have
any because you're doing extraction in
denmark
do you uh exclusively separate uh
extract flowers that were grown in
denmark or do you also operate with
flowers that were grown in
out of the european community or is this
a possibility well that's the next fun
part about navigating uh government
regulations so right now in denmark
they're not allowing for bulk import you
can import products into denmark so the
three products that are actually in the
danish medical system for available for
patients bedrocan has three strains of
their flower and aurora has a gel
capsule that's coming out of canada so
actually nothing has been produced in
denmark
but right now the regulations don't
allow me to take in flour from say
macedonia bring that into denmark
process and then send it back out
maybe one day it's uh that's where
the some of the the political um
navigation comes into play but in the
same instance there's lots of
cultivation happening in denmark
and some really high quality product
right now which is which is great for us
to be able to work with those groups
and uh how do you uh what do you think
how long will that take to until
because within the eu it's actually no
problem but how how long will it take
till the market is open to other medical
cannabis markets which is except canada
is still very complicated
how long until the danish market is open
the european market or the european
market
it just yeah it's anybody's guess um we
really i could sit here and try to be a
fortune teller with it but
it's anybody's guess i think what it's
really going to take is just just proof
proof that you know cannabis coming from
other markets
is meeting that standard of quality
whether it's whether it's a flower or
whether if it's a concentrate and
however it's being formulated from there
it comes back down to quality and that
level of quality and it doesn't meet the
medical systems if you take a look at
the pharmaceutical industry outside of
cannabis
there's pharmaceutical drugs that have
their raw ingredients that are
manufactured all over the world and then
those are making their way into europe
to be you know further processed and
then
dropped into germany or denmark or
france or whatever it might be it's the
infrastructure's there the euphorian
substance licenses um allow for that so
it's actually
it's just really just just proving up
quality and then just following the
little pathways that are already
established within the pharma industry
so we're talking about things like gmp
and
my next question to rudolphi because you
just mentioned the
cannabis market in thailand the medical
market i also read a lot about it i did
some research that it's uh existing
already it's it's uh this is uh no
no fake news or so the medical cannabis
market is already existing in thailand
but i also read is kind of on a private
level or do they know something about
gmp and
like professional production
okay look um i think it's fair to say
that the cannabis market in thailand the
legal one is fairly new
uh in a way that i think still in the
process of developing their regulations
again we only have a few instances
examples of you know companies from
australia say investing in the market um
i don't know to what extent we're really
looking at you know general and all that
stuff at the moment precisely because
it's still in the making interestingly
about thailand it's not it's noob it's
not so new because it started in 2018
when the government started to say okay
okay okay we're gonna liberalize the
market
the following year
the government decided to
take away all the patents for
cannabis-based medicine that were being
developed by u.s and japanese companies
you can imagine the reaction of the
world oh we're going to stop all the
foreign patents on cannabis because you
know you're foreigners and then they're
like no no okay okay it's fine we're
gonna make it real and boom they really
liberalized the market i think it was
early 2020.
um so again opportunities but i think
we're not quite there yet it's not
comparable to the regulations we have in
europe at all let alone in in america so
again world of the wise uh interesting
market
full opportunities but just got to be
careful
thank you
my next question to pete is more
european europe-specific
because
we know we all know you export you sell
most of your products to germany
are there any other european countries
you're already exporting to or is there
anything you expect that you can that
you have other countries because a few
already have a medical program but they
are not as big as in germany what do you
think is next it's more on the
expectations right so
um
the the various cultivators that we're
working with
and then just helping get their product
to other countries you know we're seeing
flour from denmark being sent to
australia and new zealand germany
flowers going over to you know poland
now
so yeah this market's available we have
our eyes open for just markets that have
an established rec program or medical
program um an established program where
hey they're either pointing to the
german monograph or they're pointing to
something
that says that we accept this type of
product
in the i don't know the sense of
international business
as a small business trying to
go in at a government level and try to
burn your own path
it's very very expensive right
we always find it's better to find the
local specialists right so trying to
find distributors in poland or czech
republic or
spain or portugal that's really you know
as you talk about expectations that's
where we're at right now as an
organization is finding those
specialists
if there's any out there
hi uh but really yeah finding those
specialists that say look we need
product in spain um
and we're a distributor
that's the type of organization that we
want to work with and it just makes from
an international business perspective it
makes us not have to be experts in every
single market what we can do is just
rely on strategic partnerships and that
makes the business actually run a lot
faster
and
my next question goes to rodolfi what
do you think we didn't talk about south
america yet
when i think back uh in 2013 uruguay was
the first country worldwide to legalize
cannabis and medical cannabis both
as i know argentina legalized colombia
legalized and the only player that is
mentioned sometimes is colombia
but
not argentina not uruguay and there's
also
more rumors coming from colombia but no
product so far so what's what's in south
america what are the expectations
um
i'm not sure i have an explanation for
that it has to do i guess
in the case of uruguay they were the
first adopters the first mover so that
helps but they still have a very small
economy compared to ventures to colombia
and even more so argentina argentina
not too sure but again they have an
interesting uh history of treating
foreign investments in a certain way
uh since the early 2000s that might make
more than just a few businesses a bit
reluctant to dive in there you know and
i i certainly understand that
one country you have not mentioned
though michael is mexico
and that's a very interesting case i
think because it was you know all over
the news earlier this year oh my god
mexico is gonna do it
and canada was shaking oh my god they're
going to take over you know the lead in
the americas well we're still waiting to
see it happen i think it's happening now
thanks to the courts
um but
as it
happened elsewhere before that we know
of in europe um but that is certainly
going to be a huge market from the
moment it opens up and certainly it will
opens up to foreign capital
um so i guess my eyes right now are
turned toward mexico because i expect
they're going to end up opening up uh
but but at the moment where it's still
well it's already legal uh probably
colombia it takes it all
for now at least yeah colombia's also uh
i've uh heard a lot seen a little do you
know anything about the colombian
cannabis market
oh sorry it was to you sorry
um so colombia like we just saw the the
news and announcements where colombia is
uh should be allowing or is allowing now
for the export of flowers so that's
going to be game changing for the
organizations that have invested into
colombia again just trying to navigate
those rules and regulations and do some
uh political advocacy um to make changes
right and we're seeing those changes
happening
i was just chatting with a group the
other day they're actually saying that
they're seeing some uh reminiscence or
some policies that are starting to be
put into place to allow for a more of a
localized market and actually i see a
lot of these south american
companies looking to actually just
supply down in south america uh brazil
starting to become a market where it's
consuming medical cannabis
one of our the investors into our
company is out of brazil toronto and um
they they also have an investment into a
distribution company in brazil and
they're looking for product and it's
it's a growing market it's actually very
cool to see what's happening there
so i think
maybe they might be looking to more i
shouldn't say localized but onto that
just just supplying their continent
right now um as you know many of those
companies have struggled like some of
them have gotten the eu gmp stamp and
certification but many have struggled to
get that level of certification um so
why not
ship to a more localized market where
it's it's less expensive for shipping
and
the market is growing so get a foothold
so it's cool to see what's happening
down there very interesting thank you
rodolfi my very last question goes out
to you
we heard about a lot of countries now
who are planning to open up for cannabis
investment investments and my very last
question is from the from the
perspective of the consumer of the
patient um
how many of those countries
also have a medical
law or a medical program that works for
the patients already or do they first
settle up the investments and then make
the program our open program for the
patients i think there is a tendency in
running trials before opening up to the
patients
it's certainly say you know certainly
the case in france where right now we're
conducting trials uh active ones and the
products being supplied or in part from
australia
um so i i and you know when you look at
thailand it's a bit the same at least
officially
the idea when you liberalize the medical
cannabis industry
is still to take a
precautionary approach
so you don't want to make products
accessible to all the patients right
away if you don't know what the products
are so
i think in most jurisdictions certainly
still that are developing their medical
cannabis market
the goal first is to have a good product
um and and that's where you know foreign
companies come into the picture and and
they share their know-how uh that they
have already accumulated in other
jurisdictions and then in the second
step when when the government is sort of
happy with the development of you know
the product and and has some guarantees
as pete was saying earlier the need to
see guarantees then the opening to the
patients and to the medical profession
as as a whole but it's still a two-stage
process in most instances yeah it was
crystal clear thank you very much
and i see we're nearly out of time and i
think we should open or should open the
questionnaire
so any questions in the audience
anthony
i'm trying not to be shy yeah
um
hi thank you for this uh for the for the
panel and for the good conversation um
i'm a first timer here um so i'm very
happy to be here and join you all i have
a pharmaceuticals background i have been
working all my life in pharmaceuticals
and i see these trends as very
interesting on the one hand i have
questions because you know
pharmaceutical large companies tend to
synthesize
natural products eventually i haven't
heard any word on that in the whole
meeting and i don't know if that is a
ghost that is out there or not um
maybe in the future not not so far or
not so
recent future i don't know um but that's
not my subject my subject is i'm i'm a
german citizen living here in berlin but
i represent two colombian companies that
sell
cbd and cbg and i'm very happy that we
heard for the first time in more detail
about latin america i have good news
panama has just
gone through legalizing medical cannabis
yesterday so they're going to sign off
the bill next week
and i think after panama all of central
america will continue because it's kind
of a halo effect for the other countries
as well and you know that panama has a
very large free trade zone so they are
very very capable of exporting into the
rest of the world
um we are very interested as companies
to go come into europe european market
and i find it no being new to this
market i find it very difficult to make
contact so that's why i'm here so if
anybody is interested in know making a
contact with colombian companies um i'm
here thank you that's all oh so really
more of a statement all right
it was a good statement thanks for the
nice statement yeah
thank you
yeah am i on all right let me just take
off my mask hello everyone my name is
javier i'm from resin seeds we're a
spanish seed bank creators of canaatonic
acdc and some of the first cbd strains
to be out in the market and uh we're
doing a lot of consulting work in
thailand and now in mexico i'm actually
mexican so i have a little bit of
perspective on what's going on there and
in thailand
as you mentioned we're working with
golden triangle group is
asia's premier leading cannabis company
they will have eu certification um
flowers available in europe by spring of
2022 and um medicinal cannabis oils will
be released uh and sold exclusively by
the government authority by the thai
government
called the gpo and um they will be
selling their oils in europe in winter
of this year so thailand uh already is
starting with the ugmp certification um
mexico the biggest problem in uh delays
there are with the politicians it's an
act an inept government they've been
totally unable to uh to fight against
the cartels so they just let the cartels
do whatever they want and in the same
vein they're unable to push forward with
legislation the courts um
are on the side of the legislation of
cannabis but the politicians are still
not able to pull themselves together and
uh push anything forward there's a
massive expectation in uh
local national capitalists that are
waiting to invest in mexico but they're
all uh waiting for a little bit more
clarity um
so it's kind of stuck there's really no
vision there's no way to push forward at
present and it's still
completely in in
in the cloud so it's a not really much
clarity for you but um it's gonna happen
thank you very much uh can we maybe come
to the next question to the panelists
because we're here for to ask questions
thank you
do you want to take this a statement and
an update but soon soon we'll get a
question soon
all right this is probably the last one
that's the question
uh what's the current situation uh for
the cannabis in australia
for rudolf
thank you thank you for the question
um the the current situation for
cannabis in australia
okay um
not gonna lie it it's still a developing
market it's not that big
um it is making strides on the medical
side
we've got i think at least a dozen
australian stock exchange listed
companies now
which is quite impressive because again
it's fairly recent um and not all states
have liberalized at the same time the
federal government
uh came around the idea just a few years
ago so it's been growing fast
just like in other parts of the world
there's been
a little bit of a bubble i guess in the
beginning
uh and then the stocks have stagnated
for a little bit but you've got those
those main like two three main cannabis
companies i'm really thinking of little
green pharma
can global
and a couple others that now really have
established proper operations it's still
not a massive consumer market uh it's
getting there because of the you know
the aussie way of life and we're all
surfing and wellness and all that thing
so uh there is potential but i am not
too sure whether it is a target
destination right now for foreign
um
cannabis companies certainly because
again i think what's happening is they
are growing their own companies locally
and those companies already have started
to invest abroad because again of the
growing cost and manufacturing costs so
i see it more as an outward cannabis
destination than inbound or in world one
that's pretty much the state of the
affairs
you've got more and more people at the
politician level that are pushing for
recreational cannabis to be legalized
and that's in the wake of you know
canada and the u.s that are still
revered in in australia due to their
relationship in the commonwealth etc so
i think we're getting there and
certainly you know
aussies do smoke pot and not just
because of headaches or cancer um so
there is potential but it's not as fast
moving on that specific front as it
could be in other jurisdictions i guess
to be perfectly uh fair and transparent
the shops specialty shops
yeah i'm not too sure we're going to see
them anytime soon and you know you need
to be aware they have a funny
relationship to vice stuff in australia
because like potty is okay somehow but
cigarettes are like 25 bucks a pack so
you know
it's not the clear-cut market and no i'm
not so sure we're gonna see specialty
shops
very soon uh i have hopes but just not
for tomorrow yeah
thank you rodolfi and we're really
running out of time
yeah um thank thank you pete thank you
rodolfi for expertise it was really
unique thanks a lot
and
thanks a lot for listening in driver
icbc
thank you thank you the three of you i'm
sorry i couldn't get to all the
questions
um but we had updates
don't forget food and drink downstairs
go see the exhibitors also uh 400 euros
for the vip ticket for the
global investor forum in zurich next
week all right coming now to discuss
emerging markets let's hear it for
journalists and influencers