join us for the next international
cannabis business conference in san
francisco california at the hyatt
regency february 15th and 16th
that's the conference we're having here
at the oregon convention center it's the
international cannabis business
conference and alex rogers is putting
this on and just been remarkable a great
set a diverse set of vendors and a
fabulous set of speakers
there's been a great crowd uh great
vendors great attendees the feedback has
been extraordinary i've had so many
people tell me that this is the best
conference they've ever been to and i'm
here to learn how to tell the future
and i think
i'm getting a lot of great information
the people here are great
and it's not much stress
and they have free coffee
and someone's walking around with
sandwiches the beauty of icbc is meeting
all the activists lawyers
gardeners and people on the forefront of
providing medicine and good product to
people and patients very knowledgeable
people people from all over the world
it's been a great experience
i've heard some amazing things already
there's a
congressman here who is speaking about
where the industry is headed where the
laws are headed
federally which is is very important if
you're going to be investing in the
cannabis business
my name is ed rosenthal
and
it was a pleasure for me to come to this
conference
it addressed the needs
of the local people
of oregon amazing the speeches have been
incredible i've met a lot of people that
have been great just making contacts
with different dispensaries and grow
grow houses
and kind of perform partnerships
we're here at this conference to
talk to testing laboratories and
producers and processors about
laboratory accreditation and what it can
do for them
and what we're about is about promoting
organics
in the cannabis industry
don't magazine
stands for something
defending our patients everywhere
the magazine allows us to actually put
input
and relevant articles
out into the public
oh it's great this is it's our direct
target market really anybody who's
trying to get into the cannabis industry
trying to start a business trying to
make sure that they're doing things
right doing things legitimately that's
what we're here to do just to help the
industry and make sure everything's done
done the right way
give alex
mr rogers
full
credit because
this is a really good event i like it a
lot we have got many good contacts
and i hope we will meet again they got a
stack of business cards here meeting a
whole lot of new folks that are just
getting into the business but also a few
of the business people and a lot of the
activists that i've been working with
here in oregon for the past 10 years so
it's a combination of family reunion and
kind of a speed dating session
and that is just some of the things at
the international cannabis business
conference we're going to keep this
thing rolling join us for the next
international cannabis business
conference in san francisco california
at the hyatt regency february 15th and
16th