join us for the next International
cannabis business conference in San
Francisco California at the Hyatt
Regency February 15th and 16th
what a fantastic conference we're having
here at the Oregon Convention Center
it's the international cannabis business
conference and Alex Rogers is putting
this on here at the ICBC we are you know
bringing people from all across the
world actually to professionalize and
mainstream the Cannabis industry and
work towards legalizing regulating and
taxing cannabis
hey I'm Alex Rogers I'm the executive
producer of the international cannabis
business conference and I'm going to
bring you in and show you what's going
on here a little bit follow me
we've got about 700 people here today at
the international cannabis business
conference and here's just a look inside
at the auditorium
so this is a networking Extravaganza
right here and we have all types of
people vending and exhibiting here we're
an online marketing platform for the
Cannabis industry we take data and we
apply it to find people online to help
advocacy groups and Commercial
Enterprises
we're a cannabis testing facility based
out of Bend Oregon and we do tilt and
feed pesticide and mold analysis these
are precise medical dispensers for your
medical oils and waxes and here standing
tanning with them is Chelsea from The
Greener Side they're our biggest sponsor
for the international cannabis business
conference they are a premium dispensary
model not only in terms of a business
model but in terms of a legislating and
dialoguing with public officials so
everyone's on the same page and feels
comfortable about what we're doing no
more are we going to be in the closet on
this we're coming out we're talking
about proper public policy and we're
changing the law let's come on let's
check it out yeah so the RP group is the
Premier investment hub for the Cannabis
industry one of our big ventures of the
arcview investor Network where we
connect credited investors with some of
the top businesses in this industry that
are looking for Capital and we create
extracts with using CO2 to create a
clean comfortable
convenience product for people who
vaporize instead of smoke and it's
revolutionary products like this that
are going to push the can of business
industry forward in a way that not only
makes everyone happy and a whole bunch
of money but look at this
this is fun personified right here
just getting started where you're
already a cannabis entrepreneur at the
international cannabis business
conference there's something for you
lest we not forget the endless
networking possibilities here join us
for the next International cannabis
business conference in San Francisco
California at the Hyatt Regency February
15th and 16th