thank you so much for joining us for the
medical cannabis and adult youth panel
um with quite a lot of talk about the
recreational legalization of germany
and quite a lot of discussion about what
the future is going to look like for
medical cannabis companies the policy
for patients and the industry as a whole
when vaccination legalization comes
um so it's a pleasure to meet you with
us today we're going to be discussing
some of these impacts here today um my
name is lily templeton i'm head of nasa
at howard associates
we work closely with cannabis companies
to provide them strategic and regulatory
advice as well as market entry services
um hanway is the advisory arm of the
hallway company we are a venture studio
looking to build the infrastructure to
launch and scale
businesses that are needed by
new markets created by drug policy
reforms
um we also run the network first
wednesdays so if you'd like to be done
with our free reports um they're all
available online as well
um i'm joined today by
bengal he is managing director and
co-founder of stores and nickel
they are manufacturer of premium medical
vaporizers all made in germany um and
their most iconic products as i'm sure
many of you know the volcano was
actually the first medically improved
cannabis vaporizer in the world uh
really known as the kind of gold
standard among medical prescribers and
researchers
um and they've got about 22 years
experience in the industry so
well yeah very strong and great to have
you again with us today
um we're also joined by thomas chaton
he's the ceo and one of the co-founders
of
four transfer pharma
they are a german-based wholesaler water
and distributor and producer of
high-grade medical cannabis
again quite a lot of experience they've
been active in the market since 2018 and
the inception of the medical market
and after an initial kind of interest in
music thomas first founded his first
company 12 years ago he's got a lot of
experience in software development
but due to kind of the the cannabis
opportunity decided to
leave that role and snap our ceo role to
join 420 farm farmer
um i think that's quite a strong sign of
how much you've had over here and
rumbling and having a space
and then thirdly we are joined by bozoda
who is a vocal very highly respected
activist in the space
he's got over two decades of advocacy
across slovenia across the eu and of
course the balkans
he holds several positions he's the
president of fest for human rights
association he's a member of the
international association for cannabis
medicines and he's also a founder of the
research nature institute
and the research and agency also have a
lot of experience to share with us today
they've got very deep insight into
cannabis use among patients and among
the quality of products they want to
test them for virtually so they're
pretty much in and out of these products
day in and day out so
really
joined by this panel and yeah looking
forward to getting stuck in so
i guess we are going to kick things off
it would be great to hear a bit about
how
you think the medical market will be
affected by legalization in germany and
whether you think it will continue to
grow as we've seen or there'll be some
sort of shift uh when recreational
access opens
yeah hello everybody
yeah what will happen to the medical
market uh in the moment the naval market
is well developed in germany i think
since 2017 it's a good development
it is the same development what has
happened in many countries first there
was a medical market and afterwards
there
started the discussions about
recreational and so it has more or less
paved the way in direction of
recreational
we can assume today that a certain
amount of people
inside the medical system
maybe would drop out if there would be a
legal alternative
available yeah at the same time when
discussions are
about kinetics
because more broad available there will
be new patients also available maybe
also resistance
to prescribe will will come down in the
moment we see the most restrictions in
the cannabis market by missing a doctor
soviet greece crisis who really believe
in canada's
as a medicine
so overall
although we have seen like in canada we
have seen that the
medical market is went down i don't
think this is necessarily the case in
germany because the medical market is
not so big at the moment we have seen
the numbers this morning uh
many people believed 800 thousand
patients would be available and we have
not even half of them
at the moment
so
i only believe that the market overall
all the medieval market will grow
the problem but also was several times
discussed this morning is the supply
what will people do will there be enough
supply for the medical market
at the double standards they discussed
now yeah of course for the for a
producer if you can
get maybe more easy to
to grow a recreational cannabis instead
of medieval canals of course you may
would switch to this to this side and
but
yeah overall i think for the government
it must be a priority that
the medical market is first served and
then the recreational market itself a
patient who really needs the medicine
who needs it daily to handle his pain or
whatever
must be a priority for the government
before a recreational user can enjoy
his canels
thank you and i think you raised some
interesting questions there around
where supply will come from how the kind
of framework will look
thomas i guess from your experience
working with distribution with
regulators so far
how do you kind of think that
legalization may look in germany and how
do you think
things are going to how do you think
things will proceed going forwards and
do you have any sort of a vision of
where we could be going
so after we heard some uh keynote from
our uh book at leaner here in the panel
i'm pretty sure that they will have a
very strong look at the medical market
and the experience we
just collected in the last five years
and i'm pretty sure they will be very
open towards that topic because the time
is very very right i guess you see this
all over the world to spreading cannabis
as a new market even for medical and
recreational purposes but
it's very um dangerous to have this
double standard stuff and uh for example
the medical market is very important
that the research and development
continues because you definitely have to
differentiate your product portfolio
between reg market and medical market
because at the moment you have lots of
strains in the market
and you sometimes have the problem so
what is the exact cure of that strain
and opposite to another strain and that
is the fact why a lot of doctors refuse
from that topic and i'm pretty sure that
they will have a very very
open discussion for grant market and
both markets will uh work together very
aligned i guess because research and
development will be more in the medical
market and experience in the field will
be more coming up from wreck mark
because the volume is much bigger there
so i'm guessing um yeah they will be
have a very very certain
framework in the wreck market which is
very very uh nearby the medical market
and then after
four years maybe and you see what is
really going on in the red market you
can maybe adjust this a little bit
thank you i think yeah this is quite a
little clear that while there are some
great advantages and
experiences to gain from pivoting
medical questions to recreation there
does need to be a really clear mind and
i think that's been echoed by everything
i've been hearing today
and above i guess speaking about the
current medical framework in itself
something you've been working with and
kind of
uh doing activism for over the last 20
years
do you think that the current kind of
pharma framework is meeting the needs of
patients and do you think
it's easy enough to kind of access the
natural remedies and to access
um the type products and the formats
that patients want
not really i can talk
for slovenia where the bureaucratic
obstacles are
as severe as maybe in germany
we have no
medical cannabis approved since five
years but you can probably find a doctor
in slovenia who will prescribe it and
even if they prescribe it legally they
can propose all the medical chambers and
they just want to avoid it
the problem
for this medical part because i would
not mix personal use of so-called
recreational
use of cannabis is not recreation it's a
personal use we don't have recreational
mining no
but i think the education is crucial to
get doctors
on the
cannabis side
because
they need protocols they need you know
everything around because they
and it's a quite individual approach so
in slovenia it's hard to find doctor
today even if it is they can prescribe
flowers they can describe everything
but everything is more or less on
satellites
and cbd
this is what's allowed by slovenian
public agency for drugs
therefore we started already four years
ago
educational program
all together also with medical chamber
of slovenia nurses chamber slovenia we
organize already
actually three education courses for
doctors
and i hope this will bring some changes
onto this field
fantastic thank you and i guess moving
on to kind of what legalization means to
operators into businesses themselves
such as a lot of people here
and what kind of does legalization mean
for your stores
i mean one of the things i find quite
interesting about you guys is you're one
of the only kind of
bit of businesses that have got proven
revenues from medical you've got a deep
understanding of consumers both kind of
in the recreational space uh overseas
alongside a medical kind of the german
space
and i guess from that position how do
you see
things shifting through stores of
bicycle and how do you see your
consumers and revenues being affected
yeah
um i say i think we are a little bit
cautious about uh our expectations uh we
are already in business as you mentioned
yeah we are distributing them to more
than 100 countries uh in the year
yeah we are available with
what we call hostile devices well the
intended uses of chamomile and such
things and we have the major products
where the intelligence is for kennedy
nights
but we think once this legalized of
course you will have a
push
always hit at least at the beginning
you will have more information available
therefore we will
should we reach more clients but we
don't believe that our business will be
have a little skyrocket because of
legalization in germany there's as
mentioned already a good business
in germany
and
and so if you look to the to the rest of
the world of course there it can be if
you look to canada to experience there
of course here there was improvement in
but also not too much and many times
this legalization it also comes with a
lot of regulation who you have not in
place before you know of course we
cannot in a moment do advertising for
cannabis but we can do
advertisement with life science
stuff and things but once like in canada
then you are not allowed to
for example to show your products or you
must
must your products bring to it that
you're not usable you're taking a better
result so you cannot turn them on in a
shop and and and things like that
so overall we see um this legitimization
because government there's so much fear
about it and so they think about all
this what we all hear today about yours
uh protection about uh consumer
protection and then these fees then at
the end of the
of the day uh you cannot even show where
you can get your cannabis from yeah even
you they even think about having um
at the state distributing in their own
shops you know what you have in the
model of quebec for example yeah if you
look to grab
the government
by themselves and there's for example no
weaponries available at all in their
shops yeah because they they don't think
this is necessary yeah so there are only
also devices available so overall which
legalization also can come additional
difficulties
for for the business
so overall we will have
some improvement in business but
not skyrocketing
thank you so much very very valuable
insights
um
you mentioned the product differences as
well the difference in your kind of
portfolio that you might need to stop
from medical and recreational do you
expect to see any kind of overlap of
products and suppliers or do you expect
this to be a completely separate thing
completely grounds for that format
no because because i thought as i said
at the beginning i'm pretty sure that
the politics will be very aligned
foreign supplier for medical and
suppliers or rate markets to be
something in the same
but
to answer the question i'm pretty sure
that from from the product side in the
medical market what i really mean is you
have to develop a real medicinal product
to to get all the doctors on board
because at the moment i would guess
maybe two three four percent of the
doctors in germany prescribe cannabis
and all the others say okay give me some
data and that is for example the reason
why we as a company do not hire as much
farmer sales guys as we could because
what should they tell the doctors they
come to the place and say yeah this is
cannabis and what's the difference
between that
it's another strain and has another
turbine profile but the the real data
based medicinal standard
we are far away from that so and we
definitely have to put more and more
effort
into that to really create a medicinal
product which more and more doctors can
prescribe because they are responsible
for that and when i would be a doctor i
would be very interested in the fact
what exactly will happen to my patient
when i'm describing this kind of product
and i think the wreck market when this
is coming up
and the
topic cannabis as such is spread among
the
whole society i guess then more and more
doctors maybe
put away their doubts about cannabis and
be more open into and and do more
research and stuff like that and so um
this will be a very crucial process
during the whole great market opening
fantastic thank you so much and
i guess a kind of closing question
as uh as well as kind of the impacts on
companies
of the industry
at the bottom line of this there is
quite a big fundamental human rights
question this is it's not just any sort
of product this is like a human right
noise to be able to consume calories and
to be able to enjoy that as giving
personal use
and i think
there's been a lot of activism as we
pioneered and i think
that's been a huge role in getting the
medical market off the ground
and i think do you see a place for more
recreational activism how do you think
that kind of civil disobedience and
these forms of activity can help to kind
of progress
the cause and help achieve some of these
aims that we will be talking about
of course the use of cannabis special
for medical purposes and purposes is a
basic human right you know because we
have enough data that we cannot just ban
it and
take it off
of the table
but i really think we should divide
medical market and personal use
because for personal use i think
we don't have to invent hot water again
we have regulated alcohol everything
what is needed we have huge
because of alcohol and everything so
just copy paste and i think it's
regulated more than enough alcohol also
domestic use and domestic
brewery it's very hard to regulate so i
think we should apply something similar
for this
and medical market
rules are completely different different
laws different approach so we can i
don't think we can mix those two
fields you know in one past
years
so
unfortunately i have to tell you that
around 15 percent of slovenians are
using cannabis on daily basis that's
that's a lot and we cannot look away
and
now actually patients are forcing
doctors to prescribe cannabis because
patients are also well educated
especially when they are
you know very sick or they need really
help so
in slovenia without the survey of
faculty of social sciences 30 percent of
oncological patients are also with
candidates
and i think this is not really good for
credibility of the
medical
societies are the same
you know so i think this should be
changed
and
the crucial of the personal market or
personal use market
is
quality control we have quality control
now for our last eight years
and it should really be controlled as
it should be for cannabis because now
is the worst thing where you can buy
whatever
[Music]
fantastic thank you and i guess just
just wrapping up now as we are close to
time i'd like to offer everyone everyone
the same question is there an ideal
scenario where
everyone can win the industry
governments the recreational users the
patients
operators
um and i know it's quite a broad
question but in a nutshell do you think
that's possible
of course it's possible uh maybe we
should invest a little bit more into
education
not just the research because this is
most research planned on the planet
you know but i think we should
put more effort to education and things
will change soon
perfect words i cannot add some more
because education is the crucial point
here in this case especially for
cannabis market and
yeah
if we achieve to have a very good
education base and
acceptance within the society i think
there could be a win-win situation for
all relevant players in the market
yeah i think in the center of the wind
you must be the patient and the consumer
of course it's available so for the
government it is important to make it as
easy as possible be as no or as
few regulations as possible in the
moment there's still all this this fear
and then also
[Music]
and all these things i think you can
treat this much much easier and and if
you look to a congress where they have
legalized it you see the negative
consequences are men enough and they are
definitely lower than the consequences
of prohibition so i would say the more
liberal the approach is the better it is
fantastic and thank you so much for
coming that was the end of the panel
i just want to say thank you to all of
your parents
[Applause]