but yes i'm jamie pearson i'm the ceo of
bang
bang's 12 years old
we were born in a warehouse in oakland
12 years ago when cannabis was really
um
it was still medical
in california at that time and the
industry was just
coming into its own so think about 2012
where cannabis was
so 10 years later almost 13 it'll be 13
years next month
you know we've been around a long time
now we're in seven u.s states we're the
number one number two and number six
chocolate in canada for the first year
of cannabis 2.0 in canada we were the
number one sku
we outsold any skew of flour of pre-roll
in canada so
we've done very very well across the
world we have cbd that's in europe and
we've been in europe for about five
years um we're gonna skip the two
coveted years because that doesn't count
we all skip the two coveted years right
um
and what alex asked me to do was talk to
you guys about how cannabis is going to
impact the recession so i just want to
take a little bit of a show of hands how
many of you are german in this room
okay
and then how many americans do we have
oh okay five um and then i see i met a
bunch of people yesterday from thailand
yay
um and then just regular european
non-germans
okay so
i think i covered what what did i miss
israel israel what
australia welcome
new zealand
colombia south america awesome
what
uruguay oh
the country that started the whole
movement going
going legal uh federally legal welcome
so truly an international group not that
many people here yet but we are
expecting a couple hundred here um
what i'm talking about today is how
cannabis is going to impact
or could potentially impact
the recession that i think raise your
hand if you think we're in a recession
because i think europe and america are
pretty similar
so but so the americans are saying yes
the europeans not so much how is south
america doing
same i mean it's just turbulent times in
the economies uh because we're all
responding to what happened with kovid
um
so the question is are we in a recession
maybe
likely
um
no one's gonna argue that the economic
times are certain i think we're all in
agreement that we're in uncertain times
right now
i think cannabis can play an important
role i better silence my phone here
um
in riding the ship but the key here is
going to be that legislators are going
to need to get it right and i think what
we can all agree on is especially in the
u.s is legislators have not done a good
job of getting it right because i think
a lot of the legislation comes in
america based in fear
and what i'm really hoping is that in
other places where cannabis is coming
into its own and i got to give big kudos
to thailand you guys have done some
making cannabis legal and then giving
plants to people groundbreaking stuff
and that's really kind of grabbing the
industry and saying we're we're going to
embrace it i think we can do that in
europe i think the germans
personally
um
i have a special affinity for
deutschland
my kindese and here's disinviter
deutsche burger
deutsche pesa
um
so
i'm going to go back into english
um
i think that we can learn in germany and
you guys are getting ready to go wreck
you're going to go adult use here you
can learn from the mistakes that we made
in the u.s and i think if you get your
legislation right
you could actually impact the recession
and give yourself a new bucket of money
so in
the technically the definition of a
recession is if you have two quarters of
negative um economic growth so your gdp
goes backwards for two consecutive
quarters that's the technical definition
of a recession
in the u.s we're about
any day they're going to announce
quarter two results and we think that
they're going to show that it went
backwards and that means that quarter
one went backwards and quarter two went
backwards and we will technically be in
a recession here's the issue
the people who are charged with naming
the recession are called the nber
it is the
national bureau of economic research so
it's an eight-member panel non-partisan
they are the ones that say whether or
not it's been a recession
looks like for the first time in history
that eight member panel is going to say
we're not in a recession despite the
fact that we've gone backwards two
quarters in a row
and we've never seen that it's
unprecedented but the reason that is
probably going to happen
is because we have the lowest
unemployment in about 70 years
we're hovering right around 3.4 percent
in the us of unemployment so you've got
this strong job situation
but the economy is moving backwards
and then you couple that with inflation
that we haven't seen the likes of in
about 40 years and we haven't really
seen anything like this economically so
we can't just go back and learn from
history so what i'm going to do is take
you back
we're going to talk about what's
happened historically in recessions and
then we're going to talk about how
cannabis can play a role in that and i'd
like you to raise your hand how many of
you are cannabis entrepreneurs
how many of you are investors
okay so there's only a few investors so
i've geared this talk to investors but i
think what i'll do is just on the fly
shift over to the entrepreneurs um
okay so
are we in a recession maybe
likely but regardless uh we can use
cannabis to get ourselves out of it so
over here in germany the economy is are
also arguably in a recession in the
research that i did several prominent
economists said yeah we're probably in a
recession um regardless
we're all recovering from the pandemic's
impact on all of our economies right so
we also have
interesting things going on like the
climate crisis
and we have an alarming increase in
nationalistic politics we've got the
brexit and we've got the trumpers and
we've got all this weird politics going
on
and apologize if you're a trumper and
then um
you know what we basically have is a
financial crisis
sitting over a bunsen burner because
we've got all this other stuff happening
and at this moment in time
on top of all of that we have the war in
ukraine
and that is
arguably also impacting the supply chain
not just the pandemic but now the war in
ukraine is affecting wheat and it's
affecting gas and the i think the
biggest thing that people are talking
about is russian oil
and russian natural gas and there's a
big fear that russia is going to shut
off the natural gas supply to to germany
and if that happens the german economy
is going to be in trouble and that is
the one thing that everybody agrees upon
so i'm i'm not trying to scare all of
you but what i do want to do is kind of
give you a backdrop of
where the economic times are and how
cannabis is could potentially figure
into this
because what you basically have is
massive inflation
now inflation always impacts consumers
and consumer goods because people stop
spending money when things get expensive
right
so we have this massive inflation we
have a recession we have our economy
shrinking we've got a war going on we've
got a climate crisis and
things are uncertain and so we're
sitting here saying how do we as an
industry impact all of that in a
positive way and i think we can do that
and so investors have a right to be
worried and then here's the last thing
uh bang is a public company so
you know i watched the markets pretty
closely and we are what's in considered
a trough bear market so raise your hand
if you know what a trough bear market is
okay so a bear market's when
you've got a 20 shrinkage of price
across the board doesn't matter if it's
uh what sector so if it's across all
sectors you've gone from bowl to bear
a trough bear is when it's more than 35
percent and it's more than two quarters
in a row we've been more than 35 percent
across all sectors for many many many
quarters so we are
it's unprecedented what's happening in
the capital markets it basically means
liquidity has dried up
so we can all agree it's really hard to
get money when you're in cannabis it's
hard to get money anyway
so if you're in cannabis trying to get
money and you're trying to get money in
a trough bear market and then you have
all of that backdrop that i just laid
out for you
the question is how do cannabis
entrepreneurs build an industry
in the middle of all of that
and i think one of the things is we have
to talk to our legislators about what's
actually happening
the other thing is if you're an investor
and you're liquid
there is this is where
fortunes are going to be made because
there is a lot of opportunity out in the
world
you can buy pretty much across the
sector 35 back of
normal pricing so
liquid people are gonna go get richer
and
uh
the really good news for cannabis
investors and this is where the
entrepreneurs need to perk up
is that our entire industry is not going
to function across normal market sectors
we're going to function like alcohol and
tobacco
and alcohol and tobacco in tough
economic times actually have an increase
in demand makes sense we're all
depressed we want to get drunk
right but the difference is now we're in
this massive inflationary environment
and we can't afford top shelf liquor so
what do consumers do
they go get the cheaper alternative
here's where the rub is if you're in
cannabis
what's the cheaper alternative to legal
illegal cannabis so it actually is going
to serve if legislators don't get this
right it's going to blow up the illicit
market
because people are crunched they're not
going to stop buying cannabis they're
going to buy more cannabis but if they
want to buy more cannabis they've got to
buy it at cheaper prices so if your
legislators over tax it
if they over test it if they do all of
these things that we've seen in
california i'll give an example
bang was born in california
in california they test the plant before
it goes to be blasted into oil then they
test the oil
then you need another test when it goes
to the distributor
then when it goes from the distributor
to the manufacturer you need another
test
and then when you get it from the
manufacturer and you put it in the
product you need another test before it
goes to the retail market the same
cannabis is tested four times
each one of those tests costs anywhere
from eight hundred to fifteen hundred
dollars so if i'm going to put
five thousand skus into the market it's
going to add whatever that math is to my
sales price at each juncture so it
continues to increase the price increase
the price increase the price
it's also taxed at all of those levels
so now i make a chocolate bar that costs
anywhere from two to three dollars to
manufacture
guess what the retail price of my
chocolate bar is in california
20 bucks
and about 80 percent of that goes to
taxes
so there's no profit being made because
the government has their hand out at
every level of that process
what we're trying to get done in new
york is we're trying to get new york to
understand look you've already invented
the wheel
you've got bodegas on every corner that
sell alcohol and tobacco
you already have distribution you
already know
how to give these people permits so you
can make money on the permit of 200 000
bodegas
and then you can limit how much they can
sell but you can let them sell at the
corner store
so the woman in curlers doesn't call her
plug
she goes to the corner store and buys
legal clean
tested cannabis so if you open the
barrier of entry and you allow
all the citizens to access
safe clean cannabis and you don't tax it
to death
think about how much money they'll make
in new york by giving everybody access
to it because guess what
everybody already has access to it new
york it is the largest nascent cannabis
market in the world
the the statistics are 200 metric tons
of cannabis are sold on the island of
manhattan every year
and i did not make that number up
it's a little bit of a low estimate i've
heard it much higher
i've heard the lower estimate is 40
metric tons of cannabis well guess where
all that comes from comes from
california
and that's the californians selling it
out the back door because it's the only
way they can keep themselves in business
we can learn from that here
so what we need to do is really urge the
legislators to do a few things so i made
a list
the list is
number one
i'm going to go back here and talk about
the recession again because i know we
all love that
reasonable tax rates so
they should take their money in volume
rather than having a few people
allowed to do cannabis and then taxing
them to death and if you tax it too much
you're going to drive people to the
illicit market they should have lots of
retail access points
if you give them lots of retail access
points they have no reason to go to the
nascent market reasonable and achievable
barrier of entry meaning if you are a
legacy cannabis person you've admittedly
been breaking the law for all of these
years so in the industry i call them the
roots in the suits so we're sitting here
with all the suits the roots of the
people that made sure cannabis was
available when our laws did not allow
cannabis to be available on the open
you know openly
we need to embrace the roots we need to
let those people into the market we need
to lower the barrier of entry for them
to get into the market because the the
suits have a lot to learn from the roots
and if we do that we're not going to
drive people to the illicit market
because what we're going to do is bring
the illicit market into the legal market
which means we're going to invite all of
the people who know everything about
growing we're going to grow better
cannabis we're going to provide better
cannabis and we're going to have all of
those lessons that they've learned over
the last 20 years and we're going to
elevate the entire industry by bringing
the roots in
a lot of the suits will say to me yeah
and they need us because we're going to
teach them how to do kpis and we're
going to teach them how to do business
i'm going to tell you
if you've been running a business
in an era
that's illegal
and you've been able to skirt all of
those laws you're still growing you're
still packaging you're still
manufacturing and you're still selling
at a retail level
they have more to teach us about running
a business than we probably have to
teach them probably what we need to do
is really embrace the roots at a core
level and then we can just teach them
our vernacular they need to learn about
15 vocabulary words and then we're all
going to be on the same playing field
um so we bring those um we bring the
roots into the game and then the next
thing we need to do is have strong
social equity programs and that's
because the war on drugs in the us
and i've read in europe has been a war
on race
it is not about squashing drugs
governments know that everyone's using
drugs
what cannabis the cannabis war on drugs
has been is putting black and brown
people in prison and what we need to do
is get all the black and brown people
out of prison and we need to give them
entry into this legal market and when we
do that
as an industry we reduce the amount of
people that go into the illicit market
and then we also reduce the number of
taxes that we pay keeping people in
prison
here's a big one governments need to
allow cannabis in all its forms
people want edibles they want beverages
they want concentrates they want all of
these products and what governments do
is they go oh we're scared we think
we're only gonna let you have flour
and then people want edibles they're
gonna go get edibles in the illicit
market
what the government needs to do is
accept that cannabis is here that people
are using it
and they need to let us have it in all
of its forms and when we do that we
actually then increase
the legal market
the ability to tax the legal market the
bucket of money gets bigger and this is
a way to combat the recession because
it's the first time in my lifetime that
there's a new bucket of money
so think about it we've always played
monopoly with taxes oh we're gonna give
it to the military and they're like no
no i'm a democrat i'm going to give it
to education it's the same dollar we're
just moving it around on the on the
playing field
but if what we do is go get a new dollar
from the illicit market we actually now
can increase our economy by the impact
that cannabis will have on it what we
need to do is accept that cannabis is
here
it's legal
and we need to give the people who want
it access to it in all of its forms and
the last thing that i think governments
need to do
hope you're all taking notes and that
you're going to go talk to your
legislators because this is what really
needs to happen i've been doing this for
12 years
i've watched
countries states legislators get it
wrong
and then we always end up back at the
same spot
i watched california do you know that we
have the biggest illicit market in the
united states in california
there were three 000 legal dispensaries
on 1231 2017.
and california went wreck on 1-1 2018
and there were 300 legal dispensaries
the next day but guess what there were
illicit shops because none of them
closed
so then what happens is the consumer has
no idea that they're buying from an
illegal store
and
those dollars are not going into the tax
bucket they're going into now somebody's
hands who does not have to lab test and
who does not have to pay taxes
so the last thing that governments need
to do is stop doing milligram limits
they think they're somehow protecting us
so all of a sudden in california you
could buy a thousand milligram chocolate
bar or cookie or concentrate and the
next day after cannabis was made
legal recreationally you could only buy
a hundred milligrams
well guess what everyone did
they kept buying their thousand
milligram cookie they just bought it in
the illegal market so these are the
lessons that we can learn and if you do
these things if if germany gets this
right
and if they allow home grow and they
allow consumption lounges and they allow
high milligrams and they allow cannabis
in all of its forms and they embrace
social equity and they lower the barrier
of entry and they let
let you go by cannabis and aldi you can
go buy liquor and aldi if they do those
things they're going to have a bigger
bucket of money
to help their economy
they're going to be able to control the
cannabis market because they're going to
they're going to actually have access at
the point of sale of the data they're
going to know who's buying it how much
they're buying
but when it's in the illicit market we
have no idea what's happening
right and then you allow a free market
economy to function the way it's
supposed to because people who are doing
good business stay in business and
people who are not doing good business
don't make it and that is the hallmark
of a free market business economy
let them do business
and let them fail if they're going to
fail and let them succeed if they're
going to succeed but when you legislate
them to death
everything becomes fake
so what happens now is
we're in this recession we've got this
high inflation we have an opportunity in
germany
and it's really exciting you guys are
going to get your rules
any day
and what everyone's what i'm reading is
everyone's predicting that it's going to
go wreck on 1 1 20 23 and then it'll
take a year for them to get their rules
correct and the first legal cannabis
will be sold probably in sometime in
2024 so it's going to take a couple of
years for all of that to get going but
it's groups like this that can speak to
their legislatures and say go learn from
colorado go learn from washington go
learn from massachusetts
and that brings me to the next point
germany is what i consider an emerging
market right now you've got medical
you don't have wreck
and what we're learning in the us is
that the really really advanced markets
the colorado the oregon
california alaska bless you
these
markets
are in a race to the bottom
so cannabis is selling for less money
and it's really hard for operators to
make money but the markets have limited
licenses and that are new
are the ones where there's limited
competition
and
those people have an opportunity to make
money so you're in a situation right now
where germany is technically an emerging
market
you have an opportunity to limit the
number of licenses which i'm a proponent
of having lots and lots of retail
licenses and then having your bottleneck
at the manufacturing because that's
where you can control quality that's
where you can control safety but once
you know you've got clean safe legal
cannabis sell it to the masses
so you limit the licenses at that
manufacturing level and you also allow
as many distributors to exist as
possible so you get it to the people
because people are getting it anyway
so what i want to do is talk to you
about
what would happen if the if we are in a
recession how long is it going to last
okay i'm going to take a poll
how many of you think that this economic
downturn is going to last longer than
two years
one year
less than one year
a few of you okay the majority of you
think it's going to last more than one
year the average i i did that i looked
at the last
um
five bear markets starting in 2001
the amount that the market decreased was
37 percent
and it was 546 days
2002 278 days 34
2008 408 days
2009 62 days that was coven uh 27
percent and 2020 33 days 34
the average bear market lasts 265 days
so less than a year
so let's say that the recession starts
july 1st
it means that it'll be over sometime in
march of 2023
i don't i don't think that's my
prediction is that that's not what's
going to happen because of all of those
things that i've told you about the
warren ukraine
supply chain the gas situation in europe
but what i'm saying to you is if you
have some liquidity if you are an
investor cannabis is a great way to
hedge inflation it's a great way to
diversify
your holdings
it's recession resistant because it is
going to go up in demand
and so you've got an excellent position
in germany get your legislators minds
right stop them from being fearful we
all see that the emperor awareness wears
no clothes
we've got to get our legislators to see
that as well
and if we can get the entire
cannabis community to understand this is
what we're facing we can be the ones
this industry can be the ones that
single-handedly help governments beat
this recession
thank you
jamie pearson
[Applause]
you