oh yeah ICBC 2024 rapping review yeah
this is is what we do every
year just to get your ears perked get a
little recap of w Guan in a dis here
cannabis industry situation you know
what I'm saying yeah come on y'all Let's
Get It Started go around the globe a
sweet little Alpine Country call slow
AIA which just passed a referendum now
here comes legislation of medical and de
that's right not a matter of if but a
matter of when you see the communities
down with the program and man let's talk
about Japan p in on CBD out on THC and
so we'll see it look like it going to be
a few more years until they free and
then there's the health Ministry of
Spain a medical Royal Decree to cure
your pain medical advancements enhances
props to the politicians that are Taking
Chances now where else are they
legalizing South Africa and Czech
Republic I'm surmising common sense is
rising Clash of the Titans kind of
exciting no more dividing Australia's
Rising so don't get duped y'all medical
down under has straight of quadruple so
big it up to all the jurisdictions that
ain't afraid of a little friction open
up your ears and just start to listen
and rearrange the game we believe in
change through the Galaxy tap into the
reality proponent of personal Liberty
listen to all as I drop the science of a
serious Alliance Defiance is key son to
protecting your freedom going through
the Galaxy tap into the reality
proponent of personal Liberty listen to
Alexy as off the science of a serious
Alliance Defiance is key s to protect in
your freedom it can't be understated
what Germany has created normal house is
getting raided hey your cast is Getting
Faded we made it a it anabe it you want
it you going to get it hey there I said
it a million times cuz medical Imports
are in the billions and I'm here to tell
the world that when it comes to cannabis
I hope I don't receive no animus
Germany's the silver Pearl and medical
Hing has swollen to four times the size
just since the last time you got high so
sick how quick change comes cuz so long
so many wrongs done stay strong in the
dis phenomenon and don't always go along
with the masses toxic assd I'm asking
your sisters and brothers just to pass
it going through the Galaxy tap into the
reality proponent of personal Liberty
listen to Al as I drop the science of a
serious Alliance Defiance is key son to
protecting your freedom going through
the tap into the reality proponent of
personal Liberty listen to Alex as Dr
the science of a serious Alliance
Defiance is K son to protect and your
freedom going through the Galaxy tap
into the reality proponent of personal
Liberty listen to Alex t as I drop the
science of a serious Alliance Defiance
is key son to protecting your freedom
going through the Galaxy tap into the
reality proponent of personal Liberty
listen to Alexy as I Dr the science of a
serious Alliance Defiance is key son to
protecting your freedom
a
[Music]