so i'm very excited to introduce our
guest here today another california
industry pioneer uh to talk about some
of your insights and experiences in
cannabis financing
so
let's just kick it right off i just want
you to tell me a little bit about
yourself and your background and what
brought you into cannabis investing well
thanks mary and thanks for having me
we're happy to be here
we just attended the last conference at
london and that went very well and we'll
be at the uh the conference in zurich um
we find these conferences very
informative to aggregate all the
information that's coming in through uh
the european markets and and basically
everywhere outside of the united states
market but we were the first dedicated
lender in the united states that was
privately held doing bridge loans to
cannabis use specialties properties in
the united states
prior to entering cannabis we've done 5
000 transactions for over 5 billion
dollars
we had the skill set when our local
congressman dana rohrabacher
passed the roebuck or blumenar amendment
which in the united states was the most
consequential legislation ever passed
that nobody ever talks about that
legislation defunded the department of
justice from any prosecution of a
cannabis related business so
when congress used what we call the
power of the purse to take away the
money from the department of justice
from prosecution we quickly realized
this was the largest newly created asset
class in the world
of 50 billion dollars is now what we
have been able to project out that just
the real estate asset class in the
united states so we started lending in
the sector by 2016 and today we've done
69 transactions for 435 million with 34
payoffs we've originated more
transactions had more payoffs than any
other lender and we've seen over 2 000
transactions in just the cannabis sector
we've also aggregated all that data to
have the most robust data sets of
anybody in the world
wow that's incredible thank you for
giving us that great background
you know it seems like six years is a
short time but in cannabis years it's a
very long time uh it's been about 10
years since the united states started
really getting into commercial cannabis
for personal legal use
and you know 10 years into it
knowing what you know now is there
anything that you would have done
differently
when you were getting started
we're on the real estate side so we're
not um
owners in the cannabis equity businesses
so
we tried to move into it as early as we
possibly could
was the year that that legislation
passed
we were actually trying to lend in 2014.
just couldn't get our third party
service providers title insurance
property insurance our investors our
legal teams our compliance our errors
and admissions insurance to sign off on
it
and
you know being a leader in an industry
is not always about doing things in the
most center of this of a circle of the
of it being the safest in the center
sometimes you need to be all the way to
the edge of the outer perimeter of that
circle where you're on the edge of risk
and so that that that circle of of what
risky is and what what is on being on
the edge is something that as you're a
leader in an industry you're constantly
redefining that and you're we're
poloris was the one that was
establishing getting the first fdic
insured warehouse lines of credits
getting the first investment credit
grade ratings in the industry getting
the first institutional
uh investors as a privately held fund so
you know that that per the the risk is
perception and if you have the data and
the facts to back back you up you can
continually move that that risk
perspective out as long as you're
shoring it up with with
facts and data to to de-risk the
downside of it
okay well i'm glad you brought up risk
because i actually wanted to talk to you
a little bit more about that um
you know obviously the economy is in a
difficult place right now we've got
global inflation uh you know what are
you doing to mitigate that risk i know
you're you're speaking about a lot of
data but you know what else are you
doing to to mitigate the risk sure so
there's two sides for us there's the
borrower side and how we look at risk
there and then there's also how what
we're doing to
offset those costs on the investor side
or or the fund administration side so
for the borrower side
we want to underwrite each of these
transactions so we look at the real
estate as one part of the equation so we
call that the property company and then
we look at the op the cannabis business
side the prop or the the
the operating company and so for the
operating company when we look at these
transactions we want to look at their
make sure that they're an expert an
existing experienced operator we can't
afford to work with somebody that's just
getting in the industry it's it's too
complicated of an industry for us to
take that that risk or for our borrower
the property owner to take that risk
but the second thing is is for that real
estate it has to be specialty purpose
built for cannabis use and that requires
certain licensing
specific tenant improvements specific
equipment specific power specific water
all these things and so what we want to
do is we want to underwrite 100 of all
the costs that are necessary we can't
leave anything to to guess or
speculation
so when we do an an underwriting of a
transaction we want to understand what's
the total cost for the property purchase
what's the total construction cost or
tenant improvements and what is the
equipment that is necessary to get that
facility up and running we want to we
underwrite 100 of what the costs are
required to get that all the way to
being a cash flowing facility and then
from there we'll typically lend up to 60
of that so the borrowers need to know
that they need to come up with 40
but the difference between us and a
traditional bank and by the way we'll
talk about banking in a second in the
u.s
the difference with us is we're a cost
basis lender so we're going to look at
that 100 percent cost basis of all those
things the the acquisition costs the
tenant improvement construction and
equipment we're going to count that as
100 cost basis and we'll go up to 60 of
that whereas
banks or other lenders are only going to
look at the real estate value and
99 of all of them are going to look at
what's called the alternative use which
is not cannabis use and so that value is
probably going to be half of what the
valuation is so you're you might there
is traditional finance in the u.s
there's 704 depositor
fdic insured federal and state banks out
there there's four dozen banks that are
uh that are traditional banks that are
lending including ours in the united
states so
believe it or not
as much as you may hear differently
out of the 2000 transactions we've
looked at since 2014 we've never seen
one transaction that didn't have banking
in place if it did would be a massive
red flag to us so
there is banking out there it's
typically state banking any bank in the
us can accept cannabis deposits if they
wanted to they just don't have the
compliance to risk their their banking
license to accept that the banks that
are doing it they have their own
specific compliance department for each
state they're charging for that
that deposit so imagine paying money to
make a deposit it's usually point two
percent and they have higher banking
fees so
so there's those robust banking out
there um but um you know we we just we
just are trying to
basically all these cannabis operators
are entrepreneurs and we are our goal is
to take whatever equity that you've
raised and take it as far as you
possibly can because when you're doing
that initial equity raise it's the worst
possible valuation it's your lowest
valuation possible so we want to
minimize what equity you need to raise
and you want to come to us and
understand how much equity do i need to
raise so that i'm not raising selling
too much my company too early
uh well it sounds like your model is
working
uh you know i really appreciate all that
you've done to really help a lot of
these companies get a start because you
know it was so difficult in the
beginning to get investors or to get a
loan or to get banking and you know what
drew you into being one of the first
when when there wasn't really very many
people that were already doing it well i
i wish i had some awesome story um and
and some of our my my
partners uh we do have stories but for
us it was more um just that we had the
skill set to do
the the building and acquisition of
these types of properties and dana
roebacher is our friend and local
congressman in my my state
so that when that's passing when we
launched our fund he was he was on the
on the congress floor got calling in for
a live interview when we launched the
fund so that was that was kind of the
genesis for for us
but as we've been into it and get
further and further into it um we're
hearing and we're learning all these
stories and just as a kind of a metric
this is about a 50 billion dollar asset
class of real estate once it's built out
there's been about 3 billion put out of
that 3 billion we've done 435 million of
it so our facilities are generating
probably at least 2 billion worth of
revenue coming through the united states
each year and for me personally
the the fact that that that much
cannabis is being legally produced
some some of those people that are
purchasing that are not purchasing
opioids and for me even if it was just
one percent people are
that that five opiates are now
transitioning over and using a cannabis
instead that's a win for me um there's a
it's an enormous economic uh driver out
there it's a lot of jobs and as nick
said earlier you know it's it's it's
resilient to recession and economic
downturns and even during covid we were
deemed an essential business none of our
transactions had any distress during
that time that's that's fantastic well
thank you for everything you've done in
the united states now switching into the
european markets um you know this is a
really exciting time i'm curious what
kind of due diligence you're doing as
you prepare for a growing european
marketplace it's hard to do
due diligence from a
a debt perspective when you have no
rules so so we're we're here building
relationships trying to get a lay of the
land it takes time to
to understand these markets and how
they're emerging and and the underlying
things that that you don't see in the
uh pitch decks and the and the data sets
out there
perceptions and and how things will
really shake out sometimes takes time so
so for us it's just starting to build
those relationships starting to look at
transactions starting to run those
transactions through our modeling to see
okay this would me
this would all work here but what would
we need to solve for that so for a debt
provider we need to have attorneys that
are licensed in those states or those
countries we need to have right we need
to have relationships with regulators we
need to know what do we need to be able
to do in the event that we had to
foreclose on that facility and we're
going to be potentially directly in the
business ourselves and so we have to
think all those things all the way
through
my my job
at one point was i was worst case
scenario rob because i always had to be
the one that that broke the transaction
the models to see what are we going to
do in these worst case scenarios to make
sure that we can unwind that transaction
get it repositioned and it sold so
for us right now we're looking for our
third party service providers which
attorneys i earlier uh at the conference
this morning there was four attorneys up
here and two of them were our attorneys
so i thought that was pretty funny um
denton's and zuber um so
and but there's other things we need
construction consulting companies to run
our feasibility reviews
we need to have um you know who are we
going to be using for insurance there's
it's a little bit different nuance in
the uni in europe and united states in
the united states these traditional
third-party service providers errors and
admissions insurance property insurance
are it's federally illegal so there is
in any policy that you traditionally get
it says that it's null and void if you
break the law and so you you need to
make sure that you're uh in the united
states that you've got those carve outs
that they acknowledge that that as long
as it's legal in the state that you're
that the policy will still be enforced
so we have to understand how how
how these things are going to work and
and the biggest question i've been
asking some of my some of the people
i've been been speaking with already at
this conference and the one previously
is
i personally and all of our team really
needs to get comfortable with you know
these these facilities and we only do
indoor facilities we
production facilities we don't do any
agricultural deals so that's a farming
lender and that's not what we are so
we'll only be doing cultivation testing
distribution dispensaries things like
that and we we need to understand we
know how much it costs to build these
facilities we've seen these facilities
and when you're putting out 10 20 50 100
million dollars into a facility that is
an enormous capex expense how are you
going to re
re recover that capex and be profitable
when you can import from
countries that have lower capex and opex
costs and i just that's that's the
biggest one we're struggling with right
now and it's not that it's it's that
it's uh unsolvable we just need to
understand how we get comfortable with
that because if we can't get comfortable
with it we certainly aren't going to be
able to
uh get it get our investors comfortable
with it oh yeah that's for sure now
i'm also really curious as this market
blows up and and how that relates to the
u.s market on the u.s federal uh time
frame for rescheduling what that might
do for interstate and international
trade and if you're looking at that as a
as a way to gauge how you're going to
enter this marketplace
so
in the united states uh for the my
political prognostication is is that
there's there's always a push to get
the next bill through the house and our
it's the senate you need to get through
and to get 60 votes in the senate means
you're going to need 10 republicans and
there's actually 17 republicans that are
identified as being pro-cannabis but
they're not pro-cannabis when you throw
every single thing that the democrats
want and the democrats are not going to
let their trophy piece of of of what
they run on go through unless they get
social justice reform and social equity
components put in there and i think that
the republicans and i think the whole
industry is okay with that but the the
democrats problem is they always go
so far overboard that you can't keep the
republicans on board so
that i i don't see any
i my prognostication is it's going to be
in the next administration whether it's
republican or democrat at best and
that they're not going to see any
meaningful reform in the united states
and
eventually we do see it being
deconflicted from from federal policy or
federally legalized but even if that
happens i don't
i don't think that the united states is
going to allow importation if it becomes
federally legal and you know true leave
is betting that it will be x be able to
be exported they have one of the most
advanced facilities in in the world in
southern florida or sorry just in
florida and that facility is being built
to gmp certification so that they could
potentially out uh you know
ship it internationally
it's just going to be interesting to see
i do think that there'll be some
compacts put together between states
that you can cross state lines but
right now i think it's just going to be
the status quo and the further
it gets down the line like in the united
states where you're 38 states with
separate uh compliance for every single
state the harder it is to wind all that
back in and make it under one compliant
package i just i don't see it we
yeah so well all right well that's
that's
you know a lot to think about obviously
i'm thinking of the importing and
exporting and a lot of international
trade um we'll look forward to that in
the meantime you know there's probably a
lot to be said about how you're going to
be investing from other countries that
are going to be doing trade before we
get a chance to do that ourselves with
uh with europe in america um but since
we have only just a few minutes left i
wanted to just first ask you one last
question and then open it up to the
floor to see if anybody else has any
questions
for any
new entrepreneurs or investors that are
just getting into the industry what
advice would you give them
so
we had a lot of investors and raised a
lot of capital when we entered the
cannabis space i had the mistake of
thinking that you know we would be able
to use those same investors to to go
down this this direction
and that wasn't the case at all
and the opportunity
was passing us by and we were not able
to uh lend for 24 for two years
and so i've tried all kinds of different
strategies so i've been on the same side
as as many of these entrepreneurs
as this market has emerged it's a little
bit easier for us to raise debt than
than you guys because we have a secured
asset but there's not the upside either
um and so if i could give a
super
massive piece of advice is
you always hear try to get you know as
few investors as possible and as big a
checks as you can but in reality
nobody
that's a very difficult proposition and
so what i would tell people is don't go
the traditional way of of trying to
raise capital try to have the the lowest
entry point or the lowest size check
writer in the and the most amount of
investors because raising money at five
twenty five thousand dollars at a time
is going to get you further down the
line than waiting for guys at 100 000 or
250 or a million at a time and you need
that basis of capital to get the bigger
check riders so just just when you start
thinking about how you're going to do
your raise think about your your
securities offering or your structuring
or your how your the the third parties
that you're going to use to manage your
investors in the united states that
might be k1s or investor portals just
think about using third-party facility
third parties that can facilitate a way
higher the maximum amount of investors
that you possibly can and minimize those
those investment amounts
it's better to have uh to have capital
flowing in all the time than keep
talking to people and they're they're
thinking about it you need those checks
flowing in all the time and so we
switched to retail investors in 2016 and
today we have about a thousand and
eighty of those so our fund is is
currently about 303 million assets in
our management and it's compromised
it's con consists of probably at least
95 it might be 98
of individuals and so an individual is
going to be able to give you a decision
within a day or two because they're
their own credit committee when you
start going to funds when you start
going to institutional investors when
you start going to these other people
you lost that that direct connection to
the person making the decision of being
able to pitch your story and answer
those questions that they might have
when you tell somebody and they go to
tell your story to a credit committee in
cannabis
good frickin luck trust me
i mean we have four years of audited
returns we're investment grade rated we
have institutional investors and
still it's it's enormously and
challenging and i have a lot easier than
most people are because of the history
we have so that would be my my primary
advice and and another thing too is that
it you should be using data and facts to
educate them the investment should sell
itself it's not about sales it's just
about giving it educating them letting
them know um you know what
what what this is going to do and this
is why this is how we're supporting
these facts based on the information we
know today and that event information in
facts is going to continue to evolve and
change and that's okay but as long as
you're using facts to back that up
great great that's great advice did
anybody here have any questions so we're
going to open it up if you'd like to
we'll start over there one more time for
rob seacrest and mary patton
[Applause]
as a retail investor and as a cannabis
company how would one connect with
polaris
um you can reach out to us through the
app um our website um my email is rob at
pelorus equity group i'm sure you can
see it in the in the the the material i
think we have an up we also have the
hoover app w-h-o-v-a
or catch me afterwards i'm happy to give
you my contact information
okay question over here here we go
coming
speed walk
thank you as a um a u.s multi-state
operator um i'm
thinking about coming into the european
markets so do you write underwrite in
the european markets currently and then
the second part of my question is going
back to the u.s markets how do you feel
about the opportunity zones and is that
an area of development within your own
business
great so the first one is
we are looking at preliminarily looking
at transactions here in in europe in in
foreign countries
if we if we land on a on a transaction
that that meets all of our our metrics
that we've established in the u.s
and then we can get past answering some
of the compliance or the uh the the the
the underlying questions that we're not
sure of we're willing to come here to
you to we're willing to lend the next
part is our fund is only authorized to
lend within the united states so then we
have to decide are we going to do us
stand-alone transactions or launch a
fund here
right at this point there's not enough
business for us to launch a half a
billion dollar fund here there's it just
doesn't make sense we would have dead
capital so we'll probably aggregate a
few transactions and then assign those
into our funds in the next three to five
years something like that but we're here
early to get an understanding and build
these relationships today as it relates
back to the united states and
opportunity zones and opportunity zones
in the in the united states is just a
zone where you have really beneficial
tax
structures and
we are just a lender so we don't own the
property so the owner of the property is
the one that would benefit from the
opportunity zone not us as the lender
but
as we do have our own division we do own
lots of projects we have a whole
separate division the company that
entitles stuff
entitles projects for cannabis and that
builds relationships with with the
cities so that we can
take advantage of those so we are and
we'll probably launch a fund in the
united states that is not an opportun
opportune zone focused fund but we're we
believe that there'll be some
repositioning of distressed transactions
in the u.s in the next 12 to 24 months
and so we're positioned to to
reposition those assets with that that
fund a great question
wow great anyone else
you guys getting hungry yeah let's go
eat one more time mary pat and rob
seacrest
[Applause]