so i'm thrilled to be here and talk
about intellectual property perspective
for the cannabis industry today
right
so i'm gonna
share some insights about advertising
cannabis and cbd products in germany and
i also will talk about brand protection
in europe which is really important for
you
let's start with the advertising
i will focus on i think the most
important products which are medicinal
products cosmetics
and food
let's start with the medicinal products
cannabis or cbd containing drug is
subject to prescription in germany
as you surely know so medicinal products
subject to prescription may
be advertised only among healthcare
professionals so
it may not be advertised among
consumers and consumers
however if you do advertise it among
healthcare professionals you have to
observe some
there are also some limits of course
misleading advertising is not permitted
i give you some examples um
where to
under which it would be misleading for
example if therapotic
efficacy or effects are attributed
which the medical products do not have
that would be not allowed
if the impression is falsely created
that success can be expected with
certainty of course illegal
if false or deceptive statements are
made about the composition
also not allowed if you use expert
opinions
which is often done or testimonials
this must be scientific and properly
cited
if you do not comply with these rules
you
face jail time
or at least you get a fine and of course
your material will be confiscated
so
i think more
more problematic is the food food and
dietary supplements
these are some examples i made
screenshots of over the weekend when i
did this presentation
these are all claims from german
websites
there to cbd
it says cbd has been shown to inhibit
the appetite cravings or cbd helps with
pain
stress sleep disorders or
migraine
so the question is if these examples are
allowed under german law
again
you have to observe the again the act
against unfair competition
so in general of course unfair
commercial practices are illegal
um a commercial practice shall be
regarded as misleading if it content if
it contains false statements regarding
the main characteristics now what does
that mean unfortunately we do not have
that much case law in germany
on advertisement claims yet we do have a
lot of about regulatory questions
however i found one
example a recent example from the court
in munich thereto it is unfair to
advertise with a statement in a
prominent place where two cbd
content is 10
and it is only explained in the small
print that the product actually only
contains contains 10 percent
cbd liquid there's a big difference
between that and there the chord held
that would be a misleading and false
statement
just to give you one example
talk about food and dietary supplements
of course you have to observe the eu
health claim regulation
there to the use of nutrition health
claims shall not be false ambiguous or
misleading
nutrition and health claims shall be
based on and substantiated by generally
accepted scientific data
and at last health claims shall be
permitted unless they are included in a
special list which is part of that
regulation and unfortunately until today
cbd is not included in that list
therefore
specific claims linked to cbd
linking cbd to health
is not permitted for food
so avoid these health claims i'm sorry
to be a party pooper here but at the
moment this is
the law
so if your product is not a drug you're
not allowed to claim that it's
beneficial for your health
just to give you an example
how
or which lar to which large extent the
german courts say what um a health claim
is so these are all examples from german
cases
so if you claim your food keeps you
young
that would be
not allowed if your food contains cbd or
if you if you only say it it has a
health benefit or it is good for the
body
it's good for
my organism it strengthens the body's
defenses
helps to overcome phases of weakness
so this is
actually
not so bad but
under german case law this would be a
health claim so the health claim
regulation applies
and
cbd products are not in the list of the
health claims that would be forbidden
or a slim and fit
there's another example
facilitate sleep calm and gentle sleep
or body comes to rest
would be problematic
right
my last
the last thing i would like to share
with you about food and that's um
specifically important for the german
market
so you are manufacturing a manufacturer
and you you claim that you this is not a
drug it's it's only a dietary supplement
let's say still you advertise it as a
drug so from the overall get up the
claims and the advertising you use it
looks like a medicinal product
in these cases
the courts would say that it is a drug
and then you have a problem because you
didn't get drug approval in advance
so whenever yeah yeah just watch out not
to to make the presentation of your
product to
look like too much as a medicinal
product because then
it could be helped that it is actually a
drug even though you did not plan that
and this is specifically important for
the german market
right um
the last uh thing is the cosmetic
products
again i made some um here are some
examples from german websites i found
there too
it was claimed that cbd products
are particularly good against skin
diseases
scientists have investigated
cbd fights the cause of acne at its
roots
well the question is whether this would
be allowed under german law
so
under
the cosmetic regulations whatever you
say it has to be true of course
so if it is claimed on the product that
it contains a specific ingredient the
ingredient shall be deliberately present
or
marketing communications shall not imply
that expressions of opinions are
verified claims unless the opinion
reflects
verifiable evidence so you always need
verifiable evidence when you make a
cross claim for your cosmetic product
further you need evidential support
so claims for cosmetic products shall be
supported by adequate and again
verifiable evidence
evidence for claim substantiation shall
take into account state of the art
practices and at last where studies are
being used as evidence
they shall be relevant to that product
so just not using any any
evidence it always have to be exactly
for your product then you can use it
okay so that was uh in the limited
amount of time a really narrow insights
about the strict rules of advertising in
the cannabis field until
today and at last i would like to share
some
thoughts about brand protection i'm
handling trademarks for
the cannabis industry since 2017
obviously in germany
and i brought you some
recent case law about
cannabis trademark so that that one is
um a quite important one from the
european court of justice
the cannabis store amsterdam
unfortunately it was rejected
the european court stated that this
would be contrary to public policy or to
accepted principles of morality
yeah i find it quite astonishing i think
it's a beautiful trademark but somehow
the courts saw it differently
they acknowledge that the cannabis
consumption is
generally legal in the netherlands
however
a violation of the public order in other
eu countries would be sufficient for the
rejection of the mark
so and that was a starting point for
many more
trademark decisions we had afterwards
with
terms of
yeah some
for cannabis products like this one it's
quite recent a decision from the board
of the appeal of the european trademark
office
again it says it
is contrary to the public policy
the marks conveyed a message related to
the consumption of prohibited and
harmful substances and therefore were
rejected
also this one which is
i think not so drastic but still it was
um rejected the well weed
here this is in quite interesting
because the applicant cited the
ruling of the european of um
the european court of justice from
november last year
there too as you probably all know the
cannabinoid was held is legal for um
yeah for bringing over the over from
france i think to germany it was held
that this cannot be stopped it may be
freely marketed so they held that um
hemp is actually legal so the applicant
argued how can you are how can you say
this infringes public policy
well um the opinion of the board was not
changed so they they uh the the mark got
rejected unfortunately
all these on the left side
are
certain types of cannabis all these were
rejected because again
contrary to the public policy and the
principles of morality
also
bavaria wheat
and the hemp fest
right so
yeah you see despite the greater
tolerance toward the consumption of
mariana within the eu
it uh still it's still problematic so
until today i would advise my clients
not to use words like mariana cannabis
hemp grass pot wheat hush or anything
like that so
because you probably get a rejection
um
right and at last we also have
purely descriptive trademarks
these are some examples
cheese is also a type of cannabis no you
cannabis the court said well that only
says well you know what is in your
product so it's purely descriptive and
whenever you have a purely descriptive
trademark you cannot monopolize it and
you cannot register it the same happened
to just cbd cannot farm midi hemp
ease
was also one i handled and lost
unfortunately because the court said
well it was not the court it was the
board of appeal of the european
trademark office
they held well this only tells the
consumer what the cbd in the product
makes to your body
it releases and so it's purely
descriptive and not legible for
trademark protection
right thank you so much for your
attention
okay sure
all right you can be first
um may i go back to the the the
trademark you for the dutch for the
dutch one the cannabis
um could it be a solution that you first
put it in the benelux
how you could trademarks and then maybe
afterwards go to the european
i remember that that was like a trick
many many years ago if whenever you
because i'm from germany and the german
patent office was really strict so what
we did we advise our clients go to the
benelux and then you file an
international trademark and then nobody
really looks anymore what happened there
but i don't think this
still works actually because when you
your
your idea is we go to the banner looks
you probably get it because they're very
easy to get trademarks still what i
heard
then you file an international trademark
based on the on that mark but then
this
application goes to the specific
trademark offices where you apply for
let's say germany us
or the european union
and there is an examiner and he or she
will examine the trademark under their
law
so i don't think that this will help you
just because you have the banner looks
mark the german examiner will still say
well here in germany you don't get the
trademark protection
did i answer your question okay
sorry yeah thank you uh madam
hello i have a question related to
cosmetics cbd cosmetics so if you're in
a brochure or whatever which you hand
out
maybe not to the patients but to the
pharmacist so if you
for example state an oil a cream which
you put on your term is poisy or can
be anti-inflammatory as a khan and
sundung semen work and how about that
yeah that's a born-a-line case
you just have to whenever you make
claims like that can be
anti-inflammatory you actually need
evidence for that you cannot just say
something it's just saying no evidence
it may be anti-inflammatory people have
reported
that it's a some people say
i get it and you know what what is
possible and i see that on websites i
see that at like they say
there
are a lot of
research done yet
still we are at the beginning we cannot
say 400
sure but we see the trend goes there so
that would be possible
you know just to be honest to say where
we are right now and i think actually
me as a consumer from a consumer side i
would feel more confident with that
just you know
promise something which you don't really
maybe cannot answer now in america
there's always a little asterisk and
then very small print this has not been
proven by the fda or
we're probably lying but we're doing our
best okay yeah that's a good solution
so many thanks for the nice insights and
i have them to elaborate with the topic
claims so
you can make claims as soon as they are
supported by verifiable data you
mentioned that but how does the law
define verifiable data as a scientist i
guess that's scientific data but even
within scientific literature there are
different levels of evidence for example
the use of cbd as anti-agnet is is
published in the cell model so this
pre-clinical data it's still and we know
which
biochemical mechanism makes this
possible so it is a fact in science
can you use this claim or do they the
law means uh randomized clinical trial
placebo control so this pre-clinical
data double blind
randomized study okay because for that
there are only four applications of
cannabis which are actually have this
kind of study so if you go beyond this
for applications you cannot use spray
clinical data i mean if it's published
in nature or science or why not yeah
it's um
yeah there's a great risk
that it would be illegal absolutely
you just have to make clear that this is
not randomized double etc
okay so you could use it and be clear
that this is based on this level of
evidence in science okay because it
brings me to my second question which is
i mean you give many examples regarding
food for instance what you cannot write
so
health claims yeah so what will be an
example of what you can actually write
if you at least one example
used to have the context i mean it's
very clear what you cannot write but
what we have like um
probably but this is you know
this is very specific and of course but
uh but that we do have case law where
the courts say that might be okay to say
become lich
which is in in english good for your uh
what is it in english like
regards
digestive so so there are some
expressions where they say well actually
this doesn't really refer to the health
so it's always about if you if you say
you feel really better it makes an
influence on your body then it's a
health claim
but
yeah as i said this is um a very
difficult question a difficult matter
and it's from um
case to case we have to
to evaluate it all right right it's not
an easy one to just offer so if i if my
anti-acne cream cbd cream says okay this
can help you address acne with the
asterisk based on preclinical data that
you can find in this scientific journal
i might get away with that or
yeah
sorry
why don't we have a chat outside and we
make her
a special deal
we have one more over here
hi
let's say my wettest dream comes true
and cannabis becomes
fully legalized and we have a regulated
market here in germany on the eu member
state level what does it mean for this
topic on the eu level
yeah it would be a big change for
i mean
then
it would i guess it would not take long
until it's included in the list of for
the um admitted health claims
and then you can actually
claim that your food is beneficial for
your health which you until now i mean
you
you're not even allowed in germany to
bring it on the market in the first
place and not we're not talking about
advertisement but
if we as you said if we
in if we're in the future and we can do
that
and then i guess we you have to wait
until it's also in the list of the
health claims and then you can use
beneficial health claims for the food
so that would make a difference
i'd like to expand on the question
before that
so would you think that
for health claims it would
need to test the product specifically
for health benefits
instead of the isolated compound
you mean what is the procedure to get
accepted in that list yes uh can you can
you take results from uh science and
look at the isolated uh product or would
you need to take your uh your product
that contains cbd to test for these
health claims
i'm i'm an appeal lawyer not so much
regulatory i don't i don't really with
the regulatory issues that there's a
colleagues of me so i don't know how you
actually get the how the procedure works
to get uh registered at the health claim
as an admitted health claim
so
i don't want to answer that because i
don't really know how what exactly you
need to do if it's the ingredient or the
product i guess it's the ingredient
yeah that was wonderful and perfect and
thank you for taking time to answer the
questions one more time for margaret
knitter
from skw schwartz