well good afternoon happy 4 20 everyone
from San Francisco
um let's see here
our panel is about disruption everything
that we've had to do to get where we are
and also I wanted uh Ashley one of our
panelists said like not only are we
industry disruptors our industry is
being disrupted so we're going to talk a
bit about that too how the Cannabis
industry is actually being disrupted and
disrupting I guess well my name is
Debbie Goldsberry I've been in the
Cannabis industry for 30 years I'm the
CEO of Magnolia Wellness dispensary in
Oakland and I'm the chief compliance
officer for High Fidelity dispensary in
Berkeley please come visit we have a
vape lounge at Magnolia so you can
actually try the samples if you want
um
I have been a disrupter from day one the
first thing we had to do of course is
disrupt prohibition we had to tell the
DEA and the police and the elected
officials that this is a democracy the
voters run the Democracy that the
government's supposed to make laws based
on facts and Science and when they don't
we the people take charge of the
democracy and on cannabis prohibition
they had failed us epically and in fact
prohibition was illegal and our Acts
were what needed to be done to as Jack
Herrera said so eloquently all those
years make sure that hemp can save the
planet so I've been very excited to be a
part of this movement
um my own activism I've ran two local
marijuana initiatives I ran a recount if
you ever get a chance to demand a
recount it is just as fun as you can
imagine to demand a recount we won the
recount we did a referendum in San Jose
when they passed a law trying to make
marijuana dispensaries illegal we did a
referendum you know if the city passes a
law you can undo that as a citizen using
the referendum process I was subpoenaed
by the feds to test testify against Ed
Rosenthal in his federal trial and
refused went to federal court in front
of Judge Breyer who said
the refusal is
has been brought into my core with such
dignity and care and we can see that
when people have strong views of these
intense issues that they can come into
federal courts and make their case in a
way that's intelligent and comprehensive
and matters and he congratulated us and
rather than making us testify set us
free that was incredible
um
I opened my first dispensary Berkeley
Patients Group in 1999 when it was the
right thing to do not the legal thing to
do and now at Magnolia Wellness I've
been involved in a turnaround project
for those people in the industry you
know our industry is 20 years old in
California people like me if we've made
it this far it's been tough and we're in
debt and we've struggled and a lot of us
went to jail and we've suffered we
probably all have post-traumatic stress
disorder from having to fight the feds
and fight our government and deal with
our families and face the stigma of the
Cannabis prohibition all these years
um
cannabis can help with that hell yeah
smoke them if you got them not here
um
so at Magnolia I've been involved I took
over Magnolia if you want to get in the
Cannabis industry in California now at
retail really the only way in is
Acquisitions I took over Magnolia like
one of the many dispensaries it was
seven figures in debt I've been working
on a turnaround project there so close
so close can't wait to finish this
turnaround project and start sleeping at
night again
um and uh we'll get there there's a
strain for that um and uh and and look
I'm still on the mission hemp can save
the planet and I know we're all here for
that too I've known Alex Rogers the guy
who puts on this conference for almost
30 years and yeah we're building a
business but we're also building a
community and we really are trying to
make nicer a nicer Society through the
legalization of cannabis so with that in
mind we've got a panel of disruptors
from a bunch of different fields
um we have uh a really I think exciting
panel planned and so just let me
introduce the panelists and then I will
turn it right over to the first
speaker first we have Zach darling right
here Zach is a marketing guy from a
hybrid Collective doing a lot of stuff
I'll introduce him in a moment we've got
uh plants we've got Lance from Boveda
but of course Lance comes from online
the online world he was the former GM of
marijuana.com and a number of different
companies so I'll tell you about we've
got Ashley down there Ashley is a lawyer
and also a uh in the banking industry so
I'm looking forward to find out what is
coming up for Banking and then we have
venu down there at the end I mean this
guy's such a badass lawyer you're not
even going to believe it he's an East
coaster he's still doing criminal
defense people are being arrested for
cannabis out there I mean they still are
here to some degree he's going to make
sure that our industry stays safe and
we're going to legalize it but in the
meantime we're going to keep people out
of jail while we do it so with no
further Ado let me introduce my first
panelist here which is Zach darling I
mean I love this guy he's the CEO the
chief eternal optimist of his company he
uh founded the hybrid Collective it's a
full
creative
it's the hybrid creative
Zach is from the hybrid creative
yeah because the collective should be a
dispensary right there's your
opportunity he's from now he founded the
hybrid creative it's a full service
design and development marketing company
they do branding they do identity they
do package design they do packaging
website development marketing tools and
much much more so Zach take it away
hello everybody all right hot mic I like
it how's everybody doing
good good thank you so much for the
introduction uh as I mentioned as was
mentioned I'm the chief eternal optimist
at the Hybrid creative we are the top
creative Agency for cannabis Ventures
here in the United States and soon to be
International uh in we've been in
business for about nine years uh working
within the Hydroponics industry before
cannabis became avert our old school I
was raised on a hippie commune by pot
farmers in the Emerald Triangle so uh
that was you could say I'm second
generation
um I I before we got started this panel
I really felt like I wanted to just
identify like what what does it mean to
be a disrupter it's a buzzword in the
industry in here in San Francisco and
and in the.com world and in Silicon
Valley it's definitely an overused
buzzword so what does it mean for us in
the Cannabis industry and for us as
individuals to be disruptors well when I
was a hippie kid I got kicked out of the
Waldorf School and I got kicked out of
the other hippie school because I was
always a disruptive child and I learned
the value of uh of attention through
disruption now maybe that wasn't the
most positive thing because it ended me
up in public school where I learned
discipline but it's a valuable lesson in
in how uh we can challenge the status
quo of what's going on in any given
moment and then all of a sudden divert
attention to what we're doing cannabis
in itself is a disruptive industry right
we have disrupted the world and it's
such a tremendous fundamental basis from
the alcohol industry from prohibition
from legality from conservative uh uh um
agendas
from from what law enforcement has been
telling us from misinformed propaganda
cannabis turned that entire world on its
head so we every one of us every one of
you is a disrupter by just being a part
of this and that's part of the reason we
love it we're excited about it because
it's Purpose Driven purpose-driven
Brands purpose-driven businesses
purpose-driven Industries are creating
change and people love being a part of
change so by its very nature being a
disrupter it's it's valuable for us to
be involved in and it's exciting for us
to be involved with this because we're
challenging the way things work because
the way things were were wrong and we
all agree about that so
um but now we're in the situation we're
inventing a new industry in a world that
never existed really before because it
had been driven in the in the black
market and
now we're disrupting ourselves if you
look at what's happening in various uh
you know how many small Mom and Pops do
you know that are out of business right
now because things have changed so much
the way things were we're becoming an
internally disruptive industry within
itself and uh this is presenting new
challenges for every entrepreneur and
business person and Venture as big money
and big multi-state operators and hugely
capitalized businesses are starting to
crush a lot of the smaller brands in
smaller businesses there have that
disruption is causing people to need to
consolidate come together and bond is
and and and create kind of in uh
collectives and communities through
distribution networks or what have you
so there's I have so much to say on this
matter and I'm looking forward to this
panel with these incredible people but I
I thank you for having me and I'm
looking forward to the talk
let's hear for Zach
[Applause]
hybrid Collective I mean I did it again
hybrid uh creative names the hybrid
creative tell us what do you guys do
over there I noticed on your website you
really have a lot of killer brands that
you represent and you're doing a great
job getting them seen in the industry
um who are you representing how do you
do it and how are you guys being
disruptive over there
great well we are like I said we're the
premier creative Agency for Canada's
Adventures we've launched and taken to
Market some of the biggest brands in uh
here in California especially uh in uh
January our agency was acquired by
kushco Holdings previously Kush bottles
uh which has really empowered our agency
to create our dream of being the
international cannabis agency so we want
to basically understand what marketing
and compliance means in every existing
and emerging cannabis Market
globally to where when people are ready
to take their brands Global uh we're
obviously the agency to go to because we
truly know what that means on a cultural
level as well as a legal compliance
level
I you know one of the brands that we
work with is bang one of the sponsors of
this event and I and I take my hat off
to them because they were disruptors in
the very beginning when nobody was was
becoming multi-state when nobody
actually was being bold enough to be
re-licensing their their brand across
state lines bang was already vastly
ahead of it and that's part of the
reason they've become such a a household
name in the Cannabis industry one of my
other clients that I would say has done
a fantastic job of being disruptive is
Canada craft uh absolute extracts makes
a a bond agreement with Lagunitas they
come out with two products one is a line
of of cannabis extracts that are infused
with uh with um hop terpenes right so it
tastes like you're vaping an IPA there's
no alcohol in it they're bringing that
terpene profile flavor into the
experience and then on the opposite side
they're using cannabis terpenes to make
an IPA taste like uh to taste like
cannabis that's Innovative see that's
really the root of what disruption means
it's Innovation it's not novelty I would
say things like double barrel is is
novelty it's tchotchke it's okay fine
cool take two things make them work
together but true Innovation is taking
something completely different and
changing the Status Quo but it is a
perfect example fitting that that Niche
that needed to be fit finding that spot
and then changing the industry and
dominating their portion of the market
so for us everything at the root of what
we do is in strategy
there's plenty of good looking Brands
out there if you are a high quality
brand or a consistent brand then you are
what we uh that's what we call a minimum
standard how are you going to radically
differentiate your brand and and as we
call it zag in the industry it's where
you're not another sheep in the herd
because your main competitor is not
another cannabis brand it's brand noise
it's brand clutter and so what we do as
a creative agency through all the
variety of full spectrum tools from web
development to design marketing
packaging
Etc the whole Spectrum we help you find
your zag we help you determine how you
can radically differentiate your brand
and rise above the noise of the industry
and all the other brands that are out
there vying for attention
I definitely recommend that you take a
look at the website for the hybrid
creative I learned a lot on there and
also you can see what a good looking
brand looks like and you can learn more
of course about the work that Zach does
that seems so it's so entertaining and
so Charming so thank you very much glad
to be here with you
um our next speaker is Ashley ellsner
she is a CEO and founder of artery Inc
and Green Market Bank Ashley is a
financial expert she's a lawyer she's an
expert in financial services and
technology for the Cannabis Market she
works in digital payments banking
Alternatives and more Ashley are you
going to save us this banking issue what
are we going to do let's turn it over to
Ashley
thank you thank you so much for that
introduction
um that is far more than I deserve
um I hope very much that uh there will
be there will be more movement
um by traditional institutions into into
the Cannabis industry
um they're
I I disagree on where the
the actual
um motivation comes for for them staying
out of it having worked with with quite
a few Financial Services firms in the
past
um I am aware of the the conservative
nature of it and for good reason they
they want to make sure that these stable
um that the economy remains stable and
is something that is available to
everybody and if there are situations
that cause them to shut down they don't
they don't want to have that happen
and there are opportunities uh for them
to to do well in this industry there's
also opportunities for them to fall into
pits with this industry so there are
there are a lot of things that need to
change
um in order for them to get comfortable
with it and we are working towards
pushing them towards accepting more uh
being able to use our services to accept
more cannabis
accounts
I
um
following Zach is just really it's it's
hard look I wanted to put the Charming
marketing guy first because I didn't
realize he was going to intimidate thank
you is the number one most pain in the
ass problem it's the reason behind all
of the crime all of the all of the
challenges all of the all of the dark
side of cannabis comes from from banking
so to be to be willing to tackle and
jump on something like that and and take
that on as the focus of your business to
me feels like it's bold it's Innovative
and therefore should you be the one
that's successful highly disruptive
whoever cracks this code is going to be
the one that like saves the day for the
industry
um I think we've cracked it
um so this is my background actually is
financial services law I was with sidley
Austin for several years in their
financial regulatory group out in New
York City
um I worked for Bessemer Venture
partners and legal and operations
um I this is my second fintech actually
my first fintech was an online hedge
fund investment it platform this was
back in 2011 before that space got
crowded uh we we did fine in that but
nobody invests in fintech frankly
um it's just not one of those spaces
where where institutional investors like
to invest I'm sure that that's a
familiar thing that many people in this
industry have also had to deal with is a
lack of institutional support
um banking itself is a challenge there's
a lot of regulations around it and doing
it wrong you go to prison period
and it's one of those things where
people also don't recognize that
payments is another space that you can
you can get into pitfalls with and there
are technologies that are usable for
this our our banking industry see I
would I would argue that our our product
is less
um it's less disruptive for this space
it's just frankly a necessity for this
space and more disruptive for
traditional banking services and
traditional payments this is a rail that
frankly could replace ACH it could
replace fed wire you're seeing that
actually in a lot of locations across
the globe and the US has actually been
very slow to adopt Financial
technologies that could be very
attractive for Banking and and frankly
are no-brainers when you start actually
looking at the technology themselves and
what they're currently using but our
disruption the disruption that we
provide is and as you can you can tell
I'm really a background person I'm
disrupting things on the B2B side I'm
interested in providing the the options
for people to use as an alternative to
bank owned rails
or federal government-owned rails this
is a it's it's something that
provides an additional layer of security
because you don't end up being closed
out of the system which is controlled
frankly by a few small not small large
but just a few corporate players and
it's you know the the ugly truth about
this is that the majority of uh State
Banks and smaller institutions Regional
Banks they're licensing their rails from
the larger institutions and that means
that they have to be careful what they
do they want to support the industry
they do most of them are affected by
this themselves but they also have to
comply with both both regulation of
course but I think that the government
has been more supportive to trying to
bring financial institutions on board
and the the financial institute the
financial industry itself has been
um very
uh cautious in moving in because they
are
it's a circular argument you guys are in
cash so it means you're more likely to
money launder and we don't want to be
handling money laundering but it's like
okay well but the the cash piece the
only reason why we're in cash is because
you guys refuse to bank us and so this
this ends up being the sicular yeah
exactly this this silly argument that
frankly has this circular format to it
that that really doesn't have a whole
lot of logic and it is fixable and
frankly I I put it upon the
the financial institutions themselves it
is their responsibility within our
society to actually monitor these
transactions that that they have a
privileged place in our society and they
need to live up to that privilege
so that that is what we're trying to
help them do get them more comfortable
with it and also get them more
comfortable with financial technology
that they are also not really that well
up on
Ashley
um Green Market Bay together
Green Market Bank is focused on
providing business banking services to
the marijuana industry tell us a little
bit about that what is it that you guys
do
so actually Green Market Bank was my old
trade name while I was learning this
industry I knew that I wanted to solve
the banking problem I knew that there
was a problem with payments as well and
was trying to take a two-pronged
approach to the cash problem in this
industry
um
artery is our product
artery pay is our website
and what we are doing we are working
with banking institutions some of the
smaller institutions that like I said
have been Limited in their ability to
work with this industry because of
either lack of capacity or concern about
whether they were going to lose the
licenses on their ACH and fed wire rails
concern about whether they were going to
yes possibly get into trouble for for
working with this industry on a on a on
a legal basis although I think a lot of
them have sort of moved away from that
uh that expectation
um so we wanted to work with them and
get them comfortable with it and so what
we do is we do know your customer we do
anti-money laundering
um reporting all of this all of this
compliance that they have to do anyways
we do it ourselves it's an added layer
of compliance and then we provide this
back Channel separate distributed Ledger
we are using blockchain with smart
contracts there's no fluctuation in the
value of any of the contracts the
capital in is the capital out it
represents your contract to the
underlying dollars that are held in
trust on your behalf it is not there's
no Shenanigans
um we're not trying to build something
that is going to be
um
outside of the banking system we know
that we need their help there is no way
to do this without them like I said they
have they have a privileged place in our
society they are our transaction rails
and we need them to work with us in
order to make this work and so we we are
working with banking partners of course
I can't tell you I'm under NDA I can't
tell you who but we have banking
Partners here in California and they are
holding capital for our our members
they are
allowing us to handle the transactive
rails on that behalf but basically we're
PayPal on blockchain
it's a very simple system it's a ledger
that is closed there's no exchange
Trading but it allows transactions to
move seamlessly and instantaneously
using the newest and most secure
technology that's available for
transaction processing
it really is kind of the
it's a new age in financial technology
and the US will be adapting
a little more slowly than the rest of
the world that had some enabling
regulations come into play but they
they will eventually have to adopt this
TR this as well so our our disruption
may be more towards the banking industry
and more towards the credit card
industry than actually towards cannabis
because what we want to do as artery
implies is provide you with that
lifeblood and make make it safer for
everybody to transact in this space
transact with one another as well as
transact with your customer
thank you so much Ashley let's hear for
Ashley the passion that she's bringing
to this issue and I I cannot imagine how
difficult it is to be where you are
um so disrupting we're trying to
disrupt the media in marketing we're
trying to get ahead in the banking
industry and financial services we've
got so much that we have to do the next
speaker I'm going to introduce is Lance
Lambert he's the Strategic business unit
manager that's a mouthful by the way of
Boveda which I use on a regular basis uh
my dispensaries you know we have to keep
our cannabis fresh the product is
actually very Innovative and useful it
keeps the Cannabis just Shelf ready and
great for our consumers but he has a
background that's so diverse I mean
Lance comes from media over the past 12
years he's worked primarily in the.com
and digital media space he's worked for
several big companies including Scripps
the Cannabis and weed maps who is
actually the director of media
operations and the publisher of
marijuana.com he became a part of the
industry in 2013 really when he joined
up with the Denver Post where he was the
director of AD operations and the GM of
the Cannabis
um so Lance recently took over position
there Boveda tell us more about the
product about yourself about the
disruption that you're causing let's
hear it that title was so fun the
further I get my career the longer my
title gets I don't know what that and
sorry I lost my voice yesterday
um yeah so as far as disrupting it's
kind of funny that's that's been a
better part of my life for some reason
did spend several years in the digital
media space and uh you know was a part
of.com first started disrupting I'd say
with autotrader.com we decided to
disrupt a well chip Perry the founder
but we decided to disrupt the automotive
industry as far as uh how you find cars
uh that was the early years back when I
think Craigslist was the only option
outside of print Publications but then
yeah just continue that on in my career
and uh as far as disrupting in this
specific industry um it was interesting
I was working for Scripps media which
you all might know if you're familiar
with Food Network DIY those kind of
companies uh that's who I worked for and
then got called by a former VP to move
to Colorado and it was January of 2014
when I officially moved and as funny
being from Northern California
um from up by where the Waldo's came
from here in Marin County
and you know ivp said hey I think
there's a good opportunity here you know
Colorado happens to be legalizing
cannabis and I was like yeah I heard and
uh she's all you know you've done some
great things but we're launching a
website called the Cannabis I was a
brainchild of a friend called Ricardo
Baka who was my editor-in-chief and went
over there to head up media operations
but I was a guy behind the scene of the
Cannabis the way that that was a
disrupter to this industry and I'm not
knocking I'm friends the the media pool
as we call it in this industry is very
tight I mean we have a couple
individuals In This Very Room that are
in this uh in the space but we're all
friends and we all respected you know
while high times was uh Matt saying and
the crew were kind of more on the deep
end a little more cultural a little less
mainstream we did have other companies
like dope and Eugenio at cannabis now
and and the list goes on
but when we came along with the Cannabis
we wanted to take a different approach
we wanted to cover the industry from a
true professional journalism standpoint
uh we followed what was called spj or
what is called SBJ code of ethics a
society of professional journalists and
so we covered The Good the Bad and the
Ugly so when companies not naming any
names but that first year had a thousand
plants seized because of exposure
exposure to pesticides we covered that
when edible companies uh were off by I
don't know 90 milligrams of thcm what
was deemed 100 milligram bar we covered
that so we didn't necessarily make a lot
of friends but the people who were doing
it right in this industry respected us
because we were covering the good the
bad the ugly we were pointing out the
people that weren't doing it right and
weren't doing this industry a service
and then obviously rewarded and
complimented and covered the ones that
were so that was definitely a fun stint
did move on to become director of media
operations at Weedmaps and become
publisher of their subsequent news site
marijuana.com
I'd say another disrupter in the
industry uh love them or hate them they
they definitely have made quite a splash
in this industry they've been around 10
years is definitely a good ride and then
segued over which I think Debbie came up
to the boo she's like okay you're in
digital media and you're in.com and all
that then you came to Bovada it's like
well you know after weed maps I kind of
decided I want to be my own boss I'd
start a few companies so like this guy
over here has like you know I know
enough people in the industry you get to
know some key players and uh and so I
was going to go off on my own and uh
Bovada approached me phenomenal company
a huge fan of theirs they're similar to
other companies I work for where they're
an industry leader and a disrupt her in
their own right and um you might ask
what they disrupt so Bove what I'd say
you know slowly we're disrupting the
sales of tortillas of recycling orange
rinds and lettuce maybe some wet paper
towels if you're like me back in my
childhood years up here in Northern
California but really it is joking aside
you know the technology can be looked at
in many perspectives but really Bove it
as a 10 technology company and I compare
it I love speaking of metaphors and
analogies and this guy coming from media
will appreciate because that's how you
help people understand what you're doing
um but it's like taking your clothes
down to the river when you have a
washing machine in the garage like
seriously people it's time to get with
the tech put down the tortillas put down
the wet paper towels there's a there's a
safer way to uh to to not only store but
to carry your cannabis the industry as a
whole you know I'm a huge advocate I
don't consider myself an advocate I do
it activists it is more so an advocacy
of being cancer-free for 15 years I I
transition my life to being a True
Believer of holistic in eastern medicine
definitely believe that cannabis falls
under that but I'm a big fan of everyone
that is a disrupter and I agree I mean
you started touching on it but um
there's a lot of outside disruptors a
lot of inside disruptors
in but not everyone look underneath I
mean there's definitely sheep out there
I think a good example is everyone loves
talking about big Pharma big alcohol big
tobacco they're coming they're here they
own property and in all the prime
locations
um but it's interesting we're working
with someone uh most people might not
know but you may recognize a name
Adolphus bush who Adolphus Bush V
happens to be the great great grandson
of Adolphus who started a little company
called Anheuser-Busch they got bought
out by a company called inbev for
several billion dollars a few years ago
um you know when first hearing oh I'd be
possibly working with someone at Bush
I'm not a big fan of alcohol I mean
don't get me wrong when I skim and hurt
myself surfing or something I I
definitely use alcohol but it's more so
topically
um but for anything both medical and
recreationally I'm more so a cannabis
guy but hearing his story in in hearing
this individual speaking he's like you
know what uh interesting thing happened
this parent company bought bought out my
family company part of the contingency
was that no Bush could work for
Anheuser-Busch ever again
so that's kind of an interesting fact so
don't think someone with the last name
bush is that big alcohol that's coming
in to besiege on our industry but number
two he pointed out an obvious which all
came together in conversation was he's
doing the same thing that his great
great grandfather did he's coming in
since he did get because he went through
college he he due process he tried to go
back to his family's former families
company he went through the proper steps
to apply for a job they said nope the
the stipulation still stands no Bush
will ever work for this company
so what do you do he moved to Colorado
he started his own company in cannabis
and I'm like dude props to you ABV is
the company he started he's like I'm
doing the same thing my my great great
grandpa did and I think that is so cool
that you know if you look at things and
you just step back and look at not just
the trees but the force as a whole and
look at this individual as he's
disrupting 2.0 for a family and uh so
same thing I think with uh you know with
other aspects of the industry not
everyone in Pharma is bad Pharma not
everyone in tobacco is bad tobacco
we need to be open-minded and understand
that some things are inevitable and if
we want this it's a catch-22 we can't
have our cake and eat it too and I'm
like this guy I mean growing up in Marin
County
although I made fun of hippies because
the patchoulio always got to me but I
have a huge respect you know I've come
around to Hummus and 10 grain bread I
truly do have a respect for it but if we
want this to go mainstream we we need
the help and we need to find those those
partners and and get those alliances in
place but make sure that they carry
through the culture in the craft that
has been around for decades you know I
mean that's the thing that we really
need to be cognizant of no matter if
you're an activist if you're an advocate
or if you're just out of the Green
Closet like me it all matters and making
a difference in moving this industry
forward so all of us to your point we're
all disruptors in this room just for
being a part of this and maybe posting
up on social media that you came
I love it uh very articulate okay here's
a question you you come from this broad
perspective uh you're in consumer goods
right now you came from Tech how has
Tech changed the way the industry cures
stores and sells cannabis products
great question there you wrote thank you
so many different levels my gosh uh guy
long live the turkey bag that's one
thing I'm waiting for for change on but
we've done some extensive studies and
there's so much more to a turkey bag
talk about not taking a book by its
cover I get why so many of my friends
use them but a lot of the technology I
think I'd say one company just as an
example on the Cure side cure tube which
is an up-and-coming group out of San
Diego uh you know traditionally anyone
that knows or anyone that has friends in
the industry we talk about black and
yellows or hdx's or or totes or whatever
you want to call them but a lot of
people leave them when using turkey bags
store and totes they're not the most
advantageous way to go no matter if it's
curing or story and they're awkward
they're bulky you you load them all up
you load them all down never mind the
fact that they weigh several pounds then
these guys come along with something
that does make sense that's easier to
roll that's easier to check that's
easier to to
um to go through the curing process with
as far as venting and such and burping
and then they were smart enough to go
you know we want technology it matches
our efforts and created a tray
unbeknownst to us in the beginning and
by no means were reoffended it was kind
of cool they created a tray for Bovada
because they said you know again you
shouldn't be using tortillas to try to
bring up the relative humidity of your
flower I'm a purist my friends might
call me a can of snob I prefer the term
purist so I am very picky on what I
consume I want to know where it comes
from I want to know how it was produced
Etc I don't care about the race to the
top you can keep your Chernobyl and
Amnesia half of those 30 percent THC
ratings are [__] anyway but the fact
of the matter is that they embrace the
fact that Tech exists in the last thing
that someone like me wants is
cross-contamination from something that
happens to be produced with yeast like
tortillas or something that has its own
respective terpenes like orange rinds so
I think that's very Innovative and and
definitely makes a difference when you
get into the tech side what some of
these companies are doing rather be
green bits
um you know or trees I mean the POS
systems are Next Level it's stuff that I
wouldn't have expected to see for
another several years I think the fact
that you know people like art View and
and BDS analytics Roy's company are
saying hey this year in 2019 that's
going to be a 19 billion dollar billion
with a B industry it's only going to
continue to grow it's nice that the
right people are coming in and taking a
chance I mean you guys don't realize
there's a lot of ogs in the room that I
see right now by the way which is cool
but some of you newer to the industry
those people are leaving some seriously
great opportunities and jobs and all
these guys get hit up I know I I don't
throw it out there people know I'm I'm
an advocate but when I travel and and
seriously I I'm a gen xer and my friends
are still like you're in cannabis why
are you going to South America why do
you go to Australia why do you go to
Europe like we do right it's like
because we're not the only ones U.S is
not the the number one in many things
anymore uh cannabis we definitely have
the culture and the craft and the
strains but my gosh the stuff that's
going on from a medical and from a
scientific standpoint in a little city
called Tel Aviv it's only 70 years old a
lot of people to know about bits in
Israel
um it is phenomenal we know about 435
strains or excuse me strains
cannabinoids Associated they're upwards
of 900. it's insane what they're doing
so they're disrupting too hey let's hear
for Lance you guys that's incredible
okay and Kyle's up front scene we gotta
move along here five minutes and it's
perfect timing because we have our final
speaker with five minute presentation
look this guy's got an incredible
history uh Vino fenu varghese he's an
East Coast lawyer he started in the
Brooklyn District Attorney's office he's
award-winning he's a nationally known
criminal uh defense lawyer he's a
white-collar criminal defense lawyer he
practices in federal courts he's also a
talking head he's on Fox he's on CNN CBS
MSNBC HLN where he's a legal analyst and
he gives commentary trying to keep
people out of prison he's not a business
lawyer he's on the East Coast where
people still go to prison for this stuff
and he's got a presentation for us so
let's hear it thank you take it away
[Applause]
I wanted to uh just say I'm very happy
to be here I run a law firm in New York
on Wall Street
um you know criminal defense firm but we
practice all over the country one of the
things that I get to do as Debbie just
mentioned is I get to be speak about a
lot of different things on television so
I've been on Fox talking about taxes I
often talk about the Mueller
investigation I'm snbc this is Israeli
TV
I've been on CNN talking about you know
whatever you know that insider trading
at that point
um
there are different things Tucker
Carlson
um there's a whole bunch of different
things that I get to speak about and I
enjoy speaking about this stuff uh Laura
Ingram it was a lot of fun so
but one of the reasons that I'm here is
I want to talk about the War on Drugs
that's still going on
this is something that's very near and
dear to my heart because I was a
prosecutor so when I was starting my
career 20 years ago in the Brooklyn DA's
office I was a soldier in the war on
drugs and this is something that you
know after a time and reflection and
seeing what I saw I left it was one of
the big reasons I left and I write about
this stuff I wrote a post last year
about Jeff sessions and going back to
things and making him the most dangerous
man in America earlier today they talked
about the new attorney general soon to
be Attorney General William Barr and how
he seems to be a little bit you know
better towards the drug world I'm not
sure that's true I just think he's a
more polished version of Jeff sessions
there's still a lot of arrests all
across this country
you know involving marijuana and it
shouldn't be
the reason is that the DEA still has a
marijuana schedule on drugs I don't know
how many guys have ever seen this but
I'm sure most a lot of you have but if
you look what it says
schedule one drugs substance or
chemicals defined as drugs with no
currently accepted medical use and high
potential for abuse heroin and marijuana
around there schedule Two drugs a little
less severe include cocaine meth
methadone hydromorphine
for the oxycodone fentanyl thanks
I mean this is amazing that this hasn't
changed because the the law enforcement
prosecutorial powers in this country
keep it this way and they and they do
that because you know we have a uh
prison industrial complex in this
country which I'll talk about show a
little clip here right is El Chapo worse
than El chapet I don't know I mean 150
murders a billion dollars forfeited I
mean and then when you talk about
credibility which was your your original
question you know do these guys have any
credit building right I mean they are
clearly here these are awful awful human
beings and listen I've been on the I've
seen this in court myself when you've
had Witnesses way worse records than my
client or the other defendants on trial
you know in a white collar case so the
guys who committed 10 times more fraud
than the guys testifying against them
you know the question is why is the
government doing this and ultimately
you're going to ask the question when
history judges us you know it's a couple
decades from now you know billions and
billions of dollars spent on the War on
Drugs was this worth it right if they
had legalized this taxes and brought
this and moved to erode the violence but
you know we have a prison industrial
complex in this country and that's what
you know that's what this War on Drugs
is really about and El Chapo is just you
know the way for the United States
government to say hey we got the big
fish or one of them or everybody else
will have them cooperate right
so one of the things we provided in your
bag is a little chart
and it has where the basis you know
where marijuana is from a legal
perspective where it's been legalized
decriminalized medical marijuana there's
a list of all the states it's in your uh
in the bag that they came in so take a
look at that
um you know that's uh pretty much it for
uh for now
uh question yes let's hear it
you're on the East Coast things are so
different we're here in California we've
had a legal market for 20 years I mean I
was just in in Boston I couldn't believe
how alive and well prohibition is it was
so frightening to see in these kind of
new and emerging uh
markets how far behind people are but I
know you're you're a lawyer and you're
before federal judges what are the
judges thinking these days
unfortunately judges haven't really
changed uh judges are these are lifetime
appointments Federal Court District
Court judges so some of these guys have
been on the bench for 20 30 years and
they believe in the War on Drugs most of
them were Federal prosecutors before
they became judges and so this is what
they're used to when you talk about the
schedule one drugs that's built into the
federal sentencing guidelines and how
much time people are looking at so it's
going to take a generational change
before judges change
generational change well we've only got
one minute to accomplish that
generational change that's not going to
work okay look you guys would not
believe how intelligent and dedicated
this panel is and if you open up their
brains like a file cabinet how much you
can learn so I encourage you we only had
45 minutes to talk about this incredible
topic we can't tell you everything that
we wanted to tell you during this amount
of time so stop them in the hallways
stop them outside stop them on their way
out the room and ask questions and get
involved with their companies and learn
more and hey I guess if you're on the
east coast and you need a lawyer we got
the best guy that there is over there
right now
um I want to say thank you thank you to
everyone yeah come by my dispensary by
the way really I'm leading tomorrow a
tour of Vape lounges in San Francisco
you can go to the emerald farms uh
tourist booth and get your ticket we're
gonna go see what's happening in San
Francisco do you guys know that that
on-site consumption is not even legal in
the Netherlands it's just tolerated
California is one of the few places on
Earth where we have legal lounges where
you can go in a dignified enter and
consume cannabis I was so curious to see
them all I talked to my friend Victor at
Emerald farm tours I'm like let's do a
tour and go see them all we're going
tomorrow we're going to see at least
five legal Vape lounges where you can
consume cannabis right on on the spot
I'm very excited about that talk about
disruption we want to be ourselves we
want to be in peace we want to live our
lives free and we're going to do it make
no mistake about it prohibition is going
to end the federal judges are going to
die I don't know eventually eventually
they're gonna we're gonna put new people
in that is better ideas or maybe they'll
just have to follow the law if we get
the laws changed we are going to
transition out of prohibition and it's
going to be with the help of every
person in this room so thank you so much
for attending our panel and we look
forward to talking to you
one more time
Debbie and the entire panel moving right
along thank you so very much