we're here at the Grand Hyatt on kawaii
for the ICBC conference on cannabis it's
a good feeling to know that Hawaii is on
starting to get on the map because to be
real like Hawaii is known for its
beaches and tourism and so this gives us
a chance to really shine in ways that
are really important
my name is Ed Rosenthal a writer
publisher and activist and here at the
convention to help people produce better
pot a lot of people are talking about
CBD and talking about cannabis is
medicine but I want to talk with you
about cannabis as something that
liberates your mind and that to me is
important as a as a medical aspect
reggae music
traditionally is the restaurant gospel
music the rest'll money utilized the
arab not to get high or just for
recreation it's more of us it has a
spiritual significance Graham's Morgan
you know in the group his son had to
have a quarter of his brain cut out at
birth because he was having seizures
internally the mother of his child being
a scientist created their own brand of
CBD oil called Messiah we sort of have
like a walking talking breathing case
study of why we want to be in this
industry and it's a hard story to tell
and
kind of been one that I've kind of kept
to myself it's hard to tell it without
you know breaking down into tears I'm
staying professional at the same time
but again I see now the value in it and
I believe that it's kind of just my duty
now and it's in my hands to be able to
help other people so sharing it was
phenomenal and I'd love to do it again
oh yes now I've been to many conferences
and conventions and the cannabis ones
are always the fun ones and then you
meet a lot of people and you network and
and it's a good group of people to be
with especially when we're looking at an
industry which is just growing so look
forward to being a part of this or
helping out in any way again I would
never ever get any kind of
commercialization if I wouldn't of got a
ticket to come here to what it was that
it made it work it worth it and yeah I
mean it's been wonderful and I really do
appreciate it it's a great feeling man I
mean we're we're learning a lot we're
happy to be here we look forward to
getting deeper involved in becoming
activist even for this herb