I love that shoutout thanks a guy out
thank you so much Alex for having me
again I'm really looking forward to this
conversation we're gonna talk about
regulations and Canada regulations and
Germany regulations in Switzerland and
regulations in a bunch of other
countries as well first up we have been
arne he's the CEO of Kanna trade based
in Switzerland in a manual cuts ian is
the CEO of an palico which is actually a
brand underneath soviet which has really
awesome little design features actually
no I really liked that quite a bit
so please welcome them both and I'll
start with you Ben can you tell us a
little bit more about yourself and a
little bit about can trade yes please
thank you very much thank you very much
for the invitation Alex cool to be here
I'm Ben from Switzerland I'm in the
business since 2004 I started there as
an activist in 2008 I became the CEO of
Khanna trade we are the oldest still
existing hemp rare in Europe and right
now we do a lot of cannabis events in
Switzerland
so the canna trade the trade show we do
the counter Swiss cup this is
Switzerland cannabis cup we do a joint
roll contests for attract the crowd at
our events we do cannabis will each
that's a special show we visit all the
big Swiss public affairs and bring the
topic cannabis to the normal people like
my mom and my dad that's what we do
thank you and Kenna traders is the
oldest cannabis expo in switzerland
what's the story behind that how did
that happen
in the 90s it was not illegal to grow
wheat in Switzerland
it was just illegal to consume it as a
narcotic so we had hemp pillows for
example we had the aroma bags called the
dogs actually probably somebody if you
remember that time we could smoke in the
trains we could smoke everywhere we had
more weed stores in Basel than bakeries
it was really a crazy time and in that
time it cannot read was the third hemp
Fair in Europe there was the high life
in Holland the common business in
Germany both of them are no more
available on the planet
so canna trade is the oldest still
existing a hemp Fair in Europe maybe in
the world I don't know so and we're
going to come back to some of those
elements because you know we're talking
about how different jurisdictions sort
of play on each other and how something
that happens in one can affect what
happens in the other and Emmanuel tell
us a little bit about yourself and in
palico and so yeah well first of all my
nickname is Amy my long name is Emmanuel
I'm doing business in a cannabis for now
20 years and I'm very proud that I can
say we are one of the oldest clients of
the of cannot trade of pain it's really
we we made her high times the nice times
and also not on that nice years to Cara
and last 20 years on the european on the
german market a lot happened we started
with magazines or we have like the
biggest magazine on the german market
it's a cost-free magazine and
distributed through cro shops and head
shops and with the time we tried a lot
of projects we feel very active istic we
are coming from the activist scene and
through the times we tried many many
projects and in this moment we are a
network of seven companies across whole
europe doing a lot of things and
actually I'm Holly crow which is in this
moment the most active company I have to
say is dealing with CBT we made three
years ago a decision not to take part in
the pitting to supply the German market
with medicinal cannabis we decided to
call the CBT away and yet just just to
make it round we are neighbors we have
really some aspects of history which
which are really parallel and
really similar but one aspect and this
is very interesting to understand Europe
to understand we speaking sometimes even
the same language but having taught a
different system so in Germany the
consumption of cannabis never has been
forbidden its exact opposite of
Switzerland but of course the possession
buying and selling was totally
prohibited and it's why this combination
with one border made a lot million
German people going to Switzerland when
there was the very nice time and again
people are going to Switzerland now to
buy CBD cross and there's an American
connection there as well we were
discussing this earlier probably about
20 years ago
High Times did a story on a dual citizen
who is American and Swiss and she had
gone to Switzerland and found out that
they had never actually made it illegal
they just kind of assumed it was illegal
so nobody was doing anything with it and
she opened a hemp farm and would have
people come and visit and you know we
were also talking a little bit about how
California and what happened here
so what San Francisco started licensing
dispensaries here we were able to use
that in Vancouver to get licenses there
in Vancouver also you know some some
when the border started closing down a
lot of BC bud wasn't getting across the
border anymore which sort of spiked
Washington California and Oregon to go
even to step up production and something
similar happened when Switzerland kind
of cracked down which we didn't quite
get to so there was a middle phase where
Switzerland was doing all of the stuff
that Ben mentioned and then it sort of
stopped and when it stopped it started
kind of encouraging more Germans to kind
of start growing for themselves as well
was there anything else you wanted to
kind of say about that time period and
how that how your two countries are sort
of how they affect each other well to be
honest the first one have been added
touch for sure they had a first show and
because they are good neighbors they
share what they have a lot of Germans
lot of with Swiss people love to go to
Amsterdam and to enjoy the nice
circumstances and that's why and it's
it's also a matter of the hippies coming
back from Goa from India and apart came
back to California apart came back first
to London then to Amsterdam and then
from there to Germany and to Switzerland
so that's the history and yeah
sadly the Dutch shipyard don't happen
anymore and also sadly all that German
fear also don't happen anymore but this
makes the conductor age really the
oldest fear at least as I know also in
on this planet because I don't know any
other fear which I think it's not 18 so
it is edition isn't it almost yes I
think maybe Hempfest in Seattle as you
people maybe one or two years in terms
of world stage OPA I don't know that I
don't know about the earlier hemp scene
in the US so sort of a unique thing it's
not other other festivals haven't quite
had the same sort of pedigree and
holding together so Germany I started
medical cannabis program a little while
ago
and then sort of sputtered on it and
then started buying cannabis from Canada
instead and now there are tenders that
have been accepted by the government but
nobody's been told yet who they are you
talk a little bit about that and the
impact that's having on on patients in
the medical market in general one day
Hollywood will make a really interesting
movie about it
two years ago the German parliament
voted for the patients to supply them
from German cannabis from companies two
years later there is still no German
cannabis available last year we imported
exact 26.9 tonnes from Canada
mostly 98% something like this
so the happy Canadians I'm very happy
for the Canadians they have full
legalization meanwhile but it meant for
the German patient again there was no
cannabis on the German market so this
was really exceptional law the German
parliament voted and first time after
Second World War a full Parliament 100
percent of all parliamentarians voted
for one law and two years later we see
this law doesn't really help the
patients and this days the responsible
governmental office declared the tender
which was given is no it's now finished
and the companies which when the tender
will be proclaimed and in the next days
or weeks but if you compare what has
been tendered it's about 2.6 tons per
year which is given in certain different
pieces so it could happen you will win a
tender for producing 200 kilograms of
cannabis flowers each year what is
nothing especially when you see already
the consumption numbers and the
prescription numbers when when you see
the consumption already last year was on
the level of nearly 27 tons and the
tender is about 2.6 tonnes
you see excellent possibilities for all
licensed producers which fit the GMP
level and the country has an agency for
cannabis installed so they can take part
and please send more cannabis to Germany
yeah I cannot tell anything else it's a
huge opportunity for everybody because
the market just started and
is we we are now at a level of 40,000
patients with real prescription about
two-thirds of those people are getting
rebounds it by the healthcare and the
dimension it could happen we will have
four million patients so you can upscale
yourself and and imagine their fantasies
yeah well and it's a good thing that is
tenders offered finally because you're
not gonna be getting a lot more cannabis
from Canada we when we started with a
recreational market patients started
finding it very difficult to access
medicine
those of us in BC that are used to a
different sort of level of cannabis in
West Coast cannabis aren't very happy
with what the legal product looks like
and so when we hear that it's going to
patients in other countries it actually
doesn't make us feel very good because
we don't really want that's not the
cannabis we would choose to send you
know thankfully there's some movement on
the CBD side you know we were talking
also about how this twists into some
people seem to think that THC is harmful
and CBD is beneficial so there's last
panel mentioned there's a lot of
Education that needs to be done about it
but at least there's for some conditions
for some people they can access CBD
particularly in Switzerland so
Switzerland's had a bit of a resurgence
I'm not quite like it was in the old
days and a little bit about that in 2011
nobody knows why but the Swiss
government changed the law of producing
him usually in Europe and as well in
Switzerland it was allowed to grow up to
0.2 or 0.3 percent of THC and
Switzerland changed that to 1% of THC
and then it needs some years up to 2016
we're the first company get the license
to sell it officially as a tobacco
substitute weed and now two and a half
years later we have more than 500
registered companies you can buy weed in
every supermarket at every gas station
at the highway everywhere you can buy
wheat as a tobacco substitute and across
that people started fast to a
you CBD oil CBD extract and as you may
may better know than me with the plant
up to 1% THC you can grow up to 25 30 %
of CBD so actually we are a strong
player on the worldwide CBD market
because of that even if Switzerland is a
high in production high and paying
everything but we are now a partner and
as well it feels like it's the the food
in the door we have now many many
companies big companies with big indoor
producing facilities factories so we are
ready for the THC everyone is just
waiting for it and Dubai side a lot of
money in the CBD market yeah and I mean
that's that's its own kind of crazy
thing you know when we legalized in
Canada we actually changed so we've had
legal hemp farming for quite a long time
but they weren't allowed to actually do
anything with the product they could
grow it they could take the fiber out of
it but they weren't allowed to actually
extract anything from it at all now
they're gonna be allowed to extract
things and sell it so it was good news
for hemp producers and we're gonna start
seeing CBD in natural healthcare
products and cosmetics and topicals and
things like that but we already as soon
as that was announced the market was
flooded with 100% legal CVD we see the
same thing happening in a lot of
American markets but it's like oh no CVD
so it's totally legal
what's the situation I mean Switzerland
is obviously kind of unique and kind of
leading the pack in that front what's
the situation with CBD in Germany so
sadly the CBD flowers themselves are
forbidden but about all other products
there are go and it looks good and we
are happy a lot of our customers are
real pharmacies and proving the legal
market and the legal aspects it's a huge
market and just in this moment the big
retail chains are coming
you know eleven seven in Germany it's
called Riva Kaufland cheapo and they are
now asking for CPT product what what of
course means a total different target
groups which we with our possibilities
we never would have reached or we would
have need another 20 years to to tell
everybody yeah and we were also talking
about different concentrates and things
like that and so for myself I I you know
I'm paste in PC now but I grew up in
eastern Canada and in eastern Canada
there was a lot of ties to Lebanon and
Morocco and we smoked hash that's what
we smoked and that's all we got for a
very long time until I moved to be see
basically Germany and and Switzerland
what are the hash mark it's like one of
the concentrate markets like is it is it
sophisticated at all is it not something
people are really interested in then
we'll start with you
they are and it strange um we are
allowed to grow the the weed up to 1%
THC but we are not allowed to make hash
with it because there is still one
sentence in the law who says hash is
forbidden at all like a hard drug stuff
like that but it's quite a nice hash
available everywhere over Switzerland
we're close to Morocco and as well the
ways from Nepal and Lebanon there it's
coming to Switzerland but we are not
allowed to produce it by ourselves right
now in Germany there is of course also a
gray market for extract distillates and
the situation especially for CBD ash is
looking a little bit better than cpt
flowers still still my lawyer says
better better don't try because it's it
might provoke 8 the prosecutor to visit
you yes
some things may might be little but
still you have to find a compromise with
your neighbors and with with the society
around you if they if even if everything
concerning CBD is little might be they
will find something in account
most of shops I have seen broken and did
not probe because of the legal laws
about cannabis but because of the very
normal business reasons cash flow
management liquid is scale of employees
and things like this and not because the
procedure computer came but better
better not to provoke eight the police
so so still there is a market but I
don't believe it will become that big
like in the u.s. I was here in the
dispensary and the guy told me have
fifty percent of what we're selling is
is something to vaporize and not the
flower and I don't believe this market
will be that big in Europe but might be
just a question of generation yeah I
mean we've seen the same thing in Canada
too and you know legally you can get
hash if you make it yourself you're
technically allowed to do that but
that's literally the only way you can do
it you can't buy it for a little while
somebody it's sort of they sort of
tricked Health Canada they kind of said
you know oh no this this Keef is just
dried cannabis that's all it is and so
then we're actually allowed to sell it
but I think it only lasted like a week
or so and then Health Canada wait wait a
minute and then stop this I have I have
to tell the story because nobody
believes but it's true
Germany of course also regulated yes so
if your doctor tells not to smoke the or
vaporize the pure the CBD flowers
THC flowers he can write on the
prescription that the pharmacologist
will prepare it for your consumption so
he can make out hush of it or test
delayed and yes he kept paid for making
you like the doctors are told you have
to inhale it or to eat it or whatever
and this is a crazy thing so if you
really want good hush then pass wait you
talk to that you need you prefer to
to consume hushed and flowers and yeah
and might be even their house insurance
will pay well and you know I think one
of the things that's really interesting
to and this is a you know Switzerland
you chose CBD joints to replace smoking
whenever I go to Europe I can't I can't
really take a joint from people as it
was passing around the circle I'm no
thanks you know unless I know the
person's Canadian or American because
it's all mixed with tobacco which is
something that you know that was one of
the reasons why we like when we don't
have to smoke ash we like cash in Canada
a lot but you know most of us I think
prefer just the flower particularly
because we never mix it with any tobacco
do you see that sort of custom changing
or is that just like super ingrained
into the way that people smoke cannabis
in Europe I think it will change right
now it's a most people smoked with
tobacco for sure but with the CBD you
are allowed as well now to sell CBD
joints so people start to smoke it pure
people start to wait and if I have a
look to the United States and probably
to Canada as well all although the way
saying depends everything like that I
think it will come over Europe as well
and Swiss people and row people will
start to smoke weapons as well yeah I
think so too I mean III do have a
concern about that when it comes to
medical patients for example because
vaping there's certain compounds that it
just it won't get and the concern is is
not actually the vaping it's the idea
that oh vaping is okay and anything else
is not okay and that's not really what
we've seen and again in particular for
certain conditions you can't do that in
again in Canada you know most of until
we had legalization come in which is not
necessarily as nice as it sounds
until we had that point the government
was fighting every step of the ways and
no you can't grow more than one plant
okay no you can't grow more than to plan
okay you can't grow more than three and
this was like years of court cases in
between we won the right for medical
patients to have access to edibles when
Health Canada finally allowed it it was
an oil that's capped at such a low point
that it's almost not even a concentrate
anymore do you do you see regulation in
Europe being maybe a little bit more
sensible than that or how much is
Canada's regulations and approach
influencing what what German and Swiss
and and other European governments are
doing probably probably alone because I
think we will we will never or I can't
imagine that we will be allowed to sell
THC calm beers green and red and blue in
Switzerland I don't think so
as I know my country and my government
so I think it will be strictly regulated
with especially with edibles and stuff
like that
so our proposed edible rules came out
and it's ten milligrams per package
which is ridiculous I know it's it's a
little bit of a cultural question when I
was young I travelled to Amsterdam and I
learned a lot about cannabis to smoke it
with tobacco sadly sadly but that's a
typical European way and it's it's
changing its changing because more
cannabis is accessible you can afford to
have a own joint this was like one yeah
you don't share anymore everybody has
one that's a thing I've noticed about
Berlin is everybody has their own joint
where maybe in the States or Canada you
stand in a circle pass around Berlin
everybody has their own blend like - 75
% - back at 25% - this is that it's very
interesting exactly and and then we
learned also in Amsterdam that cookies
and
and pralines spacecake it's hard drug
you're you can buy it somewhere but
don't use it too often better with
somebody who is experienced there are
some there is also some demand we have
also some friends which have on a
prescription 30 or 40 grams per day how
to consume without using edibles you
have to cook with it you have to eat it
and no other way suppositories
suppositories it's a very effective
medicinal treatment for a lot of people
and it doesn't get you as high on the
THC because it doesn't necessarily go
through the liver just go 30 grams a day
though is a lot of suppositories it's
also if you're crossing the border yeah
we have always regulated we have a nice
formula for crossing all the borders I
can go also to Switzerland with my
German cannabis and but many people try
to to put it into the normal diet and
for other people it is it could be
really dangerous this these doses of
course we have to learn because we what
we learn is or what our politician could
learn when you when you have legalized
you are just starting to legalize you're
coming to a certain point and then you
see new question well what is going on
and each society has to solve it for it
also we are learning from from Canada
and and also from California and on the
other side we have our own system and we
have to make our neighbors happy as well
so I don't think we're gonna have time
for question we got time for one well
I've had one more for them actually in
terms of okay Europe who's who's next I
mean so so Canada is the first g7
country to legalize cannabis Uruguay was
the first country in the Americas to
legalize cannabis so who's going to be
first in Europe probably looks and work
they made an announcement to the
government of Luxembourg that they will
legal
medical and recreational but when it
will happen we don't know actually you
can play bingo with Europe I seek your
chances for Switzerland we have now two
important things on the way in our
government one is the easy way for
medical use and the other one is like a
pilot project to get your wheat in the
drugstore both projects are on the way
to come in the next 1 to 3 years
and yeah I hope for Switzerland I hope
also of course for Switzerland I hope
for Switzerland as well thank you well
be in Zurich in May right international
cannabis business conference there you
go one quick question then we got a move
thank you thank you real quick Ben my
mom Swiss just Mazurek Switzerland
always been very progressive with
addressing the drug problem with heroin
problem but this is questions for
Germany as well our both country are
your countries using that as an
alternative to you know to sell to
market cannabis as an alternative to the
opioids as well as heroin and addressing
it that way you can you need the right
doctor in this moment we still have a
big lack of doctors which prescribing
and dare to do it we have might be to
thousands for Germany and you need one
doctor who over takes the responsibility
and start doing exactly this and
singular singular cases unknown but I
don't know any doctor who is specialized
on this in Canada we do have a lot of
doctors that specialize in it
unfortunately our regulators are going
the opposite direction and making it
very difficult to do that particularly
Vancouver one of the reasons why they
legalized dispensaries before it was
legal in Canada was specifically because
of the very serious opiate problem that
that BC is facing and and it's been the
opposite we've made it harder for people
to access we've you know our got our
provincial governments are now spending
a lot of money on it
campaigns around cannabis still not
saying a word about opiates you know
they're still shoveling those down
people's throats so it's it's we went
the opposite way of the way we should
have gone in and and we see that a
little bit here in California as well
you know the Bay Area when when Berkeley
in San Francisco started regulating
their own dispensaries they cared about
the health service the health component
of it and who was actually getting
access to it and whether it was covered
and subsidized a little bit and then as
soon as you start having the state
regulated that kind of goes by the
wayside and then when you have the
federal government regulate it more will
go by the wayside in it and it
unfortunately seems to be the pattern I
think the only kind of hope is that once
it's legal we can get research done on
it that makes it harder and harder to
stop to stop those things from happening
and stop those types of programs from
being put in place great thank you so
very much let's hear it again for our
panelists I was very enlightening and
fantastic