[Music]
we're starting in just a couple minutes
so get in and take your seat y'all
[Music]
this is international can business
conference and many people who came here
kind of took a chance bought a ticket
wasn't sure what to expect right and the
feedback I'm getting is I can't believe
this I didn't know it was going to be
this good what they mean by good is
information and networking and just the
general attitude of the people here just
want to thank Alex and Anthony and guo
uh for putting on in event that really
Blends activism and business uh in a in
a really really great way the Outreach
has been phenomenal people from Brazil
to Mexico uh Texas uh the West Coast uh
let's see Michigan and other places in
the country are here today A lot of fun
a lot of nice people with a lot of
information you can see the people kind
of go oh I hadn't thought about that
before it's raising a lot of
Consciousness about the social rep
percussions of prohibition and I'm not
sure that everybody here came in the
door worrying about that but more like
oh how can I make money or how can I fit
into the industry and I hear that
they're being inculcated with more and
more Progressive thought about why we're
doing this why we're fighting to end Pro
so what's happening in in in this
situation right here is people are a bit
overwhelmed by the breadth of the
understanding that people have for one
another and empathy and and you know
this might sound like some hyy toyy uh
stuff to if you're if you're just a
businessman well I'm a businessman I do
well in the industry and I believe in
karma I believe in community I believe
in love and understanding and I actually
believe if you hold true to some of
those tenants and precepts that you're
only going to benefit yourself for so
many reasons and and in my case it's
actually helped me make money also so
it's this new win-win situation that's
happening uh with the Cannabis industry
uh in particular and I I think that's
what people are very surprised about
that that they can make money they can
be successful and no one else has to to
lose all right it's the fastest growing
business in America and I just want to
thank Alex for bringing the keynote
speakers that he brought the panels Dr
Carl Hart and um Ethan nlman and Rick
Steves and yeah there're celebrities
they get people in the door but they're
saying
really change happens when people get
involved in step forward come to
conferences like this today check check1
two this isum NG AO 420 on Twitter the
culture editor marijuana politics.com
and uh we just wrapped it up here at the
international cannabis business
conference it's been a fantastic time uh
Steve Bloom from celeb Stoner and
freedom Leaf magazine was here uh Steve
D'Angelo was here uh Ethan nlman from
the drug policy Alliance gave an
impassioned impassioned speech about
what we need to do I mean as all the
suits jump into the business we got to
remember to keep the hippie ideals right
uh I've always proceeded from the idea
that the hippies were right and I try to
let that guide my actions uh but this
was a great conference you can go to om
mbc.com and check it out what's
question no we've had an amazing weekend
here at the international cannabis
business conference you know when we
when we started doing this or when we
had the concept to come up with the
international cannabis business
conference uh of course business
business is is in the title however we
wanted to do a whole ton of advocacy
politics and culture that's our that's
our passion that's what we were pushing
and we were curious of how people would
react to it there's so many other
business conferences out there that uh
talk about Investment Banking or penny
stocks or whatever and we thought if we
did a business conference that was not
just focusing on on business business
business and money money money we
thought we were actually taking a chance
and people might not groove on that or
or not get what they expect for their
highend uh ticket price well uh what's
happened in fact is people are actually
overly excited and happy that we have
decided to dedicate so much of this to
culture politics and uh advocacy and I'm
tremendously happy with the
feedback I never doubt a small group of
concerned citizens can change the world
it is indeed the only thing that ever
has thank you for being a part of this
to