[Music]
[Applause]
at the ICBC San Francisco it's just
really heartening and refreshing to see
how the industry is growing so I was
telling Alex I told Alex this morning
that the opening event that they had
last night a VIP cocktail party between
the cocktail parties and the smoke
session that was going on outside on the
street I met so many
would not have otherwise met people were
incredibly accessible you know hanging
out with retired NBA Hall of Famers
people that are leaders in the cannabis
industry and people that were new to the
cannabis industry meet and greet the
night before it's a great networking
event it's wonderful to meet other
people that we hold hands with in the
industry making new relationships and
new business opportunities new
possibilities
well I tv3 of a lot of the
school activists who really love and
respect the plans and are also kind of
making the week to become more
professional and move
it's going so I think it's nice about
what what Alex and team do is gain the
right people in the room to have those
important conversations very
professional very international vibe the
fact that he does one and Berlin is do
one in Barcelona and yeah
the conference's are really important
because it's a place for folks who are
interested in the industry to come here
and find out more about it
but Alex does an amazing job there's
this altruism in the cannabis industry
that comes out at these ICBC events
everybody who loves this industry
everybody wants to be a part of it but
not a lot people know what's going on on
the ground level and this is kind of
that really opens people they're trying
to Shepherd this industry into the
future to me it's a lot more fun than
being at sort of the more cut-and-dry
corporate events with people who only
look at it as a commodity and don't
really
enjoy the plans and celebrate the plant
in the same way it's all about the love
you know it's all about building
community
I think what Alex was done here at the
ICBC is just transformative and ICBC is
just amazing conference this isn't my
first and it won't be
we love this place