how's everyone doing that's excellent
okay if we could all do that now that's
a spectacular I'll just wait for the
room to a couple more minutes seconds
here and we'll create a little
environment to talk about international
and commerce so you're probably noticing
that our panel is a little better than
anticipated with me on my immediate left
is Andrew Muir off and on my right is
Linus Weber and my I'm Robert Lawrie and
well we were missing mr. Tom's uber and
who I'm told had some flight
complications and Clint Young
unfortunately as really under the
weather so what we thought we would do
given that there's just three of us our
panel discussion is really more going to
be I would call it a fireside chat and
we should have enough room for questions
and with that I think we'll kick it off
so Canada as we all know has been in the
world leader in international cannabis
market being that it's the first g7
country to federally create a regime
devoted to legalization but competition
is certainly ramping up as other
countries legalized and we're seeing a
whole bunch of different models from
Uruguay Israel the Netherlands Germany
Australia I could go on Thailand
every day there seems to be another
country either decriminalizing
legalizing or introducing some form of
regulation and with that being said why
don't we just take a moment YouTube well
we'll start with mr. you
introduce yourself and just take us
through you know the your involvement
with international cannabis and then
we'll hear from Linus alright thanks for
having me glad to be on the stage with
both of you and the other guys missed
out so their loss my name is Andrew and
I'm the CEO strain print technologies we
capture patient reported outcomes from
medical cannabis patients who are
treating with legal product mainly and
we deliver that anonymous data back to
the industry we have the largest data
set of its kind in the world today over
1.4 million patient reported outcomes
were Toronto based where Canadian
company and we service today
Canada the us-israel and hopefully soon
in the European Union right on Linus
thank you for having me my name is Linus
I'm from Germany founder and CEO of
nimbus health fully licensed
pharmaceutical wholesaler we've been in
the business since July only started two
years ago sort of starting building up
the yeah connections to producers
outside the European Union now also
inside European a very keen to see how
the market especially in the European
Union now as more and more producers
coming in but of course challenging
challenges are rising also on the
Canadian side let's see how the US are
moving as far as I can tell the domestic
supply in Germany is not enough at least
for the next four years so we are
heavily reliant on you producing and
importing together with us hopefully
thank you thank you
those are both great answers and
certainly give us a platform to build on
as I indicated earlier my name is Robert
Laurie and well I by trade I'm an
international lawyer I'm licensed in
England and Wales and here in British
Columbia and I studied law at Oxford and
with my previous life I was a securities
fraud lawyer
a hedge fund formation lawyer which
developed a great understanding of
onshore offshore tax arbitrage and
that's effectively what we're starting
to see more and more are companies that
are structuring their operations in
manners which are tax efficient and I
would like to I guess put out to both of
you the question as what is driving your
your respective businesses is it
following Canada as an example or is it
other considerations such as tax
efficiencies wondering if you might be
able to comment let's start with lioness
this time well basically if you look at
the history for Germany in 1998 we have
dronabinol which is a purely THC
compound which was sort of given to
patients since 2003 we have flowers
already from from the Netherlands so
there has been already a market for it
however in 2007 t it became possible to
reimburse medicinal cannabis by the
health insurance of the people in
germany and this was sort of the game
changer we're now ramping up in the last
two and a half years it's only 70,000
patients but this is due to the fact
that we don't have the education of the
doctors so sort of copying on the one
side from the medicinal space we are
basically as an experiment in Europe
from everyone so a little bit from
Canada in the United States and so on
and so forth but in the end we need more
doctors education and this is something
we should start copying more efficiently
sort of opening up the world of the yeah
of cannabis to our doctors in Germany to
be able to sort of bring more patients
in because we have 70,000 patients and I
think the potential is between 800,000
and 1.6 million because it's roughly one
to two percent of the population of
Germany interesting Andrew we track
patient performance against lab verify
product and in most jurisdictions you
don't have even a testing requirement
today so the key to us understanding the
science behind what works and what
doesn't is to be able to identify which
chemical constituents are are Co related
to what's symptomatic improvement and
drilling down by cohort by age by gender
and being able to see that 35 year old
women react to certain chemical profiles
different than 50 year old men for
example so if we think about other
jurisdictions where the u.s. is a good
example every state is an island every
state has its own regulatory regime for
how they both how they grow as well as
how they test so for me it's about
taking the experiences from Canada with
lab verified products and the those the
data that's related to those lab
verified products and translating that
into foreign markets where we haven't
actually tested local product there but
we know that chemical profile aligns to
two personality so even in Europe today
there's as we know there's very little
product there so we have an opportunity
right now to take what we know and we've
had the fortune to do that here in
Canada only because the regulations are
the way they are so I think we actually
from my perspective we had a great
advantage here that the regs were so
tight interesting well an avenue that
you may not think about that certainly
should come to mind in the discussion of
international it was with certainly
First Nations now at the moment as c-45
the cannabis act stands there is no
information or guidance as to how First
Nations should be setting up legal
cannabis operations we have to remember
that First Nations are also technically
a fourth level of government and
recently I was made a board member on
the Zagg emmaus inna Beck First Nations
cannabis board which you starting to see
First Nations understanding that through
their own process of self-determination
provided they are then
endorsed by banned and ban council they
then are able to create infrastructure
such as a cannabis board on their land
and begin to engage in this process but
I have always thought that that could go
a step further depending on the band
again depending on the nation if it's a
Jay treaty band and again that goes back
to the late 1850s or so which was a
recognition of by the US Canadian and
British governments of the First Nations
that were in existence at that time and
the stipulation was to recognise the
free movement of people in goods and I
think well what I know is coming is that
you're going to see a lot more First
Nations exercising their
self-determination in some form or
another to realize a tax efficiency and
I started looking at this like 6 7 years
ago and my first legal aid case in Haida
Gwaii I was up there and they're talking
about you know getting into the wine
trade and I was like have you seen the
wind that's 180 like miles an hour
you're gonna be harvesting grapes and
Prince Rupert what about cannabis
because ultimately I looked at it as
Haida Gwaii could very much be the
bermuda or the bahamas of british
columbia with respect to an onshore
offshore arbitrage so that i think we're
going to see across the United States
First Nations engaging in
self-determination which could lead to
international deals with the European
market and with certainly cross-border
what are your thoughts on that I think
it's couldn't happen soon enough I mean
we there's there's a massive opportunity
in production and a massive opportunity
in export once a level of compliance is
reached I think that's the big king
right now is is bringing production
facilities on those lands up to the same
level that are in and that's not to say
it can't be done of course it can be
done it's just it does is it a priority
right now and it hasn't been
until now but but it will be and and
there is a lot of opportunity for
product to cross borders that don't have
the same level of export regulation that
say any of any of the big producers here
today have right on any thoughts yeah
it's it's a weird perspective on First
Nations exactly I mean we have from a
from a European standpoint and that's
basically the word everybody heard of is
the u GMP certification process and Nick
did it in his in his speech that there's
like a huge effort to really reach that
kind of certification we're engaging in
that and I think there need to be clear
standard ways of how to produce
medicinal cannabis throughout the world
and this can only be done through
collaboration and I see that this really
urge for collaboration in cannabis is
there I mean my background is Pharma
there wasn't like everybody was working
in their little offices and now with
Canada we have the possibility to really
do that collaborative work in order to
find really standards that would ease
the export and ease also any processes
in a sort of bringing products either
from Canada to other you restrictions or
also into Canada I would say I mean
domestic supply in Germany is not enough
but others will be ramping up so there
must be some kind of standardization in
the process yeah and that's what I think
is the big challenge in the near future
well given there's a lot of products
going from A to B and C and D and back
to a probably how are the products
getting to their destinations
I'll just have now given an anecdote I
mean I I have BC product that I bought
that got delivered to me in Ontario and
I brought it back to BC you know
products are getting transported in a
lot of different ways and I think
there's there are both logistical issues
but there are regulatory issues I don't
I don't even know
how we're ever going to get into the US
and then in the near future because it's
it's very exclusionary for lack of a
better word I think it's a short-term
problem but it is what it is right now
so I don't think the US market is gonna
be but how do we get products into the
UK we're just talking about this earlier
or into the EU if you can get into the
market is it transported by air is a
transported by ship is it transported by
rail and we know that they have a
prevalence for for rail so I'm just a
data guy but I'm just speaking
observationally on what I see
so Linus you've get somehow this product
comes from the Netherlands makes its way
to Germany do you want to take us
through that exactly and we actually are
using a normal transporter springing in
from from from bedrock and basically
everybody knows that company doing
standardized medicinal cannabis products
out of the Netherlands that's those are
the ones which we are currently
distributing in Germany we are in
discussion with several Canadian
companies already but then this Eugene P
certification comes in where it
sometimes gets really difficult but we
now have a GMP professional and our team
really helps the companies to sort of
ease that process but I must admit of
course it's from coming from Canada it's
always by plane and we had the first
plane arriving from tilray
in Germany last week from Portugal
so there are no new countries coming in
where we can build relationship also
inside European Union which makes which
makes it a little bit easier but I mean
there are products coming in and there
are possibilities and we are more than
happy to help you understand what is
needed to bring products to the German
market / at the European market because
once it's in the European Union its way
easier of course distributing it to
other countries such as for example
Spain Italy Portugal also but
particulars now has a huge domestic
cross that I don't think there is export
needed to Portugal so can I ask a
question to get it into the EU it's the
same regardless of whether or not it's
the end is going into Germany or going
into Switzerland er yes it's not as easy
as that
so of course it
once you're inside European Union it's
it is easier to have the export license
as a European company to export to a
different jurisdiction within the
European Union
that's what's easier because it's
already yeah checked by a qualified
person which is also in our team and
then it's also medical approved in
Germany which makes it easier to
distribute any other the other way
around it's a bit more difficult because
the Germans always looking very deeply
into the processes and a check if
everything is alright but the other way
around it's it's more easy so so if
you're Canadian you'd look for the
easiest jurisdiction in the EU to get
into and then from there you transfer it
into Germany that's its market so I want
to engage the audience just indulge me
for one second you've been a great
audience here with a yay or nay I'd like
honest answer we'll see who's louder I
guess Canada cannabis regulations are
they over regulated nay yay okay good so
we can continue because if it went the
other way I don't think I could have
asked the next question given that
Canada had first mover advantage and has
created a system that the rest of the
world has been watching some have even
been adopting and applying but do you
feel that the standard in Canada has set
itself too high
that'll be very hard for the government
to come down to be competitive so I
guess the question is has Canada in a
way by being so cautious out of the gate
has it kneecap itself with respect to be
truly competitive I think it's I think
it's actually been a boon for us because
by setting the regulation so high it's
forced us to come to the table with real
pharmaceutical type production
facilities and really high quality
product that no other jurisdiction would
accept if we weren't at that faith so I
kind of look at it the other way if we
were if we were like the US where the
the lens is really about
commercialization and not about public
safety I don't think a country like
Germany would even consider bringing it
in with
the type of testing and experience level
that we've had over these and remember
we started out the only reason why we're
able to have that jumpstart into the
European Union as an example is because
we had a medical program has nothing to
do with a recreational program and the
only reason we're able to go into
foreign markets today is because of the
medical program so I don't think having
a tight regs around the recreational
program is is gonna be a limitation and
I also think that it's way easier for
the government in Canada to loosen the
reins than it is for for instance in the
US if they can put it back in what's
that that's if they get voted back in
yeah I mean from a German perspective I
think there can I can tell if Canada's
over-regulated my first time here but
basically what we see is a German would
always do something rather not than
doing it wrong
and that's why they're very cautious and
careful by sort of importing products
into Germany and nobody knows really how
to do it right every local authority
needs to do that import license for the
respective producers base of respective
distributors and this is also based on
the place where you're located in
Germany for example I'm from Hesse in
Frankfurt and we have three authorities
which are sort of overlooking the whole
process we have a nakaka
in narcotic agency would end in the end
decides what is done so we have of
course huge regulations as well but it's
sort of the processes are getting easier
because they've been done a couple of
times now and yeah as I said we are more
than happy to assist I think as Nick
said earlier we you should always go
with the with a good GMP consult and in
order to be able to sort of overlook
what is needed before you end up having
huge cost and will not be able to bring
products in hey before we go to
questions
is there anything in particular that we
haven't covered that either of you'd
like to share about the uniqueness of
being ahead of the curve if you will
with your business and be happy to learn
about this we were fortunate to be
gathering data in 2016 so we had a
pretty big head start and doing it now
we still have to deal with as we go into
international markets we still have to
deal with jurisdictional transfer of
data across borders so going into Europe
for example we we have to be GNP GDP are
compliant which is the privacy
regulation in in that market and if if
you will in the u.s. there's HIPPA
compliance that's if we consider right
here Canadian compliance is PIPA done
it's basically level compliance this
year and GDP are is way up here so it's
a big step up and and for us having a
first mover advantage of gathering data
and being cloud based and only keeping
in data only residing in Canada and
never leaving the country on servers
here as we go into the UK or into
Germany or anywhere in the in the EU we
have to be gdpr compliant and we are now
so we're almost are now interesting ok I
think data is a it's a it's a big big
point and that's where the game is
changing and I hope you write and when
Israel also coming and I think we headed
already earlier in the conference but
somebody was talking about Israel how
much data they gathering they're doing
it for 20 years I think this is really
really something what is important and
needed and I said it already in the
beginning collaboration is the key I
would say combining different
jurisdictions see what what works do
experiments I mean Germany is the
experiment for Europe in terms of the
patient numbers and sort of inserting
inserting products from all over the all
over the world so yeah I see I see data
is key and we should be exchanging more
more of the data and I'm looking forward
maybe working more closely with you in
the future ok yes or no answer to this
question and then we'll open it up to
questions the cannabis production yes or
no is it a race to the bottom
making me put me on the spot without
he's got an answer - yeah I mean sadly
the reality is it is right now
I think it'll stabilize at some point
but you know at this point every
producer can sell everything that they
grow there's just so much demand at some
point there'll be enough supply to
service the market and I don't know when
that is but at some point there'll be
enough supply to service the market and
companies are gonna have to figure out
how to differentiate their products from
others and it's a very hard Mauri I'm an
IP lawyer so it's very difficult to
actually protect a particular cultivar
because somebody can just come up with a
formulation that's slightly different
and it's no longer covered sir the same
question yes just for an example for
Germany in 2018 we had 3.1 tonnes of
cannabis flower material which was
distributed this year we are probably at
five to six next it's going to be again
doubled let's say 12 tonnes for whole of
Germany and if I just see what amounts
are currently grown there will be a huge
enamel I'm not afraid but it will be a
huge challenge to sort of differentiate
different products but let's look at
Greece Weathers
where there are hundred tons grown
another Spain coming in Portugal can
Canada's there nobody knows what's going
to happen with the with the US and short
notice and so yeah it's going to be a
huge challenge in terms also of the
pricing and competitiveness because they
are also Eastern European countries
coming in north methadone yeah Poland
which are produced at really really low
cost so let's see how it turns out I
don't have a require answer to that
question but yeah thank you yes so your
fight answers right the German yes and
though it's every technical okay there
any folks let's hear it for the panel
first of all right away I have a quick
question first you mentioned to IP as in
respect to cannabis strains how is it
even possible how do you how do you
patent train wreck how do you patent
bubble cush how do you
patent blue dream like I mean cannabis
hands have been with the open source for
the longest time and it's just it's
weird to me to see people try to if
anybody's ever done a patent before you
know it's there there's a there's a long
process to it it's yours and it costs a
lot of money and not everybody can
afford to patent a strain and if you
were to take a particular if you went
through the effort to genetically test
your product and and that means beyond
just you know CBD and THC but if you
actually go through the effort and look
at the full chemical profile and you
patent that that's great you're gonna
spend fifteen twenty five thousand
dollars on that it'll take a couple
years and then somebody's gonna change
the formulation by slightly than one
slight different amount and then you're
no longer covered so I don't think it's
patentable hi
are you guys talking what about the
Caribbean market because I know love you
guys and Caribbean right now but here
you mention nothing about the Caribbean
market
well I also think the Antarctica market
has potential but we can't discuss
everything to answer your question so I
think that's a huge market and
unfortunately none of us are technically
working in that jurisdiction well there
are a lot of guys with you in the region
right now oh I have a number of people
in this room I know who are working in
Jamaica right now but I've never had in
there and but I will say this is that
the Caribbean has a huge role to play in
the cannabis industry because it will
allow a lot of companies to do what's
called they'll be eligible for something
called a citizen's Investment Bureau
passport program meaning that if you
show up in Antigua Barbuda and say hi
government like to give you our IP I'd
also like to talk to you about a
distribution agreement and in return
we're now eligible for your citizens
investment for your passport scheme
happy but the point I'm trying to make
is is yes you're going to see a lot of
places that use the Caribbean for
cannabis just like they're going to use
the Caribbean for banking services which
means it's going to be a very central
hub either way thank you all right over
here
you're welcome not a question about
strategic partner out of question about
strategic partnerships so you kind of
mentioned the tribes I had submitted a
tokenize a tribal tokenized asset in
California with the collateral being a
blunt rolling machine with the idea of
combining tobacco and cannabis they
didn't like the idea maybe it was too
soon and so I'm curious about your
opinions in utilizing Native American
tribes in North America and combining
cannabis with you know tobacco so
individuality that's normalized
professionalized you guys see that as
being an option I know that Germany is
probably never going to allow that but
it's popular with spliffs
but do you guys see blunts you know
tobacco and cannabis eventually being
combined together there's a massive
tobacco production facility on Six
Nations and in Hamilton outside of
Toronto and if you've ever been there
it's one of the largest production
tobacco production facilities in the
world and I don't think I don't there's
much interest in combining tobacco and
cannabis in a product but there is
definitely interested in utilizing their
infrastructure to produce cannabis to be
exported and yes cannabis is a no excuse
me tobacco at least in the Supreme Court
cases with First Nations have recognized
a very general right to the possession
of tobacco for commercial purposes for
guys van der peat I think was a Supreme
Court case where a guy been stockpiling
tobacco clearly he was going to sell it
but that was something that First
Nations we have to remember we're doing
since time immemorial before Europeans
showed up so it would that that type of
a scenario fought very night or fit very
nicely within the existing jurisprudence
and that's why I think cannabis isn't
really a too big of a stone's throw from
tobacco and in fact it's just one of
many natural medicines and
you know from the work that we've been
doing more of the bands are wanting to
not just take on cannabis but they want
psilocybin you know the fungi peyote
through the cacti vines ayahuasca DMT
which accrue know all of these natural
practices that I think they will be able
to do a whole host of commercial
endeavors under food social and
ceremonial thank you for your question
yeah no it's currently done in in
Germany too bad there's no possibility
because known cannabis patient is
smoking cannabis in Germany no basically
what we have is vaporizing option or tea
option those are the things which are
actively known as application methods
and this is a huge problem most of the
doctors have because if they're giving
medicinal cannabis flowers to a patient
they always have the risk that they are
smoking it giving to their grandchildren
or something like that so there's no
option but from a scientific point of
view I think there is a yeah it it might
be a possibility to use also to tobacco
plant to find solutions of for example
also creating cannabinoids but that's a
very interesting talk we should do maybe
afterwards lol Oh questions my name is
Phil Hardy Director of Sales with craft
Depot and we're currently contracted by
50 LPS to help with wholesale
distribution and creating efficiencies
and transparency in that market LP jlp
my question is specifically for Linus
and it's concerning importing into
Germany or importing into the EU I've
heard variants of what's acceptable was
not from a GPP standpoint so if you have
a cultivator whose GPP compliant and as
is doing their post harvest in a GPP
level can they go into the EU GMP
because I've understood that this GAC P
and then once they harvest has to go
into a GMP process so I'm trying to get
some clarity because I hear people
saying it was cheap EP all the way till
it's packaged in kilos it can move
overseas and I've heard that say no it
has to be GAC P at harvest
down moving into GMP for your curing
drying and and packaging and then that
can move into the EU can you speak to
that a little bit yeah sure I mean there
are a lot of things a lot of rumors
coming around G ACP is it possible not
currently there is no G ACP grown
product in a German market so what you
need is a new GMP certified facility is
the best would be by a by a German
Authority currently waiting times are
year 12 month at least at our authority
where we are working with then your your
safe and can sort of distribute also
prepackaged medicinal cannabis products
and then all the qualification and the
medical approval will be done inside
Germany the products will be then get an
additional label on it and you can
distribute enema Germany that's the
easiest way there are now things
discussed if it's possible to sort of
grow GAC P certified products have them
extracted as an at an EU GMP certified
facility packaged labeled and then sent
to Germany but it's not yet possible but
this is I think a feasible solution
because GAC P is easy and I don't think
everything needs to be grown indoors
greenhouses is an alternative which is
also used in Israel for example thank
you very much so then just for further
clarification as well a GPP cultivator
just with the cultivation license who
then sells to an EU GMP certified
processor who then creates those
products and then they can export is
that a possibility is that as a supply
chain that works as I said every process
so every process every supply chain is
tested itself so for example if we are
now coming together and you give me an
an overview of the products you would
like to import I have to get that import
license based on those products exactly
on all the information all the lab tests
you have what we do is we usually do a
sample shipment have it tested in
Germany and directly
yeah burned basically disposed and then
we sort of test all the processes
because German authorities feel way more
comfortable if they are tested by a
German lab and have been tested by a
qualified person so it always suggests
use a distributor where you have GMP
knowledge and who have already done
those sample shipments and understand
the process there are a lot of people
running around
currently there are 13 licenses of users
including us so be careful good talk you
talk question thank you perfect thank
you do we have time for one more is that
it and someone has a brief one anyone
have a short question is that you
raising your hand over there all right
here we go
what are we good one last question
please be brief to the variable B right
here here we go just a question about
Germany and what a free is doing
so if RIA has a distribution license one
of the one of the 14 and Germany they
spoke of and from my understanding a
free is just purchasing products from
Switzerland and getting the distribution
revenue for it from a company called
blossom and basically they're just
getting those companies and flipping
them for pennies on the dollar my
question is like what do you think about
that strategy for companies like a free
and yourself long term who are basically
using the distribution network to create
revenue and so basically what we've set
up I mean we have solely focused on
distribution at the moment we are doing
some scientific work as well with the
tobacco for example but where we see
ourselves we see ourselves as an entry
gate for Europe we of course can
distribute to pharmacies we are very
well connected to the biggest pharmacies
in the cannabis space we're the only
distributor who is part of the network
of cannabis pharmacies in Germany so we
think we have a good overview of the
market and sort of know how it's how
it's working out currently the process
is not that much regulated that
something like this can happen so
exporting for example from from from
Switzerland those are mainly I think
also CVD products which are sold in
Germany as aroma oils and it
has to say that it's not it should not
be taken orally at any time so what
they're currently doing for the aroma
oils in CBD is they put it on on a
pillow and then smell it through the
pillow that's that's how it's currently
the application method should be of
course you can easily take those
products but I mean we have huge
problems with the novel food that's a
completely different story so I think it
will be too much to answer that question
in this but I'm more than happy to talk
afterwards yeah yeah all right all right
thank you so very much is here once
again for the panel
[Applause]