straight plate the president CTO lives
here per day thanks for the nice intro
we are going to break tradition from the
other formatted discussions that are
panels that you've seen here we've got a
very diverse panel we're studying
advancements in medical science from the
perspective of cannabis cannabinoid
medicine and we have a very diverse
group here so I'd like to give everyone
the ability to introduce themselves with
the support of some slides and to give
them the ability to fill in the blanks
so interestingly I'm the only one up
here that does not have an MD or a PhD
but I come to you with some interesting
experience so a couple of years ago my
partners and I were onboarding into the
Canadian medical program and trying to
find a way to to get in get more
information about the appropriate
products we should be using how we
should be dosing and what we can expect
from the outcome of our treatments and
we found that we looked at literary
reviews we spoke to our doctors we spoke
to clinics and other care givers and
there was no data available so so we set
forth to to build that data set and
we've done that in Canada in North
America and we're actually here having
great discussions with a number of
people in the German and Swiss market
about ways we can apply our our approach
and and what we predominantly do is
we've developed a mobile app that allows
patients in Canada to track their
interaction with lab verified products
so we do this across 350 different
medical conditions and we analyze their
response to Canadian registered products
so this give us has given us a preview
of of a lot of consumer and patient
behavior and observational use over a
two-year period of time so it's it's
quite quite enlightening and
and especially for the medical audience
so all of our data is crowd-sourced
that's gathered from patients we also
have a community where we support
patients for discussions that are hard
to have on Facebook and that rolls up
into an analytics platform and the data
that we collect from this platform is
used by retail pharmacies across Canada
to provide prescribing guidance when a
patient calls in so it's based on the
large cohort data that that we produce
in the app we've been fairly successful
in our mission so far we've gathered
over 1.2 million patient interactions
this is on a platform that's hip-hop
HIPAA and HIPAA compliant and we're
probably the largest medicinal
observational data set in the world and
what we do is we provide this tool to
physicians to researchers and clinicians
to help them to identify what is working
and what is not so that's that's kind of
a background of how I arrived at this
table I have a different view of medical
patients it's based on statistical and
choral Ettore analysis and what I'd like
to do is is give everyone else the
ability to introduce themselves in a
similar fashion so in in order of the
slides I'd first like to you to
introduce dr. Fran drew Franjo Croton
Herman who is very well known amongst
this crowd he is the executive director
of the International Association for
cannabinoid medicines ICM in Germany he
is also the chairman of the Association
for cannabis as a medicine in Germany
and he is also a a medical practitioner
so let me hand it over to Fran Joe to
introduce himself very good so I have
only two slides I don't know if you know
the legal situation in Germany it
exactly and I thought I would like to
introduce it first this is a slide on
the prerequisites for reimbursement for
cannabis medicines by a German health
insurers and this is also kind of a
guideline for German physicians in which
transitions they prescribe cannabis and
there are three prerequisites first the
patients have to suffer from a severe
disease sometimes there's discussion
between the physician and the health
insurer if this is severe for example
they have to Shoreham a arguer while he
is able to work so the disease is not so
severe the second veracruz it is that
there that a generally recognized
medical standard treatment is either not
available or cannot be applied on the
reasonable assessment of the treating
physician and the third which is very
interesting interesting or important
which when it comes to research or the
available data
is that there is a founded chance or a
kind of justified chance of a noticeable
positive effect on the cause of the
disease or unserious symptoms and the
latter requirement is fulfilled if there
is scientific research supporting this
chance it is not necessary that there is
that there are large clinical studies
with 200 or 300 patients it may be
sufficient that is for example for
Tourette Syndrome we have only very
small studies 1020 people but to read
system Tourette syndrome is accepted so
it would be interesting to have research
with 20 or 30 people 20 or 30 patients
in these disease where we have nearly
nothing today I give you some examples
please next slide
ah sorry I give you some diseases which
are promising but currently unresearched
and the number of people suffering in
Germany with this disease for example we
have about 2 million people with ADHD
above the age of 18 the current
guidelines for treatment of ADHD in
Germany say don't use cannabis they
explicitly say that you should not use
it we need some more data to show it is
effective at least in some people autism
we have no real good medication to treat
autism no good standard medication to
treat estate but cannabis often is
helping and we have about a half million
people in Germany suffering from autism
and there is no absolutely no clinical
research for ADHD we have at least one
clinical study conducted with the
cannabis sector Sativex in the UK what
with autism we have nothing depression
we have good antidepressant medications
but 1/3 or 30% of patients do not profit
from standard medication so if we have
3.5 million patients with depression
there would be about 1 million depressed
patients who do not get sufficient
relief by standard medication and there
is no research there's some research on
reactive depression in in cancer for
example but with neurotic depression or
major depression we have nothing post
about a stress disorder we have some
research on it but
we should have more obsessive-compulsive
disorder we have nothing we have a few
case reports for example from the
charity in Berlin here 1.4 million
people suffering from
obsessive-compulsive disorders these are
not always severe cases but as in any
case any disease you have light moderate
and severe conditions psychiatric
conditions are usually under researched
when it comes to cannabis
this has tradition because psychiatrists
often are very reluctant when it comes
to the medical use so we have to do
research in this area of psychotic
conditions because the patients are
suffering many of them do not get enough
relief from standard medication and for
the companies this is also a market if
you say it in other words for the
patients it's a need for the company is
the market and for researches it is a
must do we have many physical conditions
where we do not have much on research
for example I see patients with acne
inversa it's not well known and research
an unknown disease suffering more than
half a million people in Germany alone
and we have no good medication they are
usually undergoing surgery once a year
or something just a headache we have
something with migraine but we have
nothing with customary hyperhidrosis
I have several peoples with hybrid roses
severe hyper-v doses there are three
grades from light moderate to severe and
I have patients who have undergone
surgery to treat their hyper two doses
of the arms and the hands and they kind
of is at least in some people works well
you do not have think research so we
don't know the person
age of people who may profit from a
treatment cannabis what I can say at
least some people profit very good
Crohn's disease or bowel syndrome
tinnitus when it comes to research
example with another and researched
condition which is restless leg syndrome
with restless leg street or some wrong
you see also see that it is not only
about THC and this is may be true for
other indications so it may be
reasonable for example to have a three
arm research one arm recibo one arm an
indica strain one arm sativa strain or
one arm CBD THC strain and one the THC
strain the example is the following four
weeks ago I had a patient with restless
leg syndrome treatment resistant to
standard medication she went to the
Netherlands to try cannabis it worked
very well she she came back some months
later she had an appointment in my
practice and I told her well in restless
leg syndrome
I usually prescribe indica varieties but
they were not available you know the the
problems with getting enough cannabis to
Germany and I prescribed a sativa
stranger and three days later she was
read the pointer said it does not work
and meanwhile the indica strains were
available I've prescribed integer strain
and some days later she said I have the
same effect as with the cannabis in the
Netherlands I could sleep like a baby so
thank you
alright thanks for having me my name is
dr. Tim Shue
my background is veterinarian I'm from
California prior to starting my company
vet CBD I practice in general emergency
critical care medicine and the reason
why I find a vet CVD in 2015 was because
as a health care practitioner I believe
we have a moral and ethical obligation
to pursue all potential courses of
therapy for our patients and my approach
is that if cannabis has potential
therapeutic benefits then we owe it to
our patients and the pet owners to be
able to pursue those therapeutics and
even if cannabis doesn't have any sort
of therapeutic benefits we need to find
that out we need to make that
information available to pet owners so
they can make the best decisions for
their pets the reality is that for
animals the lifespan is a lot shorter a
lot of patients don't have time to wait
it's now or never so from the time that
we bring them home when they're puppies
in the blink of an eye lifetimes passed
by before we know it we're saying our
good-byes and so in 2015 I retired from
practice and start a vet CVD so that way
we could provide cannabinoid
therapeutics for animals and the things
that we've used it for for the past four
years for thousands and thousands of
patients across California are primarily
things like pain anxiety inflammation
nausea seizures and cancer and a lot of
people may be familiar with using
cannabis or CBD for dogs but we also use
it for cats we use it for horses
guinea pigs rabbits rats pigs ferrets so
you name it the reality is that all
vertebrae animals have endocannabinoids
systems and they do stand to benefit
from cannabis therapeutics you know a
lot of people talk about THC and they
don't know about that's used for THC in
animals but we do use THC in animals
it's not just CBD we do use
full-spectrum products that include THC
we also look at CBC CBG really when we
approach cannabinoid therapeutics the
reality is that the endocannabinoid
system was only discovered in the 90s
and so as a field of medicine we're
really just scratching the surface and
ultimately my goal is to be able to
integrate cannabinoid therapeutics with
veterinary medicine so that way we can
benefit our patients we can provide them
quality of life and
we can provide sustained value to those
pet owners hello everybody I'm a senior
scientist from volcanic centre Israel em
I'm a a head of a lab in Vulcan II which
is a governmental Research Institute and
in my lab we are focused on cannabis
studies a we are involved with the
process that Israel is going now of this
reform of medicalization we're with the
other national bodies like the Israeli
gene bank we form genetics collection of
seeds of genetics that is the national
collection of Israel and will serve
growers and scientists for the further
developments of this field we
characterize this a this collection and
however the main activity in my lab is I
think what might be the major challenge
that we face in this field of cannabis
for medical use and this is the
generation of head of evidence-based
medicine and this is what we are focused
on in my lab we ask what are the best
mixtures of active cannabis compounds
for optimize treatment for different
medical indications or conditions to
answer this particular question we have
a very small farm for research purposes
only we develop different extraction
protocols or use different extraction
protocols we do deep chemical analysis
we see far and beyond
THC vers
Zippity but rather we look at many
different cannabinoids terpenes
flavonoids whatever varies we a do
separation of day of the compounds and
ven examine in different bio essays that
reflect at least to some extent
different medical conditions we are able
to identify the compounds and the
compositions and then taraj effect that
we have heard about a these days we are
able to identify these compounds with
act together for optimized treatment of
patients we work with physicians from
hospitals in Israel and the information
that we find in our studies is being a
now developed by commercial companies a
two products that are going into
clinical trials in hospitals in Israel
so just in briefly let me take you as to
the future at least as the way which we
see it in a cannabis for medical use so
we all start from from weeds and
satifying in dicovered we heard about
quite a lot and from different strains
or cultivars but we heard about by
conducting bioassays we identify
synergies between cannabis molecules
these synergies of course by also
biochemical analysis leads to
formulation of active pharmaceutical
ingredients or active plant ingredients
all derived from cannabis but we are
able to determine what the formulation
of active compounds is we look for
targets and mode of action of these
specific synergistic api and then by a
process of development being
by our commercial collaborators that
include different steps of regulation
and development of drug delivery which
is also highly important with that we
are able to to promote and to bring we
believe new generation of cannabis based
products for medical use those that will
be based on API on synergies and will be
standardized for optimal and specific
use for a patient's thank you I'm trying
to steal her mic so we've had a lot of
discussion about the ways that that
cannabis can be used to treat things
like IBS Crohn's disease depression
we've heard about its use in in animal
and veterinary care and we've talked
about isolating cannabinoids and
terpenoids that morally more closely
approximate a molecular drug so one of
the things that that I think is
necessary as the as the industry moves
forward and as cannabis develops into a
medicine is to understand those
interactions and the entourage effect
because it's it's the seclusion or
preclusion of certain elements within in
a strain that actually will dictate the
way that it that interacts with the
human body and as fragile had mentioned
there's very very big differences
between the people will respond from
strain to strain in terms of the Israeli
approach we're looking at isolating and
reconstituting product for test within
market and and in order for doctors to
be comfortable of with it this is at
least something that we see in the
Canadian medical program is is that you
need to be able to talk the language or
the rubric or lexicon that the doctor is
used to prescribing against and because
this is an evidence-based
daddy a lot of physicians these days at
least from what we see at strain Grant
are reticent to prescribe because they
don't have the the data of that
molecular drug there there's also a gap
that we see in terms of their
understanding of the application of
cannabinoids for various therapies so
maybe I can ask Franjo what what are
some of the gaps that you see in in
terms of our knowledge for treatment in
inpatient years
well let me say one word on the history
of modern cannabis research which
started with clinical studies the first
was conducted in 1975 all clinical
studies on the medical use of cannabis
in different diseases has been initiated
by patients patients went to their
doctors at a university and if they were
lucky this doctor found it very
interesting this experience and he asked
other patients if they had similar
experiences let Mesa gave the example of
Tourette's syndrome
Studies on dread syndrome have been
strong ducted at the medical school of
innova because there we have a professor
dr. Kestner Laval who was told by their
patients in the 1990s if we take
cannabis we have relief of our symptoms
then he made the first study with one
patient the second party study with ten
patients one day studies then a study
was for use a few space patients over
time of four weeks this has could could
been have happened also to patients with
other diseases it is important that at
hospital doctors or doctors listen to
their patients
and don't say this is not possible we
have no clinical data we have to gain
clinical data
my first patient with hyperhidrosis who
use cannabis and was successful and met
in five years ago before I did not know
that cannabis may work in high doses
then I wrote a very short piece in a
journal journal journal and I got
feedback from other patients said I am
also suffering from Pedrosa's I am
profiting from it so what we need is
doctors at last hospice hospitals at
universities who listen to their
patients who tell them incredible
stories about what can cannabis can do
and and then to start research
unfortunately research is rather
expensive so if there is an interested
doctor at the University he will usually
only be able to do an open study with
ten or twenty people and they will not
be able to carry out large studies so
what is necessary that companies and the
scientists at university come together
to look what can we do to profit the
patient the doctor the industry great as
I guess as a follow-on I'd like to ask
the same thing of Tim you know we see
that a lot of people in in in terms of
prescribing for their pets they really
do think of them as extensions of the
families so you know we hear stories of
people putting their dogs on Prozac or
on on cardiovascular heart drugs to
extend their life also dealing with pain
you know we've seen applications for
PTSD depression anxiety what what type
of things are you seeing in terms of
veterinary medicine and and the approach
is that you're taking using cannabinoid
therapy yeah I think some of the things
that are uniquely challenging
when it comes to the medical aspect of
cannabis is that it's it's very
backwards a lot of times when we're
looking at other therapeutics other
drugs you know we tend to have these
clinical trials that are established and
then what happens is the patient's
benefit afterwards but cannabis coming
from a black-market essentially what
happens is now the market becomes the
driving force and the science and the
medicine take a backseat and have to
play catch-up because the market will
operate whether it's a black gray or
legal market the market will always be
there and it will continue to operate
now the reality is when the market is
black or gray the scientific in the
medical aspect of it are going to be
unable to operate and so what we see is
that we see in terms of the real-world
evidence we see a lot of patients using
it for all sorts of different things
we see a lot of case studies that have
been successful for things like pain
anxiety inflammation whether it's
allergies our autoimmune diseases nausea
seizures and cancer but we're seeing a
lack of complete clinical trials and
clinical evidence because of the market
that we have to operate in that's really
really unfortunate and veterinarians is
especially in America are in a unique
position because across America veterans
are actually not allowed to discuss
cannabis with their clients so something
that's potentially beneficial or even
life-saving for their clients they can't
even discuss that now California has
changed a little bit because last year
we helped get a bill passed called a b2
to 1/5 that allows for California
veterinarians to discuss cannabis with
their clients so first bill of its kind
in the country and hopefully it leads
the way for people to be able to discuss
this with their veterinarians because if
they're not hearing it from their
veterinarians they're our primary source
of medical information what happens is
they're going to go on the internet
they're gonna you know google these
symptoms and find out you know what it
may or may not do and a lot of times
this information could be false or
inaccurate they're asking friends or
family when they really should be
talking to medical professionals about
this unfortunately when it comes to the
endocannabinoids system and cannabinoid
therapeutics in general the the medical
teachings are far behind so when I talk
to a lot of veterinarians they don't
know about the endocannabinoids system
they don't know about endocannabinoids
and so you can just imagine if you went
to your doctor you went to your
veterinarian you asked them about the
endocrine system you asked them about
you know what insulin does for your body
you know what happens if you have low
levels of testosterone or estrogen and
they threw up their hands and say I
don't know how would you feel as a
patient how would you feel if that's
what your medical professional said and
that's the reality of what we're dealing
with a lot of times these veterinarians
or physicians they say I don't know
because they're not being taught this
material in school and this information
isn't being made available to them again
partially because of the legal blockades
that are involved here and so this is
the problem that we're seeing is a lack
of education and this is one of the
things that we're focused on is
educating veterinarians and veterinary
clients to be able to have this
education so that they can make informed
decisions about their health care that's
really wonderful
one of the things that they that we're
looking at is is building custom
solutions for custom disease states so
we're we're looking at isolating
compounds so that we can deliver next
generation proper pharmaceuticals and
and this is something that that
underneath is doing in Israel so maybe
you can tell us about what you think are
some of the biggest opportunities for
development and exploration based on
your view of cannabis I would like just
first to say a few words about the the
issue of fail of education and what I'm
involved with in Israel in the frame of
the Ministry of Health is the teaching
medical personnel physicians nurses
pharmacists about cannabis and it's so
interesting to see how a stigmatized
this subject is nevertheless the stigma
is being slowly being reduced and and I
think and I completely confer to what
you said this is a matter of Education
of really a educating the personnel the
medical personnel on cannabis and on the
different properties
so I definitely agree with that's
wonderful say so that's that's one a
taking the same line answering your
question a what I think the main
importance here is to close the gap that
we have today between the the current
knowledge of what we know about cannabis
on their different compounds on don't
rush affect and the actual compounds
that are working together or separately
for different medical indications I
think that for my experience at least
that many of a of the physicians the
doctors are having a real problem to
recommend a patient to smoke a joint
okay to do get better if we do not see
that as a treatment as a medicine and
this is you know I think it's not just
in Israel but I think North America
shares a similar view towards smoking
and as a non-medical form most
physicians that I talk to will prefer
that people use an oil or use an edible
or or vaporize using a device because
obviously it's not good to combust and
you get all the the other bad chemicals
in along with the good chemicals exactly
and not just that this is not a medicine
agreed so a so here first of all
specifying what what compounds are the
the the active ones this is so important
definitely for treatment and also for
the physicians for their medical
personnel to accept cannabis as a
medicine that's one and then two is the
delivery the method of delivery which
should be much improved no doubt from
smoking to actual products that have
certain
a formulation high bioavailability high
absorbance dosing these should be dosed
III agree so one of the things that that
is is needed when when we're looking at
this as a medicine is is the concept of
transparency and standardization because
if you are gonna take it from a dried
flower and you're gonna render it down
into isolates that are reconstituted or
formula or formulated you you need to
deliver an experience that is going to
be the same every time and that's that's
what it's going to take for it to you to
be well understood but what we're seeing
in studies from ones like in Israel that
that daddy Miri had done on cancer cells
where he looked at six hundred you know
cancer cells and subjected them to six
hundred different strains of cannabis to
identify one that stopped the tumor
growth if we if we're gonna have to do
trial and error testing like that it's
it's it's unfortunately prohibitive and
and time constraining so a lot of what
we need to do to get our knowledge up to
par is done through observational
science because like it or not this is
not a drug that's coming to power
through through clinical trials it's
been brought in by government and and
constitutional rights around around the
world so perhaps I can I can turn it
back to to dr. Franjo to ask you about
what your experience is in the German
market and and what changes that you've
seen in your practice over the years
that you've been involved in in
prescribing as I understand you look at
a number of advanced cases
we all we all were surprised that the
number of patients are increasing so
quickly in in Germany it is clear that
usually one or two percent of the
population in industrialized countries
need cannabis as a medicine we see that
from Canada Israel and Netherlands that
it will be one or two percent also in US
states and I was aware that this will
also come to Germany so we expect to
have eight thousand eight hundred
thousand or 1.6 million patients in
Germany in the future currently we have
about 40,000 patient patients and it is
creasing very quickly and doctors
politicians are just currently realizing
that cannabis as a medicine is not an
exception to compared to standard
medication but that it is a very an
important medical treatment a good a
good medicine and the number of doctors
are also increasing we know it from
other countries that its first there are
very few physicians who are ready to
prescribe it and that's what's happening
in Germany there are few paid through
physicians and the development is
quicker than we thought that physicians
are ready to do it even against the
obstacles by the law it's not so easy to
prescribe cannabis in German in
physicians do it anywhere for their
patients and the number of patients are
increasing quickly and the number of
doctors also but of course there is much
uncertainty what is he described here as
a chance that cannabis is so diverse and
we have different strains and batches
for a beginner this is a confusion
and it makes it not easier but more
difficult that is the reason why many
physicians adopted in Germany start with
dronabinol only THC or with standardized
extracts and what we have to do is to
give them education so that relay regard
the different portents the different
possibilities of cannabis treatment as a
chance and not as a threat or as a
confusing issue I talked about indica
sativa or CBD THC patients want to find
their strain which works best and they
want to have it standardized that--as
get the all of the same strain and
physician physicians have to understand
that cannabis is more than thg and
regard this as a chance to find a better
treatment for the doctors we need
education we need standardization and we
need clinical research thank you so Tim
with standardization research what what
what are you seeing in terms of
veterinary science is there
standardization we're seeing pet foods
we're seeing hemp products what what
type of products are being frequented by
pet owners in California and for what
yeah so like I said before you know
primarily what we see is tinctures oral
based medications we definitely do not
have pet smoking or vaporizing so I just
want to make sure everyone's aware that
I get that question all the time please
don't have your pet smoke that that's
not enjoyable do not hotbox your dog
please don't that's coming from a
veterinarian but yeah we use it for pain
anxiety inflammation nausea seizures and
cancer like I said before now the unique
thing about cannabis is that it's an
incredibly complex plant there's over
500 pharmaceutical components of the
plants the endocannabinoid system is
infinitely complex the cb1 receptors we
used to think that they were only in
this
nervous system now we know that they're
found all throughout the body same thing
with the cb2 receptors and even when
we're looking at the cannabinoid
receptors in human studies they've shown
to have genetic polymorphisms what that
means is that your cb1 receptors may not
be encoded as the same as the person
sitting next to you so cannabis the way
it works on your body is it may not be
the way that it works on your neighbor's
body and so we think that that may be
the case in animals also because we do
see variations in dosing protocols so
you know we could have a 70-pound dog
that uses a for epilepsy that uses a
higher dose than another one that uses a
much lower dose and one may need it
three times a day the other may be able
to use it just one time a day so that's
some of the difficulties that we're
encountering is that you know it's hard
to standardize dose for each individual
patient when we know that there can be
so much differentiation you know CBD the
molecule works on over 40 different
molecular targets you know has a very
weak affinity for the cb1 and cb2
receptors and so this is something that
it shows you just how complex it is
and we're trying to get a clearer
picture of it but it's going to take
time and you know in the meantime the
the mantra of starting low and then
gradually titrating up to the effective
optimal therapeutic dose is is good
advice not just for people but also for
animals so that's that's good advice in
in any time using cannabis start go low
start low go slow so one of the one of
the things that we've just been asked is
to open up the floor to questions let's
hear it again for the panel first of all
let's ask the Krays
hi my name is tamas Garlin you have a
question too fragile so when your claim
is or when you say well okay there must
be more doctors to support this and need
to be educated when I saw a video or a
report on German TV were the the the ax
the comma you know the the the cocl
sukima
has been strongly kind of very
controversial and against you know
supporting cannabis maybe you can tell
me you know how how's the strategy to
really break brick out of the wall
because you know this is this is a lot
of effort without you know with maybe
you look just a little effect today you
know with a lot of effort on your side
that's my question well what we see
today is that every doctor is somehow
finding his own way to treat their
patients for example a colleague in in
my in the board of directors of the is
a.m. and the ICM is also a german doctor
at a university and we recently talked
together and found out that we have the
same idea of the usefulness of cannabis
as a medicine but we have different
approaches and this was a reason why we
decided to have a panel of doctors at
our next is same conference which will
also be in berlin where doctors tell the
audience what is their approach it's
it's we need education this is one one
thing what we also have to realize that
it is difficult to get different
approaches it is physicians i use
to give single molecules for example
tthe and or standardized extract
stresses sativex it is for example from
the EXA comma they are more supporting
these efforts and sometimes are saying
that cannabis louse is a kind of
middle-aged medicine and so this is the
flowers may be regarded as a threat to
usual therapy and we have to change it
that it is a chance to a better
treatment yeah if somebody's asking me a
doctor in Germany how can I start the
treatment then I usually say you may
start with THC or standardized extracts
and if you have more experience then you
can change to a cannabis flower perhaps
to get more effect than with THC pref
lesser side effects or better effects
and so so we need education but every
doctor also have to make his career his
experience his own education with the
interaction of his patients and this
makes cannabis somewhat special because
other medicines you bring it to the
market and you say you start with five
milligrams then go to ten milligrams
this always the same way with cannabis
it's not always the same way I am sure
that I have different ways than many
other doctors and that's what we try to
bring to to doctors that there is no one
golden way to treat patients with
cannabis based medicines we have time
for one more
sure hey I'm Greg from the UK kind of a
social clubs that leads me perfectly
into my question actually but we do have
a one-size-fits-all medical cannabis
products available in the UK called
Sativex
it's labeled as having X amount of THC
and X amount of CBD in it but we all
know that it's got it's a full plant
extract it's got all the flavonoids and
in there as well and you know in
Esther's and so isn't it a little bit
insincere that we're you know labeling
up well you know talking about and
creating these medicines with just THC
and CBD in it when they do have all
these other drug interactions because if
I boy if I take two other strain two
strains similar to tgw have four sativex
and say well this one produces an almost
pure THC complex tract this one produces
an almost pure CBD extract I'll never
mix them together to get the the ratio I
need and then I'm going to give it to
people I could you know if the guy Oh
takes two strains he's got over in in
San Francisco the only two got to keep
it easy on this one if you take two
strains you've got over there that you
know make that high THC in high CBD
you're still going to get a different
reaction from the strains that I'm going
to make that you know from the home yeah
we're not you know when we're talking to
government ministers and politicians and
and and journalists they're very
confused by this because they're like
well know what the pharmaceutical
company is this is just THC and CBD so
its leaves people like me you know an
activist patients I'm being denied a
prescription in the UK now and I've got
Crohn's disease and it leaves us in a
really bad situation because people want
to follow the science and who seems to
be the most educated on this when we're
actually we've got a lot more experience
in it I've got six strains on I work for
my condition the different symptoms that
I need to function on a daily basis so I
can't be turned around and told no you
can't grow your own you're gonna have
one of these available from you know
from one of these companies and you're
gonna suck it up and deal with it so
that's not really working for us so we
you know we're pushing for the right to
grow at home and I just I just want to
know where do you think that actually
fits in in this or blight interim period
before we've actually got any of these
products we're all talking about one day
making and for people like me you know
should we do criminalize for people to
be able to grow in Europe as well
I think you touch here a very important
point of the somewhat superficial a view
that most have only on cannabis and I'm
including pharmaceutical companies
talking only on THC in CBD in a in an
extract is superficial view you have so
many other compounds molecules in these
extracts and they're so important and
may change so much the outcome I just
want to share with you briefly just one
of the observations that we had in our
studies we work on a IBD inflammatory
bowel diseases and we examine in our
systems in collaboration with Mayer
Hospital in Israel we examine the effect
of cannabis extracts fractions and
compounds on alleviation of colon
inflammation we see that that it's it's
you can you can imagine the extract like
like like a pile of LEGO building blocks
we see that when we choose some of the
building blocks and put them together we
can get efficacy which is 20 times
higher you see what I'm saying
you just pay by taking the right
building blocks okay so this is just one
example to the point that you touched
that we need to know so much more on
cannabis and need to know to choose
better day the compounds let them work
together to get much better effect and
you can I think if it you but you can
imagine that different diseases should
be treated very very much specifically
by different combination I hate to cut
you off a we're completely out of time
but you're correct let's hear it again
for the pan
[Applause]