this is what we were calling an
intellectual property law on cannabis
update it's not intended as an
introductory primer to the entire field
of copyrights patents trademarks and
trade secrets as they apply to the
cannabis industry it's really intended
as an update of a couple of new things
that have happened in the last year a
couple of new interesting things what
they're handing out the piece of paper
is my one pay my one piece of paper two
pages back two sides cheat sheet that is
kind of my intellectual property law
primer on two pieces of paper the first
page has a horizontal grid that compares
copyrights patents trademarks and trade
secrets which are the four basic
intellectual property tools on five
different criteria so you can kind of
get a feel for what the differences are
and then if you flip that over I created
a fictional product that attempts to
show how each of the the tools can be
brought to life in a real product and
the reason we're talking about this is
part of the reason is this is the kind
of work that I've been doing for four
decades in general clothing electronics
restaurants music TV film any kind of
industry you can think of I'm based in
San Diego California but get up here all
the time and about ten years ago a light
bulb went on that as this industry was
starting a more from an underground
economy to a real enterprise for
entrepreneurs and creative people and
businesses to help get the medicine
medicine out it dawned on me that was
only a matter of time before the
investors we're gonna start coming in
and saying this is I like your product I
like your business but how do I protect
my investment where's the collateral
where the copyrights where the patents
where the trademarks where the trade
secrets and so about ten eleven years
ago I just started learning everything I
could about the industry and taking what
I knew from intellectual property law in
general and applying it to this industry
and so
there's been quite a quite a few
developments in the last 10 or 11 years
you know you hear a lot at this
conference and all conferences about
branding you know figure out what your
brand is protect your brand I figure out
what your identity is what your personal
brand is but in my experience
particularly in the cannabis industry
branding without intellectual property
IP for short protection they go hand in
claw they go hand in glove if you have
IP protection but no brand that doesn't
do you much good if you have a brand but
no IP protection that doesn't do you
much good you put the two together now
you got something that's going to be of
interest down the road as you grow your
business now a lots happened in the last
year a lot of new developments given a
few minutes we have I'm just going to
touch on three or four of the ones that
I think you'll find most interesting
afterwards
I'll make myself available outside or
downstairs at the lobby bar depending
and I'll be happy to answer questions
but what's what's really different this
year what's changed in the last year
let's talk about for a moment trademarks
brand names logos brand identifiers
anything that identifies your brand from
somebody else's brand Exxon Kodak Xerox
mrs. Fields Apple so forth and so on
those are all trademarks the Nike swoosh
it's a trademark the Yahoo yodel that's
a trademark all these brand identifiers
z' that separate your brand from the
competitors brand this is a hot area
before we talk about what's changed
what's talk about what hasn't changed
what hasn't changed and it's still the
big conundrum
for the cannabis industry is that the US
Patent and Trademark Office PTO for
short will still not allow a u.s.
trademark registration for anything that
is cannabis contains cannabis
or touches cannabis so by touching
cannabis I mean retail stores testing
labs and things like that delivery
services so we have a real problem in
this industry in getting federal
trademark protection for the cannabis
industry that's a challenge that's what
people like me like we like challenges
so we spend a lot of time trying to
figure out what the alternative
strategies are now what has changed in
the last year is because in on December
20th of 2018 the farm bill of 2018 was
signed starting last year 2019 the
trademark the federal trademark office
started allowing trademark applications
for hemp and CBD derived products or
hemp derived CBD products with less than
0.3 percent THC this is monumental
breakthrough for the trademark office
because for the last 10 years the
federal trademark office has had a total
block blanket wall against anything
trademark any kind of trademark
applications pardon me for cannabis or
CBD
so if you are or intend to be in the CBD
business you now have the opportunity to
get some federal trademark protection
and just in December six weeks ago we
finally started seeing the first
trademark registrations actually being
issued and granted for CBD products
that's new that's news we also think
that now let me back up the challenge
with CBD applications or applications
for CBD products is the trademark office
will no longer use the Controlled
Substances Act as a basis for rejecting
your federal trademark application but
it will cite the Food Drug and Cosmetic
Act which doesn't allow orally
ingestible products to be marketed
commercially at least as far as the FDA
is concerned
so the Patent and Trademark Office will
reject a trademark application for
orally ingested CBD products on the
basis of the Food Drug and Cosmetic Act
not the Controlled Substances Act we
don't think that they're gonna do that
for sublinguals we think they're going
to draw a distinction between other
orally ingested products and sublinguals
why I'm not exactly sure
other than the FDA considers sublinguals
not to be nutritional supplements so
there are some opportunities there what
else can you do on the federal level if
you can't get a trademark registration
for your cannabis product or your
cannabis service or your CBD product
because it's orally ingested well you
got a you'll excuse the phrase plant
some seeds by filing trademark
applications for ancillary goods and
services clothing educational services
website information classes videos those
topics those products and services even
though they concern cannabis do not
violate the Controlled Substances Act
because they aren't cannabis don't touch
cannabis don't contain cannabis so you
may not be able to get a trademark
registration today for your cannabis
product but you can for ancillary goods
and services good thing to do build up
some protection plant some seeds for the
future what else
California well one of the things that's
changed in the last year is California
the fifth largest economy in the world
arguably therefore the most important
economy cannabis economy in the world
California now is allowing trademark
registrations for cannabis products and
services if you are licensed to provide
your product or your service by the
state of California that's a
prerequisite but you can get a trademark
registration for your cannabis product
or service in California which you can't
get federally given the fact that
California is the fifth largest economy
in the world that's pretty good by the
way most other states that allow for
either medical or recreational cannabis
also allow state trademark registrations
in the old days most trademark lawyers
were only concerned about federal
trademarks they didn't give to two hoots
about state trademarks but in this
economy and in this world where cannabis
is hindered by federal illegality state
trademark registrations really important
okay
by the way state of California will
allow you to file your trademark
application online something they didn't
allow until last year that's new you can
search for other trademark registrations
that have already been issued online
that's something new in the last twelve
months that you couldn't do a year ago
so you might as well before you file
your trademark applications spend your
time spend your money see if anybody
else has already gotten a trademark
registration for the same or similar
trademark so you don't run up against a
brick wall by the way the state what
also is new is the state of California
trademark unit is applying a much more
strict scrutiny looking much more
closely at California trademark
applications to make sure that they the
packaging and labeling is California
compliant if your packaging doesn't
comply with California law they will
reject the trademark application and
tell you to go back and fix it that's
new the fact that the trademark office
is looking at these trademark
applications much more closely what else
is new
last month Keva health versus Kiva
brands show hands everybody familiar
with Kiva edibles Kiva Edda mill has
been around for quite some time well
there's another company called Kiva
health a non cannabis company they sued
Kiva brands in federal court for
trademark infringement not state court
federal court for trademark infringement
claiming that Kiva Health had a
trademark registration Kiva brands was
infringing Kiva Brands Kiva edibles
filed a counterclaim a cross claim
saying hey not so fast Kiva health we
have unregistered common law trademark
rights based on our lawn
standing use of khiva for edibles in
California we may not have it registered
for edibles but we've got common law
rights based on our long-standing sale
of khiva branded products which is by
the way a valid legal doctrine you don't
have to have a trademark registration
it's really good to have one you're not
required by law to have one you have
these common law rights if you've been
selling the product unfortunately the
court dismissed
Keva brands counterclaims against kiva
health said sorry
cannabis is illegal under federal law
you're in federal court we're not going
to give your common law claims any
credence in federal court this is a game
changer for brands and for trademark
enforcement rights I think it means a
couple of things stay away from federal
court if you can build up your ancillary
trademark registrations on the federal
level for those non-radioactive products
and services clothing educational
services website information so forth
and so on and get your state trademark
registrations there's a possibility that
if you have more of your found found a
tional bricks in place you might be able
to avoid a similar fate that happened to
poor kiva brands also you know
hindsight's 20/20 but I'm thinking now
if I have a client that's being
threatened with trademark infringement
lawsuit by somebody I may not sit around
for too long waiting to see what happens
and going back and forth with the letter
writing and the phone calls and can't we
all be friends what I might do is I
might go racing into state court here in
California and file a pre-emptive
trademark action called a declaratory
relief action in state court where I
think my client might get a better shake
from the judge than in federal court and
say judge we've been threatened my
clients been threatened with trademark
infringement by this other company I'm
filing suit
because I want a declaration from you
that we do have valid and enforceable
common law trademark rights and maybe
state trademark registrations too and I
want to preempt this and get this into
state court and keep it out of federal
court the federal court conundrum is
also rearing its ugly little head in
claims litigation claims that are coming
up now also in the patent and trade
secret arena ironically you can't get a
federal trademark registration for
cannabis products and services from the
Patent and Trademark Office you can't
get a trademark registration if you walk
in the patent door I'm sorry if you walk
in the trademark door but if you walk in
the patent door you can because there's
nothing in the federal patent law that
says the patent office is not allowed to
grant a patent for cannabis there is a
prohibition against granting a trademark
there's a specific prohibition by law
against granting a trademark
registration for cannabis but not for
patents so cannabis patents are issuing
by the dozens whether or not they'll be
enforced in federal court which is the
only place you can go to sue for patent
infringement same with copyrights you
can only go to federal court we don't
know yet these are the cases that are
starting to rear their heads now 2019
2020 and in the future when I any good
old days when I first started doing this
work ten years ago there were no
lawsuits nobody was suing everybody
anybody everybody was holding hands
singing Kumbaya we're all in this
together
then about 2014 2015 when Colorado
Washington Oregon went legal the stakes
started rising more money started
floating in and you started seeing non
cannabis companies suing cannabis
companies over cannabis parodies like a
she's instead of Hershey's and ganja joy
instead of almond joy and so forth and
so on
Starbucks filed some lawsuits you
started seeing non cannabis companies
suing cannabis companies over these
so-called parodies and that was where
most of the litigation was between 2014
and 2018
then 2018 2019 is when we started seeing
cannabis companies suing cannabis
companies hadn't seen any of that really
before 2018 but it was sort of the
inevitable consequence of the increase
in the financial stakes that's taking
place and all the money that's floating
in and coming into the industry this has
happened for a hundred two hundred years
in our society as in as in - new
industries come online and become more
mature though the bigger players the
players are more aggressive realize or
after a period of time that they can use
the litigation system to [ __ ] their
competitors I don't like it I'm not
saying it's a good thing but it's
happening it happens all the time it
happens not just an industry but it's
starting to happen in this industry and
I think if I'm invited back next year
I'm predicting I'll probably have 10 or
12 different trademark copyright patent
trade secret infringement lawsuits where
one cannabis companies suing another
cannabis company to report to you it's
happening plan ahead that's my
recommendation for 2020 let's see what
else is new in 2020 copyrights because
we can't get trademark registrations on
the federal level for cannabis products
for the illegality problem the
Controlled Substances Act copyright
registrations for your logos your
graphic designs like let's take the ICBC
logo it's got all this rich detail in it
it's got the bridge it's got the tower
it's got the sales it's got the blue
it's got the green that's what I call a
graphically rich logo it's not just a
horizontal line and a vertical line it's
got some real content to it
that graphically rich logo that you see
up there and which hopefully many of you
have to identify and distinguish your
brands those can also be registered not
just as trademarks but with the
Copyright Office not the letters ICBC
but all the graphics copyright protects
content graphics illustrations drawings
photographs computer programs so because
we can't get trademark registrations for
cannabis products copyright
registrations to be filed with the US
Copyright Office copyright gov very
simple fifty five dollars the best
bargain around you could do it online
yourself I'll be happy to do it or guys
people like me are happy to do it but
honestly if you have the bandwidth you
have the patience and want to open up an
account you can do it yourself what's
interesting about copyright
registrations for graphically rich logos
the Copyright Office doesn't care that
your business is a cannabis business
they don't have no prohibition against
granting a copyright registration to a
cannabis business they're agnostic you
fill out the form right you pay the fee
you provide the specimen the the
evidence of what it is that you're using
your copyright on they're gonna register
that copyright for you and if somebody
infringes your copyright you get to go
to federal court not state court and we
don't know but we don't know how judges
in federal court are going to view
copyright infringement claims I think
they're gonna be favorable but I don't
know that for a fact yet but at least
you have the copyright registration and
you have something to hang your hat on
the other advantage of copyright
registrations and as a supplement to all
your trademark registrations is unlike
the trademark office which divides all
goods and services into 45 different
categories and you have to pay a filing
fee of either two hundred and
twenty-five dollars per category or two
hundred and seventy-five dollars per
category so if you want to file for
clothing and educational services and
website information that's going to be
three cat
at 225 bucks a pop the Copyright Office
essentially has one category $55 so if
your cell you're putting your trademark
on cannabis and clothing and somebody
puts it on lunchboxes and bed sheets you
can make a claim against them for trade
for copyright infringement without
having to pay fifty five dollars times
three four or five categories I'm really
bullish on copyright applications for
the cannabis industry what do you think
are we done oh four or five minutes you
have a question do you mind taking a few
questions I'll take a few questions
we got time you let me know when we're
done in Doyle so it's growing litigation
over the trademark registrations if
someone is to go to federal court and
lose what type of liability do you think
their attorneys are taking on and what
is the risk for malpractice
advising then on something we expect to
go to court and be challenged and most
likely not well it's a risk obviously
anytime you're you're out on the cutting
edge whether you're just giving advice
or whether you're litigating when you're
the lawyer and you're out on the cutting
edge whatever industry you're in whether
it's cannabis or weapons of mass
destruction or alcohol and other
controlled substances there's always a
risk that the advice that you give a
client is somehow going to backfire we
try to mitigate that risk we try to use
our brains we try to talk to our
colleagues we try to talk to the other
partners in our law firm and make sure
we're not making obvious mistakes so as
to mitigate that risk but you know when
you're out at the cutting edge sometimes
you got to push the envelope I mean
that's part of our job and whether or
not something rises to the level of
malpractice boy that's it that's a tough
one that's for others who are
smarter than I am to answer definitively
but you know it's part of the reason
lawyers charge what they charge honestly
I mean I lawyer hourly rates if any of
you have hired lawyers you know they're
pretty high no pun intended
yeah but part of the reason is because
we have to cover that risk and pay rate
outrageous malpractice rates per year to
cover those risks when we push the
envelope if we don't want to push the
envelope
we shouldn't be in the cannabis industry
we should Rick you know we should we
should represent yogurt companies and
stuff like that how much I'm not sure
that answers your question but I'm
trying as a copyright or some of the
other ways you're suggesting in the
ancillary fashion against someone who
else so I I didn't hear the beginning of
the questioning guy oh could you repeat
it yeah she said are there companies who
have successfully defended their
copyright right so you you suggest
getting a copyright instead of a
trademark or something like that and
then you have a chance so are there
examples of people using that
successfully in court to defend their
property
you know I right now the amount of
litigation that we're seeing in the
cannabis industry I can reel I can
almost literally count on two hands I
mean there's just very little litigation
right now that's out there I think
there's gonna be a lot more this year I
haven't seen any copyright infringement
lawsuits I've seen trademark
infringement lawsuits patent
infringement lawsuits trade secret
infringement lawsuits but not copyright
but I'm waiting and I'm ready to go when
you know if and when a client has the
right set of facts but I think it's
coming and as far as on the trademark
side well if there's if there's a
plaintiff and the defendant and the
lawsuit gets down the road there's
usually one winner and one loser so
there's usually one of each at the
that at the end of that fight there you
go thank you so much let's hear it again
brandman that was very elucidating