the next person I'm bringing up right
now he's going to talk about all kind of
international things he is the CEO or
the managing director of the multiverse
and he's here for you right now let's
hear it for the one the only me
useless
yes
oh there we go they don't give me a
podium to stand behind here and hide
well hopefully a little different than
what you were used to they're some of
the comments from that last one will be
indicative of some of the things I go
over but Nick Easley really good to be
here back in Berlin this is the third
year helping with ICBC and really
starting to create a global industry of
the largest consumer good in the history
of the world so really excited to share
a little bit today I'm CEO of 3c
consulting I started that almost 13
years ago in Colorado and also managing
director of multiverse capital private
equity and venture capital funds they
said there's a little button here it's
got a laser on it which will probably
get me in trouble just see here perfect
just a quick disclaimer I'm not a lawyer
I'm not a CPA I'm not a certified
financial analyst I run venture capital
private equity funds I've also seen this
industry evolved for over 13 years from
Colorado 2006 first kind of bonafide
commercial medical program starting
2008-2009 first adult use recreational
state even more legal than Amsterdam
ever even wanted to be started working
in California multiple other states we
have operations in 24 States have done
licenses in 13 countries worked in over
20 countries now so really have gotten
to see the US market the global market
and from the consulting with working
with clients really have understood what
works what doesn't where as capital
powerful and really positioning like the
last panel said it's not about trying to
be Philip Morris or Pfizer it's being
bought by them and like how to position
things for mas versus private and public
so I've seen all sides and also I look
at markets based on the market for
cannabis itself not so much it's like
your country so if I offend your ideas
or your country or your policies I
apologize in advance but I'm not
guessing on what I'm going to talk about
here this is the truth from the trenches
of this industry just a little bit of
background originally I'm like from farm
country in Wisconsin I was a crypto
linguist for the Air Force I speak
Spanish a couple of their languages
unfortunately my Dutch Danish Greek
Greek and German are not very good so
thank you very much for our translators
there
from starting in Colorado like ask that
first state only six million people but
we learned specifically what not to do
which is more important as you're
investing in navigating this landscape
than knowing what to do so not repeating
the same mistakes that others have done
time and time again with product recalls
are building a giant indoor facility
that costs let's say four four hundred
and fifty five hundred dollars a square
foot to build compared to big
greenhouses so we see what works we see
what doesn't and sometimes indoor works
depending on the state of the country so
I've done this long enough to really see
what's working what's not working what
teams are really turning into good
investments and what to completely avoid
and in some of these markets it'd be
better to just put your money in a pile
and burn it then invest into some of
those markets so I want to make sure you
know how to not lose your money if
you're going to be investing in the
space so let's just kind of like look
like here at the world I mean we started
in Colorado I mean this plant we
inherited it's like hundreds of
thousands of years our our species has
been working with this plant like I
didn't invent this plant
you didn't our great-grandparents passed
this down to us and it's our job now to
create a responsible industry to like
pass on to future generations this is
not a boom and bust thing it's not like
a Snuggie or some new little fun toy
that people are gonna get interested in
and maybe not like in the future we've
already seen in the United States over a
hundred billion dollar illicit black
market economy from cannabis so people
have been willing to break the law go to
jail here they're everywhere for this
plant and now we have this moment that
this is being legalized on a medical
basis around the world now we have a
certain amount of time to establish this
industry with some of the news I'm gonna
go over from this last few months we
don't have decades to do this like we've
been doing this fast fast fast this last
three years things have exploded from
the first Tinder's in Germany or
licenses in Denmark or what's happening
in Canada and compared to the United
States we didn't have public markets
otherwise we would have really scaled
and taken that enormous market share
that the Canadian public companies are
now but when you look at Canada it's
kind of like up north there and really
cold and gray and
not the the best place to do
agricultural production to supply the
world they had that first mover
advantage and have now been trying to do
acquisitions around the world but what I
see from an investment standpoint I'm a
big advocate of private investments I
most things that I like for the public
markets are preparing to short them
because I know that the bubble is bigger
than any bubble we've seen in the
history of public markets it's 300x
overvalue or like a company doing a
million in revenue that's got a market
cap of like four billion dollars like
that's ridiculous I mean dot-coms this
we're gonna get into is like a hundred x
this is like three hundred x so there's
huge opportunities for shorting if you
know what and when to do this when we're
thinking about the world where this is
going it's gonna go very very fast based
on a few laws that are gonna be written
into law anywhere from September to
March this year so when we're thinking
about these sorts of companies if you're
an investor in normal sectors you know
market risk team risk product risk like
the normal things you have to think
about for due diligence now in cannabis
you have to remember this is a start-up
industry full of startup companies most
startups fail because they're not
bonafide businesses raising capital is
difficult especially if you can't go to
the bank and say hey I need a loan to
start this cannabis company if it's
federally illegal where you're trying to
do this you don't have institutional
capital that's going to give you your
investment so you need private sources
of capital and then we've seen over 200
million dollars u.s. loaned out at
eighteen point eight percent on real
estate like I pay off buildings in two
three four five years like that's not
like normally like a mortgage is until
death so when you're thinking about
making eighteen percent on real estate
it's because banks aren't doing loans
institutions aren't doing this so like
there's a huge opportunity here not just
for investing into the cannabis
companies touching the plant cultivation
processing distribution dispensaries
extraction manufacturing but the
ancillary side of this industry is well
like real estate is stable I mean other
than 2008-2009 of course kind of kicked
off some bad things there from the US so
when I'm looking at these sorts of
markets and like what do I need to do
for Doodle
when I'm managing like my personal
capital my investors capital my
number-one rule is like don't lose my
investors money like my second rule is
like see rule number one so I can't be
risky and just throw it all out there
but there's a lot of risk in this space
and there's always risk in start-up
industries but the opportunity of
getting large private positions on the
cap table like with board control and
seeing these companies scale that's
where there's the biggest impact for
private capital now or you can actually
get in for like let's say half a million
and get 10% of a company 20% of a
company that starts to scale these
things like we literally grow money on
trees like that's what our business does
so when you're making a cash flow
business and you're investing into that
the proceeds the dividends the
distributions are enormous if you have
the right tax structures but a lot of
these companies I'll see a New York
entity or some crazy company that's
doing the investment in some
international project so the other risk
you have to look at is like where is
your money coming from where is it going
through like a Holland BV is it going
through Luxembourg like and then where
is that capital coming back to so you
have to think about the long term exit
strategy
all of our funds are like six eight ten
year exits where we just reinvest
reinvest reinvest huge exits come so if
you're not preparing for like capital
gains taxes or how you're gonna get all
of that capital back and not lose 40 50
60 percent of it even if the opportunity
is a great investment
you're gonna lose so much money in the
future if you don't plan for these
things now those are the risks that as
you're looking at these opportunities
it's more than just can they grow good
weed or not that's the easy part this is
agriculture but the normal risks are
much more difficult in cannabis because
you've got all this Canadian public news
and all this distractions so it's really
hard to see like what's true what's not
what's good sources of information
that's where being deep in the industry
being under the hood of hundreds of
different companies and knowing what's
happening we can see this is good this
is not and for investors to go into this
on their own
very very very challenging especially
into the public market because 90% of
what you reads not true
so kind of in this slide thinking about
like that dot-com bubble so many of
these startup companies are gonna fail
and when you're looking for a unicorn
like that magical investment that's
gonna have hundreds of X or when you can
buy Amazon shares for $2 a share that's
when you want to be getting in and
playing with these things it's not like
when they're trading at 1500 a share and
that's that's what we try to position
for and you that's why you only have
this moment once and there's so much
risk in this industry that if you can
know where to put in early this is not
going away it's only a matter of time
until like larger legalization happens
medically is so important to focus on
internationally recreational is
violating international laws so always
know if you're investing into
recreational cannabis be it in Uruguay
be it in Canada be it future Mexico
recreational your country and company is
violating international law now in the
US I'll violate federal law no problem
I'll follow state law but never violate
international law because you will lose
your market share and ability to export
which we'll talk about shortly so one of
the things that we notice
internationally the same problem here in
Germany as we'll get into is that
without demand like an illegal demand
you don't have a market like we're
creating patients and this is a patient
focused market but patients come from
doctors writing prescriptions patients
are then your clients clients are your
revenue and revenue is your business and
without patients you have nothing so
there's this huge component now that we
need much more doctor education clinical
research clinical trials because so many
doctors even here in Germany they're not
stoked on writing a prescription for
someone to go home and smoke a plant
like everything from their medical
practices said like smoking is bad you
shouldn't do that so to try to get
doctors to understand what are the
efficacies with cannabis how to use this
properly and a doctor like people think
about brands like brands are so
important for normal industries yes but
in cannabis it's an API an active
pharmaceutical ingredient so when a
doctor writes a prescription they go
into that database they look at that
they put in cannabis if they didn't
write a specific brand like viagra or
some specific product they're gonna get
the generic and in these countries like
Germany where they're actually paying
for standardized health care the highest
quality standard at the lowest price is
the generic for the country we learned
that in the first round of the German
process it's not about brands it's about
the highest quality standards at the
lowest price of production but if we
don't create the demand which there's
the demand from the consumers and the
patients but legal access and the
gatekeepers are the doctors so if you're
in a country or if you're in a program
you have to work towards doctoral
education as part of your investment
thesis otherwise you're not going to
have clients to actually fund that
business so you know I think about like
planning I'm like when to enter a market
like what's important for a business
like the team the market the product
what's unique is it protected is it
differentiated do these people for me
it's not important for a project or for
an investment if they even know anything
about cannabis at all this is an
agricultural commodity this is
manufacturing pharmaceutical processing
and this is retail or distribution so if
you think about that first it's not that
special it's amazing medicinal plant but
it's still a plant and agriculture has
been around for 10,000 years
so any of these new big gimmicks you
might invest into from like cultivation
companies or fertilizer companies that
are gonna quadruple your yield it's like
you got to look into that because
traditional agriculture we weren't
growing corn and warehouses like it just
doesn't make sense
so trying to have like a six hectare
indoor facility that's GMP that's great
but your cost of production is gonna be
so high your competitive advantage is
gone so the only time like planning or a
big indoor works as if it's part of a
vertical market or for like research and
development but really for seasoned
hybrid GMP greenhouses are the best and
you can like ride in and catch a big
wave a big investment but if there's
like people around you that knock it off
or if all of a sudden your program no
longer can do what you think you're
gonna do your business is done so the
planning is more important for these
teams so if you're looking at an
investment look at the team do they know
what they're doing from outside industry
do they come from finance from
manufacturing from processing is there
anything unique there at all or they
just master growers because like master
growers are not master businesspeople
and like our joke in the US is like
their master fuck-ups but it's more
because they're the biggest problem with
all of our industry because they started
a cultivation knowing what they did in
their basement or their closet and then
they're trying to do that on a
commercial
scale and they have no idea so look for
people with agricultural experience or
pharmaceutical experience not just
people that know how to make good hash
like that's the easy part so a couple of
things that really from my investment
thesis internationally for our private
equity and venture capital you got to
know the rules to play the game and
everyone's just looking at this industry
and it's so exciting but they don't know
what rules govern them like you always
have to know what you have to serve so
like the w-h-o and the reclassification
this is enormous some of these things
that's happened the last three to six
months have changed the entire
international landscape of what's legal
what's not where to produce and where to
avoid even though there's some countries
like we'll get into with like Cyprus and
Malta and Greece and like countries in
Central and South America or your
amazing tie-in with like the Zimbabwe
President or something like just because
it sounds unique if it's not following
some of these laws it's not going to
happen you're going to lose your money
and you're gonna think of how great it
would have been and then you're gonna
regret and that's the one thing with
this time delta you only have so much
time to get your money into the markets
and private markets because public
everyone's gonna trade in the future
once this is institutionalized Amazon's
fifteen hundred bucks a share you're
just trading like everyone else you're
shorting the Hong Kong dollar the
companies that won't come in now that's
where you see opportunity now to get
your capital in and every day like I
don't have investors capital their money
is less valuable to me because that time
is so important especially with some of
these single conventions like the single
convention of 1961 is your Bible
currently if you're in global cannabis
essentially with the CMD coming out as
well of like pushing for like the
rescheduling we were hoping they were
gonna vote on this like we were with the
UN and the end of the year and not in
Vienna we were hoping this was going to
come through like for the rescheduling
and they pretty much requiring that
countries of the single convention would
be providing these products that's a
hundred and sixty eight different
countries that once this vote goes
through and is enacted must provide
those products to patients in their
country so I don't care if they want to
legalize cannabis or not or produce it
or not they have to provide
insulin to people with diabetic like
with diabetes that's pretty much like
what some of this would mean so that's
why we have like three to 12 months to
really position companies to be global
producers not Canada not just Israel not
just Holland not just Denmark but the
highest quality lowest cost of
production countries that are legal
currently or enacting laws the ones that
are gonna wait two three years by that
time it's too late for what we're doing
internationally the incb like
International Narcotics Control Board
like that's when we start thinking about
like Interpol and like adult things like
don't violate international law it's
really really bad for business and
really bad for your freedom if you want
to stay a free person their report about
two three weeks ago the 2018 report was
pretty much who's on the naughty list
who's on the nice list like kind of like
a Santa Claus and which programs are
bona fide and real and which programs
are illegal and violating international
law and just because there's a country
that makes a program if it's not
compliant with the international law
they won't be able to export their
products some of the problems that many
Colombians are going to face many
Israelis are going to face so many of
these countries are producing under the
local requirements of that program but
not knowing how they have to be
compliant internationally and for me for
where I invest I always think how do I
produce at the highest standards of the
country I have to produce at but what's
the hardest country in the world to
import to and I want to produce it their
standards so Canada started with GPP
they don't like they didn't even know
what GMP was at first and with the
European Union European GMP is kind of
important you can't just say you're
certified and processed but when the
incb is coming out and sending warning
letters to country saying you're
breaking the law like that's kind of a
big deal it's like a warning letter of
like we're going to raid you we're going
to shut this down if you invest into one
of those countries and that happens your
investments done market risk your market
just went away you were making tires and
tires are now illegal like that's the
position you do not want to be with one
of your investments so let's think about
like camp here because there's cannabis
you know there's hemp everyone's kind of
confused what's the differentiation
they're all dogs and like the joke is
like cannabis is like a poodle and hemp
is like a Great Dane they're both
dogs they're both from wolves and humans
through us breeding them like Gregor
Mendel like with pea pods back here in
Germany a long time ago that's how we
made different types of cannabis but
cannabis sativa it's the same species
and the biological definition of a
species is the ability to make sexually
viable offspring so I could take the
biggest hemp plant with the smallest
highest THC cannabis plant it's gonna be
somewhere in the middle but like don't
take a bull dog and mix it with a shih
tzu and get some is kind of
like the example there but that point
three percent point four percent for THC
is really what's the difference between
hemp and cannabis and hemp and CBD huge
opportunities in it especially in Europe
but in the United States in many of
these countries it's completely illegal
CBD in the United States is the same
scheduling as heroin so like people are
like it's legal in 50 states it's like
pretty much like heroin or narcotics
like the same schedule one so if you get
into that also know the rules to play
that game because if it's not legal you
can't do it but like with Austria with
Switzerland with some of these hemp
programs coming amazing novel foods
opportunities for CBD companies but if
it's just a CBD company and doesn't have
novel foods doesn't have some of those
registrations it's not gonna take
international market share and Rite Aid
or Walgreens or big pharmaceutical
companies are not going to buy your
products like you might think for your
revenue in the United States we have the
farm bill in 2014 which started the
legalization of cannabis like for hemp
the 2018 farm bill started and really
made things legal but the United States
will not be global hemp producers at
least as of now we don't have the
infrastructure research and development
the genetics like we're doing so much
breeding we're getting better and better
you look at Charlotte's Web like Stanley
Brothers 21 million last quarter like
that's coming up and that was just from
a small company in Colorado where we
were one of the first big hemp producers
but when you're thinking about the FDA
epitaxy of xgw pharmaceutical that that
company was approved by the FDA as a
cannabinoid and really set a precedent
for CBD from a pharmaceutical standpoint
so we have any time you hear CBD it's
kind of like a buzz word it's a snake
oil industry right now that 95% of the
products don't even have it in it which
is like selling bottles of like a few
ounces for $300 to someone with cancer
saying it's going to cure their cancer
but it's like
hemp seed oil so you have to be very
careful when you're investing in CBD to
know it's legal and it's real because
there's so many CBD products cat food
products like Water Products CBD shampoo
like all sounds great yeah the
veterinary side the cosmetics side that
sounds great but it's got to be legal
and it's got to be real and if it's not
you have to be able to avoid it
this is kind of like my favorite
metaphor I always kind of mention I just
remember the late nights as a kid
playing this little game risk you may
have seen it here it's like world
domination you know maybe not the best
kind of example to mention in Germany
here or in the United States it's
horrible but you got one shot like we
just opened up the box the board's down
all your homies you're all sitting
around the game and it's like where are
you gonna put your pieces like where are
you gonna put your investments I don't
have hundreds of billions I can just
take over everything right now with a
billion of additional capital I probably
own twenty plus percent of the sector
for life now if constellation had given
that to us we would have pretty much
been the only private thing in the world
but you know long-term so you're
choosing where to put these pieces where
are you gonna double down where are you
gonna go to war and like fight for that
territory for that country for that
company because it's only happening once
and if you come in with like one little
person on a country and you keep putting
more there if you're in the wrong
country you lose everything
so some sectors are good and some are
bad so that's gonna kind of transition
into like talking about which countries
and markets now I really think are the
most important so II use awesome I love
the European Union some of the countries
here in Europe that are not a part of
the European Union trying to get into
this program we're going to have major
problems just because I mentioned this
morning like just because you're
producing in Macedonians sell it
illegally to someone in Poland in the
who then can sell it to Germany doesn't
mean it's legal so just because you can
do something doesn't mean it's legal and
that you should do it and just because
others are doing something also doesn't
mean that you should be doing it
sometimes they're going towards a cliff
and you're just hooking right on to them
and then you're gonna get involved in
litigation is on the skyrocketing up and
up so you have to be able to protect
yourself but when we're thinking about
the EU it's huge here but it's gonna be
much slower than people think because
things go through process apparently you
like papers here
in the United States I could do digital
and get a driver's license here it's
like paper or paperwork paperwork the
bee farm so much slower but it's so big
here if you position yourselves
correctly with one of the pieces with
with monitoring of like these drug
programs they're starting the precedent
that what I see Germany and European
Union countries doing will essentially
emulate across the globe many countries
are going to be watching these countries
in here to see what they're allowing
because you've been doing things so much
longer from a regulated basis and
copying those it's not going to be
Chinese hemp companies selling CBD to
like European countries it's like I
really see like a European economy here
but also knowing that with the EU like
Germany couldn't say hey we're not gonna
allow imports from Portugal or from
somewhere else in the EU it's like if it
meets those quality standards you've got
that free trade here which is really an
interesting opportunity if you know
which laws you're following so when
you're scheduling and registering drug
products ACMs api's once you're
registering in one country and re
registering that in other countries in
part of an API database you're
essentially the Pfizer for cannabis
already even ask private companies early
on
so in reclassifying CBD this is also
like very important I mentioned novel
foods before it if you don't have novel
foods or understand what that is and you
want to be a global CVD player you're
wrong and your company's not going to be
able to sell the products that you think
and that's gonna be very expensive
you're gonna need contract manufacturers
it's a much more lengthy process than
growing some weeds sucking some oils out
of them putting them in a pretty bottle
in a pretty box and then just selling it
online people are doing that doesn't
mean it's legal but novelty foods is
something that if you're making edibles
products oils manufactured nasal sprays
sublinguals pills anything from CBD it
must be under those programs for the
future so forward-thinking compliance
don't just be compliant now what's the
forward regulations you're gonna have to
be compliant with with an investment
otherwise you're doing it you're
investing you're starting all these jobs
and then you can't sell anything and
that's not a good business model Germany
I love it like the first tinder process
like having a qualification there those
first ten having those taken away the
only value that came to me
from all of that struggle in Germany
years ago was learning all they care
about his quality and the lowest price
that's it like I have the ability of
saving government's billions of dollars
by producing in low-cost countries at
the highest standards they require an
importing to those markets not every
country needs to grow pineapples in
warehouses to have pineapples like we
grow strawberries in some places we
shipped them other places we grow
blueberries we grow flowers in Colombia
which is indicative of like flowers grow
there well but it doesn't necessarily
mean if their standards are not correct
that they're gonna be able to send to
those markets so when you're thinking
about what Germany wants GA cpg ap GMP
perfect that means if I'm in Colombia
I'd better be doing those if I'm in
Canada I'd better be doing those because
that fake GPP will no longer work in the
future this is the problem though here
we've got 80 plus million people in
Germany but the doctors are not making
prescriptions like we would like them to
because you've had to try everything and
then you can try cannabis what I love
are programs that say anything your
doctor thinks cannabis can help you with
you can then make a prescription for it
not like you've tried every single other
drug product and now everything's
failing this person's dying
okay let's try cannabis that's really
really hard to make a program but not
even a hundred million and Germany has
really been hard because people said it
is that benchmark internationally of the
market they want hundreds of millions of
dollars have been spent on trying to win
these tenders or the second round tinder
but you'll notice I didn't apply for one
of the last tenders and I I mean we got
two of the first Danish licenses we've
gotten licenses all over the country I
don't even want that here I just want
important distribution that's it because
I know that the cost of production here
is gonna be so much higher than anywhere
else in the EU down farther south your
regulations your tax your compliance
your VAT it's just like hey let's start
some companies or CBD companies or
cannabis companies in France
you'd be like it's me very very
expensive to operate but if we can just
grow it somewhere else at those
standards and import it that's what I
want to be doing you know so it's been
years it's been happening these are the
main challenges the doctor education the
right perception of cannabis but even
though it's slow right now just think
about what you're doing now indicative
for five years
for ten years that's that's that's the
timeline I look at like every dollar I
put in I don't care about it for five
ten years but I'm just hoping that
that's gonna turn into $100 or $200 or
$300 the longer you keep your money in
these markets the better it will do for
you now if it's public companies you're
just giving it to a bunch of Yahoo's to
reinvest buy things and sell things
based on what they're speculating they
can do and sometimes they can but a lot
of them they new capital and how to
manipulate public markets they did not
know cannabis and that's why you see
canopy and tilray
and aurora making all of these major
acquisitions and sometimes garbage like
I'm like you spent three hundred and
thirty million dollars on that it's
gonna be a little bit smarter if you're
a multi-billion dollar company but
startup industries startup public
companies so Canada I'm from northern
Wisconsin as a kid Canada I appreciate
what they did in starting the first
federal or a kind of medical program
like that I mean other than Uruguay and
recreational all adults should have
access to cannabis that they wanted or
not like just like alcohol or something
else we're seeing alcohol sales have
gone down thirteen percent legal states
and countries like where this access is
but can it unfortunately like they knew
there's only 40 million people here they
have a very robust illicit market they
started doing acquisitions all over the
world and into the United States the
problem though with Canada is that
you've got all these startup companies
listing on public markets that have
nothing there reverse splits reverse
mergers all of this garbage and they're
acting like they own the world but then
many of those companies are illegal in
their filings or in their processes or
they're investing into us and anytime
you have a multinational or a foreign
national investing into something that's
federally illegal that's not good that'd
be like hey let's take some money from
Germany and go down to like is Becca
stand and start a giant heroin operation
like that's gonna work out really good
like not the best but they've been
getting away with it but as soon as the
CSE and the TSX start D listing some of
these stocks if you invested into them
your money is not in a good place so you
have to be very careful with what you're
doing ETFs are good for like giving
capital like private funds and ETFs like
to get your money in and have people who
know the mark
to put it in but the problem even with
like some of those exchanges is that if
you're investing into good companies
they're tied in with the bad companies
so then as soon as that market starts to
shift or the bubble bursts even your
good companies are going to be going
down as well
that's why private investments long-term
investments are the best places for your
capital currently I kind of like this
like one-story listed there publicly
like I like them bringing access to the
world but it's like Silicon Valley right
now and just because everyone's talking
about these companies doesn't mean that
what they're doing is right the amount
of companies I see trying to piggyback
and copy these companies over and over
again it's not the goal to try to be
them what are they missing what are they
not doing what are they doing wrong and
how do you hedge your bets to position
for when they fail like you're up side
comes like our hedge fund and Macau
should be launched in live by like the
third third quarter of this year all
we're gonna be doing is just watching
their markets and knowing when to short
but I also know that like 90% of those
press releases you see are pure garbage
pure lies but no one knows it and then
it's hard to find access to information
but I do appreciate any company that's
trying to Bank bring medical cannabis to
suffering patients but not just at their
detriment or for their profit people
planet profit like that's true profit
not just trying to sell somebody a drug
that's gonna keep them alive for longer
but cost them $600 a day like some of
these other medications we see but long
term Pharma will take this but medical
and recreational cannabis is we know it
is one thing Pharma is very different
and that's like epitaxy davecs that's
where we're going you have to look at
both sectors and be in both but this is
the problem you cannot take money from
Canada invest into things that are
illegal federally in the United States
or kind of like the bee farms been
talking or a few other countries if you
have a license and you're a public
company or a private company and you're
profiting from recreational cannabis and
medical cannabis no longer being able to
act like to send medical cannabis to
medical countries so what would that do
to tell rates stock price to canopy
stock price to aurora's stock price if
they no longer can be importing to all
these other countries and then
everyone's growing a ton of
marijuana in Canada that now they can't
sell anywhere else and the price is
already like the
almost a thousand pending licenses
they're growing so much cannabis in
Canada and keep lying saying they have
all these shortages to keep getting more
investment into it but once that is all
getting established and there's so much
cannabis legal medical and recreational
and 80 plus percent of them can't send
it to the rest of the world it's just
gonna be like an ocean of water and they
Chiefs keep filling it with water so
like the prices are going to plummet
those companies are going to like tank
many of them go out of business and I
hope with our private equity to come in
and buy many of those distressed assets
and spread them around the world
but you're gonna see the greatest stock
market crashes bigger than anything
you've ever seen from Wall Street or any
past big bubble crashes in Canada and
it's gonna be so detrimental for their
entire economy but if a couple of those
big are gonna still be
billionaires and happy from having
manipulated the markets so be very
careful with some of those companies I
won two of the first eleven licenses in
Denmark we sold one still have another I
don't care about growing in Denmark it's
called a they're they work 32 hours
a week other than like one month in the
summer like I don't know man like so
Denmark the cost of reductions hi
everyone also thinks it's this huge
program it's a pilot research program
like the government last a couple weeks
ago like the Danish medicines agency
where's all these research plans we were
supposed to see you're all just
Canadians bringing hundreds of millions
of dollars to build greenhouses here but
like it's a pilot research program yeah
they've got the highest cancer rate per
capita
yeah cannabis is gonna be great for them
but it's not the country to take over
the world with it was just the second
country other than Canada that was going
to allow international export that's why
we went there but I'm not there I
haven't put in an additional dollar in I
just made five mill selling a piece of
paper it's like so you have to know
which markets and when but like where to
double down once you get a license
grease Mike Macedonia Cyprus Macedonia
actually has it a very decent program
that just needs to be changed a little
bit and could be very advantageous for
the world and for some other countries
but when you look at some of these like
Cyprus Malta like that's where you do
money laundering it's not where you grow
cannabis or wait they they close that
down in like 2009 2012 those are not the
countries that are going to take over
the world for production there's some
advantages there and there's some
patients there that need cannabis but
just because there's someone who wants a
pineapple somewhere it doesn't need
mean I need to start a pineapple
plantation so when I look at these
countries especially with Greece there's
opportunity there
tikkun olam and a few got some of those
first licenses really exciting but some
of the laws they copied from Israel
could make their program very very
challenging to do business in the future
and it's Greece but it's a member of the
EU so it could be a player if it doesn't
turn out to be corrupt or have some of
those problems
you know Spain we were there for ICBC a
couple weeks ago Spain kind of a
show of a program as well unfortunately
it's like similar to like tolerated
coffeehouse kind of clubs but they're
still years away from a bonafide program
now there's a lot of capital in Spain
that wants to get into the market but
it's not about the domestic market in
Spain but long-term like they know
cannabis there but their program has so
many problems just like the Netherlands
like they're gonna give twenty
coffeehouse licenses to start actually
growing cannabis and not like importing
hash in your butt to sell on a coffee
house they're like the current program
it's like tolerated but it's not like
legal they're gonna legalize that and
it's gonna be a probably a billion two
billion dollar market there but Spain
it's gonna be a little bit slower
you know Portugal is one of the
countries a lot of people are talking
about until rates making a lot of weird
claims right now about all of their
amazing GMP greenhouses which if you've
seen them roll up plastic science does
not mean GMP and if you don't know what
GMP is and your international you'd
better research it like for how you trim
dry crossest your package manufacturer
it's not just saying your GMP like it's
great to be like we're GMP GSEP like you
have to know what those things are and
it's not cannabis that's certified GMP
it's your processes your facilities so
in many countries we've just been buying
GMP facilities from other industries
repurposing those to easily get our
certifications that's how I've beaten
some of these public companies by nine
to twelve months in some of these
markets so just remember like Portugal
you know there are two licenses there
was a third issued a couple weeks ago
for some outdoor production just because
Aurora says that they're going to be
buying some country on in the Azores
that's gonna produce one ton a year that
they're applying for they don't have a
license and to see their stock price
what that's done Portugal will be like
the lowest cost highest quality
production but it's so challenging to
get in that most people don't understand
like what's going on there how it's
going to work but for their population I
really think that Portugal based on any
country's has the best local program
because they didn't legalize cannabis
they've decriminalized other drugs and
legalized medical cannabis so just
remember like I said internationally if
you're in this game it's only about
medical this is the second you do
recreational no longer valid and in the
international space Israel's been big I
know canna Tech is going on right now
everyone should be at ICBC cuz it's way
better for what's happening but Israel
was kind of stuck in this horrible place
for a good amount of years so much
research so much developments so much
patient focus I love Israel for doing
that but now with them being able to
export by the end of the year they think
they're now going to be world leaders so
what's that gonna mean a bunch of shitty
public companies are gonna list there
with all this speculation that are gonna
do nothing be careful about that also be
careful about German exchange now that
cannabis is legalizing here all these
startups are gonna try to list publicly
to do the same that they did in
Canada to make these high market cap
companies get tons of investment and
redeploy that in other sectors but that
is not how you start public companies
like you start public companies by being
a private company and scaling showing
revenue showing real processes and then
listing Facebook didn't go public day
one I mean any of these big companies
it's about position so when we make
investments it's about having lots of
pieces to make mas mergers and
acquisitions that then can pre IPO and
go public those will be huge titans of
industry not little startup to sent
shares maybe a 2 cent share company
makes it to Amazon but most likely not
and if you find those ones let us know
who they are you're gonna see a lot of
companies list in Israel the only thing
I really really care about in Israel is
like research and development clinical
trials drug discovery like I've got
about a twenty five million euro play
where I'm like drug discovery plates in
in Israel but I'm not producing like the
cost of production there will be so high
that I think long-term it's gonna be
challenging to do real massive
production their Latin America's got a
lot of talking right now everyone's
really interested in Latin America
Colombia by far has been the country
most people have been discussing but we
know that when it comes to some products
it's not about producing there and
shipping to other countries but like
there's a lot of patients that need
medicine there but with Mexico and
Colombia with all this talk compared to
what
actually real it's not as real as most
people would think so we're thinking on
a lot of those markets on like starting
them but not doubling down for world
production you know Columbia
specifically amazing for flour exports
with all the licenses though many
companies got the license for analytical
testing which then it didn't work really
well for Volkswagen like testing their
own cars and saying that they were good
and if you guys remember
sorry Germany it's the same thing in
Colombia a lot of companies got that
license it's fine to do in-house testing
but don't do your own certifying
Authority you're voided from UN compacts
like if you do that it's a conflict of
interest what I really care about are
the non psychoactive licenses for mass
outdoor production for bulk oils and
then shipping to other countries the
psychoactivity side like the EU's
already said like if it's not from
indoor or greenhouse or GMP for the oils
those things can't be imported so 90
percent of the Colombian investment
plays and strategies are not going to
work and the Canadians ruined Colombia a
little bit by bringing most of their
indoor varieties down to Colombia to
grow outside that we're doing great and
warehouses in Canada Colombia is a
little different to grow plants outside
so I think Colombia is gonna be major
for a few companies that do it right but
there's so much speculation there that I
haven't made major investments there as
of now Africa's kind of unfortunately
been a show I'm sorry for the
language South Africa had the best
program moving forward their government
went on strikes APRA the medicines
agency there just got out of strike
there's 21 licenses that were applied
for one was disqualified and they now
have a moratorium against new license
applications clinical research in South
Africa will be incredible especially
with the aids rate and what we'll be
able to see with clinical trials there
with cannabis and with AIDS research
lassoo 2 also has like a bonafide
program the Canadians also destroyed
that by coming and doing lots of plays
but Swaziland Zimbabwe issued those 37
licenses if anyone's been dissing Bob
Wayne knows that program it's not also
going to be a world leader it sounds
good on a press release but when it gets
to boots on the ground it's not a real
program but I think South Africa will be
the most bonafide program within 12 to
18 months in South Africa which I
already have applied for a license there
as well
Asia's been challenging like you had the
first hemp licenses in India like bang
like the source getting to where
cannabis is from in this in this area
unfortunately all I see from like
Philippines from Thailand from South
Korea it's all about import I mean right
now Vanuatu and some of these other
countries want to have these programs
but they're just not creating the
programs in a way that's compliant
internationally so and I look at these
markets
I think import markets highest standards
lowest costs getting medicine to the
people who need it but I still have yet
to see a major bonafide investment
strategy here and Australia has had such
a challenging program as well that
they've been around for a while in a
huge hemp industry but they also other
than partnering with a few Canadians or
Israelis haven't through their program
laws really been able to take huge
international market share as of now and
remember from that risk Graham like
Australia's only two troops every time
so it's like you could put all your
resources there but you're gonna get
stuck in that little corner and that's
hard to get back out if you guys
remember that game so you know I'm
almost done here but just thinking of
like we've been talking about this in
doing this for over a decade and there's
all these new people or people that are
observing this and thinking maybe I'll
get in now or maybe on best a little bit
into like some public companies to try
to get your feet wet but when you're
trying to like navigate this risk and
understand what's happening you have to
choose like where you're going to put
your capital and when because time is
the one thing that we don't have more of
and like opportunity cost you put your
time your capital into a market it
doesn't go anywhere you get distracted
not every investment works not every
country works not every program works
and I've even seen great companies not
scale into unicorns because of some
internal things or things outside of
their control so diversify your
strategies be in multiple places and
know how if you're investing into one
company what service is what products
what things do they need and how do you
invest in a way to create like circular
value versus just like oh this sounds
good I'm gonna put money into it if it's
not legal if it's not real you're not
gonna make anything from it but we have
to do it everything making medicine for
like our sick grandparents so like if
it's not a good company that thinks
about patients first safe affordable
medicine an alternative to
pharmaceutical like drugs it's not a
good investment because money is one
thing but like what do you do with money
it's like bullets in a gun it you could
have
houses full of bullets but if it's not
on the battlefield at the right time it
doesn't matter and that's where we like
help investors to get their bullets like
onto the battlefield to make impact in
profit and get medicine to patients who
need it which is the reason we're all in
this room today and always have to
remember what you do matters we're
creating an industry to give to future
generations so if you're not comfortable
with the products your investments are
making if you're sick grandma couldn't
have those products don't do it because
this is more of a responsibility of
investment and what we do than just a
big money opportunity but there's enough
money for everyone to make this will be
larger than tobacco alcohol we're gonna
take major market share from
pharmaceuticals and you want to get into
this now in five years
your capital but will be like a cent one
euro cent compared to like a 500 euro
note for what it could have done for you
perfect any time for cue later
perfect thanks everyone very much for
letting me share VP sleep is so
important thank you very much the man
knows his potatoes I'm sorry we don't
have time forces are running a little
late I'm trying to speed everything up a
little bit