my name is David Wenger I'm here with
Karina Ilana Koski John Conroy and
Francis Conlon Scanlon I'm gonna
introduce the panel and then we're gonna
try to cover a few areas first we'll
start with the US regulatory situation
for cannabis and then Karina will cover
the Canadian Carina along with John will
cover the Canadian landscape and Francis
will talk to Europe first I'll introduce
my fellow panelists so starting at the
end is Francis Conlon the managing
director and founder of cloud 9
that's a Switzerland based manufacturer
and producer of compliant hemp derived
chocolate products Anthony John Conroy
is QC from Vancouver deeply involved in
the Canadian cannabis industry Corino
anakov ski is a VP of quality and
regulatory for cannabis compliance Inc
it's a global they're a global
regulatory compliance firm that provides
end-to-end business solutions for
cannabis companies David Winger I'm a
longtime investor in the cannabis
industry I started investing in Canada
in 2016 and then in the US and 2017 my
background is as a lawyer I spent most
of my career at DLA Piper in New York
it's a daily pepper is a global law firm
I wrote a white paper in last year
called the green regulatory arbitrage a
case for investing in u.s. multi-state
vertically integrated cannabis companies
that was read all around the world
including in Congress and got me invited
and I'm part of the US Senate and the US
House of Representatives
cannabis working groups so I'm in DC
twice a month working with senior
congressional staffers on drafting and
advancing a federal cannabis legislation
in the United States we're missing today
Lea Hesse who was the chief who is the
chief compliance officer in chief
experience officer at forefront she's
not here so I'm gonna cover the US side
of things in her place so the rest of
this panel is going to be a QA but we'll
just start off with a overview of the US
landscape first and I'll address that
and then we'll move on to Canada and
Switzerland and Europe in the United
States we are seeing historic progress
on cannabis legislation it's
unprecedented what is occurring on a
federal level and state by state level
we're in the hundred and fifteen
Congress that concluded in January there
were some 60 measures to legalize
cannabis federally in the United States
that is more than all previous
congresses combined in the u.s. last
year there were about 900 bills filed
across the United States and various
states to legalize cannabis in various
states for the entire 2018 just half way
through March of 2019 there are more
than 1200 bills filed in states across
the United States to legalize cannabis
in this Congress there is already
pending legislation covering every
single aspect of legalization what is
advancing right now is a safe banking
act just passed through the House
Financial Services Committee it's going
to move on to the full house it's fully
expected to pass a house and there's a
good chance it will pass the Senate too
along with banking we're going to see a
lot of major catalysts in the next six
months including a protection for
research of cannabis protections for
veterans for federal employees using
cannabis we're gonna see major progress
oh and I think leading to legalization
within 12 to 18 months in the United
States we're at a point now where
there's a snowball rolling down a hill
that started an avalanche and it's just
a question of how long it will take for
that snowball to pick up enough momentum
but the momentum cannot be reversed
there are congressional cannabis
co-chairs working hard in the house and
in the Senate
there are meanings and full time and
people working full time in Congress to
legalize cannabis on the state side we
have ten states that have adult use
legalized along with Washington DC
thirty-three medical states New York and
New Jersey are racing forward towards
legalization New Jersey hit a little bit
of a hiccup a few weeks we could go but
I think that this time next year
cannabis will be sold in New York
probably New Jersey or will be well on
the way towards selling cannabis on the
East Coast in those major states and
Michigan just legalized cannabis
Illinois is about to legalize cannabis
too we have now most of the West Coast
with legal cannabis once those middle
states some of in the Midwest of
Illinois and Michigan legalize and one
one one East Coast states legalizes like
New York like New Jersey like
Connecticut or Pennsylvania all the
others will legalize at the same time or
very quickly thereafter so at that point
Congress will be forced to act you have
the West the Midwest and the East Coast
so we're moving very quickly towards
legalization I'm just gonna address so
far the farm bill and hemp for a little
bit because there's a lot of interest in
hemp hemp CBD products from mainstream
companies not just cannabis companies
there are now large CPG companies
looking at our industry and looking at
hemp products in the US as an initial
entry point so the farm bill passed at
the end of 2018 moved the hemp product
off of the Controlled Substances Act
hemp is no longer a drug it's now an
agricultural product no longer under the
authority of the DEA the Department of
the Drug Enforcement Agency it's now
under the FDA FDA's authority the Food
and Drug Administration the FDA has
stepped in and said hang on hemp is
federally legal but we still have
authority over food and over making
health claims so the FDA has said three
has put out three pieces of clar
guidance so far you can't add
hemp or or CBD from hemp to food you
can't market or sell hemp as a dietary
supplement and you can't make disease or
therapeutic claims relating to hemp or
CBD derived from hemp but part of the
complication is that the FDA has
licensed drugs containing CBD and THC
but CBD in epidemics once something is a
drug it can no longer be added to a food
it can't be sold as a dietary supplement
but with the hemp derive CBD my my
prediction is that the FDA realizes that
this is a product unlike anything else
we've encountered it's both medicinal
it's used for wellness it's kind of goes
across the spectrum especially for
cannabis so the FDA realizes there is
trennis demand for this product it can't
be a toothless tiger it can't just issue
regulations that people won't follow
there are thousands of companies selling
CBD food products in the United States
so the FDA is gonna come out with
regulations that reflect the fact that
there is no real downside demonstrated
to CBD just an upside and I think
they'll find a issue new regulations
that will allow CBD to take the form of
to be in a medicine in a drug and make
specific disease claims if it goes
through trials they'll also be I think
the dietary supplement route there'll be
an OTC route and there'll be a GI Ras
route for food products so unprecedented
but I think the FDA is gonna figure it
out and let's move on to Canada so
Canada legalized cannabis federally the
I think that's a major step towards the
whole world legalizing the US will come
next and I think after that Europe will
quickly follow so let's so look at
Canada as a test case so to speak for
recreational and medicine medicinal use
so let's start with the differences
between medical and adult use cannabis
in Canada and Carina you want to take
that first absolutely yes we are
definitely a test case in the world is
watching on October 17 2018 we legalized
recreational cannabis well we had a long
time that we had already
medical cannabis in terms of the
cultivation and processing of the
products there really is no difference
Health Canada requires them to be
manufactured under good production
practices the main difference lies on
how the products are distributed so if
you're a medical patient you will
register your prescription with a
license holder and have that product
delivered to you directly from that
license holder the license holder can be
anywhere in Canada where as recreational
product is distributed by our provinces
and each province has its own model it
can be private based model or it can be
a provincial II run store any adult over
the age of majority or the age of the
province has decided can access
recreational cannabis John do I wanna
add that yes recreational use of
cannabis does not involve any
constitutional rights in Canada that was
established in the case I was involved
in in 2003 in the Supreme Court of
Canada we started in 1995 rec medical on
the other hand it was a case called
Parker dr. Mutulu mentioned epilepsy mr.
Parker had epilepsy tried everything
with his doctor nothing worked told his
doctor that he took a couple of puffs
that would stop his seizure and so we
established that a medically approved
patient has a right of reasonable access
to his medicine in order to prevent the
violation of his constitutional rights
to the security of his person and the
right not to have that taken away
arbitrarily essentially was the the
bottom line and that was back in 2001
which led to our medical marijuana
access regulations eventually to the
marijuana for medical purposes
regulations where the new government was
trying to take away the right to grow
for yourself or have somebody grow for
you and ultimately in a more recent case
called Allard we established that that
was unconstitutional what they were
trying to do and to make a long story
short we've now evolved into from the
access to cannabis for medical purposes
regulations to part 14
the Cannabis act the big defect however
is that while the provinces get to
distribute cannabis in retail stores and
recreational purposes there are no
equivalent Medical dispensaries or
compassion clubs they exist and they
have existed since at least 1997 in
British Columbia but the government has
not provided for that for medical
patients and there's a huge difference
between medical patients and their
access and recreational that issue we
are still currently litigating in
Vancouver and it's in the Court of
Appeal so time will tell and hopefully
we'll establish that having the ability
to go to a medical dispensary will be
part of the patients reasonable access
and thanks John
quickly our extracts extracted products
legal on the adult youths market in
Canada today not yet not currently about
edible well edibles extracts and
topicals are subject to consultations at
the moment in order to they're going to
be regulated as of October of this year
one year from the date of legalizing rec
the problem is they're going to limit
the amount of THC to I think it's 10
milligrams in the edibles and the
extract one of my clients and a lard is
a 25 gram a day approved medical patient
who was brain damaged and who's now off
all of his opiates and only on cannabis
he would have to buy 2,500 packages from
the store in order to get his supply so
he would probably get sick from the
sugar in the edibles
so there really aren't you know they're
simply going to encourage the
underground market to continue because
people novice users may need small
amounts but there are established
medical users who will not overdose or
take too much or so there won't be
suffered there won't be separate
regulations for medical users the
medical or a dabbles and extract there
no they currently they don't plan to do
that
that's something that we will be pushing
for what about importing and exporting
cannabis to and from Canada so import
into Canada right now has allowed for
medical scientific purposes and export
is permitted so in both cases you need
to have the correct import-export
permits and the correct licenses on both
sides of the border where you're
importing and John what about for hemp
can you can you import and export hemp
and extracted cabinets from him yes it's
the limitation as I understand it is you
can only import or export and you need a
permit for each importer export for
scientific medical or industrial hemp
purposes so there is provision for
import/export of industrial hemp and
there's some technical stuff to do with
very minor amounts of THC which make it
easier to import export but generally
the same rules apply and the same for a
CBD I thought from hemp would that yeah
my understanding would be the same hey
you know what what are the kind of
highlights and maybe mistakes or things
that could have gone better
in Canada's rollout of adult youth
legalization I think one of the
highlights is seeing the market really
expand historically we've been limited
by a few large players in cannabis and
now that the licensing is picking up
there's a lot more opportunities for new
players to bring in their bring in their
products bring in their brands also with
October 17th legalization they opened up
what companies are now allowed to
declare new genetics into the system
which is very important for
diversification of products in terms of
areas for improvement definitely I think
the advertising and labeling
restrictions need to be critically
assessed if you know Health Canada has
said that one of their objectives is to
eliminate the black market but if you
can't build a brand that's going to be
very challenging for businesses one of
the things that I think that I thought
was true Justin Trudeau Prime Minister
Trudeau was most effective in convincing
people that adult use would be a good
for Canada actually was a high rate of
teen of teen usage in Canada and the
fact that legalization regular
eliminates or reduces the black market
how has that actually played out it's
still very very early certainly it is
another one of Health Canada's policy
objectives is to keep it out of the
hands of youth I have a 14 year old it's
also one of my objectives but it's still
very very early I mean the market still
has supply limitations and it's going to
be a few years before we actually
realize those objectives John what do
you take away from Canada it's a
legalization for adult use highlights
things that could have gone better the
effect on you thought usage well
currently the underground market
continues to thrive there's lots of
complaints about product quality the
good thing was the announcement that
they have micro producers in micro
processors to bring in the craft
industry unfortunately the cost of
trying to do that has become prohibitive
and so we don't have all of a sudden
many microbes that have been approved so
we're not doing well and bringing in the
smaller producers who have been part of
the market my biggest criticism is that
Canada has tried to create a new market
instead of bringing everybody in rolling
everybody in as we did for alcohol years
ago with the Kennedys and the brothels
and the Seagrams why not roll them in
regulate them give them licenses in that
way we could continue the existing
industry Karina I was on Canada gonna
compete globally
when cannabis can be grown for much much
cheaper in South America and Africa and
the US and California is where many many
global brands come from agree we have
work to do and we do have a first mover
advantage so I think that by using our
homegrown talent as well as the research
that's taking off now in Canada I think
those are advantages for us certainly
growing outside in Canada is not as good
as growing outside in Colombia but we do
have a lot of talent in our industry to
bring that to the world
god I just think we you need to
understand that
Canada has legalized a little bit you
can grow four plants per household and
they were going to make it it had to be
a hundred centimeters and no more but I
think they realized that the police
would then have to have tape measures on
their belts and that the plant might
suddenly sprout between Friday and
Monday but so they abandoned that at
least but you can possess 30 grams in
you're out and about so that's the
that's the legalization if you breach
the act and go slightly over say five or
six plants or 50 grams or whatever
there's a ticketing scheme that's what
we call decriminalization with a maximum
fine I think it's $200 something like
that but if you go above that there's
still a lot of criminal law Canada's
legislation that they're constitutional
power they've used the still the
criminal law and they've simply given
the provinces the permission to do the
the retail distribution and so when
you're above the ticketing scheme we
have still the summary and indictable
offences you probably understand better
if I use the u.s. misdemeanor for
summary and felony for indictable and
the maximum penalties on indictment in
Canada is still 14 years imprisonment
which the Conservative government jacked
up from seven years and the latane
Commission back in 1972 recommended a
max of five years so that has all kinds
of legal consequences in terms of the
continued use of the criminal law so
that's the the Canadian model it's not I
mean I think a lot of it's smoke and
mirrors in order to pacify the right
wing and I'll be surprised to see people
getting busted for those sorts of
indictable offences but that is the
landscape and so there's going to be a
lot to watch as we roll along do you
want to talk about the single convention
we didn't rehearse this but do you want
to address that all I can address that
people need to understand that unlike
the US where I think when you pass a
treaty it becomes part of the law of the
land that's not the case in Canada in
Canada we have to pass domestic
legislation in order to implement a
treaty and when Canada implemented the
treaty and passed the Controlled Drugs
and Substances Act
that's the current Act we expressly
provided that the Minister could make
exemptions to the act in relation to a
drug type of drug classes of persons and
so on so we reserved the ability to do
what we're doing so sorry for
interrupting so in Canada basically
you've been able to legalize
notwithstanding your participation it is
a little bit right not technically in
agreement with the international
cheating we signed but we're in
compliance with our law understood right
in the in the u.s. some that's one of
the issues that they're grappling with
in Congress it's an international treaty
called a single convention that would
prevent the United States from
effectively complying with the treaty
and federally legalizing cannabis for
European countries it's a big deal too I
think that the just like in Canada the
US will find a way around it and at that
point it's going to cause I think the
rest of the world to follow suit let's
move to Europe Francis and you show me a
picture of your finest with chocolate
which I and one thing that struck me was
that your packaging was very very clever
to comply with the legal landscape that
you have to navigate so can you just
give us an overview of what is the
status of hemp derived products um in
Switzerland and EU more more broadly
okay this should be entitled navigating
a minefield because it's a really
complicated topic you know up until 2018
it was already a very difficult subject
because in the different countries and
you have a lot of fragmentation in terms
of how the regulations are interpreted
by the authorities but things became a
way more confusing in January because
the European Commission decided to
update what's called a novel food
catalog and if you're familiar with the
novel food regulation it's it's a
regulation that dated
dates from Maine 1997 at that time the
the European Commission decided to enact
this regulation in order to protect
public health so the spirit of the
regulation is actually to to ensure that
food operators they continue to innovate
or win it within a framework which
allows for an approval process of
anything that would be considered novel
that means not eaten prior to May 1997
and also to to give guidance so to
operators and to regulators
so in January what happened was that in
the in the catalog you can google it you
can go onto the the novel foods catalog
it's very simple and you can type in
cannabis and you will come up with
actually three entries at the moment one
has been cancelled and that was kind of
video the other one is kind of a sativa
L and then they created a new one called
cannabinoids now up until the 20th of
January of this year we only had two we
only had one which was kind of a sativa
L and cannabadiol
so under cannabis sativa L it was a
wonderful green tick meaning that it
could be used in a food product okay
because it's been used for centuries in
Europe it's not novel it's not
considered novel the plant all right but
it also depends on the part of the plant
whether you're talking about the seeds
the flower the leaves and this all is
interpreted differently in different
legislations as well because the bottom
line with the novel food regulation is
that the European Commission also defers
to the individual country in terms of
their own specific regulations so then
you can have these torques and tweaks in
the application of that right so it's
very confusing and you really need to
know the regulations
you want to say go on and you're
packaging iuu cleverly intimate that
there is CBD because you're getting a
full spectrum M
product without saying there is CBD in
it which I thought was a clever solution
what about because in a full spectrum
hemp back you know product you have CBD
it's natural right right and but I don't
say CBD I can't say CBD if you say and
this is why you see what's happening
since probably the last since November
December in a lot of countries in Europe
like Austria they started removing a lot
of products from the market from the
shelves in Italy that took place as well
cannabis stores were getting fines so
it's kind of like the regulator's
suddenly woke up you know because they
they enacted a new novel food regulation
from January 2018 replacing the 97
regulation and it was like it there was
a delayed effect because it was at the
end of 2018 the different countries in
Europe started to actively remove
products and sent warning letters to
operators to remove their products but
don't you think though it's really just
a matter of time because if we talk
about something like alcohol or even
pharmaceutical products the regulators
are struggling with the advantages and
the disadvantages the side effects the
bad effects right yeah here we have a
product without there are some minor
example situations and certain people
have certain problems maybe can't have
too much CBD but in general terms there
is not really recognized downside to
that right so no and you saw what what
happened at the United Nations with the
w-h-o with the expert committee and
drugs independence last year so there
was a lot of good news around CBD there
was two sessions last year the 40th and
41st sessions in the 40th session they
actually made a recommendation that CBD
and also cannabis extracts should be
deleted from the schedule one of the
1961 single convention of narcotics
right and then in another session I
think it was October November October
and they're not I was I tend to both of
them as a guest yeah and in the second
one then they talked about THC and they
talked about analogs of THC in that and
then you saw that there
commendations were published in January
24th there was the letter they sent a
letter to the Secretary General of the
United Nation with the recommendations
to delist these products from vista
scheduling and on the 7th of march that
was supposed to be a vote that it was
postponed by the commission on our
narcotic drugs in vienna so that's still
pending I mean it's good news and it
will give a very good positive sign to
all the different countries that have
signed up to that convention but but I
think we're still you know it has to be
translated into you know legislation
I mean legislation and regulation is
important and safeguarding all these
products making the keeping the public
safe is of course a prime importance but
in the United States we have cannabis
cannabis edibles for years and years in
markets and nothing has ever happened to
anyone I mean no one has died from
having a cannabis edibles some people go
to the hospital maybe from having way
too much THC and ER doctors say that
they just tell them to go to sleep and
so it's not we're not dealing with a
very dangerous situation I think and the
regulators will just have to wrap their
hands heads around all it and recognize
that the market demand is there and they
have to meet that demand did you want to
add something John just I'm always
entertained by Health Canada has on its
webpage information for health care
practitioners supervise doctors what to
do so there's a section at the very end
of that that talks about overdose and
toxicity and of course the first line is
there's no lethal dose and the second
one is is that yes some people get panic
attacks and anxiety and in those rare
cases doctor when you see something like
that you sit the person diet down and
quietly assured them that everything's
going to be okay and maybe in a rare
case give them a benzodiazepine and I'm
not sure that's a good advice anymore
what we were learning about benzos so I
think we covered a lot of ground this
industry and it is the title of my white
paper from an investor's perspective
this is a regulatory arbitrage from a
business operators perspective your
as Francis said navigating a regulatory
minefield but I think if you're looking
at this from an investor's perspective
there's a lot of mismatch of value in
this industry there's regulatory risk
and overhang that suppresses valuations
especially in the United States right
where we have robust state legal
economies but federal illegality which
causes a wall to institutional capital
to big related industry companies to
enter the industry to things like
sovereign wealth funds and pension funds
in the Church of England can't can't
invest in the United States cannabis and
also in the industry has enormous
burdens like paying 80 to 90 percent
marginal tax rates because it can't
deduct the cost of goods sold we can't
do research you can't of interstate
commerce still hard to attract top
professionals all these barriers will
come crashing down with federal
legalization so if anybody is looking at
the investment landscape I think look at
it from the regulatory lens because
that's where you'll find our bajaj
opportunities where things are not
valued at where they would be if this
was a regular industry and it will be
one day but but if you wait till then
you might as well just invest in our
restaurant or any other industry right
now there's a lot of opportunity here
that regulations are creating is also a
bit can I add one more thing on the
European situation just just to finish -
yeah we spent a lot of time on North
America so yeah we're in Berlin so I
really touched on just one or two things
but just to finish on the European
situation at the moment because of what
happened in January with the changes in
the novel Foods catalog in March the
European industrial hemp Association
they met with the working group of the
Standing Committee of whatsit now plants
animals food and feed and this is the
group of
experts basically that the European
Commission deferred to in terms of their
approval process in signing off
approving or not approving anything
related to novel foods it was an
important meeting because the hemp
Association were able to put before this
committee good reasons and actually
showed 14 different examples of how hemp
had already been consumed in Europe
since they that the oldest example they
show it was from a tour in Bologna an
old tower from 1220 and it was a
wonderful inscription on the walls
because they the inscription said bread
is life cannabis protects ya and
protects in the sense of homeostasis
bringing equilibrium to the body and
then the one I like wine is joy alright
that that's how they they wrote it on
12:20 because there's a huge history of
the consumption of hemp in in Europe
even though even Pope Martin v was was
eating hemp soup you know so there's a
there's a lot of good arguments they
they made their case I think they did a
very good job and and if there's anybody
from the EHA in the room hats off to
them I think it was great because they
they're really trying to clarify this
gray area between what's medical and
what's recreational you know because
there's this whole area of relating to
cosmetics relating to food food
supplements also a construction and
industrial uses of hemp and they're
they're really pushing to to to to have
clear regulations on that the last thing
that's happened just recently on the
22nd of March so just a few days ago an
MEP from Italy called Marcos ulla he
made a written question because a
politician or a political party or a
political organization in Europe has the
right to make a what's called a written
question has to be a written question to
the European Commission and it was a
very great question because with all
this confusion going on he clearly
stated he clearly asked a commission so
are you going to come out with
legislation regarding the area of food
and
cosmetics right really peas put that
he's put their back up against the wall
with the request to answer that question
in six weeks and if you mentioned that
practice of a bunch of Congress men and
women also bipartisan basis sent a
letter to the FDA Commissioner same
exact letter two weeks ago well my dear
by the time of the next ICBC in zurich
that should correspond to when hopefully
we'll have an answer from the european
commission which will hopefully clarify
things so stay tuned so there it's a
moving target a lot of this a lot of
these topics and yeah as Francis said
it's rapidly changing what things will
look different a year from now let's
open it up to some questions yep okay of
course well we'll go this way and then
we'll go that way and we're coming
around here we go alright Genzo a
American attorney question about we
currently have state regimes wildly
disparate in how they enforce say
Massachusetts in Maine right next to
each other and completely different laws
on how you grow who can grow how much it
costs do you think when we have
congressional action and it's legal
everywhere that the states that haven't
legalized are gonna have an easier time
moving forward because they don't have
to undo all of the restrictive regimes
that are in place now under the current
proposed legislation that is most likely
to succeed it which is a states act or
some modified version of that the states
are gonna still be left to regulate what
happens in their own states I mean we
see that in many other industries right
just if you want to become a barber in
New York State it's different than
becoming a barber in another state it's
just a little different and every state
has their own regulations I think we're
gonna see that with cannabis to I think
it might be some time before
cannabis is sold in Mississippi or
Alabama but it's just their loss I think
but but every state is gonna proceed
differently and they'll have their own
regulations now cultivation though it's
going to change once there's interstate
commerce so it's naturally going to have
an effect on the realities within each
state but I think the in the u.s. we
have a strong state powers states are
assigned a high degree of powers versus
the federal government and they're gonna
continue to be able to assert their
authority over cannabis for sure there's
a little bit of parallel with Canada and
the EU because the states are gonna have
to be careful that they do have a
standard quality management requirement
for the product otherwise they're going
to create more trade yeah one of the
things we're struggling with in the
United States is that it's on a
state-by-state basis now to regulate
things like cannabis in food and states
are not equipped they don't have health
departments that are capable of
regulating food products the FDA
regulates food products for the United
States and states are looking to the FDA
for guidance but the FDA is not
regulating cannabis so once there is
federal legalization I think there will
be a much more unified situation in the
United States but despite that states
can go off and do their own thing
despite on top of that there's a big
distinction to appreciate between Canada
and the US criminal law is federal in
Canada whereas it's state power in the
US and that's why if you go back and
look at history prohibition started in
Utah and crept across the country mainly
against the Mexicans and eventually
Canada made prohibited in 1923 and your
federal government didn't do it till
1937 now history is rolling back the
other way and we've legalized so we
expect your federal government to do it
in the next 12 months
but but it actually is the federal
criminal law in the United States that
is that impedes the industry right the
Schedule one status which makes it a
crime right to to engage in commerce
with with cannabis is what makes it a
federal crime so we have state criminal
legislation but also federal crimes for
being involved in inter
the commerce related to cannabis and
other questions here Oh YUM okay free
cannabis hemp in Avalon Glastonbury my
question relates to the food regulations
novelty foods and novel ways of getting
around it wipers I've been selling CBD
Pro it's about five years now one in
first and Britain I think and since
January what I've been doing is selling
banks are unbeaten Sindhu temple incense
with the disclaimer but legally this
product is not for use by the person the
person is the legal fiction and that's
the awareness is happening in Britain
now is people becoming aware of the
fraud or the name the fiction and all
the criminality of prohibition my
question relates to is their movement
within Europe who are people have had
enough of the actual blatant crime of
cannabis prohibition and we all have an
essential need for this plant so any
legislation prohibiting that must be
criminal its anti human and is there
movement in well worldwide to actually
people being empowered to just get on
with it
grow the plant and share it within their
communities you're touching on the whole
topic of hypocrisy yeah and and I can't
give you a straight answer because it
still is that situation unfortunately
there's a mass uprising that's right and
that's why I think you said like it
can't be stopped it's a way that's
moving forward can't be stopped it's a
wonderful thing it's fantastic it's
amazing well we've seen what we've seen
in the US ultimately is is that business
and tax revenues are what is moving the
conversation forward this is ultimately
about individual liberty and about
people being able to use whatever
medicine or whatever makes them feel
good but ultimately what is driving
politicians who might otherwise not be
convinced is the dollars right so that's
what causes political progress to be
made that's the reality I've been
involved in this since 1972 so it can't
happen quickly enough
sorry I'm coming here ago if you do like
another eyes and realize you're from
Berlin
as much as I understand that there's an
outcry in the industry about CVD entry
and then the novel food cutter look but
if CVD and hemp products are food then
they automatically fall on the food
revelation that was not made to legalize
CBD it had nothing to do with it
so CVD extracts are now treated like any
other plant extract like rosemary oil
are a protein extract so it's for me
it's completely plausible that the
moment you enrich and isolate something
you fall on the regular food regulation
exactly how it should be yeah
in the u.s. we have a complication
though where CBD has been approved as a
drug so you can't add drugs to food yeah
look at the marketing claims there is
another issue coming
but for me it's completely logical that
the next rackets
as food has to be treated like any other
extract sorry yeah it's either it's
either medical or food in Europe it's
very clear-cut between the two there's
no with this grey zone for sure because
a lot of operators don't know where to
go but there it's that's the way the
regulator looks at it signed their
medical or food one or the other okay
but if a big pharmaceutical company gets
a patent for CBD to be in a drug product
that means that you won't be able to
have it in a food anymore but if I have
I'm using a full-spectrum hemp and it's
naturally present right yeah the
question I think was directly related to
CBD right you know isolate no there's
any extra I remember I I you know the
beginning of my little journey over a
year and a half ago I went to my
regulator I went to my local regulator
and I went to the controlling laboratory
and I said so I want to do this I want
to make chocolate help me what do I need
to comply with and there and they said
well basically there's three main things
one the plant has to be
EU any use from the use certified hemp
meaning that it has to be one of the
hemp right
under the common registry in the EU is
69 at the moment - it's got to be a
traditional processing technique so very
very specifically you can't add CBD to
it or take it away you can't manipulate
it it has to reflect what's extracted
front naturally from the plant okay and
three no THC no THC is zero in Europe in
Switzerland is one percent Swiss insula
is an outlier you know Switzer's pioneer
when it comes to a lot of things but but
zero also depends on the country you
know because you have some some people
say oh my analytical technique goes down
to zero point zero zero zero something
that's my zero or in another country at
0.3 or 0.5 or 0.6 and that's where the
headaches start because if you're an
operator and you're producing a Swiss
chocolate like I am I mean I do other
things too because I suck like you've
got farmers but you know and you want to
make a product that's compliant for the
whole of the EU that's tricky
yeah that's tricky you have to be very
careful Canada the limit is 0.3 percent
THC which i think is the same in the US
and there's no limits on cannabidiol or
other cannabinoids in the hemp but it's
because it's not a controlled substance
CBD yeah it never was well we have
industrial hemp regulations and
historically that really allowed you to
make hemp hearts and really nothing much
else until these regulations were put
under the cannabis Act and those
limitations don't exist anymore and
there are specific exemptions if your
hemp product is made from the seed and
is less than 10 micrograms of THC
that's not governed by the act other
than requirements of what you put on the
label when you're importing or exporting
fantastic we have time for one more
brief question and then we're gonna I'm
sorry you guys I got it back here but
I'm sure they'll be they'd love to talk
to you in the hallway here one last
question hi Mike Coogan from the United
States thank you all could you elaborate
on the disparity between the Single
Convention and US federal law and what
might be done to sort of reconcile those
two regulatory frameworks thank you
so right now I don't think there's a
there's a disparity I think if the US
would legalize cannabis which is one of
the drugs that's included in the Single
Convention then there would be a
disparity and I think that it would
require the u.s. probably to withdraw
from it or get the treaty amended
because the treaties are that the u.s.
signs on to become part of US federal
law basically so something will have to
be done but the US has dealt with more
complicated international treaty
obligations than that and there are ways
for the Congress to address that um
senator Schatz from Hawaii is
particularly focused on this I can
connect you with him if you want to take
this take up this issue further thank
you all so very much I'm sorry that
we're out of time
one more time for our excellent panel
was an excellent overview we really
appreciate your time and your energy and
your thoughts and your discussion