[Music]
well ICBC is all business right here
it's about networking and organizing a
complete new market this is a group of
potential entrepreneurs money is going
to be involved very very quickly
probably a good many of them are going
to do very well financially from
cannabis legal for for medical use and
eventually for recreational use here in
Germany it's very exciting to see such a
large market open up for cannabis
especially you know really leading the
way for the rest of the EU this is
global this is prohibition coming off
it's exciting to be the cusp of a new
exciting industry if you look around
here everyone's excited to be here you
know so it's it's very exciting to be a
part of that and to help educate people
about us and about the industry and
about where we see it going my idea that
we have a totally different approach to
addiction in general not only cannabis
that we really see it as an illness and
not something criminal and very
optimistic that we get this in five or
ten years I think the key to this is
just to try and do keep people try to
get experts from countries where this
has already been on the market for years
for example we are quite new to the
cannabis scene and for us it's a great
way to connect with people and to find
new business opportunities because the
scene is growing and growing but still
quite small and
just a great way to get to know everyone
[Music]
whenever I speak at one of these
conferences I begged these people when
they open their shop to be encyclopedias
of information on cannabis the nice
little old lady comes in from the
grocery shopping into the cannabis shop
her hands hurt she could no longer knit
here's a brochure
about what a cannabinoid could do for
your arthritis if you want to explore
that more come back and see us
[Music]
[Applause]