[Music]
[Applause]
this is international business companies
and many people who came here kind of
took a chance bought a ticket wasn't
sure what to expect right and the
feedback I'm getting is I can't believe
this I didn't know what was going to be
this good what they mean by good is
information and networking and just a
gentle attitude of the people here and I
believe in karma
I believe in community I believe in love
and understanding and I actually believe
if you hold true to some of those tenets
and precepts that you're only going to
benefit yourself for so many reasons and
in my case it's actually helped me make
money also so it's it's no win-win
situation that's happening with the
cannabis industry in particular and I
think that's what people are very
surprised about that that they can make
money they can be successful and no one
else has still to lose we just wrapped
it up here at the International cannabis
business conference in a fantastic time
Steve bloom from celeb stoner and
freedom leaf magazine was here Steve
DeAngelo was here
Ethan Adelman from the drug policy
Alliance gave an impassioned impassioned
speech about what we need to do if
people are actually overly excited and
happy that we have decided to dedicate
so much of this to culture politics and
advocacy and I'm tremendously happy with
the feedback
never doubt a small group of concerned
citizens can change the world
it is indeed the only thing that ever
has