[Music]
so what this conference is entails is a
marriage of activism and and business we
have an amazing crowd here the energy is
great we sold out of the Expo everyone's
really excited uh there's a real Buzz in
the
air
what we see here is that we have an
amazing mix of different people coming
from the US coming from uh Germany and
covering all different kind of aspects
of the new cannabis Market I think we
can really benefit from from the
experiences that different countries
have already with a medical cannabis I
have to actually pinch myself that we're
at a Cannabis Conference a global
Cannabis Conference in Germany is quite
amazing the Cannabis Market in Germany
is growing this industry in Germany has
the potential to be the second biggest
cannabis Market in the
world we've talked to a lot of people
from Berlin today in in a few short
hours and um they're asking the right
questions the questions are really about
what do you do how can I help you and
really it's about connection and
networking
[Music]
we have huge potential here in Berlin
and we have many creative and talented
people who have already established a
very vibrant startup ecosystem I think
the longevity of what Berlin has to
offer is going to set Alex and set
Berlin up for um a great prosperous
future in
[Music]
cannabis