all right and now to discuss
international cannabis markets and
business opportunities uh leading this
panel
co-founders of s f abolos
please welcome guillermo fernandez
navarro thank you
hello hello
okay hello
hello
good morning to to everyone my name is
guillermo fernandez i'm a co-founder and
attorney at cf avocados
based in madrid
we've been working
on cannabis over than than 10 years
we are involved in any single cannabis
area
such as
medical cannabis cultivation licensing
hemp cbd products
cannabis clubs
criminal defense
i
want to say that it's amazing to see
this theater full of people again after
two years
talking about cannabis i want to say
thank to hcbc to
make for making this
even possible possible again i hope
everyone enjoy
so
let's
start with
this amazing panel we have today we want
to talk about a legal framework and
business opportunities
let me
introduce
our panelists
we have a chloe grossman
chloe is the executive director of
corporate growth at trulif
tulip is the biggest cannabis company in
us right now
also we have kai fredericks he's a
founder and lawyer at
kfn plus in berlin
and
we have juana basella she's a lawyer at
mme studies
so let's
have
them introduce themselves
chloe please
hello everyone i'm chloe grossman
executive director
of corporate growth at true leap
cannabis corp
so we're a multi-state operator in the
united states
so my job entails overseeing post-merger
and acquisition integration as well as
expansion into new markets
and one of the reasons i'm on this panel
is i have a long history of working in
the competitive licensing field in the
united states so happy to be here with
all of you
my name is kaif
and i'm a lawyer from germany i'm a
lawyer since 2003 and started to work in
the cannabis space in 2017 as germany
legalized medical cannabis i'm
consulting cbd companies hemp companies
medical import medical cannabis import
companies i'm also an advisor to iheart
of the european industrial hemp
association
which has setting up a noble food joint
application
and
yeah we are looking for legalization in
germany and that's one of my main focus
regulatory approvals so uh happy to be
here thank you
thank you as well guillermo for a kind
explanation introduction my name is
juana jonah zaya i'm here from
switzerland i'm a lawyer
specialized in
medical law that's why i'm here because
i want to speak about a medicinal
cannabis opportunities and as well i'm a
professor for business law i specialize
in health law in germany so i have like
two
point of views and a disclaimer as a
lawyer maybe we'll have
let's say a weird kind of view
on the market
okay great thank you thank you guys
so
let's start with the with the panel
let's talk first of all about licensing
process and legal framework
can you please chloe let us know how is
the situation in us or in the united
states
absolutely and the situation in the
united states is pretty unique so the
first thing to note is that at the
federal level cannabis is actually
not legal
it's considered a schedule one
controlled substance meaning it doesn't
have any recognized medicinal
use and also is considered to have high
potential for abuse
so but the the way that american law is
set up the division of state and federal
authority
gives states a lot of power over
writing their own laws within their own
boundaries so that has allowed states to
experiment with cannabis policy within
their um
within their borders so
they effectively decide whether to
regulate cannabis as well as how to
regulate cannabis and this has led to a
patchwork of state regulations so every
state is very different which i think is
important to understand
so the licensing structures and the
markets
the way that the markets are structured
are very intertwined in the us and i
think probably everywhere
and the dynamics between those two shape
the business opportunities as well as
the strategies that businesses use to
succeed in this market so we'll talk a
little bit about that
later
so
in terms of the ways that states differ
in structure and licensing process
there are some more restrictive states
which tend to have limited license
systems
um and those systems typically have
higher barriers to entry
um and are attractive for reasons that i
think we can all understand
many unlimited license states see
explosive growth and one of the things
that's really interesting about those
states is
you really see the innovation and the
excitement of a true capitalist
environment that's hyper competitive
there's also licensing both at the state
and local level sometimes both at the
same time in one market
so some states typically more
conservative ones choose not to give the
localities any control
whereas others like california actually
give a lot of control to the localities
and that creates a whole different
situation
so when the localities do have control
you tend to have longer licensing
processes
you can have higher costs and just
frankly more headaches
so that is something to watch out for if
you're looking at cannabis markets in
the united states
there are also four different licensing
processes
that i would categorize them into
so the first is
limited
or competitive licensing so
this is typical of limited licensed
markets
so again high barriers to entry
and it's kind of like a professional
battle royale for these coveted licenses
the second type is a lottery licensing
model so in that case
all companies that meet a set of minimum
standards are have their name thrown
into the hat so to speak and
are randomly selected to get licenses
so the purpose of that model is
basically to try to
even the playing field and also
cut down on bias in the license award
process
another different model is
just a straight minimum standards model
and this is very typical of unlimited
license markets so anybody who meets the
minimum standards is able to get a
license
and then finally this is a little bit
different but there's grandfathering of
existing operators so let's say a market
is going from medical to adult use
so
at that catalyst point the medical
operators are typically grandfathered in
or have some process for converting into
the new market so they kind of get first
right of entry
so
yeah i think those are the key points
and i will pass it back to you
okay thank you chloe just to add one
line more
when do you think we will
see a federal regulation
that is the billion dollar question
really it's hard to say we are seeing
support on
both sides of the aisle
at the federal level now i don't think
it will be you know within the next year
but we've been saying you know within
the next two years for quite a while now
so
it's anyone's guess but we are
definitely pushing behind the scenes for
that
thank you so much
so kai how is the situation in in german
a lot of people is excited about the
the latest news so please let us let us
know
sure
yes so germany had a federal election
last year in september
and
the parties especially the green party
and the liberals
they
declared or they said they want
legalization of cannabis
and the
social democratic party they were in
favor of model projects before that
beforehand
but it turned out in the coalition
negotiations that they really agreed on
a free market model on a legalization
with
dispensaries
and
that's yeah short passage in the in the
in the
coalition agreement
and
but
they say it's coming so
we have no problems
because
the
draft of the law will be dealt
the ministry of health is responsible is
in charge for this draft
and the ministry of health is also
responsible for corona and he is also
responsible for the health crisis coming
by the ukraine crisis so we have lots of
refugees we're expecting 10 million
refugees in europe
and
many people will come to germany as well
again and they have to integrate these
people into the health system so the
ministry of health is very very busy
and he is in charge of the draft because
it's
it's a health issue
we see that it's a harm reduction health
issue so the ministry of health is
supposed to deal with it
um
and
he said already carl alter there won't
be a draft this year so he will start
working with his ministry with this
house he will start working on the draft
uh early next year
so the debate is sort of in the off this
year
on on the legal nation side
and there are still some really problems
there's some some crucial problems we
have to solve especially the licensing
question
so there is a draft in place by the
green party the so-called cannabis
control act
they brought that to bundestag in 2017
the first time and last year the second
time
and this
draft for these
caps and minimum distances between
schools and
youth facilities
the minimum distances are no problem
but the caps the restrictions on maximum
numbers
for
dispensaries in a community that is a
real problem because when you issue a
license
and the authority uses or
exercises its discretion
how to pick
who to pick
and if you have
let's say
20 20
licenses you can give away in one
community but you have 200 interested
parties okay so the authority has to
make a decision
to pick
and if they didn't use their discretion
properly and your competitor says oh no
the authority make made to made a
mistake so they start a lawsuit a
competitor lawsuit
and then you may get your license and
start working and start selling and
start investing and after two years
the court says no you i will withdraw
your license because your competitor
won so that's going to be a big problem
and we will do all we can this year uh
to convince the lawmakers that there are
no need for four caps for from
maximum
number of restrictions
because there is no need they always say
we need restrictions on the on the
numbers
the the
[Music]
the scientists the
drug scientists and social
social
social workers are saying that but it
doesn't make it make sense so then you
have an unrestricted number of licenses
the advantage is you can start from day
one with enough dispensaries uh the you
can fight the illicit market really
effectively but there will of course be
a market checkout after two or three
years because of the oversupply but
that's what i think is is the better
option for for for germany to to choose
yeah and we will see how that will
unfold this year the debate um
everyone's saying it's coming from the
government but please be patient
we also demanded a
decriminalization in the in the first
step
but the coalition said no we want one
law we want one draft we want one
solution and not decriminalization
beforehand and then legalization because
that endangers the whole project
that's what they say but still courts
are still
judging they still law enforcement is
still working on cannabis cases are
still chasing after
consumers right now after cbd businesses
so we still have to do some advocating
this year and some lobbying this year
but i'm convinced it's it's coming
they're all saying all the
members who have the power in in the
coalition uh say that it's coming so
let's let's see
i know it's not gonna be
easy it's not gonna be fast but i really
hope that germany royally is cannabis
because that would be an amazing example
for the rest of uh countries in in
europe so
let us know juana how is
everything going in switzerland
very well you know swiss southern is
called european hub of cannabis
as you know and so the socio-relation of
cannabis differentiates between the
three different uses the industrial the
medical and the recreational use and
therefore three different
regulations i'm going to speak about and
at least i will speak about the latest
developments
and you have to know it's all about the
thc concentration and irrespective of
the cbd content
unlike
thc cbd in switzerland is not considered
as a narcotic so firstly let's have a
look on the
industrial use the swiss loss regarding
the industrial use
is very liberal as you know already so
the industrial cannabis that is less
than one percent i will speak always
about this limit one percent is not
legally a narcotic but is subject to the
regulation
how how it comes to the markets so if
it's
food cosmetics tobacco what else
chemicals and so on so the uses
permitted
are determined by these regulations food
cosmetics
liquids for tobaccos and so on if you
want some i can give later on the
questions
in the discussion detailed information
so the status for the industrial use
it is legal in switzerland as long as it
contains less than one percent
than
of thc
let's have a look on the medical use
the swiss law regarding the medicinal
cannabis is
let's say
surprisingly limited in comparison to
the industrial use so growing selling
important cannabis for medical uses or
medical purpose
is allowed however
there's a distinction between calibers
containing at least one
percent thc
and other cannabis
so we have to differentiate between the
cannabis at least one percent thc
and less than one percent tc
first of all cannabis containing at
least one percent dc is qualified as a
narcotic
but
it can be qualified as a medical product
it could be very interesting
for some of you
in this case the specific specific
medicinal product relation applies that
means the cannabis can only be grown
imported and sold for medical use if
permitted
permitted by the federal office
for the public
health it's permitted but you need a
permission
and the cannabis containing less than
one percent intended to be used for
medical purposes is subject to the
general just the normal let's say normal
regulation medicine products and by that
you can manufacture who say a marketing
and market
cannabis
now or in this days the patients have
access to authorized cannabis based
drugs only on medical prescription but
they have
access for cannabis containing at least
one percent thc
patients can apply via their positions
that permission
and
so we can have
uh
say or we can say
it's legal cannabis in switzerland is
legal
even though it contains more or at least
one percent thc
but you need an official permit and a
medical prescription but it's allowed
and
thirdly the recreational use maybe some
of you will be interested in that
so the at the adult recreational
cannabis use has been decriminalized in
switzerland
so cannabis
containing at least one percent
at least one percentage
in comparison to other european
countries a lot is qualified
as a narcotic
but
production
importation selling of cannabis
use is not allowed
but what's interesting the percep the
personal procession
of cannabis
with at least one percent
of fewer than 10 grams 10 grams is not
even subject to a fine
it's not allowed
but you
can have
at least or not
you can have
up to 10 grams
and you will not be fined
it's a very
swiss approach
so the status regarding the
recognition the use is it's illegal
if it contains at least one percent less
it's allowed but at least 10 percent
it's illegal but even though
um
you will
approach very low fines
um what would be very interesting is
speak about the latest developments
there are two
movements regarding firstly the
recreational use and
secondly the medical use
regarding recognition use in may 2021
the swiss government started a limited
10 years pilot program a pilot project
to study
the economic and the health impacts of
non-cannabis uses you remember the
medical use is allowed but now we have
the pilot project to have a look on
what happens with the non-medical
cannabis so again the swiss federal
office of public health issues
production permits to cannabis growers
to supply the program
and a
variety of thc and cbd thc and cbd
products will be
available to
the pilot participants
maybe somebody of you want to be a
volunteer
with this program because the
recreational cannabis pilot schemes are
requested by public or private
organizations
and they have to work together with
research
institutes
and i had a look on
the conditions
when you get or
how it's possible to get such a permit
what do you have to fulfill
the
programs they must have a specific
research goal
for example such as acquiring data so
acquiring data it's a very wide
ideas so what somebody of you would be
interested in
for example data on the social economic
effects on the cannabis legislation
and
the
pilot programs have to be limited that's
a problem maybe to a specific
municipality it may run for five years
but there's the opportunity to extend
and
what i thought it's very interesting
and the participants
are limited to
10 milligram thc per month
and the products cannot
in delay
in the law they say
they cannot
contain more than 20 percent
20 percent i think it's a lot and there
um
yeah some opportunities
for the market so produce producers are
held to strict quality standards
and they have to follow field tries that
conducted in 2020
and
they are allowed as i said before
volunteers participants
um
up to five thousand
five thousand so maybe some of you will
be joined or wanted to join
well um and there's another
late development regardless of medical
use as i said before
um switzerland
or the swiss government
plans to facilitate the access to
cannabis used treatments cannabis used
or based medicine
products for patients
and
in june 2020 two years ago
the federal council issued the draft
legislation and it has to
come enforce this summer so it's
very close that we will be offered with
new opportunities
and under the amended law
patients will be able to obtain cannabis
based treatments directly from doctors
they will no longer be
necessary to require an exceptional
permit by the authority
i can explain about
the medical youth program later
[Music]
just
in the end about the license
see
as i said before there's a national
program that opens opportunities for
growers producers and so on and
just the last year
the
federal office
already issued some licenses some it's
the so-called cannabis licensees but the
regulations environments
of the procedure are extremely high
but we could help to go through
among other things a safety concert a
safety concept and the quality
management
must be demonstrated
but you can fulfill i think in addition
experience in cultivation of cannabis
and the compliance with the gacp
guidelines gscp it means good
agriculture and collection practice and
the attention to
sustainability and
ecology
will pay off
and at last
it would be
easier
but it's not a condition that
it's
a cannabis product of swiss origin
[Music]
that complies with the swiss rules of
organic farming
so
if you want i can give you some detailed
information later especially i have a
checklist prepared
for
producers growers
they have the interest to go into the
swiss market especially
for the approval for the pilot
pilot
trials
okay thank you so much juana i hope
switzerland move
forward to get the
integral regulation sooner than later
thank you so much
to to add to two lines about the
situation in spain we still have a lot
of work to do we are working on it
but
the use of medical and recreational
cannabis in spain is not regulated yet
the latest works
sorry the latest news is that an expert
commission to talk about
medical cannabis just started two days
ago it will work until june let's see
what happened
let's see see positive and wait for the
for the result
our cbd cbd market is not
regulated either in spain
there is a really big cbd market in
spain you can find different products if
you go around the city you will see so
many shops you can find flowers you can
find c videos you can find cosmetics
products maybe some
food supplement either but as i said
it's not regulated all these companies
are working in a in a grey
area but
the market is getting bigger and bigger
even more after the
european court resolution
like almost two years ago so i cannot
wait for the european union regulate at
least
cbd
sooner than that later also we have in
spain
some companies growing medical
cannabis but the companies these
companies have to export the product to
a legal markets with an
authorized or a legal distributor that's
how the situation in
in spain
now we can
keep going and let's talk about the
second
point of this
panel let's talk about
licensing requirements
so please chloe let us let us know what
do we need to
get a license in
the united states
absolutely
so
just like pretty much everything in the
united states related to cannabis it
really differs substantially from state
to state
there are some common threads though so
those are what i'll focus on
so first of all the most boring one but
the business basics so you have to have
business formation documents usually
insurance tax accounts etc i think
that's pretty typical
the second thing is
your team and a lot of documents related
to your team so
what your team consists of depends on
the state how they define it
but it's typically owners
people who are operating the business or
controlling the business financial
interest holders and in some cases
employees contractors etc so i think one
of the things that always shocks people
when they start to get into the
licensing process in cannabis and in the
us
is that if you are an owner or one of
the other people who needs to make
disclosures
you are going to have a very deep dive
into your background so i'll give you
one example
um in a state that i previously worked
in
there were requests for the tax returns
for the last five years not just of
owners but of their spouses and for
every business that they have any amount
of business interest in so
that's like
an unbelievable amount of documentation
also some states require the team to
meet
professional standards so
you may have to have a chemist on board
or
something along those lines
finally states also sometimes try to
limit ownership only to people who are
local to that state but that often gets
struck down in courts of law
so beyond team property is probably the
most critical thing
so
locking down a property early very
important you also have to typically
have local zoning or land use
authorizations to go along with that
property
so property control is a must
whether current or conditioned on
licensure and highly recommend
conditioned on licensure because there's
often lawsuits so if you locked on a
property you may be paying a lease for
two years three years while lawsuits are
being
resolved
once you have all of that taken care of
then you typically have to prepare a
facility design a construction schedule
because there's often especially in new
markets a lot of interest in how quickly
you can get to market
funding is also a critical thing and the
amount of funding that you have to have
in order to apply differs greatly from
state to state but we've seen you know
having to have two million dollars in
liquid capital in a bank account so it
can be quite substantial
you also have to have plans of
operations or what we refer to as
narratives so you could submit standard
operating procedures in some cases but
you typically don't want to in order to
protect your your
processes so you end up preparing these
very detailed descriptions of exactly
what you're going to do in your business
so
cultivation manufacturing dispensing but
also things like security
community impact
and so many other things
so that's where consultants often come
into play because sometimes applications
can be a thousand plus pages
um
they're also local supports really
important so you may have to actually
have a letter of support from the local
government or some type of local license
depending on what the application
requirements are
and finally things that set you apart so
that may be partnerships research that
you're doing philanthropy environmental
initiatives
diversity equity and inclusion
initiatives it really just depends on
what your company specializes in
so
now i'll just go over a few pieces of
pieces of advice for how to win
in these competitive markets so
first play to your strengths
but also understand what the state is
looking for
so i think it's really critical to
analyze public meetings laws and
regulations
application materials and also who are
the key players who are involved both in
regulating cannabis writing the laws etc
and understanding by reading between the
lines what the priorities are and what
they're looking for in a licensee
then you can find where you can deliver
based on your unique value that you
bring as a company
second if you are in a competitive
licensing process you absolutely must
distinguish yourself
you cannot just rely on the bare minimum
of what they're asking for
i had clients in the past say oh you
know what i'm just going to give them
exactly what they're asking for across
the board and i can tell you those
clients pretty much always fail you have
to go above and beyond in every regard
if it's a lottery process you should be
strategic and consider the fact that
it's a numbers game
so if there are geographic limits and
you can only apply once in different
geographies you should probably apply
once in each geography
also
if you can apply both in populated areas
and less populated areas that's also a
pretty good strategy because if the pool
is smaller your probability of winning
is higher
finally expect lawsuits don't lock
yourself into anything that
is going to drain you financially if you
have to wait for two or three years
while legal matters are resolved
thank you very much
kai please whatever yeah maybe maybe i
can add i can
agree on
most points except of the lottery system
i can't understand that
but i can add to uh we only have the
draft in germany the cannabis control
act by the greens
this is the blueprint
because it's a complete law it's really
60 70 pages long export import free
market model everything is regulated it
will also be a federal law so there
won't be any interstate restriction
interstate commercial commerce
restrictions
and you can have as much licenses as you
want to when you get one in the end okay
but what is also clear is that the staff
members this stuff has to be trained
the ministry of justice the secretary of
justice has confirmed that it's the
basic thought of the cannabis control
act is the social responsibility
of this act so you get the free market
you get the legalized market but on the
other hand to regulate that to
to yeah to to
[Music]
fight the
negative consequences you have to have
strict social responsibilities in place
so this stuff has to be trained the
staff has to have a certificate of
responsible selling in the end no one
knows yet how intense and how long these
education
will look like will be
we will have to look at the us or canada
for other examples for example but the
law says the the staff member has to
know
about how cannabis works and about
prevention or opportunity options
they have to
identify risky
consummation patterns with their clients
then they have to talk to them about it
with their clients
etc
and the shops have to have a social
concept in place so they have to have in
written a concept how they will fit in
their community
in the neighborhood and what are they
doing about prevention and drug
addiction and
they have to have
they have to be affiliated with the
drug prevention associations etc etc so
the whole set
of regulations concerning the social
responsibility
but we have to work this out
as well this year next year the details
how intense it will be
but this will come
hi uh
hi
michael sorry
we have to stop
uh no
thank you for your expertise kai um
we are soon
we come to the end now but uh like
always we have to give the audience the
chance to ask a few questions or at
least one question i think there's not
more time than one question so if
there's a question please
i see there's one question
i'll give you the microphone
yes thank you mr newman
you mentioned about the dispensaries and
shopping in germany but what about the
growing licenses in germany as i know
there is a 13 watts in 2019
after the last tender
are they planning
to
give more licensing
in this draft i don't know
yeah the cultivation is also possible
according to this draft
for sure
but i doubt that
cultivating of recreational cannabis in
germany has a future
because we have a demand of 400 to 600
tons on
for for dried flowers alone
so
you
would have to set up facilities and
plants for cultivation like we see them
in switzerland with big investments with
20 25 million
we would need 20 30 facilities of these
two to cover the demand domestically i
don't think this makes sense from a
climate perspective as well because
these
facilities are really energy consuming
and there are many many facilities all
over the world in lisotto in south
africa colombia
north macedonia they have their
facilities in place they have better
wetter weather conditions
so germany think we'll have to rely on
on imports for a long time or for for
most of the most of the material
and we have
three domestic licenses granted in 2019
for medical cannabis and the liberal
party said they want to make germany a
cannabis a medical cannabis export
nation
so we might see that that there where
there will be new tenders for medical
cannabis
um cultivation
so that
germany can also supply uh in in
domestically
the the medical cannabis market globally
maybe you should come to switzerland
because we have a use rate of
8.7 percent
we have a very
big black and white market
so maybe we could discuss later
yeah thank you very much
to the panelists
[Music]
[Applause]
them and ask them all the questions you
want politely politely
but you can do it i'm sure people do
uh thank you all so very much one more
time for our panel way to move right
along great
[Applause]