So, I just want to say thank you. My name is  Alex Rogers. I am the founder of the ICBC,
and I want to give my heartfelt thanks to you  guys. We're here for business and with business,
I found out, the more you perpetuate  the business, the more you perpetuate
the politics and move the public policy  forward. And that's what we're here to do.
Yeah, I'm so happy to be here at the ICBC and  having Whova as a platform to be connected
with all the key players in the industry.  I think it's a really good place to be.
The ICBC is a very important event and conference  for the European industry to build its identity,
ask questions itself, develop the  professional community of people who
are invested and engaged in the emerging  European cannabis industry. It's a very
unique space in terms of being able to connect  with people who are working very diverse parts.
I think the networking potential of the  ICBC is very unique. As I said, it brings
a very diverse range of people together,  you know, from operations, branding. So,
in a very short space of time, they can cover  a lot of ground in terms of different roles,
viewpoints, and people involved in  the European space and beyond. So
the networking element of the ICBC is  a very important aspect of it as well.
We'd love to come back again, and  we are really looking forward to
go as well to Berlin. We would love to be there.