no we just want to give a big shout-out
to bang to bring leroy Thornhill the DJ
from prodigy last night to the
after-party that was super fun yeah so
bangs a big supporter of the ICBC they
sponsor a lot of our after parties so
just one more time give it up for bang
y'all thank you baby
and without further ado you guys oh yeah
let's see you in Zurich so if you uh we
got a special deal going on today
service gonna be off the charts
five-star boom Stern super spa godless
hotel direct oven dish dot system VAR AK
vans in order without further ado Alex
Rogers put this whole thing together the
whole team Anthony Vinnie Noel Jesse
Tristan D'Elia Randy I forget everybody
else his name we were out late last
night I don't know if you came to the
party but it was a good time but we're
gonna start the pin I'm gonna bring up
the moderator he's the founder and the
CEO of Green Rush consulting he's very
exciting and introduce everybody let's
hear it for Zeta
[Applause]
how's everybody doing today
yeah good welcome welcome so again this
is about investments in capital markets
this is lovely this is awesome so on the
far end over here we got jamie pearson
am is the chief operations officer for
bang chocolate the world's most awarded
line of gourmet chocolate bars and
award-winning CBD products bang she
manages the executive team contract
negotiations works with bangs licenses
in the US as well as other countries and
oversees this cypress hill bang venture
with over two decades of operational
financial experience she brings a
pragmatic approach as a believer in
finding the win-win and every deal
recently she's been recognized by hi Tom
doesn't one of the hundred most
influential people in the cannabis
industry ever I give it up for Jamy next
we got Alexander Straub Alexander's a
german-born
entrepreneur at the head of the London
firm Straub ventures in Cambridge
accelerator partners he was a Rhodes
Scholar at the University of Oxford and
eventually moved to New York to
establish Lazard technical technology
partners to a 300 million dollar venture
fund in 2006 he co-founded voice over IP
specialist Truphone and was named
technology pioneer at the World Economic
Forum in 2007 and 2008 fast forward
early to 2017 he launched snap me an app
based ecommerce company based on
e-commerce enabled via computer vision
machine learning and AI in preparation
for an augmented reality and VR enabled
world give it up for Alex here thank you
thank you and finally we got Gavin Gavin
is the CEO of Alta Florida that focuses
on developing canvas science and IP
through the value chain on genetics
formulation brands in data he has raised
money in Europe for Alta flora through
HSN W and family offices he also sits on
the board of Oxford cannabinoid
technologies where there is money from
Imperial brands the largest tobacco
company in the world and can't say Verde
Capital that Snoop Dogg's venture
capital firm he also advised some of the
largest corporates in the UK around the
canvas strategies everybody give it off
a Gavin here please thank you
okay so I'm going to start to sell it's
the global CBD crazy guys everything is
going around CBD everywhere so I want to
start out with the CBD market in Europe
is expected to be worth 416 million by
the end of 2019 this just came out in
rolling stone like seven days ago and by
1.7 billion by 2023 so what are you
seeing in terms of the best CBD
investments of the European market and
specifically in Germany and do you have
any thoughts on what investors should be
looking for in terms of CBD
opportunities so Jamie you want to what
do you think well that's a good question
the CBD companies that I'm seeing in
Europe were we're actually distributing
our CBD products in Europe and have been
for about three years so I have a little
bit of experience with it but what I'm
seeing is a big shift in the quality of
the companies that are coming forward
there's more of an advancement in tech
and if I were bringing my own capital to
the table I would be looking for teams
that are working cooperatively with the
German government the European
government to make sure that they're
gonna be able to have some long term
play because what we're seeing in the US
market versus what's happening in Europe
is that you guys are getting to learn
from our mistakes and I would be looking
for the teams that have spent some time
in the u.s. learning from those mistakes
and then are operating within the
confines of maybe driving the ship a
little bit because I think the companies
that are really instrumental in driving
legislations they're the ones that are
gonna make it because everyone else is
going to come behind and follow actually
that's that's a great answer I mean it's
definitely changing the face of
everything but it's also you know what
we see in the u.s. too is we have you
know some states that in act you know
CBD losses can I have an entry point for
that so what's really interesting to see
in Europe Alex what do you think about
this the CBD opportunities are happening
to Europe right now well clearly it's a
regulated environment and so investors
in general react to regulatory
industries with caution
so we seen this in the
kind of alternative energy market on the
wind side on the solar side all
regulated markets and I think what it
looks like CBD was a food novelty act
etc are going to be also in this
category it's all more open than THC I
would say but in general I think
uncertainty creates something what
investors don't like and therefore I
think in general caution you know
certainly this is a once-in-a-lifetime
opportunity because of the demand curve
actually being created so I think one
needs to balance both sides and without
any doubts I would say that actually
well-organized governments in Europe
which have a clear plan and give clear
guidance to entrepreneurs have a huge
advantage to create the diamonds which
are in the rough right now and I would
say that mostly it will have to start on
the medical side it will have to start
in a regulated environment and I think
when we look about on my way in Germany
right now the German government compared
to the Danish or others have given a
clear guidance what they want to do it's
going to be only a four year contract
but I would say these companies which
are achieving a license are going to be
highly valuable and without any doubts
there will be huge amounts of capital
required to bring those companies to the
market we seen this in Canada how long
it took how long it took for patients to
develop I would say there's a slight
advantage here because many patients are
registered and I think there's a
familiarity was with a product and so
while one has as an investor has to
balance both sides yeah but uncertainty
is not certainly something and
regulation is not something investors
look forward to oh well certainly
there's a lot of uncertainty in this
industry and especially with how we're
just trying to educate our governments
and it's all about education and
awareness and more and more were able to
educate these governments on moving the
path forward and creating a mechanism in
which you know we're able to move
so you know what about what about you
Gavin what do you think about it so I
start with a couple of data points there
was some survey data from the UK which
suggested CBD had brand awareness of 50
percent and 10 percent of the population
had tried CBD so I think the first thing
to say this is a as a massive phenomenon
driven by word of mouth from the
consumers the second thing I'd build on
Alex's point to say the regulations are
shifting and that makes no investors
nervous it also makes entrepreneurs
pivot I've seen a bunch of folks in the
UK look at the recent EU FSA rulings and
move from food into cosmetics so I think
you'll start to see entrepreneurs look
for DIF like I guess regulatory
arbitrage is the way to think about it
they're going to be different regulatory
frameworks depending on the types of
products depending on the channels and I
think smart entrepreneurs will figure
out how to play that ARB game smart
investors will figure out which
entrepreneurs to back and I think
there's going to be a lot of opportunity
in the space but I think it's gonna be
quite fluid for the next few months in
Europe I think the big change is going
to be on the back of the farm bill I
think if the u.s. gets some clarity
around CBD I think it's going to be
incumbent upon Europe to look at that
and say actually we've got some clarity
now we can bring that to to the EU and
so one of the things that we're you know
fighting hard for is a you know
harmonized EU regulatory framework for
these products and I think the fact that
this is going to pass at the federal
level in the u.s. gives us a good
framework start talking about this stuff
in this way across the EU so yeah big
market it's kind of fluid at the moment
around the rig's entrepreneurs will
figure their ways around it I think
we'll get some clarity through the rest
of this year into next year as we look
to the experience of the US absolutely
agree with that you know and also you
know think that it's an important point
that either entrepreneurs or investors
need to be able to pivot at any moment's
notice based on their regulatory
framework I mean it's changing
constantly it's a moving target and we
like to call it dynamic compliance sort
of speak and so that's very very
important point you have to be able to
be used to that so speaking of different
opportunities besides the CBD are you
seeing any other opportunities here in
Europe besides CBD that seem like
they're worthy of investment you have an
easy thing obviously on the medical side
yeah I think it's fair to say it's grown
less quickly than people probably would
have thought I remember being here in
2017 and there was sort of real hype
around
as Alex said in the intro yesterday you
know there were only a thousand patients
in Germany and I don't think it moves
quite as quickly as people have thought
it still feels like we're in the sort of
less established the regulatory
framework for medical there's a lot of
infrastructure building happening
clearly the Canadians have sort of been
in looking at various different
opportunities there are some Israelis in
Europe they're clearly you know some
some European ox pros looking at the
space as well but it hasn't grown I
think from a sort of market demand
perspective quite as quickly as as we
thought and so there's still a lot of
risk capsule going in on the promise of
future revenues from the European market
but yeah aside from CVD that that's the
space that we're focused on right
license THC medicine production right
and Alex you have a pretty profound tech
background are you seeing any new tech
innovation in Germany specifically
there's worthy of investment that's you
don't have leading around the world or
anything like that
yeah I think two things to point out I
think investment and seems come in wave
so I think as a venture capitalist you
have seen this of the last 20 years it
was very unclear in Germany at the
beginning in 1998 what will happen was
the Internet but we have seen we're in
eventually caught up we created
companies in our own tough and and we
created them all around Europe yeah I
wouldn't say we have been as successful
as the United States because there were
early however I think in the patient
medical and doctor pharmaceutical
relationship there is a lot of lack and
slack I would say that we are at the
break out of formulating machines
software machines which can identify
much better
deceased profiles than any human doctor
and I think that's due to the intake of
information by by machines by software
machines on a machine learning side and
then by the input and in layman terms by
patients into a mobile phone and then an
analysis I mean one has to imagine the
human has we have around 7,000
identified diseases only 500
are treatable or have a medical product
against them and then if you look down
into a single disease it's often defined
and treated with like one pill or one
medication if you take autistic children
what we now know is that the DNA decides
much more about the treatment so I've
seen more and more companies which
coming from that perspective of saying
well first identify what you've got
better than the doctor because there's
more information then actually bring
those patients into a DNA test
define what the DNA tells you about
let's say autism and then define the
treatment strategy and that will give us
a a huge increase from 500 diseases to
seven thousand diseases laughs so six
and a half thousand we don't treat today
because they're so rare and and then on
top of it every single disease can be
treated in four or five different ways
depending of your DNA I mean all of us I
think have different effects on THC and
CBD and and you know it's and and that
has something to do with our DNA and how
we are made up and I think there you
have a huge potential going forward
which is much wider than I mean what
we're seeing in in this industry but
it's it's quite determined as well what
we're doing was THC or CBD products and
excellence there's a lot of pioneering
for different investment strategies with
different you know innovators in that
space that's really amazing so you know
I kinda want to move on to like raising
capital in some of these capital markets
so you know Canada obviously Canada is a
you know a leading country doing this
with with with the access to you know
public markets as opposed to the US or
other areas Jamie do you want to kind of
talk to us about how to raise capital
what that looks like and tell us a
little bit about the landscape please
bang is getting ready to go public on
the Canadian stock exchange in a few
weeks and that process has been through
an RTO which is a reverse takeover it's
been a long process we could have gone
IPO and we felt the RTO would take less
time but in reality it didn't even
though
we had a clean shell from a mining
company so what I would say to you if
you're out there going into the Canadian
market looking for capital just do your
due diligence and and be thorough about
that we had several companies come to us
with promises of extreme valuations and
different things going on and the
reality is if you know your company and
your value and your ability to generate
revenue you should have a pretty good
idea of what your valuation should be so
when companies come to you and they give
you something that doesn't make sense
you you really need to drive the ship
and say no that's not that's not where
we want to go because at the end of the
day you've got to offer your
shareholders real revenue real value and
you've got to know what that is but I
wanted to speak about what Alex was
talking about with the the technology
the plant that we're all talking about
in these rooms we don't know what it's
capable of healing what we all have is
anecdotal evidence that it does work and
it's working legitimately for people so
I just I'm excited about being part of
this industry for technology for healing
but what I would also like to see is a
real common-sense approach to the fact
that people are going to use marijuana
recreationally as well and that some of
that legislation has to happen I'm
hoping the Europeans get it right and
you know look at the taxation and look
at some of the frameworks around
allowing the plant to be used
recreationally and not just medically I
think that's one thing they can learn
from us and then the last thing I want
to say is the real commodity that I see
as a brand is shelf space and ultimately
the u.s. is screwing up we all know this
we can't scale up we we've got federal
illy it's federally illegal so I can't
build one manufacturing plant and move
my product across state lines
it means theoretically I would have to
build 50 manufacturing plants to be
animal a multi-state operator bang's
been able to get around that and when
you know through licensing and other
opportunities but at the end of the day
the companies that capture shelf space
that's the supply that's diminishing
because cannabis is going to become a
commodity and it's gonna be grown in
areas where the Sun is plentiful and you
know we're gonna be able to get back to
the the price of the commodity getting
low enough to us you know turning into
just a typical industry and
pharmaceutical quality medicine for
people who want medicine and
recreational quality medicine craft
cannabis and all of those things but at
the end of the day it's the the brands
that are going to matter and it's the
companies that are building brands that
are capturing the hearts and minds of
consumers and capturing shelf space
those are the ones that are gonna win
that's where I would be looking to put
my money obviously the bang brand is
strong and powerful but there's I think
the biggest ones don't exist yet just
like all the cannabis consumers that are
going to exist aren't in the marketplace
yet because we're we've got to you know
reach that point of social acceptance
you want to weigh your honor yeah this
brand point is interesting if you look
to the alcohol industry which also went
through a period of prohibition the
first brands that were built post
prohibition were were those brands that
established the functional attributes to
the category so in London
Gordon's gin was was was marketed on the
fact that it wouldn't kill you
and it wouldn't destroy your liver and I
feel like this first phase of cannabis
brands are almost normalizing this
product for the mainstream with a lot of
these functional attributes so you know
you're not going to get the munchies and
eat your whole kitchen you're not going
to have psychotic episodes or all of
these years of misinformation and I
think once those functional attributes
in the category are established then we
can start moving to aspirational brand
building so I think the most impactful
brands in cannabis are yet to be broke
yet the other thing I'd say on from the
alcohol perspective brands are built in
the on trade so brands in the alcohol
space not built in consumption venues
like bars like pubs we don't have those
spaces in cannabis right now and I think
it's going to be those countries that
regulate on the consumption side first
that will offer the most appealing brand
building opportunities for companies
there's a lot of ritual that is involved
with cannabis consumption that is yet to
be defined for the products that we yet
to invent and so we all know the ritual
when you you know go home and have a
glass of wine or for a smoker who goes
outside and I think those rituals are
going to be invented for cannabis and
the really smart brand market is will
tap into the psychology to work out what
those rituals are so a lot lots of
investment potential with the brands
that are yet to be built tapping into
trends that were yet to figure out
absolutely and I can absolutely relate
to that coming from the San Francisco
Bay Area which is you know ground zero
for the cannabis industry at from the
very beginning we're seeing a lot of
brands come out of California and of
course you know licensing the IP and
scaling by IP and scaling by footprint
is a methodology where you can cross
state lines or even cross country lines
you know just scaling by IP so I think
that's an important factor when you're
looking at some of these investment
strategies and whether or not the
management team is even focused on this
so that's that's really amazing
what about raising capital in Europe do
you have any insight on that Gavin on
how to raise capital in Europe how does
that look like or what is that landscape
look like yeah it's really changed in
Europe actually in the last like three
or four years on the back of you know
this was a domino effect of all these
countries legalizing medical release
putting in place frameworks and so you
know initially it was it was almost it
was almost difficult to talk about it in
somewhere like London you know how would
you approach someone to talk about this
specific topic in a space where in the
UK this was illegal until in November
last year in the last six months it's
really changed and you're starting to
see a lot more interest from the venture
capital community a lot more interest
from some of the larger investment banks
a lot more interest from the high
net-worth and family office space
I still feel we're in this space of sort
of educating a lot of the investors in
London it's quite unsophisticated I
think we've got a lot of education to do
on the Canadian public Marcus about the
metrics that really matter and and and
that has an impact on how investors in
Europe look at these opportunities the
other thing I'd say you know is I think
we can draw parallels here between the
tech industry in cannabis in that Europe
tends to be a little bit more
conservative when it comes to you know
valuations look
for entrepreneurs to get traction or an
understanding of unit economics before
they really want to scale a company
whereas I feel like there's a lot more
risk capital in North America so yeah I
think it's going to be an interesting
space for Europe over the next few
months and years as we start to see more
educated investors get into the space
with larger checks excellent Alex um you
have a distinguished career in venture
capital can you weigh in on some of that
between Europe and Canada and what is
what is like raising capital especially
for cannabis companies yeah I would say
it's it's unclear who are the structured
venture capital group's in that space
right now in Europe I would say there's
a lot of recycling of capital to to the
user success in Canada so the groups I'm
working with in somehow had huge
successes in Canada have huge capital
available and they're willing to invest
it at very fast pace and so it is
unclear yet in Europe where to invest it
I would say it's much clearer right now
in other parts of the world I would say
the United States is still a fantastic
Roche market and so but I think
structured capital is needed and I think
at much bigger scale than people imagine
in a certain respect I calculate that
Germany would need about 1.5 billion of
investment to make the whole industry in
the country grown or grow up in the
country so that's my
back-of-the-envelope calculation now
when it comes to banks it's quite
interesting I have spoken to several
banks and so some Canadians are still
close to the idea of actually dealing
and and and having companies in their
structures which are cannabis related
while European banks are German banks
are sometimes much more liberal so you
go to the chief Ombudsman of the banks
and they have no problem actually to
touch that industry at all so in some
respect it's more liberal here then when
you speak to certain investors out of
the United States as well I suppose into
some investors in London and they just
say like well our pension funds don't
allow us and . end of story
yeah so I think it needs a special
approach for the next couple of years
and that's a challenger but at the same
time also an opportunity I would say
absolutely I mean speaking of banks I
mean the United States I mean really you
can't use an FDIC shirt and bank to get
loans or anything for cannabis based
business it's just not there yet now we
do have the safe banking act that looks
like it potentially may pass but this
has been a problem for entrepreneurs and
you know especially retail owners or
anybody that's in the cannabis space
because it's mainly been a
cash-and-carry business up into this
point now more and more we're seeing
this coming you know become more you
know accessible you know but because of
the compliance factors you're not able
to do that so it's it's been really hard
for the United States businesses scale
without private funding but more more
we're seeing family offices you know get
involved but that's part of the reason
why we're going to Canada as us-based
companies just to get that capital so we
can scale and grow within the United
States so that's a really interesting
concept but I think as we go forward
we're gonna see more and more this
access and being able to access this
capital domestically so but speaking of
which you know there's a lot of
companies out there in Canada that have
like really really high valuations and
we're seeing a lot of you know
opportunities coming to investors with
these these blown evaluations that you
know you can't support those valuations
and so what are you guys seeing in terms
of that and you know in terms of
deciding on that and and how do you guys
make the investment decisions on those
valuations in terms of investing in
those companies you want take it Jenny
what do you think it's an interesting
topic that gets bounced around a lot
especially at these conferences because
people are saying to me knowing that
we're getting ready to go public what do
you think about all the valuations in
Canada aren't they all inflated aren't
isn't everything we just talked in the
green room don't you think people are
gonna lose a lot of money coming up
pretty soon
because of these overinflated
evaluations I didn't I don't know I
don't know I don't have a crystal ball
because then when I look back at the
tech industry the companies that made it
I remember thinking wow they want $3 for
Amazon and we I don't know what's gonna
happen so it's interesting what I will
say is I think when banking when that
domino falls in the US it's gonna be a
game-changer again because just in the
in the years that I've been in the
industry I'm from Montana we have a
saying if you don't like the weather
wait five minutes I feel like it the
same thing in the industry if you don't
like the way the industry is rolling
wait five minutes and there's gonna be a
new law but I think once banking falls
that domino and we can Bank like every
other industry then the dust is gonna
settle and we're gonna start to see the
real money come in so I think he's right
that the real money the big
institutional funds they're not here yet
we've had a couple of people dabble you
know Cronos got a big investment we've
we've seen you know some of the alcohol
companies and the tobacco companies
bring real dollars but those aren't
actually real dollars I think the real
dollars are coming and it's gonna take
banking for that to happen absolutely I
mean like we haven't even seen Wall
Street jump in or any of these big
groups come in or what do you think
about this Gavin about the valuations
aspect of these companies and things
like yeah I think it's interesting I can
believe the Canadian valuations if you
think they're going to dominate global
cannabis in perpetuity if you think
there's going to be competition these
numbers look inflated and that's the
only way that I can see it I think that
the interesting point on banking is
going to be right now there's a discount
applied to US stocks traded on the CSC I
think the moment this changes the
banking question these valuation these
multiples will all change the risk
profile for the US companies becomes a
lot safer the ability of the Canadians
to compete lacking this u.s. competition
disappears and I think there's a really
inflection point on on some of these
multiples that'll come on the back of
further us let it legislative change
it's interesting to look at how this is
impacting on Europe though because a lot
of the story that is promised right now
in Canada is around global growth and so
we sort of need to see these European
markets
move for the Canadian valuations to be
justified so I think some chickens are
going to come home to roost over the
next few months as we start to see you
know real data coming out as to the
actual size of the market and it kind of
feels like what we really need to be
talking about is demand generation in
Europe which is a tough tough question
speaks to some of the points Alex was
making around some of the future of
medicine in the future the clinical
trial but it requires all of us to
engage with healthcare regulatory
agencies the medical establishment to
make these markets move to have any
chance of these evaluations being
justified absolutely I totally agree
with that I mean Alex what do you think
about a couple evaluations and how that
how that's being evaluated based on
somebody's inflated your companies that
are doing it I mean it's based on hype
you know mainly what do you think yeah
I'm very cautious because I've seen it
over the 20 25 years I'm in this
industry on the tech space in a Crow's
industry it's very hard to value a
company because you have the PE G ratio
and so yes they look high but I would
say you have to be careful you know like
you have seen that I've seen that on
facebook when Zuckerberg mark was
running around Davos was 2 billion
valuation while myspace at twice the
numbers of users and sold for 6 700
million yeah
so I saw it was Larry and Sergey and
Google tiny companies others have tried
search out a Vista etc
don't underestimate gross you know and I
think if a market is growing a lot of
mistakes can be for bid I can be just
forgotten and companies can grow up and
at the end of the day it's paper money
and they these companies using that
paper money to go into markets and
Germany for example will be a gigantic
market we will see a million patients
maybe more consuming 2 to 3 grams per
day it's it's a 5 6 billion dollar
industry so you can create let's say 10
times multiple create in Germany 60
billion market cap on the stock market
alone and if you take the Canadian
companies jointly I mean sure they have
high market caps maybe they're three
times over valued like an Aurora and I
was doing three million revenue
give them three billion market cap but
it's a gross story so I wouldn't bet
against them I mean you have to be very
careful if you want to show those these
businesses and I've seen that screw out
and clearly people will definitely
decline in value some some of these
companies which make strategic mistakes
some of them won't get licenses where
they want to get the licenses there will
be cautious in terms of acquisitions and
then they will fall to the wayside but
that's the process of a next two three
four or five years ten years so but I
mean we are not here to actually bet for
stock market companies which already
floated we're here to build companies
absolutely from the base and the ground
up and I think yeah that's absolutely
possible excellent that's that's a great
answer so I'm speaking of you know
public companies let's let's talk about
the difference you know or you know
private versus public you know let's
just talk about that was this discussed
the difference and how companies seeking
investment decide on which investment
partnership to go with you know what's
best for them strategically from a
partnership perspective from a brand
perspective from a growth perspective
was his talk about that a little bit
what do you what do you think Jamie
about the difference between those two
and how you approach that we discussed
it a lot at bang when I first started
working there we weren't really looking
to go public but we just cut having
banks come to us and say we we think you
guys will be great as a publicly traded
company we want to take you public and
we saw them looking at us as an
opportunity which caused us internally
to start having a different conversation
and what I would say is the the beauty
of private money is you can make private
decisions you can make mistakes and
everybody isn't you know looking under
your skirt but when you're public
everybody knows everything as they
should the public is putting money into
your company and they need to know what
you're doing they don't need to know
what your vision is and it forces you to
flesh out your vision it forces you to
get your strategic plan in place and
have some discipline that you don't have
to have when you're private so we saw
going public as a multi fold reason
to make our company better and one was
we have so many devoted fans that write
to us and ask how do I invest I love
your product your chocolate changed my
life kind of thing and so there was just
a part of that notion that Scott wanted
to open it up to the people that have
built our company so there was sort of
an altruistic decision in the background
and also we don't want to be afraid of
having people look at what we're doing
bangs been a trailblazer we've we had
the first nutritional fact panel on an
edible product before we sold one
product we had Lloyd's of London product
liability insurance before we sold one
product and at that time you know you
were buying brownies out of Ziploc bags
so we brought that sort of regulation to
the industry so we we look forward to
the challenge of having people look up
our skirt because we've been operating a
really clean company for a long time so
I think that those are the that's the
rub do you want to make your decisions
in private or do you want to make them
in public and some companies don't want
the dilution that comes with you know if
you're an owner and you've built a
company and you go public you're gonna
give up some of your equity there's some
of that that you have to think about but
I think a small piece of a giant company
is just as valuable as a large piece of
a smaller company and so private capital
also allowed us to expand you know into
you know global markets and and we want
to dominate the globe we want to bring
our brand to the globe so how do you do
that with private funding there's lots
of high net worth individuals out there
that could have helped us go that route
this seemed like the right decision for
us yeah I mean I totally can agree with
that and I also think that it's the
difference of your business model - so
in my case you know i-i've just lost
technology you know a piece of software
SAS based software that helps with
permitting licensing and accelerates the
process I did the same thing with the
Vancouver you know met a group who was
you know a mining company they wanted to
relist on the CSC but instead of an RTO
what I did was instead was a qualifying
asset
transaction to help them relist which
doesn't require the five-year financial
audit and you know based as a campus
company in the u.s. even as a consulting
company was very difficult to find
someone or a company that would you know
basically do a five-year audit on us and
put their name on it so instead we did a
qualifying asset transaction which
allowed them to relist so it's just a
different methodology and for us we
needed access to public markets do get
access to this capital for opportunities
coming through our network so in the
case of JB's it's just scaling and
scaling the business is scaling the
brand and ours we just needed access to
that public public marketplace I mean so
it's just different ways of doing that
which i think is quite interesting to
see what what do you think Alex I mean
what is would your opinion on private
versus public like and some of the well
I think in the last year's - - I think
the large funding available for
companies company have chosen to stay
private much longer in this sector
however - - and I think not enough
investment people have chosen to go
public early and being a public board
member for ten years it's a huge burden
and it's a very expensive exercise to be
public company and for bid you decide
you want to go private I mean that's a
lengthy process and if you've gone
through that that's that's what painful
go there public - private again now I
would say a lot of these companies go
prematurely and if there would be more
capital available on the private side
people would choose to stay much longer
on the private side and we have seen
that in the tech space happening and I
think but right now I think people don't
have another choice it's a gross marker
people are hungry and so people go
prematurely to the stock market and I
think there will be a lot of shakeout
and a lot of people won't be able to
handle it properly so my choice would be
to stay private longer until you're much
larger company and then on top of it
what do you gain from being a public
company a lot of companies which went
public even I mean in Canada they didn't
have any float so the founders they have
nothing from this IP
you can't do anything with a stock and
and you're lucky one of the bigger ones
buys you so I think it's a balanced
approach you have to look at it clearly
some early ones will be winners but you
might be a big big loser being too early
public so I would say it's much better
to work with a consortium of investors
which you can trust which on your board
which you can work the process and you
get into a stable situation to take the
company's public and I mean in Germany
we have a long history of companies
which are hundreds of years old and they
have never gone public and yeah hey
Gavin do you want to weigh in on a
little bit yeah I think it's probably
worth remembering that it was sort of
speculative mining index in Canada let's
had a lot of the funding of this
industry early on and it was a point in
time when there was a lack of access to
capital and I think that's really
changing now so I think we will see
companies stay private for longer in
Europe as they're building out we do
however have a couple of companies that
have listed in London on the next
exchange so in much the way the CSC has
started to gather a reputation around
being a place where companies can go get
liquidity I think the necks in London
will start to become that sort of place
so there's sativa and our investments on
the next I've spoken to a m-- in London
about potential paths to liquidity for
companies in the future and then we have
a you know Stella Cara in Denmark you
know you're starting to see some
companies in Europe emerge and look to
public markets for capital rather than
rather than private but in general I
think I'd echo both points that you know
we're going to make mistakes in this
industry the regulatory frameworks are
going to evolve and it's I think better
to adapt to a business in private what
while you're in this quite fluid space
where where things are being figured out
excellent excellent so I'd actually like
to open up or you know some questions
because I know I'm sure you guys have a
lot of questions for us so let's get
started on some questions once again for
the panel first of all this way
a very very exciting thank you very much
this question is principally directed to
Alex you talked about governments
needing to give a clear planning
guidance to entrepreneurs to make the
right decisions could you focus a little
bit on which governments in Europe in
your opinion have the highest chance to
fulfill this requirement focus a little
bit on Switzerland which my humble
opinion seems to be on the forefront in
many of the developments and the sub
sectors you would put your money to work
please be brief well very difficult
questions I think and very hard to
answer I would say it's um
I mean I'm biased so let's put it that
way I'm very biased for Germany because
I'm German and I think I've seen it in a
lot of industries I think we're slow but
we will get to the point and when we get
to the point we'll do it I think
correctly and and then it will be a huge
success so I would say what I see so far
it's Germany but yeah so I mean we're in
a single market we're free you know so
others might have a chance as well I
just feel that from an organizational
perspective and curiosity this market is
highly educated I think they are open
for a change and they are open also to
adapt new products to confirm the
consumer perspective the pharmacies
already the doctors are much more ready
than anywhere else like it compared to
England and it's a clear path I mean
politically maybe not everybody wants
that to happen but I think when people
see the positive sides and this has to
be coupled with with research R&amp;D and
and and and more medical studies etc I
think
we'll get there that's my opinion but
this is biased and I think I'm not fully
in a hundred and informed about
everything in Europe and so a lot of
people in the audience may might have a
lot more knowledge and I have so yeah
hey great panel thank you very much
right here okay and thank you also for
saying what you did about the German
market because I'm I worked with the
startup here in Germany medpay Rx and
we're getting a lot of support but my
question to you is twofold and I kind of
bring back one of the themes that you
talked about earlier a here in Germany
obviously the regulatory markets are a
little bit tougher
I live in Frankfurt you know what a
Deutsche Bursa has this entire industry
from North America under super secret
probation basically and that has to do I
think with the maturity of the
industries you were talking about but
what do you guys see and and I'm sort of
trying to get elicit your comments and
helpful suggestions about how American
and Canadian funds are getting
information about the opportunities here
I mean this being Germany there are
incubators there are accelerators
there's government money if you're
looking at it from science and most of
the investors I know and talk to you are
delighted to have that opportunity that
was it what do you see in America about
that any question what do you guys know
who was that directed toward Marvel I
would say like look I think you look at
this conference it's still early days I
can't see the usual suspects here so
they're not here they're right now in
the office or somewhere else and I think
they will show up in this industry or
one creates new essentially investor
types what I see at the moment is people
recycling their capital and trying to
jump into this once-in-a-lifetime
opportunity it doesn't happen often but
this industry I think is ripe and has 30
years in front of it and you can invest
into it and you can build step by step
and
a lot of very very good companies will
be created in this industry a lot I mean
a lot of employment a lot of taxable
income so it's absolutely worthwhile to
be here and and and discuss it with all
of you and it's going to grow up it's um
it's it's yeah that's what I see but
right now I think the capital in this
market needs to be convinced and
recycles out of the Canadian market out
of the American market and I think right
now what I see is a Canadian investing
into the American market next so we will
see a lot there and then I think we will
jump to Europe so we will have we have a
bit of time still and as things become
clearer good management teams become
clearer good strategies etc so yeah from
the American perspective that's why I'm
here you know I'm I'm curious for
banging about what's happening in the
European market so I'm finding out about
things like your program incubators and
things by basically getting out of the
office and putting myself out there
meeting people and this is my second
year at ICBC Berlin I made some
strategic partnerships here last time
and that's why I'm back because it was
effective if you want to meet the people
who are doing things you've got to go
meet them there isn't information I
would tell you though I would not know
about you Marguerite if I hadn't come
here last year so to your point there
isn't information that I'm finding and I
have my ear to the ground of the capital
markets I don't know what's happening in
Europe
other than the efforts that I've made to
figure it out for myself
other than coming to the ICBC every time
you can to meet all the people and all
the movers and shakers let's hear it for
fantastic at all thank you that was
great
I'm sorry out of time that was wonderful
I appreciate you all for getting up so
very early in the morning because if you
were at the Gretchen last night you know
that we kind of Turks it out a little
bit there's a lot of