Beasley everybody no podium in a hard
act to follow I have a couple slides
this is gonna be a fun one here main
thing like since we're in Canada I'm
gonna try not to offend Canada even
though there's a lot of examples of what
not to do here just like Colorado which
is gonna be very very important and I
know lunch is coming so I'll try to do a
high-level keep things brief and good so
when you think about a Canadian company
how are you gonna be relevant in this
big change and what's your play
internationally that's really what we
help to do just to kind of start as a
disclaimer I'm not a lawyer I'm not a
CPA you must use these professionals in
everything you do and as you're growing
this industry this is going to be a
normal business and if you don't set up
yourself to be a normal business you
will be crushed as litigation is
skyrocketing just a quick background on
myself I started in the cannabis
industry in Colorado 2006 after the
military I've seen the entire cannabis
industry emerge from the first
commercial sales in Colorado which we
kind of helped to start with medical and
on the first adult use market scaled and
have worked in 34 states worked in 16
countries already so we have a pretty
good idea of what's going on in the
world and specifically we're not
guessing when it comes to some of these
countries and policies that we're gonna
go over but I started I'm a farm kid
from Wisconsin really deep focus on
agriculture which is what we started in
but now having worked in all sectors of
the industry a lot of the truths that
will share about Canada are very very
similar to other markets but the thing
you have to remember is that US cannabis
and Canadian cannabis it doesn't
translate to international cannabis and
you can't just think you're gonna launch
some gummy bear brand here and then be
selling in Germany next year which is
pretty pretty important so when we think
about the world and what happened from
California Compassionate Care Act in
1996 how that's scaled and what's
happened it's pretty [ __ ] incredible
to think that we actually have a
bonafide industry today that's not only
disrupting but interrupting normal
business processes
and as you're looking at the rest of the
world a lot of like that black area
still it's only a matter of time and
it's not going to be Finland producing
in for Finland it's not going to be this
continual rollout model where can you
produce lower cost at the same standards
to achieve like a global domination and
that's what the big players that haven't
gotten into this space yet are really
looking at us this scales so today we're
going to cover some on the global side
some on the US side and some on the
Canada side and really think of how it
all comes together and the key
difference here like I have a consulting
company we have venture capital
companies now do private equity
international the really similarity here
in everything is capital without it
you're screwed and how to actually get
institutional capital or private
investors is challenging everyone went
public here in Canada good for a few
hasn't worked out for a lot of them and
based on a few of the things that we'll
talk about it's not going to work for
many of them so private capital as
you're scaling is so so critical to
focus on a big thing about international
like I said it's not the same as the US
or Canada in Canada and Uruguay very
ballsy in legalizing a narcotic for
adult use purposes and God bless Canada
for having the first mover advantage in
this but Health Canada had no idea how
to go from medical to recreational and
it's been one of the biggest
catastrophes I'd say in our industry
since the inception like bigger than
vape things bigger than like children
getting products or wrongful deaths so
when you're going international you have
to know the rules to play this game an
international policy when it comes to
the single convention how the UN is
looking at this how that you like whe o
is looking at this if you don't know
those rules and you're planning global
partnerships it's not just about some
country in Zimbabwe or Swaziland or
Uganda or some Giorgio RAC play that's
gonna be a big big deal they have to be
compliant with these drug policies
because if not they just won't happen
GMP is a big thing everyone talks about
it thinks it's so so easy and Health
Canada there were five maybe six
companies that are now getting GMP
compliance
but it's not just about doing GMP to
sell to Europe you're trying to make
sure that you don't have risks and
liabilities as your business scales and
GMP is just one of these the really
important one if you're in cultivation
GA CP everyone thinks GA P is so
important but it's actually GA CP good
agricultural collection practices that
most of these businesses are founded on
but if you're doing anything
international GA P G ACP GMP GDP and GL
p for laboratories critical because
that's the big challenge here that
you're gonna see in Canada when we think
about the US quick which many Canadian
companies are coming down to launch into
Canada because they're highly
capitalized from their public markets
you think in the United States there are
47 of 50 states that have some sort of
medical cannabis law we've got 11 states
that have adult use 31 that have some
sort of commercial sales for medical
that's over half and like the previous
gentleman said like once there's 25 rec
states it's only a matter of time but
you have to know in the United States
medical legalization will happen first
and just because everyone thinks Trump's
gonna legalize it to try to get
reelected even if he tried there are
many steps and policies that would have
to happen before that would happen so
focus on medical legalization in the
u.s. first followed by an adult use and
it's not a question of if this is going
to happen it's when but in the United
States with Colorado right where we were
and started to now think of all of those
blue states that adult use is happening
and yeah Michigan is slow Illinois is
about to happen Maine and Massachusetts
kind of messed up programs initially but
over ninety two percent of all of the
revenue in the United States reported
today is from the adult use side and I'm
a disabled vet that's how I got into the
cannabis industry and we have to
remember the medical side from taxes and
quality but here even in Canada the
medical industry who's talking about it
who cares about it anymore and the
medical is the foot into the door into
the adult use market we've seen it in
the United States a hundred percent of
the time if you were medical licensed
you have some sort of first preference
to get to adult use sounds similar to
Canada
so big opportunities in the United
States now it's not a closed market but
it's state-by-state and until interstate
commerce is allowed from federal
legalization I can't produce an Oregon
and then ship it to another state so you
have to have new companies in each state
new business partners sometimes there's
residency requirements you look at
Arkansas v cultivation processing
licenses for 3 million people if that
was Colorado equivalent you'd have 10
growers for Colorado the growers that's
about 1.4 billion of the addressable
revenue so when there's a limited market
and you can get into it you have to get
into it first but the big ones right now
in the United States Illinois when you
think about that map first adult use in
the Midwest and Michigan was a very we
call it like one of the dirty seven
states it had a medical program you can
have the cards on the wall and like not
sell it but then of course like four
billion dollars of cannabis were
flooding out of Michigan every year to
the to the East Coast same thing in
Maine so you think Illinois adult use is
going to be huge major Canadian
companies are applying there it's gonna
be very very challenging but twelve
million people adult use social
consumption lounges near the borders
it's going to be phenomenal and you also
have to think about the neighboring
countries or states like here in Canada
you've got ninety percent of your
population within 10 miles of the US
border and then 90 percent of all
Canadians live in three territories that
have shitty shitty laws when you're like
Quebec Montreal Ontario and great
British Columbia you've missed out on
five six billion dollars in revenue just
from not doing it correctly so you're
thinking about these new states as
they're coming up California for example
nearly 70% of all municipalities have no
cannabis laws yet some allow medical
production some allow maybe just medical
sales the same thing that's going to
happen here in Canada so you have to
target the municipalities get those
licenses and be compliant with the
municipalities being compliant with
Health Canada laws but the United States
is not over it's just begun and it's not
just these few big MSO multi-state
operators that are going to take the
whole pie but getting in into a new
state
vital in the beginning it's so much you
think Florida
you want to buy part of a license for 86
million dollars today that license we
helped to get like four years ago they
spent less than a million to get it so
just these pieces of paper have major
major value but the United States you'll
notice a lot of Canadian focus coming
down trying to get it and capitalized
but there's one problem here investing
into something that's federally illegal
as a foreign national not the best idea
especially when you have boards of
directors and optics and image I have no
problem very confederal law in the
United States as long as I'm following
state or territory law Canada by
legalizing recreational cannabis
violated international law same with
Uruguay and this could cause some major
challenges which we'll get into so let's
get into Canada here kind of been a fun
market to watch I really appreciated
your medical market initially and what
that did but then with the public
infusion of capital 2014-2015 it caused
let's just call it chaos in Canada and
the rest of the world where I remember
speaking in San Francisco for ICBC about
a year ago if you put a million dollars
into the top Canadian public LPS you'd
have 4.1 million dollars today an Aurora
stock down four or five percent and with
the news coming out today it'll probably
be seven eight percent by the end of the
day they all got huge but none of them
remembered that you have to make revenue
eventually and you have to meet these
projections and yes taking over the
world this a giant public company sounds
great but everyone wants you every
single day and if you're trying to do
this how your redeploying capital in
buying other companies if you're a
canadian public company and in the
united states I mean Laurie Ajax was
here earlier today I mean there's some
major potential implications of being a
foreign national company and investing
into something federally illegal the
United States we love to protect our
businesses and our IP what would happen
then as we get closer to federal
legalization we want to kick out some of
these companies you have to have some
divesting strategies as well if you're
gonna get into the United States and how
you're going to structure those
companies
some major things with the cultivation
area which is expanded that's an actual
photo on the left there of cannabis that
was purchased recently here in Canada
quality is something that people don't
understand once you're an LP if you've
bought rec cannabis here it's pretty
pathetic
it's like Colorado in like 2010 and
there are some good companies that are
doing this but the packaging and the
quality and everyone keeps talking about
all these shortages which we're going to
get into but they don't realize that
quality is something that's paramount
and when you think internationally
quality is a different term it's not
like this is dank bud bro that's
consumer quality but the GMP the quality
standards by Canada you have to hit that
but you have to also remember consumer
quality it's the same problem that
better can has like world leader in
cannabis exports nineteen countries six
varieties that are shipped into Germany
and based on the price and the quality
most people don't like it but it's some
of the most standard deviation like the
lowest in the world like for consistent
supply but it's garbage and no one likes
to smoke it or the DRI kind of horrible
cannabis here you have to start going
towards quality and not selling popcorn
nugs it's just it's not how you launch a
quality brand and when we think about
brands it's very very hard to brand like
a Johnny Apple but when you're an apple
sauce company or Heinz ketchup that's
different than growing the dankest or
heirloom tomatoes and as a farmer I love
the quality side but the consumer
packaged goods and brands five six years
ago we just made fun of them because
nothing was quality and they kept
growing more and more the quality is
going to be the key differentiator
in these markets as they expand this
this is pretty hilarious here in Canada
there's almost 700 pending LPS right now
because your licensing process kind of
sucked you got your first license had to
build out your whole expensive facility
have your inspections and then have a
license with almost 700 in the queue and
this much supply that's just sitting
around it's not that there's a shortage
of supply they're saying this so that
investment dollars continue to flow into
these LPS to build-out cultivation
centers but I'm from northern Wisconsin
as a kid
there's a sink called winter Canada is
not the best place to grow cannabis even
with greenhouses even in an old
Hershey's chocolate factory your cost of
production are high your taxes are
horrible and it's very very hard to
structure correctly in Canada so when
you're thinking about the average cost
of production and what's price the
prices are happening at building more
and more cultivation centers in Canada
is not the option and if you're a craft
grower which god bless you and I love
that side if you don't have distribution
to get into the sales channels you don't
have a shot we've seen the same thing in
the United States and in Colorado we
started to put in door out of business
with big greenhouses back two thousand
nine ten and eleven greenhouse is a very
good thing but then Aurora with their
massive facility it's a hundred and ten
million Canadian to build that thing we
could have built that with like Turkish
company some Dutch companies for about
twenty five so this is not the place
where international exports are going to
happen even though you were the first to
be able to do it but there is plenty of
cannabis here and then allowing outdoor
production for oils as you're getting
into your extracted products in the
future that's gonna be a key key part
that's gonna put a lot of these indoor
facilities out of business when you're
thinking about wholesale price like
benchmarks does a great job in the
United States this is the average then
for all track sales in Canada at this
point when you're thinking about better
can like I mentioned they can only sell
for 2.5 euros a gram to the office of
medical cannabis like in the Netherlands
they then sell that you know to the bee
farm bee farm to an importer importers
to a distributor distributor to a
pharmacy that's why in Germany you'll
see cannabis from 18 to 25 euros a gram
that the grower only got 2.5 a gram for
that they're growing it for maybe at 125
to 140 a gram if your margins that
you're nothing that big sale that they
did to London the first one of like 400
grams they made less than a thousand
euros from doing that sale and the same
things gonna happen to Canadian
companies so all the people building
these facilities out thinking just
because you got first mover advantage to
ship to the world it's all about price
if you meet the quality standard and
you're the lowest price you get the
generic
tract for the country and it's not going
to be the Canadians for much much longer
this is huge for what's gonna happen to
you flower and a few types of topicals
and basic oils was not the way to launch
cannabis in Canada and 2007 and December
was the first time for all track sales
in the United States we saw that it
wasn't flower anymore and I love a good
joint but when you can just hit a vape
pen or like eat an edible it's very very
different and gets a lot more consumers
so this is gonna explode in Canada with
all the vaping issues that have happened
in the United States it's not the
cannabis that's dangerous here it's
thing we had no regulations for this and
then you're seeing the same thing with
tobacco so the companies that launched
that aren't using vitamin E or
polypropylene Ollis their solvents or
their viscous agents not reintroducing
terpenes or fake flavors those companies
are gonna scale and do phenomenal here
and it's gonna change the face of the
Canadian cannabis industry now in
October when those start to come out in
sales like December through February and
these brands launch it's gonna change
because your flower quality has been
crap your packaging has been pretty
crappy there's not been many stores when
you think in Montreal for a while that
one store for that whole place or here
in BC like there's so few same thing in
Mont Ontario as new products come out
and consumer packaged goods brands with
distribution will change this landscape
and I easily foresee that probably 60 70
percent of your market within a year and
a half to two years will be infused
extracted products but your packaging
you know has a couple issues too to be
seen here so some major opportunities
for Canada even though I'm saying some
of the challenges for it there's gonna
be more and more consolidations you're
gonna see major ancillary plays for like
ancillary products and ancillary
services since this is the first
legalized real country no offense
Uruguay you have this opportunity that
what works here for a country will then
scale to the United States and like our
point-of-sale systems our packaging
companies our distribution companies are
going to mirror and a lot of Canadian
companies will come down
take that market share so if you're in
the ancillary sign for cannabis you're
in a good place it's also a way less
risky you can do banking it's not
cannabis and that's something that for
the US has major major value it's not
your quality of how good you grow we'd
like not saying that they don't do that
well in Canada you of course do but not
making it to the stores and you've got
here British Columbia the California of
Canada grows copious amounts of cannabis
that's not text like taxed and regulated
so highly
so as this starts to change and more and
more testing is coming out and these big
producers start making quality that's
where I see some key pivotal plays but
also your distribution if you don't have
distribution which a lot of the big LPS
and pub codes have tried to tie up your
products don't make it to market
same thing in California in California
if you're not paying for shelf space as
a brand or have a really good
distribution company your craft cannabis
or your products don't make the shelves
and then you'll see companies like
canned Essen not giving a plug out here
for colors in a pretty logo small
cultivation center but with a
distribution license that buys wholesale
repackages under their brands pay for
shelf space and flood that product
around the market and the same thing
that's gonna happen here in Canada just
like many of the big Opie's they buy
from other small producers repackage it
and then get that to the stores and as
your brands start to establish that's
something most people haven't been able
to consider you've got Edison and Cova
and a few but it gets larger brands will
dictate the future and a lot of them
will be regional and territorial based
exports were huge for Canada because you
used to just have bedrock in in the
Netherlands five or six of those bigger
producers starting to do their press
releases about exports but it's still
not been that high because
internationally without doctoral
education there are no patients and
without patients there's no clients and
then no clients there's no revenue and
then there's no business that's been the
problem with Aurora and canopy and like
tilray
getting all these licenses all over the
world which we've got licenses in
thirteen countries right now but a lot
of them you have to hold it and it's a
longer term international play and
you're producing that for like medical
pharmaceutical cannabis
versus we're gonna have rekt cannabis in
Germany anytime soon but the export side
is what caused a lot of their value to
go huge through the roof but they were
thinking the rest of the world was going
to be like the United States and Canada
International we export flour and oil
compounding happens in pharmacies it's
not vape pens it's not suppositories to
get into that side you're talking 7 to
11 years
of preclinical clinical three phases of
development but that's like the
international play that's really really
valuable that most people aren't seeing
it's not just about shipping dry flour
around the world but like our license in
Portugal we could produce for about 13
euro cents a gram a tenth of what it
costs in the Netherlands and compared to
Canada
I mean maybe an eighth or I'm sorry like
a twelfth as much as Canada and we're
already in Europe that's why when we
talk about Columbian some of these other
countries there's major opportunities
but you have to use what you did in
Canada to scale to the world and not
just entrench yourself thinking this is
where you're gonna produce for the rest
of the all time your medical market
cannot be forgotten about patients or
how this market happened and we have to
always remember that from different
taxes and the same quality and testing
standards but being able to ship
cannabis in the mail awesome what you
first started here but it's it's being
completely forgotten I see a major
opportunity there long term for a few of
the companies that get into it and are
patient focused but it's something that
every single market remember for the
u.s. getting in from a medical
standpoint first is how you get into the
adult use market and if you get into
medical and just completely forget those
roots it is a total addressable market
that you're just forgetting about and
then the brand licensing the loyalties
it just doesn't happen but everything we
know about medical cannabis and
recreational cannabis in the US and
Canada is the same kind of thing it's
not true medical this other thing is
going to happen called Pharma and
they're very interested in the space
it's just way too risky for them right
now
and we already passed this threshold
called a safety profile so that's the
major value when you develop a new drug
getting past that point so once you're
getting international you think about
pharmaceutical if you're doing clinical
trials if you're getting drug
registrations just like all the value of
Israel it's not about
production it's about their old medical
research that's gonna be applicable to
the rest of the world and if you're
starting to do that in Canada it's a
major foot in the door for this
international expansion you know on your
REC side it's gonna be big it's not
gonna be as big as most people think
because your taxes are too high your
climate cost of production or too high
your illicit market it's gonna be harder
to fight in Canada than it is in the
United States because it's been a very
robust program and originally medical
producers could produce it all over the
place have their own plans then they
kind of stop that once those plants are
out there this is a weed they grow and
people continue to grow it but for a
supplemental income source it's not as
lucrative on a long-term basis but it's
gonna be very challenging to fight but
if if anyone's bought a four-year old
joint in Canada like these packages like
take it out of the big box it's like
this big plastic thing a lot of lessons
could be learned from the United States
cannabis companies and what we've done
so just think what's working in the
United States when it comes to packaging
and marketing and how to actually mark
it on a national basis which you can do
here still a lot of regulations around
it we couldn't do that in the United
States that's why it's been so so slow
but adult use in Canada is gonna go fast
and you had a really shitty first year I
mean pretty pathetic for what it should
have been mostly based on the
municipality and territorial laws
ramping up like the retail store
licenses and there's more illegal stores
in BC than legal stores and they're way
cheaper and you just walk in like you
don't even have to show an ID it's
pretty incredible but not advocating
illicit sales when you think about where
Productions happening and what the tax
rates are there and how they give
permits this is very important for when
it comes to cost of production if you're
trying to do this in Manitoba or certain
places there's a reason their prices are
higher or a client of ours years ago
like Prince Edward Island like their
cost of production was ridiculous but
they were one of the only ones there now
that this is getting nationalized on a
larger basis it's gonna get huge but
something you have to remember
governments are more addicted to tax
revenue than heroin and once they get a
taste of it they will fight for it more
and more that's why we were very scared
about the l
CVO originally like in ontario like
cannabis stores just going to be done on
like liquor stores we're very scared
about it in long term I do see the
potentiality for this to happen
so getting retail licenses know there
could be a shift but getting them early
is critical to get to revenue side your
hemp side has also been good but you had
Manitoba harvest that like Hillary
bought yours last year your hemp
industry is getting less and less
important because there's so much
competition internationally and it's not
just about growing hemp here and doing
extraction for terpenes or cannabinoids
and shipping around the world but there
are some major opportunities to do hemp
in Canada still but what I do see is
just like the LPS they fought against
outdoor production really heavily in the
beginning because when you have a
Hershey's warehouse that you put tens of
millions of dollars in due to grill weed
inside and then you can just do a big
outdoor harvest harvest it with combines
and have oils and then do extracted
products it's gonna disrupt and
interrupt your entire production market
and it's gonna start happening soon this
next year the amount of outdoor
production that you see it's gonna start
to cause your price of price to come
down and then all of your raw plant
material or your trim from your indoor
facilities that's very very expensive
compared to outdoor it's gonna change
the game just like we did in Colorado
and California and other states that
allow outdoor when we think about what
the biggest issues are your territories
and your municipalities for their
licensing these horrible corrupt lottery
systems I mean three see we do license
applications around the world when we
see lotteries were almost not interested
because you can have the best team ever
and then just you know pull them out of
a hat but when you see the judge that
stalled all of the license issuance in
Ontario for what happened in Toronto
recently like one person randomly gets
three randomly and then you know I have
a group that puts in ten and gets none
you know there's issues with that and
it's gonna continue to happen in the
United States you see the FBI getting
into like that mayor in Massachusetts
it's like yeah you want a license here
600,000 bucks did it for for people
that's been happening for over a decade
it's nothing new and they're gonna start
getting into this more and more and as
Health Canada really tries to maintain
their image
they're gonna start looking at these
things deeper and deeper so just know
like do things legal do things compliant
do not cut corners and do not get into
the shady side because if you do long
term it will come out so a little bit
here on investing like we manage venture
funds private equity I see major value
in the private side still for Canada and
for the rest of the world but it's such
a new industry from this side most
institutional capital won't touch it and
banks aren't giving loans but how you
raise capital and how you look at what
investments are real this is a major
opportunity like I could still get 18
percent interest on real estate like I
say that to a normal real estate
investor and they're like what like yeah
you're owning a building and Triple Net
leasing it to the operator you're not
even profiting from cannabis the real
estate is what everything is built off
of from hands-on companies so if you're
looking at the real estate here in
Canada for more and more of these places
I'm not even interested in cultivation a
little interested in the processing
extremely interested in the retail real
estate that's what's gonna continue to
change and those those spaces just like
we see in the US will be the major
revenue drivers when you're raising
capital you have to be transparent do
not say that you're gonna continue to
sell pounds for $4,000 a pound I mean in
Colorado five years ago it was 4,400
today wholesale is less than 600 and if
you think that you're gonna be selling
this like your investors are gonna get
more and more seasoned so be honest be
transparent show how markets are going
to change and how you're gonna continue
to lower your costs and run this like a
normal business the key thing for
cannabis when I look at an investment
which and probably see a hundred decks a
week I take the word cannabis out if
you're a company would you still be
interesting if it wasn't just cannabis
hype oh it's CBD dryer sheets
oh it's CBD pet food like what is the
other market applicable to this and how
would you be an attractive like
acquisition target when you think about
these few big brands in the middle and
then all the brands that you know and
are familiar with around this this is
going to be cannabis and it's only a
matter of time and it's not going to be
consolation until Ray and Aurora in the
middle they're even
they've been trying that but they're
gonna get so crushed on stock prices in
this next year is they're not hitting
their projections that it's that sites
really hurting the investor confidence
in the space because it sounded so
important it was so hard to raise
capital so what's everyone do run to
Canada list on the CSE now there are
good public companies up here but 80
percent are pretty much fraudulent and
lie on a daily basis to investors in the
industry press releases about growing in
Malta and like what they're gonna be
doing here they're clinical trials so
they're shipping to San Diego like be
real be transparent but it's only a
matter of time until this happens and
you have to know your exit as a company
are you gonna cash flow or you're gonna
have dividends are you going to sell the
company are gonna join other companies
are you gonna go public but how is the
investor going to get their money back
how are you gonna use their capital and
deploy their capital and what sorts of
returns could they potentially get never
guarantee anything here but you're
trying to always think who's the bigger
fish that you're gonna buy or get bought
by or try to become but it's no longer
trying to be Philip Morris it's about
trying to get bought by Philip Morris
because this industry is normalized it's
getting more and more normalized and
it's only a matter of time until the big
institutional capital comes in
so to go around the world here kind of
quickly we work all over the world just
to know the opportunities for Canadian
companies there they're not gonna
legalize rec anytime soon here so don't
don't think that's going to be the way
you're gonna sell vape cartridges in
Germany
I mean Germany's got less than 30
doctors making prescriptions less than a
quarter million total prescriptions and
the price is so high and insurance still
has problems with it when you're
thinking about where to produce in
Europe for Europe I mean a license we
have in Portugal and a few of those
countries very much matter because if we
can reduce cheaper and you're in Europe
they're gonna give preference over
buying your products but it's not just
about growing in Germany or growing like
we got two of the eleven licenses in
Denmark I didn't build a building there
I sold a license for five and a half
million the other one I'm keeping for
importing to Denmark but you have to
think what's the cost of reduction in
each market how is it applicable to the
rest of a union or a pharmaceutical act
and how that's going to be a bigger play
not just that you have a license in
Zimbabwe now you're late
doubled your value that's been the major
problem here but Europe will be a huge
market with more doctor education so if
you are a pub Co or a private Co no
matter where you are internationally you
must focus on doctor and patient
education because without it there are
no prescriptions and not like
recommendations in the US or
prescriptions here but you have to have
those otherwise there's no business
you're thinking about Africa a couple of
these colors aren't coming through the
only major countries that matter is
South Africa and Lesotho right now and
of course there's Canadian public
companies in each of those all of the
other countries that have really come
forward with programs are not compliant
with international law but the reason I
love South Africa is that they're a
Picts country which means what they do
there matters the same as the FDA so
when you're thinking about international
cannabis how is it applicable with the
rest of the world and if you're
developing products there or
intellectual property how that's gonna
scale or be applicable to other markets
but Africa for you anymore I always
think where can I produce in a country
or continent for that country or
continent under their laws other than
just thinking I'm going to do European
GMP everyone thought that at first it's
way more expensive and challenging to
get than you think and if you mess up
your first inspection they're maybe not
coming back ever
and like when those Germans come to your
place in Macedonia or you know to George
or wherever you're going to be producing
if it's not ready and right you're
screwed and if they don't come back or
if they don't come back for two or three
years you have no market to sell to so
by the time you get into these
international standards hire good
consultants for it hire good experts
that know it hire good legal that know
it to show how it's going to be
applicable other than just trying to
have a press release to be able to like
get investors interested in your space
this has been a slow one for us I know
that like the imports for South Korea
everyone was talking about Thailand for
a while anyone realized Thailand is just
for domestic purposes in research right
now it's not about producing in Thailand
all cheap and selling to the rest of the
world they don't have a law that allows
that and yes you can educate the
government and help with that but if
it's for domestic production how does
that help your Canadian public value
especially for a total addressable
market that does
have qualifying conditions that are like
pain PTSD glaucoma like internationally
if there's not qualifying conditions of
pain or PTSD in the US that's 96% of all
medical cards that means that you're
gonna have no one like Texas childhood
epilepsy it means you have 1,300 kids
you could potentially sell products do
with those three licenses granted Texas
is the third highest population in the
country but there's no total addressable
market based on qualifying conditions so
that part is key for international
Austria none of those colors came
through but Australia's been really slow
and interesting a few big changes are
coming they're more licenses and there
they are a picks country which means
their standards are going to be good for
international some of the few good
Australian companies that can take and
focus on this region are gonna do
incredible with New Zealand's reck kind
of medical programs challenging getting
better it's wrecked kind of coming
soonish gonna be good but don't talk
about your Vanuatu rec company gonna
like change the world like shipwrecked
cannabis to Canada and undercut them
because Health Canada is really really
protective of your market right now they
won't even allow exports of genetics
anymore for most of our companies and
the same thing from like an import
standpoint they're really trying to
protect this market so trying to import
to Canada is not the best acquisition
strategy to like be buying or trying to
develop towards at this point none of
the colors here again unfortunately but
you've got four or five medical
countries Colombia has really taken all
the news in Colombia of course near the
equator low cost of production they're
only allowed 40,000 tons of annual
production as a country my license in
Portugal is four hundred and
thirty-eight thousand tonnes a year by
the UN it's like one license of mine is
like 11 times the entire country of
Colombia and Colombia Khan has a season
pass
I love Colombia very much most of the
genetics that the Canadian LP shipped
down there were there dankest coolest
buds from indoor warehouses up here that
don't grow very well in greenhouses in
Colombia hence all the mold issues and
so forth there will be five or six
amazing companies that come out of
Colombia but it's the non psychoactive
licenses to focus on for now and again
wearing in South America or Central
America can you produce
for the rest of that area under their
standards compared to trying to do EU
GMP and Colombia to ship to the rest of
the world or Europe that's harder it's
gonna take more time it's gonna take a
long time to get to that revenue you get
to get total revenue first if you focus
on that region first you know I always
use and kind of close with this like I
remember like being in Boy Scouts and
playing risk like late at night and like
wanting to stab people and like 12-hour
games and like I hate this person now
it's very similar right now and all the
LPS are like little childish boys
playing you know what a fire station you
know during Boy Scouts when they're kids
they're like I'm gonna take over the
world I got Australia that's two troops
in South America that's three and where
you put your pieces matter and you got
one shot for where you're gonna put your
pieces on the board today and where
you're gonna establish partnerships and
relationships and raise capital or like
Amazon on billions and billions not sir
paying certain taxes where your domicile
where you have capital coming in and
going out of and how you're gonna trade
you think about where all the Canadian
public companies that launched up here
that was the easy place that's why
everyone did it and was so unregulated
like practical pink slip type listings
that should have never been listed as
public companies the same [ __ ] is about
to happen in London in Frankfurt in
Israel and Tel Aviv exchange in the
Australian exchange you're gonna see
probably a thousand public companies
launch in this next year that are
cannabis companies that have nothing
going on but there will be some good
ones in there but with the CSE and
others not allowing blind shorting
anymore they know there's a problem in
this market and they know that it's
going to continue to go down and some of
them will scale and be incredible we've
got one shot now to put this on and
partnerships you know in human evolution
you've got competition and you've got
collaboration collaboration always wins
like fighting people you know doesn't
wins like what can you do who can you
partner with how can you get bigger
because your company no matter how good
it is there's others doing the same
thing and you're not that special you're
not that unique even though you might
grow the dankus flower or have the
coolest water-soluble concentrates how
you're going to partner with people how
you're going to get distribution how
you're going to raise additional capital
like its capital raise capital raise
capital raise and more markets but it's
not about vape pens from Canada being
shipped to the world know the rules of
each of these jurisdictions find local
partnerships there that know that market
and can scale that market with you other
than trying to go over like an aurora or
a canopy and trying to take over the
world by yourself it didn't work for
Alexander the Great you get too far away
from your home base and then everything
crumbles didn't work for Rome either
like you can only grow so fast so far
but cannabis is here to stay I mean it's
going to disrupt almost all industries
that we know everyone talks about hemp
CBD right now what about paper and
cotton and timbers and plastics the long
term play for this industry is
phenomenal and getting an early stage
into the private companies doing it is
where I've seen the biggest returns
that's why we focus on that and know
that once this boards established just
like monopoly you can only buy a hotel
or get boardwalk or Broadway like one
time you get it solidify it raise it and
protect the hell out of it
I see more value for intellectual
property right now than even cannabis
that's why constellation and a lot of
these other companies in canopy they're
buying ship companies that just did some
really nice IP protections for things
they're gonna need in the future so
whatever you're doing protect it get
legal get compliant it's the only way to
transition and get your pieces on the
board early not sure how I am on time
four minutes
awesome well thanks for letting me share
any any quick questions from anybody
here yes sir
one more time for Nick Easley no thank
you buddy
[Music]
always informative here
and remember questions go up at the end
like not a question about strategy we're
seeing a lot of companies going into
Canada taking advantage of the publicly
traded markets and bringing that capital
back into the US a lot of them are
buying hemp and in order to get across
the 280e provisions probably with the
strategy of utilizing THC down the road
but what about Puerto Rico right now for
a lot of companies going into the u.s.
Puerto Rico is the only place in the
world you can go and not be forced to
pay US income tax so for CBD companies a
lot of them won't survive without that
kind of benefit where do you see Puerto
Rico being in the mix with international
cannabis as a strategy
you got that 183 day clause for
residency which kind of makes it
challenging great question in the u.s.
that IRC 280 e it's a tax law from 1982
to keep cocaine smugglers from being
able to have like laundromats and like
launder their money we can't
doctor our cost of goods sold I mean -
hurricanes and a few things Puerto Rico
could be good from a tourist standpoint
I didn't focus on that territory I
focused on Guam I mean I've got 1.6
billion people that live within a
four-hour flight of Guam medicals legal
Rex legal incoming and it's very very
hard the CBD side is gonna be a lot less
regulated soon because we had our first
farm bill 2014 the 18 farm bill and now
it's starting to change with a few of
the banking laws that are in the Senate
right now the CBD side and the hemp side
should have banking by 2020 and also not
have IRC 280 which is the foot in the
door which then means cannabis companies
soon won't have to deal with that once
medical legalization happens could be
some interesting domicile plays
therefore like that being domiciled
shipped there and then shipped to the US
I haven't seen anyone take advantage of
it yet but it's it's definitely for the
CBD side of potentiality well it's great
any other questions
all right well let's go eat them one
more time easily thank you all very much
[Music]
[Applause]