oh I'm sorry I have a loud voice can you
hear me better now all right I'm excited
to be here uh for those that don't know
me I'm from Houston Texas which is a
weird uh place to be in the Cannabis
industry but I've been following the
industry for six years now and I came to
the first ICBC conference back in San
Francisco and it's a little trivia I
think it's the only conference I've ever
just attended I'm usually like either
speaking or something to do with the
media but I do two things but they both
revolve around following the industry
for investors really and I run 420
investor which focuses on public
companies and you know we have one
that's about to be public here so we'll
definitely talk about that and then I
also run new cannabis Ventures which
covers the whole space and
it's the basic purpose of new canvas
Ventures is to to keep a pulse on on the
business side of the industry and help
investors and operators kind of find out
what's really going on and so I'm glad
you're here with us today we have three
very different types of people and
companies and we'll be learning from
them a lot has changed two of these are
OG guys that I've known for a while so
I'm going to start from the far right
so we have Scott Van ricksell from bang
if I'm sure everybody's pretty familiar
with bang but he's been in the industry
since 2010 and uh about to go public so
we're going to hear that perspective uh
of what it's like to transition from
private to public and then we have Dean
arbit who's been in the industry since
2011 I believe and I didn't even know
this I've known him from the media side
and all of his Investments but he has
been involved with a really interesting
company called Wagner Demas which is a
technology company for pre-rolls and
other things as well but.com and then I
just met Carly and uh pinch hitting
actually and I wanted to point out Jake
had a family emergency you may be
expecting to see Jake Highmark he could
make it and Aaron also had a family
emergency unfortunately but we're lucky
to have Carly and uh I'm going to let
everybody start off by introducing
themselves but Carly is from garden
Society all three of these folks are
from California but what I think is
going to you're going to find to be so
interesting is that they're all involved
not only necessarily just in the rest of
the country but really in the rest of
the world as well things are changing
that much so it's cool to be big in
California but there's a whole big world
out there we're going to find out so
what I'd like to do is start off with
you Scott and then we'll work our way
back if you could just talk about what
you were doing before you came into the
industry and what you're doing now
um actually what I was doing is kind of
how I ended up in this
um
I had a chocolate and gelato company in
Albuquerque with my brother
uh
we had a
problem with our gelato and a friend of
mine who opened one of the first
cannabis Labs here
uh Robert Martin invited me out as he
was opening his lab and he took me
around showed me the dispensaries and as
a chef I was dismayed and then when you
add that there was supposed to be
medical products I was
kind of embarrassed
not that people weren't
capable is that people weren't making
the choice to to kind of do things what
I saw as right
came out a couple months later started
bang and we progressed from there into
what I believe to be one of the leading
cannabis brands for finished goods
Dean same question to you
thanks Ellen so I started in 2011 uh
previously I was in the media space
had an exit there and uh
initially got into the media side of the
Cannabis industry was it as an
Enthusiast uh as as long as
as I can remember but um got into the
media space which gave me a lot of
visibility
um and uh a lot of color a lot of data
and then a couple years later started to
uh actually make investments and and uh
embed with companies and so actually one
of the an event that I founded New West
Summit was where I met Mitchell
and Morgan my partners uh in Wagner
demos which is a very interesting
technology it's essentially we've
patented a
a pre-roll platform that allows us to
produce uh in great scale and so we work
with big public company in Canada to
license that and then the other
interesting thing I do so we we produce
our own we're our own likes to see in
California working with other brands and
then on the retail side
I help run bud.com which right now will
be Statewide
delivery in California
sometime in the second quarter and then
we're also launching an online store for
non-thc goods that we'll be able to ship
worldwide CBD and
merchandise and that type of stuff so
I mean Carly Warner same for you sure so
uh Carly Warner with Garden Society just
like Aaron but a little lower altitude
um we had founded the company in 2016
that's when I entered the Cannabis
industry uh previously was in wine for
10 years which is where I met Aaron and
we really launched Garden society as a
way to reach women in a mark in a market
that where they weren't being reached
and in a way that they weren't being
talked spoken to so we're really proud
of what we're building we're really
excited to be working with a lot of
different partners within the industry
to make sure that we can help break that
stigma down and make a change you
weren't just in the wine Industries with
constellation Brands right yes I was
with constellation Brands and actually
helped launch Aaron's husband's wine
brand through that company which is how
we met
um yeah okay so now you know a little
bit about who uh who you're going to
learn from today so my first question is
for both of you on the right you guys
like I said are kind of OG's in the
industry you've been around for a long
time and things are definitely changing
right now and I was wondering if you
could share your perspectives on
compared to five years ago perhaps how
things have changed in terms of the
capital markets and raising capital
um you and I kind of spoke about earlier
that the the idea of institutional money
uh uh was absolutely unheard of five
years ago
um that's that's an obvious significant
change I think the risk
factor of people feeling comfortable now
that companies are public there's more
of them there's more options there's
more sites like yourself that have are
providing good information for people
where they're they're able to make
investments without just putting on
green goggles and saying oh I'm going to
turn a million dollars into 50 million
overnight
and and aside from that is also the
maturity of the companies you know the
the even our licensing program went from
you know who you could get to now
actively searching out the best and and
I think that that's something that I
then goes to people feeling more
comfortable and mitigation rests is the
maturity of the industry the maturity of
The Operators
um regulation has certainly imposed its
Mighty well in California you look at
how many operators there were in
California
18 months ago to how many are in place
now and
Dean can certainly attest to that
it thinned the herd and that's happening
across the country and California was
unique in showing how that would happen
in that it had a very thriving
functional
in Industry at a large scale
with relatively no regulation and then
suddenly there was regulation whereas if
you take most of the other thing you had
black market but that influence of
Regulation allowed it to grow and I
think that's a testament to the
California companies that survived were
the ones that could adjust quickly and
and I think that that's a big change was
and those companies will be rewarded
Dean you've seen both sides of it the as
an investor and in somebody raising
Capital how things changed I'd probably
just really Echo a lot of Scots thoughts
there the the sophistication level of
investors has has just picked up
um
I think a Big Driver there is uh
Canadian legalization
um what that's done is it's sort of it's
just exacerbated uh I think it's it's
pushed the process along uh for even U.S
based investors who now see essentially
missing the bus
um and then obviously
with constellation
you've got now an Avenue for for
institutional money it's just go north
but still then it sort of matriculates
down so it's it's just essentially
sophistication which is ratcheted up and
I'd say that's probably true for both
investors and operators
if Carly I think your company operates
solely in California right now but
you're raising money from investors and
I'm curious when you have these
conversations how much pressure are they
giving you or how much do they want to
see you guys go outside of California
and what is your philosophy on how to
handle that pressure
so we're definitely getting that
question from all investors that we're
speaking to in a serious manner
we aren't currently looking to expand
outside of the state but it is in our
you know future plans
um I think you that's mandatory
um but I definitely we're not getting an
immense amount of pressure I would say
to to quickly go multi-state but it's
definitely within like the first couple
of conversations and how many calls a
week do you guys feel from Canadian
investment bankers
Fields most of them but they're quite a
few
how serious they are is questionable but
definitely a few of them have been
okay so my next question and someone
already hinted the constellation
investment but Altria ambev which is
Budweiser
constellation and Molson they've all
made these strategic Investments or
Partnerships into the space and I'm
curious uh you know on the one hand it
kind of validates the industry but on
the other hand I think smaller companies
have to be a little bit concerned and
I'll go in reverse order here how do you
view these big strategic investors
coming into the space is an opportunity
or a threat what's it make you do
differently definitely opportunity
um I think that there's a lot you know
for all of us to learn from what they've
done and the money that they're bringing
in I think we need to be really careful
and then that's a a big reason why we're
trying to scale sustainably right now so
that we can be appealing to someone like
that but um you know it's not necessary
it's a little ways off for us right now
is it impacting you well I think it
validates the space I think uh if you're
talking about look there's still there's
still some murky issues there as far as
legality and when you're talking about
you know the borders and I think it's a
testament to the upside in our industry
the fact that um you know blue chip
brands are now seeing that this this is
a mandatory play
um so I think it's absolutely an
opportunity I think it's one that
operators need to embrace it's just it's
it's not going backwards yeah
yeah are you afraid of this scattered
you embrace it no I think the the first
round of those Investments were those
companies seeing two things
can we cover the losses that we're
seeing in our you know Southern Wine and
Spirits was fairly open about the fact
that in markets where cannabis is
legalized they experience a six to eight
percent reduction in alcohol sales
they've got to cover that somewhere and
I think that the alcohol and tobacco
industry that first round of investment
was a how do we
re-deploy money to a market that we're
losing ground to that's number one
and number two is those smaller initial
pushes were how are our shareholders and
is the market can respond to us as a
company getting our toes wet once they
saw that that was going to work out well
and it was a good thing that's when you
had that second big plops of money now
now they felt comfortable to dive in as
opposed to touch a toe
um
since we start our company I've always
believed the end is either going to be
one of two things bought or bullied and
I would much rather be on the bot than
the bullied I think that the Cannabis
space has to focus on having products
and Concepts that are going to appeal to
those who might bully and are more
appealing to buy I mean you look at
vitamin waters a perfect example
Coca-Cola very easily could have
developed a vitamin water on their own
it was far more efficient for them to
just buy it
um I think that there's a small handful
of cannabis companies 20 years from now
that are going to be still stand alone
unacquired I think that'll be a rarity
not the norm
the tobacco industry the pharmaceutical
industry the alcohol industry they just
have such a head start and such access
to funds that it will make it difficult
for cannabis to just be a monster on its
own but I do see them bringing their
Technologies their their marketing
Insight you know all of us in the room
that are are hiring from those other
Industries we're hiring from those other
Industries because we know they have the
experience to do what we want to do for
our companies
in relatively similar
hate to use the word Vice but Vice
related Industries pharmaceutical being
a little different but you know if
you're going to look how to Market
cannabis well you're going to look to a
company that's been doing either tobacco
or alcohol because those are the most
similar things that are being marketed
and I think that they offer a lot but
they have to be managed and those
relationships have to be managed so you
don't just get pushed so one one thing
I'll add is I think
um
yes those businesses all have uh they're
mature they come from mature Industries
um and they obviously have framework
that can be adapted for our space uh
especially things like CBD where you're
talking about mature distribution
channels the one thing that all those
Industries are going to need and this is
what we all need to understand is it
doesn't work if you go and spin
something up and there's not
authenticity behind it and you and you
get into cannabis
um
I I think the the consumers
um see past that and smell it out
um so I think that bodes well for those
of us that that understand who our
customers are and our customers
ourselves uh and live it
um I think that the marriage between
understanding cannabis and the Cannabis
culture which was bred over the you know
70 plus years of Prohibition that that
doesn't just sort of get wiped away
Altria doesn't get to come in and and
sort of do as they did
um you know with tobacco nicotine so I
think that's the one uh the one piece
that
that I think we all need to understand
is that they need us it's a big part of
it they don't understand the space all
they understand is that it's white hot
and they got to get some
um but they need us to be able to uh
sort of Route them uh and strategize
essentially one thing I'd say what that
is the the worst investment or purchase
one of those big companies could do
would would come with a clearing of
house because to your Testament they you
know a lot about distribution you know a
lot about manufacturing cigarettes
whatever it is what you don't have is
that ongoing relationship with the
Cannabis space and and that is
um
you know very few products that people
consume the product itself do they have
that close connection with I mean in the
alcohol world if you have a really close
connection with alcohol you're an
alcoholic in cannabis it's part of
whether you're using it for healing
purposes or you're using it for
enjoyment or whatever it is there's a
there's a connection there that simply
slapping another brand name or a large
scale operator and I think a good
example of that is you know the
Starbucks guy was I'm going to take over
the world that did not go over well
because the Cannabis space rejected that
idea of just spores feeding that down
their throats and I to agree with Dean
is I think that
we have a lot to offer them as well and
I didn't want to present that we don't I
just also know that
a lot of what we're building in many
cases they already have National
Distribution uh
framework for dealing with interstate
commerce and taxes and Regulatory stuff
I mean that's something that's
completely we deal with a single tax
Authority IRS a state or a federal level
and local but when tobacco and alcohol
moves across state lines there's all
kinds of new tax things that'll again be
new to our industry unless we have
someone kind of showing us the way
through those acquisitions
is so the next question is about CBD
which is really a juggernaut right now
white hot I think you said and I want to
uh everybody to hear kind of your
perspective and we'll start down here
and work back uh on how the popularity
of CBD is impacting your business
uh for us in particular it's it's
significant because our model over the
last
um eight years going on nine years has
been our licensing where we're
collecting a royalty from our licensees
in individual states it's substantial
it's nice it grew our company it allowed
us to spread our brand but it wasn't
reflected in a significant top-line
Revenue generator
um if you reverse the math out it's
great but again it's not our Top Line
it's our licensees Top Line CBD allows
at least our company the ability now to
have that centralized manufacturing
whereas cannabis you're stuck with
potentially 50 separate production
facilities that's economically not
sensible centralized production
centralized distribution is something
that we can accomplish with CBD so I see
that as a great value to our company in
addition
CBD and CBD products and terpene
products are a great way for us to start
to access those cannabis curious
marketplaces where cannabis is not yet
legal and Retail
um
where you're not dependent on you know a
small group of dispensaries you you have
access to
hundreds of thousands of locations
across the country I mean take
cigarettes you know Dina's in the
pre-roll business we have a hemp
cigarette there's 374
000 locations the United States that
sell cigarettes that's it's a huge
access to a market that we wouldn't have
previously had even if we had a licensee
in every state so I think that that's
certainly going to pave the way for
success for for cannabis companies that
have the understanding to see that
that's another part of the plant
another part of the market and another
opportunity for us to access buyers that
we wouldn't necessarily be able to do if
we were just focused on selling
I would say THC products but marijuana
products in the marijuana Marketplace
so uh
I agree I think
CBD and hemp and specifically what the
farm bill brought on uh is it's an
absolute Game Changer uh so for my
businesses for Wagner demos we so we
have a technology that rolls joints I
can roll more joints than people can
smoke uh however hemp
is a different story so now we can sit
there and we can distribute to 370
000 stores smoke shops or C stores
instead of the 500 dispensaries
uh in the U in California
um
so you're talking about a massive broad
market and you're also talking about a
great organic product that we think as
far as smokable hemp Which Scott does
we think it's uh it's a tobacco
cessation play
um not sure about the health benefits
but we think it tastes better and uh
it's less addictive for bud.com same
thing instead of delivering
um you know within a given footprint
that's tied to compliance in in each
state
um
now we can ship worldwide it's just just
that simple so now the you know 97 of
folks that land on bud.com can actually
buy something
Game Changer yeah so it's a California
company uh are you guys able to
capitalize on the CBD Trend yes CBD is
really interesting for us our Target
demographic is definitely right for hemp
Drive CBD products
um that said uh it you know has the low
point of entry and women really feel
safe there's a lot of you know Buzz
around it right now
um it is also a little gray in terms of
legality still for consumption so we're
really as a smaller company trying to
stay laser focused in our THC side of
the business making sure that we build
and scale sustainably in California but
it's definitely something that we keep
on our Horizon in addition to things
like multi-state and that sort of thing
okay and my next question is about
licensing and just I'm sure everybody
can appreciate this uh you just heard it
a while ago 50 different states that you
have to build factories in ETC if you
want to be a THC company and so a lot of
companies right now are partnering
they're jving there's a lot of different
models out there royalty and so I'm
going to start with you Carly why why
are you guys not licensing your name
into other states you said that you're
not there yet so I can understand why
you don't want to physically build out
in other states but what's holding you
back on the licensing part um I think
part of it has just been
focus on building and scaling in
California but again it's something that
you know we've had conversations we've
had conversations with different people
in different states but it's it just
hasn't been the right opportunity yet
but it's not something that the door is
closed to in any way do you think you
guys would rather build out in separate
states or is the licensing smarter how
do you guys go about thinking about it I
mean we have every day is different some
days we're like we should move into this
state right away we have this in this
connection it would be so easy and then
other days we have you know we had
someone call us from Florida we're like
hmm that's interesting we hadn't really
considered Florida as much as you know
Nevada or some other states so it's just
different day to day we just haven't had
the the right opportunity come across
our plate yet but I think once it will
we'll
make that decision then Dean is an
investor and an operator you see both
sides of this what are some of the pros
and cons of owning everything yourself
versus partnering and royalties things
like that I I think we we see
um look California is bigger than Canada
right it's it's a massive Market here
um
our ideas are sort of across the board
with all the businesses is is definitely
uh to partner with with strong folks
that understand their regions and have
resources there we do what we do and
then I'm a big believer in licensing
we've uh We've licensed our technology
um in Canada and now we're rolling out
licensing the pre-roll technology to
multi-state operators in different
regions of the US so big Believers of
that rolling out I got that
Scott you guys obviously are very
Advanced on the licensing and you talked
about some of the pros and cons already
but what else do you see as some of the
the pros and cons of owning the assets
versus partnering with people I know
you're in Canada through a partnership
for instance yes I mean part of the the
um it I would say more in some levels
now it's a necessity because
almost all states have limited licenses
they're they're
many cases have to be vertical you're
talking about huge Capital outlays
um you know our licensee in New York
just to turn in their application was a
million dollars
just to apply that's doing that 50 times
over and and then trying to manage all
that and each State's tax I mean really
each company would have to run as its
own entity or
you know more hair falling out than as
is
um it's it's something that we just felt
licensing was the best path for our
goals now there's more mature players in
the marketplace there's more mature
operators in the marketplace now we're
still doing either licensing or the
preferences JV simply because they feel
we have a bit more skin in the game and
and that's been driven by both sides of
the table in that
when you're in a market that there's a
limited license count
in many cases they're the driver five
years ago I'd get
a lot of calls of hey we'd like the
license being hey we'd like the license
bang because there was that drive on the
other side of the table they're like
well do we do we need Bang
because we have a captured Market
um I'm going to use true leave as an
example in Florida
when they called to ask us if if they
could license Bang
my first question is why you control 75
of the market between 70 75 of the
market you're you're you've got a
strangle on the market why would you
need bang and she said because people
are asking for it that's the right
response that I want to hear we did a
licensing agreement with them versus a
JV
um
it's just
the the players in the marketplace I'm
actually more comfortable licensing to
now
royalties they're publicly traded uh
true leave just went public there's
there's a lot more confidence that this
is not going to be someone that you
gotta you half the babies that you
babysit your brand but them as operators
the state's looking over their shoulder
with testing the states looking over
their shoulder with compliance a lot of
that babysitting that we had to do
several years ago we don't have to do
now and we can focus on supporting them
as a brand rather than just making sure
they're doing things right
so what I hear you saying is a few years
ago you really had some risk in who you
license to they can mess it up and you
didn't have the control night there's
enough confidence there's enough
information out there that you're you
can do these deals and pick the right
Partners yeah I mean even on testing
something simple is having to hound
people we need your lab results
because there was no regulation
mandating them to do it it was us
mandating it versus now I simply get a
copy of what they're already sending to
the state and in a lot of cases the
state is picking up
that responsibility we still mandate it
as part of our agreements but I don't
have to stay on them to do it because in
order to sell the product they already
had to do it for the state just just a
follow-up for you anybody else can weigh
in as well but uh you know we have these
captive States like you mentioned and
some of them are doing uh some of the
operators are doing the license deals
like you did with true leaf that you
said but at the same time we're starting
to see some of these uh operators
multi-state operators go out and buy
brands in the market I'm just curious
what you think about that I mean they're
trying to be everything it seems like
I I've always believed do what you do
best and
um you know I I've never been a fan of
verticals simply because I I don't think
that as a operator that that's
you can't be a great grower and a great
brand Builder and a great retailer and
and all the things that come through
there
out of the gate now acquiring a bunch of
those things and now I'll use origin
house as a good example they took the
best of each of those levels in their in
what they felt and put that together but
they kept those teams in place that were
doing those jobs well that makes sense
but to come out of the block and say I
can do everything well I I don't think
that's happening so the buying the
brands is building a brand developing a
product is that's a specialized skill
set so they're going to acquire those
items
um that they feel they couldn't do as
well on their own just
because it's it's it's economically
sensible they already have a market
share they already have loyal followers
they already have formulas they already
understand and
equipment list everything you need
picking that up and then applying it
into their Market is is a great
opportunity but every company is going
to have a different model and
um
you know that's again just one of them
so we we actually see as the industry
sort of grows
um
we see sort of roles shrinking and I
think to Scott's point
on the pre-roll side where we co-packed
for you know 44 Brands we see folks
really slotting into lanes and I agree
that I think vertical integration is uh
is just not the way to build great
efficient companies it's kind of absurd
frankly if you look across the board at
other Industries
so what we do see is we see Brands being
brands
and then working with cultivators as
their processing partners
and then working with a distributor to
go and sell their stuff so um
that that's what we see is essentially
folks falling into roles they're
becoming a little more granular and
defined
okay I think we'll open it up we have a
few minutes left does anybody have any
questions we do let's hear it once again
for Alan and the entire panel it's very
informative
all right I'm coming I see you down
there once again please keep your
questions brief if you have a long
statement write a book here we go
when guy will help you
hi I guess I was a little disappointed
in
the future being painted
without vertical integration and I'm
concerned about it
with the opportunity of this being the
people's plant that the big guys are
going to come in and it's going to be
trickle down
which doesn't trickle down and I'm
mostly concerned about the farmers so
being a farmer from New York and we are
starting a company that has a vertical
integration through Partnerships
the comment
because when I see all those big names
it looks like we're going to miss the
opportunity to be the people that have a
different economy for the future in the
picture that I just heard
I I don't want to say you misheard what
I said but vertical actually allows the
farmers to be the farmers and Thrive as
Farmers
um
we didn't do and build a farm because
there's a lot of great Farmers that we
can build relationships with and support
and I I think that that
when a large corporation comes in and
says we're going to do our own Farm
and our own extraction and our own
production and our own retail that
doesn't acknowledge the fact that
there's already those four groups of
people there that would be better to
support and that's Bang's position is
we've never been a farm we won't as
maybe not while I'm in charge but
because we're not Farmers there's
there's great Farmers out there and as a
brand and as a product producer our best
contribution to the industry as a whole
in its vertical form is to support those
who are already doing that great not
figure out how to make more money by
getting rid of them there's a there's a
great opportunity for us to support them
and the the idea of vertical integration
is something that the Cannabis invented
Miller doesn't grow wheat Hershey
doesn't grow sugar they don't grow
Coca-Cola doesn't grow corn that that
that companies are successful because
they support Farmers not try to push
them out by doing it themselves so I I
hope that's not what you heard as my
position Scott I'm over here
the ghost in the back
um how can smaller Farmers or smaller
businesses work with some of these
larger investment companies and things
how do you without getting squeezed out
I mean you say that Coca-Cola doesn't
buy corn syrup but I'm sure they have a
say in the corn prices right and so if
you're not getting as much per acre or
per planter per pound as you were when
you were an independent guy and you got
to work with these bigger things how can
they maximize their profit or their
yield while still working with some of
these larger places so I think um well
I've got an answer for you but but I
also think that the first step of that
is grow really good weed and someone
will watch always the first step that's
always the first step weed sells itself
good first step
um look one thing
that the first thing that comes to mind
is actually a value proposition that uh
that we explained to all our partners we
tell them to you know essentially to
put as much of your weed into into
pre-rolls as you can because you get
more for your buck
it's the highest sort of net back out uh
for for a cultivation uh essentially so
pre-roll is just
back out they penciled the best so you
take your small buds and you make them
worth more than your really nice colas
by putting them into pre-rolls simple
answer
hi I'm
seeing and wanting ownership information
and this is a coming from the California
permanent regulations that just were
released regarding
you know it was an issue if the BCC
wasn't going to allow California
companies to license in other states and
it turns out they probably just want the
ownership information but you know I
just want to know how you guys had come
across that if there were any issues
around that
I I honestly I'm haven't
uh my very quick answer to that is along
the years we've had to adjust our
licensing agreement sometimes they were
a per unit fee sometimes it was a
percentage of sales so part of that was
understanding how you can operate within
the confines of the regulatory issues
um or I'm sorry within the regulations
and in some cases we ended up not doing
licensing agreements because there was
not a way to do it that was within the
confines of state law we would have been
considered an effective owner and would
have had to go on their documentation as
an owner of their license or a purchase
you know a portion of their license and
in that case
they put up all this money for a license
they are not going to have us be an
owner of their license so
um I think you got to work within each
State's regulations and in some cases
that means you don't get to go play in
that sandbox
yeah so uh basically that was the answer
essentially you have to back out state
by state and basically put the puzzle
together and it a lot of it is basically
reformatting your the pay structure the
compensation structure it's either a
percentage or a flat fee
um
or the selling of materials so it's just
it's getting creative to sort of back
into whatever that jurisdiction uh wants
it to look like