welcome to the international cannabis
business conference barcelona
uh this is we thank you guys all so very
much for coming out we also like to
thank our sponsors grow glide and bang
we have a great day
uh lined up it's going to be fantastic
we also have i think we have translators
available if you need it but you guys
probably speak
eight different languages you know i'm
an american i speak like one and a half
languages uno imelia idiomas i asked a
guy once i was trying to ask him how
many languages he spoke and i was like
quantos language dna he's like how many
tongues do i have i was like no
all right that joke's probably better in
french
okay
[Laughter]
it's getting there it's getting there
give me two more days
we are just about to start um our
keynote speaker we are we are very
fortunate and honored
and lucky to have her she is
a badass i don't know how you say that
in different languages but she's a
wonderful person
and she just she just told me
that she has been invited to speak at
the united nations on may 5th because
they're having a cannabis and hemp day
huh
how about that that's not bad you make
some noise for that that's exciting
listen
cannabis is coming a long way right it
used to be a felony and now it's an
essential service
at least in america i don't know how
they're doing out here but they're
coming around and you know in barcelona
it's just um something to do on a
tuesday
but she's the well i'll just keep going
she's the ceo and the president of bang
incorporated she's here for us right now
let's hear for jamie pearson
[Applause]
okay that's better
normally i have a podium but this is
gonna work and i know you guys don't
mind
so
good morning
and now randall how are we doing on the
powerpoint there we go
what i'm going to talk about today
are the top 10 things investors
operators and consumers should
anticipate as legalization spreads
across europe
and
the reason i think this is an important
com conversation for us to have right
now
is that
on both continents uh united north
america well in all continents actually
south america also in europe
legalization is spreading
like wildfire i had a dinner last night
and there was a consultant nathan he's
in the audience he said 55 countries
right now
are looking at some form of legalization
and there's some
suspicion that most of europe will
probably follow the canadian regulations
when
when it goes wreck
and that's okay what i'm going to talk
about really handles both
canada and the us
it's a historic time it's been a bumpy
ride and one of the things that we have
to rely on
are is history
so we had prohibition in the united
states and alcohol
and it's a really interesting
idea when you look at
the fact that
i took this right off the history
channel and this is where within minutes
of utah so utah was the last state that
had to ratify the pro get rid of the
prohibition of alcohol
and within minutes
you can see liquor was flowing delivery
trucks were
filled with beer
and everybody was ready to go
so i'm always asking myself how is that
possible that within minutes of the end
of legalization everybody was ready to
start drinking alcohol again well we're
doing that now in cannabis because we've
got these medical programs we've got
decriminalization
we've got medical marijuana in lots of
places so the reality here is that we're
ready for this to
to happen again this is really clunky
i'm sorry you guys um okay so i want to
tell you that
this story really begins with roots and
suits
roots are the people that
risked life and liberty to keep cannabis
alive during prohibition worldwide we
call them roots how many of you in here
consider yourself a root
i've got a few of you
thank you
and then we have the suits i consider
myself a suit
i was a real estate investor for 25
years
i didn't jump into the industry until it
was safe and legal
and a lot of the suits came in now that
we have a bona fide industry and they're
here to make money
my dad's a root
my dad's been growing cannabis for 56
years since 1966 i think is the math i'm
52. so i've literally grown up
in and that's my daughter's hand by the
way on one of my dad's plants
we've all grown up in my family
harvest
is a thing we have a harvest party
everybody sits and trims weed when i was
a kid i had a choice do i pick up dog
poop or do i uh trim weed for me it was
easy i picked up dog poop because i
really wasn't a fan of cannabis
and um and i hate trimming and i still
hate trimming um
for all you roots out there or maybe
some of you suits you know what i'm
talking about
so i had a root background but i still
don't consider myself a root route
because i didn't choose to go into
cannabis until it was
legal and safe
and plus i had all of the real estate
holdings and things that i didn't want
to put at risk the other thing i had
going for me i think i'm just going to
give up the give up the ipad and just
wing it here
dj mugs from cypress hill how many of
you know cypress hill
a lot of you he's my first cousin on my
mom's side
so
muggs and i
invested in real estate together
and when it was time for cyprus to do a
weed deal
he came to me and said would you help us
find a weed deal because he had
experience with me doing business
because i'm a suit
he was more comfortable having me go out
and make sure that the band had a good
deal so in
2015 i found bang
cypress did a deal with bang and i've
been with bang ever since so it's about
seven years
we went public in 2019 i've been the ceo
since december of 2019
i was promoted into that position we are
now in seven u.s states soon to be nine
because we're about to open a couple
more states we just signed an 11 state
deal with true leave which is the one of
the was the most profitable cannabis
company in the world
and we're the number one number two and
number six chocolate in canada and we're
looking for a european partner and
you'll see all around this i put
flyers that have a qr code on it if
you're interested in in having an
american brand
and i understand it's a long game we're
not ready yet in a lot of places in
europe but you've got to start planning
ahead so that's what i'm doing i'm
looking for european partners
um so go ahead and fill out that qr code
now i'm going to see if you guys are
awake i have a gift
it is a
this is a shameless promotion it's a
bang football is there anybody in the
audience that wants it
there you go
i've got another one now you also see
around the the crowd that i have a
giveaway
um that sweatsuit that's shown right
there i have here i have a t-shirt i
have some more footballs and i have a
bang chocolate bar so any of you that
would like any of those things
i've got a qr code and this is an
experiment i want to see if this works
from the stage can you scan that qr code
and
fill out your entry form for my contest
i'm going to get to why i'm doing this
later
is it working
yay it works
love it
oh who else still needs the qr code
we'll go back
anybody else
and they're all over the auditorium so
you guys can
you can scan later
this is the current map of the united
states of legalization so 18 states are
adult use
31 are medical seven are cbd only two
have decriminalized and the four orange
states are the weird ones that have
actually gone so far as to outlaw
cannabis so it will take federal
legalization to get
those four states on board although i
have seen that a couple of them have
some ballot language
coming up
i want you to pay particular attention
to idaho and wyoming up there
surrounded by washington oregon and
montana the citizens of those states
just have to cross a border in wyoming
when montana went wreck on january 1st
of this year
85 percent of the transactions
in the southern part of montana were
wyoming residents because we have to
track them
people want cannabis
this is clear
and legalization has been sweeping the
united states since 1996 that's when
california went medical
when i jumped into the industry in 2014
there were four wreck states in 2015
four more went wreck and that was the
year that everyone considered the
tipping point
what we're seeing in europe is malta
went wreck germany signal that's going
wreck and you're starting to see the
same thing but you have the benefit of
this
as your playbook and i'm going to talk
to you about the things that you need to
know
so that you can educate the people in
your communities to not repeat the
mistakes that
the really swimming upstream hard row we
had to hold
the one thing i'll tell you is when you
have
46 states with some form of legalization
clarence thomas our supreme court
justice the most conservative supreme
court justice we have
this is his quote
this was a dissenting opinion about
cannabis and he is basically saying
you can't have it both ways federal
government you can't look the other way
and let states have states rights
and then when it comes to the feds you
get to do these cash grabs you get to
raid people you get to take their money
you get to take their equipment at some
point there's going to be a lawsuit
that'll get to the supreme court or
they'll pass safe banking congress will
pass it or there'll be some sort of a
vote but we are in the process of
we in the industry of
this balancing act of waiting for
legalization federal legalization
so here are some of the things that we
have seen i'm calling them expectations
things that you can expect are coming as
we legalize cannabis
number one there's competing interests
so we have consumers and the authorities
people want it
the authorities are scared your
governments are afraid
and medical people are afraid they don't
doctors don't learn about cannabis so
imagine in the us 44 states amer in
america wake up with some form of legal
cannabinoid
we don't know anything about the cross
indications of drugs interactions i mean
i can't say we don't know anything
thanks to ralph michonne and people in
israel and people in canada were
starting to learn more and more but we
have so much to learn about what
cannabinoids can do
people want it they are using it they
never stopped using it and it's time for
all of us to get the government and the
medical professionals on board
because it's it's better for us it's
safer for us here's some more competing
interests the roots in the suits
the roots want a seat at the table and
they deserve a seat at the table
it's not necessarily that the suits
don't want them but there are a lot of
assumptions people make the roots assume
that the suits are just doing cash grab
but i'm going to tell you the suits that
are in right now
have left some cushy jobs i know some
people that left pepsi they left
constellation brands they left kellogg's
to jump into an industry that is not
quite legal yet
so
my guess is
they're a little edgy
or they're cannabis fans and they see
this industry going somewhere and they
know that cannabis makes people feel
better so you have the suits jumping in
and they're a little
edgy in the roots deciding that oh
they don't know anything about cannabis
we have to teach them everything and
then you have the suits assuming that
everyone in cannabis is a bunch of
stoners they don't know what they're
doing we're going to have to teach them
about kpis and we're going to teach them
how to do business
but the reality is i have a guy on my
team that did a 13 years in prison and
11 years of that was in solitary
confinement he still he ran his cannabis
business from solitary confinement
i'm not going to teach that guy much
about running a business he's got a lot
to teach me right so we all have to stop
making assumptions
and finally federal state and local
authorities have
competing interests everybody wants that
tax dollar and everybody wants that
glory
but none of them want to take the risk
of doing something unpopular and it's
our job to educate them that this is
popular we want this
this is not unique to america
there's been a drug war across the globe
and it's not been a war on drugs it's
been a war on race and let's be very
clear
there is no difference and this is
statistically proven and i will tell you
you can look it up
white people black people and brown
people use cannabis at the same rate
but black and brown people are four
times more likely to be arrested for
cannabis use there are forty thousand
black and brown people sitting in prison
in america
those are the roots that have given
their life and their liberty for all of
us to be here with an industry
social equity is a conversation that
needs to be had
and the roots should have a seat at the
table and social equity is the right
thing to do it is a moral imperative
and what i would challenge all of you
and what we do at bang is we give a
portion of our profits every month to
the last prisoner project to get some of
these people all of them out of prison
there should be nobody in prison for
possession of a plant that grows in
nature
while we're out making millions of
dollars and so i'm saying to you and i'm
challenging each one of you
incorporate that into your business plan
consumer demand is always grossly
underestimated
and what happens then is the
governmental authorities you can i you
can count on this
they underestimate the demand they don't
give enough licenses they want to dip
their toe in the water rather than
saying oh let's embrace this plant
everybody wants it it's never gone away
everybody's still using it
i just had a talk with a gentleman out
in the in the foyer cliff who said oh
south africa's got a big a big market
well
we all do
america has a big illicit market canada
had a big illicit market south american
countries had big illicit markets
europe's had a big illicit market
cannabis never went away
and if they don't put a lot of licenses
at every level of the supply chain
you're going to end up with bottlenecks
and what we've seen across the united
states is the bottlenecks happen
wherever there aren't enough licenses
and now i'm going to tell you how it
works
you're going to have dispensaries in
some form or fashion
the recreational cannabis will get to
the consumer
and then they're going to say omg we
didn't do this right and they run out of
product it's not happened differently
anywhere in the us
every single state that went wreck
underestimated the amount of product
they were going to need
and then
the legislators go oh tax dollars
awesome we're going to meet demand and
then they open up cultivation and then
cultivation explodes
and then what happens we end up with a
glut
so i'm thinking specifically about
canada
i'm thinking about oregon
these places where there's a glut of
supply now because
cultivation exploded because they
realized they didn't have enough
cannabis to meet demand and that's when
the market speaks because eventually the
good operators operate or the people
that have deep pockets
and the operators that aren't so good
don't make it
takes about three years
depending on the government it can take
longer minimum three years you'll start
to see the supply chain normalized these
are things that you can expect
because they're going to underestimate
the demand
and in europe i think they're v
the numbers i'm seeing come out in some
of these trade publications prohibition
partners and uh leafly
they are way underestimating the demand
i think you guys are going to be
surprised at how big the european market
is going to end up being
expectation number four
the bottlenecks will be local this
always happens
because when we talk about the federal
and state and local legislators it won't
be the european union that's going to
screw up cannabis it's going to be the
school board in stuttgart or some
little town that's going to go
not in my backyard
that's nimby i didn't i didn't coin that
but we used that in cannabis in america
a lot the nimby effect not in my
backyard so everybody's like hang on a
second we want this but why don't you do
it and we'll watch and we'll see what
happens
and
is where you guys come in you have to
teach the people at the local level
that everybody wants this plant it is
safe nobody dies from it
we always see the media talking about oh
in america
oh halloween candy there's people giving
the hell you know medicated candy to
children
and i always laugh and usually go on
record and say a bang chocolate bar
costs 20 dollars believe me nobody's
buying a 20 chocolate bar and forgetting
and handing it to some
child on a trick-or-treating expedition
doesn't happen
and every year they're just
peddling fear
we have to keep the media from peddling
fear and start peddling solutions
and we have to stop
really buying into it we have to start
educating about things like
when cannabis is legal
the age of onset
goes up
so kids start waiting more and more it's
harder to get cannabis for a kid
when it's legal
kids don't buy beer in the middle school
bathroom but they can buy cannabis in
the middle school bathroom but in states
where it's legal it's really hard for
them to get domestic violence goes down
drunk driving goes down
wellness goes up
our communities at the local level need
to embrace this
not just because there's a tax grab but
because
it improves wellness in our communities
fear is the most powerful
force
in the fight against prohibition and our
job is to fight the stigma so the first
two years i was in cannabis i really
didn't want people to know
i was still kind of worried like how is
this going to impact my business
my real estate business
now people say well what do you do i say
i'm in cannabis and then a discussion
ensues
be loud be proud be out let's fight this
fear
there is a lot of ignorance about
potency about the
system about technology
and about the industry in general
people are still talking about indica
and sativa people are thinking that 10
milligrams is enough if you have a
tolerance 10 milligrams doesn't
doesn't affect a lot of people
if you're using cannabis for a medical
reason to sleep or for seizure disorder
or for cancer for nausea a 10 milligram
dose isn't enough and yet that's the
dose that most municipalities and states
recommend as the starting dose
the media has an aversion to facts and
boy we know this in all areas of the
world but we need to educate and demand
better from our media
expect a time suck and expect a green
tax
so everything's going to cost 10 times
more and everything's going to take 10
times longer why
they will not fund the government
offices with enough people so when the
application for those licenses comes
open they're going to have a stack of
licenses
it's going to take forever to get them
meanwhile you're going to figure out
that you need this particular spot for
your retail shop and you're going to pay
rent for months and months and months
while you're waiting for your license
does any of this sound familiar to you
this is what happens
it costs 10 times more because
everybody's on a learning curve
so you want to get a zoning
consultant to come in and help you
figure out your zoning well guess what
the zoning consultant that knows
cannabis may not know the rules where
you live
so part of this is
understand when you're planning and when
you're making your business plan
expect things to take longer expect
things to be more expensive we are not
in business
we are in prohibition
a lot of companies start and fail
because they underestimate what it's
going to take and how long it's going to
take
lab testing inconsistencies you can
expect them in the u.s and in canada
there is very little regulation about
how a standard lab is supposed to test
cannabis
some of them have different equipment
some of them calibrate differently and
what ends up happening is that you end
up having different results and it can
really
lab testing has bankrupted companies
because they've
put a crop out it didn't test right they
gotta destroy it throw it out
usually it ends up on the illicit market
each step in the supply chain is an
opportunity to tax and what happens is
they say
we're going to we're going to have you
lab test and we're going to tax
cultivation then we're going to lab test
we're going to tax the extracted oil
then we're going to lab test and we're
going to tax the manufactured product
then we're going to lab test
uh the final product before it goes to
the retail shop and we're going to tax
it there too oh and we're going to tax
distribution so now what you have is
because of this lab testing situation
because let's be honest you only need
one lab test to know that the product is
no pesticides no no um mold uh no heavy
metals do we need to test it at every
function at every juncture of the supply
chain no but that's usually what happens
and so under the guise of safety
consumers bear the brunt of that cost
and then guess what they go back to the
elicit market where the products cheaper
it's not lab tested but
what we're trying to do under the guise
of safety is we're driving people to the
product that's probably dirty
how am i doing on time
what time is it
okay
metaverse crypto and nfts are here
companies are selling cannabis in the
metaverse
i'm gonna i'm gonna burn through this
one quickly i just want you all to know
that if you're building cannabis brands
in europe
this is where cannabis brands in america
are going
uh be ready
job creation and tax revenue
the u.s cannabis
industry created 450 000 jobs
in 2021 last year
in comparison the financial sector
created 145 000 in construction did 165
000. look at that
when you think about
countries like greece
that have an ailing ag sector imagine
what the cultivation will do for those
countries and the jobs that are going to
be created in europe
tax revenue numbers are reported from
sales
they're not really reported from all of
the employment tax that comes through
all those jobs
and the data never counts ancillary that
450 000 jobs those are in the cannabis
industry
but think about the lawyers and the
accountants and the bankers and the um
the people that are selling tables and
lights
that's also part of the cannabis
industry and those aren't even counted
this is a
huge opportunity for governments
data collection which is why i had you
guys uh give me your qr code now i know
a bunch of you i'm going to be able to
communicate with you
people are buying everything now
on their phones because of covid online
shopping exploded
cannabis delivery exploded
and phones track behavior location and
preferences and believe me
everybody's buying every every time you
get that little terms of agreement and
you agree to it
you are agreeing to share your data and
everybody's buying it that's how you
know that when you're searching for a
mattress on google the next thing you
know when you're on instagram or you're
on facebook mattresses are popping in
front of you
they're buying this data
you should be collecting data
build a data collection
model in your business plan because the
data
is the key to effective marketing
because you got to market to people on
their phones people are not going on
their their desktops
and when you think about what's coming
with crypto data collection is king
maverick
innovator aspirational
those are the three words i think of
when i think about all the people in
this room
this is who the cannabis industry is
our industry is full of people that are
blazing this trail i'm so proud of all
of you i'm proud to be part of this
industry because we're not going to shy
away from what's hard
we are not going to be allow fear to let
us be pushed out we walk into the face
of this fear and we're going to help end
cannabis prohibition
and i'm going to leave you with this
quote from eleanor roosevelt when i
landed in barcelona two days ago it was
international women's day and i felt
like this was apropos
you gain strength courage and confidence
by every experience in which you really
stop to look fear in the face
and do the thing you think you cannot do
we can do this
thank you
jamie
jamie pearson one more time she's very
soft-spoken i'm a loud person jamie
pearson i'm sure you can talk to her
later