we have a very special guest in the
house right now
six-time NBA world champion actor vegan
an all-around awesome guy how many y'all
want to see John Salley make some note
Johnny you here yo makes it easier right
here yo make some noise for John Salley
everybody what's up how you guys doing
this was very it did you learn anything
I did did any of them leave any money up
this [ __ ] I when alex had me
here like three years ago my daughter
Tyler and I we had just started our
brand deuces I'm not wearing it right
now because I'm really bad marketer no I
didn't get to New Jersey but we we
decided from this spot when I was here I
met Tommy Chong in the back I smoked
weed with him I'm lying he smoked weed
with me and it was my [ __ ] and then I
decided just from this conference to be
serious about being any kind of his
business a lot of people are gonna
you're gonna hear these people sit up
here and talk and a lot of them seem
like you know sitting there like stiff
they're not this I've been to all of
them
I've been to I've been to some of them
seriously
that didn't even have booze but they was
renting the booze I've been to the low
low end I've been to the ones that
thought they were high end we were high
at the end and and so I hear I hear some
of the best sales from Wall Street guys
Wall Street ladies Wall Street
transgender I see him from every I'm not
leaving anybody out goddamn it and I see
him and I hear it and they don't know
how long I've been in it so I want to
tell you so
2005 my boy got 20 years in jail for
making sure that the weed in New York
smelled like California you'll get that
in a second
so I've been literally trying to help
people before that
I was trying to get them out of the
business because I thought that they
shouldn't be selling that because I
didn't smoke weed at that time and start
smoking until 2000 I was in Sacramento
38-24-36 and I and she said you'll get
that joke is on the back of it and she
said do you smoke weed and I said nah
you know I don't do that stuff and she
was like I believe it I was like let me
try that let me call my wife and tell
I'm going to sleep I'm joking I told I
was going out but I smoked this weed and
my left leg became my right leg and and
I do yoga and all of a sudden I was
doing things different I was in one form
I was like yo this is the bomb so the
next day I get up with my teammates and
I was like yeah I'm the last one on the
bus which is usually not happen I get on
the bus and I sit down that was the
chronic Sal I told you not to smoke it I
was like we I get the chronic like I
have chronic pain where do I get that I
found this out a month before retiring
now if I would have found this out when
I was a bad boy I might have you know
hit more people I would still be playing
so Tom Brady smokes a lot of weed
obviously cuz there's no way to play
this unbelievable [ __ ] and not smoke
weed you can't drink alcohol because and
you can't just keep eating bad food
right because it destroys your your body
destroys your liver your kidneys your
relationship you make you smack your
kids kiss your dog you don't want
alcohol you want this so I've been in
this for a long time
I've heard just about everything guys
have no idea
when I hear them speaking gibberish or
where I hear them speaking in in what I
call MBC talk pivoting and this and that
when I hear that [ __ ] I go I don't
want you in the business I don't and I
just had a conversation where the guy in
the back was asking how he can help
regulate I think we should go back to
the mentality when weed was never
thought of of being dirty never thought
of of being bad for you never thought of
having herbicides pesticides only when
we try to scale up to fulfill
everybody's dream of being wealthy I'm
sorry rich
because that's all you're gonna get if
you scale up to 80 hundred thousand to
make this you [ __ ] up the business
I'm saying it to you keep it as small as
possible in our brand doose's and also
in the brand lucky 420 which my friend
Rachel's the CEO of great pre-roll try
it
I smoked it at ten and I woke up at nine
today I'm just saying I'm just no on the
real keep it let's make Louie to 13th
let's not make Ripple
let's not make MD forty forty stop
destroying the business so you out there
who don't like what I'm saying I don't
really care I have a friend in jail for
making sure that New York smell like
California and he didn't even get caught
with the weed so what we should have in
here one of the things I want to get
this legislation everybody that's in
jail God willing for making sure New
York smell like California should be out
everybody that realized it was a
medicine before good teach the new teach
the newbies my friends I here from
Detroit she came all the way to San
Francisco to find out how to get in this
business can you imagine that she came
all the way and she went to OSHA damn
oxy damn
okay well Oaksterdam yeah I went to and
I can't pronounce this [ __ ] that was the
first thing I did and like I think it
was 2008 so we could teach this business
we can have this business together we
can keep the corporates gonna come in
and buy the whole [ __ ] I hope they buy
me first but I
I'm just being serious I hope they buy
me first but I want him to buy a product
that doesn't turn out to be like the
products I took what I was playing I
used to take these pills I won't say
their name because I don't want to give
them advertisement so when I took advil
6 a day so my knees wouldn't hurt my
elbows wouldn't hurt my neck wouldn't
hurt my back wouldn't hurt
really it was so my kidneys wouldn't
work
that's what wound up happening this
business this plant is healing this
plant is wonderful you guys saw avatar
don't Detroit don't destroy the [ __ ]
tree don't do it I'll have some blue
guys and girls coming on some [ __ ] you
know I did ayahuasca a little while ago
obviously you can tell so I used to be I
had I had a filter because I've been on
television so long so I would know to
take it to the edge and then fade back
and if he went a little bit too over the
edge I would say sorry and somebody
would write an apology but I did
ayahuasca at this very very wealthy guy
in Beverly Hills
he was so wealthy he bought a shaman
from the middle of the Amazon he like
landed a helicopter grabbed a shaman
bought his ass back to Beverly Hills you
know how we like it
and and short enough I was into one
ayahuasca and I'm watching all the [ __ ]
happening in my brain and the colors and
I start laughing and [ __ ] that happened
in 1979 and I realized this is healing
my brain that ayahuasca made me see
things differently
it made me open up it made me you know I
was introverted yeah I would have never
gotten up on the stage to lie it again.i
right integrated I would have never
gotten up and spoke so much truth in fun
so I'm not gonna like when he said I'm
not gonna get up and tell you what you
should do how we should do it the only
thing I'm asking you to do is keep the
plan a plan
keep it healing
keep it fine make it louis xiii if you
want to do some liquor i met somebody
yesterday was talking about infusing the
beer with it [ __ ] that keep the alcohol
over here keep the plant over here beer
is down 30% wine is down 50% and that's
not because people don't drink it's
because people now realize this is how
you should enhance your brain this is
how you should literally feed everything
that's inside your body by smoking it by
vaping it by eating it by sharing it
alright so that's all I wanted to say it
seemed like I jumped around trust me I
didn't you did great
oh thank you one more time John Salley
everybody let's here with John Salley
number 22
fight the power deuces 22 I'm tom deuces
22 dot-com that was fantastic