[Music]
keeping the legacy alive
right that is an interesting topic
because
up until now cannabis has been one of
the
uh biggest success stories of like
decentralization
you know and now
capitalism trying to capitalize they
want to centralize everything it's an
interesting thing we're going to talk
about it and to lead this panel the
founder and ceo of green rush consulting
let's hear it for zeta city
[Applause]
hey
what's up guys how are you guys doing
out there
yeah
how's everybody doing great my name is
dana sunny i'm ceo founder of green rush
consulting
and we're here to talk about culture and
cannabis keeping the legacy alive in
corporate campus i've got four panelists
up here today
very special people on the far end down
here we have aaron smith
he's the co-founder executive director
of national cannabis industry
association
aaron has successfully built coalitions
with elected officials on both sides of
the aisle in order to advance cannabis
policy reform legislation in the state
capitol and among the public please
welcome aaron
next up we have elena staller vice
president of business development i
aspire a cannabis or a company focused
on high-end consumer vaping technology
luna earned her place as a thought
leader in the california cannabis
industry by helping to shape the retail
landscape
driving sell through in maine both
mainstream and niche markets as women
terrorism she hosted networking events
with world-class brands and was a
founding member at the first two events
in california music festival history
legally vending cannabis and northern
lights and grasslands she also helped
work on social equity in oakland
and decriminalize anthogens and
plant-based psychoanalysis everybody
welcome luna
next up
we got needy lucky honda lucky huh we're
so lucky to have her today guys it's
awesome needy is the founder and ceo of
lynn a california lifestyle brand forged
on the principle of radicalizing the
common narrative surrounding cannabis
culture with a focus on propelling a
multitude of topics like inclusivity
restorative justice and cannabis
industry etiquette
welcome needy
and finally we have lisa lisa is the
founder of mj universe a publisher of
digital products on the collaborative
network to connect companies along the
value chain of hemp and cannabis lisa is
also a founding member and on the board
of the bvcwev
and a member of the canafer network a
professional network for women hemp and
cannabis in germany everybody gave it up
for her
awesome awesome
thank you guys so much okay so here we
go ready a little bit of history though
okay of cannabis culture you feel
overview um you know obviously campus is
amazing these days but you know it
started with really
at least the jamaican rastafarian
culture back in the 1850s and 1860s
really kind of bringing it to the fold
and then moving into the california
counter culture in the 60s to then under
prop 2 15 from medical and then denver
washington going full legalization we're
seeing legalization all over the place
down internationally
18 legal states and 37 medical states in
the united states and now an
international marketplace potentially
worth 146
billion dollars
by 2025. pretty amazing
so we're going to start with some of our
first questions uh you know please tell
our audience what each of your
businesses are seeing out there today in
terms of how the legacy market is being
impacted as legalization is becoming
mainstream erin you want to tell us a
little bit about that yeah thanks aydah
thanks icbc and all of you for being
here it's great to learn from what's
happening here across the pond and share
ideas with all of these great folks up
here so thank you thank you all um i
really you know have been watching the
industry
really from a very u.s center you know
focus as leading the u.s trade
association so i'm not going to speak
for europe but what we see is that you
know as we've
we have done a really great job of
moving public opinion in the right
direction away from prohibition you know
switching state laws over and over and
over into 37 states of medical 18 with
adult use
um but you know the good good side of
that is that means less there are less
arrests but on this on the flip side uh
we have not done enough to create
regulatory regimes that are accessible
to
minority-owned businesses
um other you know small mom-and-pop
operators uh who who
were at one time legacy operators
meaning they were operating in the
previously unregulated market
and so we need to be doing a lot more
both at the federal state and local
level
in the u.s to open up these markets to
everybody
julia what do you think about that in
terms of impacting the legacy market
being impacted by legalization
i was born and raised in northern
california i was in middle school in
1996 when prop 215 was passed so
cannabis was everywhere i never
considered it a drug so for me my entire
community and my perspective
is that it's medicine i've been a
patient since you could be a patient
i've been selling it smoking it and
growing it my entire life it put me
through grad school and it's brought me
where i am today so to see the
extinction event happen to a lot of the
legacy farmers that
weren't considered during the regulatory
process and were left out as aaron's
mentioning it's
when i used the word extinction event i
mean that in the literal economic term
and there's been multiple of them so i
would say maybe 90 of the people that we
used to work with before it was made
legal a few years ago are no longer in
business for various reasons of course
everyone knows that capitalism is
in a lot of ways a game of greed if it's
not conscious capitalism it's kind of
got a predatory perspective and
unfortunately with capital you have more
more play in this space and so a lot of
our job is to make sure that these
things are not lost and we say grounded
in our roots whether it's as frenchy
cannoli says the terroir of the place so
in northern california we have a very
special mediterranean-type climate that
grows a specific kind of cannabis with
certain cannabinoids and terpenes and
profile that is really rich and it's you
know we were proud of that heritage and
so to lose that from just making
something that's a magical mystical
medicinal plant and do a typical
consumer package good there's something
lost there and we're here to really just
remind that there has to be some purpose
and um respect for this plant and the
plant medicine and everything we do and
not just treat it like it's another
consumer good because it's really not it
needs to be treated in a special way or
else we're going to destroy it yeah
right on and so like you know that's
really really important you know because
the fact of the matter is it comes from
the culture you know this is the folks
that built this industry right so having
to be able to resonate with that is
super super important in the way she's
talking about i mean wouldn't you agree
needy i mean tell us a little bit about
what you think absolutely i i run a
brand uh based in california so like
luna you know my perspective is very
california centric
and you know we're watching the
cultivators loon supports craft
cultivators we really they can make not
just a concerted effort but it's part of
our ethos to
buy flower from small farmers that they
are getting pummeled right now as we're
seeing you know the big corporate grows
come online the economy of growing is
upside down in california it costs 700 a
pound to grow and cultivate the market's
at 300. so you know in
2022 we're hearing about farmers killing
themselves every day in california it is
an extremely volatile moment and you
know there's a lot that the newer
markets can learn from this there's it's
it's it's really unbelievable because
you know the thing to really focus on
for all of us here interested in this
business is
the best behaved part of the supply
chain is the consumer a lot of the
problems we have in this industry are
man-made we can control and do things
differently so you know i would say
that's that's the big thing that we're
seeing at loon right on india very very
well familiar with the california market
but learning from the california market
is very very important when we take it
all the way across the world over to a
place like germany lisa give us your
thoughts on some of that
well i think in general it is very
important that we learn from each other
and that we
trying not to only create these local
markets i mean if you look at europe for
example there are individual zones like
you know from the states and i think in
the end it should all be that we are
more connected and that we are lobbying
also for changes in global drug policy
that we can create a global cannabis
industry where it is not only like
individual markets where you then see
these effects like these price drops
weigh more
than than if you have a harmonized
system where you can
where you can
trade and you can exchange products and
they're not only stuck in their local
markets but i think it's very important
with the countries that are a little bit
further ahead that we learn from them
that we as entrepreneurs exchange and um
yeah just learn from the mistakes also
that happened in other more further
developed areas yeah so these folks i
mean you understand that they've been
traumatized in a way multi-generational
farmers who have known just this is the
way they need to operate and education
is so important to help bridge the gap
and create that conduit between your
business
and the consumer right so i'd like to
actually roll that into this next
question which is you know since each of
you guys you know someone have a little
bit different of businesses um how are
you how are you guys you know tell our
audience actually how your business in
general is currently connecting with
consumers at that level that resonates
with industry culture
you want to go uh luna you want to try
it out
well we do dope hardware we lean hard
into the concept that this is um a
beautiful high-end luxury lifestyle it's
not just for losers and stoners and lazy
people we have dab rigs that are
induction heating that are really high
in technology but still are a nod to the
old school dab culture if you don't know
what dabbing is it's high temperature
vaporization through something like a
bong but it's specifically for
concentrated thc or any concentrated
cannabinoid really um for usually for
people who have a really high tolerance
and they want a lot of thc or they want
to have a custom experience so for us
we're able to have you know bring
technology and innovation into a space
that really hasn't had much innovation
people are still using the same pipes
and joints that they've been using for
you know 40 to 100 years however you
know apples or whatever you find so for
us we're really trying to be
sophisticated and polished and show the
the cannabis consumer and to normalize
it culturally um and also to investors
or to people who are on the fence about
it to legitimize it as this business but
also not leave people behind there's a
lot of brands that will brand themselves
like as anti-stoner and they put that
down to define themselves we're not
about that we we like i wear you know
everyone on our ispire team if anyone
came by our booth you'll see we wear
plug necklaces in in california the plug
means you're the connect you hook people
up you're the yenta you're the
matchmaker you you wanna you wanna get
people what they need and it's actually
a form of like love and respect and flow
and you're the hook and so we we we wear
that to show that whatever you need we
got you on that whether it's policy
whether it's parties whether it's
culture whether it's dab rigs vape pens
it doesn't really matter where you're at
if
you're you know contributing to the
normalization of this plant that's what
we're all about we have you know we
always focus on hiring women people of
color trying to incorporate as many
folks as we can
when we partner with people we give
preferential attention and support to
people that have marginalized
backgrounds queer folks people who are
giving back to non-profits so we do a
lot of corporate social responsibility
work we do uh beach cleanups and we give
back where we can because if you're not
giving you really shouldn't be in this
space this plant is giving in its nature
great that's awesome and then i would
love to actually jump to you lisa with
mj universe
which is a platform that's providing
access to experts and again education is
key here right so tell us lisa how are
you how are you guys bridging that gap
well for us it's all about
yeah explaining cannabis to mainstream
businesses also a lot of my clients for
example are pharmaceutical companies
they don't know anything about cannabis
so you really start from scratch about
explaining what the plant does about the
contents and bringing across
this potential of cannabis to
conventional industries that exist but
like if you talk about this donor
stereotype for example i think this is
often also abused in certain ways
because we for example in germany we
just had a raid in a supermarket they
had a promotion for hemp products but it
was all labeled as hash brownies and all
these kind of things it had little rasta
people on it which is like really like i
don't know
not acceptable exactly and in the end it
was all about ham products and they
didn't make use of this vest potential
that is in the hemp nutrition that they
could have used easily but they decided
to take this donor stereotype make it a
red yellow green and then put a raster
man on it which is really a lot of
cultural appropriate appropriation also
that's yeah that raid was unfortunate
um so needy tell us a little bit about
how your products are connecting with
consumers your business in general is
connecting with consumers in the
california market
how's it going
yeah this is everything that we think
about every day at loon as a brand that
is really focused and committed to
building out a new narrative telling new
stories about the 3.0 consumer what is
possible for our industry i think we all
understand that there is a lot of
potential here which is why we're all
here
but creating that bridge telling the
stories both the social justice reform
stories in a palatable way to a consumer
we put out a quarterly magazine at loon
called honestly grown it marries
lifestyle so there might be a feature
about how to style your weed cart
instead of having a bar cart and then
also tells a story about social justice
reform and how we can actually
actionably get people out of prison for
some you know serving these non-violent
cannabis crimes this is something that
every single one of us should be very
not just passionate about but feel as a
moral imperative is part of our work and
at loon we take that as part of our
mission so it's it really you see it in
the packaging is recyclable you know the
little details that really like feed
into we know a lot about cannabis
consumers they care about mother earth
they care about conscious consumerism
how that outlays and how we market and
message i think is so important so
absolutely it's part of everything
really in the brand ethos and that
bridges the culture i mean it's really
getting people to feel comfortable i
love that palliative stories
that's just awesome palliative stories
around your brand right and then also
focusing on a lot of the issues and
challenges and aaron i'm sure you can
give us a little bit about that with
ncia in terms of a lot of issues and
challenges in terms of restorative
justice and how that works gives you a
little bit
yeah thanks well when we put this in
perspective um
this you know we've been facing nearly
100 years of marijuana prohibition at
the federal level in the united states
that prohibition policy was put in place
to subjugate people
uh blatantly
um and and let's face it it's not people
that look like me it's it's to subjugate
black and brown communities and we
absolutely as we move away from
prohibition we're still in prohibition
but as we move away from it we
absolutely
must ensure that the industry
does everything it can to try to repair
the harm associated with with the
previous policies and nci is always
there
educating entrants into the industry
because we are the first place that many
people go when they're they're coming in
to try to find their place in cannabis
and making sure they understand
that you know what that history is and
what our new role is and this this is a
once in a lifetime experience that we're
or once in a lifetime opportunity that
we are all engaging in here and creating
a brand new industry um and an industry
that
we could just you know seed it to big
tobacco big pharma big alcohol
but no we're making sure that we stick
to the values that are you know taught
to us you know through the legacy of the
cannabis plant and the previous industry
that's a big part of us as ncia is being
kind of part of the bully pulpit so to
speak um on the policy side there's a
lot going on at the state and
national level kind of focus on national
um you know i look at what the work we
do is really kind of bifurcated into two
tracks
lobbying congress and the administration
to pass the kind of ultimate
perfect marijuana bill that's going to
um you know that that will have all of
the you know all the bells and whistles
that we all want to see in a land where
marijuana is legal at coast to coast um
and then also what we can get done like
today or in the you know in the near
future what's politically
possible um on the more comprehensive
legislation side there are something
like seven cannabis bills in congress we
support all of them to some degree um
we're really excited about a new bill
coming out though from that kind of
brings elements from all of them from
senator uh senate majority leader chuck
schumer should be out by the uh
before the election
which we're really focusing on lobbying
him and his office to understand the
need to include restorative justice
measures in that in that legislation to
ensure that there if there's a federal
licensing system which will be proposed
that that we don't have arbitrary caps
on those licenses that the barrier to
entry capital requirements etc are at a
point to where you know not just anyone
can get a license but
anyone with a reasonable acumen can can
get a license at the federally and then
leave a lot to the states we want to
leave as much as possible to states
because the states have been the
laboratories of democracy all along um
on the kind of what's more practically
likely to happen in the next couple
years i think the biggest most important
policy objective we're working on
is this is a piece of legislation in the
u.s called the safe banking act uh which
would allow u.s banks to do business
with cannabis operators
and licensees without fear of you know
getting their you know getting shut down
by the feds
and also would allow the cannabis
industry to access financial services
without being gouged many of them are
being gouged with exorbitant fees just
to deposit their you know
deposit their cash at the end of the
night not to mention they don't have
access to lending and traditional
lending and financial services this bill
would allow would open up the open up
those opportunities which are really
mostly needed by the smaller operators
the big multi-state operators have they
have private sources of capital um and
are not as dependent on uh the things
like the small business administration
and other uh mechanisms that we have for
small businesses in the us
awesome hey guys can we give another
round of applause for ncia doing this
type of work for us i mean come on this
is awesome
this really paves the way for new
entrepreneurs to get into this space you
know and provide something called legal
amnesty like let's just say you're here
now in spain and you're you're you're
doing stuff underground this type of
work really helps us pave the way for
the rest of the world so really thank
you guys so much for for doing that um
and moving speaking of legal amnesty
um you know in new markets it's critical
to support these folks
because we're seeing this happen in
states like new york um you know it
happened in california they've created
measures or ways of of supporting these
folks and bridging them from the
unregulated market to the to the
regulated market you know also bridging
the gap between culture and corporate
here um you know in multi-generational
farmers you name it right and i'm just
kind of wondering you know
with each of you guys as businesses like
what is your business doing to support
these folks you have been targeted by
the war on drugs let's say um you know
to create opportunities to work with
them in these new types of markets linda
you want to give us an idea what
ispire's doing in that space right now
with all the work that you've done
awesome
so yeah we
actually just ran a
holiday
gift that we donated in instead of you
know spending a bunch of money to send
something we sent a custom we make a
wand which is a torch replacement we had
them custom painted by our friend jv
arty is a well-known artist in the
united states and we made a sizable
donation per gift that we gave away in
that person's name to the social impact
center which is founded by two women of
color in san diego and
they are working on
basically the drug war so people have
been
in disproportionately impacted by the
war on drugs so usually people of color
people that live in highly policed areas
um and really working on initiatives to
make sure that they
are able to vote afterwards and they can
participate in democracy that they can
get good jobs that they're able to move
forward in their lives and um yeah
really the the most important thing for
us is that pete is is autonomy
sovereignty and everyone being able to
do exactly what they need to do for
themselves
so there's people that we work with one
of our partners is exhibit he's a
well-known rapper he started a company
called napalm
he is you know an african-american guy
who you know was famous for
selling weed and rapping about strippers
and doing this stuff and he's been able
to
raise a cannabis company in a state
that's traditionally locks people up
with people that look like him that he
would be locked up for doing that if he
didn't have you know the proper lawyers
in the proper capital but we we're
seeing people rising up from situations
where they used to go to jail for
selling weed to being someone that a
young person of color can look up to so
we uh fill their hardware we offer them
their cartridges if you go into
california and you buy one of exhibits
napalm's cartridges or um one of you
know that we have a custom battery for
them we're able to like uplift different
people in our spaces women-owned
businesses i work with a lot of
women-owned businesses too that we're
able to do extra promotions for them
give them extra love on social we're
able to um really make sure that when
they're going through their processes
that we can be a true partner to them
and show up with for them with
intentionality instead of just using
them to check boxes off of our list
we actually have jessica redenbo our
marketing director right here in the
audience
she's also a woman of color and an
amazing advocate and activist who's been
in the regulated market in a
pre-regulated market so she runs our you
know our brand and our events and she
very much puts herself into that so like
having women and people of color and
marginalized people at the center of the
decision making is different than just
hiring a couple people to work the front
we need to have them in positions of
leadership and
positions of management and positions of
ownership as well and stop a lot of
companies will do these things where
it's all about optics and pr they just
want things to look good so they'll
check boxes obligatory and it's just it
feels very perfunctory it doesn't feel
authentic and genuine we need people to
actually step up and really be sharing
you know we were talking earlier i i
know in germany um lisa was saying that
it's it's people are you know there's a
brain drain people are leaving their
industry because they're not making
enough money the rich people are not
sharing with the workers and so we have
all these brilliant people who know how
to grow who know how to do these things
that are leaving because it's an abusive
environment so making it a really safe
space connecting with women's groups we
do a ton of work in
women's empowerment just going out of
your way make cutting out time and
cutting out budget
to really overtly do this work with
these people that's awesome and it
really coalesces with their brand
message right because at the end of the
day it's going to be flowers flowers
flowers flower you know it's really
important to have this message and do
this work for the communities
and for all these different types of
folks and i imagine you know you guys
are doing just as just as good as well
tell us a little bit about it no
definitely and you know it's kudos to
you guys that i aspire because you know
i think that's all we all need to show
up and at loon we've been really
dedicated to that from the jump so when
i first started the brand and literally
had no money and was very eager to keep
mission central to everything that we do
i went to last prisoner project and said
hey
guys i don't have any money but i want
to support you what can we do can we we
have an amazing creative team can we
create content can we start amplifying
the message of what you're trying to do
we started there and today we have a sku
on the menu all the time at loon where
100 of the proceeds go to mission like
last prisoner project so you know i
really think it's important that at
every level in our industry just show up
you know today i think the most
impactful work we're doing at loon is
with an accelerator called momentum it's
a phenomenal program it supports
underrepresented minorities and folks
disproportionately affected by the war
on drugs
by giving them fifty thousand dollars
with no strings attached no equity
requirements in in their brands helping
them succeed putting them through a
12-week program teaching them things
like you know how important compliance
is it's phenomenal to me as somebody who
has a brand how many founders i meet who
don't have budgets for compliance the
best way we can help the legacy market
bridge the gap is by really educating
and to luna earlier you know mentioned
we need to stop using this blanket term
education we need to flesh it out
education on compliance and really
understanding the market
it seems like there's a massive gap
right now for folks you know if you're
running a billion dollar company and you
have an entire team of lawyers dedicated
to compliance those are not going to be
the same friction points that if you're
a small mom and pop trying to just put
products on the shelf and you don't
understand that the california universal
triangle now has to be a quarter of an
inch instead of half an inch
that can screw up your entire business
so i think you know it's really i'm very
passionate about the work that momentum
is doing i sit on the committee and as a
brand we also sponsor that initiative
financially
but in general i think the message
should be just show up so if it is the
beach cleanup if it is showing up in
whatever way
put your value system first i think
we're in an industry where that's
incredibly critical more so than in any
other emerging industry there's
obviously the money grab mentality
that's dominating most of the
conversations but you know i think
mission and authenticity is something
that will always shine through loudest
and and proudest and ultimately the
consumer will choose you know brands
that really and companies that really
show that off awesome awesome and you
know who's showing up for you guys over
here in europe is lisa right here for
germany
excellent get her around our applause
man she's doing a great job for germany
uh women empowerment tell us a little
bit about what's happening in germany in
nebraska yeah well germany it's very
interesting what is happening at the
moment because we have a little bit
different background than you have in in
the states for example like
compassionate youth programs would not
be possible for us like there it's a
very different environment we could not
do recreational grow and then hand out
medicine to people it's two different
systems in the end but um also something
that you can see in the medical market
is that is very important and it's also
something that at rosenthal i don't know
who of you saw his talk prior he said
they're the people who do the work and
the people who got the money so we need
to make sure a little bit more that more
money comes to the people who do the leg
work and who are doing the ground work
in terms of patient education for the
medical part for example which are
patient associations and they're mostly
self-funded or have small donations but
like we need to make sure that this big
corporate money also goes down to the
grass root and helps grow the cannabis
plant that we are planting at the moment
and not that everything just stays in
the top and the people who have been in
it for the long run and who have been
working in this industry for 20 years
plus that they cannot participate and
are overrun by huge mainstream
corporates right and it's important as
any business really um you know having
just the good hiring practices or good
vendor selection that really encourages
these folks to participate um that
include you know training and
empowerment programs or there's so many
different things you can do in this
industry and that's why this industry is
amazing because there's a lot of
opportunity you just got to look at it
at the right lengths and that's why it's
important that you know all these women
are just doing such a great job we're
all doing just such a great job but
we've got to do it collectively together
and that's what we're doing here today
at icbc is sharing this information
sharing these strategies and solutions
so that all of us can benefit from one
another countries to country state to
state person to person i think it's
absolutely amazing thank you guys so
much for all the great work that you're
doing um
yeah ronald apostro guys let's do it
again thank you thank you
um we're gonna go over one more lastly
moving from a legacy market to a
regulator market what are four tips that
legacy cannabis companies can do that
you can tell our audience on how they
can survive in a world where
corporations coming in that have larger
access to capital refined systems and
scalability
lisa
go ahead
four tips for me
[Music]
well uh i think like uh
one very important thing is to
collaborate and to make sure that all
this normal knowledge that has been
built up over the last years is not lost
somewhere but it is transferred and
education i think is very important
everybody should focus more on that and
like really um it's part of our job but
what i would also
would wish more for would be that the
companies understand that especially
this part is like helping people like we
have two over 200 000 cannabis crimes in
germany that are prosecuted every year
that we have a response is part of our
corporate social responsibility if you
want to put it in a manager world yeah
that we are there and we are not only
there to open up this market to grab
market share but we are also there to
give something back
awesome awesome thank you that's amazing
needy what do you got four tips for new
legacy cannabis companies to survive the
oncoming market
yeah i think uh number one educate
yourself and use the expensive mistakes
other markets have made i mean this is
like free and everybody should take
advantage of it
we already paid for it yeah exactly um
invest in compliance i touched on this
earlier i can't stress i think we see
this all the time with folks that we
work with uh who've come from legacy
there seems to be like either a real
resistance or this perspective that it's
too expensive
it's the most important thing it should
be foundational to every business
and i'd say embrace innovation and
efficiency i think that we need to hold
hands more the legacy markets and the
newer corporate markets need to hold
hands because if we're going to build
something that we can all be proud of
it's going to happen together we need
the money from the new
corporate entities and we need the
experience from the legacy market
professionals and that's just it's it's
that simple and the last thing is stay
true to your roots like the one thing
that corporate wheat is never going to
have over legacy is a real story you
have that it's built in that
authenticity really shines through i
mean
you can look at any brand you can look
at any cpg vertical in the world and
ultimately consumership gravitates
toward authenticity and that is
something that you have with timing and
experience and i think we should be
celebrating that as an industry so
yeah those are my four tips awesome
integrity guys integrity really very
cool very good luna what do you got that
was good
um i didn't prepare anything but it's
just like my typical rules it's it's
you know get the job done so that's the
efficiency part like don't get don't
don't be focused on instagram don't be
focused on what the other person's doing
don't be focused on anything hire
someone to you know to to to do
compliance so that you can focus on your
ip
your day-to-day your culture your people
get the job done remember your
assignment is to liberate this plant and
make this just like coffee or sugar or
any other stimulant like where that's
the mission you don't it doesn't matter
who you work for doesn't matter where
you are it doesn't matter how you talk
about it that's that's get the job done
the assignment is to legalize and create
more access at an affordable rate to
this plan and to stop putting people in
prison and harming them right then
there's um always you know look out for
your people like don't step on other
people to get where you are don't act
like you invented a strain or don't act
like you know don't bite don't rip off
people's ip and you know like look after
a lot of people in the cannabis industry
where we're from fight internally when
really it's us against them it's it's
our government it's the so it's the
stigma we in a lot of inter-fighting so
that's another thing you know i say so
you know look out for your mates
and have fun is a really important thing
remember why you're doing it like have
some levity you know there's there's
it's really important to remember like
stay centered have a story of a why why
you're in cannabis be able to tell
people with joy and with pride and with
honor that you're in this industry let
them know that you're there for them and
maybe you guys can share a truckload
instead of each of you paying for
something you guys go together in
coalition build we call it cooperation
not competition right a rising tide
raises all boats we're all on the same
team and the fourth piece is just cover
your ass lawyer
up get your money right and get your
lawyers right because it doesn't matter
what panel you go to what your friends
say what anyone else says unless someone
is being paid to follow the laws that
change constantly the goal posts get
moved and you're being asked to play a
game where the rules are changing and
the stadium changes locations on a daily
weekly basis you know i'm sure you're
getting some gray hairs yes it's it's
very stressful
so be flexible be adaptive and cover
your tush because it's people are losing
their livelihoods they're getting
arrested in where i'm from the cops will
come they'll shoot your dog they'll take
your kids and they'll take your trucks
in your house and you'll have nothing
left and you have a felony and you can't
vote or you know in certain states you
can't vote um and in certain places
you're not able to get a job so like
this is this is a real war that's
happening this is a civil rights war so
just watch your back it's not cool
everywhere in spain it's very serious
they're arresting people constantly so
just remember where you are and don't
get too comfortable because it's not
legal yet
absolutely and aaron what you got four
four tips i absolutely agree with
everything said here and following up on
what luna said definitely invest in a
good attorney and it's not just you know
the being worried about
the police kicking in the door it's also
you know make sure you're you know
you're working with the right people
there's a lot of predators out there
there's a lot of sharks that are trying
to come in to especially going after
legacy operators and trying to strike a
deal
just so that you know they could get get
wealthy and bounce out of the industry
when you know really we're here to stay
and need to make sure that we have that
long-term mindset
and also just i think one of the most
important things when i see
uh successful legacy operators you know
as they enter into the market they're
you know don't stay isolated connect
with other people in the industry learn
from your uh yeah i think you should
cooperation um and you know not to give
a shameless plug for you know trade
associations but join the trade
associations that represent you and give
to politicians who support you uh show
you know show up and speak your mind to
those who who maybe don't or on the
fence and be visible um those who kind
of hide out and you know think that
they're going to be able to you know
lay low and not be affected by policy
changes or regulatory changes or you
know
the criminal justice system almost
always eventually
fail guys give it up this is one of the
best in the industry right here
right here man so we're gonna
we got 10 minutes left we want to do
some q a with some of the brightest
minds in the industry anybody want to
come up some questions
feel free we'd love to answer them
any questions
let's uh
over here
hey jason shower at modern extractor
podcast i just wanted to add one thing
to too
what you guys were just saying about the
advantages that or advice for legacy
brands entering into the regulated
market your biggest advantage is the
network that you've had having to
operate as a legacy brand so that's
that's a huge thing for me just wanted
to throw that out there so use those
relationships because the uh the big
corporate big bad wolf doesn't happen
that's absolutely right i mean having
you know the relationships is very
important as you bridge that because you
can actually share connections and you
can share those types of resources so
thank you for adding that that's that's
really really appreciate that well
that's what you do with the modern
extractor podcast right because like
that's what we're talking about we're
saying education like you're bringing
people on to talk about extraction which
is not as like sexy of a topic as like
some of these other things but you're
empowering people to be able to do it
themselves and teaching a man how to
fish for himself so you're a perfect
example of just one person just having a
microphone bringing people on but that's
going to be played thousands of times
hopefully more and that's you know
that's that's a you're a great example
thank you
next question over here
so it's kind of a comment question um i
actually just recently relocated to
europe from the us after having been in
the industry for about seven years um
and part of what i realized is that
most of the topic around legacy market
kind of focuses in the us on the illicit
market and i don't feel like there's
enough information about working towards
medical and honoring the medical system
in the u.s specifically we've really
gone in the direction of recreational
because that's where the money is what
i'm noticing over here in europe is that
that's different it seems like lisa has
some things to add on that that the
culture is just completely different and
so a lot of these are kind of north
american specific problems there's no
war on drugs over in europe i mean there
are
[Applause]
but um yeah of course maybe each other
as their own but
um i just think it's going to have a lot
more
education and testing and and a lot of
the compliance centric that we're really
going to benefit from back in the u.s
and i'm really excited to see what
europe does with that i think that it's
going to be a really good thing from us
as well
you see one
yeah i mean definitely if you think
about standards
there is no real cannabis standard so
these standards have to be developed and
you have a step ahead but i think like
for the
for the european ecosystem we need to
create our own and look at what is
happening in other areas like for
example for the medicinal cannabis but
especially for recreational it shouldn't
be so strict but still there should be a
safe product for the consumer but if you
think of the legacy market in europe
what are these brands that we have here
as legacy brands it's the seed banks
it's the bongs accessories
stoner media all these kind of things
those other legacy brands that we have
here but for the real cannabis producers
there are no brands this is all illegal
so
and i would agree with her on that you
know i also want you to make sure that
you can differentiate between medical
and adult use you know medical
absolutely has a totally different path
through science and education and really
the therapeutic uses of cannabis which
has been done for thousands of years
right whereas adult use is more like the
lifestyle
right so important to understand those
differentiators but thank you for adding
that to this and i'm i'm glad that we
can you know cover that too as well
next question
and
our question to the women on the panel
do you feel that some of the projects
you've been talking about about
community and
um do you feel that women in the
industry are more com ready to
collaborate even right the way up to the
ceo level and this is where a lot of the
change is happening by the women pushing
these good causes whereas the men don't
necessarily want to talk about it as
much
um luna that's
back when women grow first came out in
2015 i was one of the bay area chapter
heads and
i oh i don't i mean
it's just the willingness and the
ability i don't know if it's just
because women are typically codependent
so we just say yes to everything we give
away free consulting all the time i
don't know if it's a bad thing but it
definitely feels like camaraderie and
there's something shared with
marginalized people i'm also a jew too
so like there's this thing about when
you meet another dude there's just like
this love of like you kind of understand
me and women just know without having to
say anything that we have to work extra
hard and our ideas are not always
considered valid and we will say
something that a man says and it'll be
ignored until he repeats it and it's
then it's heralded so there's these
micro aggressions and these small
violences every day that wear at your
self-confidence and your ability to
really show up fully and so when women
see that and support each other it's not
that men don't it's just that there's no
way for someone who has a majority
culture um that privilege can ever
really understand how hard it is to be
and then once you start adding
intersectionality of then sexuality race
you know all that stuff then there's
like you know you know black women or
queer black women and all those things
you have on top of it so we like to
support each other because it just feels
like there's already stuff that doesn't
have to be said and we just know that
we're there for each other in ways that
i wouldn't say i've always been welcomed
in by men i i have to prove myself to
men women automatically accept me for
the most part
i'll i'll just add to that and say that
you know i think that part of you know
what what we've seen evolve in the in
the market and in america is this really
intense sense of
competition which is really
misfounded because the reality is is
that there's so much white space even
right now in the industry in the us
i think this idea of collaboration and
cooperation is actually intrinsic to the
plan it's a female plan at the end of
the day we've been using it forever it's
never going to stop whether it's legal
or it's illegal or whether it's
stigmatic or it's not i think women are
really like you know we're seeing this
in the united states the amount of
secret chats and groups and you know
it's necessary it's an incredibly
misogynistic industry in the states i i
can tell you as a woman of color running
a brand in california i've experienced
sexual harassment physical assault this
is a really intense industry to be a
part of um but the good news is is that
folks like us everybody in this room is
like awake and that we have these
conversations because the opportunity to
exponentially grow is
like it's boundless so i think when we
when we have these kinds of
conversations that luna and i are
looking at each other you know rolling
our eyes half and also half like so
excited because we see the opportunity
we see you know i'm always open to
collaboration as a brand i don't view my
fellow ceos of other brands as
competitors i view them as part of the
same class like we all have the same
ptsd we all have the same adrenal
fatigue we're all getting beaten up at
the same rate so let's hold hands and do
it together because at the end of the
day the enemies the real enemies of our
industry your tobacco big pharma like
let's be real like we need to be focused
and be aligned and work together i think
it's it's massive so amen awesome
awesome that's amazing thank you so much
thank you i would like i would like to
to thank and congratulate all the
speakers you have been brilliant
i think when it comes to education it's
very hard for us to talk
without expressing
the need to work with schools and at the
university level
because we need to prepare
all the health professionals
[Music]
on this subject you know
and it's hard to believe that things are
going to change if you don't involve
schools and universities and also the
biggest organizations corporations in
the world that lead with education like
unicef
u.n
and unesco
world bank and all the institutions that
that
finance
the education around the world we need
to have this subject on the manuals on
the textbooks
in schools in different areas in
different degrees
and that's why for example i am at this
point organizing the
the international expo on
hemp
and
related with cannabis in lisbon
on june 18 and 19th
we are
in lisbon talking about all these
subjects and bringing not only
politicians and entrepreneurs and this
and that but also journalists who need
a lot this preparation
schools
universities june 18 and 19 in lisbon
thank you so much so i think
congratulations thank you i think
there's two things happening one there's
a conspiracy uh because of big pharma
that doesn't want people to grow their
own and they also don't want doctors to
learn about the endocannabinoid system
so there's like that private interest
and that whole thing but also
until this is not federally illegal in
most countries none of these other
banking institutions everything has to
come from
decriminalization or from descheduling
it in our it needs to come down from
being a hard drug because none of these
people they all have lawyers even like
instagram
their lawyers just read cannot promote
the use or sale of drugs promoting the
use could just be smoking they're just
the lawyers of all these things are just
reading the laws so the banks it's not
really up to them until we decriminalize
no one's going to get on board and put
it in schools it's just how it is that's
why we that's why we need lobbying
they're just waiting i don't even think
that there's like a cultural like i
don't even necessarily think that
they're they're doing that sorry guys
yeah
so yeah i i just think that we need to
remember that
until we
they're waiting for the green light i
think people are actually going to be
excited i think you know harvard medical
school i'm sure wants to teach about the
endocannabinoid system until until they
feel like they can do it without losing
their federal funding it's a gag rule
it's a literal gag rule they will not
give you federal funding if you teach
these things in schools right right well
guys this is all the time we have thank
you guys so much give me a round of
applause for our
panelists here and i see bc too as well
thank you guys so much you guys are
amazing