uh and now to deliver our our keynote
speech are you ready
I know you just sat down but now you
have to get back up again uh the chief
scientist for Lumiere lab and asano bio
group uh the keynote speaker please put
your hands together and welcome Dr
Lumiere hanush
[Applause]
[Music]
good morning
my name is
cannabis from 1970.
I work 20 years at the Medical Faculty
of Pulaski University in all about
Czechoslovakia
all the time in hospital we treated
patients with cannabis it was from 1955
to 1990.
and the Dr 1990 Professor meshulam
invited me for one year to Jerusalem for
research it's 33 years ago it will be in
several days exactly 33 days and
it was more or less successful and so I
stayed in adelier
and it's 33 years but during that time I
also
was several times at National Institute
of Health
in Bethesda Maryland
and I was an niddk it was a kidney yes
and there is a Russian ni Triple A
National Institute of alcohol abuse and
alcoholism and over there I did a
research of hibernation
overground scores
and uh
we studied
concentrations of endocannabinoids
during hibernation of this grounds War
because as you can see later
it's very important for certain human
problems which can be
treated because they are influenced by
endocannabinoids and if they are
influenced by endocannabinoids it means
that they will be also influenced by
cannabinoids
yeah
you know concerning sleeping it can be
estivated estivation during summer that
animals won't protect
from dry season
but we talk about hibernation it's more
interesting because it's in the winter
when it's short day
it's low temperatures and is not enough
food
so animals enter a stage with they
called hibernation and also it's a lot
dark and it's quiet because the nature
is quiet and it's very important for
hibernation
concerning hibernation so through
hibernators
[Music]
Grand scores hedgeworks and other
animals and
they enter this stage because is not
enough food
so during summer they eat a lot of food
to be fatty and this fed later during
hibernation they use like source of food
for their body and at the same time it's
also
protection is fed against a coward when
they hibernate from time to time they
awake just to check themselves if there
are not some parasites sometimes they
won't eliminate some waste from the body
and sometimes they won't eat like you
know the squirrels they collect
food for winter
so
also very interesting is Black Bear in
America it's not the exact hibernator
because drop
of temperature is about only between
five and six degrees but this
Bears they sleep
almost six months and
during
this what is surprising that there is no
increase of porosity of their bones and
also they don't use
any water and they don't have any kidney
problems because
urea when accumulates so it can be toxic
but they can
work up it to other compounds used to
nitrogen for proteins and so on
so scientists studied such Bears is
complicated because when they sleep they
can awake when you touch them so
it's special method how to prepare them
and uh
and they found that this this Bears can
survive without any problem and it can
help if it solves this problem how they
do it help to people which has chronic
kidney failure so they can be treated
and they check also bonus TBR its lower
part of of the lake
bound and they saw that nine months over
the grizzly and six six months later
there was no increase in porosity
so
hibernation protect them because all
metabolic processes goes down
up to 1998 percent
concerning these bonds so
it's about 19 years ago
they brought me bones
from mice and wanted this was tibia
this is the bond which they use from
theirs to check porosity and femur and
they told me check if there are some
noise
so I analyze it and I found that there
is a very small Peak as you can see
almost invisible
it's in green
so I analyzed this peak and
we have Spectrum just to
it didn't run in
GC so we preparation derivative
and it run very nice and we found that
this is simulated to AG two arachidan
oil glycerol this was second
endocannabinoid which was discovered
this isolated
Professor Shimon Ben Shabbat
laboratory I also participated but I did
binding studies because at that time Dr
Bill Devane already wasn't over there
so he teach me how to do it so I did
binding studies
and that to AG stimulates
[Music]
bones to be stronger it was proved and
there is also patterned from
that when they used to AG
with animals so as you can see Romans
were stronger there was less porosity so
this is very important to agendo
cannabinoid which can protect not only
animals but also
it must be vodka but also it will be
very useful for human being
you know
concerning bones because there are a
osteoclast and osteoblasts these are
cells which
decompose bones and
below the bones so this we call
this we call bone remodeling and it it
goes all the time so bones which you
have before are not the same bones you
have just all new
or newborn cells
and this endocannabinoids this already
know everybody that CB1 is in a
reproductive system and brain and in
Bones uh CB2 because it's an immune
system
and back to the
hibernating animals what is very
interesting that
they drop breath if they breath
200 times per minute it drops 100 times
to two two breast per minute and hard B
from 200 it drops just only two beats
per minute
so it's important that the hero is
hypothermia
temperature goes really
strongly down and it protects and also
all metabolic processes goes up to 90
and 8 percent down
as you can see marmots this is probably
also here in the mountains in Slovenia I
think at least in Slovakia we can see
them
so they the temperature of the body
drops from 31 to only five point seats
and respiration what I said respiration
drops down 25 times and heartbeat drops
down 25 times and also brain activity
bronze
drops down about 90 percent but the
world champion between hibernators are
Arctic Grand scores
temperature of the body it's
unbelievable decrease from 37 to minus
3.1 minus 3.1 is like frozen meat yes
but nothing happened they survive
without any problem
and uh
after hibernation State they are again
okay and solve all this
secrets of hibernation can help solve
some life threatening situations that
the human being but
[Music]
to understand hibernation they can they
hibernate six months but it's impossible
six months because they can die so each
two weeks temperature goes up it's
extreme energy and as they stay about
one day
on the top and then they again hibernate
and during this one day they check if
they don't have parasites eventually
they eat or they eliminate waste from
the body and it's repeated regularly up
to the end of hibernation and you see
down these dots this is temperature
temperature of the soil so if they stay
somewhere so they are sleeping in the
fact at -10
anything so they can survive so this is
one day when temperature goes up and
against down and this sagaround squalls
what we studied this uh again
animals which can
hibernate about half a year
and during hibernation again goes down
as her deed as a frequency of breath and
metabolic rate also decrease and
covered and dark in everything together
help them survive
you know and
these these pictures these are these 13
ground scores
and this is like human in the fact when
we look on the situation which is in the
body of this world it's like human which
suffer a stroke
but they have no problem and what they
found that blood doesn't clot
that there is a rich of ascorbic acid
blood what can be interesting for for
human being and
and other
white cells are going to hide in for
that time so it everything helps them
survive code and if a human could have a
hibernate
so body temperature should drop to 5
degrees as you can see heard me three
per minute
and breath in one per four minutes
so it's impossible but we can
learn it and use it by different way to
help human beings
now concerning our study at National
Institute of Health
we studied brain parts of hibernating
non-harby hibernating and regular
squares non-harbenating this was at 4
degrees Centigrades
room temperature they are very very wild
so we need special gloves because they
can bite you but as soon as
they are and we studied several
endogenous compounds
anandamide
2 AG olamide olive oil
this
was like standard
and when hibernate this ground squirrel
because it's cold four degrees so they
are like from a refrigerator
so they are like ball and when you catch
them they cannot protect themselves so
sometimes happen that some wild animals
find them underground and eat them
because they cannot protect themselves
if I keep it one hour in my hand and
opens slowly one eye and it takes about
three hours to be okay
[Music]
so we studied several part of brains
this was especially
Professor parkovich from Hungary which
separated for us this part of brains
every time on the spot in
in at NIH and this was cerebellum limbic
for the brain amygdala hippocampus and
hippo thalamus
and to the results the most interesting
was 2ag
this looks that this is very important
endocrabinoid
and uh
as you can see RT is room temperature
for this is four degrees
and HIV is hibernating
they were engaged at four degrees but
not all start to hibernate some of the
them
stay
regularly but at four degrees
but this even Discord
influence amounts of their
endocannabinoids
as you can see
2ag in comparison with room temperature
and this 4 degrees
I shall talk about like four degrees it
means which referred for the the
temperature 4 degrees it was
significantly different in cerebellum
a similar
it was also in limbic for a for a brain
it was not like cerebrum but still it
was significant for three stars limbic
foreign and then we studied also
2ag in amigdala in amigdala still you
can see
that significantly higher concentrations
of 2he
the better at hibernating scores
from other compounds we studied
epilolamide in cerebellum you can see
that it
scores at four degrees and hibernating
it increased significantly in comparison
with room temperature and the last
compound
which we studied the number of
differences but I'm talking about this
whichever the most significant and
olamide this is called sometimes
sleeping factor in limbic for a brain
you can see that increased significantly
when labor at 4 degrees and also at the
hibernating
and we studied also olamide in the all
compounds but polyamide in plasma was
the most
important and in comparison of this
regular squash at room temperature you
can see that
this only am I think the significantly
increased so probably
these are the most important and the
cannabinoids which
protect these other protection factors
of course this ground scores
survive
our interest was also concerning some
compound which we would like to call
hibernator
so we try to find which compound
has rise changes and this is part of
part of chromatogram and we founded this
compound which is in blue
that significantly decrease so we try to
identify this compound and on the left
is NOLA in itra this is one of
endocannabinoids which we isolated at
Hebrew University
[Music]
there is one double boneless
otherwise it's the same as noladin ether
unfortunately
didn't have somebody who can synthesize
this for us
to to prove that it fits 100 percent
because only analysis and Spectra it's
nice but we like every time prove it
with a real compound
so what
is the result from this our studies you
know if we understand molecular
mechanism
of a bone Mars main financing beers so
it can be it can lead to prevent
osteoporosis at chronically hospitalized
patients because they stay in the bed so
that it goes very fast osteoporosis
formation that
just kidney
drops urine in kidney drops by 95
percent so it can be very important to
treat people suffering from chronic
kidney failure
and understanding how body temperatures
are tolerated by squares
May facilitate that organs for
transplantation we can store more time
because sometimes for long distance so
it's a long time so it can be
safer and molecular mechanism of
Tolerance of blood flow because its
blood flow is very low so it can also
give us a hints
for treatment of ischemia
and then
during
hibernation blood flow as I said drops
down up to 98 percent for several weeks
and identification of this molecular
mechanism
can again help us protect from injury
due to stroke or heart attack so these
are very important thing and
I would like to tell you it will be at
the end but I want it there now so
Extreme Survival this arteries of
hibernation of animals and occasionally
human as I show you directly and
it can overcome life's threatening
injuries
that human body also can fight against
cold like animals I show you three
unbelievable examples there is more but
I choose three
in Norway
one radiologist she did cross-country
with friends and the neighbor across in
the river
so
breaks ice and she fall exactly was as
you can see they couldn't take her up
because also they can be under eyes so
she found her some air bubble and was
fighting for minutes for life
then she finished and she was more than
ever in this icy water
no breasts no heartbeat
more than our and her body temperature
that they brought you was only
13.7 degrees
he survived
they treated her
and they hit slowly blood
outside they took it outside and back
and she survived
in Canada
at two at night
I work as small smaller girl and
accidentally she opened door and went
outside to snow there was minus 20
degrees parents found her and she was
more than our already without breasts
without
a heartbeat and had 21 degrees they took
her to hospital and the next day
they treated her next day she was okay
and this is very interesting this
hibernating man one man went from France
from region where are usually are not
people
he fall and broke his Paris
and he couldn't move so stayed one day
and then he lost Consciousness and they
found him after 24 days there was
temperature 10 degrees
he was without food without water had no
pass almost organs at all almost shut
down and body temperature was only 23
degrees
they took him to hospital he survived
without any problems after that
so human body has possibilities but we
must
find we must study it and find these
possibilities concerning hibernation
what really can help in treatment and
Professor meshulam which unfortunately
this is ingenuary we celebrated his 92
and he was perfect then
he became Chicken in six weeks he died
so he said that there is almost
any physiological process which
is influence in the body by
endocannabinoids and he said that
whatever THC doesn't understand also so
I can only add that cannabinoids can do
whatever
endocannabinoids do and in the
cannabinois they mimic
endocannabinoids so if we can see that
during this hibernation
uh
examples of lice threatening situations
which can be treated humans that we
should study it I know only another one
publication appeared after us we studied
this endocannabinois uh grandson in
hibernation so it cannot really help
humans
to treat this serious problems
thank you very much for your attention
Dr Harris
we may have time for a few questions
does anybody have a question there's a
question right here here yeah
hello Roman from The Faculty of Health
Sciences I would just like to maybe if
you give us a follow-up you show them
that you found the molecule which is
responsible for hibernating and you said
that nobody isolated do you have any
follow-up any progress on that specific
molecule
I don't have progress because when I
finish at NIH
so we didn't have anybody to synthesize
it so I
and I was forced to return because we
had a project in Jerusalem so I couldn't
stay longer I returned again for months
and we studied it so we came to decision
that this is the compound which I showed
you
so
we have to look into it if somebody else
did it then something okay thank you
it's still opened
but probably it's this compounding so it
will be probably
also endocalabinoid
are there more questions oh over here
I'm closer so
It's a Wonderful presentation do you
have any idea or hypothesis of what the
Ananda mind does what is its function in
the hibernation because it was so much
increased
is very interesting compound
it's not the best compound from
endocannabinoids I isolated even more
active compound but because anandamide
was the first one
so it's such studied you know this is
like active was THC so everybody studied
the AC and here was
an undermine so everybody studied
anandramide and then they studied 2ag
y2hd and not docosa
retinolamide which isolated and which
was more active because 2ag is different
chemistry because one time it's am I the
one time it's Easter so that is why they
wanted to study
different chemical nature of the
compound that is why these two compounds
are mostly studied and we saw that the
main function in organism is protect
humans from stress
why we name it anandamide there are two
reasons
Ananda is bliss Delight and Dr William
Devane studied Eastern philosophy and
they found that in sanskrat Ananda is
bliss Delight
so he wanted to name it anandadin
when you isolated we shall call it
anandarin he said because he was a
specialist in molecular pharmacology and
all my isolates he tested for activity
so we did it together because
one without the other one couldn't do it
so it was a perfect cooperation and when
we identified it professor musulam said
ah but chemical nature also and it was
ethanol amide
[Music]
because it should Express happiness of
discoverers and ex expected effect
that is in organism
compound which makes you happy or which
beats your stress
thank you so you're saying that weed
makes you happy which is great
are there any more questions
[Applause]
over there no one's going to come over
this is this is Noah let's hear it for
Noah everybody he's helping
he's got the nice shoes
hello uh fascinating uh presentation so
curious so the final closing statements
of endocannabinoids and cannabinoids
having a high crossover effect
what is your proposed study how we can
start seeing the effects of the
cannabinoids and
endocannabinoid systems since like you
said everyone jumped on THC because it
was the first there's so many potential
subcompounds to study what's the
framework that you're looking at does
that exist does it need to be done
what's the future look like in this
space
you know in the fact when I
was forced to enter pension because you
can work in Israel only to age 68 so I
work at the University at 69. we are
head of department but I wasn't
you can stay for good
up to death yes so I finished at 69 and
I came to to the company
which wanted to treat endometriosis with
cannabis so we studied endometriosis
it's really very interesting because
about between 10 and 11 percent women in
productive age
has endometriosis some of them don't
know that it's endometriosis because it
can take long longer time
to find that this disease is
endometriosis and probably I am not
going to talk about that because you
probably know all these signs
from which we understand it so in Israel
I know one physician
he treated with cannabis several women
misendrumentriosis and he was successful
so this is filled which is very
interesting unfortunately this company
as we say coronavirus ate ate them
so this laboratory doesn't continue
because they didn't have money because
of Corona
so
this
at the moment it's in the eyes it's
waiting to continue then we'll be more
favorable situation they also moved from
here Jerusalem it was very complicated
to travel you know travel every day
three hours
to the left it's too much so
so what happened this happened and the
study of cannabinoids of course the most
interesting study should be a real
calabinois it means real carabinoids are
acid cannabinoid acids of course
and they studied the carboxylase and the
carboxylase of this real seeds are for
cannabiserolic cannabis romantic
tetrahedral cannabinole cannabidiolic
and also cannabis hero
cannabidi or tetrahedral cannabinol and
cannabis Roman so these are the main
compounds which are studied because they
are in highest concentrations
and uh
sometime we must find how how to give it
to the patient because
if you imagine that concentrations of
anandamide if I knew that I never start
to isolate it the concentrations are
nanograms per gram
what is nothing it was now when I
isolated for the first time and I
evaporated it so glass tube was clean
that was nothing but I dissolved this
nothing and we build and tested it so it
was active yeah so it's a very low
concentrations and
with our effort at the end we have half
milligram it was enough for
identification half milligram it was a
huge amount when you imagine so probably
calabino is when they are used so also
very small amounts in the fact are used
by the body
all everything is lost because sometimes
people use grams of cannabinoisms and so
on yes so it's still even when uh now
thousand Publications I cannot check
everything before I sense
uh snail mail and I had all reference
today it's impossible even though you
cannot download all papers every week is
between one and 300 papers on kind of
you know it's an endocannabinoids
so if you rest one month so then you
have
almost 2 000 papers sometimes so it
takes me two days I'll just only go go
through these papers and to find what is
important
so of course it must be studied because
cannabinoids mimic
endocannabinoids and not everybody of us
has
endocannabinoid system enacts enough
strong to be diseases
somebody has disease but
endocannabinoid system fast returns to
homeostasis and then is balancing
organisms and you are healthy and
sometimes organism is in a is not enough
strong so you must use cannabinois to
help to the person
so and there is so many diseases
that discuss it is not such easy and why
is so many diseases which can be treated
because kind of endocardial system and
cannabinoid receptors are one of the
most spread receptors in human body you
can find it almost anywhere that is why
it worked with so many diseases
thank you so very much one more time
[Applause]
he does make a good point like we're
just starting to really understand all
the the compounds and the the chemicals
and the terpenes and the Essences in the
CBD and the CBG and the CDN and THC and
the thca and the thcv and the rama lama
ding dong and the
supercalifragilisticexpialidocious
there's so many different
chemicals and we we've never really
studied the cannabis plant for you know
for a long time we weren't allowed to so
I'm great that I'm very happy that
everyone is here to to study more and
it's going to be Years and we're going
to learn new things all the time it's
going to be great yeah
yeah don't forget we're gonna donate to
the floods oh thanks Alex let's hear it
for Alex Rogers everybody
I'm like
you hear that the ICBC is going to match
up to a thousand Euros so there you go
that's a good deal
right so everybody here put in 10 euros
uh but we'll do that in a minute