the California Bureau of cannabis
control Laurie Ajax that's here for
everybody there you go good morning
everybody this is gonna be kind of a
unique experience for me because I get
to sit next to a regulator without
wanting to shake some sense into them
so it should be kind of a fun
conversation just before we start I want
to kind of cover a very brief history
because those of you that know me know
I'm a nerd that way of both California
and Vancouver and BC in particular they
share a very long parallel history they
were both hubs during the gold rush
they both housed a lot of X railroad
workers they were both involved with the
opium war and they also contributed a
lot to cannabis both individually and
together starting in the counterculture
movements in the 60s we saw a lot of
draft dodgers come up to Vancouver and
BC which did actually revitalize our
cannabis community up here but it also
created an interesting situation where
one of those draft dodgers met a
descendant of a Chinese man who had come
over here during the opium wars and they
formed one of the most potent pairs in
cannabis cannabis Cheech and Chong so
that was one of the first sort of
partnerships that BC and California
shared in 1991 a man named Thomas
O'Malley opened the first compassion
Club the first cannabis dispensary in
the world for at least 50 60 years and
he inspired a bunch of cannabis
communities up here to also start
compassion clubs the VC compassion Club
Society Victoria cannabis eyelid
Beiler's Club and Toronto compassion
Club calm and a few in Toronto as well
so they shared very similar histories
until fairly recently now of course in
Vancouver we have federal regulation
which has meant that BC doesn't really
get a chance to kind of regulate its own
industry whereas in California the US
federal government is not so much for it
which leaves California free to at least
kind of regulate their own local state
industry some of the other issues that
we've been having that are both parallel
is that the focus on adult use market or
the recreational market has really sort
of left Medical dispensaries as sort of
a side issue that people aren't really
interested in talking about right now it
keeps being kind of put off so Lori
that's my first question for you is
where is California in terms of their
medical program well first of all thank
you very much for having me here in
Canada it's just an honor to be here and
as much as she may want to shake a
regulator I'll put myself over you can
shake me thing we weird they're just so
much to learn here I just find it
fascinating what's going on here in
Canada but when you look at like the
medical market in California I think you
know we're also seeing it shrinking just
from the sheer fact of how we regulate
it now at early on in 2018 we used to
require licensees if you wanted to do
adult use and medical use you had to get
separate licenses to do it so you'd have
to come in and get your medical license
to self to medical patients and then
adult use license to sell to consumers
and that really wasn't working well
that's probably when the industry
brought it really was like it really
this doesn't make a lot of sense we're
getting two licenses for the same
premises we're having two your basically
filling out the same application so
within about six months of 2018 we
change that and we have one license and
then the license is designated adult use
or medical use and that's really
determined by the local jurisdiction
because California in order for the
state to issue any sort of commercial
cannabis license it has to be approved
by the local jurisdiction and at
California's very large so that's over
500 different local jurisdictions across
the state so they that's determined so
we still have jurisdictions that just
allow medical some allow both but I
think what we're seeing is is for the
average patient it's a lot easier just
to go in and get you know by it you know
as adult use because they don't have to
get a recommendation
it's you know that that costs money they
don't have to get a medical marijuana
card and so I think you're finding more
consumers are just skipping that part of
it the other thing we've been looking at
though is access because you know we
still have a lot of jurisdictions in
California that don't allow commercial
cannabis activity I think we're just
about two-thirds still so for our
medical patients there are some areas
that's very difficult for them to get
legal access to cannabis so one of our
regulations does allow if you're
licensed to deliver in California you
can deliver anywhere in the state and
that has created some controversy in
California for us what happened there
whoa hello oh I think that's working
yeah that was one of the things that I
wanted to talk about a lot unfortunately
Laurie can't talk about it that much
because the state really did go to bat
for delivery services and they're being
sued by cities now to not allow delivery
services which is why she can't talk
about it as much as she'd like to also
one of the reasons why I was kind of sad
when I heard that because it was like
that's a really that that sort of sets
you apart from most of other regulators
up here our regulators appear very happy
to forget about medical the situation
that you're describing is almost sort of
wished for where they can just shunt
medical patients to the adult system and
then they don't track it and you know it
it becomes easier to forget the cannabis
as medicine again right so with that in
terms of where it's at for medical what
is going on with just the strict this
strictly adult use side well again with
you know we're looking at about 6,000
license I think around 6500 licenses
across the state across the supply chain
so we are seeing you know a lot of areas
that still don't have licensing so in
those areas it's you know we we want to
make sure that people have a legal
access to get cannabis but you are
seeing people go to the adult use market
go to lie
since retailers they want the different
brands and varieties that you can get
from licensed retailers but I think what
we're looking at right now is Believe It
or Not when you look at distribution
versus retailer we have more
distributors right now than we do
retailers and so I think for us we're
hoping we can get more jurisdictions to
allow retail sales because I think for
consumers you want competition you want
you know again you don't want to drive
two hours to get legal cannabis so so a
lot of work to do on that front and
working with the local jurisdictions
yeah and that involves different
jurisdictions because sometimes it's the
city sometimes it's the county correct
correct yeah it's fun what I said I
wasn't gonna put you on the spot but
what other governmental agencies are
getting involved like so for example
here in BC the agricultural land
Commission decided that that they were
gonna have a chance to kind of express
an opinion on stuff we've got Metro
Vancouver that's trying to put limits on
growing there's like all of these other
areas of government that are also trying
to step in yeah our our statute actually
sets up I mean we you know we didn't do
anything easy in California we have a
lot of different state agencies involved
so not only do you have the local
control issue you have three different
licensing authorities the the agency I
oversee the Bureau of cannabis control
is the lead agency but when it comes to
issuing cultivation licenses we have the
Department of Food and Agriculture for
manufacturing the Department of Public
Health issues those licenses if your
cultivator you also have to get your
water permit you got to get a pin rent
with Fish and Wildlife and then you deal
with for your seller's permit on taxes
you have to deal with the taxing
agencies so a lot of intersection with a
lot of different state agency which you
know especially when you're looking at a
market that was really in California a
medical market that really wasn't it
wasn't regulated by the state and at
some point maybe some regulation at the
local level but trying to get all those
folks in and then say hey by the way you
got to deal with you know five different
agency it's
it's a it can be daunting for anybody
you know and and then again it's like
you know here is the government we want
all this information from you we want
you to keep records which you know
typically that's probably what you
didn't want to do you know prior to
regulate sort of something the
government encouraged you not to do so
it's interesting and and for sure
challenging and I think you know for any
regulator you know maybe we have a
tendency to probably be you know we you
know over regulate at times are a little
conservative but a lot of times it's
because we don't have a lot of
information when we started out in this
journey a three and a half years ago
with first setting up medical statutory
framework and then adult use it's like
you're you're doing you know and not
that you want to hear this but you know
you just didn't have a lot to look we
had you know Colorado look at in
Washington but really for California
it's so unique and a lot of times as a
regulator you just you you put something
out there and you know sometimes it
works sometimes it doesn't but I will
say in California when you look at all
the folks regulating I mean the one
thing I will say is we we want to
continue to engage with the industry and
we do make changes when things don't
work we make changes and we try to do it
fairly quickly because we know for for a
lot of you that are in the legal market
no matter where you are it's a struggle
and if the regulators aren't listening
and we aren't seeing like hey you know
what as long as it's not going to
compromise public safety it's up to us
to really continue to engage you and
make sure that we're making those
changes so you can thrive question
around consumption so some cities like
San Francisco allow consumption on like
retail type premises or lounge areas how
is California deal with you know up in
Canada of course that stuff is actually
regulated provincially but usually they
just kind of sweep it under the key
tobacco smoking act and just kind of
leave it alone so how does California
handle that
so California for the most part
consumption on retail premises it has to
be approved at the local level so most
of that's pushed down for the local
jurisdiction to determine whether or not
they want consumption right now it's
just that it can only happen at retail
premises and I think you know but we're
starting to see you know places at well
we don't want to sell cannabis but we
just want to have a place where people
can bring their cannabis and consume and
I think we're right now trying to deal
with that and what does that look like
do you need to be licensed do you not
need to be licensed so those are the
some things we're dealing with and and
we're dealing with some issues with
cities that they want to have more than
just consumption they want to also you
know serve other items like coffee and
you know you know food and things like
that so those are the things that we're
gonna be looking at really closely over
the next few months is you know how do
you normalize it because you know you
know for most of us if you don't consume
cannabis but maybe you have friends that
do you want to be able to go to places
where you know your friend can consume
cannabis and maybe you can have a you
know a coffee or whatever and so I think
I think we're gonna see more of that
coming especially with all the tourism
we have in California so well I think I
think it's time we evolved I mean it
seems like I'm gonna tell you it's been
a year and a half like you're in seven
months in California and it feels like
it's been so much longer and we're like
hey let's evolve and and but but it's
true you guys you guys move at
lightning-fast speed and you know you
just sort of drag us along with you so
well at least you're willing to be
drugged not all regulators are one of
the favorite things you know you
mentioned normalization and that's been
one of the favorite things I've seen out
of California so far there was a
campaign awhile ago I don't remember who
was responsible for it but it was
showing like Rockwell type family images
and over in the corner there just be an
ashtray with a joint in it and it was
really subtle and really nice to see you
guys have launched weed wise hashtag
weed wise can you tell us a little bit
about that program yeah so you know as
most of you know we've we've got a lot
of challenges in California and
especially the illegal
market right and the unlicensed market
and making sure people understand you
want to always you know we're always
looking to issue licenses and then
aggressively attack the unlicensed
market but we always felt there needed
to be an educational component to that
so we lost a launched a public awareness
campaign back in June called hashtag
weed wise and it really has two goals
one it's to let the unlicensed market
know that if you're conducting
commercial cannabis activity you have to
have a license and you need to get
licensed otherwise you're gonna get shut
down so that's that's one part of it and
the second part is really educating the
consumers on why it's important they go
to a licensed retail shop so you know
it's great that we license everybody but
if an average consumer doesn't know
whether they're walking into a legal
shop or not we've only we haven't done
art we haven't done our job right we
need to just because we talk about you
know I don't I think we all talk about
this probably 24/7 but your average
consumer doesn't know when they walk
into a retail shop is this license is
this unlicensed and why it's important
that they're probably paying more than
they are on the illegal market why it is
that you know telling them we're testing
it you're gonna get safe cannabis and so
it's been it's been really interesting
so we just launched a license we know we
had our regular license search and but
we've launched in it's called see a pot
check comm and we've been really pushing
that out there so people can check if
they're walking into a store they can
check to see if or not they have a
license and stuff so really some
exciting stuff going on with that and I
always say I I don't I don't think in my
entire state career I'd ever think that
the state of California would have a
website called see a pot check com but
here we are isn't it's great actually
well and you also ran public service
announcements starring Cheech Marin as a
government regulator who would answer
your questions if you wanted to get
licensed you know one of the issues that
we've been having up here is that our
existing illegal market
is actually higher-quality by most
standards than our regulated market and
they've got a lot more customer loyalty
there's barriers around testing for sure
because some of them do get it tested
but they can't really tell you that they
got it tested because the lab doesn't
want to say that they've been testing
the legal cannabis and California is
also in a very similar situation where
you've got some areas that have a lot of
experience with cannabis very
knowledgeable consumers and a highly
developed market and then you've got
other areas that the markets probably
not quite as developed so what would you
say are the barriers for currently
illicit retailers for example to get
licensed
well I and most of it is their local
jurisdiction maybe where they've been
operating for a long time is not
allowing a commercial cannabis so that's
that's a big barrier and then finding a
city or county that is going to allow it
and you know when when we say there's
four hundred and eighty-three cities and
58 counties that means you're going to
each local jurisdiction trying to see if
your business can do you know if they're
even accepting application so it is a
patchwork of ordinances across the state
so I think that's a big barrier I also
think you know again going back to I
think it's a daunting task you know
where do you even start so if you're
somebody that has been doing this for a
long time it's even hard to know where
to start so more technical assistance is
needed for these folks trying to you
know you know you know remove the
mystery I think when you just tell
people hey fill out this big long
application and you got to get a
background track
I think it's an intimidating process and
I think as a state we've got to keep
realizing that this is not easy for
folks and how do you bring them in to
the process and one of the things we
look at when we do look at enforcement
we are making we are looking at going
after the folks that really have no
intention of getting licensed but if you
have people that are trying to get
licensed trying to work with their local
jurisdiction in the process we're really
trying to to really make sure that we're
bringing those people along because
really we want compliance
that's what we want and I think you know
if we're working to you know I know it
sounds strange to say we want we've got
to work together with the industry to
make sure that everybody survives
because as the state we want the legal
market to survive we want them to do
well we want them to thrive and if we're
not doing it with the lis with together
with you it's not going to work yeah and
there's the difference right there
between a regulatory body that's able to
regulate its own local industry and a
regulatory body that's on the other side
of the country that has to worry about
other local industries as well there
have been questions around shipping I
think that's mostly quieted down last
year was when it was a really big deal
there have been issues with testing what
what have been some of the biggest
challenges from the regulator's point of
view to make sure that you're doing what
works for the industry but what also
works for the state it's a
transportation of cannabis in California
you have to be a distributor just to
transport cannabis between licensees and
then you also have to submit a man if
you have to have a manifest showing
where you're going and what you're doing
and and it is it's a great system and
having that in track and trace but again
it doesn't allow for a lot of
flexibility right if something happens
and you you need to go to another
premises so it's pretty strictly
regulated and transportation and then a
lot of these folks are carrying a lot of
cash so you know they're our
distributors are responsible for
collecting the taxes from the different
licensees so a lot of safety issues
regarding transportation and it is it
you know I think eventually over time
that'll that'll change I mean when you
look at like the alcohol world in
California you don't really have those
strict rules in place for transportation
but I think for right now that's what
needs to happen because we still have so
much illegal cannabis being transported
for the laboratories I mean I'm sure
we're having some of the same we are
having some of the same issues all the
other states have had we have very
strict testing regulations we have labs
that are
you know they're they're getting they're
getting better at what they're testing
for but uh but you know one of the
things we are saying it's expensive for
them for the legal market to test and
especially if things fail you know fail
and they can't remediate it and they
have to destroy it so it's really tough
on the industry the good thing is is
that you know our our failure rate
compared to you know when we started you
know back in January of 2018 our failure
rate was at about 20% we're now down to
just about 8% the labs are getting
better the product you know there's a
lot of testing that goes in our indi
testing that goes prior to at the
regulatory testing so we're seeing a lot
of this product getting through to the
legal market and then we've had some of
those vaping incidents in California
where people were getting sick very sick
off of vape cartridges they had
purchased and the good thing is is that
so far that appears that it only come
from the unlicensed market it has not
come from our legal regulated market
which is really oh I mean is you know
you don't want to see people getting
sick but it's good to see that it is
working having this product tested well
and I think that from you know from a
longtime activist point of view that's
the whole point of regulation you don't
want to see people being able to take
advantage so a you know in the illicit
market for ten thousand years it's been
fine but there's also been stories of
the random person that sprays something
that they know is bad or and it's like
you know they end up giving everybody a
bad reputation but that's the point of
regulation for anything should be just
that make sure that it's safe with
shipping I know that there was a union
that got involved that wanted to kind of
try and provide all the shipping they
didn't want smaller growers to be able
to ship themselves you don't really have
a database of that stuff the way that
Washington State does though so that
protected you from hacking because
Washington State not that long ago had
somebody break into their system and
find out where every single shipment of
cannabis was going everywhere in the
state for like the next two weeks are
you worried about cybersecurity of
any of California's records or documents
absolutely you worry about that all the
time because we you know most of our
applicants submit applications online to
us I would say probably at least 98% of
the application we get is is through our
licensing system and not paper and in
the thought I'm going to tell you the
thought that anybody hacks in and gets a
hold of your information is is really
concerning because you know you need to
if we're gonna get people to come into
the legal market they need to know that
their information is protected by the
state unless it unless it's required by
under our Public Records Act to disclose
you don't want people just getting a
hold of this information and I think you
know that's our job you know and doing
our due diligence to make sure that your
information is not compromised so that's
always something you worry about and and
have you had issues has it been no not
you know we're just starting you know
we're just getting everybody
transitioned to track and trace it over
over the last six months so we haven't
had any issues yet but yeah you know I
don't have any would hear you guys but
yeah we want you to root we want you to
feel like when you come to the
government you're not worried that you
know all your information is getting in
and for safety reasons if everybody's
getting ahold of your shipping manifests
and they know where you're going that's
not a good thing so I mean again there's
only so much a state can do in terms of
municipalities they have their own
jurisdiction over certain things we've
seen cities for example again in the Bay
Area where Oakland
you know offered you know parody
licensing they've offered in Berkeley
they cover some medical cannabis there
have been other cities that have kind of
picked up Oakland's banner and said yeah
you know what we unfairly punished this
war and now we need to make sure that
those people have the same opportunities
how do you reconcile the fact that as a
state you kind of have to stay out of
some of that but you've got one city
that is
happy to try and address an injustice
and another city that's happy to keep
that injustice going as long as possible
yeah and I'm gonna tell you Oakland San
Francisco Sacramento LA the big cities
have really been the leaders these local
jurisdictions on the social equity front
and it's it's it the state is really
trying to catch up and looking at you
know how folks have been affected by the
war on drugs in California and sort of
writing those wrongs one thing the
administration and we have grant funding
at the state level for local for local
jurisdictions that have a local program
in place for social equity we just
closed that application period and next
month we're gonna be awarding ten
million in grants to those cities that
have those those at local equity
programs and then just recently the
governor and his latest budget even put
more money for next year so it's a
thirty million will be going out next
year so another round of funding and
what we're starting to see already is
you are the big cities already led the
charge but now you're having local
jurisdictions going hey we need to do
something in developing these programs
and so I think we're seeing a lot more
cities and counties that are saying hey
we need to do something about this as
well so a pretty it's I'm pretty proud
of the state of California for taking
this on
but you're right it's it'll be
interesting to see what happened
hopefully I can come back next year and
tell you guys how that first round of
funding went and what we were able to
accomplish that's awesome I had another
question it just popped right out of my
head just as we were talking some some
of the issues that that have existed are
around security records up here pardons
expungements whether that stays on your
record or not so I mean I'm I'm really
happy to hear that actually California
as a state is is kind of encouraging as
much as they can within their realm of
what they're allowed to do is there
anything that you think that the state
could be doing more because I mean
it's already more than most states are
doing you know I say we got a lot going
on in California just like you do up
here
I always think we can do more I mean
there's I don't think there's a day go
by when you feel like we're probably not
doing enough to really assist the
cannabis industry and and so and that's
good you want us to feel this way right
there's always something more we can do
to help small businesses to level the
playing field and do all that and so
that's something that is always very
important to us and and we have a very
active cannabis industry and they're
very innovative and creative and
sometimes I hear these business models
and I like I didn't think of that one I
didn't think of that one so it's always
good again I say but thank goodness for
you guys for telling you know cuz we
wouldn't figure out you you guys have
probably more good ideas and we the
regulator's so I always say don't keep
your good ideas to yourself bring them
to us so we can start implementing some
of this I remembered that earlier
question
California's had water rights issues for
a very very long time how has that
played into cannabis regulations in
different jurisdictions yeah that's um
probably for our cultivators that's a
really big issue for them we have a
separate state agency called the State
Water Resources Board that deals with
this but yeah that's become a you know
that's a big permit you have to get when
you're a cultivator so where you're
getting your water how you're getting it
very strictly regulated in California
but not hasn't really it's kind of
stayed in that Bureau and not really
crossed over too much for us at the
bureau cuz we sort of have the supply
chain starting with distribution testing
labs retailers so it doesn't really hit
our agency as much but I know a lot of
our cultivators they there there is a
lot of permits that they have to get in
order to cultivate and I know that's
been very difficult to expect especially
on your small legacy cultivators sort of
a similar question here in Vancouver
we've got a group called Metro van that
represents a bunch of cities in the
Lower Mainland area and all of them and
they're trying to basically say that
outdoor cannabis growing is bad for
pollution and smog to the point where
they've actually suggested that I want
bad air days people move their cannabis
plants inside California has also
traditionally had a lot of issues with
smog has this been an issue at all that
you've seen well I'm not I don't not
that I know of yet I mean that it's
become an issue but I'm sure that
doesn't mean there's not that something
going on in LA or whatever because it's
it's almost I don't know about you guys
but I like do a ton of reading like
every night you're reading tons of
articles and there's always something
going on but I'm sure that's going to
hit us very soon on these sorts of
issues all right I think we're pretty
good to go to the audience for some
questions and answers all right let's
hear one more time for Louie Ajax and
Jamie Shaw very informative I'm coming
over here to you right now sir also
please try to keep your questions brief
no rambling we know how you are then we
don't have to hear the whole story about
the history of cannabis and just hold
your hand up if you have a question I'll
get right over to you hey Lauri I've
seen you speak out a lot I've seen you
speak out a lot of events I've done
public comments in front of you for
regulation specifically on topical
pesticides I remember that and you know
just got to say BCC did really good job
of luck publishing the draft regulations
taking in public comment across the
state listening to the business just
listening to you now and talking about
how you want to work with the cannabis
industry in California is inspiring
especially compared to another
department like the DMV where they don't
want to work with you so nobody wants to
be compared to the DMV thank you so
thank you for that and my question is
I'm starting to see a lot of Wars going
on between
wine in cannabis in California specific
example would be Santa Barbara County
that has limited the amount of cannabis
that will be cultivated in the county
reasons for that being land issues water
issues but also what they're calling the
terpene drift where these like terpenes
draw up going to the air and affect the
terroir of the wine I'm in the taste so
any other issues like that coming up in
like Sonoma County or other parts of
California that you see and how do you
see that being resolved yeah it's it's
actually I find that that's fascinating
what's going on with our wine industry
in the cannabis industry and how you
know Farms next to each other are
dealing with you know because our our
wineries can use pesticides that our
cannabis folks can't use and how do they
share you know being side by side yes I
think this issue will it is is already
for lack of a better way drifting up
north again I think you're looking at as
much as we can now probably engage our
wine grower our grape growers and
whatnot and I think already there's sort
of a like sort of like natural they're
all going well wait a sec we don't want
the cannabis people next to us and the
cannabis people don't want them next to
us so it's an interesting issue that
they didn't really see coming I will say
this I think the alcohol folks are
saying please don't regulate us like you
regulate cannabis because I think
they're worried that at some point we
might be testing grapes the way we test
cannabis and so in some ways maybe
that's good they're seeing that because
I think what we're starting to see is
other industry now getting affected and
seeing like wow cannabis is really
regulated really highly regulated and we
don't want to be regulated to that
extent so I think that'll be interesting
to see how that plays out hello
Laurie and Jamie my question is about
edibles or alternative products here in
Canada we have legal dried cannabis but
I understand in California you have more
experience rolling out edible products
it's gonna happen this year in Canada
can you talk a little bit about edible
products in California yeah we we
edibles we started out with edibles
right on the onset I know that's a
little different than here and one of
the things we really looked at is that's
where we really looked at some of the
other states and how that rollout went
and so we have some fairly strict
regulation when it comes to edibles
you know the package how you know how
much you know you can have in a package
and child resistant packaging what what
those edibles can look like they can't
be attractive to children and so I will
say we've we really that's where we
really did look at some of the other
states and seeing where they were having
some issues but you know like anything
you know edibles are they constantly
change I this does the other day we had
to ask our Department of Public Health
we saw cannabis infused toothpicks and
we thought well is this what is this is
this an edible what is this and you know
it came out it's an edible so I think
for further regulator though I think
whatever regulations you put in place
it's always going to change with the
different products coming our way and do
they really fit into the edible category
and whatnot so I think that's always
going to be a challenge for any
regulator is keeping up with the
innovation of the the market
alright Laurie I'm wondering is there
any communication between your Bureau
and Health Canada and learning from each
other and on how to adjust public policy
accordingly moving forward so your
health Canada did come to California and
we did meet with them and then they they
were pretty they call they work a lot
with our Public Health Department here
and so you know our I think the best
thing we can do is just share
what we're going through our experiences
share our regulations and and provide
that you know open line of communication
and I will just say this nobody wants to
like you know just like you as an
industry folk you want to be able to
call your counterpart and get an answer
and that's our commitment not
necessarily shaping what they do here
but at least making sure that we're
answering their calls and we're
providing whatever support we can
because I think that's good for
everybody slow clap hi
you mentioned packaging I haven't
actually been any in any of the
so-called legal stores in Vancouver yet
but my friends tell me that they're
packaged within an inch of their life in
non-reusable etc etc this doesn't seem
like a good idea for the long haul
what's California doing well we package
we do a lot of packaging in California
and we even have child resistant
packaging on flour so a lot of packaging
and we get a lot of complaints that you
know it's hard to recycle and whatnot
and I I do think like we're gonna I
think in California you know what are we
really trying especially with like
cannabis flour do do we really think
somebody's a child's gonna get into it
and smoke I don't know but I think we
did start out very conservative because
the last thing we want is for children
to get into this packaging we want to
make sure that parents you know are
putting it in a safe place and I think
we want to make sure that on the onset
if something we want to make sure we had
those protections in place and I think
in some ways that's good but I think as
we evolve I think it's time to look at
some of those and determine where do we
really need to really be strictly
regulate that packaging but you know
there's a part of us that we don't want
any negative press to come on our legal
market for things if we didn't do the
proper prick
Auctions and again it's just not really
knowing I think as we see like maybe
there's not an incidence and we start
making those changes I've just got a
question about banking and payment
processing could you give us a little
update into cali as to what that's what
the latest is on that well I don't
really I don't have any latest
information on banking as as you know we
struggle to get banks and credit unions
to to Bank the cannabis industry in
California our what we do is right now
just try to work with those banking
regulators to give them as much
information for those that do want to
bank the industry to provide them
whatever we can to give them the
assurances that this person is in good
standing and so I think you know right
now the banks are still hesitant to get
in it's very expensive for them to bank
the industry and then you know for us
you know we want to get out of the we
want to get out of taking accepting cash
at the bureau or you know last month
we're accepting like 3 million in cash
for licensing fees I mean it just
doesn't make a lot of sense right and
all the security we have to put into
place so and you know we understand the
average if somebody does get banked and
the bank doesn't know they're a cannabis
industry it's usually 12 to 18 months
and that Bank figures it out and then
they have to start all over again so
you've seen some bills in the
legislature on banking so I think we're
continuing to try to push the issue and
hopefully we're going to see something
from I mean I think if we're gonna see
anything from the federal government
that would be a start
to see it when it comes to banking issue
because it's just not safe anymore for
people one of the things that came up
around that was starting a state bank
what do you think the possibilities of
that happening are I I think it would be
very hard one I think it would take too
long to get up and running and I don't
know how effective it would be
I really think really working on our
current banks and credit unions and
probably giving them the assurances that
we need because a lot of the information
we have as a state regulator is what the
banks want to see and I think
continually
working on that at our level and then at
the federal level and and I'm going to
tell you as a regulator lower it's it's
really hard when you're dealing with
such a cash intensive business it's hard
for you guys to pay your vendors and
that's hard for us to know it you know
to regulate something when it's so much
cash up hey Laurie a quick question
about vapor pens just had a good wanted
to see if there was an action plan in
order to sustainably recycle paper pens
as that whole industry has gotten a lot
more popular I've just heard that
there's a lot of regulatory issues with
that yes so we require like when you
have to make it like unrecognizable and
unusable but most of that is handled by
you know guess what another state agency
in California called Cal recycle so we
got a lot of state agencies but you're I
think it's you know just like the other
gentleman's questions on packaging I
think California needs to start really
looking at how best to recycle these
products these vape the fate pens the
housing units all the packaging and I
think you know California is very
concerned about the environment and all
that I think you're gonna start seeing
some changes go through when it comes to
those issues I think like again we're
learning more about these products and
now we're learning more about you know
cannabis waste and so again I think
you're gonna see more of that I my name
is Jeff I have a question about prison
reform in California I'm over here I'm
over here prison reform in California I
know that they've promised to to let out
all of our men and women tell us about
full clemency how many have been let out
or what is the plan to release our plant
prisoners that should not be in jail
so that doesn't fall under the Bureau of
cannabis control where we're not
involved with that that's at our at the
administration level with the governor
and so I don't I can't answer that
question for you I can speak on a little
bit a lot of cities and counties are
already expunging Records and they just
I can't remember the name of the Nerds
that came up with the AI algorithm that
searches through the database and finds
people whose records would be helped by
the new law and fills out the paperwork
and just sends it off to the DA and the
DA either signs off on it or decides to
try to fight it but that's going on
right now so they've already got like
five hundred thousand people have had
their records clear I'm Marissa who's
from San Francisco the cannabis
regulator I know she could probably give
you a lot of information hi everyone the
nerds are at Code for America and in San
Francisco actually were the first
jurisdiction to retroactively Lee
expunge over 9,000 records I don't think
we thank you in the Bay Area I think
you'd be hard-pressed especially in our
local prisons to find anyone
incarcerated for just a cannabis offense
on the federal level I think the work is
still needed for sure but yeah the the
programs are happening we want to
encourage other jurisdictions to do the
same work it is doable you can do it you
call the San Francisco District
Attorney's Office speak to George Cusco
and he'll tell you how thank you hello
my name is Ellen okay uh you were
talking about the different conditions
in California for medical versus in
Canada and I just wanted to say that
Canadian editions actually seem quite
different because we have a medical
system here that pays for things so we
don't have to go to pay to get
prescriptions so we can get a doctor's
prescription for free providing of
course we can find a doctor who will
give us a prescription that's still an
issue so here we have to our new
dispensaries or whatever we want to call
them our new recreational outlets can
only provide a dosage of 10 milligrams
okay and that's a problem for our
medical users so essentially our legacy
dispensaries are being shut down which
we're providing all the medical doses
and stuff and now these new dispensaries
the legal ones are being opened with a
ten milligram per dose limit which is
totally ineffective and you know like
you can imagine a kid with draw vets
having to take 2,500 milligrams a dose
and having to take two hundred and
twenty five hundred pills I don't know
what that is but it's a lot okay it's
totally unreasonable it's just wrong and
this is a real issue that has to be
dealt with so how did you guys start out
was did they just start out having any
possible dose or you know like we're
limited now so yeah so that's the
manufacturer part of it is handled by
our Department of Public Health and they
do have limits on package size and ten
milligram dose but it is different
between the adult use and medical market
so it's a higher limit for medical
patients and it is for adult use but an
in it but again they if they can sell
the higher dose if they have if they're
designated as a medical retailer so
they're licensed is designated and so
that's that's how we're doing it right
now
and then I should mention California is
also because as most probably some of
you know our collective cooperative
model was us that that sunsetted early
in January of this year so we don't have
the collective and cooperatives but
there is a bill pending in the
legislature - what what's really
happening California is similar to what
you were saying we had a lot of
compassion care programs that would
really help our veterans and our our
terminally ill patients and once the
collective cooperative model which you
know allowed these folks to give them
medicinal cannabis went away there there
really wasn't a path for them so we do
have some pending legislation that would
allow our cultivators and manufacturers
to donate product to a retailer to give
to those compassion Care program at the
local jurisdiction so we'll see what
happens if that gets signed by the
governor so something else we're trying
to you know and
and there's been talk of doing something
like that in Canada when we get back to
medical because basically one of the
reasons why we haven't talked about
medical more is because the federal
government has said there will be a
review once we've actually kind of got
this other one in place so they've just
been able to just push off everything to
that point I'm just curious if there is
a process in place to receive steak
industry stakeholders input for when
you're creating regulations yes oh boy
you need to come to California and we
have we have a really robust I'll say
robot
it's wild yeah if it gets wild so yes so
what happens is at the agency level we
develop regulations and then once we
have our draft regulations we provide
them and then we go around the usually
go around the state and do public
hearings so folks can either they can
come to those public hearings give
public comment they can also write them
in they can email them to us so we we do
a really really in-depth process of
getting public comments and then once we
get those public comments we're required
to respond to those public comments so
for example last year when we were doing
our final regulations the bureau I think
processed over 8,000 comments that came
in and that's all that's all available
to anybody to see how we responded in
addition for every regulation we put in
place we have to do what's called an
initial statement of reason meaning we
have to say why we're putting that
regulation in place so if we tell
retailers they're gonna be open from
6:00 a.m. to 10:00 p.m. we have to say
what's the reasoning for that and we
have to justify that reason so it can't
the only problem with that robust
process it's a lengthy process so you
know so it there's a balance there so we
try to get through as quickly as
possible but yes there's a lot of we do
encourage that feedback thank you all so
very much sorry we're out of time one
more time Laurie Ajax Jaime's char
[Applause]