there are few people rare politicians
that actually fight for these freedoms
and our Mexican our keynote speaker is
someone who fights for this Liberty to
have fun freedom fun freedom fun freedom
nobody's hurting anybody so without
further ado I would like to bring to the
stage
the great one of the band who helped end
the Cold War and the man who has helped
end the drug war the number one ally in
Congress for cannabis industry please
give a warm Swank's and welcome to Dana
Rohrabacher I would really love to have
introductions like that well thank you
very much for any be with you this
morning then but this is this is quite
inspiring when I started discussing the
cannabis issue we would never be in
residence like this and we would be
having a walk in the woods someplace
doing the paperwork that was necessary
for such a discussion but this cannabis
now has reached a new stage and that's
what we need to talk about and
understand that it is not the cannabis
industry that was around when I was a
teenager and so we'll talk a little bit
about that I just you also you know
about ever sit in Congress for 30 years
I was in gray and white house for seven
years I was President Reagan's a senior
speechwriter and a special assistant to
the President and then I ran for
Congress for 30 years I've been in the
house and after all of that time in
public service peoples ask you know well
what's it like and what do you feel now
that it's all over and you look back
there's a story in Ronald Reagan always
told me well Dana
sure that you always start off with a
little funny story and there is a story
I didn't that Regan like to tell about a
fellow who and he was younger had a gang
of friends that they and he hung around
with all the time and as they got older
most of them didn't succeed as much as
one of them did one of them just made
millions and millions of dollars and
when he got to be about 50 or 60 years
old he decided to get the old gang back
and he invited the old gang to his
mansion and they were in the backyard
and he said I'm going to show you those
something or ugly never seen this is a
swimming pool that one and he pushed a
button and all of a sudden the long
started the part and there was a
swimming pool like underneath the turf
beautiful swimming pool except it was
filled with crocodiles alligators sharks
piranhas this was you know our story and
then what he did all these fish going
after each other you're going after
whatever we got in the water and the guy
who owned the place that does old the
gang you know I'm willing to give 250
thousand dollars the any one of you are
every one of you who will swim across
this pool is you in order to succeed
you've got to take risks okay so no one
jumped in the pool as I said I didn't
think anybody would be foolish enough to
do that
come on over have a little barbecue as
they walk toward the barbecue he heard a
splash he looks around and there's a guy
in the pool he's beating away the
crocodiles as a shark
and he hits on the nose he swims across
the pool and as he's getting that with
that swimming pool the man runs over to
me says that was incredible
how do you want me to give you the money
and he says I don't care about the money
I want to know who pushed me in that and
now that I'm done with my congressional
career I sort of feel huh who pushed me
in that pool and however they you know
no one said democracy was going to be
easy and no one said that just because
you believe in what you believe in that
you're econo sincere about it which I've
tried to be in my career that you are
going to succeed or that you will be
remembered for the good things you did
because quite often than the way when
humankind is they remember the bad
things are the mistakes that one makes
rather than the accomplishments while
I'm very proud and better whether
they're recognized or not a nerd
probably played a role yes and ended the
Cold War and but also I'm very proud of
them that I played a major role in
ending the war on cannabis especially
reading books today I wore a special
shirt and remained out of guns last
night you probably some of you may have
noticed I wore my yeah this is elephants
in the weed that's why they call it
that was given into heat by a
neighboring town from Ethiopia who is my
survey partner in California and there's
a few only a few black surfers and
here's one of them end just let you know
that is my sport I am a surfer and I've
been a surface that many many years and
I'm going to give you this analogy
surfers in order to catch the wave you
don't look to the inside wave you don't
worry less breaking right now but you
look to the outside wave and then you
position yourself so where you give you
get the maximum ride on that way and
what we have to do now is understand
that there's a wave coming that's on the
outside people think that right now that
the cannabis industry oh my goodness
look at what it is today compared to
what it was just a few years ago and it
was only about five or six years ago
that my amendment finally passed in the
Senate that went to it or the house and
then was written law of the thing and by
the president only a five or six years
ago that was you know that's right now
but on the outside there is a wave a
cannabis wave about to hit the world
economy and you represent that wave
that's coming because for too long for a
hundred years
cannabis was suppressed as a benefit to
mankind that for a hundred years
what could have been used in a number of
ways to help human beings was denied
them by various forces in our societies
so with that that's all changing now we
have to prepare for that those who are
prepared will will make a profit those
who are prepared will be able to do the
most good and then will be however a lot
of changes in the
misery s compared as I say to what it
was when it was underground and when it
was not legal so first of all let me
just say my cheap motive and getting
involved with cannabis was the same but
if I had in fighting communism earlier
in my life and that is this is a freedom
issue to me and I wouldn't say that
missus I had time so he gives me I go so
that's the world about freedom and and
be afraid um and somebody was mentioning
that to me how they were at one of my
presentations I never stay free and I
couldn't help the thing I think it's a
little bit nicer than feeling we'd have
an open or sophisticated to call for
freedom but what we are experiencing now
is a revelation to so many people that
this suppression that we've had has had
a tremendous cost on society and first
of all let us just note we have been
financing gangsters and drug dealers who
are the worst of the lot for the last 50
200 years we would provision the
headsman for alcohol the gangsters were
finally cut off from their source of
revenue and had to go to some other
business well what we have because of
the illegalities we have created a
gangster system in the world you were
the ones who are going to break that
gangster system you were the ones who
are going to make sure that what we have
is a product that is safe a product that
when you sell it to someone after what
you have done they know what they're
getting after and you they will know
exactly how much they are taking they
will know whether or not there are
dangerous things to be it as part of
that but they're consuming you are going
to be the ones
are providing that and at the same time
making sure that was some of the worst
anti societal elements in the world
these gangsters are cut off from their
source of funding so this is really a
tremendous a tremendous time to be alive
and to be in the cannabis industry it's
exciting and I have no doubt that in the
future that we're going to make sure
that people understand and they will
understand just what that means to their
lives after they've been told that
marijuana and cannabis is some sort of
really horrible thing that needs to be
stamped out you know when I thought I
was a surfer I really am and I I've had
troubles those surfers yeah most people
only see these wonderful beautiful
bodies on their surfboard I will tell
you something
surfing is really hard on your body
especially when he had to be 71 years
old as I am right now and it all comes
back yeah you're you're paying the price
for those moments ecstasy on that way
and what's happened is I get mental
shoulders of my arms now I surf away all
the cartilage in my arms because it was
all like this but also I've got
arthritis in my neck all right so I've
been a cannabis advocate for a long time
and I was mentioning this pain that I am
now in my neck and some guy says hey you
know why don't you fuse this CBD cream
that we've got you know your your
advocate why don't you use it and so
okay I want you to know that this was
only about two or three weeks ago and I
had this horrible arthritis in my neck
and so I finally reached it and put it
in there whoa I do know that I the pain
stopped for three days and then in just
a little bit more cream on where the
keepin came back now is it is this
wonderful for me but the bigger question
we have to ask ourselves why the hell
we allow so many people to sit there in
pain suffering all of this time think
about it before there was that cannabis
cream
what alternative did they have well they
just drink more and that's what I've
been especially in old folks homes and
senior living centers people we were
they were they be they begin about 10 20
years ago was noted that they're filling
up with drunks because they would be
drinking too much to deal with their
suffering what making cannabis illegal
has done then one major thing making it
illegal made sure that we had people
were suffering and they now of course
instead of having to drink there to
alleviate that suffering or or take some
other type of drug they have an
alternative that I believe God created
the cannabis plant in order to serve
mankind and to help us eliminate that
suffering and in order to do that and
take advantage of that opportunity of
course you have to have freedom and it's
always again if someone does not want to
take advantage of this plant in order to
alleviate suffering from themselves or
anyone else they should be free not to
use it at the same time people should be
free to make those choices in their life
and that's what this has all been about
now Republicans all of course did not
think that way but let me just note that
when we finally got this passed I've
been trying to hit this legalized
medical marijuana amendment passed for
about 15 20 years now and when it
finally passed it was because we came up
with the formula and we just heard how
this relates to Switzerland as well
that's with your Canton system is very
similar to the state system and the
Republicans in the United States have
always been talking about the Tenth
Amendment and states rights so I was
able I was able to get the Republican
vote that I needed
by simply saying we're going to leave it
up to the states realizing that the
people of the states would make the
right decision for them and once that
pass there's as I say that's what you
see now beginning to break but if you
look right about right past what's going
on what's going out there for the in the
long run we now have a seismic change in
the nature of Western civilization and
it's because this plant does so many
things this plant will provide look you
see see this okay now that's just the
elephant in the weed but how do you know
that this isn't made out of weed right
my family were all North Dakota farmers
they were very poor farmers say my dad
left this farm in North Dakota a
daughter to fight World War two and he
never went back to the farm he stayed in
the Marine Corps and when I was young I
would go and work on the farm with him
when it's on his month off in the Marine
Corps
well farming life is really a hard life
and they're always looking for a crop
that they could use and sell it has been
illegal in the United States to grow
cannabis to grow this plant the has so
much positive to offer and it has been
illegal and at the same time however
here might my grandfather's farm is
about 20 miles from the Canadian border
but we have permitted the Canadians to
import a billion and a half dollars
worth of of him every year although the
farmers on our side of the border were
not permitted to do so I mean this is
the insanity of the type of regulation
controls we have in order to quote
protect us from ourselves and that's
what we have today of course is we have
a recognition by so many people at least
by the Republic
are finally admitting that government
isn't there to make the personal
decisions in your life for you now we've
had this dichotomy the Democrats want to
control every inch of people's economic
lives they think they can do business
better than the small businessman who
runs his business they think the
government can do better by giving him
the orders of exactly what he can do but
the Republicans think that they can run
your personal life by telling you what
to do in your personal life and I think
that what's happening now is as a result
as is with the states rights issue we
were able to break down that that
political dichotomy which ll Duss right
where we were for so long let me just
give you a couple things about what I
expect in the future and I we are happy
to answer a couple questions
the a my I hope we have enough time okay
let me just say this about where people
are coming from and and you know when I
was a kid people got put in jail for
smoking marijuana just having a joint
would put you in jail but the people who
were going to jail for so long in the
United States weren't just people like
myself because I at least came from a
upper-middle income after my dad got it
got out of the Marine Corps he got a job
in the aerospace industry and so we
lived in the upper middle-income life
well the kids who smoked marijuana back
in my day if they got arrested they
would go to jail and within a very short
period of time their lawyer would emerge
and then what would happen the lawyer
would say we've worked a deal out with
the judge and you can just you'll get
oil off with a misdemeanor and then that
was forgotten but all the kids from the
black community or from the Chicanos or
little lower-income they'd be put in
jail if they were caught with a baggie
of marijuana in their pocket
and they'd be told the well first of all
they'd sit in jail for two or three days
before the public defender arrived and
said you need to plead guilty you need
to plead guilty and then they'll be
lenient on you and by pleading guilty
they ended up with this with a whole
generation of young people from the
poorer communities who ended up with
criminal records and after that what
kind of jobs could they get we what case
oh the overall impact on our society was
horrendous but nobody could see that
nobody saw that the black and Chicano
communities understood it but nobody
else could see it so that hopefully now
we are going to eliminate that type of
horrendous result in what was meant in
let's face it I believe the people who
came in and made it cannabis illegal in
the first place we're doing so because
they thought they were trying to help us
and know they were ended up creating
gangsterism condemning poor people to a
lifetime of unable to get jobs and they
were actually destroying our freedom and
that's what it was all about so with
that said I am proud to help play a role
in coming up with the political formula
that broke the logjam and created a new
America and a new world that is just
right out there for me it's the wave on
the outside we haven't even seen the
impact that this is going to create yet
we're gonna have paper we're gonna have
safe drugs the opiates that now cause so
much agony and one of our people we have
a way to replace them now we have
actually from what I understand that
cannabis is a way a method we use call
it the gateway drug this way they have
to eliminate it now we understand it's a
gateway all right it's a gateway out of
drug addiction in that it can be used to
actually get people off of an addiction
to other drugs
so what a tremendous exciting adventure
we're about to have and I'm proud to
stand with you and the other people in
this world and in my country that really
truly believe in freedom so with that
said if you have any questions I think
I've got a couple minutes left yeah give
it up for Dana Rohrabacher
Thank You Dana thank you question
question who's got a question anybody
got a question okay here I come I'm on
my way
Thank You congressman when do you see
federal legalization in the u.s. you
know we'd step-by-step you know we've
already legalized it to the degree that
for medical purposes in the States
that was the first step and that we and
also now we have the hemp bill which is
an actual first step towards an actual
federal legalization I think that and
this is gonna sound optimistic but I
don't think it is optimistic I think the
way the politics is shaping up in the
United States today that in this some
place early next year because our
Congress is you know we have two years
so the second year of this Congress
before the elections start taking place
you will find a consensus right now
there's all kinds of ideas out there
people are putting there they're putting
it bills in the hopper that go for this
and different elements of the challenge
we face and I think that what you'll
have is probably have about January or
February you'll see that they'll start
organizing it so all of these ideas will
start being put into one bill and there
will be a cannabis bill and that's when
you will have a negotiation by something
a lot of people have missed of the
significance of I'm gone okay I'm no
longer there to to play the referee and
to try to get some movement forward but
I may be gone but there's another
Republican there
who is in as incredible influence on
this his name is Donald Trump and Donald
Trump I've had a number of a couple
conversations with him and during the
last election he made his position very
clear and that he believed that medical
use of cannabis should be they should be
legal this round they cannot the whole
country and that personal recreational
adult use should be left up to the
states and he repeated that in public
three times during that election now a
lot of people mistakenly think that
because Trump has such a wonderful
personality and yes and it gets in the
way so wonderful he gets it away
no but President Trump has an abrasive
personality and they mistakenly because
they don't like that now remember I
worked for Reagan and Reagan everything
was had to be proper it was a sense of
propriety and by the way I'll do one
thing about that I know I could describe
this first you got to understand why
that is Reagan came from a very poor
family Ronald Reagan literally what they
were the poorest of the poor in the
United States and Reagan in order to
have a self-esteem he had to make sure
he acted in a proper way and he dressed
in a proper way and he talked in a
proper way and he told funny stories and
and it was likable in a proper way
Don Trump didn't have to do any of those
things
he was he came from a very wealthy
family so he has a natural tendency to
say well I'll try not to use a swear
word here well screw that or whatever
and and so people look at that as being
you know abrasive and it is but don't
pay to end and everybody who hates Don
Trump is usually you say why do you hate
Don Trump it's always always because of
his personality
well there's policies that he is talking
about I happen to agree with
policies most of them but the policies I
like the most is the fact that he is
going to be the leader and the lead sled
dog in the con the cannabis issue mark
my words you will have this coalition
form it surprised everybody and you know
I tried to be the lead sled dog on this
issue and you know what they say it was
a Norman times the lead stealth sled dog
has the best view but the lead sled dog
is the one who gets bitten on the ass
and just because your ass is bleeding
doesn't mean you're the lead sled dog
but I'm no longer the lead sled dog but
Trump is going to be and there's going
so work that's what's going to happen
and I think that there will be a new
bill and it will pass and it will go
about half the way to what we need but
it will be a giant step forward and
that's where I think we're at all right
do we have one more question right there
here we go so I was just wondering you
mentioned that cannabis is the gateway
out of other types of addiction or
dependence um I also see it as a gateway
to the end of the war on drugs in
general and I'm wondering what your
views on that are especially with
regards to perhaps the dissolution of
the Controlled Substances Act and also
on an international level or on the
international level with the 61 71 and
88 controlled substance conventions if
you see the u.s. changing its stance
internationally as well in the future no
I I agree with everything you said I
look I am someone with a libertarian
background and I just want the guy but
the government should but out of our
lives
yeah leave us alone leave the lead hey
those individuals and his business
people leads us leave us alone however
that's not the way most people feel even
in
states where we're so proud of of
liberty as being you know look our
founding fathers first of all we came
from every religion and race in the
world they came there in order to create
this new country based on the principles
of what they said it right out this is
the principles of life liberty and the
pursuit not of by the way not that he
didn't say they were suitor property
which is what was popular in those days
the pursuit of happiness this is
wonderful and I do believe that that
that still is the guideposts to to
Americans who think about it
but most Americans aren't thinking about
it and they just are sort of going along
with with a basic concepts of what's not
going to disrupt society etc so I don't
think we're gonna have that that
traumatic that the type of liberalism
say liberation I wouldn't say
liberalization the liberation that we
would have however let us just note also
that we have had a horrendous situation
here the the opiates now when we're
talking about the opiates it is a horror
story that our government approved the
sale of this and doctors kept
prescribing this knowing that these
opiates were addictive and harmful yet
they went instead of instead of
legalizing cannabis they were willing to
do that with people's lives
I'd only given one last story and that
is how I realized that what that I was
going to be able to succeed politically
I've been the front man on this for a
long long time because I believe in it
and I I believe I tried to do and I was
in Congress the things I believed were
true and right but that didn't mean that
at any moment I could be unelected
because again the public attitude has to
be taken into consideration but how much
leverage that you've got so I didn't
know whether or not I was going to end
up with booted out of the Congress
probably five six years ago because I
was about to succeed
in a major step forward in liberalizing
cannabis restrictions so I decided I had
an appointment in my office with a
person with a guy who is my a resident
of my district and I said to myself this
guy is the quintessential Rohrbacher
voter now I'm gonna ask him and find out
what he thinks about the fact that his
congressman is leading the fight to
legalize cannabis and and legalize
medical marijuana and so he came in and
he sat down and we were talking and I
said gee I want to know you know
actually I'm gonna be succeeding in this
effort that I've been working on for a
long time
about medical marijuana because we're
gonna leave it up to the states and and
I've you know I've got the vote figured
out and I'm gonna win this vote and what
do you think about the fact that your
congressman is leading the fight to
legalize medical marijuana and he said
well Dana you really don't know me do
you I said well I know that you were in
the Navy and that you were a pilot in
the Navy and that you are an officer and
that you now work for a major aerospace
firm I know that and I know you're
Republican they says yeah but you don't
really know me you don't know that I
have three sons and you don't know that
the day after 9/11 by three sons joined
up they all marched off and signed up
and then what you also don't know is
that a few years later two of my sons
came home but one of them that came home
the third son was no longer my son he
was having convulsions every day on the
floor and I could do nothing to save my
son he says and now I don't know how
many of you have children and I have a
son that would break my heart if that
was happening to me and so
he said I couldn't do anything I
struggled and I we were taking him to
the VA hospital and they were doing
nothing for him and finally he said a
doctor pulled me aside said see me in my
office out in the town on the city and
we did and he said look your son needs
marijuana this is how to get it and this
is how to use it do it and he said you
know my son hasn't had a convulsion
since that day he says how do I feel
about you how do I feel about you he
said I'm gonna come over and I'm gonna
give you a big hug now this story would
be over right here at this point but it
even gets better okay because that of
course it touched my heart and I've
repeated that story and that man has
become someone who I've kept in touch
with and I got this call about six
months ago and he said well we got
something else to thank you about and I
said well what is it he says well my son
the one that was having the trouble and
still you know his face is a real
struggle he went to the VA hospital and
he was there he felt something coming on
so he went down to his car I guess to
smoke a joint or something and he goes
and he says and the damn parking lot
attendant arrested him and I don't know
what and he says yeah it's he arrested
and today he was brought to court and
that's why I'm calling you
I said well why are you calling me he
says well because when it went into the
court the judge looked at everybody
around he says look at this case and
this case is young man was possession
and utilizing marijuana and it says here
that okay and I see that the case is
being brought up by the the DEA and the
Department of Justice DEA and that's
where the
the people doing the prosecution or part
of the federal government but I can't
help but read this position in this law
that was passed that says that no one in
the Department of Justice will use any
of these funds in order to supersede a
state law that legalizes medical
marijuana he says I believe this is what
we're calling medical marijuana and I
believe you are federal agents so this
case is thrown out bang and so the guy
immediately went to the telephone and
called me to thank me
very literally helping his son for a
second time so look right now there are
all kinds of people like that young man
there's all kinds of people who were
getting arrested because they had
cannabis in their pocket and their
family didn't have a way to defend them
against unhealthier or over prosecution
so right now we've made some giant steps
forward this all of you are part of the
wave that's forming that's going to
reform this whole area of humankind and
we will be proud that we fought for
freedom and we eliminated suffering and
we brought more fairness to the world
thank you all very much done one more
time thank you