wooden Morgan you are the Troopers that
are here for the Friday morning session
and you shall be rewarded with a
wonderful conversation
um so I want to introduce you to my
fabulous panelists this is David
very important thing to know about him
is that he used to be a professional
bodybuilder an award-winning
professional bodybuilder
and in his spare time he spends his time
in his home gym teaching his
nine-year-old son how to also be a buff
Fitness Pro which I think is pretty
fantastic
a little bit about your company
you know thank you very much Hillary and
uh hi everyone great to be here again I
was here last year and wonderful to be
here again seeing the seeing the crowds
and the interest around this industry
that's forming in one way or other
there's there's The Good the Bad and
occasionally the ugly that we're seeing
around the industry right so um I've
been about 11 years now working in this
space originally in Canada working on on
licensing compliance security areas and
over the years just kind of saw that
there was a global market forming so I
worked on quite a few projects
um as the markets rolled out Germany
some of the Consulting for the early
producers here ultimately I was about to
really launch into the global side when
covert came so after covid now I've been
getting back into the global side we do
m a uh um across the global cannabis
industry so working on Acquisitions
mergers
um some smart investment work as well as
the capital markets have have um have
have tightened up and yeah again excited
to be here
so Carmen is a bit of a speed demon she
used to drive race cars uh and in her
spare time she likes to hurt her hurdle
herself down mountains either on skis or
bicycles going as fast as she possibly
can and now in her spare time what there
is of it she manages a race car team so
we'll be sure to have to learn more
about that but tell us a little bit more
about your company
yeah Marina everyone my name is Carmen
Darren I'm the CEO of Helios
Therapeutics we are New Zealand's
largest licensed producer of medicinal
cannabis
Helios is a medicines company we are
very much focused on delivering outcomes
for patients and have moved its speed
um to be able to do that in New Zealand
uh one of the things probably is a
little bit of background around the New
Zealand industry is just to understand
the environment in which we work so we
are a full Medical Market in New Zealand
any doctor can prescribe for any
condition and that came in on the 1st of
October in 2021
the 4th of October 2021 just four days
later Helios launched our first products
into market so we're coming up on two
years of products into Market
last year we launched new zealand-grown
New Zealand made medicines and we're
really able to drive access and
affordability for our patients in New
Zealand and it's great to be able to
come here and share some of what's
happening in New Zealand with all of you
this morning thank you
um Peter the true love of his life is a
gorgeous uh she a lab golden lab a
golden retriever golden Retriever named
Daisy who is beautiful do we have any
other dog people in the audience can I
see a show of hands about who my dog
people are uh-huh thank you
um and in his spare time he likes to
Surf and I have seen a video of this man
absolutely shredding it
so tell us a little bit about about your
company sure thanks Hillary so
um Peter Croc
um I consider myself one of the veterans
of cannabis in Australia seven years ago
um I joined canned group so I was CEO at
can group we were the first to be
licensed in Australia and I'm also the
founding chair of the mcia I'm wearing
that hat here today is chair of the peak
industry body and we've got a great
delegation here from Australia and and
sitting right next to a New Zealand
funnily enough across the ditch in room
two but um yeah here to to see what's
happening on the global scale and and
Australia's role to play in that
fabulous thank you and I'll just
introduce myself very quickly I started
Distributing medical cannabis in the mid
90s in Canada so I started a movement
that turned into an industry in Canada
and then spent the past few years in the
c-suite of canopy growth and now I'm
doing independent Consulting work
um so the first thing that I want to ask
you when any one of you can chime in do
you think that in Australia or New
Zealand or other Emerging Markets are we
going to be able to avoid the same boom
and bust that we experienced in Canada
from hyped up valuations and inflated
Market predictions
now I might start with that one because
in fact we've already been there done
that in Australia
um we definitely got caught up in the
Canadian bubble as it was inflating with
the whole wreck Market coming on and the
excitement that happened back in 2017
and 18
um the Australian system only came into
effect in 2016 uh it was announced 2017
we got the first license in in March of
that year was right when Canada was in
full inflation mode and and we had
Canadian activity in in our part of the
world as well so uh when the Canadian
Bubble Burst that definitely had effect
right around the world and it has meant
that we've had to pull pull our horns in
in Australia and New Zealand we've done
that and it's
because we've got such a good regulatory
structure underlying it though we've
we've gone through that rough patch and
we're now in a really strong position to
to move forward without it just being
seen as another uh bubble coming up so
it's it's inflating carefully since I've
been here this week I've heard some
pretty dramatic and optimistic
predictions for the rapid exponential
growth of the German market and it
really does make me worry that we're not
learning from the lessons of what we've
experienced in Canada what are you
seeing in other countries around the
world that you're working in in terms of
this issue yeah I mean you know
definitely
um when you when you look at this the
Canadian situation what happened
definitely a learning curve I think for
the world and I lived it close by I was
actually involved in very close to it I
think really When I Was Here a year ago
I look at valuations I look at company
performers I look at performance metrics
forecasting and look at you know what
this company is saying might they be
successful because you've got to pick
winners and losers sometimes in this
industry if you're an investor
especially
um and I think it's been a big
difference from last year to this year a
year ago we were still seeing the really
hype valuations particularly in the
European market
some companies that had were really
basing their valuations on on
projections and forecasts that frankly
weren't really defensible
um I think now even to now to this year
there's a big difference you know I'm
seeing now we see a bit more realism in
terms of the evaluations that we're
seeing on the private side definitely
the public side to a degree as well but
there's maybe not quite caught up yet
but definitely seeing some Evolution and
I think that the
the the investor class are learning from
what's happened around the world
particularly in Canada
I think they're adjusting themselves and
they expect to see more veracity to the
the these pitch decks
um assumptions it's not going to be ten
dollars a gram or 15 a gram or whatever
it is in this market or that it's
actually going to be more like this and
the market size is not going to be this
it's going to be more like this this is
what I think we're seeing a bit of now
although there's still quite a long way
to go do you want to add anything yeah
absolutely so my nana always used to
I think that New Zealand for us our
cannabis industry started coming online
just as covert hit and then the whole
country went into lockdown
and then we went into a global financial
crisis and depression so
um we probably haven't seen the crash in
valuations just because of the timing of
when our industry came on and we
absolutely had some companies that were
at higher valuations in the beginning
including Helios that have now come down
to more realistic valuations but there
hasn't been the multiples crash that
we've seen in other places and I think
that actually quietly delivering down in
New Zealand a lot of the New Zealand
cannabis companies for what they have
delivered already and the potential they
have to go into the global markets are
undervalued we have a couple of publicly
listed companies in New Zealand heliers
is a private company we have been able
to do that all through individual
investors and I think that it's really
it'll be interesting to see how things
settle and how the valuations play out
as now the New Zealand companies start
exporting into markets around the world
world thank you
um David another one for you so you
really have your finger on the pulse of
the global supply chain and I'm
wondering if you can tell us a little
bit about the countries that you work in
how you characterize them and then let's
just get right down to it and tell us
about the range of the price point for
companies that are selling into those
countries
yeah sure I mean I I think again we're
seeing
um a very very variable
um Global Market I think there's an
assumption sometimes that the EU is a
monolith and all those countries are
somewhat similar or something of course
they're all very very different
um even even in Germany all the states
have slightly different takes on
elements of import export Etc so there's
a lot to learn out there I think one of
the first things I'll probably repeat a
few times there's a lot of sources that
folks get information from this
conference is called of course one of
them and I encourage you to do that and
to and to be insatiable in terms of your
take-up of information
but all sources aren't the same and so
you know you need to be cautious about
what you assume or what you know what
you learn about the global markets
and the sources of data are quite narrow
really there's not a lot of really
reliable data out there that's up to
speed in terms of how I kind of
characterize the different market
segments I think there are some
countries that I would call pre-ranked
markets right their medical of course
but they're a prereq where the whether
it's a self-payers as in Germany or
whether there's other reasons why the
medical Market is is partly medical
patients that have sometimes serious
needs other times of Wellness related
but there's still a medicinal patient
but then we have you know the prereq
idea where really you you see a
microcosm of Canada one of the things
that we've heard a lot at this
conference already in talking especially
in the evening you know what's new in
Canada what streams are coming out you
know where's the crack where's the craft
uh um next drop coming you know because
I think some of the companies in
countries like Germany and I think would
be Australia too actually are looking at
what's happening with kind of on The
Cutting Edge of in California too and
what can we grasp on to and kind of
bring into our Market
the German Market is getting a little
busier I think there are about a maybe
150 odd different products I think 600
listings so some companies are
multiplying the products uh but the
interesting thing is a lot of those
products are running out you know and to
me you know that kind of again
underlines one of the key things I think
in these different market segments is as
a as a supplier into those markets and
the distributor if you can't latch on to
Reliable Supply that is consistent that
hits a similar Mark and you can
replenish those orders on and on we've
seen the harm that does certainly in
Canada other countries where once you
lose the confidence of the patient you
know you're really in a in a sticky spot
so just to roll up um prereq Market
countries Australia would be in there
Germany would be in there we are Pure
medical uh UK I think is Pure medical I
think New Zealand probably is more Pure
medical where we have it's a much more
of a very focused medical Paradigm
um and and the idea of a prereq kind of
thing really or Iraq is is in the in
Legacy Market or the black market for
the most part
um and then there are some Emerging
Markets too that are fairly interesting
around the world obviously we're looking
at some of the European countries Poland
is uh is coming on Brazil is a country
that's that's got things happening
um so you know really you know I I think
the the key to this is to really educate
yourself as if you're cultivating and
producing into the market if you're
Distributing whatever you're on the
value chain if you're looking at the
global market as a as a playground for
business you need to know where to play
and how to win that's really to me the
critical thing and we always be crass
about it your success relies on your
knowledge understanding of where to
choose to channel your products or your
interest and how to negotiate and
navigate that with respect to getting
those products into Market in a reliable
way and David I was just going to say in
terms of
characterizing Australia as a prereq
market and you're pointing there at the
volume of flower that's being sold into
Australia but uh I'd push hard on the
fact that from a medical focus and
perspective Australia's in a really
strong position and it is absolutely
where we're focused around bringing the
science into cannabinoids and medicine
and the regulatory environment we have
there and that's why it's important
people understand if they're going to be
bringing product into Australia and how
it'll play in that space the GMP
requirement and the Law changes as of
tomorrow so first of July TGO 93 has a
requirement that Imports our equivalent
quality to GMP so that needs to be
understood but having that framework in
place the real opportunity we see is
that being the basis for bringing
clinical trial work to Australia and
that capability is going to from a
medical perspective really been
important Avenue forward for the global
industry I think so I want to come back
to talking about a price per gram in
terms of the the price that cannabis is
selling into these markets and then how
that corresponds to what the patients
are paying
so perhaps you can talk a little bit
about the range of what you're seeing
sure yeah and then I'd love to hear
about what patients are paying program
in both New Zealand and Australia yeah I
mean pricing is is very um elastic and
pricing is is not a stable thing of
course it changes over time certainly in
the Canadian market we've seen a
decimation of the B2B Market where you
know high quality craft Canadian
cannabis you know can be selling for a
dollar fifty two dollars a gram in
Canadian which is which is sad to say
considering it costs that much almost to
grow it so it's been very challenging
and there's lots of reasons for that
it's not I'm going to be Focus for
today's panel but the Canadian Market is
is difficult and so there's lots of
exporters from Canada that are looking
for the higher price point in the global
markets that's that's a one of the
biggest thing to know about how the
global industry is moving around because
there's lots of pressure from Canada and
lots of flower from Canada that wants to
go into the market
um when you look at the pricing into you
know Israel is obviously a large Market
that pricing is moved around you know I
think what we're seeing right now is
anywhere from a I'm going to talk
Canadian dollars um
probably from like a 275 to 375 four
dollar type pricing into Israel for for
decent Quality Craft
um when we get into a market like
Australia again this is
categories I think of product and and
all the different distributors pay
different prices there's no sort of set
limit but I think Australia I've seen
pricing actually get fairly low but I've
also seen pricing up at five dollars six
dollars Canadian a gram 5.5 is probably
a good number to say is uh was a Target
if you're if you're if you're selling
into that market uh Germany
um I think there's a little bit more
opportunity if you are really doing
quite craft cannabis that really ticks
all the boxes
um for what for better or worse high THC
which is an issue that that you know I
think is a is a quite a debatable point
what we should be doing there
um high terpene profile bag appeal all
those boxes I think you know we can see
up to uh price of
or 50 euros a gram 4 450 around that
range and we're seeing roughly maybe
double that for sales into the into the
into the um pharmacies roughly it's kind
of a bit of a guide again it very much
depends on the quality of the product
and and the players involved so now
we're talking in euros and now I want to
talk about the price per gram to
patients in your countries but I'm not
doing the math on the Fly
I'd love to hear about what patients are
paying per gram and also Insurance
structures in terms of if there's
coverage for patients talk a little bit
about which patients are eligible for
what kind of insurance coverage
yeah sure so from an Australian
perspective
pretty simple math the flower around ten
dollars a gram so that's about six Euro
I think isn't it something like that but
um so that's the patient level there
there is some health cover but it's not
um under the PBS though the
pharmaceutical benefits scheme in
Australia you have to have a registered
medicine go through that process and all
of the product in Australia is being
sold as a under the special access
scheme as an unregistered medicine so
it's um
yeah and there's a range that's been
happening and and with the Imports uh
previously where they've been um
importing under TGO 93 the Therapeutics
Goods order that remain silent on on the
GMP requirement meant that we haven't
seen a whole lot of flower coming from
Canada and elsewhere that uh so there's
quite a range of quality product that's
around and um patients in that space are
quite Discerning and it's been an
interesting space so I think as as that
washes through now and and there there
has been a pile of material pushed into
Australia ahead of the the change in the
legislation
um but I think we'll see that settle
down
yeah I was going to ask you what the
rules changing literally tomorrow how
long do you think it will be before the
pricing in Australia settles down and if
you've got a prediction on where maybe
explain about the rules that are
changing tomorrow in case everybody in
the audience isn't quite up to speed
with that yeah so TGO 93 is the
technical term therapeutic Goods order
and when they introduced cannabis and
opened up the special access pathway
schemas unregistered medicines they had
a requirement that anything came in had
to be free of contaminants heavy metals
aflatoxin okra toxin and and but someone
worked out pretty early on or hang on
they didn't say anything about GMP
whereas Australian manufactured material
all has to any licensed operator in
Australia has to produce to GMP we're
only allowed export GMP quality product
so it was a not altogether helpful uh
oversight in how the legislation was put
into play to start with yes it helped
get the ball rolling and because we
didn't yet have an industry producing
any material it meant that we could
bring material in and and that worked
but then some entrepreneurial people
worked out hang on we can actually get a
technical term shitload of material in
that doesn't come in with that GMP
overhead on it yeah well there's a lot
of talk right now about what I'm hearing
is GMP washing in terms of being able to
really steal people trying to figure out
how they can still check the boxes on
being able to get their product into
Australia you know I think it's also an
interesting conversation the difference
between GMP and quality cannabis you
know you talk about bag appeal and how
well it's cured and how well it's
trimmed and a lot of the conversation
that I'm hearing really is I think is
assuming that a GMP product is going to
be the highest quality product and in
fact I think we know from a consumer
perspective that that's not true yeah
and and look I think the really
important thing is that underlying all
of this is the fact that what we don't
want to have is confidence undermined at
the patient level at the prescriber
level and probably the the kicker in all
of this which comes back to you really
do need to understand the technicality
of what's required to have product in
there is that and the TGA made it really
clear at our conferences here at a
cannabis that if they find product
that's not fit for purpose it's being
transacted in the market it's actually
not just the product sponsor that
brought the product in but the
prescribing doctor the pharmacist who
issued the product they're all liable to
be prosecuted by the TGA and they made
that pretty clear so
back to what we're trying to do here is
establish an industry we know it's not
all going to be based on Australian
grown and produced material there's
absolutely scope for
cannabis to move around the world in all
directions what we don't want to see
happen is confidence undermined and
doctors being put in a in a position
where they say hang on this doesn't look
anything like a medicine you know I told
you it wasn't real and they pushed back
um
your regulatory framework has some teeth
that's a little bit different than other
countries maybe you can share with us
about your driving legislation and how
you feel like that's impacting the
growth of the Australian Market yeah
that's that's a really good question and
it's it's a
discrimination that's happening with
cannabis in in Australia is it's been
caught under this legislation where uh
if you're a driver and you're found to
have cannabinoids in your system the
police are obliged to prosecute you
doesn't matter if you're impaired or not
and as an industry obliged to prosecure
they have no discretion they have no
discretion so other than in Tasmania
we've got a small island to the South
that someone made a legislative mistake
and it's an oversight that actually
allows people in Tasmania who are using
medicine to treat a condition to to
still drive which is exactly what should
happen we're not saying anyone should be
driving while they're impaired but
there's no way they should be prosecuted
by having cannabinoids in their system
and it's having a huge impact at patient
level where even in my own family I've
got people who know it would be useful
to help with sleep or with pain but are
not prepared to take cannabis because
they can't afford to not drive and
they're they're worried that they'll be
picked up so that's that is a key Focus
for us is to get that drive change
there's a whole push along that line
um
that we're saying treat it like any
other medicine if they are talking to
their prescribing doctor and managing it
they should be able to manage and
understand how and when they can use
medicine for their quality of life and
not impact on on driving and I would
comment that that kind of stigma that
permeates regulatory Frameworks is a
hangover from prohibition and it's
really important I think to continue to
unpack the history of Prohibition in
North America and for us all to really
understand how racist that legislation
was and what the intention of it was and
for us to realize it as we're regulating
cannabis around the world if we don't
address that part of the history of
prohibition if we don't address it with
our Regulators if we aren't informing
and educating people about the history
of prohibition we actually will see that
kind of stigma permeate the regulatory
framework and cause those kinds of
really serious discriminations for
patients in Canada our regulatory
framework we legalized cannabis Within
intention to minimize the harms of it
not because my government said hey I'm
really sorry about the Hundred Years of
lies and all of the like lives that were
ruined and people that were jailed and
that all of the indigenous and brown and
black people were disproportionately
punished why don't we figure out a way
to correct that we didn't do that and so
even though we have legalized cannabis
in Canada both for medical and
recreational purposes the stigma that
permeates the regulatory framework is
actually strangling our industry so high
taxation over regulation we're not
allowed to talk to Consumers so actually
doing the ethical and purpose-filled and
values-based work around addressing the
history of prohibition we don't just do
it because it's the right thing to do it
actually needs to happen in order to be
able to build healthy functional
Industries around the world brief rant
from your moderator
um
let's and also
thank you
let's talk about uh New Zealand as
Carmen as I've had the opportunity to
get to know you one of the things that I
really appreciate about your narrative
is you are really patient focused I
don't hear you talking about Market size
and margins I really hear you talking
about patient outcomes and you have a
beautiful patient-centric approach and I
think that that is
um it that approach is growing your
market and tell us about how you see the
stigma dissolving in New Zealand and how
and why that's happening and what you
and the other companies are doing to
address those issues yeah absolutely so
maybe to help put into context let me
start with the numbers that I haven't
spoken about already and that'll give
you some insight as to how we've been
able to move the dial on those numbers
so when I was here last year at ICBC we
were talking about 30 000 patients in
New Zealand accessing medicinal cannabis
in 2021 we're a small nation just five
million people in 2022 we had 60 000
prescriptions written for medicinal
cannabis so a double
we predicted that 2023 it was going to
double again to around 120
000 prescriptions but actually halfway
through the year we see that the market
is growing faster than what we thought
it was going to be and it will land
higher than that
um that is because people are talking to
each other the medicine is actually
really helping people a lot of it is
patient driven and patient-led so they
might be talking to their neighbor Over
The Back Fence and their neighbor is
complaining about not sleeping and they
say oh I'm trying cannabis how about you
tried that so where the Gap then Falls
is to the prescribers because a patient
goes to the prescriber and says I want
to try cannabis and the prescriber says
I don't know anything about it so one of
the key things that Helios but also all
of the other companies that are
providing medicinal cannabis in New
Zealand are doing is working with the
doctors
uh we were all at a GP conference just
two weeks ago before jumping on planes
and coming to Berlin and at that GP
conference in Rotorua there was a
two-hour plenary session around
medicinal cannabis that was really well
attended so there is also I guess a pull
from the doctors and we are trying to
fill that vacuum of information so that
we can then provide for more and more
patients awesome and Peter maybe you can
talk a little bit about the growth of
the patient access and the market also
in Australia because even though your
patients have to deal with these
Draconian driving laws your your your
Market is expanding and more and more
patients are getting access every day
yeah absolutely and and some of the data
that came out earlier this year there
have now been over a million approvals
through the special access scheme over
the journey so that's not a million
patients but it is a sign that it is
becoming mainstream we've got something
like 30 000 doctors in Australia
Australia is around four to five
thousand of them that are now actively
prescribing under
um special access scheme and the
authorized prescriber scheme the the
numbers and I was talking to our
government people here today about
getting some clarity and transparency
around what is happening with patient
access and products to patients is
something that we're working on because
at the moment it is difficult to pin
down exactly what's happening but
there's no doubt there's a push in a
growth which is really encouraging and
investing in physician education is
something that sometimes companies in
the early stages have a hard time
committing to because it's an investment
that Rises the Tide for All Ships right
but instead of companies really focusing
on the same group of prescribers and
trying to get their sort of loyalty the
work to convert new Physicians into the
space is actually what's going to touch
more patients in the end yeah and as an
industry Association that's a key role
we're playing to to do that because
as an registered medicine it's illegal
to do any sort of promotion or
advertising so and you can't do that at
a company or product specific level but
as an industry Association we can
absolutely bring a teacher positions
yeah so you two have trade
representatives from your government
here at this event and I was chatting
with them both yesterday and coming from
Canada where our government is not
interested in helping to grow our
industry they're not definitely not
interested in helping us be successful
in a global Marketplace how on Earth did
you navigate the relationships with your
governments where they are here at ICBC
and chatting about how much they love
this industry and support your companies
to me it's like a miracle
do you want to go first or well so uh
Global Victoria have got to stand here
that's the Victorian government and they
actually the Victorian government got
the ball rolling in Australia they were
the first to put legislation into play
um but then had to step back because as
signatory to the UN single convention
that had to be federally legislated and
that's when the federal federal
government came in over the top and
created the Office of drug control but
the Victorian government have been
strongly involved the whole way through
they saw the opportunity and there's no
doubt we punch above our weight in our
corner of the world I think Australia
and New Zealand but Melbourne and
Victoria in particular have a really
strong Medical Science Background as
well and the uh I think it came up the
other day in the global investment Forum
that someone made the point that if
you're looking to do clinical trial work
Australia and Israel are the two key
areas to focus on for that so there's no
doubt the next challenge for us is to
bring the science into the application
of cannabinoids in human health and
we're at the Forefront and with a really
strong regulatory environment to support
it and that covers both Australia and
New Zealand and I think we've seen
you know we're next to each other out in
the hall and uh it's it's a nice
juxtaposition to have in terms of how
we're working together as both
government bodies are talking to each
other it's really it's really wonderful
to see we are 10 minutes out so I'm
going to start hustling us through so I
have a big question for you but I want
you to try to give us a short answer to
a brief question so you have we're going
to kind of like go from talking for to
Australia and New Zealand and kind of
pull up and look at the globe again so
you have a very nuanced system for
assessing markets you do really deep
Dives when you're looking at new and
emerging markets and I know that this is
a big question because we talked about
it for about a half an hour but can you
take a couple of minutes and just talk
about all of the Nuance factors that you
look at when you're looking at new
markets
yeah sure and I think that what we've
been sharing here from our colleagues
Australia New Zealand is really
exemplifies the differences you know
some of the nuances so we're looking at
you know things when you walk right back
to the patient level
how can patients access the medicine in
that country
how many prescribers are there how are
the prescribers educated
um how is you know do you look then at
the the actual provision of the medicine
where are people
um going to buy this from how many
outlets what's the availability so we
start off with you know doctors
prescribing education we move through
then to you know actually how the
medicine is going to get transferred or
made available to the patients
um you know there's a lot of other
factors to look at the regulations
obviously are very very important the
regulations can be
um they're always going to be fairly
strict on the medical cannabis side
because that's the way that the system's
set up but there are some countries that
are more amenable or perhaps there's
ways to navigate their regulations a
little differently than other countries
so I think we said New Zealand earlier
it's very strict there's a Jewish GMP
requirements and there's not a lot of
wiggle room you look at other countries
and sometimes there are ways I mean even
in Germany if you look at the
variability in the states in Germany
people would prefer to import into
certain States than other states right
it's because there's an ability to have
a little bit more of a certainty around
um just how strictly applied the
regulations are going to be because at
the end of the day you're looking at
regulations that can be interpreted by
people and oftentimes those
interpretations can vary a little bit
they can be very strict or not so much
but in these markets I'm also looking at
Legacy I mean to me the existence
virtually every country has a legacy
Market cannabis is being grown in that
country somewhere and that's what the
legal markets tend to be built upon in
Canada the massive mistake that was made
was that the was the Legacy Market was
rejected out of the program they were
left out completely and so we have a lot
of folks coming in to try to try to make
this this work grow grow cannabis I mean
took Canada four or five years to really
get up to a decent quality and Cadence
with this cultivation
largely because the Legacy Market was
rejected so I look at the Legacy Market
how is the jurisdiction approaching that
again I look at the things I mentioned
earlier and then all the way through to
the import export side of it obviously
supply chain is really really important
um don't believe all that you read in
the supply chain analysis is
exceptionally important and last thing
I'll mention is I really believe
strongly like I don't know everything at
all I learn every day and I rely on
experts in these various narrow domains
you know so I I go to people that are
smarter than me with respect to the
supply chain that's all they do or with
prescribers or with clinics and this
kind of thing these are the that's very
very important to focus on you cannot
just think that you're going to read and
understand you've got to go to the
experts in those narrow areas well as a
long-term Legacy operator I certainly
appreciate your respect for the wisdom
and the experience from those of us that
have been in it for decades before
regulation continuing to have a a key
place in the the new Global industry
okay I want to switch and talk about a
couple of my favorite subjects so I want
to talk about social justice and
sustainability
I'm wondering in both New Zealand and
Australia if there is conversation about
how to include your indigenous
populations that were disproportionately
punished by prohibition and if they are
on ramping into the industry and if
they're going to reap some of the
benefits of regulated cannabis
yeah so in New Zealand I think we're
working on that there's still work to do
but if I go back to the beginning where
our regulations came in I think there's
some nice examples of where we've been
able to pave the way for those that
maybe have been disproportionately
punished in the past there's two things
in New Zealand that are really
interesting around this one is that we
can transition illicit genetics into the
legal medicines Market through a
declaration process with our Ministry of
Health and so those Legacy strains where
people have been accessing that often
medicinally are able to come into a
legal framework and then the other point
is really something that was petitioned
before my time before I came into the
industry but that the founders of the
industry across across the industry
really pushed for was around those with
criminal charges being allowed into the
industry or not and I know this was a
contentious discussion at the time but
in New Zealand those that have had
previous convictions for cannabis can
work in the industry and I think that
this opens the doors to some people to
be able to transition across and we've
seen some examples ready to move to New
Zealand I'm sold
um Peter can you add just very quickly
because we're getting close to the end
if you want to comment anything about
on-ramping and including your indigenous
populations in Australia I think we
should look at what they're doing in New
Zealand they've done it really well
we've got a big issue in Australia this
year with the referendum that's
happening around the voice for
indigenous people and unfortunately
unfortunately that's become politicized
um I'm hoping Australia doesn't miss the
opportunity to take the first step there
which should be to give them a voice so
that's my position and I'll happily put
that out there but yeah no there's still
a lot more to do and what about
sustainability reporting is there
conversations in your countries about
requirements for starting to report on
your carbon footprint and your other
Environmental kpis
there are it's it's definitely a focus
and for a number of the research bodies
and universities involved in some of the
work we're doing I think that's going to
be a real Focus for the for the next
stage but there's a long way to go on
that too but it's definitely high on the
agenda in Australia and I'm just going
to take one minute to say that any of
you that are operating in the EU it
would be good to have a look at the
corporate responsibility or the
corporate sustainability reporting
disclosures that were passed in April
because pretty much all small and
medium-sized Enterprises working in the
Cannabis industry in Europe are going to
be required to be doing very significant
sustainability reporting in the next two
years including reporting on scope 3
which means the impact of your supply
chain so your partners are going to need
to be able to be doing their data
collecting and their reporting this is
something that I've been researching and
I'm super passionate about making sure
that the folks in our industry are sort
of waking up and getting prepared to do
this kind of work because you don't want
to be scrambling to do it at the in the
last moment it becomes very complex and
expensive to do if you're scrambling so
if you want to talk about sustainability
reporting come and find me the last
thing that I want to do is I just want
to give each one of you an opportunity
to essentially tell the audience like
why did you come to ICBC and what are
you looking for so in terms of the
connections you're trying to make the
partners that you're trying to make if
you want to buy something or sell
something for the folks that are in the
audience who are the people that you
would like to come and talk to you when
our panel is over
yes so I think for Australia with the
the recent changes to the legislation
people understanding that the
opportunity for medicinal cannabis is a
global one getting cannabinoids into
human health um is the the key Focus
I think that's the key message for
Australia I think the the prereq
discussion around what's happening in
that flower space and moving too quickly
to a recreational Market would would
really damage getting the clinical work
and the science done so that's one of
the challenges we've got but we want to
move the whole thing forward and and
having
confidence in and not undermining uh
confidence is is really a key part of
the the focus so being aware of what's
happening in this part of the world and
vice versa is why we're here for ICBC
Carmen
I think this is a two-way street in
terms of what we are asking for
um so I've found some great Partners
already to bring our New Zealand grown
New Zealand made medicines to this side
of the world but if you are looking for
a super high quality medicine then stop
by the New Zealand Booth Booth 383 and
have a chat to me or some of the other
New Zealand companies that are here
we're looking for Partnerships and
distribution pathways the other part in
terms of the the two-way street in terms
of what I'm looking for is as we are
growing the industry quickly for us at
Helios we are looking for people who
might want to come to New Zealand I know
it's a really tough sell to move to New
Zealand Hillary's coming already
um but I can bring my dog right
we're looking for people with EU GMP
experience and highly controlled indoor
grow or an extraction that might want to
come and spend six months or a year or
maybe even longer in New Zealand and
help us to accelerate our industry so
that we can deliver more products to
more patients around the world so I
think we could um we could show you a
good time in New Zealand and we could
also learn from some people who've been
there and trod the path before well said
and David let's talk about the services
that you offer and the partners that
you're looking for here yeah I mean it's
a B2B conference obviously we attend
patient conferences and the focus
there's a bit different this is B2B
which is going to make my remind
approximately focus in that direction
where we really recognize the lack of
capital in the market and that's what a
lot of people are telling us whether
it's clients friends Associates then
they're struggling to get access to
Capital and in that environment you've
got to be a lot more creative a lot more
Nimble so our work is based around
navigation we help people to navigate
access to Capital we help people to
navigate creative ways to get their
products into Global markets that's kind
of where we where we operate we're at
Booth 345 and happy to talk we're a team
of four people there and love to talk to
anyone that wants to come by it's been
such a pleasure getting to know the
three of you as we prepared for this
conversation and you're stuck with me
for life now we're going to be lifelong
friends I look forward to continuing to
collaborate and thank you for this
fantastic conversation what a pleasure
thank you
[Applause]