hi guys thank you so much for joining us
for the global rise of medical cannabis
panel my name is Lily Templeton I'm an
international cannabis analyst and I'm
Georgia Glick head of Partnerships at
Hanway Associates
we are an advisory firm and we offer
research Regulatory Affairs and we focus
on New Market entry strategies for
pharmaceutical and medical cannabis
companies across Europe and Canada
alongside authoring reports through our
publishing arm first Wednesdays
While most panels today will focus on
the largest Medical Market Germany in
today's session we will zoom out and
take a macro view across the global
medical cannabis sector
to discuss some of the key trends market
dynamics and considerations when
operating in new regions
outside of Germany we see a number of
interesting medical cannabis Frameworks
Australia in the UK in particular have
seen notable growth rates in the last
few years and with the limited pilot in
France and unique Frameworks in Italy
and Portugal there is a lot to discuss
despite this there are still regulatory
blockers hindering these medical markets
and we also want to discuss some of
those hindrances today
it's a pleasure to be joined by such a
diverse set of panelists today who are
who are going to bring operational and
expertise from a range of markets
um so yeah I'd love to hand over to them
to introduce themselves
hello my name is Lisa Huck I'm founder
and CEO of mg Universe gmbh we are a
strategic advisory company and but we
also operate our own projects for
example crowd investee
hello everyone welcome
I've been coming here since 2017 helping
Alex Rogers with ICBC bringing lots of
Canadians with me here I've been in the
industry since October 2013 so almost 10
years a lot of fun a lot of ups and
downs which we'll talk about and now I
work with luge Brands we're a contract
manufacturer of Edibles in Canada and I
have a pharmacy called hybrid Farm where
we are the only Pharmacy in North
America that has medical cannabis on
site
thank you
hello I'm Gosha meniere and I'm Chief
strategic officer from Hapa Farm we are
pharmaceutical company from Germany
having fully integrated operation in
North Macedonia
um I'm still living in Israel about two
weeks from now I will move to Germany
but I have almost five years experience
in medical cannabis also from Israelis
company so I would like to share some
experience related to regulation in
Europe which we gained last four years
I'm happy to be here thank you
uh good morning everyone my name is
fleeta I am from little green farmer and
little green farmer is an Australian and
a Danish producer of a medical grade
cannabis medicine so we have operations
in Australia and in Denmark we're
vertically integrated and we are
exporting these medicines across the
globe to patients and we have a really
big focus on the European market it's
such a special market and really looking
forward to you know joining this great
panel today so thank you for being here
and listening to us
fantastic
um so I'd like to kick off today by
talking a little bit about patient
access and medical Frameworks Gosha and
flita um you both have experience
operating in a number of key Emerging
Markets such as Australia Portugal and
Poland
um I'm Keen to hear from both of you
maybe to kick off how has the over or
the under regulation led to supply
shortages for patients or a lack of
diversity in product formats
um I think so let's go back a step if I
can and I think it's really important to
recognize that each country has its own
unique Juris or a regulation or um
regime and I think that's it comes back
to each business and I'm just going to
speak at a business front to begin with
is what is the business model to begin
with because which markets do you want
to play in because it's not like you can
send to Germany and you can send to all
the countries in Europe the EU are just
not aligned like that and that was a big
learning curve coming from Australia
when we were exported through a mutual
recognition agreement initially into
Europe we have to understand the unique
jurisdictions legislation and because of
that the patient access system is really
different in each of these markets in
Australia it's a huge demand at the
moment there and we we our patients
access it through a special Access
program through GPS and specialists who
can prescribe whereby there are other
countries in the UK very restricted in
terms of patient access at the moment
it's growing it has potential but right
now it's only Specialists that are
actually prescribing there and then look
France is a very different cattle
official together you know that's just a
pilot program several companies are
including a little green farmer are a
part of that trial and again it's a very
closed system but we hope that that will
catalyze in the next coming years to a
legal Market there and I guess coming
back to your your question or just about
the product registration side of things
every country is different yes it might
have to be approved by the local
authorities but if you look at Poland
for example you have to go through a
product registration process or a
marketing authorization process and the
same for Portugal and that can take two
to three years to actually happen
and of course when it's over regulated
it is very hard for patients to access
because there are limited products
available but often that's how an
industry actually begins
yes I will also add um uh thank you
because we have very very similar
experience but I would like to add
mainly that when you the countries out
of Europe like Israel Australia Canada
for example wants to enter uh European
uh Market first it's not only business
strategy but it's mainly regulatory
strategy so you are already cracking
regulatory puff country by country how
you can register your product first of
all what is the frames regulatory frames
because some countries as as felita you
said are very similar approach like
Magister formulation we know that it's
in Germany in Switzerland in Italy in
Poland and some other European countries
but for example Poland my origin country
is very specific because
um you have to submit full marketing
authorization dossier of uh
pharmaceutical raw material it's mean if
you are registering like propylene
glycer or I don't know any other solvent
it's the same heavy quality the sale
like medical cannabis so we can say that
a patient will wait for a little green
Pharma product for example in Poland up
to two years for flowers and maybe up to
four or five years for extracts so how
is going on now in Poland on the market
you have maybe in like in real life in
the pharmacy I don't know four or five
type of different flowers and only one
on two extracts which is crazy if you
compare it with with German markets
which is oversaturated I don't know more
than 100 different flowers and and maybe
80 or 90 different extracts so the
doctors in Germany they don't know how
to even prescribe so it's like
from French we can say for the patients
and doctors and then what is going on to
back to Poland also that the even the
registrated products which are
prescribed by the doctors are high THC
and only one flower is balanced uh CBD
thc88 so if patients are searching for
CBD flowers for example CBD products
they will go to the to the hemp shops I
don't have any problem with the hemp
shops but the regulation for you know
this CBD food supplement products are
not so strict not controlled so
sometimes the labels we don't know what
is inside so I think that regulation yes
but maybe not over regulation and for
sure we should control quality of the
products because we know very well it's
not only the the
label regarding the API content but also
the heavy metals so all the toxins which
can be very toxic for the patient so yes
I think that in Europe we are struggling
with this lack of harmonization from
European Union because we know that from
pharmaceutical industry there's always
the harmonized path to access the the
European market but in case of cannabis
it's really National path and and so
many countries still are waiting to have
the regulation and we are all waiting
how the Pharma European pharmacopeia or
hmpc for example will classify a medical
cannabis so I think the patient are like
initiators of um of Regulation we see it
in Spain for example it's still ongoing
and uh we'll see we are looking forward
what will be the next steps but France
also was initiated by by the Association
of patients and we still have this
extension of one additional year of
French a pilot project and um hopefully
next year we'll have the regulation in
in France to to let the patient have a
regular access and control access to the
product a very similar way that we
started in Canada uh very challenging at
the beginning when we first started uh
we would ask people to go to their
doctor to get their authorization and
they would say my doctor doesn't
authorize they threaten to kick me out
of their Clinic if I use cannabis so
that was in 2013 so we had to create
cannabis clinics which are ways for
patients to come in and get educated uh
of course licensed producers had to fund
this and we couldn't pay doctors because
that's illegal of course but we had to
find other ways to fund it because no
one else was funding it otherwise the
patients would be paying and we didn't
want the patients to pay so what
happened was now with legalization the
doctors are no longer scared that
they're the gatekeeper they were before
forced to be the controller of cannabis
because if the doctor didn't authorize
no one was getting cannabis of course
that's not true but that's how they felt
and they were worried about the college
coming down on them but now the
recreational happened and people can
just go by cannabis across the street
everywhere anyone who goes to a doctor
are actual real medical patients and no
longer are doctors afraid anymore and
you know it takes a long time here we
are 10 years later so just a quick
thought on that no thank you and I think
that Taps into something at least so I
know we were having a quick chat about
just before we came in which was how a
lot of the market dialogue is about how
flower still dominates and and there's
various reasoning for that I mean
doctors have conflicting preferences
sometimes they're preferring a more
controlled dose to product but what are
the kind of dynamics that are at play
here it's not just potentially patient
Trends but price and accessibility
um I think uh what we have to understand
in Germany is that there are different
groups of patients there are patients
that get their prescription via the Paya
via the doctor and the doctor suggested
because he may think that's the best
type of therapy unfortunately that's
still the least common variant I would
say we have these patients who are
voluntary or unvoluntary self-payers
that are mostly in the flower section
where there's also a huge huge kind of
availability of products I mean the good
thing that we can say is that prices
meanwhile are below illegal market
prices which I think is some very great
achievement but still we have a lot of
bottlenecks that patients have to jump
through in order to get a prescription
in order to get maybe reimbursement by
the health insurance but you can see
that it's an ongoing discussion and that
the government is trying to make some
some improvements in that regard last
week for example
um Miss kapad konta was on the panel
here before she announced that um there
will be like uh like a short a short
image of the time you have to wait till
your application can be approved and
also there may be some doctors um that
get like where you the application does
not need to be happen and so they can
just prescribe which would also be great
but it's baby steps and baby steps and
we're really
um developing on on a micro level if you
want to say so for sure and in terms of
that blur as you say between people
liking it and funny easier and actually
better quality products often from the
illicit Market do you think the entrance
and maybe Alex will also have some
insight here from Canada of the entrance
of categories like live rosin and hash
and and more kind of recreational style
formats carts for example
um can help with some of this and can
help bring patients on that potentially
uh into flower absolutely and I get this
question all the time coming to Berlin I
mean let's be honest people in Europe
love to smoke Israel loves to smoke
there's certain places and they just
they just love to smoke but uh bless you
and uh the difference is these other
forms are just much better medical
products and here I am so many years
later having the same discussion once
you allow these other formats in they're
a lot more consistent they're a lot more
clear you know again I love flower as
well but when you're talking about
medicine there's just so many better
ways and you know we're making the joke
backstage how in California when I was
there a few years ago they talk about
distillate as hot dog water that is like
the lowest form of input and look if you
can't afford a higher input it's fine
but for those that can and want to Hash
Ross and live resin these are way more
pure full spectrum much better effect
you can try five milligrams of
distillate versus five milligrams of
hash rosin edible it's completely
different and I know we're not talking
about that yet in Europe you're just
starting to get your markets established
but this is where it's going and and you
need to kind prepare for that and
especially as a medical product I'm
sorry smoking cannabis as a medicine I
know it seems like that's what you're
fighting for but you're going to be like
five to ten years in the future and
you'll be like oh my God I can't even
believe we were even saying that so
that's that's
thanks can I can I just head on to that
as well I think that the concentrates
whether it's live rosin resin they're
very pure and the volume and the intake
is probably lower there will be
applications it's about finding a way to
do that safely and obviously to register
those processes but let's not forget
that it's less unadulterated
and there therefore
um the Entourage effect which we all
know will play a really big part less
terpenes are lost less active
ingredients so I think we're mad to
think it's not going to happen it's just
a matter of of when and how
I just wanted to add regarding the also
product and back to the regulatory
strategy we are facing in Europe still
the problem that we have only two
countries currently in Europe allowing
finished product registration so we have
Portugal and we have France but France
is still not under this pilot trial so
we cannot introduce the new product now
but this is also like a kind of problem
for the company's pharmaceutical
companies to bring this delay to
purified extract to the market because
when you have the monster regulation
under Magister formulation you are
bringing to the pharmacist kind of yeah
pharmaceutical raw material and the
pharmacist must formulate to continue
formulating under Medusa formulation the
pharmacy
uh we know that in Poland and I told you
that there is only a few flowers and one
or two extracts registered but the the
pharmacists police pharmacies are very
Innovative so how they are doing because
for information you can have per
prescription in Poland a purified extra
85 THC with the prescription or legally
so how it's how it's going on it's
pharmacies it's really in this Pharmacy
the extraction equipment so he's doing
this ancient way extraction so he has a
crude extract then he's standardizing it
and then purifying to obtain this uh
highly purified 85 percent per percent
um extract for the vaporization so yes
it's possible it's only one product
currently in in Poland but and obviously
from from like even price perspective uh
Poland has no no reimbursement so
everything is from the pocket of the
patient but they can access this uh
Vapes if we can know from legal uh legal
sources and especially with the high
quality and and Purity but regarding
also about the the purified extract
every patient is aware about Entourage
effect so it's it's not only searching
for TC CBD the patient we know are
searching for specific serpents so
there's also the way to enrich this
purified extracts to I think it's our
role now as a pharmaceutical companies
to bring to the market maybe
complementary I don't want to say food
supplement but why not the blend of the
turpents to complete like to give give
away a package or kit for the patient
which a medical doctor can supervise and
and advice for example because we we
have these large knowledge about
turpents or even other synergistic
herbals so this is something which we
must ask pharmaceutical companies to
introduce because we are limited by this
regulatory path of Magister formulation
and of course hope that in most of the
countries will allow to have finished
product
and along with that will come education
because it's so key to educate our
stakeholders including our doctors you
know how to prescribe such different
different products and unique Delivery
Systems yes and you mentioned earlier
obviously um you know the fact that in
Australia General Practitioners can
prescribe which obviously we don't have
yet in the UK would you say there were
on any other factors that have
contributed to this growth that we've
seen in the Australian Medical Market in
particular
yeah there are a couple of things um the
first one is actually doctoral education
I think that is huge now you know it's
up to us as producers and and everybody
in this room to have a part in the
education process because that's how an
industry evolves uh it or it obviously
starts from patient demand but then we
need to educate doctors it's the 80 20
rule so you'll have a handful of doctors
who are your main prescribers but that's
definitely growing we've got over 5 000
prescribers now in Australia and the
other reason and it's it's there we
haven't really talked about it and that
is in most markets it's the Quasi
medical where the recreational and those
using it for self-medicating purposes
access it legally through the um you
know the regime or the the legal process
because why not you know you would argue
that the quality is safer just in terms
of extraction techniques and what have
you you get the consistent the same
supply all the time it's a and most
importantly it's legal
I will also add something regarding the
education of the doctors and thank you
flita to touching these sensitive points
it's not I after education but of course
because they are used to have the
clinical data or some support and we
know all that this plant with we are
discovering every day some some
publication and there is a lot of
clinical trials observational studies
but after the the trainings we we know
it from France for example the doctors
must to practice and then have this
relationship with the patient very close
to take the the feedbacks from there
because it's constant interaction I
would add also in this relationship the
pharmacist so back to France we know
that the first year the doctors were
prescribing a high CBD product to to
treat the pain and after a few months
patients were just not happy and they
stopped this uh um they stopped they
asked to withdraw we withdrawn from the
from the project effect because they
didn't receive any any relief so only
after one year the the French doctors
they just learned that maybe they should
start titration with the balanced
product and then to to obviously start
Slow and Low but that increase this uh
this content of THC I think there's the
huge stigma about THC everyone is very
afraid of THC and and the doctors needs
to practice and have interaction because
it's really like personalized medicine
so interaction close interaction with
the with the with the patient and and in
the other countries like Magister
formulation in this duo we have to add
the pharmacies because it's really like
pharmacists who is doing this module
formulation but he may do it only if he
has a prescription so if for example you
would like to introduce some very
Innovative formats I don't know some
topicals or even I don't know liposomal
Solutions we have to first of all
educate the doctors that yes we will
introduce it through the pharmacist so
we the we are initiate like the
prescription then the pharmacist is
formulating in the pharmacy so and you
actually said something really important
uh the follow-up we did tons of doctor
education if they don't practice it
doesn't do anything so what we would say
to them is why don't you find a few
patients that nothing else is working
for try those patients and then follow
up with them and what the doctor has
found because I would go to a lot of
medical conferences every year and I
would see the same doctors and they
would at first they were very skeptical
then they were like you know I tried it
with a few patients and you know it's
kind of working and one of the funny
things they would say to me is you know
either this cannabis stuff is working or
all the patients are coming together and
agreeing on what they're saying to me
because they're all saying the same
thing and either it's working or they're
just all working together to like trick
me so after a while they realize it is
legitimate and it is helping but it's
all in the follow-up and pharmacists
which only now in Canada are getting
involved is the secret to it because
they're the ones that are more following
up they're the ones monitoring the other
medication the doctors can't be expected
to do all that and I think that's a big
help yeah I think like the pharmacists
are actually like an interesting point
because if you think about it in Germany
we have had the prescription of Thrones
which is pure THC for ages like the
pharmacists I have the impression that
they feel comfortable working with it
the doctors feel more comfortable
prescribing it there's more like this
barrier in the mind for the flower
products and for the extracts but I
think also that we owe a lot of the
progress that we have in Germany to some
very motivated pharmacists who want to
become experts who are working together
with doctors to get these prescriptions
or who are there to maybe do test
filling of cartridges like let's if you
look at in Germany for the extract
products there's only one extract
available for inhalation all the other
extracts are basically oral Solutions
and but there are also pharmacists who
are processing flour into extracts for
example so there are possibilities
through the magistrial preparation and I
think it's uh quite interesting to get
the pharmacist also involved as well as
doctor because you need both right are
there any pharmacists in the room here
is there any pharmacists here checking
out only a couple in the back all right
awesome let's talk to them they're smart
sorry
fantastic
um and I'm Keen to hear from all of you
actually how do different countries
trees approaches to which conditions are
eligible for medical cannabis how does
that impact access
yeah I think most countries are probably
relatively conservative when they begin
and do restrict to a number of
conditions epilepsy pain tends to be in
there so cancer or going through chemo
treatment and Ms and I just feel
rightly or wrongly that it's based on
what the perceived evidence is
and I feel that there is so much more
data out there now that we need to just
open our eyes because it is there we're
getting a huge amount of data being
gathered from Real World evidence but we
do know that governments need to be
conservative particularly to begin with
and so if they restrict to a certain
number of conditions but we have seen
that that quickly evolves and take
Australia for example they have now
prescribed for over 200 different
medical conditions it started off with
just five so that was you know within
four years it got to over 200 conditions
so it's got to start somewhere
yes and I think that in Europe we
actually now we have two type of
countries like first those who are
preparing them the regulation by
reviewing all existing data so from last
year so clinical and scientific data and
then they decided with the pluri
disciplinary Committee of scientists to
set a few indications like France for
example they said this five indication
and for this pilot project we know in
Portugal there's seven indication and we
have this simplified marketing
authorization submission but it's also
for only for this specific seven
indications and then in parallel we have
these countries like Germany and Poland
with no limit of indication only the
knowledge or Convention of of a doctor
again I'm sorry I'm back to example from
Poland because I was practicing this
country for four years but I remember I
made a very very young motivated
medical doctor his specialization I
think was
uh general medicine and then he was
doing the PHD in medical cannabis and he
started just discovering using
prescribing the the Cannabis and he told
me that he had a group of
um six or seven a woman with very severe
[Music]
pain you know
what is the pain of the day
menstrual pain period pains
migrants I'm sorry yes it's a very
severe and migrant and one of the
patients was so it was so difficult for
her to manage this pain that she she
planned twice to commit suicide so and
so she was really desperate and and she
started to have this prescription of
this purified extract for Vaping so 85
percent THC and she she said obviously
that it changed her life but on on the
on the scale of pain on pain it still
was like two but she could function so
so then he was motivated and he said
okay I saw it's working so I started to
um to have a group of these women
between 40 50 having this uh these
severe migrants and and he was convinced
because he was just uh close to this
patient and and he even said like okay I
would like to start observation study in
my hospital to maybe produce some some
scientific data so so observation is
Studies by the way it's it's very good
tool to have there to generate this real
life data we'd pay from patients on
under control condition and maybe not
going directly to the full clinical
studies which is obviously time
consuming and money consuming but but
again it's it's enough to have one and
two a few doctors which are specialized
in specific domain and they are very
motivated close to the patient with a
lot of empathy and then I think we can
generate a lot of information from
patients fantastic could you both
mentioned the French trial quite a few
times do you think any of the data
collection from the French trials will
be useful for other markets
of course I mean I love that the French
government are collecting this data and
we really hope that they do something
with that
um you would expect a report to be
published on the efficacy or
particularly the safety sorry in that
particular trial so we hope that they
will
um but in if they don't then I know we
as a company supplying into that trial
collect our own uh pharmacovigilance
data and that's going to be really
important as we continue to build you
know on that data Gathering so yeah
let's hope that France come out because
I think that could be a turning point
for other countries as well
yes I will add also that here a French
pilot project it's not clinical trial
okay it's it's really the purpose was to
to have uh to check uh kind of supply
chain uh how it can be controlled from
from yeah manufacturer this through the
distributor to the patient so it's a
trial a lot of learnings I think first a
report was published already after two
years and and as little you said
something new which is not existing in
any other European countries
pharmacovigilance so it's also like a
kind of hybrid through the Audra Alex
website Etc but every month every
company participating in this trial are
receiving the the report of the of the
of the complaints of the patient some
sometimes these are very light cases
sometimes it's severe cases but we have
uh statistics and we can see it and and
by the end they will generate kind of a
report for information lack of efficacy
is also a side effect we can say and and
this is what I was mentioning about
doctors who started to to treat the pain
with the high CBD product the first year
so we lost a lot of patience because of
this lack of knowledge or maybe yes yes
lack of experience but then we practice
we could improve this data in France I'm
sure and and this is why it was also
this extension of why one year for this
pilot project big deception for the
patient obviously but I think that it
will allow help authorities but also all
the institutions who are implementing
regulation to to use this data to maybe
not only use that digest and and take
some learnings to implement the solid
real not only because this is what I was
mentioning about over regulation like
realistic regulation to help a patients
have a high quality product but in the
easy way not too complicated way
fantastic I think it's been so great to
hear um and I'm sure everyone in the
audience agrees the detail from the
different markets and how much we
actually do have to learn from what's
Happening we're not doing all this in a
kind of microcosm country by country and
there's so much globally to learn
um as as a result of that I'd love to
kind of open up to the audience and see
if there are any burning questions key
thoughts anyone wants to raise as we've
got such an international uh panel of
amazing women and Alex as well uh here
with us today and Alex as well let's
hear for all these amazing women and
Alex as well
this man right here has a question
[Applause]
yeah hi yeah so uh coming back to
education because I know in Denmark well
fleeta you were saying in Australia part
of the success has been the fact that
doctors have been educated maybe
patients have been educated and I think
in Europe that's still a huge problem
because a lot of patients don't actually
know that they have access to cannabis a
lot of doctors you know they don't
they're a bit scared of prescribing it
most Europeans in theory have access to
cannabis but you know they don't in
reality I know in Denmark the Danish
government are also trying to you know
Implement uh events and conferences to
kind of bring you know people like
yourselves doctors and patients together
to sort of implement it but what can the
rest of Europe do because Alex you said
you had to almost take it you know take
control yourself and create these
cannabis clinics I mean how do you move
that conversation forward and try and
get medical cannabis out to the masses
well you know one one thing that I think
is really important and I didn't want to
touch on earlier because I wanted to get
to questions but I mean since you
brought it up I think something that was
really important is for people to be
honest with their doctors what we had in
Canada just like everywhere else there
was such a stigma where people who were
using cannabis were not telling their
doctors to use cannabis because they
were worried what they were going to
think and then when we started teaching
the doctors we said you know talk to
your patients about it be honest and
they were blown away that the patients
once they felt more comfortable talking
to their doctor that their doctor knew
something about this then they were
opening up and the doctors would say
holy cow I didn't realize how many of my
patients are using cannabis once I was
started to be like hey it's okay I'm not
asking you because I want to kick you
out of my clinic I'm asking you because
I'm interested and all of a sudden that
all changed and people were being honest
with them and then they were like oh
wait a minute more of my patients are
using cannabis maybe I'll talk to them
about it because the reality is cannabis
is so readily available pretty much
everywhere in the world like everywhere
we go people use cannabis it's easy to
get so I think once doctors realize that
that the patient are you going to use
cannabis whether they like it or not and
now they should have a harm reduction
approach and maybe we should talk to
them about maybe not smoking it or using
CBD or not such high THC then we can
have real conversations and I think that
is a big game changer that I would like
to share with people is be honest with
your doctor and if the doctor is hating
on cannabis maybe you should find a
different doctor there are open-minded
doctors out there
it is such a patient-driven industry you
know and our doctors do from patients
they don't
and are open and willing to learn about
prescribing cannabis medicines they
potentially lose patience
and the patients move on and that's
where you start to get these clinics and
other specialized doctors or authorized
prescribers in the space because they
are willing and open and
there are channels you know whereby
patients can access and know who to
access just in terms of who prescribes
more often than not so you know patients
have got a huge voice but it doesn't
take away from the fact cannabis
producers just like pharmaceutical
companies have got a role to play and we
need people on the ground educating and
we need to be continuing our webinars
whether that's sending out faxes to
doctor clinics because believe it or not
that's still happening and as well as
other strategies to bring doctors
together to educate
great thank you uh I think we have one
question up here one question very
quickly please because we're running off
time you've all talked a lot about
concentrates but you haven't really
mentioned anything about pills or about
ingestibles Edibles that kind of thing
is there is there any market for that in
Europe today and uh if if not yet in THC
what about CBD
so yes all the garlic formats are
possible but obviously we have to submit
full marketing authorization to the
country which is ready to obtain such a
submission So currently it's Portugal
very ready from few years I think three
four years very explicit and detailed
regulation
but currently nobody achieved to have
marketing authorization we have only one
approved flower in Portugal and so
still I think there is the path and this
is like confirmed from Magister
formulation so this is why the the
proactive Innovative page pharmacies
which I see that are sitting there for
example having the big Magister
formulation and the labs in their in
their Pharmacy if they have a knowledge
of formulation if they have a
prescription for the doctor for example
for the tablets with CBD or TC they're
able to do but there is the also the
financial aspect in the reimbursement
like for example in Germany because I
don't think that the pharmacist will
spend their time in doing these tablets
or any other Edibles in the in the
Pharmacy in the Magister formulation
only to help the patient so I think this
is more a complex project the problem
not only from from form formulation from
visibility because this is possible if
the doctor is prescribing the tablet for
example we I don't know 50
um a milligram CBD 50 milligrams THC it
can be manufacturing by pharmacies in
the pharmacy in Germany also in Poland
yeah but but I think there is the the
problem of the of the time on the
reimbursement also of the pricing of
this product
yeah there are there are some available
there are soft gel caps in the market
and I think again it's a patient driven
thing
um perhaps it's what's the content and
and what is inside the capsule that's
probably the issue at the moment and not
getting the results but the patients
just don't seem don't seem to be
demanding that right now but I think as
you find as will as the medicinal regime
progresses and more doctors start
prescribing they will want these options
but they do need to go through
registration processes as well and
earlier in the beginning of the talk we
touched on it we didn't touch it on it
too much because there's not really any
regulations for it but truthfully these
products are amazing we see a lot of
Edibles beverages extracts being used by
medicine reduces stigma doesn't have the
smell uh you know one thing I want to
point out about this is that you're only
letting the illicit Market win by not
having these products what we had in
Canada is every product that wasn't
legalized was what the illicit Market
was celebrating and now the only
negative we kind of are left with is a
10mm maximum per package which is
extremely wasteful and stupid so now the
listen Mark is pretty much holding on to
100 milligram a thousand milligram
Edibles outside of that there's almost
no reason to go to the listed Market
anymore and we'll I predicted two years
ago by 2025 we aren't even going to have
an illicit market so you know this is
what the future holds for everyone else
which seems like a lifetime away for
everyone I get it but it's going to
happen I hate to cut you off there but
we are actually out of time one more
time
panel
[Applause]