thank you for being here so my name is
Benjamin Patak I'm as introduced I
worked for Bovada
some people called Boveda so we do these
little humidification pouches that
everybody loves and if you don't know
them we're still outside with a booth
come by get a sample
um so I want to just have everybody
introduce yourselves really quickly and
we're going to dive into the matter
so we'll start with Chris please
my name is Chris ulick I'm with serious
Greenhouse Solutions we do energy
efficient
greenhouses for cannabis but also for
other purposes
my name is Adam Coates I'm the chief
Revenue officer at decibel cannabis
company we're a cultivator and
manufacturer in Canada
um and yeah that's it
good afternoon thank you for staying
here so late on this afternoon my name
is Lori glauser I was the CEO of evio
labs a 12 lab testing lab company in the
U.S in Canada and I also have worked in
Consulting area now I'm here in Germany
looking at opportunities in the German
Market
beautiful yeah you can applaud that's
fine
[Applause]
thank you so let's let's talk about
strategies for developing and marketing
cannabis products
and Beyond and before
um so the way I I want to look at it is
first if you want to enter the Cannabis
Market that can be a challenge per se
right so let's talk about the challenges
that you guys faced
just trying to be a part of that market
it's like just anyone how you feel well
I can I can start we um
we found we were founded we founded the
company in 2011
um before we had a first cannabis
product and in 2015 we that cannabis
product came along
um so the first things we learned is we
had to separate our websites because all
of a sudden Banks were saying well you
can't do business with you anymore
um so it's it's little things like that
along the way that that we've learned
yes so um I started in the business in
1314 doing compliance licensing for
clients and then moved into the testing
space pretty soon thereafter what we
found at first was actually for for many
of us it was actually fairly easy from
coming from industry I came from the
energy Consulting space coming in at
that time it was relatively easy
starting a company was relatively easy
getting licensed back then was
relatively easy but it very quickly got
very hard and it got very hard why
because competition started to increase
Regulators started really locking down
regulations and costs increased and then
of course Banks you know I had to open
reopen 12 bank accounts in the US as
well so multiple times over so it was
I would say the the real challenges that
would that emerged later largely were
regulatory and fitting into a
semi-illegal market
yeah and I think the the regulatory
aspect is something that's really
important to consider
um as you're starting a business as
you're thinking about getting products
to Market and whatever that market may
be whether it's the US Canada
um or or some of the other kind of more
Emerging Markets um it's really
important to understand the Regulatory
and just about in every Market uh maybe
aside from the US you're very limited in
terms of what you can do from a
marketing standpoint so you can almost
throw out you know all the different
playbooks that are out there for
Consumer good or medical good
um and you know my biggest advice you
know to you if you're starting up a
business or looking to get products to
Market is focus on the product all of
the bells and whistles of social media
and you know marketing agencies and you
know don't spend a ton of time or a ton
of money and resources on you know what
the brand is going to be what it looks
like
um you know what it feels like obviously
you need to have something that looks
well but the most important thing and
the most marketable thing that you're
going to have is your product it matters
what's inside the jar not necessarily
what the jar looks like and that is what
your consumers are going to remember to
put it in perspective decibel has a
brand called general admission it is by
far the largest brand product brand in
Canada
only two weeks ago did we have a
functioning website and that's not a
joke so we focused on the product being
Innovative with the products that we put
out understanding what the addressable
markets were and where their pockets of
volumes were and that allowed us to be
tremendously successful as we focused on
the product and how it was going to meet
our consumers needs and I think you can
still do that in all the sort of
different jurisdictions of of selling
and and marketing cannabis and that's
the biggest marketing tool all right so
just directly to that so your biggest
challenge then was product development
I think the big yeah the biggest
challenge is understanding
um
the right segments to go into and to
compete in and how do you find your Edge
in those you know sort of larger
um you know segments in the industry
that will allow you to be successful and
build a profitable company because you
know some of the products that sound
really great that you know may be more
of the the sort of the purest products
may not have a very wide sort of
consumer base and if you're building
really great products but they're really
expensive and they have a very low
addressable Market you're going to be
very challenged to build a successful
business
you know I think that the the the the
moderator here has talked a lot about
you know the beer industry and I agree
but the bill industry also has Brands
like Corona and Bud Light and Miller
Lite and those big Brands those aren't
the most sophisticated products
necessarily but they're the ones that
have the most broad appeal and you need
to really think about that as you're you
know building your business and you know
building your sort of product and
marketing strategy
yeah interesting so I like the the idea
of the wine actually but also because I
mean we live like in Germany like
alcohol is fairly
mildly regulated compared to other
environments right I mean you can buy
beer in every Supermarket if when you're
16. right and we're probably here at
somewhere tobacco same thing so some
in that venue here there might be a
tobacco vending machine so you'd still
have to swipe an ID card right but it's
like in some nightclubs but you're not
allowed to go in under 18 but this
doesn't even have that right so and so
it's so my my Approach was always to
regulation is not so much as
you know will cannabis be as wine like
regulate from a regulatory perspective
but what will the regulation of cannabis
will do to those Industries because
cannabis will be the most regulated drug
or legal drug in the beginning right
so let's talk about like and I think
regulation plays a big big part of this
so and and you all have faced regulatory
struggles probably
so I'd love to tap your mind on that
really so what would like the biggest
struggles how do you overcome them so
what's what's that so one thing I've
learned along the way and I would advise
others going into this business is is
first start out not only looking at the
federal and or state laws that are
coming out but also start early looking
at the other compliance areas look at
the GMP rules look at ISO rules don't
wait to hire a consultant to put a line
in your business plan hire JMP
consultant you know start today reading
what those rules are what those
requirements are and build your business
around that next once you've built your
business around these rules you've built
your Sops Sops are not shelfware and
they're not something that you write
somebody writes them all you win this
application yay it's exciting and you
train everybody the first time and then
people kind of forget they exist so you
really need to make sure those Sops are
true working documents and keeping your
teams on point reviewing those Sops and
modifying the Sops to match your actual
day-to-day operations is also really
important
from a yeah from a
you know building uh these facilities
perspective
um we're facing the same thing right
with GMP gacp uh in the US it's not even
a topic for most people some customers
that we talk to think a little bit into
the future but we as a provider of
buildings were actually dealing with an
international market where
designing building here in Europe we are
we have customers in Australia and New
Zealand in the Caribbean and because of
that you get exposed to different types
of regulations or different local
regulations different types of GMP and
gacp regulations and you also see that
there's different interpretation of
these regulations and so what we are
learning as a business is to essentially
not necessarily try to hit all these
rules but be prepared for our customers
that when we are building something in
the US that when and the Market opens up
in two three years that that facility
still functions and that they can
upgrade it or add features so that they
can get those certifications when they
are needed and I think that little
foresight right is important in in the
business and what I want to turn it to
is
you can't do anything you can't do all
of this on your own you always need to
have a partner someone that you need to
work with right and you need to find the
right Partners as you are building your
business
that brings that expertise to the table
advises you and and helps you to get
there in the future yeah and look like
regulations are going to change and
they're going to change over time and
what we you start with is not what
you're going to end with by any stretch
and so a lot of mistakes that we've seen
in Canada and there's been a lot and
frankly we've made a lot of mistakes as
well as but one of the things that's so
important is building up personality and
flexibility into what you're doing so
you know as Chris was talking about you
know as he's building out facilities
he's offering to his clients you know
the optionality you know in case
GMP or jacp is going to be required for
that certain region that's a small
example and and don't getting married to
one idea because that's the way the
regulation is today
um you know there is going to be
Evolution that will create opportunity
but if you're bolted down into something
that becomes immovable because of it
becomes too much to invest to make the
change or you're essentially committed
into a certain strategy and then the
regulations change and you're not able
to Pivot and you're going to be left
behind so building in that flexibility
you know around your systems and around
whether it is your facility or strategy
is going to be so important but the
Bedrock of everything that you do I'll
go back to kind of my earlier comment
needs to be about the product about what
consumer you're trying to address and
what size of opportunity there and
always providing great value for money
and I don't mean cheap I mean for
whatever you're doing if you're the most
expensive product that's totally fine
but you need to provide the value that's
going to deliver against that and so
um that is where the regulation and the
restrictions and guidelines that are
coming out you just you need to you you
can use them to your advantage in a lot
of way and that is going to be a huge
strategic advantage of keeping your
business Nimble and able to react to
these changes that will more than likely
over time open up opportunities for your
business to flourish
yeah I would I would add to that too in
order to be flexible and to be and what
I've seen in the market with all the
clients that I've worked with over the
years
um those who are most focused in the
beginning tend to be the most successful
because if you want you may only have
one really fantastic product but it's
going rules are going to change
um you know your formulation is going to
change you're going to have personal
turnovers so you might get really
excited in the beginning I want to do a
whole line of products but that's 10 you
know that's multiple times the
complexity so staying really focused in
the beginning on doing one thing really
well and perfecting that before
replicating is also a lesson that I
learned early on oh that's I mean again
going back to Canada there's a lot of
chasing of shiny pennies
um you know we started in craft
cultivation that's still sort of our
hero product in a lot of ways with the
brand Quest but that gave us them
permission to go out and then we got
into the Vape category and then you know
there's a a nice line in sanction into
some other you know categories and sort
of doing things one of those time in a
way you know allowed us to stay focused
but also you know
build the businesses in such a way where
it can then sustain some more complexity
yeah I can I can double that I mean
Bovada is really just a one-trick pony
right we only have one product in
different variations but that's it so
for us the challenge was you know you
build it for let's say like a
recreational Market all of a sudden you
have customers that are in the medicinal
Market
and he's like oh they have moisture
regulations you have to build around
that and they have GMP and all these
type of things for instance for us a U.S
company and we we Source everything
United States will never be EU GMP
because all of our supplies would also
have to be eugnp since we Source United
States we can't do it so we'll have to
build a production line over here to
achieve that and so on and so on and so
on so
um but yet still GMP FDA GMP so there's
ways around it some places
um but you know but the focus Point what
you what you guys mentioned I think is
very important right you have to be
really good in your core service or
product right all right so how do you so
you have a product or service
the next thing is you're not alone
right so how do you differentiate
I mean my perspective on it is one of
the things that we've done really well
is customer service
um you know to me it's making sure you
have a really great product
um that serves you know and basically
serves a consumer need and consumer
tensions but it's followed up with
customer service I think those who are
in you know sort of more emerging I call
them Emerging Markets like Germany and
Australia and the UK and some of the
others that that are making headlines
um unfortunately what a lot of Canadian
LPS are doing or or or or kind of other
LPS that are exporting into these
markets is they're basically dumping and
running essentially they've made the
sale they've got product move over and
then it's kind of wiped their hands and
and move on
servicing your customer and that like
that's it sounds like so basic but it's
amazing how much that is not done and
understanding and being there for them
and following up and problem solving
when things don't go right because let's
face it it's cannabis and it's a very
fickle plant you know and and every once
in a while something is going to go
wrong and it's how you back that up by
being there and being Partners in what
you're doing and actually making sure
that you provide that great service so
to me that that is the second way to
stand out is having exceptional product
that is consistent as you can get that
is innovative in addressing consumers
needs and then following it up with
customer service and just doing what you
say you're going to do and
um you know that seems to be a very
novel Concept in cannabis
and yeah and I think it's funny right
listening to Adam
um you're looking at it from the plan
perspective and bringing the plant into
a product that you then sell to
customers and it's it's a very similar
story for us uh you know that's that's
so funny I mean we have as a product we
have a product That's Unique worldwide
we have patents and we have IP to
protect that and protect it into the
future but that's the core of it right
then on top of that the focus is on
delivering that consistent product in
our case it's those greenhouses to our
customers a big thing that we realized
early on is also customer service
because when you build a facility like
this
um you can't just
run away after that customers do not
know how to run it so we started
essentially incorporating into our
contracts a
an offering that we stay engaged with
our customers to make sure that they get
what they bought from us with regards to
the outcome how that environment is
controlled how those rooms and those
systems are functioning and
um and it's the same story right it's
just I mean we're doing a completely
different business and we're supplying
cannabis Growers but the story behind it
the business terms are very similar
yeah do you want to add something
no I'm fine so I don't know just because
I I
so it's customer service it's probably
not just limited to the Cannabis
industry per se that's more like a
general truth I reckon unless you wanted
to say something else he's like no
customer service sucks don't do it
um is that is that kind of like also
like the pathway into like real Customer
Loyalty because that's what we're all
looking for right we want loyal
customers
starting maybe all right okay sure so um
in in my area we we provided B2B
services but I also worked with a number
of customers that had
um
product I watched the product
development process of companies so I
saw them from the formulation stage
through the development stage
um and I saw which products were
successful and which were not and I
think
of course the quality point is most
important you know you have quality of
focus on one product and really getting
that feedback from customers
um I would just I would just say that
it's it's it is like virtually any other
products that that's really what it
comes down to is making sure you're
really hyper focused on the customer and
as as it comes to the competitors uh I
think if you if you really focused on
your customer listen to your customer
and if they go to a competitor ask them
why did they go to that competitor and
work with them from that way really
develop those relationships so yeah it's
customer service
I would actually take that another a
step further and again that's from
personal experience but but you can look
at customer service as part of a p l and
say you know I've got to be profitable
right and I'm gonna you know put a
number in there and and once I've once
I've used up that number I'm done right
um that doesn't work in an industry like
cannabis where
where the mistakes are being made right
I mean Adam just mentioned it we know
that there are suppliers there's you
know problems with the builders and in
our case there's different regulations
in different countries and knowledge
that's there or not there
um if we don't engage with our customers
Beyond just looking at a p l and just
saying look it doesn't matter this
customer needs to be successful
um then we will not survive and I would
go that far
and I mean customer service sounds so
you know cliche but it just is not
happening in a very meaningful way in
cannabis I don't think and I think parts
of the problems that you see in some
cannabis companies failing is that the
folks in the c-suite who are making
decisions aren't aware of what's being
said about their product about their
business
um and you know it it just it goes such
a long way like you know myself and our
head of marketing product who's here
with me today we used to answer the the
customer emails that's on the label of
every one of our products we used to
personally do that that's not scalable
for us to do that all the time but it's
still an inbox in our Outlook that we
look at every single day to understand
what when stuff is going wrong what are
consumers saying and then how can we fix
that or is there an opportunity in these
things and it's it's amazing when you
actually respond back and say hey you're
right that's not great here's how I'm
going to fix this for you or you know we
you know have customer you know big
customer in Israel where we ship our
product you know something wasn't
looking or feeling right and flew over
there the next day and walked them you
know walked through it and you know made
a solution that that fit for everybody
and so you have to go above and beyond
to support it because they'll remember
that and it becomes easier when things
you know don't go right all the time
that you can overcome them and you're
not losing a piece of business and so it
sounds really simple but just showing up
and being there and doing what you're
going to say it's a very simple business
but it's also not being done enough in
cannabis and I think that's also what is
really hurting our our industry as well
with with some less than I say quality
actors yeah if I could add to that too
it may be that we're not budgeting
customer service the way we should we're
putting in this big marketing budget
maybe it's 10 15 20 you know revenue is
marketing but what is marketing
marketing is keeping the existing
customers happy and perhaps that's a gap
that we're not really focused on on
investing into the customer service area
all right so it's
to summarize it's kind of like a simple
business and a complicated regulated
world right I mean I think that's fair I
mean in in a lot of ways it has been
over
uh or may have been made overly complex
like don't get me wrong it is a
tremendously complex and capital
intensive business like there's there's
no question but I think in all that it's
very easy to get lost
uh in the fundamentals right or or have
the fundamentals be lost of
really damn good product big addressable
Market service your customer well like
there's no secret I'm not saying
anything revolutionary here but I think
because it moves so quick because the
regulations can be very confusing and
changing all the time and there's a
whole bunch of different Theses and
approaches to this industry that those
key elements can really get lost and
um if you do those things well
um you know then then I think you can
really be successful and and I you know
I think decibel is a great example is
we're profitable we're growing we're
cash flowing and there's not really any
Canadian licensed producers out there
that can really say the same
yeah we were joking which was like oh
you're that one profitable company in
Canada Okay so
um because time is running low
are there any questions from the
audience now's a chance
no you have taught them everything they
need to know you think good job good
well thank you all for being here thank
you everybody on the panel
thank you