yeah thank you very much welcome to our
panel about cannabis extraction my name
is Michael Knott I'm a freelance
journalist author of and author of The
so far only book in German language
about cannabis extraction which is this
one
and so I felt competent to moderate this
panel and have a lot of four very
competent guests from the Cannabis
industry
and I want to start I have to look at my
note I'm sorry I want to start with the
president of the decimal decimal
engineered systems which is the
oregon-based market leader in commercial
extraction system for cannabis and hemp
Jonah Baba welcome and Jonah could you
tell us about the background of your
company what are you doing what's your
everydays business
oh
yeah so we actually started back in 2012
from an analytical cannabis uh testing
standpoint we helped set the standards
for uh testing hemp and cannabis in the
U.S and then we actually started making
CO2 equipment based off of test results
just to have more consistency and
repeatability implementing Automation
and then we've continued to evolve with
to ethanol hydrocarbon distillation
isolation with a focus on automation for
more repeatability less Manpower and
then now a focus of course on compliancy
of EU GMP
thank you very much
next to Jonah we have Nick the last uh
hello
thank you very much you founded
collaboris in 2019 which is uh um for a
medical distribute of leading
manufacturer foreign services for
specializing on the medical cannabis
sector so what's your daily business
when it comes to extraction or how are
you connected with the extraction
business yeah we represent a very
reputable manufacturer for extraction
for CO2 extraction from Europe
and we like to propose this as the main
proposal from our company combined with
a closed system for winterization and
the waxing
other than that of course we can offer
other extraction methods like ethanol
like water extraction or even Vapor
static which is a new thing for us but
our main proposal is the CO2 extraction
with a closed system for winterization
and the waxing coming after that and
here company cannabreeze is based in
Greece as well yeah it's based in Athens
Greece
as you know we have a local medical
cannabis framework and some Investments
happening and in Greece you need to do
everything from cultivation processing
packaging and you need to have a
facility that does everything so that
was one of the motivations for us to
offer all the solutions for the
cultivation to extraction to packaging
in order to help our local projects and
this of course allowed us to enter other
markets like Israel like North Macedonia
that were more mature markets than the
Greek market and of course afterwards we
expanded to Malta Switzerland and
hopefully we're gonna get
towards the West a bit more
very sold the Box Macedonian Market is
already a player in in the game yes of
course uh the company that we represent
has already five or six CO2 extraction
systems working and installed and it's
an active market and it's been growing
up of course you know they're some
facilities that are more successful than
others but it's considered a mature
market for us and it's closed on
neighborhood we can drive there
and it's a big Market actually
thank you Nick come back to that later
next to Nick we have a doctor george
stun Chef did I pronounce it the right
way that's correct thank you very much
you're an entrepreneur and CEO of a very
Innovative cannabis extraction company
uh tell me more about the background of
your company please
Soviet European company out of Bulgaria
25 years experience in Botanical
extraction we got into the Cannabis
industry by accident literally 10 years
ago and we have U.S office of extraction
and sales we're most famous as pure five
extraction Purity in five senses were
known for building system based on a
134a aerosol which is extremely
selective solvent and extracts High
Turpin profile with full carbonide
profile about 85 potency no need for
winterization no need for any
post-processing so that's literally our
biggest advantage in the industry being
there we've seen a lot into the Cannabis
Market
even we make some other systems like
ethanol hexane we really focused on what
gives the best value to the market
and your company is based in
the U.S company is based in Arizona
thank you we have offices in Colorado
Pennsylvania Oregon and California where
we extract also cannabis and hemp the
factory is still in Bulgaria so we built
everything in European Union
interesting and to my left we have Dr
Joe Thompson who already put up a lot of
or enabled a lot of companies to be a
part of the instruction of the
instruction
Bronx in in the USA please tell me more
about your company in the background
yeah so we spent uh basically we got
started in 2014 we have 132
installations total not specifically
only extraction but we do extraction
distillation we have a lot of
chromatography preparative
chromatography where materials company
so we do selective materials our primary
focus these days is just servicing
clinical trials we're doing phase one
phase two clinical trial support CMO
type work and that's been really a good
direction I think for the industry in
general we know that extract action
systems alone are really not not
adequate for you know for the the market
you need to have you need to be able to
refine those you need to be able to
purify them and full contained systems
fully automated systems so our whole
entire approach is a holistic approach
that it really is fully contained
systems basically from extraction all
the way through to isolate from
extraction all the way through to
chromatography 100 contained nobody
touches it and it goes right through
fully CIP system enabled so that you can
clean it out with just the push of the
button so that those are what we're
really working on and and we've been
making those for pharmaceutical
companies primarily so we don't we
haven't serviced the recreational Market
in several years
yes uh thank you very much when it comes
to Germany I maybe have to explain that
we are not on the level like in the U.S
or in Canada when it comes to attraction
because our medical law does not allow
the same extractions or the same
extraction a product for patient as the
U.S or the Canadian law allows so our
extractions here in Germany so far are
limited to 25 in the pharmacy this is
why German companies are not so
experienced in that and we choose a lot
of uh over experts from overseas and
please let me ask Jonah we there are a
lot of different ways to extract
cannabis which is the most popular way
to extract cannabis for a company in
Oregon or in the US
so when it comes to extraction there's
no one perfect extraction method I think
that's important to understand anyone
that's just trying to sell you a
specific piece of equipment without
understanding you know what your
specific needs and goals are is not
going to be set up for success and so I
think the way we approach it
we actually engage with the customer
essentially reverse engineer what their
goals are so we talked to them about
what kind of products do you want to
make what's kind of your through foot
what's your throughput you're looking
for what's your budget what kind of
accreditations do you need and then we
actually reverse engineer the whole
thing essentially TurnKey even if you
need like C1 D1 rooms and all the
equipment all the way from the beginning
extraction all the way to again
distillation or isolation I'd say right
now
in Oregon probably the most popular is
BHO now initially it was CO2 because CO2
was generally recognized as probably the
most safest extraction
jurisdictional and municipalities also
felt most comfortable with that and also
from a customer base just people
thinking it was you know the solvent
with CO2 just made them feel more
comfortable now that the Market's been
more educated and understand that you
know hydrocarbon really isn't dangerous
if done properly that's become more
popular just because of the versatility
as far as being able to do you know you
can do dry fresh frozen you can make
dabs now you can also make shatters and
also vape pens and also distillate so it
really covers a lot of the basis even
from a cost standpoint as well too but
then if customers are gonna then we have
hemp customers though that would like to
make you know do ten thousand pounds a
day and want to make all distal and
isolate and for something like that then
we're going to go like a large ethanol
system so it's really just Project
Specific is how we look at it we're
really try to partner with our customers
to understand their needs and and tailor
something specifically for them
thanks Jonah Nick as a European
extractor would you agree uh why what do
you think why do you think we do in
Europe we mostly do CO2 extraction
sometimes you do ethanol yeah but BHO or
P even p-h-o is not attractive why is
that so from what we've seen so far most
of the requests and most of the
Investments depending at this moment are
with the CO2 extraction method
of course we get requests and they are
investments with the ethanol as a method
it's well established as well but at the
smaller number and now we start to see
some requests for water extraction which
I think is also interesting and a little
bit of vapor static but mainly the
requests we receive is for CO2
extraction much less ethanol and let's
say water extraction is start to picking
up and be part of the discussion which
is quite an established method for the
recreational Market in the U.S in Canada
and we understand the reasons why they
want to approach it and it could be a
cheap solution not an investment a high
investment and it's quick and it uses
water so
may that be maybe because the Terps and
the German or in the European Medical
Market the terpenes do not play a major
role no George would you agree if I if I
say that may be a case because if
terpenes do not play a major role the
method of extraction is not so important
how's the experience in the U.S states
you're working at
yeah one of the things that is important
obviously is the stability of the
extract especially in a GMP setting and
when you have terpenes in the GMP
extract there that is not a stable
extract and so from the standpoint of
GMP it's really not allowed in fact we
know from the FDA trials with sativax
for example which failed what primarily
because of those terpenes that were in
there and the background and the
unknowns that were being generated so
when you think about a clinical a
clinical like a Pharma type a clinical
mindset you're typically looking to get
an extract that's as clean as possible
that's as stable as possible the Shelf
stable and that's why uh it's that's why
it's important to have you know multiple
different means to purify your your
extracts not only to the extracts we can
all talk about different ways to extract
but uh you know ultimately it has to be
purified it has to be formulated like
you said 25 only is allowed that's a
formulated extra right
if we look to Colorado droughts for
example
um is that do which are all do terpenes
play do they play a major role or do
kind of cannabis play the major role
when it comes to extraction
Entourage effect is very important
um usually terpenes are a multiplier
with right serpents in there you really
can turn them out like one plus one
makes four because they really make that
extract more bioavailable and the
turpins they manipulate the cannabinoids
into the proper way I've been talking to
a lot of patients from Oregon and
Colorado when I did the first stage when
they became legal and they recognized
that this drink can help him for this
this thing can help him for that and the
difference in between strain is really
the chirps helping profile they're about
30 000 trips in nature and they're about
300 troops no known in cannabis in
combination between them they amplify
the effect a lot so chirps they play a
major role and
there's a lot to talk about it like uh
looking at U.S markets we've learned a
lot so how that market evolved starting
from uh accrued from like Simpson going
through distillers going through
um
enhanced Botanical extraction like
Botanical terpenes that's all about
experience and adding the right terms
mostly for
um
most of our experience not so much for
medical and but there are new
regulations in California we're going to
talk about that too that regulates the
chirping now but yes chirps to me uh
they play a big role into the Cannabis
experience and they enhance the medical
effects big time thanks uh so we come to
to the next question which goes out to
all panelists in that case is that a
conflict between the patient's demand
and the regulatory when it comes to FDA
or or the German cannabis agency when it
comes to clean clinical studies on the
long term uh the the one the the one
side says we don't need to we cannot
have the terpenes or we we don't want
them because they they don't stabilize
the product and we have an unstable
product but on the other side we have
the patient's demand for herbs how how
can we solve that on the long range
Jonah
you know I think it's important to to
consider the difference of course
between recreational and medical and
when it's medical like here in Germany
typically what we're going to see is the
government's going to be overly cautious
when they're first introducing a new
product or a new market and they want to
be able to have predictive results and
so when you so that's even when it comes
to like diluting and things like that
that way they can identify you know
repeatable experience with the cus with
the patient from that site
and so I think the only way to be able
to handle that would be again where you
can kind of fractionize you know you can
either fractionize different camera
noise get exact percentages and then
even with terpenes now you can do that
and so I think it would have to be again
a very repeatable controlled process for
it to actually you know be acceptable
here you know medically from that site
Joe please well one of the key issues
here is
um you know the fdas and not only the
regulatory bodies they want to be able
to show that uh the placebo effect is
real versus versus a placebo which is
nearly impossible to do because you're
talking about multiple hundreds of
different compounds within the
formulation so from a clinical
perspective or medical perspective
pharmaceutical perspective
those types of things are really have a
real big of a problem and if I'm going
to spend 52 say 50 million dollars to
get a drug through I'm not going to
start with a product that has you know
something in it that's going to degrade
because it's too costly when the FDA
says at the end of it that that's no
good because it's degrading so and then
also the claims themselves what would be
the end point would be the key question
in in a clinical study and that would be
like okay uh okay so this this
particular terpene has a 10x effect with
with a ratio of say THC or CBD okay well
then you have to prove that and versus
placebo so that that from a medical and
pharmaceutical perspective that's really
the the key barrier because the even the
real world data is uh is very convoluted
it's not very very easy to come up with
a real world data that says hey this is
actually working so one of the one of
the great things about the recreational
Market is that you can get clinical real
world data from that as for efficacy
um if if those companies actually
designed their studies to get that data
they could really do a lot better with
their clinical studies
thank you
Nick let me ask a little bit provocative
or provoke to provoke you a little okay
what do you think it would be better to
have two kinds of extracts one without
anything pure cannibal needs just for
the medical side and another one for the
recreational site containing all the
terpenes and other
ingredients which are not in the medical
what do you mean exactly like to have
two different products one two different
for to have the medical Pro product
terpene free so it's a stable product
and to have the recreational product
like full of terpenes yeah like like
full spectrum but to leave the uh to
leave it out of the medical product not
to have conflicts so to speak with the
regulatory site
yeah we can discuss about this it's a
matter of Regulation as we all discussed
before
so if they allow this to happen and we
can have these products in the
creational OR adult Market within Europe
it will be a good scenario for the
market and for the patients or users of
these products
when we're talking about medical
products as we all discussed you need to
be very specific and to have specific
formulation repeatable and tested and
proven
and to have the reasons of why this
formulation is there for what
application
so yes of course I would like to see the
these products to be available in the
European market in any way possible
would that be a solution for the U.S
market top free extracts for patients
George
well everybody knows what Indica is
sativa is and hybrid is it's all
disturbs the chips make a cannabis oil
Indica sativa or hybrid we know that in
marijuana usually 95 is the THC there
are a minor cannabinoids but there are
less than 10 less than five percent
so everything else that defines the the
medicinal values of the extract or how
it works to the human being is based on
the tubing profile I
would say maybe for certain patients
that they have a cancer conditions here
use the distillate or something combined
with Direct cannabinoids in a certain
recipe literally a recipe like CBD to
THC one in one with five percent CBG is
a plural recipe for cancer it's from
some medical institutions and the
reports based on that but for the
general consumer they're going to be
looking for the properties under the
original strains
yeah one of the issues there is just
simply once it becomes a drug like CBD
became a drug in the United States all
of the formulations essentially by the
Regulatory Agencies became it became
adulterated products and that's why
they've been even though they've been on
the market uh they're basically not
allowed to advertise they're not allowed
to have banking they're not allowed to
have all these things that are that a
normal company would have the same thing
is going to happen with THC in the
United States and I think that that will
have a global impact also so I I it
would be really great if there was such
a thing as like a recreational a tasty
version which there has to be there's
going to be no matter what we do from a
clinical standpoint but I think that the
FDA is going to try to you know squash
at least in the U.S the competition yep
um what's the role of the FDA in General
Life Trust uh what's the role of the FDA
in general because as a German I think
it's federally illegal so the FDA
doesn't have to do anything with it but
it's all like this is it
yeah I mean essentially the role of the
FDA is to ensure safety you know for our
consumers in the U.S but where it can be
frustrating of course is you know
they've been talking about having CBD be
um essentially approved by the FDA for
they people thought it'd be three four
five years ago and it still hasn't
happened
oh okay yes from a pharmaceutical side
you're correct but from what people are
talking about as far as being able to
put it in food products and Beverages
and things like that like a lot of
people in the U.S expected it to happen
by now and it hasn't which you know
costs a lot of companies to then you
know go out of business from that site
because they're expecting for that to
happen by now and so but you know so
until the government's actually put the
right budget behind things to do the
studies that they say they're going to
do you know things are just going to be
continuing limbo you know from that side
because it's a drug they're not allowed
to do that without it being adulterated
so the the fact that epidiolex is there
basically makes all that all that
development impossible without going
through the FDA process
uh compared to
overseas in Germany we have very little
use of users of extract
my guess is I don't have the numbers
here but my guess is we have less than
five percent of medical users or even
recreational users using extracts what
are the numbers in the U.S
judge about you you work in a lot of
States how
compared to butts what's the pressure
how many people's consume liquids or a
consumer extracts so United States most
of the users were medical a few years
ago now most of these are recreational
so with that change
we're looking at industry growing as a
gourmet industry we're really literally
cooking for our customers we're
preparing the best experience for them
and
um with that said I see in the last
years vaping is going uh crazy vaping
and eatables versus the flour
would you agree that the fastest growing
sector within the Cannabis industry
Jonah yeah no 100 and we saw that a lot
in Oregon to where initially like early
on it was like 15 16 I think it was
probably about 70 80 flower cells but
now it's I think by 60 70 percent more
oil is what you'll see because the oil
is the Catalyst for all the other
products it's not just the vape pens
it's the Edibles it's the tinctures it's
the creams the lotions topicals and so
yeah it significantly surpassed flower
and we start to see that in all the new
states that come online as well too it's
pretty predictable
Nick what do you think is the future of
extraction in Europe do you think we
will reach the U.S level soon or how do
you see the future of extractions in
Europe yeah hopefully it will get bigger
it has to get bigger I think extracts
are more suited for the pharmacies
in the way they're working in their
applications the final products that
will be available I think they're gonna
see more delivery methods targeting
specific treatments like different like
maybe inhalers of mixed inhalers nasal
sprays this type of final products
and yeah hopefully we're gonna see more
of that
um George
you work in several U.S states
it's the regulation all the same there
or do you have to like okay this this
cultural Colorado this counts for
California or is that is that a big gap
or uh
what are regulations of course they're
different but they're different in a way
of Taxation and on the way of Licensing
everything else seems to be like The
Branding is allowed like if you have a
brand in one state that can propagate to
all the states that are legal which
pretty much provides same quality of
extract everywhere but again every state
has a different policy and Taxation and
Licensing which is the biggest
difference
you know uh in the United States uh
certainly
um basically the FDA has just issued
eight DEA licenses
um that's the first federally federally
allowed licenses for the production of
um for the production basically of drugs
and I think that that is going to
eclipse the multi-state operator model
uh within five years
um simply because once those drugs get
through the FDA then the FDA will have
action against the states and we'll kind
of see them Flex their muscles on that I
I think that that's what's coming so
again the federally the the federal
illegal stuff that's happening in the
states is is is probably on its last
legs I think in the next five years I
think uh definitely we're going to have
the FDA running the show and that's the
way it's been in the United States I
think it's going to continue to be that
way uh with with these drugs which makes
be comfortable by final question I think
this step is the most important I will
give the Cannabis industry a very very
big push when the when it's the it's
medical legal Federal in the U.S do you
think this will still happen on the
Biden
uh yeah it looks like it's going to be
rescheduled sometime in September or
November or September based on we work
with five of the eight uh licensees
right now and uh we've worked with the
DEA which is the Drug Enforcement
Administration directly so yeah that's
going to happen and that will have a
ripple effect around the world for sure
would you agree it's again James
it's federally illegal as a medicine
I wish I don't know that's uh that
protest never really happened we've been
talking about in the last two years
um but I see that really the the biggest
problem is yes FDA is going to need to
take a call on the doses because they
need to issue proper doses for
everything uh for different ages I guess
there are different Kickbacks in every
state how do we Market how do we license
how do we do all those details now in
California like two weeks ago they shoot
another
um
another limitation you cannot even you
cannot Market
strains and products with uh
kids attractive names like candies like
uh you know all these things they're
going to be a lot of limit when that
gets
um Fairly Legal they're going to be a
lot of limitations I don't know if
they're ready to do that in this fall if
they're ready
um they're probably gonna do it
thank you very much my last question
goes to Nick and Nick we don't hear so
much for Greece we hear a lot about
Europe Europe but from Greece on federal
level uh do you think they will ease up
a cannabis loss also for medical uh
cannabis in Greece soon we already have
a framework that has been around for
five years but you don't have so many
patients we have zero patients I know so
yeah we are preparing the framework we
are preparing the way these products are
gonna enter the Greek pharmacies there
is being some moves from some big
players on how this will happen in
combination with the
how it's called the pharmaceutical the
classic pharmaceutical companies that
deliver these products
and of course the main question is when
and how many and how easy it will become
to become a patient and to actually have
access to this product which I think
this goes not only for Greece but it
goes for all Europe and maybe the
previous questions that you asked about
FDA hopefully what you say is going to
happen in September and I think this
will allow Europe will allow maybe
Germany to move a bit faster and without
being afraid of FDA and then if Germany
moves forward then I think the rest of
the Europe will follow that so I see it
a little bit like Europe is waiting for
FDA Germany is waiting for that and the
rest of Europe is waiting for Germany
thank you very much and I also think the
FDA move would be a game changer also
for Germany because uh also money trans
money transactions will be legal on
International level and this will be if
the can chamber thank you very much of
to all panelists or the experts
thank you again Michael