well thanks everybody
um good morning I just want to start off
by thanking ICBC for inviting me to to
speak I think this is my fifth or sixth
time here
um today I'm going to talk about some of
the economics of of cannabis I'm first
going to talk a little bit
about
the global market and then the US market
and then uh do a little bit of a deep
dive into the German Market
um so
um a little bit about Whitney economics
we're a global leader in business data
economic research as well as Consulting
both in the adult use and Medical Market
but also in the in the industrial
cannabis or hemp Market
um and so we have clientele all over
the world and practically every
continent except for of course
Antarctica we're trying but uh
um
so in terms of the global Marketplace
there's over 70 countries now that have
some form of access to cannabis either
adult use medical or some type of
cannabinoids CBD
Etc
and the reason for this reform
is different from country to Country to
Country some want Economic Development
someone access and re to medicines some
people want Alternatives
but those reform is taking an
accelerated Pace now
I mean so it's good to see
um in on a combined basis the Cannabis
industry is about a trillion dollar
Global industry a lot of this is driven
by Industrial Hemp but then you've also
got the medical and adult use and so
it's about one-third cannabis two-thirds
hemp and
um so right now the U.S is driving a lot
of the narrative they're driving the the
policies at the UN level
International
but the market in the United States is
so dysfunctional
that there's a possibility that the
European
blog could displace the U.S as a global
leader in driving direction and reform
uh globally
and so here's a U.S update what we did
here is we've tracked the the U.S market
and then we projected out the growth a
lot of the growth is coming from the new
markets that are deploying
um last year surprisingly to some 10
states out of the you know 38 that are
have deployed some type of legal
cannabis
10 states actually showed negative
growth and so but nonetheless overall
the market eked out some some growth
we're forecasting 12 growth this year
and then it should really take off by
2025.
um the reason for the sluggish growth
last year was that there was a return to
work a return to school people didn't
have as much opportunity to consume
cannabis and as a result of that the
demand shifted back down to pre-covered
levels and then there was a change in
consumer Behavior
typically in the U.S the consumer would
spend about the same amount each time
that they go to a dispensary or retail
outlet but with all the narrative about
inflation
about potential recessions and like
um they write in the August September
time frame they pulled back their
spending
um and there was a downward shift in the
basket amount that they spent each time
that they go to the to the retail outlet
and so that really impacted the market
and took down
um you know the overall demand now even
with that our forecast accuracy was 93
so we didn't do that bad of a job it was
98 the year before so we have a pretty
good pulse on what's going on in the U.S
market
um but
um we're not going to going to see much
growth
um you know in the you know until 2025
and then it'll really take off
so
um you know we we've forecasted the
European market on a total addressable
Market basis this is the total number of
consumers elicit legal it doesn't matter
and then we applied a spending pattern
to that and then we projected out what
the total demand is
um it's a pretty sizable Market it's
actually the second largest market
um by spends but it's you know a pretty
small Market relative to you know other
markets like Africa or Asia
um but there there's a lot of
examination of reforms a lot of interest
and if the German market and the Czech
market and their policies if they team
up then they could really be the
Catalyst and further reform and growth
in the European market
so here's just a total addressable
Market it's a pretty sizable Market
five countries really dominate it may be
surprising that Italy is up there that's
based upon some un data that shows the
total number of consumers that actually
have used cannabis in the previous year
so they had higher consumption patterns
than in in other countries
um but nonetheless it's a real sizable
market and
um depending upon if you use the UN data
which has some limitations on it or if
you use our data we actually show that
there's more consumers than what the UN
is saying
um and also there's potential of 150
million consumers if you expand the
market out to like Russia and other
periphery countries within the EU
now back in 1850 little history lesson
um the Czech Republic and Germany got
together and they defined the the
regulations or standards for Pilsner
beer
and that became the de facto standard
for the rest of the world and there's an
opportunity here for Germany and the
Czech Republic who are both considering
reforms to do the same thing and set the
standard for the rest of Europe but
right now is there enough motivation
right now is there going to be a
champion Within These markets to do so
the jury's still out on that and
um you know from the briefings earlier
um or yesterday and the like
um it's there's a reason to be
optimistic and there's a reason to be
pessimistic
um now last year I presented some data
on what the ramp would look like if they
deployed full Federal legalization in
Germany and the um ramp actually was and
we look at things in terms of the
percentage of legal capture the amount
of participation in the legal markets
and like
and the the ramp scenario for Germany
last year was
um that they would have a greater
capture than the U.S but a little bit
less than Canada so a pretty successful
ramp
um that was based upon last year's
policies though and those policies have
since changed so the demand has been
significantly shifted downward the
percentage of legal participation has
been shifted downward as well and so
it's really cut the legs off of this
market
and so I think that's important when
you're looking at this from a business
perspective and you're trying to find
where the opportunities are to see this
potential growth last year and now not
so much then it really plays a role in
your decision making on Market entry
strategies and the like
and so here's an a revenue projection
and so
um you know I appreciate the the efforts
of metric and their presentation
um they did they do a really good job
um we take a little bit different
approach where we look at the legal
markets and we've mapped out all these
ramps and then we look at the regulatory
structures in each one of these markets
and the as a result of this shift to the
Social Clubs it's really
um pulled down the potential forecasts
through 2030
um and so for example this is roughly a
you know four billion dollar market by
2030. it's now an 800 million dollar
market so that's a pretty significant
haircut just based upon policies
um I think it's important to note also
that
um
you know although there's been a
downward shift in the market
um in the market projections
um one has to be prepared for another
shift another pivot in this space and
really be ready to ramp at a rapid Pace
um so in terms of German Supply
requirements so
um the total addressable Market requires
you know about 950
000 kilos of cultivated output and
that's output that's required for not
only flower and pre-rolls but for your
Edibles and your tinctures and your
extracts and all that so 950 000
um it's a pretty sizable Market
but as we can see
there's really
there's I don't think right now at this
point that there's enough capacity
online to support the demand even at the
lower numbers and so the orange was the
um the ramp scenario from last year and
the requirements and at that time I said
I put out some warnings to the German
government and I said hey look I don't
think you have enough capacity and it's
going to take time to ramp and you're
going to inhibit your growth and the
amount of conversion of the consumers
but even with the lower downward
revisions based upon the Social Clubs
I'm still skeptical that there's enough
capacity online
to support you know this this potential
ramp but we'll see I mean the jury's
still out
so implications so with a slower rollout
the business opportunities are smaller
um but there's still opportunities there
and so you really have to be strategic
and use data in order to ascertain where
the markets are what the potential are
and then be prepared to scale and
because of the fact that there's a
limited amount of Supply
you know there's opportunities there to
to fill that void
and the success of a regulated rollout
depends upon three variables there's
Supply if you have enough Supply and if
you have enough Supply then prices are
moderate they come down it incentivizes
a consumer the consumers are very price
dependent they're they look at price and
they'll participate in the legal Market
if there's an incentive to do so they're
willing to pay a premium
um just as long as the premium is not
too much and so price is another one of
those factors that plays a role and the
amount of legal participation and then
access and so if you have a lot of
retail outlets there's a lot of legal
participation and so if you have a
reasonable product a lot of access you
have reasonable Supply then that's a
successful scenario for a launch but if
you
a regulatory rollout so but if you don't
have one or two of those factors then
it's going to be problematic and it'll
it won't
um eliminate the legal conversions by
consumers it'll just slow it down
dramatically and so you know this could
turn very quickly so if you get more
access and more clubs and more retail
potential then there could be
um you know a quick turn in the in the
overall market and increased
opportunities
um so I'd be remiss if I didn't talk a
little bit about in the industrial side
of cannabis there's a strong Market in
the EU for industrial hemp I put
together this chart a while ago but it
still seems to resonate with people
there's applications in traditional
markets
to convert over to hemp on a more
sustainable basis a lot of um you know
incentives on the ESG side and so the
environment only friendly bringing in
more opportunities for minority
communities and the like and so even
with just a modest conversion
you know there's a lot of it's a sizable
market for in the industrial
applications now in Germany
you know there's the automotive industry
BMW already uses I think 20 of their
cars are made from Parts um derived from
hemp and so there's already this
conversion going on
um and this is could accelerate in the
area of fibers for construction
materials for plastic Replacements
plant-based Plastics and the like
um and so there's a lot of potential to
the hemp market and the EU right now is
kind of taking the lead displacing the
US they're taking the lead with regard
to hemp policy and so my firm has
country reports for 27 countries in in
Europe on the Cannabis Market looks at
rules and regulations on the industrial
side as well as adult use and medical
side
and so you know when it comes to
regulatory rollouts you know like I
mentioned price access
Supply it's really important to have
that
um and a lot of times Regulators will
copy and paste from other
um rollouts in other countries other
states and sometimes they bring in
policies that haven't worked in previous
markets
um and so it's really important to be
mindful when deploying the regulations
to make sure that you meet multiple
goals such as Public Safety as well as
presenting and providing a good healthy
business environment but right now
There's an opportunity to displace the
U.S in terms of of cannabis policy but
it's going to take a little bit more
work by the federal Regulators in
Germany
and so in terms of the industry
um as as stakeholders in this space it's
really important to communicate not only
with Regulators but amongst yourselves
developed networks
um set expectations that are reasonable
relative to the market size and data
plays a real big role in that
um and you know don't get too far out
over your skis there's examples out of
Canada examples out of the United States
and other markets where they built too
much capacity didn't have enough and
drove up their costs and the prices
crashed and they didn't have a good cost
control and so they weren't making any
money so it's really important to be
disciplined and look at your cost
structure and like it's also important
because cannabis is so localized
cannabis policy is so localized it's
important to act locally but to think on
a global basis for example in the United
States friends the cost per gram to
produce cannabis runs 25 cents to 50
cents a gram uh in some countries the
wholesale price is a pentagram and so as
soon as the international markets open
up this could be a serious threat to the
U.S market and so it's important to be
mindful of where you know things are
going on around the world just as much
as it's important to track things going
on locally
and so you know in terms of the future
if Germany does become the first Major
Market in Europe to roll this out
um uh they have a potential to really
shape the market
um even on the hemp side and but given
the fact that this is now home grow and
Social Clubs don't expect significant
increases in legal usage there's just
not going to be enough Supply there's
just not going to be enough access
but once policies change then there's
going to be an opportunity for
Accelerated growth so it's important to
plan for that time and I think also
there's an opportunity here for Canada
tourism people come to Germany to
consume in the clubs if they are able
and but that will be short-lived because
once reform takes hold across the EU
sector then they'll be less and less
kind of Tourism because they'll have
access to cannabis in their home country
um
and then also look for prices to really
normalize once the rollouts are complete
and once you get more capture because
initially because of the limited amount
of Supply you'll have you'll keep higher
prices and so once Supply normalizes and
is in equilibrium with the with the
demand then prices will normalize and
they'll ship downward it happens in
every Market
um
I think yeah so in some there's great
potential here uh there's a little less
potential than there was a year ago
um but uh you know who knows there could
be additional
um uh opportunities as uh things evolve
and so I just want to thank you again
here's my contact information
we've got data on every country we ramp
the we look at ramps in every state
every country we have a lot of data a
lot of insights and so happy to help you
out so thank you very much
awesome