good afternoon thank you everybody for
joining today
um as the introducer said my name is
Atia and I'm going to let the panel
introduce himself so we'll start off
with sunny
hi good afternoon everybody I'm Sony
managing partner of cultivators out of
the Netherlands and we help The Growers
and investors from business ID towards
cultivation and cultivation support
that's a short video
my name is Lucas targos I am the VP of
control environment AG at urban grow I
formerly was a commercial vegetable
grower turned to cannabis grower and now
have worked for urban growth for about
eight years we really specialize in full
design build projects specifically on
cultivation facilities
hello my name is Sabrina Carvalho and I
am the Cannabis specialist developing r
d for Phillips lighting
hi everyone I'm Darren Kaplan I'm a
senior consultant for sustanza Global
we're a consulting company that focuses
on the design and operation of of
cannabis facilities around the world and
we're based in Canada
and my backgrounds come Academia and
also a grower so kind of both the
science and the Practical aspect of
growing
a wonderful good afternoon my name is
Timo I'm the general manager of fluence
fluence is a Horticulture lighting
company and we are all happy to be here
thanks Timo
um so chatting about Innovations in
cannabis cultivation is obviously a very
large topic so we wanted to kind of
start off talking with the very early
phases of development which is
propagation and tissue culture so we'll
start off with what are some of the
major advancements that you've seen
maybe in the last year or so in that
field of both sourcing fantastic
genetics and the technologies that we
can use to ensure that we have a great
start to the grow
well
well maybe I give it a start I'll take
the advantage
ladies first well one of the advances
that actually we ourselves worked on is
on recipes specifically used for
propagation and tissue culture So
currently we have
rolled out the recipes of LEDs specific
to improve propagation
we managed to improve propagation in all
aspects of it from speeding when it's
difficult from
situations like Germany where you cannot
use rooting hormones it is a challenge
we created recipes for that that Growers
can use and we find that we are well at
least that one we are very proud of
bringing to the market
um but genetics indeed also very
important working with breathers is very
important having bad genetics for
rooting can kill your business so yes
Choose Wisely if you go for it and now I
would say is also very important
yeah
um yeah on my side I would say that
we're seeing a lot more of
um desire to have tissue culture labs
and practices within the facilities on
the early stages it's definitely become
an evolution
um and and a lot more standards around
tissue culture for cannabis specifically
which I think is it's very good and
um you know I think as most people know
there's there's certain viruses that are
kind of working their way through the
industry right now and tissue culture
provides a very
helpful Safety Net in that so I think
that whether it's a retrofit or or
you're looking at you know building your
first facility uh allocating that space
to some sort of tissue culture ability
tissue culture lab
um Can can de-risk a lot within the
facility and then also provide that
genetic security there as well too and
maybe in addition that you also have the
possibility to have the back up at
another location right so from a
business model it makes you a little bit
more resilient and if you have a problem
that you have maybe somewhere back up so
I think that makes a lot of sense yeah
because if you Outsource it what
happened what a lot of people try to do
is the risk for getting something in
from the supply you buy it from so that
is for me always a risk factor that have
it on your own you you can really
preserve that things go wrong like
getting in let them over it in for
example
you know in a way tissue culture
nowadays when I talk to Growers many of
us we create varieties that we love they
are unique to us and we find that that
is amazing variety that I managed to
create right
tissue culture to me for this type of
love for a specific variety for whatever
reason you like it is your safety net
you can have it now and in 10 years from
now
you can always go back to it it's safe
so I find that at least for even from
the most unique varieties to scale up
production tissue culture has its place
for this aspect of innovation you can
always go back to it many of the Growers
that we talk to they actually say oh the
variety that I had or that somebody had
and that we lost tissue culture will
even in the future can you imagine
having a library of a collection of
breeds that I can a hundred years ago
somebody used and we can still look at
it
and it's becoming yes more and more
important this past couple years with
very much yes you mentioned the virus
The Hop Lane thyroid is probably one of
the biggest concerns with cannabis
Growers right now and in Canada
specifically it's maybe 90 of the
facilities I've heard numbers around
there are infected and once your
genetics are infected if your mother's
stock is infected it's there might not
even be a way of getting rid of it no
yeah having tissue culture reserves is
kind of one of your only ways of really
securing your genetics so yeah I believe
tissue culture is the only way to rid
the facility of it and it's a very scary
virus too because it's
um from what we're seeing right now
stable
um even in water which is that's right
um yes and even traditional tissue
culture if you're doing nodal culture
it's not effective yeah so you need to
be doing meristem culture which takes a
long time and it doesn't always work so
starting with clean stock yeah exactly
so I think it's less of a fear fear
tactic and more of a reality necessity
backups yeah when we started seeing
tissue culture in Canada in 2018 I
worked at one of the earliest tissue
culture facilities it was just an
internal lab for ourselves but it was
very hot and heavy at that time everyone
was very interested and then everyone
got a little bit less excited about it
because it's not a fully proven method
it's not cookie cutter cop and paste I
can't just take my protocols and use
them for the 700 cultivars you want to
work with so it requires a lot of time
effort and expertise which is something
that was not as readily available in the
industry and money you know it's not
something that you can just pump a
couple hundred thousand dollars into and
be for sure guaranteed all the cultivars
are going to work so that's really
interesting for me to see in the last
year or two is kind of the the rise of
tissue culture again because it's become
an absolute necessity using a continual
mother clone system indefinitely with no
backup and having cannabis grown at a
commercial level where it's never been
grown before and hasn't been bred
specifically for resistances to a
variety of pests and viruses it means
that it's something that everyone should
be looking at in their cultivation
strategy if you're not it's very risky
like Sabrina said you could breed
something for a very long time have a
fantastic genetic and then lose it in
the matter of a few months so I think
that's a really big area that I'm glad
to see Europe actually I feel has been
more on the Forefront of that there are
very few European clients that I have
that have not already begun their
strategy with tissue culture either
internally or looking for somebody to
Source it and do it externally so I
think that's been a really big
Improvement
um along the lines of kind of moving
past our tissue culture and propagation
phase moving into kind of cultivation a
mix of both veg and flour there's a
number of questions there one I wanted
to start off with is environmental
sustainability so as we all know
cannabis is bashed very often for not
being the most environmentally
sustainable industry especially when
you're doing indoor cultivation which is
predominantly what I work in it's very
power heavy and those of us in Europe
who have felt the increase in power
prices in the last year we can really
attest to that so I wanted to know what
if anyone has seen anything very
interesting along the lines of more
environmental sustainability in
basically any of your flower cultivation
projects
yes
and I think that's only at least can
also say that yes
let's put it this way I I don't know a
lot about a lot about other regions but
in European Union you have two things
one is the rules of a country and then
the rules of European Union
we all know that European Union will
become more strict on how much energy we
can spend whether we like it or not we
need to be sustainable growing our crops
independent of what it is the
Netherlands for example is already
starting to apply that and planning to
apply it even more fiercely and we are
talking about
situations where they say we will only
support with subsidies or discounts or
whatever else if you fulfill this energy
gap if you go over it you will not be
supported you will not and can you
imagine
everybody here is going to kill me for
that but doesn't matter
um tomato right now high high okra yes
the Netherlands is sporting sustainable
measures of if you want to be supported
you will need to be within this energy
gap and every single grower that has
been doing this for years is asking how
do we even hit this target
if they would put anywhere near to that
Target to cannabis right now we would be
in trouble
so we all need to start thinking of our
projects of how can we make it more
sustainable in numbers not even even for
spending less money of hours but
accounting already that if you're going
to do that in Europe you will have these
coming sooner or later so we better
prepare to how low can we go with our
energies and so on to get a good crop a
balance crop what can we do together to
lower it because this they will come
these rules will come it's it's just a
matter of time and for us if we can get
on the front line of saying
we know how low we can get and European
Union can say okay hopefully soon they
will say we will listen and we will
consider those if we can have that
influence great that's how I see it
European Union will always come with
rules on them sooner or later yeah but
it's not only the the energy it's also
water yes like in in Netherlands we
already have an Horticultural world the
zero emission law by 2027 so from that
moment Growers cannot
discharge any water anymore so all the
water they are using and coming back
from the rain they need to disinfect and
reuse so it's not only the energy part
by yeah you guys with with fluence and
Phillips work on and reducing the energy
costs it is also all the other sources
we use to grow our plants and it's not
really a common practice for cannabis
Growers to recirculate no it's not it's
complicated and also with the way that
cannabis Growers have learned to grow
with specific brands of fertilizer and
products if you're recirculating your
nutrient solution you have to readjust
specific elements and it's not an easy
thing to do if you don't understand each
component of your fertilizer that you're
using so it's I think it's a lot of
learning and a lot of learning from
what's happening in Europe and in the
Netherlands because it's been happening
for a long time yeah yeah so we we work
on the Wastewater management side a lot
and it's been a long road and I think
the biggest difficulty is that in a lot
of cannabis fertilizer regimenes you see
two things that are very difficult from
a recirculation is high heavy metals and
a lot of organic materials which make UV
um not not as effective to get the
transmission through so we've had to
really play around with a lot of
different Technologies mainly I would
say the one that is really making moves
through the entire Horticulture industry
is Ozone as a very well wave of
disinfecting water and then we also talk
about a lot on the the condensate
recapture as well too so recapturing
recapturing all the condensate that's
being produced from the HVAC from the
facility
um and you know utilizing pretty some
pretty simple ways believe it or not
that's that that is very clean water but
it's so clean it's too clean
um so it's very easy to end up getting
biological growth within there so
um it's something that I think is going
to be a large part of the evolution of
the industry because as you mentioned
with a recirculating system there's a
lot of commercial Horticultural
practices that need to be taken place in
order to have those systems operate
properly I will say that we've been able
to kind of make a hybrid and a lot of
times bring in more of a blending system
to where we're actually blending that
recirculation with a direct inject
system to allow us to kind of have a
happy happy medium right closed yeah
exactly well to add on that I think that
for example nowadays cannabis Growers
Focus indeed on breeding to a specific
Niche choices of looks smells and so on
but I think that the true Innovation
will come when we mix that with
efficiency choosing the varieties that
also bring the efficiency into account
we can have really nice varieties but we
have to have the notion that they are
very expensive to run we have clients
asking us I am from light but we have
clients asking us to actually increase
light to a light level to achieve a
yield that they want with this
particular variety while we prefer to
actually look at it and ask can we breed
something similar but that operates at a
reasonable level
because we can't keep going higher and
higher even biologically these plants
cannot take everything they are amazing
plants they are very flexible but they
cannot take everything
and one of the things that also clients
of ours and of all of us are suffering
from is that technology is advancing
many of these breeds they were bred for
sunlight for HPS for
whatever it was being used in each
region and LEDs are a technology that
pushes these plants much harder it's is
unique
but breeds need to keep up with that we
have technology sometimes that for us is
innovative but is waiting for the other
Innovations to come in breathing is one
of those we only now are not starting
it's it's whether we like it or not for
this capacity and scale out we only now
are starting on the efficiency of having
good crops that can handle a reasonable
level so I I think that breathing will
change a lot of the techniques and will
help another a lot of the technologies
that we have and that we are developing
work better as well but yeah working
with breeders is important on that as
well I would say maybe the common look
as you mentioned about heavy metals that
that can be also a problem thing that
also starts with making the right
choices for your starting order your
your fertilizers so use high quality
brands for fertilizers and for
substrates so that you don't get it into
a system and then I agree if you have it
then it's difficult to get out of it of
course yeah yeah and I think there's
there's been luckily has been definitely
a movement around from where we were
back in the day of you know shelf bought
liquid fertilizers that are extremely
expensive not that I'm bashing on them
but
um there's a better route right and you
get better quality better consistency
um and you'll see that both in the
product but also in your systems just in
everyday use
yeah and so from facility design that's
super important so when you are
designing your cannabis facility I think
everyone knows in this industry it's
really important to be flexible and it's
really important to understand even if
you're in an Emerging Market there are
more developed Markets Canada being
example certain countries in Europe
where you can look at the lessons
learned and make sure that you have the
ability to Pivot that's what I always
encourage my clients to do have the
ability to be flexible and malleable as
the market progresses and so with your
facility design I have a client and they
did you know direct you know water to
waste because they said their water was
really cheap and I said it's not about
just the price of the water that you
make these decisions that's not the
guiding force and surprise surprise the
government has now said that they cannot
put all of their water into waste but we
don't have any space to put a
recirculating system so this is one of
the fun little challenges but it's
really important to work with really
experienced Developers for facilities
that will tell you your options and let
you know why you should do these things
and why you should have these options
available but not only water and power
we were just talking about you know the
things you actually put into your
products so cannabis is very garbage and
garbage out if you don't use good
quality lights if you don't use good
quality substrate fertilizers Etc you
don't get I would say the robustness of
that genetic you're really not doing
yourself any favors you're not getting
the full capacity so
um there's also been a lot of questions
regarding substrates in particular and
the environment sustainability of things
like rock wool and cocopeat and things
along those lines so have you had a lot
of clients or any projects they've been
working on where you found that you're
kind of battling with them about making
the more sustainable choice for their
own kind of betterment in the long term
but they're kind of maybe hung up on a
practice they've had previously and not
really willing to let it go
um nine out of ten yeah
I think I think cannabis is pretty good
on the uh let's say the Kobo for example
a lot of cannabis Growers are pushing
for Cocoa ahead of really having to make
those decisions
um a lot of rock will Growers still but
compared to
let's say other crops I think there are
a lot of progressive thinking cannabis
Growers that really do want to push the
sustainability and the substrate is
usually the first thing that they'll go
with LEDs and the substrate
I would like to say that this
the struggle is not the material you're
using
many materials that for at a certain
scale one substrate that you're using
can be the best substrate you have
but if you're moving to scale up or if
you're moving to a different way of
growing if you're applying a different
technology and with that technology you
could have the problem that that
substrate is no longer the best solution
for that is we need to understand is
that
many of us whether we are doing for
recreational small scale recreational
bigger scale medicinal this and that
clubs and so on there are products that
work very well now for a particular
system that having this project
insisting that they will continue with
that product towards the other system
and we can't change that my lights
cannot fix is the choice of you choosing
to go with that particular substrate is
not fair to the substrate it's not fair
to the lights or it's not fair to the to
the irrigation system you chose we have
to be very careful is with the choices
we do with the combinations we do please
if you would come to me and I would say
with my light I know from experience
with other clients that we had that they
are applying this this same method they
have a hard time with it you would
please consider something else we can
even tell you well you can talk to this
person that person that person
please we can't fix that
it is it's literally that and many of
these Innovations they work on the right
place many of these Innovations are
coming they work for their place don't
try to push it to work everywhere else
they have a place for a reason so many
of these I believe that is more about
the balance of where they work best not
that they are wrong or that they don't
work at all I think if you look to
substrates we all know that we can grow
in all type of substrates but clearly in
the medicinal markets in Europe you see
a movement and Trend towards Stone why
because it's clean and inert and you
start uniform and that is always more
difficult if you grow in soil or cocope
because it's the mixture so having from
one port to another Port exactly the
same is more difficult it's just logical
so therefore you see a movement for
clean inert product with Stonewall I
think at Timo you also see that
everywhere like in June they were
talking even for the three medicinal
license holders you only way Eastern
will because of that
you're absolutely right so because it's
mainly a medical Market obviously the
product quality and stability is
extremely important and with Rockwell
you have a clean orig starting point but
still the rockwool issue is an issue
what do we do afterwards that is you
know you brought it up at the beginning
the question was about sustainability so
there is a question unanswered we answer
one question safe product for the
patients we don't answer the question
what to do with the with the waste
product now you have in the Netherlands
but that's only in the Netherlands so
you're not going to transport if you
grow in Germany all your stone will end
product to the Netherlands for that
recycling solution so it's also a matter
of having sufficient volume where all
the Growers are to have this in place
but you're right that is at this moment
a tricky point but I think that's also
an
opportunity for people to see that
there's there's gaps within receiving
yes programs right and that that's
that's a there's a big use for it right
so those markets that need them I mean
it's a great it's a great area to look
into yeah you are entitled if you are
working now or even if you're developing
a project you are entitled to ask every
single company what is your disposal
techniques protocols do you have it can
you receive it back what is the
recycling program all of that just ask
it needs to fit into your guidelines how
it's like is a waste you need to get rid
of it if it is a circular economy or not
we have a lot of uh cocoa developments
they are improving a lot and developing
a lot as well because exactly that they
are challenged they need to keep up with
the with the techniques even for
cannabis uh we see a lot of these
um substrate irrigation systems as one
improving a lot and
I I find that more often than not if you
ask companies that are doing this job
and that they are working
fiercely to improve they will give you
an answer of where they are in that
stage they will have no problems
addressing the fact that they will say
in your region we have no capacity to do
that and it's fine it's just fine if you
have in your region someone that is
capable of doing that now good but
sometimes even the companies take it as
is it good challenge
the companies to do that and ask them to
do that most of the times they will be
honest enough to say well it will take
us a couple of years but we accept the
fact that this is a new challenge for us
sometimes we even are the ones telling
exactly please be prepared
because we foresee that in the next
three years something is going to happen
so if you cannot prepare for that then
we can't do it anymore so ask talk
interact if you don't like the answer
just say that you didn't like that you
need that you want something better yet
we are all working for improving uh uh
Even in our own Innovations sometimes I
have an idea that I think is great and
everybody looks at me that is great but
expensive and I was like okay I need to
make it cheaper okay how to fix that
right we like the challenges because if
we don't talk and interact we don't
make it better
I agree and I think that we touched on
something here which is that to do
medical grade cannabis is not the most
sustainable practice because the most
sustainable way to grow cannabis is to
put it in a field outside but then you
have this like large level of
variability between the crops so you're
not really meeting kind of that
tolerance limit you want for your cfas
we like growing in rockwool for many of
my clients because it's inert because
it's clean because it's something that
we can get consistency of A's on and
make sure that it's always the same
every single time but that's a bigger
conversation that I think the European
Union needs to discuss you want
sustainable practices but you also want
super consistent products so how are we
going to find ways to meet in the middle
or how are we going to work with
different companies in the space to make
more improvements along those lines
because we all want to be more
sustainable but we also have to meet
these very strict requirements that you
have for our cultivation and production
one area I'm seeing a lot of really cool
Innovations in which is the most
interesting area for me we spend so much
time in cultivation and then for me post
Harvest is always very fascinating
because I always tell people you can
spend 10 to 12 weeks on a crop and you
can ruin in a matter of days in a dry
room by you know having a mold
overgrowth or something else so that's
been a really big area of innovation and
I'll pass it over to the panel as well
to discuss a little bit about that but
one point I wanted to touch on was
microbial remediation which is a very
hot topic because coming from Canada we
use pretty much irradiation e-beaming
for everybody but you guys don't really
have as many options here and there's
not as many licenses available and
Europe's not a single country it's not
something you can easily move the
product Between Borders so I've been
seeing a lot of things on the floor and
some private conversations but I wanted
to know what
um you know your best guess is for the
next big wave of microbial remediation
technology in Europe
so that's a very good question
um it coming from Canada where as many
people know it's very strict in terms of
microbial standards and thresholds uh
first off it's definitely possible not
to have to remediate which is even
Meeting those tricks thresholds if
you're growing let's say you're using an
inert media you have very highly
controlled environment with good air
filtration you have sanitary practices
if you do all those things it's very
possible and you can do it consistently
not having to remediate which
there are so many remediation
um methods out there and I'm not even
familiar with all of them there's
probably new ones that you guys know
that I haven't heard of but um e-beam
for example or or a radiation it has it
has an effect whether or not it's huge
on product quality uh and so and it also
has some stigma associated with it you
know there's radiation going into the
product so some buyers don't like that
or some consumers might not like that
idea and so it's possible to avoid it
all together with just the proper
practices it's
but I'd like to hear more about what
what's out there maybe um what I think
is really important that because in
cultivation we often talk about climate
you know and this discussion is
sometimes also happening in in the
drying phase it's like if you talk about
microclimates and so on is it really
understood how vertically my temperature
humidity Etc is
it's not really and it's also not
measured so the sensors are partly not
installed and I think as you said in in
the question there is so much potential
to make it right so give it the time it
needs have it under control I think um
there you not necessarily need really
high tech you need just sensors
dashboard look at it something out of
balance correct so it can can be pretty
easy as well but have it under control
and I think we always know
um you know a relatively High drying
rooms and if you go through the room you
feel already the differences and if we
feel it already then it's an issue for
sure so yeah yeah so I think I I would
agree with that is not I think there's a
lot of different tools from a technology
standpoint
um
for reducing microbials but I think
really what it comes down to is your
climate your environment within that
room and I think there's a disconnect
that we see right now in terms of
people's strategy around sequencing of
climate set points within those dry
rooms during the drying period you know
personally I can't speak for everyone
but you know for myself the what I've
seen the most success in is touching the
plant as least as possible during that
harvesting into the dry room phase
um and then it's really you need to be
very strategic in terms of your climate
within that room
um during really the first three to four
days are the most critical and there's
there's a big misconception around
moisture content and water activity and
those are two very very important things
they come from really the food industry
around drying foods and microbials and
foods but they they hold very very true
to cannabis so that's what I would say
that is the biggest the two biggest
things is focusing on climate sequencing
on those first three to four days within
the room how much moisture are you
ripping out of that out of the product
to having the least amount of touches on
it and then understanding water activity
how does water actually move within this
product during that drying phase I to
add to that I think that even
we don't read for post-harvest
for example
for me was fascinating when I started in
cannabis and suddenly it's like okay
let's Harvest and I started seeing the
methods of hang dry for example
this plant is not uniform at all
you have small flowers big flowers even
bigger flowers all hanging on the same
plant plants on top of plants we have
we've seen methods of people even
pushing plants on top of plants to dry
them all and just all of this is a
problem
just the basic techniques is a problem
and then for me in an innovation is
really asking these questions of how can
for this type of methods what are the
best plants to do with this method if
you have a crop where you have this
discrepancy of flowers you will always
have problems no matter how even good
your climate is probably because some of
these flowers are already dry and the
other ones are still with moisture and
it is a big challenge I I for example I
work with plants for years and I find
Cannabis I post Harvest like that very
challenging it's very challenging
we with all the techniques of not
touching and so on just the unique
aspect of dry hanging is a challenge and
this is actually a challenge that I find
very specific to cannabis
because in many fruits and in many
vegetables you you actually chop it
apart or you put the fruits separate and
so on and suddenly in many aspects of it
kind of doesn't do that and for that
aspect is unique I find that this
challenge to how can we improve on this
for this particular method is
something that not that many people are
looking at because it's very unique to
uh to cannabis and and I I find that a
interesting challenge
but also not the cheapest one to go at
this point to be honest is is
research and development in cannabis is
expensive if you look to the drying
methods it's also depending on what
Market are you serving are you going for
dry flour or is your Market extract yeah
then it becomes a completely different
ballgame of course and you know all
about it of course
um I think that's what is really
interesting about cannabis so
um coming from agriculture previously
and one of the jobs I had before I
started Consulting I managed a 1 million
square foot cannabis Greenhouse that is
a very unique situation your 36 000
plant Harvest your 2 500 kilos pumping
through a post-harvest process in six
days it's a lot and it's very difficult
for you to and you know we're partially
owned by a vegetable grower a very large
one and I always remember him really
focusing on cultivation being the most
important part of this process because
that's what they're used to their post
Harvest is pull it down wash it and put
it into a container that's all they do
and they weren't understanding why we
had to have so much labor and so much
time in this part and that you know if I
was actually strapped for labor during
covet I was putting them more in
post-harvest and in cultivation for me
missing a small step in cultivation was
way better than having a bunch of
product I couldn't dry down because we
couldn't bring it down in time so we're
able to take a lot of Innovations from
uh you know the agriculture industry for
cultivation but not so many for post
Harvest because it's so unique to
cannabis and the Cannabis product itself
is really heavily Reliant upon standards
that were set in the Legacy Market as to
what is considered good bud or top Cola
explaining to pharmaceutical Auditors
that the bigger buds are more desirable
even though they have the same trichome
density and effect as the smaller buds
is a very complicated thing to explain
but it's because regardless of the fact
that we're a medical Market we come from
a very long-standing Legacy Market I
want to thank everybody for all your
contributions today and the great panel
I just want to leave the last couple of
minutes in case anybody has any
questions for anyone on the panel
let's hear it again for uh Tia and
everybody
[Applause]
are there questions
Michael's running like you see someone
holding there you go all right
all right I'm Rocky petrulo with a
Colombian grow operation and tissue
culture you talked about earlier we're
we're trying to utilize that in our farm
in Columbia
and there's a question that I've had for
a while is that the DEA came out with
the seeds don't have THC so you can mail
them
can you mail a plantlet in a test tube
across borders across countries is that
possible it's going to depend on the
regulations if you want to send it to
the Netherlands no tissue is a plant a
seed
bear with us a seed is not a plant the
moment it has a tissue out of that seed
is a plant so tissue culture is a plant
in the Netherlands for example so it you
be very diligent on checking the
regulations of the country because some
countries might not consider tissue
culture
a plant and others will and if that
plant crosses all of those borders it
will be stuck on the country that
actually considers that plant so it
doesn't matter very very careful it
doesn't matter that it doesn't have any
THC it doesn't matter okay for example
speaking for the Dutch that I find
unique on that sense it's like it
doesn't matter at the THC level is a
plant cannabis tissue is a plant
therefore no
so yes be careful
yeah
do you know another country if these
rules function the same as in the levels
I think it depends on the hands of the
country yeah yeah you can just send it
to my house
[Laughter]
I'm a citizen of the world
well you've taught them everything
apparently
what wait oh up there
go Michael let's hear it for Michael
canoes
walking all the stairs
[Applause]
hi my name is Christina I'm a cannabis
educator you were speaking about
sustainability
um
so I was wondering if you could comment
on growing in living soil and using
microbial inoculants for plant health I
know that would probably introduce more
variability but I just want to hear your
thoughts thank you
um yeah so I'm so my ironically enough
my background is actually in
regenerative AG so I was I was very much
a hippie in my upbringing but uh the
difficulty that I see both even coming
from regenerative AG into the Cannabis
industry is scalability
um that I think that you know living
soil is really it's a great solution to
a lot of things but it is very tough to
make them feasible at scale right and
um I think there's some hybrid systems
that we can find within there
um that can kind of meet that goal but
living soil at its foundation there's so
many benefits to it just at a commercial
scale it's very difficult to make
feasible yeah to add on that
the plants
have plant soil feedbacks they
communicate
top to bottom
scientifically scientifically that is a
thing nobody's denying that but we use
Rock horse Cocos neutral systems for
scalability nowadays Innovation is
coming into that aspect of testing
um even from the root side not only for
example we have all biological control
protocols that exist that function
really really well many of these are
techniques of animals and
fungi's and insects that actually are
interactions of the plant with their
system that we are bringing into the
greenhouses into the indoor facilities
to balance the system out
there are very interesting Innovations
in that field to bring even further on
but that also takes time because we are
talking about living beings interacting
with each other and understanding how
that it works in scale you will see
often
scientific papers coming with a new
technique with a new aspect of it that
they say it works very well there's a
positive feedback that the plants will
grow x amount
please bear in mind that that was done
in a scientific
system
small areas highly controlled to
actually understand the mechanism of it
and then that needs a scalability and
that is the where we are at with many of
these we have biostimulants coming many
of them that are coming into the market
if they are coming to Summer feel free
to ask them what was tested and how did
it scale up
because then you will get the feeling of
where it stands on the ma on on the
market compared to the scale that you
have some things work really well at the
small scale but then at a larger scale
it dilutes it just don't have capacity
to keep it going on a large scale
but on a small scale it works really
well then if you have a small scale
infrastructure then it might be a good
solution for you if you have hectors of
it might not it's not that it doesn't
work it's just that it's not scalable so
measure the solutions to the scale that
you're working at yeah I would suggest
that but yes
thank you let's hear it once again we're
out of time unfortunately that was
fantastic TF rules the entire crew
Sunny Lucas Sabrina