so really happy to be here got a great
panelists of uh well quite a few
Canadians actually on the on the panel
uh we're gonna go through we don't have
a ton of time but we'll go through some
introductions we'll find out what got
each of these guys into genetics uh and
then we'll just kind of start a organic
conversation and see where it takes us
uh so I guess we'll start with you Manny
if you just want to introduce yourself
and maybe uh you know give a little bit
of a background we don't have a ton of
time so it's like a couple of minutes
two three minutes each
um just uh what got you into genetics
and how you ended up on this pathway
hello
what up
Canada's in the house I can see so I'm
Manny de Silva I was originally born in
Portugal my whole dual citizenship as
I'm a Canadian citizen as well my
experience started with cannabis when I
was about 14 and I started growing when
I was about 15 16 and quickly learned
that there was more to this plant than
just putting a seed in the ground and we
started experimenting with with
different males and females and it just
became a lifelong passion to be able to
see the different Expressions that we
could get out of each individual
cannabis strain that led me to
make transition into the legal Market in
in early in 2015 2016
owned my own facility which I just sold
last year and in the meantime I had met
some wonderful people in Israel and we
started a company out of there called
Green boys and we do import export of
high grade only high grade cannabis out
of Canada to various parts in the world
and we also Supply genetics to various
facilities well John bless you for that
thank you Dave same question you know a
little introduction and where are you uh
how you got into the genetics
uh my name is Dave OJ I'm the
commissioner for Big League genetics we
've we've been selling genetics across
Canada for the past two and a half years
um I got my start in uh in cannabis
breeding and genetics uh the first time
I ever grew I grew some Panama Red and
some blueberry and white widow ended up
with a male threw some pollen around and
was pretty excited about the outcome
um we final hunt we've got a 20 000
square foot grow that we produce
cannabis for international markets we
actually have some new stuff doing an
epic drop here in Germany in in the next
few weeks and we sell flower into Israel
and we provide genetics now all over the
world
excellent how about you Steve hello hi
guys my name is Steve tan I started
growing 26 years ago turn of the century
um why did I get into it I grew three
strains for nearly four years nl5 Hayes
Scentsy star UK cheese
um you know I came out of the.com Boom
making too much money going into weed
and you know since then I've traveled
the world you know I enjoyed Marcus's
company you know when he had dreadlocks
in a tent
um coming out of Jamaica must have been
what 2001 2002. yeah and you know fast
forward that you know mucked around in
California for three or four years you
know played in the Bay Area grew grew in
hybrid greenhouses I like greenhouses
um you know I like the moving ship
indoor bores me these days and you know
so I kind of catered genetics for
greenhouses I like a lot of the minor
cannabloids you know I like to put
flavor on CBD
um you know so I like these little
interesting Niche markets and I think
you know weed should be for everyone and
you know we can all debate about high
THC and all that jazz but I think you
know there are a lot of areas that I
think in two or three years will become
more prevalent and you know
um I invite everyone here to you know uh
push against the boundaries and you know
release products that your marketing
companies are telling you we can only
have these kind of profiles and you know
sensory panels in Canada just started
and I think those things are good and
really understanding your supply chain
after genetics Innovation happens after
you have to plant you know Marcus talked
about something about you know rosin and
supply chain with that right unless you
can have a code line going straight
through and I remember that talk
somewhere you can't you can't show the
strength of those genetics and you know
extraction genetics are going to be very
different from dry flower genetics
equatorial Greenhouse genetics that can
be very different from Canadian Outdoor
so I think I'll just stop there
all right we'll finish off with Jameson
thanks Marcus my name is Jameson
Wellborn I'm managing director of the
Banyan Tree
um we work with a lot of Legacy
participants to leverage their
intellectual property mostly through
seeds and and and cuts into newly legal
markets
um my relationship with the plant
started a little later at the end of
high school and by University I was
lighting up multiple houses and having a
really good time I was uh an ADHD child
and so when I found cannabis I really
found what worked for me and it
curtailed my Alcohol and Other Drug
consumption and made a major positive
impact in my life and it's something I
continued on and after University I kind
of came clean with what I was doing for
my beer money to my family and what I
wanted to continue doing with the plant
and they quickly put a stop to that so I
worked in the corporate world for about
four or five years before seeing the
light at the end of the tunnel in Canada
and legalization and started Consulting
in the space working with a few publicly
traded companies and then ultimately
helping a few startups get started one
cultivation business one genetic
business that's up here beside me before
I decide to go off on my own and start
uh start my own business and yeah I've
spent more time uh putting my focus and
energy into championing the Breeders and
Fino hunters and hashmakers then I have
actually done in in in breeding myself
so I really like to think of myself as a
more of an agent that is able to speak
and and bring these talented artists
into these newly legal markets and
leverage all the work that they've done
in the the quote unquote Grace space
so that it brings me to the next
question which is great
um
the the Legacy market and the market the
the the the history of breeding in
cannabis has often been connected to
these almost savant-like people who are
spending time with the plant they're
going in and they're checking subtle
nuances in the in the grows whether it's
outdoor Greenhouse uh indoors I'm
wondering what you guys all think and
I'll give you all the chance to answer
this question
um how you see breeding moving into the
future away from traditional methods uh
and into tissue culture crispr methods
DNA fingerprinting where we can now
identify very easily through tissue
culture and fingerprinting What gene
synthesis are present on the plant
whether they're turned off or turned on
and how is this going to help us breed
for novel cannabinoids novel volatile
organic compounds as we move out of
traditional methodologies and and gain
these scientific advantages we can start
with you if you like Manny
so one of the things that we're starting
to see is the recogna the recognition
between the human and cannabinoid system
and the cannabinoids that are produced
by the plant the outlying area that
we're we're missing is the connection
between those two not every single
strain is going to work for every single
patient and point in case you look at
Charlotte's Web that was an amazing
Discovery for Charlotte but a lot of
children that were brought and given the
same the same medicine did not did not
do well with it the efficacy wasn't
there and so I think through uh breeding
and through using things like DNA human
DNA we can find that connection and be
able to prescribe better medicine for
people
thanks Manny Dave
um you know we're with you know we're
not growing in basements and attics
anymore
um you know that's why we're Big League
genetics is is you know this is this is
the big leagues now we're getting
scientists involved uh you know DNA is a
factor they're viruses and and all kinds
of uh different things that you need to
look out for as it relates to the
commercialization of a strain uh just
because something worked in you know
somebody's backyard or their tent
doesn't mean that you're going to be
able to operate a hundred thousand
square feet of it and put food on
families tables and participate in
international Commerce and everything
else so more and more science is going
to be dedicated to this over the next 10
years marker assisted breeding is
already happening
um and I think it's going to continue
that way way
thank you Steve Marcus
um yeah that that topic I you know I
might hijack that topic because um we
have a startup and we've already done
two crispr cast 9 edits
um we've got these seeds now at the
University of Guelph and we've done
knock-ins and Knockouts
um I didn't actually realize you were
going to pose a question like that but
um so I'm going to plug our biotech
startup called hypercan and we're
working with a molecular biologist who
has also developed best of class
yeast-based enzymes with improved
cannabinoid synthesis so you know to go
backwards and forwards on the question
Jonathan Page at anandia really did a
lot of great work and I think he was
based maybe in Berlin I forget but um
you know at that stage and you know
corporate cannabis definitely knocks
good or indeed down because you know to
do good plant r d you're really talking
10 years and the way that corporate
cannabis situation that's happened in
Canada has has made me realize that
working with universities provides me
with a longer more stable pathway so
we've taken these seeds which for the
record are non-GMO point mutation edits
and when we breed these seeds we will be
Crossing these mutation point mutations
and our first knockout is actually
taking THC out so we can produce a plant
that is truly no percent THC for markets
like the Asian market the Japanese
Market which want to grow cannabloids
but they don't want THC so you know
editing and Engineering won't come up in
in our space I think you know at least
three to five years marker assisted
breeding and pan genomic work is
happening very strongly and I'll plug
you know a great company in Switzerland
called pogene they've done amazing stuff
and there are also other companies I
believe in Canada and you know many more
in different states that are working on
these things I think what they have and
what we didn't have is they have scale
they obviously have signs and to measure
minor cannabloids like cbcvs and and
these kind of things you really need
science behind you you know we can't
test smoke it we can't use our cpg
values to understand it you know we
don't have the ailments you know I
couldn't tell you
um if a CBD product works I just I just
um as a user so I think you know science
is going to take it I believe in Legacy
I think the cpg the flavor the Louis
Vuitton the Louis XII alcohol I think
that's all going to come from a cpg
value brand and I feel that we'll all be
in that empowerment but I think you know
we will have to play with these guys
because they are going to build
bulletproof plants that appear in
resistance viroid resistance but then
they'll need our flavor profiles to
layer with it so I think that's where
that relationship will be they'll build
Powerhouse cars but they'll still need
us to put the flavor on it or at least I
help so I think yeah I think that's
where we are thank you go ahead Jameson
I think that over the next 10 years
there's going to be a clear and
definitive line between artistic
breeding and Fino hunting and scientific
backed breeding and Fino hunting and the
reason I say that is just like tobacco
we're seeing uh the actual smoking uh
combustion of tobacco reduced but we're
seeing the vaporization of nicotine pens
and things like that increase we're
going to see that same thing take place
over these markets in in every any
legalized or unlegalized market and each
market happens to be at a different
point in its Evolution but when you
really look at the ability to assign
drug identification numbers make medical
applications or
um
you're going to see individuals using
crisprin and things that Stephen talked
about to separate out different parts of
the plant where you're going to have
certain breeding projects made for
specific volatile organic compounds and
the THC and CBD that that plant
produces are the overall inflorescence
of the plant isn't going to be a vital
key factor because that's going to be
destined for isolation and extraction
and then those different marker assisted
breeding projects where one will be for
high THC one will be for CBD one will be
for beta carophylline one will be for
valancine will all be utilized on mass
and extracted and when you're not
looking for
the optimal concert of all of the
different characteristics that you're
looking for that we see in artistic Fino
hunting and breeding where the plant
needs to hit hard taste good be powdery
uh powdery mildew and mold resistant and
you know resistant to to drops in cold
temperatures those factors won't have to
all line up when you're only focusing on
one characteristic and I think that will
be isolated to the medical side where
extraction focused drug identification
numbers are being sought after and that
will likely be the larger portion of the
market and then the Craft
um you know
uh artisanal side is going to still
remain with the Fino Hunters who are
looking for that overall experience in
that plant
yeah I definitely don't think you're
wrong I see in these pharmaceutical
markets that they want to stabilize and
I'm
I mean they're scientists so they have
to understand that stabilizing volatile
organic compounds
is impossible
you can't you can't do it so this is
what Jameson's saying you've got one
group who are like let's stabilize it
well how do you stabilize it you short
path molecularly distill it you reduce
all of the volatile compounds out of it
and then you're left with cannabinoids
oh look it's stable yeah but now it's
boring it no longer has those volatile
organic compounds but it does fit into
the pathways that are this sort of this
medical pharmaceutical pathway
um I also wanted to talk to you guys a
little bit about the importance of
tissue culture all of the clonally
produced plants on the planet currently
being clonally produced are done through
tissue culture cannabis is one of the
only plants that's not done through
tissue culture so the question I wanted
to pose to each of you as as breeders
that are producing genetics are
representing these Artesian breeders
that are you're selling their genetics
how important is it for you guys to
understand because
if you give someone a plant that is
completely impregnated with viruses and
bacteria and fungi and they go and try
to grow this genetic it doesn't matter
how good of a grower they are they're
not going to be able to get the plant to
express itself the way it should often
in the industry
this looks bad on the breeder instead of
the grower who's and it's not even the
Grower's fault in that sense so how
important do you guys think it's going
to be to have your genetics initiated
through tissue culture to have any type
of anything bacteria fungi viruses
removed from the plant before it goes
into production do any of you guys think
of that
uh yeah tissue cultures immensely
important
um it's uh it's not a silver bullet uh
but it's absolutely especially with
Germany and European markets and and
international markets operating all over
the world
um just like Marcus said you know if
you've got viruses you've got problems
um seeds aren't necessarily safe and so
we have a tissue culture lab for Big
League
um I'm sure others of you up here also
working with tissue culture
um it's definitely a very useful tool in
the toolbox to be able to make sure that
you've got stuff stored in vitro that is
safe
we do a lot of heat pheno hunting at our
facility and so we will run
um large populations of different types
of seeds that you know we don't know
what might have been you know what might
be contracted and and uh and so you want
to make sure that you know when you're
starting a new facility or taking in
genetics from somewhere else that's been
tested that it's safe or at least as
safe as you can be and then making sure
that you've got the the fail safes in
place to you know to be able to take
care of yourself
yeah I mean I completely agree with Dave
like when you're when you're selling
um you know Championship racing horses
or or race you know Premier breeding
dogs they need to come with their hip
shot and all the test results and you
know that's really what this is bringing
this into a
um a time where
you know all the teas need to be crossed
knives need to be dotted and when you're
realizing the value and having and the
time that we save these cultivators
um through these Fino hunting processes
you know a lot of these cultivators I
know we saw it in Canada where they
would raise a bunch of money they'd make
a bunch of promises to their
shareholders and then they'd say you
know we've got a bunch of seats and
we're gonna hit the ground running and
we're gonna have a crop ready in four
months for you guys and then the c-suite
learns about this Fino hunting process
and The Growers at the board table
trying to explain what Fino hunting is
and he's going okay if you and your wife
have a hundred kids they're going to be
short and tall and fat and wide and
skinny and smart and stupid and we've
got to find the LeBron James of your
kids and that's and that's what female
hunting is and and
um that can take eight months or 12
months or 16 months you know depending
on how lucky you are and so I think
there's a tremendous amount of value
that you know us as genetic providers
add that sometimes is a hard-earned
lesson for newly created companies and
c-suites that aren't as much educated on
that process and with that
responsibility and with the price that
you know is demanded needs to come
proper testing so I mean tissue culture
is just the start there's a lot of other
stuff that needs to be done and provided
whether you're doing nodal tissue
culture or meristem tissue culture you
know you need to educate yourself on
that process and you know where it's
coming from and all the tests you need I
mean hop latent is what's on the tip of
everyone's tongue but there's tobacco
Mosaic there's there's a a list of other
lettuce chlorosis there's there's a list
of other tests that need to be performed
to really feel confident
um in in the genetics that you're
bringing into your facility and even
when you have all those things you need
to have a quarantine program in place
before those genetics go into
commercialization
just to elaborate a little bit on what
Marcus was saying about you know good
genetics and uh and and Growers a lot of
times the growers in these companies get
a very bad rep because they have a bad
genetic and a good grower uh you know
can uh can be brought down by a terrible
genetic just like a terrible grower can
be brought up by a good genetic the
other thing that that's important is
that a lot of people think that you can
just get a genetic and start growing and
it's going to be wonderful I've learned
over time that it takes roughly eight
turns of any single genetic to be able
to have a a good understanding of that
plant and how it's going to express
itself and what it likes what it doesn't
like what temperatures you can take it
to so there's there's a lot more to this
for me
um I think it's it's somewhat
disappointing that the industry has such
a low value for genetics they all
believe that uh you know they should be
able to pay next to nothing for them yet
genetics are what these companies are
making their money off of if they don't
have good genetics that produce good
quality flour how can you expect to sell
it
and I think you know to pick up on that
yeah I mean you know I have a slide and
you know Microsoft invests you know 10
to 12 15 on r d
uh you know when I talk to Big LPS and
you know I sit them down I'm saying like
you guys need to invest two and a half
to five percent of your revenue on your
Innovation on your plants on your
genetics whether you want to run your
own programs do your own feminizing you
know do it in-house have a good guy you
know has a good background yeah there's
a lot of people that are doing that
whether you want to you know go to the
market pick the latest Kali hype strains
that's all good but you know the focus
markers on tissue culture the reason why
cannabis hasn't turned into bananas
which and everything else it's actually
quite easy to maintain mothers if you
know what you're doing yes the disease
element is there yes biobanking has an
advantage but if you try and send a
thousand TC cuts across the border at
the moment it's a nightmare so you know
we send fresh cuttings we put fresh
cuttings in a bag and we send them and
and that's worked great so you know the
history of tissue culture is trying to
fit a triangle into a square and you
know cannabis is very different so the
reason reasons why we don't use tissue
culture is you know banana and durian
and a lot of other bamboo propagation is
a lot harder you know these plants root
in six to ten days and they're pretty
bulletproof and you know hot blades and
viroid and some of these stuff I know
guys that put that into their TC room
because that's such a mess on its own so
just because you have TC doesn't mean
you know you're going to avoid diseases
it's more about your Baker who does it
how they do it and you know your
formulations between different strains
um and you know all of that kind of jazz
yeah well after coming out of about 100
Years of cannabis prohibition and all
living under the mentality of how much
can I get and how fast can I get it I.E
flowering times and vegetative growth
how much does it affect you guys in your
breeding of your genetics now that
people seem to be more understanding and
interested in the production of
cannabinoids and volatile organic
compounds which don't necessarily
correlate to vegetative yields finishing
in seven to eight weeks
don't understand the question so you
know if you want to look at some
companies you can value their output by
pure cannabilite output so rather than
biomass so to start there you know as we
know extraction plants have slightly
more open profiles you know your oil per
kilo ratio you know your value chain is
to your extractor so if you draw
extraction strains you add a value chain
to them if you grow dry flower strains
then that's that if you look at your
whole plant as a total cannabloid output
and you value that as pre-roll trim dry
flour and you take that type of strategy
then you you start to understand and
don't do what you know and I and I lived
in Canada for the last few years don't
do what the Canadians do which is oh
yeah we're just going to make a hash
line from the trim off the greenhouse
and you know that's Canadian yeah yeah
and you you we we all know the first
hash products that came out weren't
weren't built for that and you know hash
plants actually don't do well indoors
because of their Leaf to Bud ratio and
you know so you're going to see
different environments in different
markets being operated four different
segments because it's clearly you know
and we're we're building good Auto
flowers you know California who hated
feminized seeds who hated Auto flowers
you know now they're making a lot of
autoflowers field extraction you know
some of the emerald Cup winners are now
being turned into autoflowers are here
and you know people are trying to run
these so you're trying to get an acre of
you know cannabinoid output so calculate
your stuff not on biomass because that's
not really where you're gonna win you're
gonna win on quality cannabloids or
volatiles depending on the market you
want so put that into your business
plans figure that out and that works a
lot better I think you know getting you
somewhere
add to that
um depending on your customer like I
mean at least for us the customer's
desire and outcome is really you know
kind of where we start the genetic
conversation there's certainly
um you know I don't know how many times
today I got asked if we have high THC uh
if we got high THC strains
um so that that's obviously the first
and foremost on anybody's mind
um you know we try to look after our
customer and their goal uh for what
they're trying to achieve a lot of our
customers right now are on uh are
selling dry flour
um and and that's what they want and so
you know it sometimes that's where it
ends up for extraction but a lot of
times it's you know this is what they're
looking for so
um yield and and potency is still you
know it's it's what on the front of
everybody's mind right now Pi THC opens
the door whether whether you move the
conversation forward or not and then you
can really dependent on the company's
structure and how the how they make
their decisions the overall yield the
flower time and the amount of volatile
organic compounds all play a role in in
a different order for different
companies and so there's a
situation that we're facing right now
where
the uneducated and uninitiated want to
assign a value to a percentage and and
that's how they're able to achieve sales
volumes and that's how they're able to
communicate value to the end Sellers and
users and so even though most of us up
here have had 18 cannabis that is far
outdone any 35 cannabis that we've
smoked uh that's not the reality right
now and so having a threshold of a THC a
number that is going to get the
conversation started and then you can
start looking at okay well this one is
finishes in eight weeks and this one
finishes in six but the six weeker
doesn't yield as much grams per square
foot as the eight weaker and is a little
bit less powdery mildew resistant and
we're dealing with powdery mildew in our
facility so you have to weigh all these
variables and work with your your
cultivators and your clients to find the
right fit for that genetic so I really
think that cannabinoids opens the door
to the conversation and it's a it's a
full stopper start you can't go okay
I've got something that finishes in six
weeks yields great per square foot but
it's only 18 they're going to say we
don't care it you know it could be the
greatest thing since sliced bread we're
not going to look at it but once you get
over that 25 26 threshold then other
characteristics and factors start being
put in play
so just to go back on the whole THC
thing it's something that I don't think
we talk about enough I think it's a real
misnomer that we use THC as the
barometer for quality in cannabis we're
trying to equate THC in the same way
that they do with alcohol the problem is
with a bottle of alcohol if it says it's
40 it is from the top to the very bottom
you can't have that with cannabis you
have a thousand plants with 30 40
colas on it they're not all going to be
the same you know and it's unfortunate
that this industry has
been so pigeonholed in how we present
cannabis to the customer like in the
days when we were doing it we were doing
packs you basically opened up a bag you
liked how it looked you liked how it
smelled and that's the reason why you
bought it today the consumers all they
have is a number to go by and it's it's
terrible way to represent cannabis
well it leads me to our last question
because I believe we are close to the
end and guile another four or five
minutes so this will be a perfect
question for you guys each of you to
answer
in your perfect world in your utopian
cannabis breeding world how does the
future look
I think the future looks really good
because we are making some really big
steps in cannabis breeding you know with
the science base that we have now and
the Legacy uh ways that we did things
it's it's starting to come together and
I think that in future we're going to be
able to develop genetics that are going
to be able to Target
a certain cannabinoids and certain
profiles even better than we do today so
I think it's a it's a bright future on
the on the genetic side
go ahead I think it's
you know
I think it's good and bad
um I think that there's a a bright
future and a lot of exciting things
um with genetics and and still yet to be
discovered and explored
um I'm kind of an old Bean Head and I've
been collecting seeds for a really long
time I like
um new stuff and I I like the old stuff
and I'm you know with with new countries
coming online if we're pulling out of
genetic Banks from from Canada the the
population that we get to pull from is
going to get smaller and smaller there
will be breeding projects that expand on
that but there will be stuff that's
truly lost
um and you know as a I guess a bit of a
preservationist yeah land race
preservation and and stuff that's just
old like Thailand is is uh you know gone
through legalization right now a lot of
Cali genetics are over there and there's
an impact to that
um you know there's going to be cross
breeding that's going to happen in pure
Thai land races are are going that that
that genetic bubble has now been
penetrated and so there will be less
things like that and for me me I guess
that's a little bit sad
um but uh yeah the future is definitely
exciting you know marker assisted
breeding towards you know going after a
certain potency or a certain cannabinoid
or or terpene value effect
um all of that's very exciting stuff but
I guess the you know the old Bean Head
it means still like uh you know I'd like
to pop some old Urban Poison and see
what we find
well it started optimistic it went
medium I'm not sure if I could go
downhill or uphill on the future of
cannabis genetics I could say you know
half of us might not be here in three to
five years
um I think you know I'll touch on Dave's
optimism you know it's so cool uh you
know at my age 46 to come in and have
all these tools and to be able to go
back into my old seed bank and open it
up pull it out turn it left right center
get support have stuff that I'm not
worried about the door getting knocked
down and losing that [__] you know today
if you collect winning resources you
should be able to hold on to them we
never had that privilege and I think
that's that's amazing
um I think the future is going to split
like the Artesian corporate and I think
that's that's inevitable
um and I think you know DNA
fingerprinting and all these things are
going to give the small guy a little bit
more tools I think the pressure will be
on maintaining facilities maintaining
biobanks I think good relationships
exclusive relationships will become
stronger as things close down you know
as the market matures
um and you know yeah
I think it's going to be more science
and less art I think if you take all the
colors of the rainbow and mix them
together you end up with brown
um we're dealing with a lot of just
polies on polies on Pollies and you know
the names are the only things that
differentiate these things and if you
open up a large enough population you're
going to find everything that you were
looking for in your other packs in one
pack and so I think that unfortunately
like Dave said the bubble has been
popped
um you know I've spent a lot of time in
the Caribbean and you can see
Auto flowers and you can see wide Leaf
uh you know different Expressions that
have been brought into the country to
help the the Cannabis population but
really it's it's it's heard it and so I
think that as we move to a more
scientific and cannabinoid
value-based World we're moving away from
the magic of selecting based off
experience and I really think that
that's sad but I think it's the reality
that we're heading towards and until
there's going to be some type of
Renaissance that we saw in alcohol very
similar to you know a hundred years of
six different beers in Canada those
those were what you had to pick from and
then eventually there's this Renaissance
of beautiful craft beers coming to
Market and that's when individuals like
guys on this panel who've been holding
on to beans for a long time are able to
bring them forward and and find Value in
a market that currently does doesn't
denote value for those quality markers
and characteristics so I think it's
going to get dark and then it might get
a little light well I have a utopian
view of cannabis and the way I see it is
once the regulatory once we have to stop
promoting the lie that is you need to
protect children from Cannabis once the
regulatory dissipates and and and you
know is removed massively I look forward
to personally because for me genetics
are nothing without the Appalachia and
the terroir to allow those genetics to
express themselves and I look forward to
the day where I can purchase Lebanese
hash in uh Canada and I say that all the
time yes of course I want to taste I
want to taste the Appalachian you can
buy French wine yeah you could buy
Australian wine and you'd pay a lot of
money for it right we'll pay a lot of
money for it wouldn't you I would I
would pay a lot I would pay a lot of
them only hash in San Francisco
we may find that there are appellations
and terroirs that we have never taste
did because they were so prohibited they
weren't Afghanistan or Morocco or
Himachal Pradesh Parvati Valley Nepal
all of these hash producing countries
there may be countries that come up and
surprise us and when you say things are
lost
things can also be found so we're going
to end it on that note
that was fantastic what a way to end the
conference