hello thank you for the warm Applause
welcome to the very last and quite
familiar panel
which I'm going to open now and first
I'm going to introduce to you mark
ignita
the LA the rest of our panelists oh
there they come okay
Virginia and Simon
I will come through those two later
Mario canuta is a partner of the German
Law Firm skw Schwartz and certified
expert for IP additionally she is head
of the Cannabis Practice Group in at SK
we Schwartz Margaret please tell us a
little bit more about your cannabis
activity within your company as a lawyer
hi everybody it's first of all I'm happy
to be here oh hi everybody happy to be
here
um I worry was a speaker two years ago
so I'm glad to be here again actually
I'm stepping in for koliki unfortunately
got ill last night and is lying down
with a flu so
um right skw Schwartz is a german-based
law firm we have four offices we are 130
lawyers full service
um I got into the Cannabis field in two
2017 when medical cannabis
um became legal in Germany and
um yeah I had the opportunity to
administer a big trademark portfolio
from a canada-based firm so that was
really exciting because uh obviously
back then everything yeah it was a new
field and I had the opportunity to get
the whole development from from the
start and by now we are not only doing
IP but I'm my specialty is IP and
advertisement law but also M A or
licensing procurement
Etc
thank you Margaret I'm looking forward
to your expert expertise later now I
have to say hello to Virginia Garcia
first he's founder of cannabis now which
is one of the biggest English-speaking
cannabis Publications worldwide is that
right correct so uh
how did cannabis now develop within the
last years where since the legalization
in the states or since the legalization
of many states in the United States
uh thank you and um welcome everybody
really appreciate being here with you
all
we started cannabis now in 2009 in the
United States it originally be was uh
developed as a medical journal for
cannabis and enthusiasts and users with
a strong political focus and at the time
there was a lot of media available but
mainly it was focused on either the
unfortunate terminology of a Stoner or
the Breeders so there was a lot of
European media it was very focused on
breeding seeds genetics and then there
was the traditional uh Publications that
were really focused on the uh aggressive
use of cannabis so we believe that there
was a new consumer coming in the future
that would be an enlightened Enthusiast
somebody that would really care about
education about plant medicine about
spirituality about health and wellness
uh and about moving the industry forward
so we created cannabis now to be that
voice for the new cannabis consumer and
we knew we were early but we didn't
quite realize how early we were fast
forward to
2023 here in Berlin we're still about
only halfway through the Journey of
where I think we will end up as a
community and as cannabis media
expression so cannabis now is a print
digital social media and in-person Media
Group and we mainly operate in North
America we are in the only magazine in
airports in the United States so we're
in 58 airports Nationwide in Hudson News
which is a testament to the type of
content that we produce and we have a
social media community of just over 4
million so
thank you for being here with us and I
look forward to the conversation
yeah thank you original
and the last guest I have to introduce
to you is Simon Espinoza is that right
and that's right yeah I think Spanish is
not so good and I'm glad to have my
second panel with him I already already
had the penalt before which was uh we
really enjoyed it last year I think and
um how did things develop with your
publication called or voila or on voila
yes
so uh we started this uh Community it
was not a company when it started it's
it's it has always been a community and
started 10 years ago uh and then that
has evolved to become what is now which
is the most watched cannabis media in
Spanish we started we're based in Chile
but now we have outgrown our Frontiers
and have um reached new communities
across the glove all in Spanish so Spain
Mexico Colombia Argentina Peru and
surprisingly enough Florida and
California where half of the people
speak Spanish and like nobody's
communicating cannabis in Spanish which
was a great opportunity for us to you
know feel that Gap and what we do is we
communicate educational and scientific
content in a fun way all our hosts of
our shows in social media are stand-up
comedians or really funny people I'm the
less funny at all so I'm sorry about
that I have some jokes though we can
share if you want but uh yeah that's
what we do we try to communicate in a
fun way in a very approachable way and
kind of a bringing kind of these two
mainstream place where stigma does not
longer exist and where cannabis users
are free to be funny and intelligent at
the same time so that's what we did so
education thank you very much so your
education is a very important part of
cannabis marketing I would agree on
because uh you always have to justify
cannabis Marketing in a way and it's the
best way to justify marketing for a
track of course is education and we
you're an online platform you do online
work mostly yes but or genius you're
doing classical print print magazine as
well of course you're active online
but you're doing a classical print
magazine which everybody says at the
moment oh no no don't invest in print
magazines that does not work do you
agree agree on that
I agree that if you do anything poorly
it will not work but I also agree that
print medium whether it's books or
newspapers or magazines or whatever
you're doing is more challenging than
it's ever been however from a technical
perspective
high quality Niche which is a small
Publications are actually on the
increase at least in the United States
not to get too esoteric with everybody
but we all have these with us and the
digital Revolution is fully
in our system right now and we all spend
a significant amount of time on our
phones I'm sure a quarter of the
audience right now is looking at their
phone so we are absorbing media in five
four three different ways all at once
and what is going to end up happening
which has already started to happen is
people are going to make the conscious
decision and they are already
subconsciously making the decision to go
back to non-digital
non-screen forms of entertainment and
media our brains are not going to stop
we're now these humans that absorb media
and it's part of who we are now as a
species but so our brain still wants to
be entertained and educated but the the
drain that we're getting from our TV
screens that we have in our pockets is
now pushing us back to traditional and
different forms of interaction so in
person is coming back and print is
coming back and on a more basic level if
you have a print magazine that is
telling very very Dynamic interesting
stories and is made in a way that will
hold up over time that is not just meant
to be thrown away but maybe archived or
put on a coffee table and that will last
that is what is being successful and if
you don't hit those marks it's very easy
not to be successful
yeah so the truth is uh no matter if you
publish as a print magazine or you
published online you have to get some
Revenue by advertisement you have to you
know that you know that and I'm glad we
have an advertised expert here and also
we I have to tell that to our American
and Canadian audience or non-german
audience that you may not know
or maybe you know that in Germany you're
not allowed to advertise for medical
cannabis recreational Cannabis is
illegal so how can you advertise for
cannabis and that's what your customers
ask you
correct
um first of all maybe I go one step back
before we go into what is allowed to
advertise and what is not
um
for some of you it might be obvious but
sometimes it's not um so I would like to
share that so um it's very important
that you get brand protection
um we know in U.S it's not possible to
get a federal wide trademark protection
but in Germany or in Europe that's
different since 2017. so that would be
the first you should think
um when you come to Europe to get brand
protection
um
yeah in the beginning it was hard but
nowadays it's not a problem even for
goods and services for recreational
Cannabis which I must say it's it's uh
astonishes me because it is illegal
however
um you do get treatment protection we
file it all the time so that changed
totally
um the only thing you have to be aware
of use trademarks which do not have the
word cannabis or something related like
wheat or pot or whatever in there
because the European court of justice
still
holds that this um yeah infringes public
morality
so you you don't get a trademark
protection for that but apart from that
um go for go for trademark protection
the first step now
um the next thing is can you advertise
it and
I agree it's I'm astonished when my U.S
and Canadian clients tell me well this
is what we did in in the US please tell
me if this is possible in Germany as
well
um usually I I have to decline it's not
possible somehow even though yeah it's
very strict um usually when we talk
about cannabis mainly well cannabis we
we cannot as you just said there is no
advertisement allowed at all because
recreational Cannabis is illegal and
medical cannabis you're you're not
allowed to advertise in Germany because
it's a few pharmaceutical preparation so
what we have is CBD products that's what
we're checking claims for CBD products
here in Germany and there is usually
what we see is that
the industry wants to make some
beneficial health related claim
and that's a big problem like uh yeah
makes you easy to sleep or some
something what it actually does because
the courts then say well we know we want
scientific proof for that and I haven't
seen any Court uh case law yet in
Germany which would hold that in the end
there was
at least according to the Judgment there
was not sufficient scientific proof so
so far health related advertisement is
not possible
so if I'm not allowed to talk about the
beneficials of a plant or the
beneficials of the medicine can I talk
about my brand openly I may have mention
my brand if it's if it's not merely
related to cannabis so may I advertise
for my brand if I don't advertise for
the specific medicine yes absolutely you
I mean we do see legal advertisements of
course but just
don't say like anything health related
uh yeah so it's possible if I want to
bring in the medical cannabis strain in
the German Pharmacy I could not mention
the I I will not mention the specific
cannabis brand but I can mention my um
my my company brand
on advertisement but as you stated
earlier medical cannabis you cannot
advertise it at all what you can is
provide information about it
yeah like guidance something like you
said what you're doing
um not yes but you're not allowed to
like promote a specific medical cannabis
product okay and I'm not allowed to hire
a agency to promote it for because well
you can but then you might get sued okay
okay thank you very much so uh how do
you how do I do that in Chile how do I
do how do how do advertise for medical
cannabis in Chile thank you so uh first
of all um the regulation down there it's
known as strict as the German regulation
nothing is as strict as German
regulation though that's true sorry but
it's true but um that being said all the
content that we've done it's educational
and for educational purposes and you
have to be also very very careful on
what specific words you used when you
refer to certain I don't know if you're
going to talk about chemical profiles if
you're going to talk about effects about
or any of those you have to be very
careful on the information you provide
you have to make disclosures first so
you have to take care of yourself and
generate this sort of ecosystem in which
you let your viewers and your audience
know what's the purpose is the specific
purpose of every publication first so
you have to Nest them under this
umbrella of protection uh 18 plus
content educational content etc etc
and uh after that you have to be in
charge of uh like do a follow-up to your
content because things change and
something that you publish like years
ago on YouTube channel can be or can
raise the Red Flag by certain specific
institutions and then you have to react
to that before you get in legal trouble
I experienced that a lot of time also as
on my YouTube channel I experience I
have to agree I experienced that a lot
of time times that I got banned and
banned or I got strikes it was not
pleasant you know you you can't you try
I try to contact YouTube A lot of times
and they don't they just don't answer
why they give you the block or why they
block you why they give you give you the
strike so you have to find it out
yourself last time my YouTube channel
was blocked it was quite interesting was
because I had a contract with a seat
company advertising on my channel
for already 10 years and overnight
YouTube changed rules and the seed
advertising was illegal although seats
were not illegal to advertise in in in
in the countries where they are illegal
and that's and I advertise for Spanish
teeth company so it was for sure not
about German law but overnight I got two
strikes and my channel was nearly
blocked because I had a very short
advertisement for seats in the beginning
of my of each episode so I had to cut
off the seat advertisement of each
episode and I'm still working on that
may I add something to that it's very
interesting point
um just want to make clear that in fact
if you choose to use one of the social
media platforms it's their playground so
they make their own laws which is legal
and with um yeah posting something and
agreeing to their terms of condition
um you you agree to it so even though it
might be illegal under German law or
whatever it's their own law yes I never
complained about it because it's I know
it's it's this has nothing to do not
press freedom of press I have my on my
own homepage but I don't reached any so
many people on my own homepage but if I
go to YouTube It's if as if I enter a
bar if the if the owner of the bar he
doesn't like their face he just can ask
me to go out it's the same the same with
YouTube you know freedom of press is
nothing which has anything to do with
YouTube especially when it comes to
cannabis I agree to their rules and if I
break the rules and they make the rules
I have to draw the consequences it's not
YouTube so this is why I never thought
of suing YouTube and I've had this
problem since 2006. the first uh my
first episode on YouTube was blocked in
2007 because I showed how to grow
peppers indoor
but only it was just a pepper growing
indoor and it was blocked and I got
striked for growing peppers on the light
sorry for interrupt no no worries no
worries so the way we've understand this
is a there is these guidelines that's
how they call it right like the the
rules of a certain specific social media
platform and I got myself into a
conference of media I was not supposed
to be there but I got myself in there so
I could talk to someone that worked in
YouTube in a high level position right
and I got myself the meeting and then he
they explained very clearly why those
guidelines are no are not clear that and
that that's the issue with with social
media platforms first they can change
change their guidelines without any like
previous uh warn uh secondary those
guidelines are quite often like uh
General so that they can decide like in
in different aspects on how to proceed
uh according to themselves and not a
third party and they do uh they do say
though that um the promotion of of
consumption of any uh regulated
substance it's not allowed in their
platforms so uh what we've find out is
that you have to be prepared to get
strikes if you are in the Cannabis
industry no matter what your strategy is
you can get your YouTube channel banned
your Instagram account like taken away
and so the only answer to that is to
have your own strong platforms or your
own platforms as strong as possible so
your website you can say anything you
want on your website nobody will take it
down right this one and then there there
is other platforms there are sorry there
are other platforms that are wheat
friendly
Twitter LinkedIn those platforms you can
publish anything you want like as long
as it's not like like you know something
that uh uh sorry offensive
and I think that um
you know some of what you're saying is
is not only true but it's also
indicative of the future of marketing
um
social media doing you doing your
content on other people's platforms is
is almost we're almost at the point
where that's the past and what you're
talking about is the future but
we can still use it so for a community
like ours which has four million
followers it would be ridiculous for us
not to try to monetize that but we know
that we don't own it so we put very
little investment into it but we do it
as value added for our clients so we
will charge clients money for marketing
and services that we control
but as a free value add we will say and
we will publish it on our on our YouTube
and we will publish it on our social
media but we we can't make it our core
business because it would jeopardize our
business too much to rely on that
how do you advertise or how do companies
advertise for a medical cannabis in the
US we talked about Germany we talked
about Chile but how do they uh how how
is it advertised the answer depends on
which state you're in because the United
States is much like 50 52 different
countries so it does depend on what
state and sometimes it depends on what
county and sometimes it depends on what
city you're in so it's very complicated
the majority of the U.S has actually
very unrestricted laws but some places
like Florida for example has very
restricted laws
but I actually believe that the first
place that a company should look to
invest to promote their brand in media
and marketing and this is a little might
seem not natural for marketers like us
to say but earned media and journalism
is actually the first Frontier I believe
of a positive marketing and media
strategy and then you can back that up
so earned media is first and then you
back it up and you reinforce it with
paid media not the other way around and
earned media is what you do for getting
free stories
based on your value to the community and
to people so if you invest in quality in
your own story in your own brand
recognition and then hire or have your
own team
have relationships with the journalists
the independent journalists who they're
not that many out there anymore but
there are still are some one over the
one right here
to tell your story in an authentic way
you can get more value from that almost
than any dollar that you can pay and
there's no laws against that
thank you very much I would agree on
that I recently did a job for like in a
Florida company called fluent you may
know them it's a dispensary they own
like 70 locations they are publicly
trade they're under a lot of scrutiny
from like several local institutions so
this is one example we we created
content that would explain people how to
get a medical cannabis license in
Spanish right so that's what we did for
that Community but we couldn't advertise
anything else so it was a very tricky
how to get there but it's already
published and you can see it in in our
YouTube channel how to get a medical
cannabis license in in medical cannabis
prescription sorry in Florida and where
to buy it is not set but it's sponsored
by fluent cannabis right so their kpi
there was to acquire new patients right
they need to get to new patients but
they cannot do it you know on
conventional ways so that's kind of a
service that we provide for for the
industry as well
I hope it helps so as we see uh
the way to thank you for that are only a
plus no not no one else please no more
Applause
thank you for the left no more laughs
[Laughter]
they're coming they're coming at the
least expected minute so as we as we can
see uh cannabis marketing uh differs
from country to Country I would say
Sheila and the US is more related
Germany has a kind of a special role and
if customers ask you uh how uh how how
should I build up a company to build up
a good brand what do you recommend to
customize the Cannabis company except
not using the word cannabis in the word
uh in in the in the company name
or not any cannabis related term in the
company name what do you how how do you
build up a company profile or when it
comes also to AdWords not advertisement
but to bra let me let me let me call it
branding
yeah actually that's not so different as
from other branches
um
the more a name speaks for the goods and
services it's supposed to be used for
the better it is
but on the other hand
um the more difficult it is to get brand
protection for it because then it might
be purely descriptive so you have to
find with your team marketing team a
strong brand which is however
um
there there you get brand protection for
it so it's it shouldn't have the word
cannabis in it because of morality
issues and it shouldn't be purely
descriptive and then
well then it depends where where do you
want to go which is which are your
markets and that is trademark strategy
like usually I my clients come from the
US in Canada so so they already have
their marks there and then they come to
Europe that's what we usually see here
um
and then you do yeah you have you go
with the Madrid so-called Madrid
protocol International trademark filings
but they all come from over there and
then you you we handle the the
trademarks from there and what we also
see
they especially the Canadian and the US
of course because they don't have any um
trademarks Federal wise in the US they
go for European protection that we have
uh uh the so-called European tradepark
office in Alicante in Spain which is
very convenient you make one finding and
you have protection 27 in all the 27
member states so that's quite good and
then you need Switzerland as well which
is
another story then
uh yeah that's a quite interesting
because that's a total a different
approach than in other countries because
it's a restricted so uh so highly here
in Germany
um but what you uh
what you say or other a lot of suing
cases that companies get sued because
they do not stick to the rules because I
hear that from time to time as I can
tell you I've already seen a lot of
companies just not sticking to the rules
yes
how probable is it to be suit for this
yes and I think that might be also a
difference but please correct me if I'm
wrong to like the us or other countries
we here in Germany have a really strong
um consumer protection so we have a lot
of consumer protection associations and
they take those cases to court so what
we see it's at least in the Cannabis
field I I don't I'm not aware of any
case where one competitor sued another
which would be
possible but I don't see that they they
just go their own ways but we're not
that kind of people you find me we're
not that kind of people we wouldn't Sue
each other exactly we already have too
many problems we have other industry
they sue each other all the time so I I
agree it's it's the same with the
influenza marketing they're also very
strict rules in Germany but the
influencers they don't switch others so
but we have those associations and they
go to court and the other thing is which
is probably
um new for you in Germany it's all case
law so when we talk about
um Health claims or influenza marketing
uh all these advertisement related
topics we don't have an advertisement
agency like in the US
which then go after you it's the courts
so you always need somebody who sues you
for that and as long there nobody sues
you I guess that's why we see so much on
social media which is my probably not
legal
you just continue
and when it comes to the fights in the
so-called I have to use the German term
because that's they are quite High
aren't they
absolutely yes yeah that's a special law
which regulates
um advertisement for
um
not pharmaceutical preparations but for
anything which is beneficial for your
health and it says um yeah that you
whatever you claim needs to be true it's
obvious but also when you say something
health related you need the scientific
proof for it
that's a very high burden the whole CBD
Market is suffering from it I guess and
um from this higher hurdle uh I think
you can tell stories about the CBD
Market CBD uh entrepreneurs are
suffering from that absolutely yeah it's
a shame
well and to speak to the CBD Market
it might be suffering because of
legality issues but also
one of the things to remember with any
brand is you have to be true just in
general to keep your customer so you can
you can legally say whatever you want
but if your product does not stand up to
what you're saying you won't be in
business for long and if you look at the
the US CBD Market about 80 percent of it
has disappeared in the last three years
not because of Any increased regulation
it's just
people are either transitioning to
different uh more advanced cannabinoids
or THC and or a lot of the brands said
hey this will do this for you and after
spending a certain amount of money it
did not do that and they lost the
customer and they're gone so legal or
not legal
marketing and media and brand loyalty
starts with the value you give to your
customer
absolutely I would absolutely agree on
that
um
Simon if it comes to Sheila how you you
have a medical cannabis program and
Sheila since very recently yeah very
like a couple of months ago we legalized
a medical kind of issues with a medical
prescription so that's we're very happy
about it yeah
so thank you very much
that was a good joke we'll sell that to
the camera so that you yeah
do you feel do you already feel that
when it comes to a publication that
there's a interest on advertisement or
on introducing or educating people on
medical cannabis more than it was before
now yeah for sure and it started very
quickly so the next day after the the
law was set in place formally right
there's this whole process that needs to
be published in an official journal and
whatsoever but the very next day we
start getting calls from new
dispensaries that were not actually
legal formally but they know that
they're protected by the medical
prescription so they're basically
associations that would take medical
prescriptions and then provide a service
accordingly to what the medical
prescription says
and we started getting you know um
inquiries on how how should they you
know promote themselves in this new
space in this news so we had to
basically open a new Aria a new branch
of our company that would only assess
them right on how to properly engage
with us or with any other Media company
or agency so there is a huge increase in
interested in this area uh it needs to
be taken care of I think there's a lot
to say still that we don't know than how
it will unfold but we do know that
there's already a certain framework for
for uh what to what you can do and
cannot do with regulated substances and
we are sticking to that frame until
there is like a new new
um updates on cannabis specifically but
so far we are advising them to promote
the same way they would do with Vicodin
right but basically yeah so we're doing
Vicodin shows now it's very profitable
we don't know as a work I hear very
often when it comes to cannabis
regulation yeah and every country
especially also in Germany we don't know
it's a it's a very common uh phrase when
it comes to we want to regulate cannabis
within this and this time but we don't
know how to do that yet I will hear that
in Germany every every day what I would
say which on the other hand of course
creates gray areas because no no country
decided to legalize from one day to the
other
going from a black to a white Market
within with a state of decriminalization
as Germany plants means also to accept
the gray Market
not a lot of people think of that going
from White from black to white in the in
the middle is gray and if we
decriminalize
which is which is not legalized we
accept a gray Market everybody uh
California did that even Switzerland
does that there except gray areas when
it comes to home growing for example
Switzerland is accepting gray areas
since over 10 years
and how is that for a lawyer in the
industry where you have to work with
gray areas that's that's what I wanted
to know from you Margaret
well we we had a of course trying to
solve
solve problems you want to be
um not just to show our clients what
they cannot do but what they can do
and but in this typical now in this
specific field at the end it's we tell
them
what the law says and then we tell them
what the risk is and here's they break
it here's a very good four four minutes
and 20 seconds
or less expression of a gray area this
is a real example
uh in March of 2020
no in 2021 March of 2021 the a lawyer uh
sent a letter to the DEA in the United
States and he said hey there's a gray
area in the United States can we sell
seeds in the United States it's a gray
area DEA which is the federal government
of the U.S regulatory can we do this
certain amount of time goes by and the
DEA response with a letter saying hey
lawyer
the DEA
deems seeds as hemp they are no longer
uh deemed a controlled substance in our
purview we will not be going after seeds
or genetics they are a food commodity
and and they are a hemp product thank
you very much the lawyer published that
Lo that letter on the internet
nine months later
cannabis now was working with a client
called Royal Queen seeds who is a
genetics seed company from Europe who
had
decided to come to the United States
because of that letter because it was
safe to now sell outside of a gray
Market it's still a little gray but a
lot less gray after that legal letter
was published and we teamed up with them
to take over the New York City Times
Square building at 4 20 for an
advertisement but we did it in a very
unique way what we did was we teamed up
with Royal Queen seeds to celebrate 420
and it was not an advertisement to hey
buy our seeds and grow marijuana it was
let's celebrate the fact that we can
grow cannabis legally in the United
States using these seeds brought to you
by Royal Queen seeds in cannabis now and
we had a party in Times Square at 4 20
gave out 200 free joints or more and the
news station showed up and we got over 4
million eyeballs on the on that story
you couldn't pay for that kind of
marketing uh and it's a really good
example of how we identified a gray
Market that had become a lot less Gray
and for the lack of a better word
exploited it for the benefit of
everybody
but it always takes a while till a black
market becomes white and I would say if
you don't accept the time the gray uh
the the great the the gray area takes uh
we have uh we are in talent and you know
and and nobody I think nobody likes uh
what's going on in Thailand right now if
you legalize one two one to one uh from
one day to the other overnight if you
legalize overnight this is also a big
chaos and uh yeah so I think from a from
a legal perspective though I think or or
from a media perspective I think that
also with the gray area if we look at
the gray area and then we push on it
specifically we might actually find out
or get a response that it's less gray
than we thought or actually turn it from
Gray to Green yeah this is this is what
I think we should all work on because
Germany wanted to legalize without a
gray area and they worked on it for two
years and then they understood okay we
have to accept this gray gray area with
the three plants and 25 grams because
everybody knows 3 grams and three plants
does not mean you can grow a lot of
cannabis out of three plants more than
your own need so of course they accept
gray areas and they found out after two
years of discussing with lawyers and
they're checking a ruler and federal law
that they have to accept this career
area if they want to have a proper
legalization I think we have one I'm
sorry that I interrupted you but I think
we have one more minute for a question
if anybody from the audience wants to
ask a question
thank you
no jokes
not a plus please
no
let's hear it for the panel by the way
let's hear it foreign
one more time please
[Applause]
[Music]
I don't know all your names but write it
down
wrong go ahead and and for you brother
[Applause]
hi my name is Luke Monroy I'm a
filmmaker and uh like Mika I'm also in
the realm of like thinking about ways of
you know collaborating with Brands and
knowing that this issue is all around so
I really like the the last example you
gave because it's actually an example of
how to empower the issue and not
standing there as a
sponsor right but as a collaborator in
the car so I would like to know of of
you
um what other examples in the in the in
the last few months or years come to
your mind when it comes to very creative
way of pushing the Cannabis subject out
in society
well I I will say that a minor example
of that is what we're doing here today
at ICBC I'm I'm here uh with Jason
Washington who's in who's in the front
row I'm I'm here with my wife and my
baby boy who's over there and we are
here um we're filming a documentary on
cannabis culture and education in Berlin
and in Europe and we've invested our
time and our money to uh document what
we're all doing here today so this will
turn into a film project that we will
then distribute for free to people who
want to learn about not everyone can be
here we're in a very unique important
group that a lot of people wish they
could be here and whether it's time or
health or money they're not and um so
this is a really real world example of
us capturing this moment and then
Distributing it globally for people to
create change with
I personally think when it comes to that
aspect we should focus on prevention and
youth protection
because this is a very important topic
and when it comes to
the people who do not want to have a
cannabis industry in this country this
is also this is always the topic where
where it comes to we have to protect
Youth and we cannot protect our youth
with the legalizing cannabis but if we
do a proper harm reduction work if you
do a proper safe I use work it will be
much easier for the whole industry
to to have Revenue here and if you
really give them good protect prevention
and protection concept for our youth for
our youngsters because this is what
Society is afraid of and this has a
doubt this is a win-win situation
because we protect the youth and we help
our industry to act more free more
freely and this is the last word I
wanted to say here we we should not
neglect that political issue of youth
protection safer use and harm reduction
because the whole industry will profit
from it when it when it will become a
big cannabis industry thank you very
much for being at the IC thank you thank
you very much let's hear it again
thank you all so very much one more time
for Eugenio and Simone and Margaret and
Michael canos that was great thank you
so much
[Applause]