thank you thank you ICBC for having us
here today
so my name is I'm a lawyer here in
Germany since 2003 working in the
Cannabis space since 2017
Consulting hem companies medical
cannabis import companies CBD companies
and I'm the legal advisor of the
European Industrial Hemp Association
which submitted these Noble food
applications for authorizing CBD oils as
novel food and I welcome our fellow
panelists
we have to my left Dr Philip Gerber
Philip is managing director of dimican a
German pharmaceutical company
specializing in the production
production and distribution of medical
cannabis with his expertise in the field
of farmer he's now actively involved in
shaping the future of the German
cannabis industry Zeta Schubert Zita
serves as the General Secretary of the
European medical cannabis Association
and is a prominent lawyer in the
Cannabis industry her legal knowledge
and experience in the farm industry
provide valuable insights into the
regulatory landscape and international
aspects of the Cannabis industry
Daniel Heyman lawyer from mme legal
Daniel Heyman is a lawyer at mme legal
specializing in Regulatory and
compliance issues related to cannabis
which is expertise he assists companies
in navigating the legal complexities of
the Cannabis industry and advises on
strategic business decisions
and we welcome Bob Holborn from the U.S
he's a renowned figure in the Cannabis
industry serving as the co-chair of the
Cannabis Institute group and member in
charge of the Clark Hill Denver office
with his extensive experience in
cannabis law he provides valuable
insights into the global cannabis market
and its legal landscape this was done by
Chachi PT so it works
let's see what we can eat of the
questions so we heard a lot of the
latest developments in Germany today
pillar one pillar two I won't um
reiterate on on that I will give you a
quick overview of the history of
cannabis in in Germany so the latest
reform we had was in 1996 the bear hemp
was where farmers were allowed again to
cultivate hemp on their fields before
1996 even that was prohibited that was
the big reform from 1996 what they
forget were the seats so they said the
seed trading of seats is not allowed if
it is for an unlawful purpose and only
farmers allowed to to sell seeds rather
than the Netherlands and in the Czech
Republic they allowed to sell to sell
seats that was the first big
disadvantage in 1996 and there was one
provision in the new law called the
misuse of intoxication has to be ruled
out and this provision caused a lot of
trouble still right now then there was a
long time there was nothing from 1996
till 19 till 70 to 2014 2014 the first
patients were granted their exemption
for using cannabis as a medicine
we started with 1 000 patients about
that time and there was this lawsuit of
this patients who applied or who wanted
to grow his own cannabis on his balcony
to provide himself with cannabis as a
medicine he won this case finally in the
last instance and the German government
didn't like that that every patient can
grow his cannabis on his own balcony so
they set up a whole law in 2017 the
Caribbean cannabis as medicine act
as I said we started with 1000 patients
now we have probably 200 000 250 000
patients no one knows exactly because
these figures are not documented
we have
again Imports last year 25 tons of
medical cannabis were imported to
Germany we had a domestic production
about 1.52 tons altogether with all
these three domestic cultivators we're
talking about total revenue in the
market of probably 300 million euros
according to the reimbursement figures
but still these numbers just a guess
it's not documented what's really how
big the the size of the market really is
so a small Market still
and these are one figures but I want to
tell you also the Wheel World here in
February 2023 I had three court cases
for the um and the criminal offense was
the trading of CBD oil in February in
within three weeks one acquittal one a
sentence was eight months on probation
and the other one was 19 months without
probation so this is the reality besides
180 000 con consumers uh getting having
criminal proceedings by police and then
shut down by the prosecutor so that's
the situation we we have right now
um Philip let's let's start with you uh
what and the most important thing is of
course as we heard many times this
morning uh cannabis will be removed from
the narcotic act this is a milestone
this is a milestone for all the CBD
Traders which are prosecuted right now
the CBD flower Trader CBE oil Traders
this is a milestone for the consumers
and probably a milestone for the medical
cannabis industry
Phillip what do you make of this draft
what do you think what potential can
that be for your company tell us a
little bit about damicon and what you
make of it and what the chances and
options of that yeah so Joe demikan is
the only uh German company who won one
of the three licenses back then in 2018
2019 from the government so we produce
for the government right now wonton here
in Germany we also process Imports
obviously because we are not allowed to
grow anything in Germany which we then
can sell also to the German Market which
we obviously see as a big disadvantage
but that's how it is right now in
Germany
obviously what you just mentioned Kai in
terms of the draft which has been leaked
um there I think there's quite some
potential if you have been a Mary Jane
you have seen maybe some talks as well
the market says okay it will grow in
size in terms of three to ten times
um so I think there will be a huge
growth in the beginning it may be a bit
limited by the number of prescriptions
or doctors who are willing to prescribe
but I think as more as we remove the
stigma from Cannabis this obviously will
lead to a market growth
and we ourselves prepared for that so in
terms of obviously a good supplier
Network that we are able to have good
medical flowers to be delivered to
Germany on the one hand and obviously
logistical wise also to get it
distributed to the pharmacist because I
think this will be then when the market
grows obviously a certain bottleneck
next to that I think you didn't mention
get the Social Clubs which are also part
of the First Column as they call it in
Germany so that first draft of the law
we really um are eager to see what will
happen there when they may start growing
as well it's not yet clear how exactly
it will happen but we just can say that
we have enough space at our facility we
have 12 factors in total and 30 000
square meters of facility buildings
where also we may enable Social Clubs
obviously to grow cannabis at very high
standards and I think that is very
important to say let's stick to the
medical standards which we have in order
to ensure High product quality because
we have seen many different products I
would say to keep it neutral in Germany
and I think to stick to that quality
scheme is very important
and we are very open to support those
cannabis clubs as well so I think there
will be a major change with that First
Column so taking it out of the narcotics
law which will definitely grow the
market in terms of medical cannabis but
also obviously in terms of the Social
Clubs and do you think that the numbers
of prescription will increase
just by the fact that it is removed that
it's not actually recording anymore yes
maybe some of you don't know exactly the
German system so a narcotic prescription
is a serialized prescription so the
doctors need to apply to obtain their
block of prescriptions and can't get
like hundred thousands because they are
limited somehow and so they are very
restricted on how to prescribe uh
medical cannabis right now and in the
pharmacies it the workload to handle
narcotics is also tremendous and for
ourselves as well so we need to do a
full inventory twice a year it's a
nightmare when you really got to do that
and count every single cram so I think
with taking it out of the narcotics law
many hurdles which are there right now
in the market will fall and we will be
able to serve more patients adequately
with good product
are you in direct contact with
Physicians saying if that will move from
the narcotic we will be more openly
prescribed cannabis then or is that not
a topic well we see that they are more
oh they will get more open so that is
like first feedback we got
um and I think obviously then at the
same time you may have seen that on
Friday Germany passed a law that the
reimbursement of cannabis products will
also be easing it so I think these two
common factors in combination will lead
that the market will grow and will open
new opportunities
like you can't give in more exact
estimation on what's Happening currently
we don't have more exact estimations as
I said I mean estimates are between
factor three to ten
um I think it will take some time it's
education about educating doctors as
well but it will definitely lead to a
growth of the market
good Zeta tell us a bit about oil what
are you doing with this organization and
what do you make of these new
developments in Germany in terms of
medical and and Social Club
first I want to thank you for the
invitation to be here and I'm really
delighted to speak in front of all of
you
umca is not a standard industrial
organization but we are a kind of one
voice approach which means from the
pharmaceutical industry of doctors
Association but more important patient
organization and I think Kai mentioned
it so nicely that at the end the reason
why you all are sitting here is based on
the Supreme Court decision which one
patient fought through and is Gosha and
fleta mentioned before this happened in
all the other countries I don't know how
much you are engaged in this kind of
field but I think this is worthwhile a
consideration
the second one is I would just like to
respond to this narcotic situation
because I think this this is a very big
question mark the route to reimbursement
is a prescription and the route for a
product is to be as in a status of a
prescription which means the narcotic
status gives a prescription gives
reimbursement so my question mark is if
it's not a narcotic anymore like CBD
which is also not a prescription product
and not reimbursed what will happen with
cannabis
in a medicinal field and here I think
there will be a big question mark
opening and when you hear it before the
political discussion they will try to
fix it well we have the whole health
insurance companies 130 I think at
present who will not be really the the
ones to bring it forward so to fix
something which has been lost is again a
process of years
and I might you might find yourself in a
few months or years pretty disappointed
when the prescription might not come
because I don't know what kind of
prescriptions will then happen and to
feel pity with doctors to make a
prescription on narcotics who daily
prescribe Fentanyl abestral and all the
opiates is maybe not clear to me maybe
somebody knows more about it but talking
with the doctors associations I never
saw that this was a hurdle and not to
have it as an narcotic does it delete
the memory that it is a narcotic and has
some harm at the doctor's perspective I
think this is questions which would have
been maybe also interesting to ask a
doctor who is unfortunate here today but
um I think I would clarify that before
before moving something forward which
might be maybe a release for the
cannabis clubs but to my personal
assessment are pretty far away and I
think it was very nicely mentioned also
before that
um there are several federal states who
already told that they will not allow it
and the same was the pilot project so I
think there are so many hurdles piling
up in a lot of kind of visionary
development so I really strongly
recommend to think about the existing
possibilities which are legal which are
clear which are accessible and maybe why
all your companies are presently on the
market here is to be in a system which
is reimbursing a very important medical
treat which has an unbelievable
yeah opportunity for unmet medical need
in more than 44 diseases which are
presently defined may I just ask a
question as well oh please okay I'm
happy to do so what why do you say that
removing cannabis from the narcotics act
might have implications for doctors not
prescribing it or prescribing because
they are not on the prescription list
anymore
prescript which prescription list
how do you think that drugs come on up
we have over the I don't want to go too
deep into Pharma which is my background
but they are over-the-counter product
which are not reimbursed they are
menstrual preparations which are not
reimbursed and then we have products
which are by legislation reimbursed and
they said for example narcotics and as
cannabis is not yet a marketing
authorization process which went through
the GBA to be listed in the prescription
I don't understand under which kind of
status it will be reimbursed then
okay interesting uh what do you think of
this conflict between dried flowers and
finished products uh what's your point
on on that I think that dried flowers
had an absolute absolute
um authorization to be on the market I
have spoken with so many doctors who
were so delighted to have a quick
reaction medication against heavy pains
and this is not comparable to anything
what is presently on the market I just
take one sample cluster headache I don't
know if anybody had heard about it but
this is something as soon as it starts
people are ready to commit suicide and
there's no medication who is stopping
this kind of heavy pain and I think we
have about three million people who with
heavy pain and we have uh percentage I
can recommend to you University of
essence here in the lead for magistra
for this cluster headache with a big
reach through Germany and the wave of of
flowers is giving during minutes of
relief and this is the first time they
receive a medication which is working so
quick and I'm sure there's also another
one which we did not have and
unfortunately we are missing data but I
think it is pretty clear having such a
long prohibition time that we cannot
generate data so quickly but this is
what I see also as our task is to speak
to Regulators to find a way like we
found it for all other medical
challenges a kind of registration path
which enables you to bring a product as
quickly on the market maybe a marketing
authorization and a condition and maybe
it was a patient registry and we are in
discussion with several Regulators who
are really listening to such kind of
proposals but also not to forget a
commercial part is to have some kind of
data safety which allows you not to be
replicated so I'm understanding being
here a few days and uh also that
sometimes you are you are desperate
about difficulties but maybe you you may
take it also as a chance but everything
which is difficult is not impossible and
everything which is not impossible is
reachable it's a strategy and it's a
strategy of your self-protection and
make it it for competition may be a
little bit difficult and you might find
yourself in a niche as Pharma does it
and you might say oh what have I to do
with Pharma but you are Pharma you
produce Pharmaceuticals you are in
Pharma welcome you in a business which
is so wonderful to treat patients to
have this wonderful experience to be
part of the sealing system and maybe one
day of you everybody of us will be
patient and will be very grateful for
this options and I spoke with doctors
they are very happy to have more options
in their toolbox to treat patients so I
do not see resistance against flowers
well what do you think of these cannabis
clinics coming up coming online here in
Germany is that something you support
with your organization or well I think
that presently the German clinical acts
are very clear about what they consider
clinics and we have the full provision
Etc so I think
um yeah um I I will not put a statement
on that I know too few about the
processes and how they work on that but
I think that talking to Regulators it is
also seen critical
okay
Daniel the Switzerland has a timely uh
is a timely ahead of us in in Germany
in terms of model projects so we're
talking about we're thinking about
introducing motor production in Germany
please tell us how long did that last
did that take from the first day of the
decision of let's have a model projects
until they really became implemented in
Switzerland and what can Germany May
learn from learn from your experiences
so much well no in fact it's it's funny
because we've been watching very closely
what's happening in Germany for a month
now and it was quite a disappointment to
see in which direction it goes and and
especially the opening up of
recreational markets so we understand
there's going to be two tiers the second
tier here in Germany is what we already
implemented in Switzerland it started I
would say
around 2017
when the federal committee for addiction
issues issued a report claiming and
rightly so that drug policy in
Switzerland has failed period
and they took for example particle as a
model and and other countries where
there is a more open approach to
narcotics in general and that led to two
movements on the one hand
a medical cannabis was was opened up
further and last year was implemented
the change in law whereby every doctor
now can prescribe medical cannabis you
no longer need a special permit from the
federal Office of Public Health so
that's one thing we all know the issues
doctors don't prescribe it they don't
know how their all these issues are
there in Switzerland as well but we hope
it's going to change soon and there's
more and more Creative Solutions to
tackle that on the other hand
there's a movement that opened up and
and the realization of politicians that
they need to do something about this
recreational Market in Switzerland
there's a give or take 300 to 500 000
depending who you ask regular cannabis
consumers for
of which a hundred thousand claim they
take it for medical purposes and of
which 200 to 400 take it for
um are consuming for recreational
purposes and that's a lot if you
consider that the entire population is
eight or nine million so really we're a
population where cannabis is very
um pervasive throughout the society and
and also I would say relatively open
we've had we have held already in the
90s we've had a very open market
circumvention of certain laws where uh
people were able to buy cannabis in in
scented bags okay so you would buy this
scented bag in in in in in a shop
perfectly open you would ask which
strain and you would buy it for 100
bucks you would buy a little bag and
people were looking at them
openly long story short it's really only
since about one and a half two years
that the law has been enacted and it led
to a change in the narcotics act and let
me read you now quickly what it says and
what the framework is and from that I'll
give you some more flavor so after
Consulting the cantons and communes we
have cantons concerned the federal of
the health Ministry May authorize
scientific pilot trials involving
narcotics containing an effective
concentration of cannabinoids
what that means I will tell you in a
minute
a that are limited in terms of location
time and subject matter that allow
findings to to be made on the impact of
new regulations on the use of these
narcotics for non-medical purposes and
on the health of participants that are
conducted so as to ensure that the
protection of health and of minors and
the protection of public order and
Public Safety
and in which if possible cannabis
products are used that are Swiss origin
and that comply with the rules of Swiss
organic farming
so there are certain limitations here as
you see one of the limitation is
location has to be limited to certain
municipality it cannot go and and be
over all of Switzerland that's not
possible time is five years plus an
option for an extension of two years
subject matter has to be clearly within
a scientific scope
and usually in the context of and with
the support of a research Institution
so it's not an easy quick fix it's not
such a quick thing to just say we're
gonna do a pilot project you need to
have money you have to finance a
scientific study
um and usually it's quite capital and
time intensive so I wouldn't
underestimate how complicated it is and
everybody here in Germany that's what
you could learn from us maybe is if
you're interested to to conduct such a
study don't wait until pillar two falls
into place come to Switzerland and see
how it already works and get you know do
your homework
then
findings to be made well again the scope
has to be defined the idea is to to
analyze Health psychological health
physical health
um
in addition to that consumer
behavior is one thing that is being
analyzed youth protection all these
things just Define your scope very
clearly and then you may able to to
um to proceed with that and in the end
the way the way it works now there's
five or six different model projects
that already have been
approved and are getting into motion now
the first one was in Basel and it's a
dispensary in the pharmacy so patients
can sign up to the study it's a few
hundred people we were always concerned
because many of these people they have
to give their name their address they
have to report back on a regular basis
there's data being collected on these
people and we always said before me
including I was completely wrong that
people will not do it people already are
that cannabis readily available they can
buy why sign up for this and go all this
length and the reality is that it was
pretty much sold out you know in a few
days it was just filled no problem
everybody wouldn't and the main reason
for that is that people want to get a
clean product there's an excellent track
and Trace solution that is implemented
in Switzerland in in conjunction with uh
with a privately held company that one
attender from the Ministry of Health
essentially to conduct try can trace so
it's very transparent
and one of the biggest issues in
Switzerland today is that you have
cannabis products out there and cannabis
is probably one of the most dangerous
drugs period in the market today because
a lot of it is spiced up and has
synthetic cannabinoids and synthetic THC
and is incredibly potent and people
don't know what they're buying so the
interest was really really there to to
get access to these to these trials and
we're all now waiting for the Zurich
trial to commence where we have uh 21
points of sale
including 10 pharmacies and 10 Social
Clubs so let's see how that rolls out
greatly thank you yeah that's what we
all fearing that we have these model
projects implemented within the next
five years until we have designed
defined the study design the financing
security Etc and then another five years
evaluation period so maybe there will be
a legalization in Germany in the next
decade may I just add one thing to that
the model projects are just one layer
there's another layer in Switzerland
that is going on which is on the
political Arena because there was a
parliamentary initiative in parallel
that has been launched and the the
essentially the parliament or the the
health commissions that are relevant in
the context already approved a full
legalization
of cannabis in Switzerland okay that
doesn't mean that it's going to happen
very soon but it does mean that since I
know you mentioned this initiative and
nothing's happening well well there is a
subcommittee now in Switzerland that is
actually already working on drafting the
legislation together obviously with the
federal Office of Public Health
and I very much hope that they're
looking at Germany
and that they say we can be a bit more
courageous than that good
Bob you you heard that no commercial
route in Germany why did you still come
that's a great question no I Germany
needs to be comfortable with a medical
system that has elements of a commercial
adult use system that's a fact you have
to use from a commercial standpoint and
let's face it we are all about having
access to patients we're all about a
medical framework here but for
businesses to survive what has to happen
you guys know the answer to this
question for a business to survive there
has to be an economic model for there to
be an economic model you need to have
purchasers on a regular basis for all of
the wears that come out of all of the
expensive infrastructure so Germany
needs to get comfortable with this
notion that it's going to have a medical
model that is slippery you know what I
mean by slippery meaning it that it is
in certain ways masquerading as an adult
use program and that's okay it doesn't
have to be called adult use for us to be
comfortable with it have giving adult
use elements it just has to be legal and
regulated so that the purchaser is
buying something that's consistent and
quality driven that's the most important
point and my U.S perspective is Tainted
a bit because that's how it started in
the United States in Most states right
Look at California as a Pioneer look at
Oregon Colorado where I call home
Colorado once we had 100
000 patients registered in a medical
marijuana program it was Game Over It
was a commercial regulated system we
have in Colorado what we call a severe
pain catch-all meaning if I have a
migraine you talk about the cluster
headaches if I have back pain I qualify
to purchase as much cannabis as I'm
lawfully allowed to purchase
that opened the floodgates because I
didn't really have to have a technical
medical condition I just had to have an
experience of pain validated by a
physician well if I wanted to game the
system
if I wanted to go to a doctor and say
Doc my back hurts can you give me a card
to let me purchase cannabis nine out of
10 times a doctor's going to do that so
the system became a bit strained but
what did it do it created the financial
and economic legs underneath of it which
were necessary for it to survive you
can't just start a system have everybody
line up at the start line build
infrastructure and then give a trickle
of patience to the existing system that
needs patients consumer dollars so I'm
also a bit jaded Kai in that medical
marijuana in the United States doesn't
really mean medicine
that doesn't mean that there's not a
medicinal benefit to cannabinoids we all
know that's true I hope we all know
that's true that's why we're here it
just means that the purchaser has to
qualify under a condition
it just qualifies the purchaser another
way to qualify the purchaser is to say
You must be 21 years old or over it's
the exact same thing so medical cannabis
in the U.S simply means safe consistent
access to cannabis for whatever reason I
should choose to use it and I think
that's the notion that that we need to
get comfortable with particularly here
in Germany it's a fascinating experiment
guy and that's why I'm here is to see it
happen in real time obviously to to hang
out and see great friends and to see
what's happening because it happens
uniquely country by country two other
points I'd like to make quickly and that
is you have to understand a
jurisdiction's why the reason that the
jurisdiction legalizes cannabis it's
critical because not any jurisdiction
legalizes it for the same purpose
sometimes it's for adult use sometimes
it's Criminal Justice Reform so
sometimes it's Social Justice Reform
sometimes it's because you need an
economic driver you need job creations
don't look at any of those reasons and
go oh that's not why we're doing it and
look down on it it doesn't matter what
you think it matters what the sentiment
is in that jurisdiction so you have to
understand that and then the last thing
I'll note
at least now is there's really four
models for cannabis legalization there's
four policy Lanes they exist already we
don't need to invent them there's the
industrial Lane speaks for itself the
second lane FDA or the equivalent
approved formulations Pharma
the third lane
nutraceutical products Products that
come from the cannabis plant that are
for health-based purposes that don't
produce an intoxicating effect the
fourth Lane
OTC you understand OTC over the counter
OTC cannabis in Germany you mix all
three of the last ones that's not
sustainable you can't mix
over-the-counter cannabis FDA approved
medicines and nutraceuticals they have
to be separated because the systems
already exist policy makers bureaucrats
business owners are used to those three
lanes existing independently right now
you throw them all together under the
guise of medical and maybe just a little
bit with this social club experiment
that's coming that it begins to open up
that OTC Lane just a little bit just
enough so that's the future not because
I say it but I think it matters that
it's coming from a lawyer because we're
trying aim to respect and understand
existing policy Frameworks those
Frameworks exist already stop trying to
reinvent the wheel
thank you Bob thank you
hmm
so what I take away from this is the the
medical cannabis Market in the US where
the facilitator uh facilitating the
recreational Market uh in fact and you
had also like model projects or Social
Clubs did they play any role in in the
US in in the during the legalization we
should answer please we still struggle
in the U.S with this idea of consumption
uh where to consume Social Clubs uh you
know having an element of consumption
allowance we don't we don't really
Embrace that in the United States we're
starting to get around our heads around
that uh Nevada Las Vegas will be an
interesting interesting way to see how
this evolves other states have evolved a
little bit but the social club model is
not something that's uh really in Vogue
and and really not understood uh policy
makers want to legalize it but they want
a very tightly controlled supply chain
down to the consumer who does what pays
tax tax money that's all the governments
care about got it yeah yeah
Michael we have one minute left for uh
or is it the panel over soon one
question if possible please and then
we're over
yeah yes 1250 yes let's hear it for Kai
Newman and everybody first of all
we have time for a quick question not a
long history of your personal use with
cannabis before you discovered just one
anybody have one quick question there
there's a microphone right there for you
sir or Michael will run up to you he's
going You're Gonna hurry up he's going
that's right
he's wearing the comfortable shoes look
how his hair bounces in the wind yeah
thanks uh just a very quick question
um how do you think uh especially in
Germany and Europe will we go into the
direction of clinical trials as
currently in Germany uh cannabis is an
unlicensed medicine so will we get
um
cannabis flowers that have an Mah a
marketing authorization or will there be
different models maybe using
observational data real world evidence
or like a shortcut or will it just stay
as it is at the moment to be unlicensed
yeah I think for flowers it will be
difficult because they are not
protectable and there are so many
flowers right now in the German Market
that's really difficult to get a group
of patients together to really get some
data data which will talk for itself for
extracts I think it is different
um there you have a bit more of
differentiation and then now there are
already some studies going on and there
will be more studies going on to gather
data and show exactly what effect has it
for patients in different indications
thank you
I would add to that that there's never
anything which is impossible
um in my Korean Pharma we started like
medical gases impossible to register
biological is impossible to register uh
I can name a few other parts at the end
they have been registered there is the
correlation proof of concept in a
product so the indication and the
product has to fit and if you have here
proof of concept then Happy Days and
once I want just one to say one
something or to add before my pizza
seller says you can make the best pizza
in town but if nobody knows you will not
sell one piece and maybe you think about
here about the situation in Germany so
if not the doctors are not knowing what
you have they will not prescribe it and
I think there are a lot of wonderful
models who do a perfect job on that so
if you look for that I think you will
find your way and a very successful high
margin way to be in the market
thank you all so very much that was
fantastic one more time foreign