thank you appreciate it thanks good
morning everybody how many people went
to the party last night and still are
making it here this morning okay that's
pretty impressive I didn't uh so uh but
that's good to be here thank you so much
for coming uh so today's presentations
is like intended to talk a little bit
about data and not just data um for a
sake of talking about data but data that
we actually know exists
um but before we get started I really
want to thank all the uh organizers from
ICPC this has been a really great
conference this is actually our third
year here I also want to thank the the
teams working with me in metric uh for
getting us prepared for for this and
then I also want to thank all of you
again too for all the great panel
discussions and uh and and uh
experiences that have been shared uh
yesterday and I'm sure there's gonna be
more today in fact as we've been
listening to everybody talk this uh last
couple of days
um it's really started to solidify some
of the thinking that we have around what
the potential is uh here uh in Europe
for a larger scale commercial Market
that includes more medical sales and
also at some point adult use sales so
this is the agenda we're going to first
of all just kind of talk a little bit
about my background and some of the work
that we've done creating centralized
supply chain data and then we're going
to talk a little bit more about how that
data actually gets transitioned into
actionable insights we'll actually share
a little bit of information from inside
the system that we utilize and then
transition some of that into some
thinking about how that might actually
look here in Germany and then start to
maybe prognost a little prognosticate a
little bit on what a market here might
look like in Germany
so
um I know and we've heard it like quite
a few times uh this week uh that there's
like I think a a sense of disappointment
um and skepticism around the path that
Germany has charted for itself
especially since April of this year when
we all were kind of thinking this time
last year when I was presenting at the
same conference that there was this
potential for a very large German Market
that would then also start to encourage
other member states within the EU to
take up more canvas policy but after
April I think everyone and like our we
took a hard look at it too saw this big
Market potential which we knew was going
to be challenging really shrink and
almost get kicked down the road a little
ways where we were really starting to
get concerned about how soon this was
was going to happen and so my background
so you know is is both in government
service but also uh in the private
sector and in government service I was
the director of the Colorado marijuana
enforcement division in 2013 going into
2014 when we first started adult use
legalized sales there in the country
and at the time we had really three
goals uh that were preoccupying our
thinking the first one was to do
everything we could to disrupt the
illicit market and then supplant that
illicit Market with a viable commercial
Market that could produce a much safer
product at at scale to Consumers and
then the third one which was not
unimportant but was we wanted to limit
the amount of exposure that children had
to cannabis products whether they were
illicit products or commercialized
products and so that was back in 2013
going into 2014. those are the exact
same goals that we see we keep here get
repeated by countries that are
contemplating more permissive cannabis
policy
and so now since that time we've been
part of and I've been part of close to
two dozen different implementations of
cannabis policy and as we've seen it
played out we've seen a lot of different
approaches to that cannabis policy and
uh we
um have seen a lot of successes and a
lot of failures but when we lay over all
that experience over the pathway that
German Germany has stated we still see a
viable path forward for a commercial
Market at scale that can be done within
the confines of a scientific framework
that would help
not only address some of the the
concerns and the goals the government
has for legalization but to actually
build sustainable investable Marketplace
for cannabis in here which is great news
I think for everybody in the the room
who's really focused on kind of the
business side of this
so what I'm going to do today is I'm
going to use supply chain data to kind
of illustrate
and substantiate some of the things that
we think could be like outlined as
success factors for countries in Europe
to follow based on kind of what we know
from from other marketplaces
so sticking with the nostalgic look back
on my experiences in in government
when we first started regulating
cannabis uh in 2013 and 2014 for adult
use
um in Colorado we were we were cons we
were we were like aware of the fact that
there was a dearth of data that was
available in fact one of the first
things we started to realize is that
there were massive gaps in data where
people assumed there would be data so
for example we assumed that there was
data that existed already on youth
consumption rates or driving under the
under the influence of cannabis or
testing data Etc there was just like
what we what we learned is that that
data hadn't been collected at all during
the uh prior to adult use legalization
and so as a as a as a state and as a
government
we we became hyper focused on trying to
collect the right data to be able to
inform the market and we realized at
that time that we were going to have to
recreate the data structures to collect
the data and start all over with brand
new Baseline data which is probably to
some extent true in a lot of the
countries here in Europe
we are also cognizantly aware of the
fact that the industry was brand new
it's not what it didn't have the same
appearance that it does in a lot of ways
today it wasn't uncommon at all for us
to see handwritten labels
um on on on products that were being
sold at retail
um it wasn't uncommon we actually saw
concentrate production done in slow
cookers we call them crock pots in the
U.S or washing machines they did we saw
cold water extraction of of cannabis
concentrates in older washing machines
uh and and then we also saw packaging
that was probably more similar to what
you would see at a high school bake sale
than an actual retail Marketplace and so
there was a lot of business aptitudes
that just didn't exist at the time and
so we knew that this would be
challenging for this new Marketplace to
in the in the actors within the
marketplace to actually be able to
comply with a comprehensive set of
regulations so we we needed a tool we
needed a tool to have some visibility
into to the supply chain and we needed a
tool to help start collecting data so
that we could describe what was
happening in the marketplace to the
population writ large to demonstrate
that there was some credit bill and then
also be able to compare and contrast
some of that data to Showcase what was
happening in the industry we also were
really cognizant of the fact that
government success in this area of
public policy is indelibly tied to the
business success and so we wanted to
make sure that the tools were available
for small medium-sized businesses to be
able to comply what we landed on was
supply chain track excuse me supply
chain tracking and just a quick little
overview of how that works in almost
every supply chain tracking system
there's a physical tag that goes on
every plant
that follows that plant all the way
through its life cycle all the way up
until the point where it gets harvested
and then as the plant material is
packaged into other things like trimmed
to go to a manufacturer for concentrate
Productions or testing batches going to
testing facilities or buds go going to
storefront
all those those products get packaged
and they get transported to various
other license premises and it's tracked
all the way through the supply chain and
all of those data events are collected
from the time it's a little baby plant
all the way to the time it's sold at the
point of sale so every movement from one
room to the next the date of the Harvest
how much the yields were the results of
the tests how much it sold for at
wholesale how long it takes to transport
it to a a facility and then how much
it's sold for at the point of sale those
things and everything else is collected
along the entire supply chain so
government has transparency into what
the the licensed Community or the
regulated Community is reporting in and
businesses then can uh
um if the government chooses to can see
a lot of the aggregated data from the
supply chain to help make strong
business decisions going forward
so to illustrate this a little bit
further we're going to talk a little bit
more about some of the actionable data
that comes from uh having a centralized
platform where many of the stakeholders
within the Cannabis uh
um many stakeholders within the Cannabis
industry co-create value with one
another and so what we've done is we've
created what we would call like a sample
jurisdiction or fictional jurisdiction
to demonstrate some of uh what you can
see in our system and I'm going to start
with two slides that are going to be the
bookends of the supply chain one is is
like how much cannabis is output by a
particular Market followed by what does
adequate to in sales and so think of
this as a if if you're trying to like
frame the size of the sample Market that
we've created for you think of it as a
state that's somewhere between 10 to 12
million people in population
that has a long-standing medical program
and an adult use program that's been
ramping up since around uh 2019 for the
First full year and what you can see
here kind of looking a couple of years
after this Market's really been up and
running that the commercial Market takes
time to be able to supply all of the
inputs into the product categories so in
2020 we are at 181 metric tons in our in
our sample Market by the time we got to
2022 we were closer to 925 metric tons
so if you put that into perspective you
know the how cup study that was here
done here in Germany where they
estimated it at 400 metric tons this is
a market of like 10 to 12 million and
we're seeing something closer to 920
metric tons of cannabis produced and
there's a lot of reasons why there might
that might be it might be that that
edible products or concentrates take up
a big part of the marketplace which also
takes up more plant material and many
other different things but I think what
the the most important thing to
understand is that even if and this kind
of gets to my Unapologetic optimism
around what could happen here in Germany
is even if
uh Germany were to legalize today and
intend on having their initial sales uh
start January 1st of 2024. there is no
way that even the full-scale
legalization model would be able to
accommodate
um the demand for cannabis uh here in
Germany on day one it's going to take a
matter of years for that to be able uh
to ramp up and so when we think about
that in the context of Social Clubs and
model projects they could potentially
produce if done well and at scale in a
sizable enough market of somewhere
around five to ten twelve million people
uh the German of the German Market they
could actually like potentially produce
a fair amount of of the product for the
entire demand in Germany so to kind of
put this in perspective I think a lot of
times and again I know this is a little
self-serving because I have such close
ties to the Colorado model but it's
considered to be one of the more mature
Market places in the world for cannabis
and even though it's been fully
legalized for a number of years now
since 2014 when the first sales began
less than half of the local
jurisdictions in the state of Colorado
allow for cannabis commercialized
operations within the state and if you
look at a state like California which is
massive which is starting to get close
to like half the size of Germany in
terms of population it also has a local
approval requirement in its law and less
than half of those local jurisdictions
have allowed for for cannabis
commercialized activities in in their
jurisdictions so that means that Supply
in those States is coming like that goes
to people who live in in cities or
counties that do not allow for
commercialized cannabis they're still
able to supply
um the Cannabis that people are going to
consume
so this was one end of the bookend the
the inputs into the system this is the
other end this is the sale so if you
look at our sample Market
we see that buying patterns are also a
little slower to shift so overnight
consumers are not going to trust that
the commercial market and all the
products that are produced in that
market are fit for their needs and there
just might be supply shortages that
prevent that from happening but we see
that buying patterns also kind of follow
a similar trajectory where
uh um the the consumers are uh
purchasing more and more over time and
then businesses are ramping up or
scaling their operations to be able to
meet that but again it doesn't happen
overnight it takes a little bit of time
for this to happen
so this is a a bit of an eye chart so I
want to take a little bit of time to
explain it so we've looked at
um both all the the inputs uh to the
supply chain and we've looked at what
the total sales so now we can start
taking a look at the breakdown of of
sales or what the breakdown sales look
by product category so for you all in
the upper left-hand corner of the screen
is the market share per product category
so we have seven categories that we've
listed here for our sample Marketplace
and what we do here what we did here is
we took the sales
that we had from the previous slide and
we broke it down within the category so
you can start to get a little better
understanding of how much of the various
product categories are purchased and
consumed so on our slide here roughly 45
to 50 percent of the market has
consistently been with smokable Bud that
goes directly to the store from
cultivations
followed by concentrates and think of
concentrates as essentially like vaping
products and other types of concentrates
along with infused Edibles that are a
bit of a distant third in comparison to
those two
categories of buds and concentrate and
then on the right hand side because this
is a very important issue is you're able
to actually track what happens to
pricing of products over time so in a
saturated Market where we think that
there's overproduction of cannabis
oftentimes we see prices really starting
to decline rather than the scenario that
we have here where can this bud is
actually kind of like continuing to
climb throughout the first five five
years of legalization and we also start
to see concentrate Productions start to
decline in this particular scenario
now don't know exactly why that is but
this is giving us some information to
kind of like indicate that there's a
change or a shift in the marketplace I'm
just going to go back here to this slide
real quick
um speaking of the product categories
the the the the graph at the bottom is
just kind of charting out you know how
sales and each one of those product
categories has changed uh from the early
Inception of legalization all the way to
2023.
here we just kind of take a closer look
at the buds and concentrates and and
what's happened with those over time
because they seem to be kind of like
competing with one another for Market
space in this particular sample Market
that we created for you here and it also
might be on the concentrate side that
those have become much more popular
products and so they're producing more
and more of those and as they uh as more
of them are available in the supply
chain than uh um the prices are
decreasing too the bottom line though is
that we can always look again kind of
going back to this slide we can always
kind of look at these things to get a
closer look at in more detail so while
I'm showing you the aggregate kind of
bigger picture data we can drill down
all the way into or government can drill
down all the way into the the
um different categories of products to
get more insights which also is kind of
like uh kind of gets us to this next
slide though as I mentioned earlier like
part of the reason we want to have the
kind of like centralized collection
point for data so that we can inform and
evolve the policy as we see changes in
the marketplace that might be negatively
impacting businesses within the
community within that that regulated
community and one of the more common
things that we hear when when concerning
ourselves about market segments is what
is the impact going to be when adult use
is implemented on medical programs that
already existed beforehand and what we
see here is kind of like a common uh
pattern that we've that we've seen in a
lot of different states where
the adult use legalization as it's
ramping up we actually see increases in
patient counts and and medical sales as
the regulated adult youth Market is
really kind of starting to take hold and
then as the adult use sales surpass the
medical sales then we start to see those
decline back to what they were prior to
legalization and there could be a lot of
reasons for that it could have to do
with
pricing and adult use and medical being
in parity with one another and so
patients migrate back towards the adult
use Market
or like in some of our states we
actually see where the medical sales are
saying somewhat steady and that might be
because that the products that are
offered to patients are altogether
different than the products that are
offered to in the adult use market so
there are markets still in the U.S where
the the
medical products are more focused on
high potency low calories versus lower
potency products that are offered in the
uh in the in the Market at any rate if
you look at the the data that's down
towards the bottom of the slide it's a
it's a lot of data but it's still
looking at how not only are we looking
at the different segments and gross
sales but we're also looking at how
those different customers are are and
their buying patterns are shifting over
time so we can we can tell if a patient
purchases are shifting away from
smokable cannabis to concentrates or
edibles or vice versa and then we can
take a much closer look at what's
happening in the marketplace to make
informed decisions about that both as a
business but also as Government actors
too
here's a quick close or a closer look at
at the cultivation so going back to
cultivation uh one thing that I think is
really important to mention here is or
just like to kind of point out to you is
the the number 226 so when we put our
data together we ended up with actually
a fairly High number any cultivators
here in the in the audience all right so
you know that's a pretty high number of
what you probably celebrate if you had
226 that you packaged out of every plant
so that's a pretty sizable number but
again this is like intended to be
directional and give us a a like an
insights into what the marketplace looks
like so this is along the y-axis is 2018
to 2023 and across the x-axis is January
to March and this is a heat map so the
lighter the color the less the yields
were on average during that month
um the darker the color the higher the
yields were and if you look at this like
at a diff like from a different
perspective you'll see that almost every
September and October there's this
massive spike in the the number or the
amount of yield per plant and that
almost always has to do with that being
the time of year where outdoor
cultivations which are included in our
sample jurisdiction are harvested and
they tend to have a little bit higher
numbers so like the the takeaway from
this though is and what's really
interesting and happy to talk more
detail with anybody in the room about
this is laters we did a an analysis on
what this might mean for Social Clubs so
if a social club just say it was like
200 grams was the gold standard per
plant you harvested if you were only
able to do that like 65 percent of that
your first year in production uh and you
had 500 customers as part of of or 500
members as part of your Social Clubs and
assuming that those three plants that
you're allowed to home grow can be
delegated to the Social Club a social
club a good grower would be able to
harvest those three plants four times a
year and if they were able to do that
and assuming that the numbers that were
used using to kind of inform the
analysis out of our system they'd
actually be as big or bigger than 50
percent of the regulated cultivations
that exist in the U.S those are rough
rough directional numbers but Social
Clubs could potentially be significantly
sized and so that kind of gets us
thinking about like that that the the
um different schools of thought on how
Social Clubs should be structured going
forward one is is that if they can be
sizable that there probably should be
some form of sensible kind of like a
small scale regulation and transparency
of that Marketplace and then the other
side of it that we think about a lot is
is the the reality that those uh that
those social clubs are probably going to
at some point want to transition into
the the fully regulated for-profit model
so thinking strategically now uh like
how do we start to collect data on those
that we can better understand how
they're impacted over time when the
Market continues to grow with regional
model projects Etc
so uh
now I want to kind of transition a
little bit out of that but before I do
um what I want to just like like really
drive home on all the data that we just
looked at in the previous half a dozen
or so slides is that that data that
we've collected has been proven in every
state that we operate and we operate in
23 different states plus there's other
companies that do similar work to us so
almost every state in the U.S and Canada
they do some form of track and Trace
data and that data has been proven to be
evidentiary in in value and if it's
evidentially and very evidentiary in
value in a Judicial System it can also
certainly be used as evidence to support
science and and I think we've like we've
heard a couple of times today that's
very important whatever framework gets
adopted in the EU under current
circumstances for regional model
projects has to fit into a scientific
framework and we think that the data
that exists right now for describing
what happens in the markets and then
being able to compare it and contrast
between the various model projects is is
is uh is a is a viable path forward for
creating Regional model projects that
can be done at scale so that the market
is is is supports business models like
all of yours and it also supports
investment into those those business
models something that makes it
sustainable going forward
so
um
getting into the thought experiment on
Germany and to kind of elaborate a
little bit more on what I just shared we
took some sample data from our system
and we randomly plant uh plugged it into
Germany kind of like pretending that
Germany's been legalized or we've been
tracking cannabis data for for the last
five years and again I mentioned that
it's really important like from up from
a scientific standpoint for uh
government officials to be able to
describe and compare and contrast we've
randomly assigned data from different
areas within the U.S market into states
to kind of just demonstrate for you
please don't put a lot of stock on these
numbers it's like we really think that
there's going to be a billion dollars in
sales
um in barbaria I think we know barbaria
is probably
one of the states that may be slower to
take up Regional products but the the
idea is that you're able to use the data
that's collected within a shared system
where everyone's co-creating value and
be able to compare and contrast what's
happening in those regions and then you
can even take a little bit deeper dive
into
those various regions and get a better
understanding of what might be happening
with those like for example with product
category sales this is just one example
and we could look at test results we
could look at transports we could look
at
plant yields we could look at almost
anything that's in the system and we can
start to be able to compare and contrast
what's happening within those
jurisdictions and we think this is a
very important
aspect of creating a scientific
framework and we also think it kind of
fits into that that definition although
it's a little bit different way of
thinking than I think we've seen in
other attempts at adult use legalization
outside the U.S
um
so with that I want to uh
kind of like close with a couple of of
thoughts that we've had as we are
watching closely What's Happening Here
in Europe one is like we're actually
really excited about what the potential
is here and one of the reasons why we're
so excited is we've seen this replicated
time and time again where government
collaborates with the industry and other
uh stakeholders that exist within the
ecosystem
to support an industry's effort to
supplant the illicit market and replace
it with safer products and we've been
able to like we've been able to see
government like balance the the
regulatory requirements not always but
like in some cases be able to balance
those regulatory requirements with the
business needs like some of the
businesses have been successful and
while we recognize and we're not tone
deaf to the reality that
um the market in the U.S and a North
American General is is definitely
experiencing some hardships along with
some of the other economic downturn that
exists but we do know that if you have
the right data structures in place they
can help to inform that policy when
things are a little bit tougher and able
to
right-size the regulation over time no
matter what happens you're not going to
get the the regulations and the laws
correct the first time so you have to
have the right data there to be able to
inform how different actors within the
market are being impacted and you can do
that at the same time collaborating and
partnering on what's important to
protect Youth and public health within
within the market
and so
um
we we've seen
traceability platforms work successfully
in a lot of different markets and I've
put that into perspective of what's
Happening Here
um in Europe and in particular today
it's focusing a little bit more
um on Germany
is that research is going to be
key for regional model projects and we
think that the research can be
structured in such a ways where you can
have a scalable Regional Model Market
Place that's investable and and
sustainable and we think that that while
that's happening that this could also be
done
alongside of what is already a viable
Medical Market here in Germany that can
coexist alongside of the adult use
Market but to ensure that that's that's
more likely to happen
we think that it's important for the
data to be collected so you can actually
kind of showcase and be able to
demonstrate what what uh um different
decisions on the regulatory front of
kind of impact that they're having on
various segments of the market and and
in including the medical market and then
the last one uh just the recognizing the
fact that
every time every time with almost almost
without exception where there's been a
small allowance or a modest allowance
for
um like an unregulated non-profit uh
um a framework for providing cannabis
whether it's in a medical or whether
it's an adult use it always always takes
on the form of a commercial Market at
some point maybe not right out of the
shoot but a couple of years down the
road so it almost always takes on the
appearance of a commercial framework so
since we know that to be the case and
and and we know that Social Clubs has
has the potential to be one of the the
key policy lovers that Germany wants to
to pull here then
knowing that those are eventually going
to be taking on a commercial appearance
then now is a really good time to start
thinking strategically about how Social
Clubs can scale and grow to meet some of
the demand which out of the shoot but
also have a viable option at some point
in the future to be able to transition
into what uh we also think is likely to
happen which is a more full-scale adult
use Marketplace
and I'll close uh right where I started
which is
our experience tells us that
government's successful implementation
of cannabis policy is tied very closely
to business success so businesses are
not successful in a regulated framework
the perception is because it has it's
grounded in reality is that the
government wasn't successful and so that
we have to have both of those empties
among another like another couple
different sets of stakeholders that
exist within the ecosystem around
cannabis regulation to be able
uh to work together and collaborate for
the common good the public health and
safety concerns but also
um the the important aspects of creating
a sustainable Market uh where businesses
can Thrive
um over the Long Haul so I want to thank
you again uh for your time today I think
I'm I'm really close to being right on
time for uh for where we were and I want
to thank you again for all being here
this morning waking up early I really
appreciate you and to the extent that we
can uh elaborate on any of the data that
I showed today I'm happy to meet with
people one-on-one and share some of our
dashboards and some of our data and
expand on some of our thoughts we're
also happy to hear push back and
different opinions on how we think this
might go again I'm the Unapologetic
Optimist in the room when it comes to
what we think is possible but it's
grounded in a lot of the experiences
that we've seen
watching cannabis regulation unfold in a
couple dozen different jurisdictions so
thanks again for for the time Lewis
Koski