Maya hello everyone my name is Chris
bite I'm one of the subject matter
experts and founders of isolocity we are
a quality management software that helps
cannabis companies across the world
automate their qms compliance that's
what we do and we make headaches go away
jorgon
yeah my name is Jurgen bikel I'm a
co-founder and managing director of
stores and pickle we are producing
vaporizers as maybe one or the other now
the most famous one is our Volcano
Vaporizer for those of you handheld
products
hello everybody my name is Louis Koski
I'm the chief strategy officer for
metric we're a leading track and Trace
provider in the United States we provide
track and Trace to 23 different
government agencies across the country
in in Guam and we've been uh spending
quite a bit of time investing into a
better understanding What's Happening
Here in the European market over the
last 18 months so really looking forward
to the conversation
hi everybody my name is natal partowski
I'm the founder and CEO of a company
called sorting robotics we build robots
for cannabis manufacturers our main one
being the chico robot a device that
infuses joints and Blunts and pre-rolls
with cannabis concentrate among that we
do a bunch of other various robotics
Technologies Vision systems vaporizer
filling and uh yeah it's interesting
being here in Berlin and meeting
everyone in the different sector so
looking forward to talk
hello hi guys my name is Hans I'm
Regional director for sisa for Europe
so Caesar is part of small small Tech is
the largest
web equipment manufacturer in the world
and Cesar is their brand which is
dedicated to making hardware for
vaporizers for distillate Life resin
Rose and high viscosity extracts
basically so um thanks
sweet thanks guys appreciate it and
today I have the pleasure of being the
moderator of this High-Tech high times
panel all right guys so talking about
where technology is going not just from
The Producers perspective but also the
end consumers how does technology need
to change to help this industry become
more successful and safer for the
consumer
You're Gonna Let You Nail this one and
then we'll go along
yeah of course um of course the
vaporizer is a high-tech device yeah we
know that uh yeah from a design uh
perspective you need to be very careful
what you are doing uh people at the end
of the day are inhaling this is uh so so
the vapor you are producing is getting
into the lungs so yeah and on the
technology side it is very important to
have their very high quality and of
course technology goes through
everything you do it goes through your
design it goes through your production
process things like traceability are
extremely important in our case to
produce a medical device it is the
certification is very important like
either selling for 85. we have no new
certifications available from UL 8139
it's new standard who is used for
vaporizers uh what VR follow at least
with every new product and of course on
the end on a customer site diet of
course all of our new products they have
coming with an app yeah you're always
able to control your device with SNAP
but you're also able to get statistics
out of it yeah you can see how long you
used it what is your main temperature
you're using it and of course it gives
also feedback to us once we get a device
back on hand to see how it was used yeah
and how was it if it was if there was a
failure or what was the failure so it
improves the experience for the customer
and it improves our database to make
better products in the future okay great
loose before I get to you it's
interesting so it's kind of like that
the car model right where the cars are
now analyzing how you're driving it and
feeding that information back to the
oems so what type of improvements have
you guys made based on key data points
that you've collected like from can be
like an example of a product enhancement
you've done that has met consumer Trends
or uses
yeah in in our case the
what we have seen a lot of seeing how
people are using and which temperature
they are using it right yeah this was
one of the main the main things we got
back and but at the end this is uh what
the car the customer can do by himself
oh interesting all right Lewis now
taking a look at the back-end
infrastructure of any producer and
being from North America and being
immersed in that market what are certain
things that you are seeing or that you
guys are predicting at metric that the
evolution of data flow from seed to
Consumer but how do how are we making
those more efficient as well for the
chemistry producers
yeah so um so those of you don't know
metric is uh is a platform that
government uses to collect data from the
supply chain so every actor that is
active along a supply chain in a
commercial Market
it contributes data along the supply
chain and ends up being this massive
this massive data set that government
uses to help inform policy and kind of
evolve it over time so what we've seen
happen is is that not only does that
data set really help government be able
to create some efficiencies but it also
serves businesses really well and we
think the future of it is like the is
the potential for information sharing
where businesses and technological
solutions that are contributing or
participating in the platform can
co-create value with one another along
the entire supply chain so when it comes
to ways in which we're creating
efficiencies in Supply chains first and
foremost the data that's collected in in
track and Trace systems is intended to
be collected during the normal course of
business when businesses are collecting
data that's important for making
business decisions anyway and then
second because there's been somewhat of
a reluctance some from a very large
technical companies to get involved in
the canvas Industries in particular in
North America and in the US where it's
still illegal federally there's been a
lot of innovation and a lot of new tech
startups that are providing a lot of the
services to businesses to help
streamline some of the reporting
requirements that go to the government
but also be able to streamline and
better informed business decisions that
they make throughout the entirety of the
supply chain so it's it ends up being an
ecosystem of data collection that's
capable of being shared amongst many
different actors within the in the
system
that's again to sort of build off that
notion of the tech ecosystem within an
organization the one thing that I've
noticed compared to different Industries
we work in other Industries is that the
tech set up at cannabis companies can
get a little over complicated
what are certain things that individuals
or business owners should be aware of
when they want to get into a technology
package is it looking at the ecosystem
that it plays with Integrations are
those important maybe we can just build
a little bit on that yeah so we actually
see both we see
um you know businesses that are still
collecting or or contributing to data
via spreadsheets or even handwriting and
then later adding it into a system and
other companies that have pretty
sophisticated uh internal systems that
they use and because it's important to
create efficiencies within the
marketplace a lot of businesses have
worked with their software providers to
actually integrate in with the system so
for our for example in our system
there's been over 500 companies that
integrate with metric to either to grab
information and get it out of our system
but also to put information back into it
yeah thank you all right let's talk
about automation a little bit shall we
so what trends and Evolutions are we
going to be able to see how cans
producers actually produce cannabis well
maybe we can touch on that a little bit
yeah I mean the Automation in the
Cannabis industry is I would say Stone
it's an Asian form because the industry
itself is still kind of figuring things
out and to Lewis's Point how he's in
some companies be you know lightly
software driven and some being very
heavy I would say right now there's a
pretty high variability in how much
people use automation to manufacture
finished goods and it plays into the
fact that
there's so much change in what the end
product is going to be that it's not
like a traditional manufacturing and not
traditional automation where you can
build these huge facilities that are
going to pump out hundreds of thousands
of units an hour because there's no
volume that's like that so I think we're
going to start seeing automation that
pops up that's things that we make where
all of the devices are made for high
variability because this plant is
something that we're still discovering
we're still trying to understand what
are going to be the Staple skus in every
dispensary what are going to be the
Staple skus in every market and we're
also going to start seeing them become
smarter so less like dumb automation
that's huge and massive treadmills of
products coming down the line
and more small variable iot systems like
everything that we make is built off of
a database and all that database is
going to be synced with the Erp system
of the company and then it's going to be
synced with metric and it's going to be
a much smarter manufacturing because
we're not starting this industry in the
1300s OR 1960s like we have you know we
have the internet and we should embrace
it as we are building out your
automation but let's face it though
people were still smoking weed 1300
years ago yeah they still were smoking
of course they were all right no good
question though on that so talk about
the Automation and some people in this
room may have cannabis facilities that
produce grow extract Etc what are key
data points they should be looking at in
their operation to inform them that
maybe it's time to move towards an
automated system for production like
what are those key data points that they
should be paying attention to to
understand that the ROI is real and it's
there and they just need to uh got
technology to become efficiently can you
speak on that a little bit yeah actually
so uh me and my team we actually built a
cannabis co-packing company in Oakland
and ran it for three years Oakland
California in the United States and uh
it was surprising because you know we
were a robotics company kind of
sponsoring the development of this uh
Bay Area service provider and we didn't
use a lot of Automation in the beginning
we did it all by hand to make sure we
could understand what exactly the
traditional Market was doing and then
our decision making on like what we
wanted to automate what was the most
important was when the balance between
throughput and the ability to hire
became so difficult that it made sense
just to automate things because uh the
workforce at least in North America
Canada United States
I think the culture has shifted from
people wanting to sit down and do
knockbox their joints and finish them by
hand it's difficult to hire for that
position and so when you get to the
volume level where you can't find you
know another 20 people then it's time to
make the change into Automation and um
it's most of the time better to do it
later yeah even though I mean I would I
would hope you guys buy my machine the
first day you decide to start a cannabis
company but the best time is really when
you hit that break-even point that
breaking point between can I hire more
people and can I maintain the quality by
having a higher amount of volume and
usually that comes like in the pre-roll
range if you're doing more than 10 000
pre-reals a week in the co-packing range
like for jars and bags of flour if
you're doing more than three to five
thousand a week it just doesn't make
sense to do those things by hand but
along with the variability that I
mentioned before
you don't really know what you're gonna
do when you first start right and I've
seen many cannabis companies Canada the
United States they'll spend five ten
fifteen million dollars
building out this whole facility having
this whole idea of what they're going to
do
and then they turn on the lights and
they don't use half the facility or it
turns out the market has shifted and
this product that they were working on
just doesn't make sense anymore or the
form factor has changed or this this new
SKU that's coming out right so I would
say start very slow
look at that Breaking Point
and then automate aggressively from
there yeah and if you look at any
industry and the companies who are the
most successful in that industry are the
ones that have been able to reduce the
direct labor component the most so the
more Capital heavy Capital asset heavier
company is for your production
throughput the more competitive you're
going to be and the more consistency
you're going to have and standardization
and product output which is important
okay let's take this to uh mobile
devices and vape products and so Hans
where what's the next step for Consumer
interaction with their Vape product and
their Vape mechanism yeah well I just um
I would like to look at this a little
bit from a different perspective
um more from a distribution perspective
maybe you know for d2c products which
are sold to end users and
um there's been a large shift over the
last two decades I would say from the
digitalization of sales really well so
it shifted from brick and mortar stores
physical stores to online sales which is
really across all categories it's not
necessarily specific to to cannabis or
high-end you know vaporizers but
um
in B2B transactions for example a
wholesaler today probably needs an
online portal where his customers his
retailers can actually Place their
orders otherwise it's going to be in a
very difficult spot
um and you know they they directly
placed their orders outside of the
regular shop working hours so um but
there's also
consequences on d2c transactions when
you set to end users which is probably
even more important and it's it's a
fundamental issue really which have
arised through this digitalization of
sales really um maybe maybe let's take
an example let's say
let's say urine decides to buy a new
vaporizer and he walks into his favorite
web shop and you know vaporizer store
head shop in titling and um there's
there's the sales guy behind the counter
let's say his name is Dave
and Dave shows young all the different
vaporizers that are available
um not the advantages disadvantages you
try to understand what what Jung really
needs and wants and at the end of the
pitch after 45 minutes Jung has decided
he wants to buy the new Pax Vaporizer
okay and the price tag is 250 euros okay
250 euros so
um Jung has decided that's the one he
wants what he's going to do what he's
going to do before actually you know
finishing this transaction completing
the transaction handing over the money
to death what he's going to do maybe in
the audience what is what is what is
Young going to do before paying actually
those 250 euros in the store
no one
check the price how he's going to check
the price
he's going to Google it of course I
would argue 80 of customers will Google
the price before putting down 250 euros
so that's what Ewing does he actually
goes the price and he finds it at 185
Euros on Amazon
so um
Dave if he sells the device at 250 euros
he's probably going to make 80 bucks on
it let's say 80 bucks if you sell us to
sell it to you and to complete the
transaction you probably needs to sell
it at 190 maybe 200. so he makes 30
bucks maybe and Dave is not very happy
about this he spent an hour with Jurgen
already uh in the stores where other
customers are waiting and he might
reconsider actually restocking that item
and in return he's not going to place an
order to his wholesaler and his
wholesaler not going to place in order
to the manufacturer so at the end of the
day it actually becomes a problem for
everyone involved
and there's you know most large online
retailers today they actually work with
pricing bots so these pricing Bots
that's it's a software which basically
tracks
online pricing for a certain item a
specific item multiple times during the
day and what the software also can do is
to adjust the pricing for an online
store for the specific online store to
actually beat the competitive pricing
beat the competitors and what this ends
up doing is actually downward spiral
where a price goes from 250 to 240 to
230 to 200 you know and just keeps going
down and it's it's a problem for for
retailers obviously because they don't
make their margins anymore even that
online retailer who might sell it at 185
is going to make 15 15 bucks on the
sales that was the hustle probably not
so it's you know most a lot of you
probably from the United States where
you got the map pricing
map minimum advertised pricing
um that's if I understand correctly
that's that's you know you can have
agreements with retailers where they're
probably where they adhere to sell at a
certain retail price and if they don't
you can send them one morning letters so
this is something in Europe it's very
different it's called price fixing and
it's actually illegal so it's actually
sanctioned with heavy fines so it's
nothing you can really do
um
but there's there's other ways you know
um you cannot come up with to influence
and impact that pricing actually I I
really need to put a disclaimer here so
uh the the vaporizer brand I used
earlier and the price is obviously
completely made up right don't take this
too serious please but I just wanted to
illustrate the fundamental issue of this
and there's certain ways of how to
control that through selective
distribution you know the the Dave might
be saying I really like you you're you
know I'm going to give you a free grind
I'm going to give you a cleaning kit and
a carrying case and you still going to
sell it for 230 and still gonna make
good money on it you know so
um but you know different different
companies different approaches uh of how
to actually tackle that propping for
example like apple
um they mostly decided set to sell
direct now
um where they might work with certain
retailers who they only give 10 margins
so they don't actually have the latitude
to play with the pricing that much uh
otherwise they would be operating at law
so it's it's a fundamental issue it's
kind of coming up over the last 10 15 20
years probably and it's becoming more
and more problem and people trying to
figure out how to deal with this
um so this is an example of where
certain enhancements and technology is
actually hurting the industry yeah we're
providing challenges I mean there's
obviously also advantages of
digitalization of sales you know it's
easier for people who live in the
countryside to get products you know
yeah of course okay
we got a few
audience we're going to hand handle
those first and then we're just going to
jump into a general q a afterwards and
thank you for those who submitted these
questions ahead of time
first question is how will the Vape
industry be regulated in Germany's
Medical Market
so who wants to take that please yeah
The Vape industry of course if you want
to be in a in the German Medical Market
uh you must have a medical device and
medical devices are strongly regulated
um and recently we have strong
regulations through the new MDR the
medical device regulations from the EU
yeah we buy was healthier for example
next week we have three days audit by
the Dov two Auditors yeah that's fun we
are in Preparation you need a philosophy
for that for these fans so it's a highly
regulated and it's uh it's a it's a
hurdle on the one hand once you have
thunder hurdle not everybody else can do
it if you look to the vaporizers
worldwide uh start some big list the
only one who really has done it if you
also claiming it but they are not
available on the market so we have done
it but it's a constant effort you have
to do to be really compliant with a
medical device and it is something
different if there is a medical device
or not it's not only the device itself
who is different it's the whole
management of the company and of course
it has also proved that this really has
a therapeutic effect yeah and all this
together uh is it is not so easy but you
can do it if you're you know if you're a
well management company yeah and I think
that's gonna let's just kind of build
some clarification there just because a
company says they are ISO 1345 or 9001
certified it doesn't mean the product is
certified the product certification is a
completely different certification with
the UL certification or CSA if you're in
Canada for example
um so one of those things that if you
see that company is boasting that
they're 9001 or 1345 certified that
doesn't necessarily mean their product
is good I just want to make sure being
the iso guy in the room that everyone
knows the stipulations there but that's
I mean that's a good point but 1345 I
think it's important because it is a
medical device it is delivering a yeah
yeah certain 485 is one of three things
you have to do if you must have the
quality management
audited according to it then the device
itself must be according to depending
which device you have a regulated and
finally yeah the therapeutic effect must
be proven okay all right so another
thank you guys so another question that
has come up uh
and maybe this is something Louis I'd
love to you to handle this one but how
can software and Hardware Integrations
degrees cost in cultivation activities
increased costs no a decrease sorry
decrease costs okay yeah my bad yeah
well I think um uh there's a couple
different technologies that can
certainly help along those lines so for
example in our system we use radio
frequency ID tags uh to tag every plant
and then every package or batch of
product that comes from those inputs
into the supply chain system and then
those tags can actually be read from a
distance so in in terms of taking an
inventory if you have just a barcode or
a QR code you can usually read one tag
at a time and you have to get awfully
close to the tag to be able to to scan
and pull that information with radio
frequency ID tags you can use a reader
that's going to the same size as a
smartphone with a handle and you can
take an inventory relatively quickly as
long as you get within seven meters of
the of the actual RFID tag and you can
pull the information off and then that
that unique identifier that's on the tag
gets you acquainted with all of the data
that has been added into the system from
that so just kind of like put that in
perspective if you had your phone with a
handle on it and every person in this
room had an RFID tag that they were
holding up if you walked up uh this
aisle and down this aisle we'd probably
be able to read most every RFID tag in
this and you'll be able to do it in
whatever the time was it took you to
walk around the that's incredible and
that all gets fed automatically into
metric exactly wow can I uh expand on
that yeah guys please yeah so um we were
this co-packer in Oakland and we started
building a bunch of technology to help
our customers and actually like help our
in-house production and so we did a lot
of hand trimming for people and so when
you trim cannabis as you all know it
doesn't always have the same yield right
some strains a little bit larcier some
strains are a lot more dense and
depending on what strain it is is the
actual veg time and flowering time is
very different and then to compound the
complexity of these different strains
some of them are more exotic and some
will go for different pricing so you
take all these variables together
and so what we did is we built this very
awesome Erp system for trimming and I
think you know we talk about later if
that's important for people but what it
did was something very cool right so you
would give a trimmer a pound of flour
and let's say the yield from that flower
was 65 and then you give them another
strain same trimmer same process of
trimming but the pound yield from or
sorry the kilogram kilogram yield from
there is like uh is maybe 55 so you're
getting roughly you know 15 10 less in
this other one however the pricing and
the market pricing for strain number two
is significantly higher but as it turns
out it actually takes a longer time to
grow and like an indoor grow maybe it's
14 weeks compared to 11 weeks and so
what you can do with technology when
you're actually
tracking from the growing the cost of
the seeds the cost of the vegging all
the way until your final product I guess
maybe you don't need to go to flowering
or your final packaging but maybe
wholesale like finished finished product
you can see what you want to grow over
time because there is a trade-off there
where if something is
takes you know 30 longer to grow but you
have a 30 higher yield but it actually
only commands a market price it's 40
lower than let's say strain a then you
can make your optimization on what you
want to grow depending on what exactly
your final value yield is for that
strain and it's something that only a
few operators I've seen in California
and really the United States actually
have looked into and you know in the
beginning of these markets margins are
very thick and so people are like yeah
let's like grow whatever and sell it and
flip pounds
um But as time goes on and strains
become more accepted and more you know
Common you're going to want to make a
marginal trade-off because that changes
the unit economics of your business
significantly like in the millions of
dollars range so uh that's something
that I think technology has a pretty
it's a it's an exciting amount of impact
and I think not enough people are
looking at that trade-off especially in
the nasian industries like early markets
they start looking at it later when all
the margins get crushed but if you look
at it earlier you can you know
completely take advantage of of that
market pricing Dynamic okay thank you
there's a question that came in around
crop steering and how technology is
going to handle that or Aid crop
steering so first whoever wants to take
this question please go for it but
before we get into it maybe we can
Define what is crop steering
does anyone to handle that
I'm not a cultivator
I worked with a lot of cultivators uh in
terms of their crops there are mostly on
the indoor side and that is that's also
kind of interesting to what I mentioned
before but we have a few friends in
California who are like very
sophisticated crop Growers especially in
the indoor space where you can change
the humidity you can change the CO2
content the nitrogen content
I know several Growers that
actually they'll grow one strain but
they'll sell it under many different
skus because the phenotype expression of
the plant
changes on like the tops the mids and
the bottom of the buds and so you can
start to change the yields of your
plants depending on what
um of the environment you're subjecting
it to and how you're stressing it out
and then you can also change the
phenotype expression so there's a lot of
interesting aspects of I guess crop
steering modification but I would say
not many people really right and is is
AI going there yeah is that what's
happening so I'm pointing out a fellow
Tech geek in the crowd he's a smart guy
with this stuff but so that's nice
because
so AI we can rely on AI and
link into your crop steering
brain of a computer and that's going to
pretty much grow your cannabis for you
with no human interaction
with automated tools I would say
eventually yeah that's that's where
you're getting to because
the unfortunate thing is that many times
the Growers look at growing as an art
form and I think that's because of the
tradition is that unfortunate
honestly I would say for the future of
humanity it is unfortunate how
because if we're ever going to optimize
things we have to look at more in a
sophisticated repeatable fashion and in
a scientific way because if you're
looking at it as an art form it's not
repeatable art by itself subjective art
is an expression so cannabis always be a
repeatable thing
it's food
right but I mean apples are different
everywhere you get a different Apple in
Arkansas than you do in California than
you do in Spain than you do in yeah if I
could jump I mean I'm not really trying
to get super deep into it but no no I'm
sorry one of the things that that I've
been noticing in the past couple of
conferences and I love science and I'm
not denigrating in the science and I
understand that you want to be
consistent and repeatable at all times
but plants don't work like that
I would I would argue that
Garden at home I do and you'd use the
same techniques all the time for all
your things
as well my garden is not as well defined
of an environment as I would like for me
to create a repeatable fashion but if
we're going to aggressively service the
Cannabis Market in a sophisticated way
then you're gonna have to control all
those variables that's controlling the
genetics that's controlling the inputs
that's controlling the environment but
it's also how you end up with only one
sort of banana and it's dying out
yeah but you also have the most amount
of surplus food production in the world
that Humanity has ever seen
so okay I just put it out there so we
can talk about it I mean I do love
boutique cannabis it's great like I I've
seen I mean can it all be booty cannabis
I mean there's not that many people we
can grow a lot of weed
I mean you can but that's not really
like a scalable thing right you're not
going to be able to service the world's
cannabis needs and destroy a black
market that corrodes the fabric
foreign
you don't need to destroy the black
market you can co-op the black market
right hire some hippies get some Growers
who know what they're doing they'd be on
your squad oh I mean right okay I want
the black market too secondly California
has supplied damn near all near all of
the United States for decades and
decades before legalization happens so I
don't think that it's a scalable like
it's a problem of scale or it's a
problem if we won't be able to grow
enough weed if we don't use computers or
make everything exactly right some of
the challenges that I'm having with some
of this newfangled weed is it tastes
horrible
okay it tastes like computers I know
we're kind of off topic and I'd love to
talk to you about this a little later I
know we're running out of time please
continue I'm sorry do you want to be in
a profitable business or an unprofitable
business
and I think that's the decision you have
to be in
cannabis has been the most profitable
decentralized business for decades
okay in an unregulated Market yeah
that's the thing it's on when it's
unregulated like I could play Monopoly
with no rules right
I love playing Monopoly no rules
I always win
um okay are we almost done uh all right
guys you know we got 90 seconds left
um any random questions from the
audience
[Music]
yeah please
I'll be quick Eric Berlin from Dentons
and regardless of any representation
that we have our actions against you uh
what you're doing is amazing uh and I
can say from the perspective of someone
who's worked at the state level now
Federal level for legalization we would
not have gotten as far as we've gotten
without vaporization uh because of the
stigma of the spell and the access to
the product so I thank you for that and
my question is and those I think are
radical changes that have changed the
whole Marketplace even though I know
everyone here likes smoking weed
um the fact that we could legislate on
on without that was really helpful so
where do you see it 10 years from now I
know we have little time but like what's
the change how are we going to be
growing cannabis or using cannabis in 10
years that maybe not everyone here is
picturing
um
have it hooked up directly to your HVAC
no hitting I don't know
yeah um well I believe in 10 years we
still will uh partially smoke weed and a
lot of it will be vaporized a weed and
thank you for the comment yeah it's true
uh if you receive today a jar of dried
flowers you don't know as a patient at
least you don't know what to do with
this you can do a roller joint but it's
not an acceptable medical application
you can make a cookie a tea but if only
the only validated version how to
applicate it is by vaporization by a
medical device
wonderful
yeah I think we're out of time all right
guys look hey that was great thank you
though sorry go ahead what are you gonna
say Chris is going to say thank you oh
sorry I just have a very quick question
are you definitely going to extend your
license for the medic multimedic and for
the volcano in 2024.
because I'm worried that the medical
market for flower will be otherwise dead
if you don't have a vaporizer to
prescribe
yeah you may you refer to the deadline
of the medical device regulation in
newborn of course we are working in it
and we will remain in the market with
medical device uh yeah so as you said
it's absolutely necessary to have this
option available and install some
vehicle is still the only one who is
providing it
one thank you very much it's here for
the panel that was
I appreciate you and uh