yo how y'all feeling this morning you
feeling good at the ICBC everyone
my name is Alex Rogers I'm the CEO and
founder of the ICBC I um I started this
event I came to Berlin in 216.
and I had a vision of B2B cannabis in
Europe something similar to what was
going on in America at the time and I
came over here and everybody said I was
crazy literally you know my German
friend said Alex Alex we are very
worried for you you know we we are how
do you say a frugal people 500 a ticket
is too much for us and I said and they
said we're very worried and they're very
direct in your very direct germanness
and I said well I'm very worried too
thank you very much for that uh brutal
honesty but what it made me do is it
made me work even harder to make this
vision and dream come true and all I did
was just you know put some blank pages
out and you guys filled all those blank
pages so the Cannabis industry the ICBC
you guys this is where it all gets done
this is where we we we we catapult the
industry at a rapid rate to the next
level now the first thing I said when I
got on stage in 217 at the first ICBC
was that the policy makers and the
administrators would pardon my French
even though we're in Germany things
up and that's normal because I had
already been in jurisdictions where I
had seen administrators you know it's
politics we understand whether it's with
tax or regulations or cumbersome fees
you know the idea is to take it off the
the black market right and I think
people will pay a little bit more to
know that they have a regulated product
we know that but there's a point where
if it's too much more they'll choose to
go to the underground so that can't be
lost on what what's coming with this
market and to be cognizant of of that uh
and understand going forward we really
need to concentrate on on on on on
things like that so we actually do have
a nascent Market a thriving market and a
very prosperous Market what I did also
say on stage was that uh on in 217 the
first ICBC Berlin event who was that
raise your hand if you were at the first
ICBC event all right raise your hand if
this is your first ICBC event ever yeah
a lot of new faces that's great that's
beautiful so what I said was I said that
politicians they're going to mess things
up now I'm paraphrasing myself and
what's going to happen is what the most
important thing is that you have a home
garden and you decriminalize cannabis
you make this flower not a crime anymore
well what's happened in Germany this is
exactly what they want to do and I know
everybody has a different opinion on
what's going on right now but I will
tell you now after all these years after
all these years this Movement we have
now in Germany is a good thing and it's
incumbent upon us as stewards of the
industry to protect
nourish and make this uh uh industry uh
go forward and like I said before be
prosperous so please give yourself a big
hand for being here
we are the ICBC we are nice people we
are old school activists from the West
Coast that came here to bring this shiny
vibe to everybody we only have one rule
at the ICBC that's be nice to everybody
and if we see Behavior Uh be respectful
to women at all times and uh uh uh just
uh love your brothers and sisters and
know we're all in this big boat together
and be approachable and be again be
respectful at all times that's the only
rule we have and guess what happens when
that happens
everything