thank you for showing up to the panel I
think you know cannabis packaging is is
a great topic because you know it's the
first thing that your customers see but
quite often is the last thing that's
mapped out in in the entire operation so
I'm very blessed to have a great panel
spanning you know a few different
countries and it'll be great to just
draw you know some experience and
inspiration from everybody's stories so
thank you for coming
so I'm from ND supplies I am a global
supplier of packaging products
specifically for the Cannabis industry
based in Canada but now global and I'm
very very fortunate to have you know all
these other experts from around the
world joining me here today too so some
of the topics I'd like to touch on today
sustainability you know and consumer use
and just overall packaging design so I
like to you know introduce my panelists
if you can all introduce yourselves
that'd be great uh sure I'll start my
name is Jack Hill I'm with chubby
gorilla we are based in Southern
California we were also a global
packager started in e-liquids and now we
were in cannabis and we package a lot of
other things as well
hi everybody my name is Petra marinko I
come from Pharmacy company the
we started a brand Nabi we don't do
packaging but we use really good
packaging and we know how to design a
good package
and uh it kind of shows
what do you want to to present with the
good package so I'm here to talk about
that thank you
yeah hey everybody my name is Felix
bishoping I'm CEO of pakiro we are a
germ company
um also supplying Packaging uh when we
started our idea was basically that we
have a solution for also small amounts
of packaging so we're very flexible in
our production so we can produce very
small amounts of bigger mods and then
when we started 2020 we directly saw
that there is a huge demand in the CBD
market and I think since that in Germany
at least most of the CBD companies know
us and we help them with up with our
Packaging
great thank you so packaging it's you
know it's uh it's one of those things
that a lot of people do struggle to
unwrap so you know when it comes to us
in Canada for example there's a lot of
regulations when it comes to
um how cannabis is packaged what kind of
materials you're able to use so you know
like first and foremost is packaging
design and how that relates to your
brand so maybe Petra you can lead us off
by saying like how do you what's your
thought process when it comes to how
your package is you know
is designed and what's your what's your
and how does that work out
when an architect
about a while I'm a visual type of
person and I believe that we are are
really visual people are really Visual
and uh the design of the packaging is
the first thing that people see and if
that you if you do a good thing then
people
take your product they take it into your
head to the hand and they can feel the
product have an experience with it right
and um I think it's really important
regarding the design and branding and
also materials you guys are doing a lot
of different materials and the other
point of view that we chose was also and
it was really important for us was reuse
um not only being recyclable but to let
people reuse so we use our
tubes which are really useful because
you can have your product in your tube
you can put a tube inside a drawer so
you have it packed like this people use
it for cables people use it for screws
for different different kind of kinds of
things they get creative with the
packaging and this was one of the most
important things for us to to to get
people our
box and reuse it again not just throw it
out and that's it and the other aspect
that we were really paying attention to
was the microplastics that come into the
product
so it was really hard for us to find um
packaging for creams lotions and stuff
like that
without plastic it's it's impossible
every part of a lotion pump is made out
of plastic you cannot do that yeah so
switching to tubes for us was a really
big thing we we ditched the Plastics we
ditched everything everything is 99
recyclable and I love how that's part of
your brand and you did mention also that
your aluminum tubes are locally sourced
yes right so that helps a lot too with
the overall carbon footprint yeah that's
that was one of the reasons why we
decided the tubes uh the production
company of the tubes is five kilometers
from where we are stationed so that's a
zero impact on the environment
um and it's actually really easy to
manipulate with the
products that you have if you have
everything by your hand so uh first line
that we did we got it from China it was
really well made premium products we
tested everything for migration of bad
stuff into the products everything works
worked fine
uh but it was expensive and it took a
lot of a long time so
those kind of things if you're pivoting
through the regulations of the CBD and
everything you need fast delivery lower
quantities and we can have this it's
amazing yeah so you know speaking of
regulations You Know Jack you're coming
from the American Market the U.S market
we're branding and and things like
that's a lot more liberal right can you
go through some of the processes with
you know design in the States because I
know in Canada everything is very very
muted I wish we had the freedom that you
did so so maybe you can kind of go over
some of that yeah I would say packaging
in the United States uh branding is
everything marketing is everything
because you have some of the largest
names biggest brands uh in cannabis who
are going to be there and going into a
dispensary in the states it is a circus
of colors shapes images everything you
can imagine on a mylar bag which is
radically different from going into a
Canadian dispensary where all that is
minimalized to be able to do that so my
company chubby gorilla that is what we
cater to so we call ourselves a
specialty packaging company we will get
your Pantone color we will get your logo
and then actually turn the packaging
into that color we also partner with a
lot of companies like Petras who
actually focus on the design of it and
we say hey we will make packaging for
you that you sell through to your
customers as well because they're far
more better at the design aspect we
would just rather make the the custom
packaging for whatever the functionality
that's needed so that's the biggest
difference that I see in the markets and
then even if I say the U.S market in
general I could spend another hour just
talking by state by state because they
still haven't had a a agreed upon for
what the whole country is going to have
as far as their packaging standards but
branding is definitely a key part of the
market that we play in
great well thank you for your Insight uh
now Felix you've been in the in the
flexible packaging game for a long time
how do you how do you see branding and
things like that play out in the in the
German Market
yeah I think it's the same with
marketing I mean if you if you often
look at the product they basically look
the same if you talk about coffee or CBD
or whatever you cannot really judge if
the how how good the quality is just by
looking at the product uh so the the
marketing aspect of the packaging is so
important and I think it's the same in
Germany or all over Europe I think
there's no difference to the States but
but still I think that there is a change
currently in the market because
um I mean for for example big Brands
we're only making the market so if you
look at the coffee brands in Germany you
had like I don't know 2030 a couple of
years ago and now more and more of the
small coffee brands appear yeah and they
all they're super creative with that
with the packaging yeah so with their
design with the packaging they want to
have an outstanding packaging so really
to to distinguish them from the others
especially from the big Brands and to
make them special and I think this you
can see all over Europe that these small
players appear and are super creative
with the packaging that's amazing so
let's let's dream a little bit now and
just imagine that you know cannabis as
an industry did legalize like how would
that affect you know packaging in in
Germany Slovenia and in the U.S
it depends in your opinion it's a very
open question right but it's also you
know like we hear you know everybody's
very optimistic so let's dream a little
bit right like the industry is what it
is it is a big discussion definitely and
but the the thing is really at the
moment nobody can say it exactly how it
will be and I think but there's certain
aspects which will be important yeah so
and I think one important aspect is what
will be the distribution channel so
either it will be mostly done via
pharmacies or it will be done a little
bit like the the way in the Dutch Market
where it's way more recreational and you
have coffee shops and all of this so if
it will go the direction more of the
pharmacies it will be kind of more let's
say yeah so we have the pharmacy looking
packaging but it goes more to the
recreational it will be more like a
aggressive marketing but there's also a
discussion because similar to to the
Netherlands who's not allowed to print
kind of marketing stuff anymore on
Tobacco packaging so this can be also an
option for for the legislation at the
moment that they really say okay the
packaging needs to be completely gray
and maybe only the logo will will be
possible so this is really a discussion
and I think it's it's really kind of in
the middle of this discussion at the
moment and other aspects but will be
also important like uh sustainability
definitely then a traceability so that
you can really trace the the packaging
back and uh yeah also a little bit kind
of protection stuff so there is even for
smaller like mailer bags you will need
something kind sort of a child
protection
I would more focus on the design point
of view
[Music]
of course sustainability and everything
that Felix said was is the same in
Slovenia it's um
the same thing but regarding design I
think the minimalism that we kind of
also wanted to present with our product
is becoming more
um
it's it's maybe more
people use it more so yeah
um
we get distracted every day by so many
information and by so many information
on the packaging you get lost you know
it's uh and everybody is trying to stand
out in a way and for for example it for
us it was easy because in cannabis
business everything is green or black
you know it's like okay so we'll be
right you know but in different kind of
uh product development and products
placing on the market uh I I see the
minimalism going to to the the little
information less colors less vibrant or
a different one in more colors and
everything just shiny and so on right
but um it's changing and you have to
Pivot through the that's right yeah
trends that are coming so yeah yeah yeah
for sure because you know and on our
side of the world it's like you know
there are very very heavy regulations
right I wish we were more like you guys
jack and we had a little bit more
freedom but if you know if the U.S is to
ever legalize federally would you think
that would change uh cannabis packaging
anyway yeah I think the biggest thing
that's going to change is that uh once
we have Federal uh wide open now it
becomes truly creative and we've seen
some people get really creative with the
products that they want to offer uh I've
seen drinking straws that would have
powder in them so that way you put the
straw on the drink and you shake it up
and then you're good to go and you drink
with a straw right so as soon as these
things come about though the biggest
thing that happens then it all turns
into regulation and compliance and
that's where really we see a lot going
on in the state of California to make
sure that you have all your ISO
certifications to make sure you have
your GMP to allow for the flexibility
and the creativity that people want to
have now that you have everything
federally regulated so that's really
what we focus on just to make sure that
everyone has the certifications that
they need and then they can get as
creative as they want to get
that's excellent are there currently any
certifications needed for packaging in
Germany
um no not not written down yeah
um I mean there is a discussion about
GMP and on some some easel Norms which
probably will be
um uh the the standard but when it comes
to Pharmacy you definitely have to have
to look way more into the pharmacy
sector than into normal food places so
like is there like Charles uh child
resistance certification needed maybe
like food testing FDA testing needed and
things like that yeah I mean food is
easier than farmer so basically every
good packaging production is somehow
certified for food
GMP and Pharmacy is always the next step
and this is something you normally have
to implement excellent yeah so you know
the next question really would be
sustainability I mean you know cannabis
at its roots is a very Grassroots based
kind of industry so you know it's kind
of meeting the middle ground between you
know like the the corporate side of and
the business side of cannabis plus you
know meeting the Grassroots side too so
sustainability is right in the middle of
that and you know in Canada at least we
have you know we have a decent recycling
program Germany obviously is a global
leader in recycling and things like that
so you know what kind of materials and
what kind of packaging what do you see
being the leader in in Germany yeah it's
um it's definitely
um called Mono material so you basically
have to produce the packaging out of one
plastic material and then you basically
get all the certification that is it is
recyclable so either you choose ppep or
whatever plastic
it needs to be one and then you have a
good chance to be recycled but the EU
will basically next here in the middle
of next year will kind of discuss or
basically close a new law which is
called the ppwr and this will basically
wants to harmonize all this
sustainability laws across Europe and
this will be it will be super big
because the the changes will be big and
it will be always about recyclability
not so much about bioplastics or
bioplastic is a little bit out so it's
still under discussion but it really
looks like more Super recyclable and
reuse so what pet hermer just mentioned
so the EU will dramatically push
especially for the hotel and gastronomic
sector reuse Concepts and I think um
yeah sustainability will not be an
option anymore it will be mandatory I
love that I'm surprised that there are
no cannabis products you know material
cannabis is a great material also for
packaging there's so many on the so so
little on the market and so many of
other things yeah we're having that
conversation the other day where we're
talking about you know how hemp right
hemp is is such a great product there's
so many things you can do with it but
you know if you were to break it down if
you to use hemp plastic for example it's
still a compound it's still a hybrid of
plastic and hemp which still ends up in
the landfill right so until we come up
with something that's fully compostable
made out of hemp I think that's that's
great and but we're still a little bit
behind on that but there are many ways
for example like an egg cartoon it would
be easily made out of hemp nobody does
that you know why I think you have that
kind of packaging I think the biggest
thing is we have to look at the almost
Cradle to the Grave for a lot of these
products and so where I agree with you
there is a lot of hemp that could be
used it still has to go through the
Regulatory and compliance testing
especially at the pharmaceutical level
and some of it will fall way short of
that
um there's also things that we say hey
we could use more paper and then I look
about who else is using paper in the
paper industry and what are we doing to
make sure that we can grow the paper
back as far as restainable Forest we
also look at materials like glass and we
say Okay Glass the gold star of
recycling it takes a lot more heat to
melt glass and we just don't get it from
the sand on the beach you have to
disturb Marine environments to be able
to dredge that up so overall the
footprint for a company like mine we try
to look at the entire perspective and
say what makes the both the most sense
in certain markets and then what is
going to work when it actually comes to
testing and compliance but I think a lot
of packaging companies are starting to
explore this to answer some of the
questions that you have sometimes we're
limited by the state or the country
sometimes we're limited by what is
ultimately going to go into it
so what I see the most promising option
currently with with hemp is paper so
also when it comes to the legislation
about sustainability it's always about
recyclability so and if you have a
recyclable paper which is made out of
hemp which is possible and then I think
we have a good solution because one hand
recyclable on the other hand paper but
it is very difficult so we tried it
already a couple of times on our
machines and it's really hard to find a
good paper which is manufacturable with
printing with spec making whatsoever
with
paper made out of him but I think it
will be possible next year yeah are
there any like government grants or
programs that support you know research
like this here in your respective
countries yes definitely yeah yeah a lot
do you use pushing that Germany is
pushing that and uh yeah I think that
there's there's really so much demand
actually currently on the market that
you really can also push forward I mean
Belgium will set up a law on the first
of January which will be super strict so
you basically it will be too expensive
to bring non-recyclable packaging to the
market so basically nobody will do it
anymore
and that's a really good point is that
we also have to watch what is the
ultimate cost going to be because if we
don't price it just right then you're
going to have a certain section of the
non-metric market Black Market if you
will that will just go and find other
packaging to use so we have to find that
sweet spot of does it meet our
Collective sustainability requirements
but also can we offer at a good market
price where people will have the demand
to actually get it from us
yeah for sure well there's a lot of
boxes to check off right and you know
they taking a look at the Canadian model
for example like
the companies they're they're not very
profitable between high taxes and you
know still trying to roll things out it
doesn't leave a lot of room for profit
so you know for us for example if I was
to say hey you know what a plastic tube
costs you let's just say five cents but
if you want to be sustainable are you
willing to pay 30 40 50 60 more and most
companies as much as they would love to
they just can't afford it right now
because you still got to keep the lights
on you got to keep the operation going
so that you know like you said like how
are we going to come together
to to alleviate that right I still think
you know
technologically and all those things
like you know where we are as an
industry we're just not there yet but
you know events like this really come
allows us to come together and really
kind of meld our minds and share our
knowledge to eventually figure that out
because cannabis you know in Canada is
five years in in most of the other
countries is just starting right so we
have a lot of time to figure it out so
I'm glad we're able to sit down and go
over these topics right and you know if
there's any questions in the in the
audience later we'd love to answer that
as well
is there any questions from the audience
or are there any wake up
okay so let's go back to sustainability
then right I think that's that's one of
the biggest topics right and so in
America and in the states I see there's
a lot of there is a lot of innovation
yes I'm seeing you know like uh ocean
ocean recycled plastic post-consumer
recycle plastic and even
um even uh compostable Plastics what do
you think is the and the front runner or
materials in the long run I think the
biggest one right now is going to be the
one that uh the Food and Drug industry
is using in the states and that is a
certain percentage of post-recycled
material so I think both uh New York in
2024 is going to demand 35 percent uh be
post recycled material California may
follow that but if any of you know
California it's just whatever it is that
they want to do because they don't
recognize compostable and they really
don't recognize biodegradable so I can't
even get the two states to to follow
that right now but I think that will be
the first phase and then after that they
will start to increase what that
percentage is as we go and then as we
approach that threshold of 45 to 50
percent then probably some compliance
will need to come into play to see if
the pharmaceutical company is
comfortable with that amount of recycled
material and where that's coming from
and how clean and how processed that is
so that's kind of where I see the window
going
amazing so Felix you have quite a few
sustainable options in your portfolio
right what do you see is the most
popular
most popular currently is really the
recyclable packaging but I mean being
honest I mean recyclable packaging is
only new packaging which can be recycled
so we don't close the circle here at all
yeah so it's really only the first step
and I mean we write a lot of Block taxes
and try to explain that and everybody
also misunderstands often recyclable
with it is already recycled so they said
hey we got recycled packaging no you
don't is there any thought to like
reusable packaging maybe you bring in a
glass jar or reuse will be big your
reuse will be a big topic but I have one
aspect of reusable that it's not many
times time seen and that's toxicity you
know if you use plastic and reuse it and
reheat it again and make the process I'm
thinking like glass or something like
that yeah I understand also also yeah
glass can be tricky too I understand
sometimes the necessity for child proof
packaging but apparently I am not as
smart as a child
because it is very hard to open and I
feel bad for some people who may have
arthritis or problems and things and
can't I mean uh the liquor bottle is not
childproof packaging and that's probably
way more dangerous to your kids than a
five milligram gummy there's any
pushback toward that or you guys just do
whatever the test is it was very funny I
mean we had in Germany it's called tooth
uh t-u whatever
who's checking that and they told us how
they check it and they give it to 10
people uh who are over 70 years old they
need to still open the packaging and
pretend people who are below seven years
old so kids and they shouldn't be able
to open it and then you pass the test
yeah well in Canada it's very important
every every package going through
retailers has to be certified child
resistant so we independently certify
all our products and we take that into
consideration too right so we want to
make sure that medical patients and
recreational patients are able to open
it easily without any issues and things
like that but I mean having a child
resistant mechanism it varies sometimes
it's finicky if you're using a bag
sometimes you gotta stick your finger in
and kind of pull it through a little bit
so you know you know exactly what I mean
right and you know scissors scissors
work too but then now you can't reclose
it and now it's not child resistant
anymore
so you know there's a lot of a lot of
things you're trying to map on a workout
but you know
it's rolled out it's not perfect but you
know like I said the opportunities like
this to get together really it allows us
to dial it in a little bit and get a
little bit more feedback
yes
in Canada we're faced we call a price
compression at that store
so packaging is a it's a it's a part of
that so the consumers are relying on a
highest TSC for the best price and
that's the bottom line that's the
reality of the world but however when
they get our packages sometimes they're
like where is no recycling why is no
matter what happened all the you know
all those options are higher costs right
what is the industry doing to a gate a
better medium like to a better place for
us to do the right thing but also be
able to compete at the start level
that's a great question I mean I could
start with we know from a Canadian point
of view it's kind of like we have to
work together really and and come out
see what the budget is and things like
that what we do what we specialize in is
working with our clients to to figure
out what your budget is and we could
build something around that we do a lot
we've spent a lot of time in the field
um you know doing r d we visit a lot of
sites just to try to see how to make
things easier but at the same time I
think you know instead of looking at The
Upfront costs it's also about how can we
make your production more efficient
right I'd rather you know spend a few
cents more up front and save you a few
salaries on the back end right and
that's that's where we're going to see
these savings right so but there is no
real hard answer right now to that
unfortunately
you guys have any insight on that and
the only thing I can think is add to
that is that we try to offer different
tiers of products and hopefully there
might be a tier above or below that's
going to meet your right price range and
then also we have other ways because it
might just be distribution what is the
shipping cost to be able to get it to
you if I have a different place where I
can move a warehouse or a hub that's
going to be more suitable I try to find
other ways to help your business out and
then also just coming up with innovative
ways to be able to close and seal the
product if I can eliminate two machines
that you would have on a line or maybe
eliminate the use of shrink wrapping and
other materials that might also be a
healthy savings for you and you might go
in the direction of my packaging so we
try to look at it from that point of
view
sure
do you have any other questions in the
crowd
don't be afraid I'm wearing comfortable
shoes I can run right up to you
all right what do you see in the future
did we talk about that already did I
miss it well I'm uh you know I love I
love to be a dreamer about almost a
revealist so I think you know
the future is undefined I don't know
that's a very general thing to say but
you know like I said it all comes back
to the industry in the community right
like how can we build you know the
Cannabis industry that we can all love
and respect and profit at the same time
right I think there's a lot of there's a
lot of open space here and
collaborations like this is what it's
really about no I think the industry
will hate me for that but I think no
Packaging
seriously I think no packaging no no I
really it's called single-use packaging
so all the packaging that we talk about
currently is that you use the packaging
and then you throw it away yeah and I
think this would have an end in the
future I think this is something what we
we we invented something in the last 30
40 years where like resources were all
over the place and nobody cared so this
is the only reason why you come to such
a stupid idea like single use packaging
and I think this would have an end but
in the next 10 to 20 years that we only
have a reuse packaging I truly believe
in this and then that we don't use
single-use packaging anymore and if we
do then it will need to be fully
recycled and really use the material
afterwards again for new packaging so
either we close the circle or we only
have reuse packaging but I don't think
it will say the same as it is today I do
love the idea of reuse packaging we're
actually kicking the idea around back in
Canada and how we have to be to collect
everything though it's it's a huge
undertaking there there were some clubs
in Los Angeles and Oakland and Berkeley
who they would give you a discount if
you brought your glass jar back and then
they will wash it out and reason but
this is before everything had to be it
was more deli style right you put a lot
of big jar weed and you get the
Chopsticks and you you put it in the jar
and now everything has to be
individually packaged which is very
weird to me but also you get all those
beautiful loud packs and everybody's got
the super colorful packaging and it's
got a football player on it and all
these other things so uh it looks like a
pinata or you know
so I think we'll see what happens
well if we're here we're optimistic
right so I'm very glad that everybody
did show up and join us for this for
this panel I'd like to thank all our
great panelists I had a great time up
here thank you I hope everybody gets a
little take away from everything
regarding packaging so thank you again
thank you ICBC thank you Germany hope to
see you guys again thank you again let's
hear it again for Kevin Lee and Petra
and Felix and Jack Hill
that was fantastic