we have a topic that I consider to be
very very important especially in the
stage of the development of the medical
cannabis Market here in Europe right now
of course A lot of people are looking at
what's going to happen with Rec and you
know how the Market's going to evolve
but we're here to talk about the medical
market and the patient experience and I
think that we can't forget that with
everything that's going on
so without further Ado I'm going to
start by just giving a little intro of
the gentleman's to the left of me
first of all we have well we have Dr
Julian Wishbone next to me co-founder of
the the bloom well group and also
algeocare and next to him we have
barinder bullar senior VP of corporate
Affairs at brains biosuticals joining us
all the way from Vancouver today
next to barinder we have Stefan verbik
who is the president and CEO of hello
cannabis also coming from Canada today
joining us out of the GTA at the greater
Toronto area and last but not least at
the end we have Dr jean-clan shikluna
who is the co-founder and chief science
officer of celotex
so I'm just going to get right into it
gentlemen I would like to know what can
we do right now to improve the access to
medical cannabis for patients and
improve the patient Journey what can we
do right now to make things better for
them
maybe we should start from from left to
right or whatever Direction so we're
focused obviously on Germany and the one
of the largest televising platforms
there and I think it's really it's
shifting it's shifting towards
convenience so it needs to be much
easier to be a cannabis patient I think
in the past we had an issue of I need to
go to a doctor there then I need to go
to a pharmacy there then then there's an
issue I keep going back and forth I
think that's not only limiting the I
think it's taking a lot of time for
patients I think it's frustrating for
patients but it's also blocking people
from considering becoming a cannabis
patient so our focus is really invest
heavily in build up in Tech and also the
operations in the background and I'm
glad to say that now in Germany which
was unheard of before we have through
our Blue Mill group footprint we have
the first patients with video
consultation on their phone on a Monday
and less than 24 hours they have the
Cannabis medication in their hand and it
used to be days or not even weeks
um I think one of the biggest challenges
right now is that there's no streamlined
regulations nobody understands what a
medical patient is if you went out and
talked to 50 people and asked them to
describe medical cannabis you will
probably get 50 or 60 different opinions
on what it is so education has to be a
real key figure here uh to to ensure
that our physicians Regulators uh kind
of streamline regulations because
jurisdictionally people don't understand
it within the country people don't
understand it and then the other key is
it's going to be access you know who's
where can I get uh the medicines is it
going to be through a specialist is it
through a regular doctor is it through a
pharmacy do I have to go online and get
it so I think education backed by
evidence and science is going to be huge
so that Regulators Physicians can feel
comfortable knowing but that education
for consumers also is going to be a huge
key
I love it I'm going to follow up on that
as well and really reiterate the
educational aspect of it one of the
first priorities that we did was to
start educating Physicians thankfully we
had a very strong network of doctors we
worked with in Ontario and one by one we
were able to communicate with them and
showing real patients not Stoners and
try and destigmatize cannabis use as a
medicine
that type of education was able to kind
of lead a pathway for doctors to become
more comfortable prescribing a narcotic
that at one point they thought turned
you into a pizza eating video gamer
that's clearly not the case and that
education I think was pivotal in being
able to help increase the amount of
Physicians prescribing from four percent
in Canada to north of 30 percent in a
matter of about four years
to reiterate the second topic as well we
need to look at actual standardization
here there's a really
um there's an interesting issue here is
because cannabis although it is a
narcotic it is not prescribed and
treated and consumed similar to other
narcotics in Canada we have something
called A din a drug identification
number which is what's required in order
in order to be able to have this listed
in pharmacies so unfortunately even
though it is a narcotic that is
prescribed the access to it has this
whole separate
tags of a path that you need to walk
down it is not as simple as seeing a
doctor getting a prescription and going
to a pharmacy and picking up so there's
this weird stigma that's still there
because it is treated differently so if
we're able to educate doctors educate
patients and then standardize the
medicine and the practice of
Distributing it treating it like
everything else I think you'll see a
much more rapid expansion of medical
cannabis use and access
I think we need to think of cannabis
medicine as other medicine and the way
to improve patient outcomes is to foster
a personal relationship based on trust
and how do we do that the way we do that
is we need to give patients the time of
day
the time of day to talk about a medicine
which is different from other medicines
they've encountered a type of medicine
which it's not a doesn't attack just one
system in the body it's holistic it's
organic and it doesn't just it doesn't
just affect them in one part of their
lives but in many different parts of
their lives and ultimately we need to
remember that medical cannabis will have
the same issues as medicine in the
healthcare sector in general so just to
take a possibly a different approach we
need to look at the healthcare sector
and what is happening there and
we've just had the pandemic right so
this is also the Cannabis patient's
minds of going to their doctors
and especially when you have a choice
because in other aspects if you're sick
and you need a certain type of medicine
what you're going to do you're going to
go to the doctor in cannabis there's a
choice
I can go to a doctor but I can get it
from from my plug so what what is the
added benefit of going to the doctor I
think we need to as as clinicians and
anyone in this tree we need to think
about the the patient's um
point of view and we need to add value
to making medical cannabis really
medical and adding that value it it
takes time it takes a lot of time and it
needs to be tackled in a different way
from the way that medicine is being
tackled currently and it needs to be
patient-centric
we look at the patient and I I like how
medicine ties in with the Cannabis
industry and medical cannabis there was
a panel before this a great one the one
about branding and
um and Jamie said in in branding you
need to start backwards like in cannabis
you have to start with the consumer see
what they like and work backwards and in
medical cannabis it's just the same
thing we need to start with the patient
see what they like and work backwards
not the hospital or the institution or
the clinic
absolutely that's a very great point I
think one thing also is one of the
benefits with this active dialogue
surrounding the the legalization of
recreational Cannabis is that one of the
derivatives is that it's becoming maybe
less stigmatized slightly so Physicians
are maybe more open to having these
conversations but also I don't want to
Discount and I would like to highlight
the role of Pharmacists in this in this
constellation because oftentimes the the
pharmacists are a little more accessible
to the patients than the Physicians are
and I mean you guys mentioned it
education education education it's it's
required now to improve the patient
experience you really also have to
improve the physician experience in
Germany it's quite complex for a
physician to prescribe medical cannabis
to a patient there's a lot of steps
required a lot of work that needs to be
done
what are some of the barriers to entry
or let's say the the hurdles of
Physicians when considering to integrate
medical cannabis into their practice and
what can we do to tackle some of those
things so that we can increase access
for the patients by making the job of
the physician easier
I just want to focus on some of those I
think there's many more hurdles
especially bureaucratic hurdles and I
say this every year making it easier for
a doctor and a patient maybe means
breaking of cannabis culture in a way
meaning strain names Etc are I think
important uh When developing new
products but as a doctor if you need to
use free lines on a prescription just
for one medication that's a hassle so
we're we're very not only experienced
but we're also still actually advocating
you need simple product names you need
as a vendor you need a portfolio that
has an as an instinctive understanding
of you know what's a high grade what's a
low intensity Etc product in those ways
and and I think this is a trend that is
still happening in Germany but it's bad
from a doctor's perspective and I don't
mean me I don't I mean treating doctors
in Germany if you introduce products to
the market and you already know you're
gonna take it off the market in three
months I think that works for certain
kinetics but for the majority of doctors
and especially in the future market so
in a restructured market in an RX Market
in a non-narcotic Market persistency
consistency with product availability
product stability and quality but also
pricing in the pharmacies is very
important I think when you look at
Germany and if you look at especially
privately insured Patients health Pay
Market which is the only growing Market
um it's crucial to understand that even
the doctors know the prices of the
pharmacies and they look at it because
it's in the best interest of their
patients so I think it's very especially
as as Jean-Claude said cannabis is very
much different and there's an overlap of
medicine but also from a doctor's
perspective many things are completely
new topics you're treating patients
suddenly you have to look at inventory
and prices and availability at
pharmacies
I think one of the things uh for
Physicians is we need to equip them with
evidence science and data so that they
have the confidence uh prescribing and
they know what dosage forms they're
prescribing so that only can happen if
industry and companies are providing the
right compounds they're consistent uh
API quality active ingredients for
clinical studies so that Physicians do
have the confidence they know the
dosages they know where they're going I
mean it is a tragedy if you look at it
some jurisdictions in the UK in Europe
uh less than 10 percent of the
registered patients are getting access
to these medicines but what's important
I think is to breaking it down to one
the molecule first understanding what uh
the different compounds are then having
that a clinical uh background studied so
that then the Physicians have the
confidence to know what they're
prescribing also Physicians will need to
know you know are there harms are there
side effects just like at the end of
pharmaceutical drug if we're going to
prescribe these things we need to know
and the Physicians need to have the
confidence to do that so that they can
build trust and continue to do this so
those are two very important points for
my my perspective uh to increase the uh
physician recognitions
yeah it's uh it's quite fascinating when
we saw recreational come out in in
Canada
um we had Canada's been a large consumer
of cannabis for quite some time I'd like
to think that outside of the Physicians
the cannabis use has been largely
destigmatized in our country
um when we started introducing it as a
medicine I myself was actually quite
surprised for that the
um a quick back story I'm I'm a Dutch
guy from Vancouver which I think are
like the two like largest cannabis
consuming areas in the world and I had
never thought of this as a medicine
until I suffered a very extreme injury
and it was through an uh synthetic
opioid addiction from post-surgery that
I discovered using cannabis as a
medicine and when when we introduced
recreational Cannabis it kind of created
this very interesting overlap between
what is medicine and what is
recreational use and I'll I'll publicly
admit that I am both a medical user and
a recreational user and I do believe
that there's two distinct uses and two
two distinct different purposes for it
as much as there is an overlap I think
this is something that we need to really
really really look at here it does
actually confuse a lot of Physicians
when they see patients that actually are
able to consume it on a recreational
side and it does also create some
confusion with respect to when they're
prescribing it as well if you were to
look at it with respect to an opioids
say like Dilaudid or
um
uh Percocets or oxycontinent you know
people that use those recreationally
there's a big stigma attached to it
whereas there is less of a stigma with
cannabis you would not prescribe
somebody x amount of oxycontinent
knowing that they would be actually
using that on using it recreationally on
top of it because it will of course mess
with the regimen of what you were
prescribing
so there are a lot of very different
variables that a doctor needs to keep in
mind with respect to cannabis use in
prescribing and I'll follow up with uh
with what Jean-Claude said as well is
there certainly does need to be a
holistic approach and this is not
exactly throwing a monkey wrench in the
system but it is most certainly changing
the pathway to A system that doctors
have been very very very streamlined
doing where they look at say body weight
appetite severity of pain all of these
different variables and then they fix a
number and a narcotic attached to it
it's there's a certain degree of
mathematics and systems that have checks
and balances there one that's for
accountability two not to kill people
and three to also save the a doctor's
license as well so that there needs to
be these checks and balances when you
look at something holistic
there is no two people that are the same
and the way that people interact with
the cannabinoids if it's completely
different different as well when you
start looking at all these different
synthetic narcotics it is far more
predictable how the body is going to
interact with these things now what
people don't understand is that if I
have had a full full meal in me and 10
hours of sleep five milligrams of
Dilaudid is going to affect me a lot
differently than if I had five
milligrams of Dilaudid with very little
very little to eat very little sleep and
a lot of stress you metabolize these
narcotics differently so I think in Full
Circle we do need to take a lot more
accountability for Physicians and
patients to be have a more holistic
approach and recognize that we're we're
prescribing something that's going to be
a moving Target
no matter what people are people
metabolize narcotics differently they
react to narcotics differently and this
does need to be a pathway that needs to
be Ever Changing ever adapting and just
like our human bodies are so this is
certainly no easy task
but I do believe that an organic
holistic approach again
um an esteemed colleague of mine was
commenting on this too it's more work
but I think it's going to save the world
from a lot more
um a lot more opioid addictions going
forward a lot more misuse of Narcotics
and I do believe that we'll have a much
more healthy Society if we're able to
start educating people on how to be able
to react to different narcotics on how
to be able to understand what their
bodies and their minds are doing when
they are using these narcotics and
educated Doctrine how to be able to
safely educate patients on using these
narcotics
exactly that and just to follow up I I
really like the point uh Bernard said
about data and about how data is
important the thing is and this is maybe
a challenge that we have nowadays we
have so much data coming into Physicians
and we have to remember in medical
school what are you trained on in
medical school you're trained to use
this analog you know stethoscope these
analog stuff but then you go into real
practice and you have a computer and all
you're seeing is data sets data sets
data sets so ultimately we need to find
a way to help the doctors turn those
data sets into actionable insights you
know you take actions and and
based on what you're seeing you
understand it and you know what
prescription or what move or what the
next clinical uh judgment decision you
need to take in the best interest of
your patients and again it gets so
complex like Stephen said it can get so
complex so you need to be ever adjusting
you need to be dynamic
um so we need to ultimately give doctors
the ability not only when they're seeing
the patient but also after that to
monitor their patients and see
continuously what is happening on many
different spheres we mentioned being
holistic so it's not just about what
it's what is happening on a maybe
whether they're feeling good or not
feeling good but we need to have
biological data we need to have data
sets which can tell us exactly what is
happening in your body
and ultimately just like Stephen said
when we start getting this right
the floodgates are open and what we're
doing I think and I think it's
interesting and being in the Cannabis
space we're already getting uh one thing
right the first tick box is already
there because I think one of the biggest
problems in mainstream Healthcare is
their rigidity not to explore these new
things so one of the things that
patients like most about any cannabis
clinic or any Clinic which is offering
alternative medicine is
I'm getting an alternative in the old
days even asking for an alternative and
you were shoot away from the clinic what
do you mean are you talking about this
kind of things I'm like and now we have
clinics which are actually offering
professional guidance for alternative
therapies so this is already something
which we're doing really well and
I don't know if this is a big statement
but I think that what we do in cannabis
medicine will send shock waves across
medicine in general because we're taking
a different approach and we're starting
with what the patient wants if the
patient wants to know about alternative
Therapies in a scientific way
and we're there to provide it this will
this will really uh have a big change
and we can do a lot for doctors for
doctors warrants
um
especially especially if we want to get
more doctors to be prescribing you need
to be safe you know when I first got
into cannabis medicine I did very early
so I got this illusion very early from
the hospital setting
um so definitely in my in my grade in my
in my year I was the first doctor to
venture out privately do alternative
medicine and when I meet my friends in
bars and and I can tell you a lot of
young doctors we certainly use cannabis
and we use
um and a lot of doctors know the science
so it's not taught in in schools and
there's no education true but doctors
are inquisitive people we we research we
want to know and many doctors they say
you know I it's not that I don't believe
in it when I ask them you know come on
join me join my clinic you know it's
cool and they say I'm scared I'm scared
for my warrant took me seven years and I
you know and a kidney to get here and
I'm not ready to go out and lose it all
so we need to give doctors like we said
the confidence to to go ahead
um and change the world for the patients
absolutely I think what's unique to the
the Cannabis industry is that as you
mentioned uh you know teachings about
the endocannabinoid system and the plant
are not part of the traditional medical
school so the onus falls on us as an
industry to educate the Physicians or
fight to have this kind of curriculum
introduced to medical schools around the
world
as somebody that has spent years in the
field here in Germany visiting hundreds
of Physicians I can tell you it's it's
difficult uh as a farmer rapper or as a
company to be the one to help a
physician take that first step they need
to hear from other Physicians they need
to hear from scientists they need to
hear the data like you said
and I want to just touch on the point
that you made Julian about the
bureaucracy that's that's tied to it
when I was Visiting Physicians really
the one thing that convinced many of
them to actually consider implementing
uh cannabis was a tool that I was
introducing them to that digitized the
entire reimbursement process and I think
that's a great way of developing Tech to
ease the burden on the Physicians and
the and you know increase access and I'm
joined here by a number of Industry
colleagues that are implementing Tech in
a number of very different uh of
different ways so perhaps you could
touch on the role that Tech plays right
now in making cannabis more accessible
but also with the recent Innovations and
you know Technologies such as Ai and ml
where is the integration of Technology
heading to further develop this market
and make the access for patients more
streamlined
I think we always look at it uh
primarily from an operational
perspective so where are potential
hiccups in the patient Journey because
again I think that's really frustrating
but keeping people away or actually
having them leave treatment because
they're basically saying hey this is
just too complicated before I was used
to getting prescription and picking up
on the next Corner that doesn't work in
cannabis
um we are very much data focused and in
a way of you know having data from all
these access points so from from doctors
and their their notes I'm a radiologist
originally so I come from structure
reporting machine readable data
um same with the patients and
prescriptions and also the pharmacists
um it's interesting I think looking at
data it's crucial to zoom out more so we
look at data for more than 100 doctors
and we use that data to educate them
because my personal experience in
general medicine but also in cannabis
medicine is that doctors overestimate
their their personal data that they
collect and never step outside that and
then start to realize okay I could have
treated that patient different and the
outcome would have been better we've
just finished the first University
collaborations first paper being
accepted and we saw as a consequence of
focus on operational focus and that's
where you invest in a lot into Tech and
operations in the pharmacy for the
patients in the app for doctors they
have a better outcome so our thesis is
really if you have a better operational
experience
your medical outcome will be impacted
it's not just about the medication
itself it's about the journey along the
way and obviously we're getting in into
a direction of
um using that data not only to educate
doctors patients pharmacists but also
making
um you know data-based uh suggestions so
for example if you pluck terpene
profiles into that equation into the
algorithm and you have all the data
available from you know an anonymous so
medical history of that patient certain
contraindications certain indications
then you become very good at predicting
not only is medical cannabis a good fit
for that patient but also which type one
of the I think in German pharmacies up
to 200 different strains that makes a
big impact
um there and then you can plug that in
because even the doctors with a lot of
knowledge are asking for how can I treat
my patient based on terpene profiles and
not just TS THC CBD ratio
um Innovation I think is going to be key
for the sector uh Innovation uh combined
with combination products I think is
this going to be the future but
um you know looking at things like how
do we enhance bioavailability how do we
enhance solubility
um how do we enhance stability how do we
get targeted formulations uh out there
right and that's something us at brains
bio with our partners DSM for minutia
are really focused on on the next
Horizon and going Beyond just you know
CBD as a golden child looking at CBN CBC
major and minor cannabinoids
understanding what we can do and coming
out with targeted formulations is going
to be really key to the Future uh one
area that really excites me also is
sports science how do we take all of our
learnings our clinical studies and look
at Sports Nutrition enhancement athletes
travel a lot we know that sleep is a big
problem for them inflammation is a big
problem for them so how do we work on
performance nutrition and that is what
Innovation is going to bring to this but
also Innovation is what's going to help
continue to bring down the stigma when
we could bring in new dosage forms we
could bring in dosage forms that are
more acceptable uh other than flour and
oils for people that's going to help
bring down the stigma and it's going to
be huge I think Innovation and
combination products is something that
I'm really looking forward to in the
future
um it's interesting when we're looking
at a holistic organic product and trying
to incorporate
uh technology into this this is one
thing that that's rather interesting
when you think of holistic medicine
something that I've heard many many
interesting stories from JC over here
and I urge you to spend some time with
them hearing about his travels
incorporating technology into these
types of original traditional medicines
is a big jump because you're looking at
two Polar Opposites of the situation
here
um one one instance where we found that
we could introduce technology without
kind of disrupting the actual natural
course that this medicine has
traditionally been used for and where I
found it has been most beneficial is
with respect to actually using tech for
accessibility not necessarily using Tech
to alter the how you consume or how the
product interacts with your body but
more or less using Tech to be able to
help with access and in fact uh hello
cannabis was actually the very first
Clinic to be able to offer to be
accepted into the otn the otn is the
Ontario Telehealth Network so what this
allowed was for doctors to be able to
prescribe cannabis through a video
conference call and this was something
that had tremendously helped our access
because once again there were only four
percent of Physicians that were
prescribing now quite a quite a few of
those were actually working with us at
one point and it allowed us to be able
to spread the access and be able to
actually have them meet patients from
around the province which is rather
large I believe larger than Germany
actually by size
um and and be able to increase access
now when a pandemic happened of course
that technology was no longer useful
because everybody had access to video
but uh what I do find is when we're able
to incorporate technology that's going
to be able to benefit a holistic and
organic approach to a medication to a
traditional medicine I think you can
find like a happy Sweet Spot there
um I I don't think that cannabis needs
to necessarily be going down a future
um Tech hole but I do believe that we do
need to see some form of standardization
with this product a lot more consistency
in utilizing technology for data
utilizing technology for Education
utilizing data and technology for
accessibility
and I do truly think that you can find a
way to be able to Harbor the future and
have it work cohesively and collaborate
with the past of traditional holistic
medicine
and we can finally be able to get the
best of both worlds I I don't think we
are getting to the uh the the Terminator
future with everything becoming very
standardized and and pill form and I I
do think that we need to hold on to
traditional holistic medical Roots I
have found that as somebody that has uh
has a very strong daily regimen of
medications required for for chronic
injuries
the traditional holistic route certainly
allows me to be able to function and
operate at my highest
um and every other synthetic form I have
found that it has actually been an
inebriation and it has also been
something that has kind of put me put me
slower and unable to be able to perform
at my highest ability so finding the
balance between technology and a
holistic traditional using technology
and have that Harbor with a traditional
holistic medication I think you're going
to be able to see a strong successful
program with respect to cannabis
unfortunately no doctor is ever going to
prescribe something that you come well
let me rephrase that please a doctor
will
very rarely condone and prescribe
something that you are going to combust
and smoke in your lungs that seems to be
something that everybody here can agree
on I hope
um but that being said there is also
something it is also an extremely fast
and effective and controlled way to be
able to get this medication into your
system
so we have been able to find ways and
use technology to be able to actually
isolate the amount of cannabinoids that
are coming in and we have found
different ways in order to be able to
use this holistic medicine without
having the
subjectivity and irregularity of how
much a narcotic you're introducing into
your body by utilizing some of this
technology as well so uh it's it's still
kind of a weird faux pas when you start
talking about high tech in the future
with a very traditional holistic
medication but there is a balance in my
personal belief is that technology
should be used in other areas outside of
the actual
indusion to be of the medication use
that technology to be able to help with
data sets to be able to help with
education to be able to help with
destigmatic destigmatization to be able
to help with accessibility however don't
mess with something if it isn't broke
um cannabis is not a broken medicine it
works and I don't think we need to
really take this to the Future and have
this into a totally synthesized
structure
um having a did number would certainly
help access and it would certainly help
destigmatize and get more doctors on
board but just as JC made a very strong
Counterpoint to what I was saying before
I don't believe it's going taking a
unholistic approach to any form of
medication is the is the answer as well
exactly that so
um at celtex what we do is we use
biological data from an individual
to assess and measure what is happening
in an individual's body when using plant
medicine taking trying to take plant
medicine out of the shadows out of this
this Voodoo medicine Shadows which which
we're not comfortable with mainstream
doctors are uncomfortable with and try
to give them data from which they can
make insights they can take insights out
of that and make like we said actionable
decisions
um but like Stephen is saying it's not
just about using it to to measure
biological data something we learned
really early on is
the tech is really a solution all across
for different aspects of Stephen
mentioned some I'll mention another
um uh with regards to to Insurance we've
spoken about bureaucracy and how Tech
can help that you mentioned that tool
I'll mention another staff shortage
Healthcare is going through one of the
biggest stuff shortages ever since the
pandemic so
um I know there are a lot of people from
North America here I have some numbers
from there that even though uh eight
percent of all healthcare jobs are open
at this point we still have 400
000 less people working in healthcare
um in North America so the same thing is
in Europe and wherever I've gone it's
always doctors are overworked doctors
are over tired and if you remember jars
with what I started with of
um giving patients the time of the day
to encourage and Foster that personal
relationship and Foster that trust and I
think Tech can play a role here by
encouraging
the patients to use Tech and engage with
tech we can foster that personal
relationship through Tech despite the
shortage of staff that we have so really
it's
it's about finding solutions for the
different problems and I think the most
important thing because it's an easy
sell right finding Solutions of the
problems but we need to make sure that
we're targeting all the stakeholders so
when we're developing tech let's not
just think about tech Fair patients
statistic for tech for everyone so Tech
also for the industry to be able to
allocate resources
well let's think of tech for the
pharmacists to be able to be able to
follow up to be able to see is there
medicine working well are there any
changes leading to lies with the doctor
um and ultimately
I also believe that we need to look at
data we're going to go back there we
need to look at data differently
um and just like care has gone from
institution-centric to patient-centric
it's the same thing with data we need to
empower patients because it is
empowering to own their own Medical Data
I don't know the last time you needed
like a scan or something but but I
needed to scan ones from from my
hospital I needed you needed to go to
customer care and wait two hours and
have that burnt on a CD-ROM as if anyone
you know still uses those
um and it made me think that patients
really don't have access to their
medical data I mean do you have access
to the to the data to maybe a CT scan
you had when you were 10 years old no
but it's your data it's the patient's
data so I think Tech can really serve to
democratize data for patients because
once you Empower patients to have that
medical data about themselves then they
can be the ones and we talked about this
going backwards and starting with the
patient they can be the ones to go to
the other stakeholders to the industry
to the pharmacy to the doctors and tell
them this is my data I'd like to share
it with you I'd like you to help me I'd
like to add value as a clinician as a
pharmacist and finally this is the
product that I want this is the product
that works for my body
absolutely I would just like to add on
to that too that
Tech can also help in the quality of
data that's collected from consumers
especially now when you have uh you know
vaporizers for example that are
connected to iot to basically have
immediate data transfer on the usage of
different different medicines to kind of
alleviate any kind of risk in the
quality of data that you collect and
also you know we didn't touch on this
yet but I think that you know machine
learning and Ai and even blockchain in
some instances are going to be
absolutely crucial in Expediting the
process of finished pharmaceutical drug
development I mean we have hundreds of
products on the market in Germany and
only two products that are actually
Market authorized so I think Tech is
going to be actually absolutely crucial
in developing these uh Market authorized
Finnish Pharmaceuticals ladies and
gentlemen uh I am going to take the last
seven and a half minutes or this
opportunity first of all to see if
anyone in the audience has any questions
for the panel first of all let's hear it
for the panel yay
very exciting you're also young and
smart
my man Javier over here ran over he's
like are they going to take questions I
have a very important question so
fingers crossed Javier what was your
question quick question
um as an introduction I'm a
recreational user that takes a lot of
cannabis every day and at the same time
I'm a breather I have a partnership with
some legendary breathers from Spain
and one of the things that I notice
because I'm very sensitive to the effect
of uh of what this thing does because I
also consume other psychedelics
um as as medicinal way not recreational
is that a lot of the land the some of
the strains that we produce that are
closer to the land race cultivars
they're not as potent but they give you
a steady result so my question is is
there anybody working on figuring out if
all these [__] up with genetics that
we're doing to try to provide the nice
little terpene taste to the kids in
California is messing up the medical
industry and is there room for the ones
that we still you know for the last 20
years we've been keeping those clones
and keep and having with that apparently
it's not desirable anymore
mind is there room for for a different
type of breathing only for the medical
business Stephen yeah if you don't mind
I got to tackle this one please that's
an unbelievable question and one that
I've taken as a personal Journey as well
um my original hobby being a Dutch guy
from Vancouver and being exposed to
cannabis since I've been like Grover
since I've been this tall was actually a
cultivation in genetics
um interestingly enough I actually had
the privilege to be traveling the world
trying to discover some of these land
restraints and in fact I'm I'm wearing a
pendant from uh which was a gift from
the queen of Bhutan which is a country
in between India and China where we were
traveling in the Himalayan Mountains
discovering land-based strains so when
when we talk about
um land races and how when we start
catering and breeding and changing
things for like different candy for kids
and whatnot let's let's look at dogs for
example right like I don't like a
miniature pincer like that that is a dog
that I'm not even sure has a brain right
like it it doesn't even know its own own
name when you start really genetically
modifying things to the point where you
are taking quote the best of one thing
or quote the best of another thing and
continually breeding and manipulating
them you you do genuinely lose the soul
I'm using that word very frivolously but
I hope I hope everybody in the audience
can kind of follow what I'm meaning by
that
um you are right you definitely lose the
potent the land race strains certainly
do not have the potency which is what
all of these breeding programs have been
trying to do but the most important
thing that they have been losing is the
actual medical benefit we have found
that land race strains have certainly
had a far stronger Entourage effect and
cannabinoid effect with respect to
holistic medical therapy and I do
believe that the further we can we are
manipulating these land race strains the
further away we are getting the the
further we are getting away from an
actual
um holistic original medical approach
here so
um the balance between that's going to
be very interesting and yes I do believe
that we need to pay homage to some of
the original land races and and The
Growers and I'd love to talk to you um
about some of the programs that that are
there
but again uh introducing that type of
stuff to doctors is going to be
extremely challenging again because of
the organic aspect of it most of these
land race strains are consumed by
combustion which is not exactly
something that's condoned by doctors
very well it's a very big moving Target
and one that I think you and I should
have a private chat over I would love
that just about something small that was
bang on the mark Stephen great question
just at this note to all the audience
however long humans have been playing
with cannabis genetics the land races
have been evolving with humans for
hundreds of thousands of years for
Millennia and so if that isn't the most
the most um I think Nature has been
playing around with genetics much longer
than anyone else and we need to keep
that in mind
any other questions from the audience we
have a couple more minutes
oh wait I had a question but I forgot it
because I hit some hash while you were
talking earlier same uh
so it was because you were talking about
the so as uh uh we've been evolving with
weed we've been evolving with us so
would you call some of these new weeds
like a junk food or would you say that
it's just further Evolution because
young people like sweeter things and you
know you know what I mean
because everything tastes like a dessert
all the old heads are always like bring
back the weed that tastes like feet and
cheese and burnt tires and a skunk but
all the kids are like we like the
Skittles and the candy and then right
when was the last time you had a coffee
flavored weed or a wine flavored weed
would you say that's just part of the
evolution or would you say that
it's more of a bastardization I think I
think it depends on what you're doing
with it at the end of the day
um it's it's medical if it's
recreational then you know whatever
tastes fine is great but if it's medical
um
the human body is is the way it is so it
changes very slowly and it doesn't adapt
as fast as modern society or especially
not as fast as the industry uh changes
and adapt so whenever we come up with uh
with new strains especially I think in
the medical sector we need to keep that
in mind that if something is new and
we're going too far away
um from from what is natural we need to
keep in mind that there's a question
mark not saying it's bad but we need to
remember that we don't know we're not
sure I think we're just always saying to
challenge why is it recreational versus
medical so if you look at data from the
US you see that in Recreation Mark
Market 45 of people actually
self-medicate and they're not fully
aware so when anybody says hey this is
reckoned as medical I always ask why is
it wreck and what are you doing in there
and then suddenly they start to say well
I'm sleeping better I have less anxiety
etc those are medical indications and
that's also from a doctoral challenge
because Steven also said to be about
that and ask those questions but
suddenly you see p patients uneducated
about their own diseases yeah I I don't
know a single cannabis consumer that
says I do it because I like getting
messed up right like I well sometimes I
like to be high as hell I'm not gonna
lie that's that that's totally fair but
the I believe that there's a medical
reason that you are doing that probably
I was probably sad There you go
so there's a perfect example right here
where that is self-medicating right oh
cannabis uses medical use according to
the late great Dennis perone he would
say all cannabis uses medical use I tend
to to agree we are unfortunately out of
time but that was fantastic thank you
all so much thank you let's hear it
again for this fantastic panel