hey everyone I am so excited to be here
at the Cannabis biotech and ICBC I you
know speak at a lot of cannabis
conferences and I feel that people are
always fangirling but I am fangirling
over this panel there's it's going to be
a really good panel if you're interested
in medical cannabis and clinical trials
and biotechnology so I'm really excited
to get into it so
yes let's get our Waters open
and we can get started we'll start with
introductions so we know who we're
talking to today so would you like to go
first since you're beside me okay
um I have introduced myself so for the
panel I'm Terry Regan I'm president of
brain's paraceutical and um I I have
been in the industry two years and prior
to that I was in the pharmaceutical
industry
pharmaceutical being sort of big farmer
okay all right my name is Clement
zapanchich I'm here with uh my brother
co-founder of company planzy we are a
startup developing uh plant injections
so plant infusion which yields more
product and my background is in
biomedical research as well as software
for Life Sciences
hi my name is Michael sassano I'm CEO of
so my Pharmaceuticals we're a
manufacturing facility for cannabis
containing products based in Lisbon
Portugal
I'm Simon nicolusi I'm CSO of tuscoli
Pharma Switzerland
my background is pharmaceutical Sciences
I'm a pharmacist by myself so I have
also some role in the public pharmacy in
doing compounding farther I did some
research pre-clinical and clinical
research and my focus was always in the
thesis on the endocannabinoid system
research so
happy to join in
thank you we have an incredible panel
here today guys I'll be your moderator
today I am Antoinette Gomez the CEO and
founder of peak Farm Labs Peak Farm Labs
is a cannabis pharmaceutical company
focusing on Sexual Health ailments we're
known for our cannabis suppositories for
endometriosis on the market
I've been doing cannabis for 10 years in
medical cannabis so I love this type of
talk and I can talk about it forever so
I'm excited to get into it today so with
the panel that we have here today I'm
curious you guys are at the Forefront of
medical cannabis right now all around
the world we have so many different
countries here speaking with us today so
I'm curious to ask you guys what are
your what are the biggest breakthroughs
that you're seeing in medical cannabis
biotech advancements that are helping
shape Healthcare today
I can okay I I I'm really getting
excited about the fact that you know
I've most probably looked at over a
thousand clinical studies at the moment
and and just the range in which um
evidence is being generated at the
moment it it really for me is a new
chapter in this industry you know it was
always about sort of THC and CBD but
we're starting to to understand the
benefits of CBG of CBN of the asset
forms you know and and looking at
potentially mapping these different
cannabinoids out and seeing being really
quite targeted about where they could
have their main benefit and for me
that's that that is great because that's
in parallel with what farmer was doing
farmer was moving into a a phase called
personalized medicine recognizing that
not everybody responded the same way and
you needed to personalize the medicine
and I think in some ways this industry
could lead in that area about really
being able to personalize and what going
to have the best best impact on
different cohorts of consumers or
patients it's so true
um it's so fascinating the way how
cannabis helps with our homeostasis and
it helps with like body temperature so
there's so many different ways that it
can help and it's really exciting to see
like CBC that's the one I'm really
excited about as well would you guys
like to add to that yeah so I get
excited about the technological aspect
of growing cannabis I think like we've
seen let's say in the past decades we
went from you know growing it
agriculturally to really growing it
high-tech uh indoor growth what I am
very excited is about adding more uh
real-time sensorics real-time analytics
uh to the growth because uh you know
better than I do but it's not just the
cannabinoids but the ratios between them
so how to get things right how to get
things just the right for the the right
patient so uh yeah it's really really
cool to see also coming to this event to
see how high tech is entering like both
for how to input uh you know how to
modify the plant and also how to monitor
what's happening uh it's really exciting
and in one side when you look at it from
a manufacturer's standpoint in one way
we're trying to make products for today
products that can be sold
um you know products that are most in
most cases generic uh in sense so if you
have your magisterial prep 1010 as an
example you know this is not something
where you're going to be have some IP
protection and something interesting
when when you make products even if
you're making them for a a marketable
product you get a lot of calls from
people in the pharmaceutical industry
trying to make different products and
one interesting Trend that I've been
seeing lately again getting a lot of
calls on is actual drug manufacturers
looking how they can take the
cannabinoids or the distillers or CBD or
TC or CBG and add that to an already
existing medical API for example one
group without naming names they they
wanted to take lidocaine and add it to
CBG and I couldn't understand what that
effect was but I found it most
interesting that people want to take an
already approved drug and add
accountability to it and I'm not sure of
the efficacy or how they're going to use
it but it's an interesting trend
um
I mean to follow up on this combination
is already given by by cannabis itself
it's I would say complex enough
I understand the approach of adding it
to lidocaine or whatever active
substance but
um we are maybe already on on the one
Edge while while Physicians not even
understand how to start the therapy and
one of the feedbacks is start simple
like one milligram THC once in the
evening
once a day so a very simple concept
which is just one one active substance
still an extract makes more sense from
from a
another point of view because the
Terrapins add additional effect through
the Entourage
and certain fractions are even more
effective than others
and when it comes to plants what strain
will be the source to manufacture this I
think that the personalized medicine
will in the end be the difference as you
said Antoinette with the with the
prescription on on an individual basis
on the ratio at the moment we have THC
and CBD but yes there will be other
cannabinoids and most likely CBN will be
one of the next one while Regulators
lack behind and in in certain countries
like Switzerland they don't even know
how to handle it but it's already on the
market
so the potential is there and we want to
we want to make use of that yeah I love
CBN I use it for sleep it's incredible
exactly
I thought we talked a lot about terpenes
clinical trials the latest advancements
in biotech there's so much like
medicinal therapeutic effects from this
plant from the terpenes the cannabinoids
what else is there I think something
that I found which is really cool a new
startup called kenerta is doing
um Planet cannabis medical products with
the cannabis plant but everything but
the cannabinoids so I'm really excited
about the future of cannabinoids myself
we're doing a clinical trial for our
suppositories for endometriosis but I'm
really excited to see what they have for
colitis and other things as well
yeah shall I respond of course it's an
open conversation okay so I'm going to
be a little bit controversial and I'm
sure you've heard of a of a saying that
a strength overplayed becomes a weakness
and I've used it with my children all
the time don't overplay your strengths
um but you know for me I think the the
Wonder and the beauty about cannabis is
it's it's a complicated plant with all
of these potential benefits and you know
the terpenes and the flavonoids and and
the different cannabinoids and all of
that it it's it's like a treasure chest
but you know the the challenge with
cannabis is it's got all of these
different cannabinoids and all of these
different terpenes and I think you know
there was a question that was asked in
my talk earlier which is when is Big
Pharma getting to get involved
um in the Cannabis sector and and I
think one of the challenges is this is
we have to make sense of it you know and
and
now this is where I'm going to get a
little bit controversial which is which
is we've got to know what we prescribing
you know we've got to know what is in
the makeup of whatever it is you're
prescribing because they do behave so
differently
you know and and and what I've seen is
that there are drug interactions you
know we know that THC potentially has a
very narrow therapeutic window
and so if you have a a flower that is
that is very high in THC and somebody
has an underlying cardiac condition or
somebody has glaucoma you you could find
yourself
um prescribing something where you think
it's going to be beneficial but
potentially could have um a detrimental
side effect I mean I saw a study last
week which in a glaucoma study where
where high levels of THC actually
accelerated the route to blindness
rather than actually addressed it so I
once again I I I'm so grateful it please
don't don't see me as trying to have a
go at anybody that's in medical cannabis
or anybody that is is a huge supporter
of the plant the reason we're at brains
biosutical have gone down the isolate
route is it's the path of least
resistance to some degree you know
Pharma and and Regulators want to know
exactly what is in the capsule or what
is in the pool and so being able to
extract it and then reconstituted with
what we want to put into it to you know
what Clement said over here about you
know we know that there's different
ratios and these different percentages
and you know we can play around with
that and then do the studies so I just
you know or all I'm saying is and and
I'm trying to get the debate going as
well but but but you know I think we as
an industry need to make sure that that
a quality is at its utmost at the best
you know secondly we know what is what
is in whatever it is we're prescribing
or we're doing research in it and that
we educate whoever is the user or the
prescriber around where the benefit lies
and just that now that you were talking
I thought of one uh challenge that we
were talking about at the National
Institute of biology is uh not only like
is it com the interaction between like
individuals and the individual strengths
and and the ultimate ratios of
cannabinoids and other compounds is
complex but uh uh there is also for
example in the in the case of treating
tumors and Cancers uh where you know
there is no hard evidence uh or FDA
great evidence that that it works but
there are
people that that got cured by by using
uh cannabis there is another element
which is uh how do these interactions uh
how did how does the interaction between
the cannabinoids the person the patient
and the tumor which has also their own
genetics uh how does this work so I
think
I I see a I see a challenge for big
Pharma because uh for for our FDA for
that matter how the drugs get approved
is
this is a compound we know exactly what
it does it does this it blocks uh you
know a certain pathway and therefore
there is no disease I think this is far
far more complex and just traditional
way of of trying to understand it's not
going to work so uh yeah I'm curious
what others think about what's going to
change I mean um it's it's certainly
difficult to get the market
authorization for a herbal medicine
product but there are I mean we have
very complex extracts already that are
used since decades for example for the
treatment of depression we have Saint
John's word extract or for example
specific lavender extract that is used
for the treatment of anxiety and these
studies I mean there are like 14 15
clinical trials that were needed safety
studies and coming back to that evidence
you have the three pillars that are have
to be followed and these are safety
efficacy and quality
and as a manufacturer you have to take
into account all the quality and
document it while Physicians have to
bring the evidence on the efficacy on
the safety level and a cannabis extract
can go the same way this is what was
shown for a for saltivex for example
which is an extract combination but you
can use actually
extracts that are compliant to
monographs currently at the stage of the
dab for example in Germany that will go
to the pharmacopia europea and then you
have the basis for that and it can be
also manufactured directly
as a magistral
compounding preparation and that allows
forms like suppositories capsules oils
are the current state but when it comes
to an authorization this is a completely
different story there you need the ctd
is a common technical document which
fulfills all the modules of yeah quality
safety and efficacy
and a lot of times when you look at it
when you boil it down into your own
world what does it mean and I try to
always look at it from a manufacturer's
standpoint and you know you're trying to
make a product that can come to Market
and you also have to realize the timing
of the markets and when you take a look
and you say Okay I want to boil this
down to a single element I want CBD
isolate you know th pure THC isolate and
you're looking at making a medicine
because you can analyze that single
element much simpler than you could
analyze the effects on the body of a
full spectrum extract as an example
and in one side you're trying to reach
that market you know that's looking at
the single elements or in one side
you're trying to reach that market uh
that's looking at the herbal extracts
and the Therapeutics effects of terpenes
minor cannabinoids and and a mix and
then trying to you know match what one
side wants and another side wants and
manufacture them that product that is
the trick uh that we're always trying to
solve in manufacturing and to some
extent it's not just you know making the
product it becomes what do The
Regulators accept and I can go country
by country and and and each one is
completely different as far as they're
similar in some ways but they have
differences in other ways how they look
at different delivery methods and how
they want it presented and how they look
at the product and that's a complication
that us as manufacturers have to address
on a constant basis
oh yeah tons of hurdles
you know
um and we talked a lot about clinical
trials I love this because it's it's so
important and I think it's a huge diff
you know differentiator for adult use
versus medical cannabis and I think that
they should be held to a higher standard
and I just wanted to add because you did
mention Terry that
Pharma isn't in cannabis Pharma is very
much in cannabis I was so happy that
Bayer put together the first cannabis
and endometriosis event specifically for
Endo and I think that goes back to what
you were saying is that we need to
create drugs that are specific to
certain diseases that's the only way how
we can it's not cannabis is great for so
many things but it's not great for
everything but we can create cannabis
drugs specific for you know certain
ailments which is very exciting yeah I I
agree and I mean there is former is like
jazz pharmaceutical board GW I mean I
know that farmer has a presence here but
I think all I was trying to say and I
think to to Simon's point is we've got
to be very comfortable that if you sort
of in the in the sort of the the the you
know prescribing flour or broad spectrum
or whatever the the path to to giving
patients access to that is most probably
different if compared to if you're in a
clinical trial program and both will
serve as a very different cohort of
patients and both are absolutely
required you know so the one you know
does require robust clinical evidence
proof of concept studies you know you've
got to you've got to get you make sure
that that you're being approved by by
the local authorities all of that in a
clinical trial program unfortunately
there is only one way pre-clean phase
one phase two phase three and and all of
them um take time and they take money
but yeah and I think that's when the
nevadises and and and the gsks and the
the big Pharma I know fazer has dipped
their toe into here and I think they've
just canceled you know just just to stop
that program but I I long to see people
follow bear and and and get into this
Market
and I love that it's clear that we're
all here for patients at the end of the
day we've seen how it's helped people
from all different walks of life
um so I'm curious when it comes to
clinical trials what barriers are you
guys facing and how are you getting
around them
what I'm interested maybe Simon you know
more uh but what I really liked was the
they did in
UK I believe they did this uh uh the
world evidence-based clinical trials so
I think this makes a lot more sense for
for uh for cannabis and that's very true
real world evidence is
um maybe I can say it's a collection of
the anecdotal evidence that exists but
the acceptance by Authority is currently
uh railings in very early stage for
approval purposes maybe they allow
certain use extension for authorized
drugs but if you come along and say hey
we have a nice real world evidence study
with 30 000 patients
well done published in a good Journal
good protocol you follow all the rules
they will say oh we're very sorry it's
insufficient the gold standard is a
randomized controlled trial and this is
where the problem comes in you need the
placebo control you need a nice
competitor like
um like in in paying you you treat it
against morphine I would bet canap
dronabinol as a single substance would
lose against morphine if you choose and
this is now coming back to the hurdle of
um what what is what are the problems in
clinical trials if you choose the wrong
primary endpoint you will fail and never
go into pain you will fail if you say
it's the primary endpoint to reduce pain
you will fail this is one of the biggest
challenges anyways in um in clinical
trials to overcome the placebo effect we
know that the endocannabinoid system is
significantly producing the placebo
effect this is why on top I mean it's
it's part of the whole thing I'm not
saying that cannabis is a placebo don't
get me wrong
um but to overcome the effect with the
significance and with the clinical
relevance secondly is is important to
show The Regulators then that the data
is sufficient to to get the market
authorization and my Approach after
let's say seven years in in Pharma
industry
is now with the scoli Pharma to make
on the magistral compounding way
apis that are manufactured like from
somai in a high quality available to the
patients by direct compounding and and
dispensing in a in a pharmacy and that's
a faster way and is accepted I mean
Authority most likely is won't like it
because they prefer the authorization
I don't know if someone is in the
audience from the Bay Farm current at
the moment oh not now
um but this is actually the way it it
goes and like this also evidence is
created on on the basis of simple oils
but when it comes to more interesting
formulations like a sublingual patch or
an encapsulated oil
um then it's a different story and there
we have the possibility to create
evidence provided to the regulators and
go the way of the of the prescribed
compounding
so this is maybe a little bit my
favorite at the moment I would um I
would be happy to join a clinical trial
program I am like a phase one study on
that point also yeah
yeah
I think for me you've got to know what
your goal is because the I would say
there's a clinical trial a lot and where
that that that what you want to do is
show a signal and so that you can give
Physicians confidence to prescribe the
product for certain conditions
um unfortunately those studies don't
always translate to studies that are
that can be approved by The Regulators
because with The Regulators you know
that you know the very first thing a
phase one study is all about is it safe
and so you've got to you you've got to
make sure you've done a proper pre-clean
program you've got to make sure that um
you you have done a dose response curve
I'm amazed at how many times people sort
of almost guessed that let's try this
dose and see if it works rather than
we've done a dose response curve and a
lot of the studies that I've seen at the
moment there's an inverse response with
cannabinoids we know you know that that
there comes an optimal point and then at
that point it actually becomes
detrimental or the therapeutic effect
um is diminished so you know I think for
me
um know what why you're doing this study
and then make sure that that you you
know the criteria by which that study
will be approved by by whoever is the
authority that needs to approve it
and what you are saying about
compounding cannabis I think that's the
perfect place that cannabis should be in
is in pharmacies like I love hybrid Farm
Canada's first licensed Pharmacy that's
where we started with our cannabis
suppositories and we got to see all
these patients with their feedback and
but as soon as we started manufacturing
them at a way higher level we noticed
that there was far more efficacy so I
love that there's opportunity and there
is space for pharmacy but we should be a
lot more open to that I wish Canada
would be a little bit more open people
need to learn from hybrid Farm not just
for Canada I know for yeah exactly and
um which brings me to my next question
I'm curious
um you know we are it's really exciting
to be at the front of a new drug of new
plant there's so much unknown so I'm
curious from you from you all
what are some ethical considerations
that we should be thinking about when it
comes to the clinical trials or
manufacturing of the plant
I guess you know I always keep staying
on I'll keep continuing on my
perspective you know as you look as a
manufacturer you get a lot of people and
a lot of scientists and a lot of doctors
that come through and and they want
things a certain way and that they want
it mixed a certain way and you listen to
them and of course in one way you want
to remain neutral and you're providing
them with a a product that they can do
testing on on another side uh you know
especially in the Cannabis industry
since you have markets like the US and
Canada they have a different perception
than in Europe and they're coming up
with let's say solutions that may or may
not possibly uh be healthy for people
one solution that I had saw not so long
ago is something common in the U.S which
carries an enzymatic inhibitor and I
thought to myself you know
how can this possibly be good for
somebody who may be taking medication
for something seriously and there is no
warning sign and they're selling this
commercially
and although it's not something we would
produce here in Europe
um it goes to the ethical question of
what you can and cannot provide and how
you need to label that and what kind of
testing needs to go through with that
and when you have a market
that's not regulated like the U.S market
uh and and it's regulated more on a
restaurant quality basis where there is
nobody saying you can or cannot put that
in there
um you do have ethical questions you
have to ask yourselves
um in that I think less so here in
Europe
um you know the the excipients you use
the ingredients you use how you use them
the quality standards that is attributed
to them it's less of an ethical matter
and it's more of a testing matter
um but you know this would come to mind
when you ask that kind of a question
most definitely people are really bold
to get out there but yeah got to take a
consideration your thoughts as well yeah
I mean I see like
let's say that uh well cannabis is going
to be accepted more and more as uh you
know by Pharma and uh approved
um I see a potential side effect of this
or negative effect like that it's then
perceived as cannabis being like a safe
plant to you know to use recreationally
as well which
to some extent that's true but
especially in you know in younger adults
it can have really bad effects on Mental
Health mental development so my concern
with you know this being taken over by
Pharma and heavily marketed what kind of
impact it will have on you know people
that will now consider it safer than it
actually is
Fair points
I I think one of the biggest challenges
for me is that because it is a natural
plant and because we've got so much
anecdotal evidence
we can sometimes only look at the
benefits of it but we've also got to
look at at some of the challenges or
some of the side effects with it and and
you guys are the most optimistic group
that I've ever worked with I mean in
Pharma we always the the you know the
glass is always half full it's never
half then um a half empty it's never
half full but um I think we do need to
be aware that that you know that
particularly if people have concomitant
therapies or or or underlying conditions
that we need to be aware of it we know
you know that that that some of the
cannabinoids actually suppress the
immune system we also know that the
cannabinoids are are broken down through
your p450 cytochrome pathway which is
where your oncology drugs are broken
down where your epileptic drugs are
broken down your antidepressants or
whatever so you could actually have drug
interactions or you could actually you
know diminish the therapy effect of your
chemotherapy and we've seen that and
certain indications you know we we know
that they come with with side effects
you know THC in particular and stimulate
your cv1 receptors which which from a
cardiac point of view if you've got an
underlying cardiac condition
um that could be really serious so I
think you know I think we've just got to
be really aware of of of of not only the
positives but also where the limitations
are and be upfront and honest about that
most definitely
I mean also from from a safety point of
view the concerns are of novel
cannabinoids coming into human already
now as a food supplement or um also in
in in waves they can be very high dose
and they do have an effect we are lucky
that cannabinoids are from a
toxicological point of view
um not leading to death in that way when
dosing High you have your intoxication
but they are in a way safe but
therapeutic window is still have to be
taken into account and there um you're
you're perfectly right I mean the
pharmacokinetic interactions for example
of CBD to inhibit the p450 side to
chromes that absolutely important to
mention to patients especially when you
are not labeling it and at the moment
there is only
um to the best of my knowledge one
authorized CBD drug that contains the
proper labeling in the in the smpc and
in in the patient information leaflet
not to take it in combination with or
always under doctor's prescription so
you don't want to actually have a bad
impact on
let's say a pro drug that would make
your blood thin and it doesn't work
anymore and then it leads to some more
severe effect so this is about let's say
ethics responsibility that we have to
see and and where we have to provide
also evidence from a safety point of
view
yes safety and access right
um
so what I love about ICBC is that we
have a lot of people here from all
around the world we have policy makers
we have manufacturers we have you know a
lot of people from so many different
walks of life in cannabis it's
incredibly powerful so I'm curious from
you guys what your thoughts are on how
policy government
um Academia universities
work together at the Cannabis industry
to accelerate research I feel like it's
a no-brainer that this research needs to
be done I've done before you know even
adult use legalization I think so what
are your thoughts and how can we
accelerate This research and have you
seen other companies do that partner
together in terms of government Academia
and Manufacturing
one thing it's nice that I can point to
in the EU is I mean at least I can speak
for Portugal and I'm sure it's for other
countries I'm just not aware of them
um the the government seem extremely
supportive through research and
development grants where you can get up
to 70 percent of your money back that
you invest in what they would call Gray
matter you know in your brain power to
create IP and create development this is
something pretty unique uh that the the
governments actually support you uh in
that way and cannabis has uh has access
to that and so for people I always try
to encourage people that come through to
try to get on those applications or to
at least think about them they're
released every so often and and to be
you know up on that and I think that's
an easy way for let's say uh an industry
that's not as capitalized uh as the
larger groups the pfizers and the mercs
where they have a lot more money to to
to research things and have interest in
many areas but for ours at least there
is access and there are places where
people can get access currently
uh maybe from a Swiss perspective and
yeah Switzerland is one of the most
Innovative countries in the world we
have
um the possibility to
um in in a small and very Dynamic and
very Progressive
um project which is interprofessionally
built to push forward certain medical
cannabis applications and then there is
a direct link to to The Regulators that
will see the data also so um it's uh in
a way evidence has to be created that's
that's That's the basis and acceleration
of that process
in my opinion always needs like a doctor
it needs maybe a pharmacist but it also
needs the nurses and it also needs the
patients so there must be working groups
that are diverse and that cover all
ranges from let's say the plant to the
patient and then on top of that you need
an education program to communicate that
good data that you have generated
because if you don't talk about it no
one will know and Authority they don't
know they you you must teach them so you
must show them the data they don't just
trust like a lot of people do because
they have an effect these cannabinoids
we know that but if you show that on
paper to non-users to non-patients and
that of authority sites and then they
will accept it
but it must be an interplay a teamwork I
agree I think one a great example is um
I work really closely with the
endometriosis Society of Canada and so
we sponsor their events we share all of
the you know medical education that we
have with them we share a doctor if they
ever need one but they've also brought
work to me they brought um the
University of Sydney Australia they're
doing the clinical trial on
endometriosis and they were looking for
a product and they recommended us so I
think that if you are working in a
medical cannabis I think that's a great
way to accelerate is really building
your community in that specific disease
and I think that goes back to what
Michael is saying is that these products
should be by you know for specific
ailments because it's going to help
yeah and we're almost wrapping up soon
I wanted to also ask you guys
um you know what do you want people to
leave here with about knowing about
medical cannabis and biotech and what
you think the future will be you know I
think that a lot can happen in the next
decade a lot has happened in this decade
in medical cannabis so I would love for
that to be the last question
all right Arkansas
um I just think I would what I would ask
of all of you is whatever field you in
whether it is in medical cannabis
whether it's in drug development whether
it is a nutraceutical and and
over-the-counter products you know just
just set yourself the highest bar
possible you know it just it's just so
concerning that every time the Swiss
Canton of pharmacies do an audit and 95
of products have to be removed from the
Shelf because they don't meet the spec
you know they've either haven't got
enough active ingredient or the impurity
levels are too high or whatever it might
be and so for me it's just you know
ultimately we need each other you know
there's not there's not one Silver
Bullet chair that's going to solve it
all we all need to work together and
collectively we need all of the
different areas that you're in but let's
let's not tarnish the industry and
confirm what Pharma and some of the
politicians think you know with their
skeptic Minds let's show them that we
can set the highest and Pioneer and
personalized medicine evidence
generation Etc
yeah and kind of actually to your point
also from the starting question right
well it gets me excited is uh the
technology technological Advance
advancements with with growing the plant
so
um here I see like also as a take-home
message you know
if we are going towards for
pharmaceutical industry basically
creating a biological drug right so in
that sense uh as a standard way of doing
biological drugs you have this huge
bioreactors with you know exact control
what goes in what comes out real-time
sensorics and I think like you know if
cannabis it's a plant it doesn't have
that built in but we are going towards
there and there is a lot of Technology
that's out there that can be implemented
you know Machine Vision our company does
uh infusion for the plants so so you can
control exactly what goes in there are
companies here that we met that do
real-time measurements of various
compounds that can indicate the health
of the plant obviously cannabinoids a
cannabinoid composition so to your point
yeah I agree we need to it's exciting
but also the whole industry needs to
professionalize uh it's happening the
growth uh the the production facilities
need to get to that to that point where
it's very clear what's happening we
understand we understand the genetics we
understand what goes in what comes out
and uh and yeah that's that's I think
the one of the crucial paths forward
just a is a closing idea
they're in cannabis there's something
for everybody uh depending on how you're
looking at it of course you have the
well-known uh Apple dialects and sativax
and the people
um and and maybe 1 000 plus different uh
trials that are going on now at that
kind of a level
um but there's also the herbal medicine
medicinal level
um you know another level that people
can participate on
um and there's you don't have to just go
out and try if you're thinking biotech
you're thinking IP protection you're
thinking these drugs um but there's
little things that you can do and
sometimes you got to look at that for
where is your the reality and what
you're trying to accomplish and I
believe there's there's a place for
everybody inside of this this space and
you just have to unlock it
I think the to maximize the medical use
of this um
cannabis plant and to to have the the
the
potential really used in in different
diseases and indication we have to
partner up and to create scientific
evidence together so that also
Regulators are further convinced to me
this is actually at a high
pharmaceutical standards necessary I
think and in the end will help the whole
industry
most definitely I love that tip on
entrepreneurship or even if you're you
know growing in your career in cannabis
this is a very long game and I think
it's just about keeping keep going and
you know partnering partnering together
I believe that there is a place for
everyone here as well there's so much
space and so much potential it's really
up to us
oh thank you so much guys
[Applause]