uh well thank you Alex Rogers for
putting this together and I think speak
for all of us it's uh it's a pleasure to
be here my name is Luke richner
um regulatory landscape and navigating
unit is kind of something I've been slid
I slid in through into over the last
couple of years
um I'll share a bit more about that in a
second I'd like to give my esteemed
colleagues here a chance to introduce
themselves before we jump into the panel
and share a bit of our insights what has
happened in the world so far and where
this is hopefully going and see if we
can actually make sense of this industry
after the next 40 minutes
Anthony
uh yeah uh um first and foremost uh
honor to be here thanks a lot to all the
organizers I'm Anthony charig I'm from
Ken intelligence I'm the head legal
analyst there we provide provide market
and legal
analysis and data for the Cannabis
sector as a lawyer in the U.S for
several years before moving to Barcelona
Spain
quite an upgrade in my opinion uh very
happy there I've been there about seven
years
I am Dr Shana fariki I'm a head of
research and toxicology at true terpenes
I got my PhD studying chemistry of
vaping and then I switched over to true
terpenes and created their toxicology
program with all that research I've been
able to educate lawmakers and regulators
and help actually write the language
that goes into laws and then also I've
been able to support manufacturers if it
does come to legal proceedings
hi everyone Deepak Anand I'm the head of
Consulting at Gateway proven strategies
I've been around the space quite a few
years just over 11 years worked very
closely with a number of governments on
cannabis policy and regulations starting
in North America and then kind of moving
across the world on a global basis done
a lot of work in Europe as well both in
the medical cannabis and also CBD sector
so happy to be here today
my name is Lucas McCann I'm a CSO and
co-founder of a regulatory and
scientific cannabis consulting company
called can Delta I have a background in
medicinal organic chemistry medicinal
and synthetic organic chemistry
um after I finished my PhD I moved over
to health Canada worked there in the
inspectorate branch for Health Products
and as you may know Health Canada is the
regulator for the medical and now
recreational Cannabis streams in Canada
following that it started a consulting
company with another Health candidate
inspector Ken Delta where I've got a
team of 25 folks who are active across
Canada we've helped launch over 300
businesses we've recently moved into the
U.S specifically the tri-state area in
New York New Jersey done a lot of work
down south in many of the Bible Belt
states Alabama Texas
Mississippi and have also done some work
internationally as well happy to be here
well absolute pleasure
um a bit about what what brought me into
this industry and and kind of will lead
into this in a second is as being from
Switzerland and always seeing you know
what is Canada doing what is the US
doing and the Trailblazers of the
industry what are the regulatory
Frameworks what are their standards what
were the different question marks and uh
between that realized that it didn't
speak a harmonized language what was
done in the U.S didn't really speak to
at the time how I saw European medical
at least and and other standards kind of
uh can be can be harmonized in the back
end and that led them to me kind of
starting something something from
scratch and trying to really bring those
different uh well regulatory Frameworks
is a big word but uh well you have
standardization and you have different
parts that feed into that
um and uh well bringing those together
and and harmonizing certain points there
was one of the big things that I put on
my uh uh cap and with having you know a
couple of the esteemed gentlemen lady
over here uh Sean you've been very
outspoken early in this how can you
bring standards how can you bring
regulatory Frameworks what were some of
the early Channel challenges you saw
over there and how did you to bring the
industry into this and what were your
approaches and and what can you share
from from those early days
so the early days of regulations one
thing that I noticed in
they're getting better at now is using
very umbrella terms to create
regulations and a lot of times they
don't understand everything that falls
under that umbrella term so they tend to
over regulate Beyond even what the
lawmakers are intending to and then
oftentimes
they are regulating with the uh you know
with the message of safety Consumer
safety but most of the time Regulators
do not have any scientific background at
all so these laws don't actually protect
the health and safety of consumers so a
lot of what I've done is to educate them
on this is how you write regulations to
protect your end consumer
I don't know where they have been also
very engaged in the early days anything
that you remember from back then that we
now in Europe were at this stage where
we can you know we can still influence
we can actually we're part of this
process what can we learn from back then
that we can kind of move into
I think that for a lot of us who are
coming from North America here to
Germany and learning about the
regulatory framework that's coming into
play here based on this beautiful leak
um the alarm Bells I think are ringing
for us and I think there are a lot of
lessons learned that we've seen from
other markets that if Germany doesn't
think about implementing very seriously
you know after pillar one and pillar two
or even throughout this process are
going to result in a framework that
ultimately will fail I think there's
some very very important considerations
and there are some major gaps and some
of those gaps I think include you know
number one for what all good robust Fair
regulation should really include and
that some means of restorative justice
and that can include elements of social
Equity it can include putting those in
line who are affected by cannabis
prohibition
it must include a means of safe reliable
access for patients and I haven't seen
any means of how Germany at this point
intends to transition those from the
illicit Market or the Cannabis movement
into this new market
no applause yet excellent uh excellent
excellent points Lucas I think I'd echo
in addition to what Lucas is is already
said you know I think it's very
important for us to look back
particularly from a European perspective
that's what what's happened previously
and what is happening before we can go
forward so when you look at medical
cannabis in Europe to your point Luke on
harmonization
still a lack of harmonization across
Europe right I mean harmonization is a
pillar of the European Union and the
fact that we don't have a single
monograph of flower which has been
talked about for the last three years is
is ridiculous you've got you know what
seven eight plus European countries that
are all selling cannabis flour and have
been for the last
you know over six seven years where
there's no harmonized framework so if
you're a cultivator or a producer that
operates anywhere you've got you know
arguably 10 12 up to 20 different
Frameworks you need to follow Germany is
completely different from Poland it's
completely different from Denmark it's
completely different from Switzerland so
if you're trying to sell the same flower
into those five markets you've got five
sets of regulatory Frameworks to follow
and that never happens in Europe right
Europe is all about harmonization so I
think it the dialogue with Regulators is
critically important right now to be
having not only at a national level but
also at a European commission level and
it's incumbent on companies now to start
holding Regulators feed to the fire to
actually make that happen and make sure
there's at a minimum there's no
explanation why there isn't a European
monograph for flower currently so then
you've got to start and fix the medical
program before you can start to
speculate and what's happening is pure
speculation on a recreational program
yeah I think that those are great points
I mean there's you know just like we we
saw in the U.S
um with this Patchwork of regulations
let's just take CBD for example you know
you have 50 different states
um with very different policies
um different products that they do allow
don't allow and we're seeing that same
type of you know Patchwork framework
um that you know now um in Europe um
that has that has really been imported
and creates a whole lot of issues from
you know THC levels in hemp
um you know at least in the U.S it's a
pretty standardized under the federal
law but you know we now see any anywhere
from point two percent you know now uh
member states now moving up to 0.3 but
then we have you know countries like
Switzerland CZ Republic at one percent
you know these these just creates all
kinds of
um you know hurdles for the industry
um you know one thing that I do think
that is interesting and even we don't
have to go far you know as far back as
the early days
um you know in North America you know
what we're seeing happen with what we
call ihdc's intoxicating him derived
cannabinoids such as Delta 8 hhc
um you know it does seem that at least
Europe is kind of learning some of the
lessons that from some of the maybe
missteps that have been happening in the
U.S with these these products where it
is just completely all over the board
from you know Statewide bands to the DEA
doesn't know really what the status is
um and then you know but at least Europe
I will say you know has been able to
react a bit better they have some better
mechanisms in place to be able to
you know address these new psychoactive
substances
um and so you know there are a lot of
missteps I think in the U.S when it came
to that where they ended up you know
started having very unintended
consequences like I believe Washington
with CBN where they wanted to kind of
ban the semi-synthetic process but then
they realized actually that's how a lot
of the CBN on that the market uh is so
um but yeah at least I think Europe and
in kind of that aspect has learned a
little bit but um still kind of I think
making some of the same mistakes that
were made in the US in particular you'd
have to try very hard to do worse than
what we have in the U.S you have to try
very hard I would just piggyback of what
Anthony said on on CBD and I think
the lack of global regulation or
misregulation on CBD is probably one of
the the worst things that we have in the
industry because you look at CBD you
know it's available everywhere
U.S that's available Canada is
completely screwed up the regulation of
CBD in my opinion because we've
regulated the same as THC which makes no
sense uh and you've got the you know
you've got the European union now that's
going on this novel Foods pathway which
is great except that no one has Clarity
on the novel Foods pathway you know I've
got clients that are wanting to apply
for an FSA application and FSI just
keeps raising the bar you know you need
to do human trials they need to do
animal trials that you need to get into
human pregnancy trials I mean it's CBD
for crying out loud meanwhile it's
available everywhere so the global lack
of regulation on CBD is just benign and
before you can start to regulate THC and
look at recreational Cannabis we've got
to fix some existing challenges and you
can't make the bower so high that you're
going to have an illicit Market you know
try live or in the case of CBD just an
unregulated Market Drive
now we've seen CBD big issues big
different approaches big well this
harmonization I would like to say
we touched a little bit the the medical
side yes when I started with with
creating the software I was like okay
where do you go so my what I do is kind
of trying to harmonize standards to
through transparency and technology and
it was like the easiest thing to do is
EU GMP because it's the most defined
of course it's the hardest to reach it's
the most processes it's the most
different steps and so forth but at
least you have a guidebook and in all
those other parts there is no guidebook
and
um I did have the pleasure a little bit
too or the pleasure the owner whatever
you want to call it to to be involved in
some of these working groups
in several countries and and a big part
there was and that's my personal
experience and I'd like to hear a bit
more from from your side was whenever
the industry came together and gave kind
of a coherent thought through uh based
on other examples input be it you know
looking at the tobacco industry looking
at other Industries looking at best case
practices looking at you know
standardization in in food health safety
standards and so forth whenever the
industry came together and really
thought through proposed something be it
through associations be it through
individuals that were a bit you know
more active in certain parts I've always
had the experience that the ears were
very open now now we all have a lot of
friends in the industry that all they do
is complain every day and this is one of
the moments where I you know look into
the audience and say if you really want
to navigate not just through the
regulatory landscape as it comes if you
want to try to
paved the way a little bit in your
direction it really helps to come
together and you know gather some
thoughts and I know there's a lot of
people on stage here that have been
involved in in several approaches there
if you could give you know one or two
advices towards the industry at this
moment right now in Europe where we
still are at the point where we can have
influence we can still learn from the
mistakes that were made we don't have to
go down the same routes we don't have to
you know try to copy paste the framework
that allowed for 400 tons overproduction
or 70 percent elicit after 10 years and
so forth so uh any you know short advice
that you would give to the audience
based on the learnings that you had from
you know the US and Canada what can we
do now here in Europe at this stage
where The Regulators are very open the
ears are open we can bring the input yes
there was a leaked draft I can tell you
that draft is not what's going to go
into action and there is the working
groups very active in there so any two
cents what can we do now to kind of not
complain after
well I think one of the biggest things
is uh is is lobbying right I think
you've got to work you've got to be able
to work with your your politicians your
local MPS mlas MEPS uh on the European
Parliament level you've got to start
engaging with them I think what has
happened in Canada is we've seen that
now companies are starting to really get
after the government but really weren't
proactively doing as much as perhaps
they could have for example the dairy
industry in Canada is severely regulated
and when they went through their crisis
on taxation I'm not advocating for
killing animals but they actually took
cows to the legislature and started
shooting them in front of politicians to
say this is what you're actually doing
you're killing our industry we have we
have no choice because I can't keep
these cows around and so like you've got
to make sure you're really getting in
the face of politicians and telling them
why regulatory change is important I
think on a European side you've got to
do the same thing you've got to learn
from the mistakes that have been made in
places like Canada and there is many
mistakes that have been made and there's
certainly really some really good things
that have been adopted so you got to be
presenting both sides of that coin very
early on taxation is a huge one I you
know there isn't a lot of conversation
happening around taxation but I trust me
once governments start get used to that
tax dollars it's very hard to to take
that back and we're seeing that in
Canada so I think that sort of
conversation needs to start happening
early companies that are raising money
and some have raised a lot of money
needs to start engaging regulators and
saying here's a report just make sure
you don't tax it and really coming and
making that public and engaging with
politicians on it
yeah I would yeah Echo exactly what you
said I mean I think that you know if
um you know legalization is to truly
happen
um that there has to be an empowerment
to have the political courage to get it
across the line
um and what I mean by that is
um you know we've now seen it unfold in
in Germany where falling back to plan B
and you know really have to have some
leaders who are willing to go that extra
mile to to step out there and be leaders
and Pioneers in what they do because
what we see you know we track
um you know about 80 countries globally
and so whenever you see you know for a
region someone who really steps out one
jurisdiction one country you know then
their their Neighbors start to look
across the border and see that oh
actually you know they're creating a lot
of Revenue
um and they're you know maybe our
concerns about legalization or not
um you know actually unfolding it like
we thought
um you know I will say you know Luke you
and I were just in in Prague about a
month ago and we heard from the
anti-drug coordinator there you know
very bold statements that were being
made and I hope that to see more if you
know if things are really going to be
moved forward you know saying that you
know we're going with plan a
um and we're not even talking about Plan
B because then politicians are going to
latch on to plan B and try to move
forward with that but you know the
government is messaging at least that
they are going to you know Go full bore
ahead with full legalization and I think
that that's the kind of attitude that
that you know has has to be in place
that you need more than just allies but
you need champions for policy change
I think an important point to consider
also since Germany is now in the phase
where you know we're sort of at the cusp
year of legalization is leaving room for
product Innovation and and for
innovation of companies to come in and
really do a successful job and to
simulate as much as possible I think the
kinds of products or the experience that
people have known to love about cannabis
and and from the plant and I think you
do that by leaving room unfortunately
for a little bit of profitability
because ultimately the goal here is for
compliance and enforcement to be to be
active and to be executed properly for
companies to be compliant and produce
safe product that the industry is
regulated but also to defeat the illicit
market and protect Youth and to be able
to do that you'll need to be able to
have commercial companies involved in
this that are that are somewhat for
profit I mean from from a commercial
standpoint the recommendation I would
give to those who are looking to start a
business would be to you know think
globally but have a very targeted
approach in how you set your business
and one of the leading causes of failure
in the Cannabis industry was what we saw
in the first year of operation where
companies would acquire so many assets
and so much territory in so many square
meters of growing space because they
thought this was a competition this was
King of the Hill and that ultimately led
to their demise and the uprise of Kraft
cannabis products which were very low
person per plant ratios and that is now
the highest amount of product being sold
in in retail dispensaries in Canada is
from these Craft products because
they're asset light and they have low
licensing fees so taking a very
staggered approach to starting a
business in cannabis is ultimately the
thing that will drive your success
best way to stay compliant with
regulations is to be proactive and
actually help write the laws that go
into regulations and the only way to do
that is to really band together and
collaborate with other businesses in
this space form coalitions get Lobby
groups these lobbyists can get you in
the door with these politicians find
emails phone numbers of these
politicians hand them out to everyone
your patients can call and say I don't
like this part of the law I want this to
be written in the law like they can
absolutely influence remember your
politicians are there for the people and
one lesson that I hope Europe takes a
lesson learned from the US is that
medical recreational CBD THC we need to
work together not against each other
just one more thing if I might add
actually two more things I'll say one is
you gotta remember that legalization is
a process it's not an event
especially when you're setting up
companies right you don't do this once
and it's done and that's the regulations
right it is going to be a process
Regulators fully understand this is a
new industry to regulate and it's
industry's job to hold them accounted
with that right so as things develop as
we're developing new cannabinoids we're
getting safety information on Vapes
whatever it might be we've got to start
holding Regulators feed to the fire and
saying you know the process needs to
evolve and so companies kind of look and
say all right legalization is done we've
now got a law and that's it now we're
going to stick to this framework it's
very much a very much a process
talking about a process
um I'd like to share a bit what we're
doing in in Switzerland right now which
I think then also leads into the model
projects in Germany and gives us the
chance to we don't want to speculate but
maybe you know give our two cents on
where this this could go based on
everything we've learned from other
industries from other jurisdictions in
other parts of the world
um what we've done in Switzerland was we
assessed what was done outside
um then we looked at the laws you know
the international treaties that have
been signed one of them in 1961 a very
special one which a lot of a lot of
things are based on that a lot of global
trade is based on the single Convention
of 1961 and under that it clearly states
you can either go you know natural
traditional medicine or you can go
research and research can be social
economical and social cultural or as we
do in Switzerland and so what we've set
up there we realized okay there is a gap
there that we can test how this Market
goes forward and instead of saying this
has worked there we do this this has
worked there the government came up and
really created I would say the most open
framework out there in Switzerland at
the moment you can go you need to be
part of the health Ministry or you
supply to the health Ministry you've got
to have the municipality you got to have
a cultivation manufacturing distribution
point of sale a study nurse which is a
qualified person police has to be
involved and a research institute as I
mentioned before and you can come up and
come forward and really share how this
could work and I'll give two examples
there
um basil is the first one that is
happening right now
372 consumers not patients have access
to regulated recreational THC cannabis
it is nine pharmacies that is being
distributed through y9 pharmacies
because it has a integrated supply chain
that already is you know fast and easy
to kind of work within compliance the
reporting is done under a general
narcotics law so so that was the
approach of Basel the easy one The Fast
One how can we do that then it was
obviously Very Fast approved Zurich went
with 2000 consumers at first those are
small numbers for you but we're a small
country so it's quite significant for
their compared to the amount of actual
users and there is 21 points of sale it
can be Social Clubs it can be and we
have this thing that if you you know
drop points if you're an addict for
heroin you get methadone government
supported and and normal dispensaries so
what did Switzerland do Switzerland
allowed
uh stakeholder driven approach to
understand all the different needs and
challenges that are within this industry
so they didn't say in Holland it's like
this and in the U.S it's like this and I
think what is very forward-thinking what
I like about that approach is that we
really everybody has the chance to come
up with a thesis and share why it would
work like this in their Direction so you
have I would say the first and only real
all stakeholder approach towards
how to then create a legal framework and
in the I think a year ago I spoke about
this and everybody said well the Swiss
you know the Swiss small country they do
what they do a couple of months ago
Germany went the same way so we have a
lot of opportunities on the table there
and I just like to you know get some
insights from you what what would you
I'm not even going to ask how would you
put your perfect model project together
but now you have the chance with the
magic wand how would you set this up for
the future
I won't touch base in Switzerland really
quickly I think it's great that they've
started to move forward with the pilot
projects but unfortunately patients have
been left behind uh it was only until
last year that Switzerland actually
started allowing medical cannabis to
really meaningfully be sold it was it
was it had a legal program for a while
now but certainly not the level that
that 20 years that's that's happened
right so and now access is starting to
be available and certainly the
recreational Cannabis pilot projects are
are definitely a model way for Europe to
be following and it's refreshing that
Switzerland is actually taking that
approach now because I think it really
is in very interesting way to comply
with U.N treaties you mentioned U.N
treaties earlier and I think that's a
very creative compliant way to come up
with it and I think that's exactly what
we did in Canada right we basically
looked at un treaties we know we're
technically in violation of U.N treaties
but it's a principal non-compliant
approach that we decided to take in
Canada we had kids under the age of 18
that were accessing Canada us at a
higher rate than any other country in
the world and so we decided to regulate
it so we could start to actually have
conversations with you around that so I
think it's important to be making sure
we're taking you know care of some of
the foundational stuff patience I think
is one Lucas brought up the social
Equity piece I think that's another
really important one and that can be
built into these legislations and that
needs to start happening very early and
it also then sort of enables countries
to go to the U.N and have a meaningful
dialogue to change these treaties
because that's eventually what needs to
happen you know you're obviously going
to have countries like Russia and Saudi
Arabia that are vehemently opposed you
know to cannabis legalization but at
least then you start to get more and
more people on your side is when you've
had a robust system when you've factored
in Social Equity when you factored in
you know age of access you factor in a
number of conditions within the country
so I mean that's quite important data
approach like clinical trials I think if
we were starting from scratch it would
be you know let's isolate this compound
these compounds these cannabinoids you
know over 130 of them cannabis plant and
actually conduct the research because
regulations are based off of public
consultation but also the sort of the
political stance of of the The
Regulators the politicians involved in
creating these regulations and public
consultation is fueled from the actual
data that's available the scientific
data so having that data in hand I think
would create a set of regulations that
is much more fair and robust and really
pays attention to you know what cannabis
can do and what THC is really capable of
and I you know I'm not going to present
here a thesis on the on the model
um regulatory framework but I mean I
think uh you know whenever we're talking
about adult use or recreational use two
very important factors I mean well first
and foremost you're going to have to be
the illicit Market
um and you know two ways that I think
are very important one of which is being
done to some extent and one not so much
one being is accessibility I mean you've
got to be able to you know have a wide
range of products that are available
um because if they're not going to be
provided in the illicit market then uh
people folks will just go straight back
to the illicit Market but then also the
the stigma around consumption I think
that even in the U.S uh still you know
we are seeing some consumption lounges
I'm starting to you know take place now
but you know you look at like the even
the the German framework that's been
leaked is you know there's still this
stigma around uh around consumption and
you have to bring consumers Out of the
Shadows you know you even in the the
German framework they're saying you know
there would be no consumption allowed in
the clubs you know home grow you know
you have to keep it very you know your
neighbors can't even see the money from
children yeah
um so you know but there is still the
stigma around the consumption I think as
long as that stigma is still around it's
going to be very hard to compete with
the illicit Market the consumption
lounges also are there is no smoking
clumps anymore so there's there's again
there's many different aspects of feed
into this from different parts from
other industry we have them in Barcelona
if anyone they're all illegal and I'll
shout it out there every single Club in
Barcelona is illegal it's a gray area
that was made for another for another
issue which was heroin and consumption
in in the 70s and 80s so it's not a
legal model and yes you can smoke inside
there and it's nobody is you know no
repression on them and I think what
really is important is that we gotta
find a legal model not saying now
Legalize It or whatever this is this but
we need to find a set of rules and
regulation that on one hand side works
for the industry and on the other hand
side works for the regulator I haven't
heard harm reduction enough on this
stage is very important in Europe
anything that happens in opening
anything towards the U.N would be very
much the focus of harm reduction and not
creating you know just a flourishing
industry and and in general yes there
are these different models out there and
you know they're not being they're not
not being
chased or whatever you want to call it
but that lack of actual yeah the
regulatory harmonization behind which is
what would then in the future allow us
to kind of work together
across you know across the pond and
towards Asia and there's some some you
know standardization approaches around
that are trying to move into that and
think one of the big things at the
moment deepunk we quickly touched it
before is there are there are bodies in
place that regulate narcotics there's an
narcotics board from the U.N and still
the industry wants to kind of like do
their own way in their own Direction so
well open question there if we where
should we as an industry try to drive
this to actually realistically based on
best case practices from around move
this whole
or navigate through the regulatory
landscape to bring this industry further
I think the UN treaty one is is really
interesting and I think you brought up
the incb particularly which is the
international narcotics control board
and basically their job is to monitor
control activities of what would be in
illicit subs or a control substance
um and you know despite legalization in
Canada you still have reporting
requirements to the incb because they
want to know what's happening and Canada
has done a really bad job and I think
that's where you get into challenges
you've got hundreds of kilos that went
missing at the Ontario cannabis store
and no one could account for where they
went in a fully regulated track and tray
seat to sale High vaults you know dozens
of cameras yet you've had cannabis
magically gone missing
um I think the incb is going to start
looking about and going you've actually
done a pretty poor job on regulating
that so I think having compliance
systems is very important and I think
it's refreshing even on the Swiss case
to hear that Switzerland's actually
Outsourcing some of those abilities
because in Canada what the government
did was Implement an internal track and
Trace system where everyone had to
report into them and we know governments
do a horrible job managing I.T systems
generally and I think that's really been
a poor thing that we've seen in Canada
so again a takeaway that the industry
can say is suggest an external entity
that everyone can agree to a process
through which you'd comply with those
reporting obligations so you aren't on
side with incb right and it's going to
make your life easier because I can tell
you the ctls which is our cannabis
tracking licensing system is is a
ridiculous system to be using and
managing and it clearly doesn't work the
fact that you've got hundreds of kilos
of cannabis disappear magically
something's not working on a personal
note I'm very happy that they kept it
the way they kept it I approached them
in 2018 and asked them if I can bring
this or learn from this system bring it
to Europe they said no this is Canada
only we don't want to deal with outside
countries the underlying basis of it is
the gs1 international standards for
supply chain transparency which is the
global non-for-profit and it gave me the
chance to build a product on that but we
have three minutes 40 seconds and Gallo
stood up when a guy stands up that means
something and no no we're not done yet
we're not opening it sorry uh any any
any closing statements by all of you uh
what do you take from the panel and you
know again navigating through the
regulatory landscape
I think creating a pathway for research
is going to be very important for
Success not just in Germany but in any
other Market as well allowing the
partnership between either government or
commercial entities and non-profit
not-for-profits uh those like
universities who are conducting clinical
trials phase one phase two phase three
and understanding what it is this is
capable of these medical cannabis
products and allowing claims to be
Associated to these products so that we
can get that monograph that Deepak was
referring to for medicinal cannibal
medicinal cannabis products I think
that's really the path forward
for my side I think it'll really be
three things one don't trace shiny
objects wait until the regulations
actually develop I think what we are
seeing is a lot of what we saw in Canada
very early on is what we're seeing in 23
at least in certain European countries
particularly Germany uh and you know
slow down right we need to we need to
understand what the regulations are
actually saying I think we've really put
the card before the horse developing
business plans and figuring out what
products we're going to sell and really
there's a leaked draft that's out there
in The Ether so I think you need to walk
before you run and really understand
what the regulations are going to be the
second I'll say is all politics is local
so you know we touched on this a little
bit but I can't re-stress the importance
of making change locally and going to
your politicians and kind of really
working closely with them and the last
thing I'll say is you know just the
importance of uh you know working
collaboratively as an industry right
being part of European medical cannabis
industry associations or any any of the
various organizations that exist I think
it's it's critical for the industry to
have a single voice both at the national
and the international level or the
European level uh and I think you know
banding together and making sure that
you're building the industry
collaboratively is a responsibility of
the industry
foreign
I would just like to stress if you are a
manufacturer processor anything like
that to regulate yourself beyond what
the current regulations may be because
current regulations are very fluid
they're going to change
um you know so for example
start with child safe packaging even if
maybe that's not required in your
Providence or country or state
and then next I just want to kind of
repeat what Deepak said is collaborate
with the industry and collaborate with
your Regulators it is much better to be
friends with your Regulators than
enemies with them start that
conversation early often collaborate and
form a very strong team with other
people in the Cannabis industry
and yeah we talked a lot about the the
kind of Patchwork regulation I think
that the successful companies in in this
space you know have some agility
um baked into what that what they do
because there is so much regulatory
change and Patchwork
um so you know we try to empower our
clients uh doing that through things
like daily tracking
um not just you know Bill a is going
through this you know here's its current
status but tracking those discussions
those debates that you can narrow in on
you know where there is agreement where
there is some consensus and what may
change in the future
um so that companies can be a little
more agile
um you know and how they operate and
navigating that landscape
and you don't see this but we literally
on the second are at zero zero zero
right now so I would like to thank my
panelists here I think we did a great
job and now is the time for Applause yes
much Applause
let's hear it again