thank you very much
so good afternoon I hope you had a good
lunch before we start let's get some
familiarity who is here from Germany
remember that who is here from Australia
oh Australia who is here from Israel
okay was he from Canada
good stuff so I'll tell you why I'm
telling I'm saying that so uh my name is
about four and a half years ago was the
head of global supply chain and
Logistics of Teva Pharmaceuticals you
know the largest generic company in the
world and I was in charge of all the
Teva logistic operations so I'm coming
from the Pharma world and my vision it
was actually to bring all the knowledge
the experience you know the
understanding of the pharmaceutical
world into the medical cannabis World hi
um so you may understand that if you go
back four and a half years ago a lot of
people a lot of you were busy around
licenses and cultivation and production
but nobody really thought about
logistics but I started to talk with
people about import export cannabis
whatever nobody really understood what
what is going on so since then we did 65
000 kilos of cannabis to and from many
many countries and we will talk about
that a little bit so this is all about
myself
few words about cannabilogue so we are
acting in many countries around the
world where you know we're doing a lot
of logistics and input and Export Canada
US
ugly Colombia Mexico countries in Africa
like Uganda Lesotho South Africa many
countries in Europe UK
and some others you can see here we're
doing about 70 80 percent of all the
Israeli important export and we're doing
a lot in Australia and New Zealand and
so on
and the best thing here in this slide is
our new partnership with the qcs qcs is
a German company specializing in
Pharmaceuticals but also in cannabis
there are 15 offices around Germany and
in two offices we're doing a lot of
cannabis operation which is in Berlin in
Frankfurt so welcome qcs welcome Oliver
thank you very much
so we will talk today about few things
okay we'll try to understand what
happened in the last year and I'm saying
try to understand where person I'm sure
that we will be able to understand
everything
um then we will talk about the
you know the regulatory maze what's
going on around the world then we'll
talk about how to maintain quality and
integrity and in the end we will talk
about do it and don't when you go to
cannabis Logistics
so when we talk about cannabis Logistics
as you can see here we have six major
challenges
the first one is the Regulatory
Compliance
remember I ask you who is from Australia
who is from Australia
so they're sitting back there later
after my presentation please hug them
kiss them because starting this Saturday
they're going to have new regulations
and I'm not sure that everybody
understand the regulations
Germany as well you had a lot of
presentation this morning about what's
going on in Germany not sure that
everybody understand it this is one of
the major challenges to try to
understand what are the right
regulations and surprisingly enough you
will see written regulations but in
practice it works differently so there's
not necessarily a connection between
what is written in the regulation and
what is practically working
the second thing is around quality
assurance
guys medical cannabis is a medicine all
the government in the world will
consider it as a medicine leave aside
the Canadian the Canadian guys that
understand that there is
what we call adult use or uh or uh I
don't know recreational use many names
just in Canada
all the rest of the world it's medical
cannabis
now maybe change in the future and if
it's radical cannabis in the medicine
and if it's a medicine you have to
adhere to all the pharmaceutical
regulations no matter what none of the
governments beside Canada will allow you
to do anything unless it's Medical
sorry there is a slide there expertise
you better know what you do okay in
cannabis you ship it
nicely you export it you're up to the
destination country if you cannot clear
it You Can Kiss It Goodbye
it will go to destruction and you will
pay for the disruptions so there's no
way back if you don't do the right thing
and you don't use the right methods it's
not going to work
security not less important that some
countries that were not even moving one
leaf or one flower unless we have a
armed escort some countries we don't
need that but security is an important
point and we will talk about loss
prevention as well
on-time delivery
very very important we're talking about
sensitive cargo we're talking about
temperature control if you delayed
somewhere for a few days you may lose
the whole thing so you better understand
the procedures and the last thing is
global yes
most of the economics today or was more
or less in country right Canada was a
big Market nobody even thought about the
export now everybody wants to export so
being Global understand what's going on
will open you new markets
for sure some news
your regulations in Australia we were
just talking about that okay very
unclear they're going to change in this
Saturday
whether it goes with bad products or
packed products or what exactly they
will get
ghcp or they will get just EU GMP or
they have some agreements with some
countries not clear
neopetism in Thailand I don't want to
talk about it a lot of people are
talking about Thailand at that point of
life just forget it it's not legal to
input into Thailand and there's no
government maybe they'll change the
rules
a lot of input into Thailand not legal
so if you want to do non-legal stuff
okay but be careful with that
well new e usage facilities we see more
and more eug eugmp facilities in
Portugal in Malta some other places good
stuff industry challenges in Canada we
all know what's going on in Canada
Israel is facing the same thing some
companies are closed some companies
emerge some companies they do
acquisition
be aware that you know what's going on
in the market the organization in
Germany are not going to talk about it
in Israel they are considering to change
the rules and additional European market
where are the markets
besides Germany a little bit UK a little
bit Switzerland we want to see the
markets developing
so let's talk about regulations what I
did here is I just copied you Google
cannabis a legal or legal cannabis or
legal medical cannabis so you will find
a lot of maps a map like this
this is the left side is the
recreational the right side is the
medical
and you will find map like this
and if you keep Googling it even from
more maps if you think that there is any
connection between remote you're you're
wrong and the reason and the main point
I'm trying to take here is make sure
because the regulations are Ever
Changing what you know today will not be
there tomorrow and there are many
examples for that so when you talk about
regulations make sure that you
understand the right picture the current
Rock picture and not a lot of stories
because the maps are not telling the
truth there's a lot of changes send
things when it comes to Europe
can someone explain me what is legal and
what is not legal and what is the
recreation in Europe medical which
countries
Europe looks like this
is Europe looks like this
again
regulations are changing you have to
make sure that you fully understand
where it's legal and where it's not
legal okay I'll talk later on two words
about CBD I'm talking here about medical
cannabis that contain THC
be careful with that
another thing that we need to understand
that according to the UN
you know the U.N from a resolution from
forced every country each country that
want to regulate cannabis to have a
specific unit in their government to
deal with cannabis so this is just an
example of all those authorized well
Regulators if I can call it this way
these are the guys that you will get
all the licenses that you need to grow
to store to manufacture to whatever and
also the Import and Export permits
each one of those guys as his own
procedures his own documents his own
application and each one of them will
take a different time some of these guys
will issue you an input permit or an
export permit in two days some of them
it will take six weeks
okay so you better understand which one
of the guys of those
Regulatory Agencies you are dealing with
what are the procedure how you can speed
it up and each country is different
remember medical cannabis is a
pharmaceutical product but it's not the
same every country has its own
regulations
all around the world
another thing that we have to talk about
is the type of products we in Canada we
are moving all those type of products it
can be genetics it can be seeds it can
be tissue cultures it can be cuttings or
clones
which is a completely different thing
I don't know if you know but when you
ship a clone
unrooted clone it has a life expectancy
of three four days after three four days
if it doesn't get into the water it's
dying so we have a very very strict
protocol how to ship Lawns or cuttings
or tissue cultures otherwise you cannot
do it so each one of those products will
have a specific solution or specific
Logistics solution but also in terms of
Licensing in terms of input regulations
and Export regulations some countries
have to involve the Ministry of
Agriculture not just the Ministry of
Health
a lot of issues to understand
dried flowers apis or I call it apis
because if from the farmer I mean
extracts okay packed finished goods
cannabis products herbal medicines CBD
products we'll talk about it in a minute
it's smokable product each one of these
guys will have this types will have a
different Logistics solution and a
different regulations that you need to
adhere to and again if you are in the
business you have to understand it and
you have to prepare for it and not just
shipping it out cannabis is not T-shirts
from Turkey it's not okay I have two
pallets on my ramp just ship it it
doesn't work this way
GDP there and GDP is the good
distribution practices something that
goes together with quality
so first of all Pharma standards this is
it if you are dealing with medical
cannabis you are pharmaceutical product
you like it you don't like it this is it
remember
it's an Agricultural Product it's not
chemical
derived Pharmaceuticals as we are used
to which create a lot of issues this is
why you will need steel things this is
why you will need laboratory tests you
will need a lot of things just in order
to ship it out
product Integrity along the
distributions chain eliminate
temperature excursions and we'll talk
about that in a minute
at the end of the day and the end of the
logistic chain there is a QP QP is a
qualified person that have to release
the product into the market these guys
I don't know if you know but the QP in
Europe is the most get the most uh High
salary in the industry because these
guys have
criminal responsibility when they clear
a product to the market they have
criminal criminal responsibility they
will never clear it until they will see
the whole tests and the Data Logger and
everything is correct otherwise they
will not clear it to the market very
very important
a lot of regulations are
counter-specific
full temperature control processes
specially qualify their packages data
loggers exactly is the farmer if you
ship it without it you cannot clear it
if you don't have a Data Logger if you
don't have the temperature records
nobody in Europe will clear it it will
approve the release to the market this
is it it's a medical product
sorry and the last week was make sure
that you understand your customer your
customer acceptance or rejection
um
uh criteria sometimes it's not on the
country level but it's your customer
that will tell you I need this in this
test so I needed this laboratory reports
or whatever the case is because if they
have an acceptance procedure and you
don't follow it they will not approve
the product you know when when it
arrives to their facility then it's too
late so make sure that you know your
customer criteria to reject or to accept
your products so it's not just the
country level it's also your customer
this is just a schematic chart how we
ship cannabis we collect it with the
temperature controlled truck we bring it
to the airport to temperature control
chamber we take it to the aircraft in
the temperature control environment
I mean take off
then land on the other side same exact
thing keep it in the chamber in the
temperature control chamber use a
temperature control truck to deliver it
and so on and so forth if you are not
maintaining the logistics chain as it
shows here
probably you will have a temperature
Excursion and the product cannot be
released
simple as that
so there are many issues around that
like stability data like all kinds of
Arrangements but in the end of the day
if your process your logistic process is
not qualified and it's not and all by
the way all the logistic partners that
has to be qualified the trucking company
the custom broker the airline or
whatever you're using then this will not
happen and if it not happened a product
will not be released to the market
[Music]
security and loss prevention I already
spoke about that to make sure that you
understand that you have to protect the
products you can protect it in many many
ways the packaging and tampering kinds
of Packaging
very very important secure
Transportation by the way some countries
will give specific license to the
trucking company otherwise they cannot
carry cannabis and it has to be sealed
in just to have GPS and you have to have
a lot of issues when you carry cannabis
in even in a van or in a truck
avoidance I spoke about that online
trackers there are many many types of we
call it data loggers right
I'm talking about temperature trackers
there are many types of them my
recommendation is to put
one Data Logger for each pilot or for
each package that they ship
two of them has to be online the online
data loggers will give you two
advantages that you don't have on the
regular one
first it will give you the location you
will know where it is because it's a GPS
system so you know where it is you know
if there is a delay or whatever and the
second thing which most important is you
know if there is a temperature Excursion
some of the logos will give you an alert
before the Excursion right if it's 15 to
25 and all the Cannabis products are
being shipped between 15 to 25 Celsius
degrees so I don't need the alert when
it's 26. I need to alert when it's 24
right so in order to avoid it you can
get alerts from this online data loggers
this is my recommendation and
they are available in the market the
other data loggers a lot of people will
call it USB data loggers I call them
postmodern data logos you know why
postmodo because you read it in the end
as my son says what was was nothing you
can do about it right you see the
temperature experience but you cannot do
anything with that it's already done but
if you use an online Data Logger you can
eliminate the Excursion even before it
happens very important and the last
thing is something that we provide as
well it's a very unique insurance
coverage for the whole Transportation
door-to-door process you know that the
receiving or getting insurance for
cannabis it's a little bit problematic
but we have a very unique insurance
policy that covers all risks for that
let's talk a little bit about the
process so you know that the the
Cannabis export starts from the import
side so if you have to issue an import
license on the destination country and
then based on that you have to issue an
export permit on the other side this is
the way it works this is the narcotics
in general is working
each side will take different time and
will require different information but
without the export permit and the import
payment
there's no way you can ship by the way
none of the airlines will carry cannabis
shipments unless you have licenses it's
a prerequisite the airlines will check
it by the way not all the airlines are
carrying kind of it's just few of them
but if they do they will ask for your
licenses
this you cannot avoid this process and
it takes time sometimes it's sweat not
just uh you know the time but it is a
very important process and uh
one thing you have to remember to really
understand is that the information on
the licenses has to be identical if the
input license is not exactly as the
Apple sorry if the export license is not
exactly as the impulse license it's not
going to work so before in our company
we have a procedure that even before we
pick up a leaf or a flower or whatever
we take the documents we send them to
the other side like in Germany or in any
other country they check it they approve
it and just then we will collect the
freight or the cargo or the shipment and
we ship it out don't ship unless you
make sure that you can clear it on the
other side because it's not going to
work you lost it
so a little bit about
the physical Logistics so first of all
we spoke about the documents we spoke
about the packaging
you have to understand that you in in
campus shipments few agencies will be
involved in the U.S it will be the DEA
Customs minister of Health minister of
Agriculture FDA a lot of agencies and
you have to adhere to that
almost every cannabis shipment almost
every kind of a shipment will go through
physical check either in the
exploitation side or in the
implementation side which means it will
take time and it may even cost more
money because of storage and everything
so be ready for that almost every
shipment will be physically examined in
some countries like Australia it will be
current time you will need to quarantine
the shipment for few days before you can
clear it into the market so all those
aspects has to be considered before you
ship out of course GDP regulations and
there's something that you have to
understand you can there is a street
requirement that you control all your
supplies so it's not good enough that
you ship it out and you export it you
have to control the hallway until it
will arrive to the other side this is
the way your Regulators want to see how
you control your logistic chain
um
and this is a requirement it's not
something it's not a nice to have it's a
must
and we were talking about online
traceability
few words about CBD
so first of all CBD products
again we need to talk about
definitions okay so we recognize six
I would say types of CBD products the
first one is a medical product you know
there are two products in the world
that's it the epidural acts and the side
effects that's it that's the only
finished product that were approached by
FDA and they can be considered as
medicines
then we have the food and drinks you
know all the Edibles that we're talking
about
then we have the food additives vitamins
novel food
from the UK here
novel food come on okay anyway so each
country even within Europe well UK is
not Europe anymore right but anyway
um each country is is taking a different
definition for CBD food supplements
so what are we going to do with that
some will be vitamins some will be
edited or whatever
just to show you remember the map from
before
how we can manage that
then we have very Veterinary products
very good product if you have a dog
that's barking too much
CBD products put into sleep perfectly
really there are many products like that
then cosmetics
Cosmetics right creams things like that
there's a lot of products in the market
not each country will accept and the
last thing is smokable products you know
there are cigarettes CBD cigarettes as
well which is kind of funny right people
want to get high but they're still
smoking CBD but the most important here
is the top when I said
be careful with claims with cdb CBD
products especially if you're in the US
in the US if you're claiming that you
are
your product is I don't know anti-aging
or curing something or whatever
every day will run after you you cannot
claim any scientific
benefit or or I don't know therapeutic
benefit from your cdb products and the
reason is there's no proof
so be careful with that governments
doesn't like that and at the bottom you
can see again Europe right different
countries different levels of THC
different regulatory requirements
kind of a mess
yet again that's what I'm saying even in
CBD which is not not politics there's
still things that you need to know and
again this is a little bit another map
remember the map is not important
because tomorrow it will be different
that's the message it will be different
so that's almost my last slide about do
and don't
the first thing is about licenses import
extra regulation and basic licenses
if you have customers sellers or buyers
you have to make sure that they
understand the procedures we found
ourselves sometimes teaching
again sorry for the example in Canada
teaching Canadian companies which are
great Growers of cannabis how to be
exporters in Canada
because they never had the experience
they have a very big local market never
exported so things like that
seller certification okay in some
countries EU GMP is a requirement
c-o-mcs gacp iqc all kinds of letters
that I'm not sure that everybody
understand them but it's a requirement
so the seller certification is according
to the buyer regulations and if it
doesn't have the EU GMP you cannot
import it and by the way a lot of people
you will meet
will tell you yeah yeah we have a ugmp
we're in the process we have an audit in
two weeks
if it doesn't show on the eurodora
website
it's not a huge MP okay so stories we
know but facts this is what should be
considered
important I spoke about it quality again
Laboratory test
coves a lot of requirements around it
everything has to be risk based you have
to do a risk analysis and risk
mitigation for each of your lanes so if
you are importing from ugly or from
Canada or your ship to Australia every
lane has to be analyzed you have to
analyze the risk and make sure that you
mitigate it okay no stories about that
temperature Excursion or an unmanaged
process can actually
bring into a situation that your project
will be rejected
security along the whole journey
dedicating the insurance coverage
packages laborers labels temperature
loggers everything has to be precise the
requirements for labels in Israel are
not the same as the requirements of
labors in Germany but if the labors on
the bag or on the box are not according
to the country specific
it's not going to work this is why if
you come to us we will ask to see
pictures of the labels even before we
pick it up so if the labels are not
correct forget it and one more thing
labels has to be printed Canadians don't
write it down in your handwriting
printed
okay
impossible practical procedure
I said before it's not always the formal
version okay I can tell you from our
experience
that we had the shipment from Canada
and the Canadian guys didn't pick the
bags correctly we delivered the shipment
to the airline Saturday evening it was
shipping to Israel Saturday evening we
deliver it to the airline
and there was a lot of smell
and then I said we're not going to carry
it
we're afraid that the passengers and the
pilots will get high
okay really real story so we had to take
it back to by the way I don't know if
you know there is anti-smel bags
so that's not around the shipment and
then we send it by a real story
sometimes you don't even think about it
so please when you're putting stuff in
bags make sure that you heat seal it and
not staple it
okay heat shield by the way twice this
is our procedure and if you're doing
Ziploc heat seal the bottom
and then the Ziploc and on the other way
around so make sure that you're doing
the right thing in order to
make sure that it arrives safely
plan your flights carefully
whoever shipped to Israel we have a very
weird procedure in Israel you can kill
clear cannabis products
just on Tuesdays between 10 to 12.
that's it
that's the law
now if you come on Tuesday evening you
have to wait a week
don't ask me why that's the procedure so
what we do is in advance we pick it up
on Fridays we fly it in on Saturday on
Sunday make sure that we have it on
Monday and then we clear it so make sure
that you understand another Point don't
ever never ever ever
land on U.S soil
okay never ever sometimes you don't know
that the airline
even very
sophisticated known Airline like the
German airlines without names
we land in the US we don't even that you
know that
he said goodbye it will be confiscated
okay so make sure that you are not
lending even not by mistake on U.S soil
that's it that's the the way it works so
plan your flights carefully not just in
order for timing but also in the route
and as I said before
don't ever ship unless you make sure
that you can clear it on the other side
don't ship if you cannot clear it on the
other side there's no way back
so now I'm open to questions
thank you very much
[Applause]