hello
um so hi everybody uh my name is Stephen
Murphy and um we have
30 minutes to solve Global cannabis and
regulations which is should be doable
on a Friday Friday evening
um
look the the I think it's very nice to
be able to talk about Beyond The War of
drugs and to kind of you know one
recognize the the impact that has been
made in the last seven years especially
coming out of of North America which is
now transferring over to Europe but you
know we're in a
crazy young industry which we are kind
of to use an analogy we're flying a
plane with both hands tied behind our
backs
um look there is there is a recent you
know there's a recent major U.N report
that came out during the week which you
know called for an end of the end of the
war on drugs and it sounds great and it
sounds super super positive but
really when you translate the the the
the social mission of ending the War on
Drugs into the reality of conducting
business and and actually working to
bring a business face to drugs and make
it more uh agreeable and certainly
certainly more professional like how
would we talk to uh conscious conscious
investment
how do you do that how do you how do you
put a how how do you get investors
excited about ending the war on drugs
and that part of the story for
businesses
uh maybe maybe Aaron if you want to if
you want to kick it off
yeah thank you I you know I think we
really it's it's all about lining
aligning self-interest with with the
cause of of ending prohibition and
um you know with what we're seeing in in
across the country is this emerging
emergent legal cannabis industry that
um you know investors are seeing just
seeing like as an opportunity like any
other opportunity and so you know what
we're you know the kind of the Gospel we
preach is that if you're invested in
this industry then you are an advocate
and you must invest in the federal
policy or state federal now
International policy reforms necessary
for the industry to prosper
yeah I mean I I would add to that that
there's not always an alignment between
the the self-interest of a particular
business and good policy so if you know
I am uh Joe's Mega Corp
um I want Joe's Mega Corp to have
Monopoly on cannabis which is terrible
policy so there's what I notice is that
there's friction
um with you know especially like the the
larger companies larger investors with
wanting to have market dominance
um versus what I think I would argue
many would argue uh is better policy
which is an ecosystem of lots of smaller
businesses that are doing things
conscientiously are paying attention to
like environmental considerations uh
Equity considerations things of that
nature so I I think the the initial
legalization effort and whatever country
we're talking about
um yeah you can get uh investors behind
that concept if if I want to be in the
Cannabis space I it has to be legal in
order for me to invest
um if I have you know a bank that's
going to finance that that's going to be
a variable issue in different places
um if I have to answer to shareholders
or a board of directors you know those
fundamental issues of legality are
threshold issues but once you get past
that threshold issue of legalization
then you know it becomes more
complicated and what that legalization
looks like itself also can become very
complicated and that's where you end up
with like a lot of like limited markets
we see this a lot in the states
particularly on the East Coast where
there is you know a set number of
licenses and what you have there
typically are like the publicly traded
companies that are publicly traded in
Canada because they're not allowed to be
publicly traded in the U.S that dominate
these markets and then the way that that
translates to the consumer is not very
many options and not very many
especially good options so they go to
their local cannabis store and they have
the options of like five different
things that are in 20 different jars and
it's all pretty gross so it's it's it's
not exactly lined up very easily I don't
think
foreign
for that one
wow you guys really nailed it I I think
that what's lost here in
um making something that is a magical
mystical
unexplained ethereal plant medicine into
a consumer package good for capitalism
there's a natural disconnect and I think
that the the people that I've seen do
the most well business-wise success wise
in California have been the ones that
bake in a triple bottom line where they
know that love is lucrative
turnover in companies lack of loyalty
boof but you know bad bad quality
products there's proof of concept
there's data that shows that that does
not scale markets that does not welcome
new users that does not bring Innovation
and polish and sophistication to the
space and so we we have proof that shows
that if you don't invest in your people
and the industry people like ncia Aaron
you know works with the national
cannabis industry Association you know
ask yourselves are you part of a Trade
Organization are you talking to each
other what happened in California we
fought like cats and dogs in front of
the state capital in front of the the
federal capital and they looked at us of
course they're going to go with big
Pharma and big Ag and big tobacco
because we weren't on the same page
before we showed up we didn't have
common language about what
sustainability meant for us and the
people that are doing the best in the
Bay Area in LA in California are people
who are giving back when we use the word
Equity we have a very uh in the United
States because of our history with
slavery and institutionalized racism and
racist uh policy we have what's called
an equity program so you might hear us
talking about it a little bit what we
did was we put people of color and
people from communities that were most
highly policed by the war on drugs and
by police first in line to get licensing
I'm in New Jersey they have really
unique
um you know structures where they're
actually getting business training
they're getting uh good loans good rates
on loans they're getting deals on you
know rent things that are are really
barriers to entry to acknowledge that
they have you know 400 years of being
treated like sub-human beings and they
deserve a step up because many of their
communities have been destroyed by the
War on Drugs not only from policing but
from the fact that most you know black
fathers in urban centers are in prison
those are all black children that are
now being raised in the hood without any
support so the War on Drugs has
incredible implications that do mess
with the economy that do destabilize
spaces and make cities unsafe so these
are the things that we try to talk about
to these msos or to you know Joe
corporation that don't know why it's
important to care about it they if you
don't actively have in your Marketing in
your budget in your community and in
your Staffing an acknowledgment of the
the underlying racism and the underlying
sexism and greed capitalism that has
pushed us to where we are now you
actually won't do well
um it hasn't really worked to be
unabashedly greedy in the space we don't
like it as consumers as B2B and in
general the world is moving towards more
conscious capitalism so we got to be on
the right side of that
like I I totally buy into you know
social equity and Equity programs and
that being critical parts of the theory
well well the the reality is very
different the reality and implementation
of us is exceptionally different let's
mess it up by the way we didn't do a
good job at this it's an idea well we're
talking about it but but it's also
for a company who is who's trying to you
know operate within the business and
then the challenges of of running a
business day to day with the additional
tasks of you know supporting a
membership and that membership you know
uh like just a constant like you know
pushing a hill up or pushing a rock up
the hill like how do you how you've
you've seen you've been scarred by what
is you know what is a David versus
Goliath task of of not only pushing you
know pushing cannabis forward in in in
the US but doing so with so many vested
parties who want to see cannabis
ultimately fail like how do you convince
companies to really Embrace that like
what's what what what's your message for
them well I mean I think in the U.S
we've evolved over time where there
isn't there isn't uh the kind of the
boogeyman of big Pharma and tobacco
really actively lobbying against
cannabis not to say that they don't have
interests that are that are you know in
opposition to ours but it's not a
priority the problem that we have is
that the industry itself especially you
know the small operators are not
investing in the policy reforms that
that are needed and so you know what's
what's really important isn't to Joe's
point is that you know we can have we we
can make this look really bad by having
one or two of the largest companies push
through National reforms that that are
favorable to them and no one else uh but
what you know what the message that we
have out there is that there is an
alternative to that which is making sure
that the small businesses have a voice
making sure that we're we're you know
creating a policy landscape that you
know that raises all you know the the
that raises All Ships uh and ensures
that you know we have we have an open
and inclusive Market
um and that's you know that's what we do
as an association is represent the small
businesses
um but you know I don't I think that you
know you're going to see yes we're going
to see big big Pharma and alcohol and
tobacco they're already playing in this
space
um but there's room for you know for
craft cannabis as well well I I think
it's not as much oppositional I think
that they seek to co-opt it
um I I think that you know there
certainly is investments from Big Pharma
and big tobacco into cannabis just not
in a way that is conducive to having a
healthy cannabis industry and in a way
that's beneficial to Consumers it is uh
with the sole focus of driving uh
revenues to shareholders and and you
know not ideologically aligned with you
know the this this plant that is
beneficial and helps people
therapeutically and you know should not
be criminalized and I think to your
earlier question
um the War on Drugs is an awful thing I
spent a lot of my career in the trenches
combating the War on Drugs Case by case
and I've seen how bad it is on families
and communities firsthand the
legalization of cannabis does not fix
that
um and you know what what Luna was
describing was that we had decided you
know starting in California but exported
to other states in the U.S to try to
rectify the harms of the War on Drugs by
providing preferential treatment to
applicants in local Municipal permitting
and the the reality which you would
think is obvious but is lost upon many
cities and counties and states is that
giving someone beneficial treatment in a
permitting process does not correct the
the generational harms to Society of the
War on Drugs but okay so
like you're you running you know running
running a compliant business great you
want to have a very strong social Equity
Mission like you know I don't think
anybody is is in cannabis you know well
you know for for for the wrong reasons
it's really it's it's you I just imagine
there's a lot of people in there for the
wrong reasons no
like when you realize you actually have
to work hard like it scares a lot of
people but like once you get over that
shock of okay it's this isn't going to
be easy you know the the the the the the
the the true the the truth green people
come out and it's you know it's it's a
case of you want to you're in the
industry because you think this is
something that can change the world and
change the world in a very you know
doesn't have the solutions to absolutely
everything but but but no one puts money
behind it to Aaron's point if you're
being regulated to death why would you
spend ten thousand dollars a year to
have them Lobby for you it's the
self-fulfilling prophecy no one has the
money to lobby and we don't have money
because we have bad policy sure but but
you've got so you've you've got federal
policy which is is is is one thing but
maybe is there any policy that you have
seen that has has enhanced or certainly
been more favorable to find somewhat of
the balance because you have to like I
think a lot of people sitting here last
year were licking their lips on the
thought of of adult use cannabis in
Germany I need to see it being more
watered down than than ever and that's
going to happen you know that's going to
happen time and again this is uh you
know this is as everybody says this is a
marathon not a Sprint but there are
policies that are being designed in
certain states that are
are finding are trying to find that
balance
no one has done it right I I think that
I can look at at globally every
jurisdiction that has sought out
legalization has done a lot of things
wrong I think that they're I would
invert that and say that there are are
bright spots in different areas where we
should replicate certain elements of
policy and deploy those and kind of
Frankenstein it in other areas so for
example Amsterdam Amsterdam is is the
thought leader on this issue
um going back to the 1970s and there's a
lot wrong with how the the Netherlands
and and I say Amsterdam because you know
in large part more broadly in the
Netherlands cannabis isn't as well
tolerated as it is in Amsterdam
especially more recently with you know
the government there but point being the
the social consumption aspect of coffee
shops and being able to go to a business
and consume cannabis and hang out is
something that's special and unique and
is not replicated in most other places
if you look in the U.S by and large the
model is an off sale model like what you
would get going to like a liquor store
you go and buy your product you take it
home and consume it and that is not
adequate for for society to destigmatize
this product however what they do poorly
in the Netherlands is that the supply
chain is not legalized or regulated and
so then you have this sort of like
illicit supply chain that feeds into a
quasi-legal model and it can never
really become mature and it's just
stymied as it has been for the last 50
years or so in California one of the
things that we did there that I I don't
know whether or not it can be successful
is we do not limit the supply side the
production side so there's no limitation
by the state of California for how many
cultivation licenses there can be or not
be ideologically I thought out of the
gate that's a good thing let's let's
allow business to do what business does
the better businesses will out-compete
the worst businesses and you know
through this process like what we see
with other Industries we will see you
know the good businesses rise to the top
and they will get the market dominance
but what has happened is that we've had
a massive oversupply problem and and
because we have created a system there
where we allow for some municipalities
to legalize and others to prohibit in
California still several years after
legalization more than 65 percent of the
State of California is does not allow
for legal cannabis for commercial
cannabis and so then what you have is
this massive oversupply that gets
funneled into to a uh to the retailer
where there's there's just not enough
retail availability for a consumers so
consumers go to the illicit Market they
go back to their dealer and amongst
other things that local dealer the
person that they've known that living
room they've gone to whatever they don't
pay huge taxes
they don't have all those added expenses
which makes the legal cannabis
businesses ironically less competitive
than the Legacy folks that never
bothered with legalization to begin with
so it's it's complicated but what I
would say is that you can look at some
things about how California has done it
you can look at some things about how
Canada has done it one of the things
that Canada has done well is federal
legalization for all of the problems
with Canada of which there are many and
I would say that the industry there is
largely been a failure at least there's
Federal legalization and you can import
export in and out of Canada and you can
have access to Banking and and that is
something that is special so if we look
at sort of this like Frankenstein
approach we could imagine a model where
there are you know there's a federal
level of legalization uh there is the
ability for the consumer to go to a
place and consume and there are some
guard rails in the supply chain to
ensure both that there is not fully an
oversupply which I think that there's
some larger debate there that we don't
have time for now while ensuring that
the point of access for the consumers
Isn't So unduly restricted that people
are basically compelled to go to the
illicit Market in order to have access
to Canvas OR like in uh in Australia
where I've heard that if you get caught
driving they can take your light with
cannabis in your system they can take
your license and it puts the license of
the prescribing doctor at risk so then
there's also the implementation that the
devil's in the details a lot of times
something I want people to realize too
as we're talking about this the word
legalization doesn't mean anything don't
use it you're either talking about
decriminalization
or tax control and regulate
because when in California they thought
they were legalizing they or then they
voted yes they thought they were
decriminalizing it for for possession
use transport cultivation what we were
actually voting for was the consumer
package good model that was sold through
license dispensaries through the state
so there's two things happening here
you've got Portugal you know Uruguay is
really interesting example the question
is is are we talking about is it good
for business or is it good for the plant
and medicine and medical sovereignty and
human rights sometimes they're not odds
right yeah yeah but I suppose this is
this has to be kind of a universal
conversation this is you know where
we're closer getting close to 80
countries around the world with some
sort of legal framework for access to
cannabis predominantly medical and
that's not including the US like you
know there's there's
every day there's some a fresh wave of
optimism for federal legalization only
to be jammed back in the can
that's that's there there needs to be a
major Domino to fall uh it's you know
it's not going to be the EU because
they you know they're not prepared to
kind of rule on something so significant
it's highly unlikely to be the US so
it's essentially going to be a mishmash
of federal of federal policies or you
know International policies for each
jurisdiction do you see any sort of
Juicy kind of or suspect any change
within the federal system uh for for the
next five years because that's you know
that's the global Domino yeah in the US
I mean all of the action has been at the
state level and I you know I'd argue
there's been some some positive to that
is that it probably has is kept uh has
kept the big big tobacco a big Pharma at
Bay
um but you know I think that in terms of
of seeing you know full regulation and
control like alcohol at the federal
level in the United States that's still
more than five years out that's five or
ten years out there's a lot of factors
on where you know who's elected and a
lot of you know factors that are in play
to you know make that prediction but I
do think what we will see in the near
term will be uh what is called in our
U.S law rescheduling of cannabis kind of
a medicalization uh that could provide
it'll it'll provide some relief for the
industry on on some levels but it comes
with a whole other host of regulations
it would not affect international trade
in any way you know most of our industry
will still be out of compliance with
federal law for quite some time but
that's probably that's probably going to
be the next you know Big Move uh short
of of other you know in terms of larger
uh policy reform nationally in the U.S
I'm seeing people really looking
re-looking at their license caps I think
that we've seen that limited licensing
is a real problem
um to the point we just heard I think
that this is one of the most important
things is you know letting business do
what it does part of that is allowing
you know not bottlenecking so I think
that having I mean the biggest thing is
is we were the consultants for the city
in the state when we were trying to push
these things through in Oakland they
didn't know their own laws they did we
had to tell them how business worked we
were just talking in the Green Room
about a lot of these policy makers and
legislators they don't have experience
in business they don't understand what
an implementation of a business plan
um what you know shareholders like the
pressures they don't know what you know
the devil ends up being in the details
so being at the table knowing who these
people are is what I would recommend I
was on a first name basis with all of my
my city council members my district
um Representatives they knew me they
knew my crew they knew our argument we
showed up we did clean cleanups in the
community to show that cannabis was
giving back we donated in Berkeley we
were giving money to the libraries and
the schools way before we legalized this
was pre-tax control regulate and when
the cops would have an issue where we
would have someone break in the school
teachers and the Librarians would show
up at these city council and saying
actually these people are contributing
and they would show up for us and fight
for us so I think that there's a little
bit of of you know making sure that you
know who these people are that they know
you in Brazil you will go to a judge and
ask their permission to grow cannabis
imagine the societal change when the
judge class which skews typically more
wealthy more educated more Elite are
hearing hundreds of testimonials a day
about why someone needs their medicine
this is the thing that's going to change
hearts and Minds it's not going to be in
the data it's not going to be in the
money you can't quantify magic and you
can't can't quantify a community
building and what this plant does and I
think that that's the most important
thing is we're not loud enough as
consumers as business people we are not
working hard enough on the policy side
because we're so big busy with our
packaging our branding our social media
content our personal laundry and
relationships if we have a life so I
think we need to put a lot more energy
what I noticed in California is when we
were at the City Council meetings it was
just business owners there weren't many
consumers there weren't many other
people arguing and as a policy maker if
you see business people arguing for
themselves you just imagine that they're
greedy and they just want what they want
in their own business interests they
didn't realize we want the movement we
want medical safe access and
recreational access so who are you
talking to do they know you are you at
the table to tell them how you want it
done because trying to undo and fix bad
policy is way harder more stressful more
expensive than baking it into the DNA
from day one and there's a saying either
you're at the table or you're on the
venue facts
um and I would say so I was I was doing
parallel things to all the things that
you just described and you know sitting
here all these years later today it
didn't make a damn bit of difference the
businesses that were there that were or
Champions that time they're gone they
don't exist and the reason why they're
gone they don't exist and why it didn't
matter is uh because there's over
taxation amongst other things and this
is something that I think if we have a
takeaway to impart on you know the
people here and on policy makers in
Germany and other places it's to not
look at cannabis as being a cash cow
cannabis is it's it's not going to solve
a budget it's it can't be over taxed
it's don't look at cannabis as providing
any more Revenue than any other business
in any other industry in any other place
it it won't do that it's not going to
fix these larger problems it's not going
to fix the War on Drugs it's not going
to it's not gonna fix like larger
epistemic things that have larger
epistemic problems so what it is is it's
an opportunity to end in abysmal and
immoral policy of what we call the War
on Drugs to incarcerate people for a
beneficial plant that helps them and
doesn't hurt anyone that's never killed
anyone ever in the history of humanity
has never caused a single death
that's all we're looking to do we're
we're looking to just fix that wrong and
allow businesses to succeed and to allow
people to use it and to use it fairly
and reasonably freely and the the model
that I think if we're looking at it one
of the things that we haven't talked a
lot about is the beverage model I what I
think is going to work the best for
cannabis is essentially what we see
working for wine it's there's a lot of
parallels there and in your home country
when you think about how is wine
regulated where can I access it how much
does it cost what's required in order to
get into the business extrapolate that
into cannabis there's a way to do that
and I think that you know just in how
we're having this conversation and we've
been in the trenches since the beginning
we have a lot of Battle Scars here we
have been through it all and it can be
absolutely awful and we can tell you a
lot more of what not to do than what to
do don't do what we did in California
don't do what we do in America don't do
what has been done in Canada the first
model for legalization in Germany was
there was it was going to lead to
Monopoly and it's not a bad thing that
that didn't pass so I think that there
is just an opportunity here for
re-examination of a fundamental policy
issue and to think about what can we do
in order to make uh businesses
successful to give some benefit to
communities and allow for safe access
those are really the only things that
are going to be accomplished well if we
accomplish those alone that's still
something pretty significant and then
and then it comes down to judging well
what is what is winning the war on drugs
and what does that look like because I
think if people want everything it's not
achievable but uh I think that wraps it
up if I yeah yeah the flashing red
lights
thank you thank you so much for your
insights thank you thank you thank you
everyone for coming Stefan Murphy Aaron
Smith lunar store and Joe Rogue away