good morning everybody I am Bruce Barca
and I am a senior editor at Leafly
Leafly is a company in the cannabis
industry and I get up every morning
every day and take the bus I take the
ferry and then I ride a bicycle into the
office at Leafly I go there I sit at my
desk I sign articles I edit articles I
talk with colleagues we make plans we do
all these things and every two weeks
Leafly sends me a check
what Leafly and I have is not a mutually
agreeable arrangement it is called
employment I go to Leafly because it is
my job that's one job my colleague David
downs back there he also goes to Leafly
he often gets there earlier than I do in
the morning that's two of us we just
heard from Alex Rebecca
Jared Ruben and Tara they two are more
or less in the cannabis industry now
we're up to seven and Gaea I'm counting
you that's a you could make it without
the legal cannabis industry but we're
gonna count you in there um here's the
thing I did a rough count of the room
here we've got about a hundred people
more or less we're probably all in the
cannabis industry or want to be in the
cannabis industry here's the thing the
federal government does not believe we
exist they don't count our jobs I'm here
to tell you we do exist and Leafly we
make sure that those jobs are counted
our annual cannabis jobs count we do
this every year and it started about
four years ago when we asked a freelance
journalist he had a great business
background to go out there and nail down
the number we said look there's a lot of
talk about how many jobs are supported
by legal cannabis there's there are
varying numbers very vague numbers go
out there and just just bring us back
the number right so it goes out does a
lot of research talks to people talk to
labor economist talks to the
Bureau of Labor Statistics comes back
after four weeks and says there's no
number nobody has a number and the
reason nobody has a number we said wait
wait there's got to be a number like we
exist you exist and he said no no
there's no number because there's no
recognition by the federal government
obviously federal prohibition is is in
in force right now and most state
economists take their cue in terms of
how they tally jobs from the Federal
Bureau of Labor Statistics well the
Bureau of Labor Statistics won't touch
cannabis obviously but there's something
more than that
it's that marijuana jobs actually don't
exist in the classification system for
tallying jobs and there's something
called the NAICS system I've got it up
here North American industry
classification system so every job has a
number you'll see here if you type in
marijuana or cannabis in the last couple
of years you got no results zero so
people complained about this and the
folks who keep track of the NAICS said
okay okay we hear you we see you
actually exist you have jobs we're gonna
add you to the system and everybody
thought oh okay great you know we're
finally there we're finally in the
system well there's a problem with that
and here here's the problem
marijuana retail is now lumped in with
27 other jobs as you can see here let me
show you here we are
marijuana retail marijuana stores
recreational or retail we're in there
with beer making supply stores binocular
stores calendar shops candle shops
closet organizer stores and hot tub
supply stores we all have the same
number us and aqua quip we're all
they're in there together so no matter
how many jobs we add there's no real way
to tell that we're adding them or if the
binocular stores
adding them or if there's some new
American Renaissance in hot tubs farmers
are in the same position there is
actually a farmer a cannabis grower
number but they're in there with mint
farmers with hop growers this sort of
thing so we decided to take a look at
the data that existed because every
state reports something on legal
cannabis whether it's a patient count or
its number of licensed retailers or
maybe it's weekly sales monthly sales
the state of Florida actually reports
ounces of cannabis leaf sold per week
that's that's what they they don't
report retail sales they report ounces
sold per week weird stuff as out is out
there the state of Arizona reports by I
think number of pounds sold per month
there's weird data out there but we used
a number of existing reports and work
with some economists who work with
cannabis and and labor data and we came
up kind of with a with a system that
allows us to take that existing data and
turn it into estimates of full-time
equivalent jobs per state and we do this
every year we start in December we run
through December in January it takes
about two months to put it all together
and this year's number is two hundred
forty three thousand seven hundred
full-time American jobs that's nearly a
quarter of a million Americans whose
jobs depend on legal cannabis that's a
very politically powerful number here's
how it here's how those numbers have
grown over the years twenty seventeen we
counted one hundred twenty two thousand
eight hundred jobs one forty nine in
2018 two hundred eleven thousand in 2019
and two hundred forty three thousand
seven hundred in early 2020 and if
you'll notice we're basically adding
jobs at a twenty thousand a year 40,000
a year 60,000 a year clip
and this really is you you've got to
know that this is unique in America no
other industry is doing this right now
like the cannabis industry is doing it
sorry guys can you click forward here
I'm night there we go and we're doing it
you know we've heard this morning about
the tough times in the cannabis industry
and it's it's it's no secret a lot of
major companies have undergone layoffs
including my own we went through the Bay
P lung crisis over the last six months
vape sales are down we're going through
a lot of turmoil right now but in that
turmoil and within you know companies
laying off hundreds of workers we saw
aurora up in Canada just laid off 500
workers this week within that
environment quietly the engine of
cannabis is growing jobs over the last
year growing jobs at a 33,000 jobs per
year clip which is again a remarkable
story for us to tell here's how those
jobs compared to other jobs I don't want
to point out the top three job jobs
there that I listed I listed for a
reason I listed them because they are
very politically powerful symbolic jobs
there may not be a more politically
powerful job in America than coal mining
as we saw in the last election
coal miners only 52,000 jobs rely on
coal mining in America that's it 52,000
logging the Pacific Northwest logging is
a hugely politically important job
72,000 people textile manufacturing
especially in the American South 73,000
people legal cannabis 243 thousand seven
hundred jobs these jobs matter and one
of the reasons we do this count again is
to spread the message make these jobs
politically powerful our jobs are out
there and they're worth defending
where did that job growth come from in
the last year we saw most of it in
Massachusetts where their adult use
legal market really hit its stride in
the past year added we estimated more
than ten thousand jobs in the past year
Oklahoma and they'd be been to Oklahoma
right Oklahoma is going nuts its
Oklahoma now has more than 5% of the
population with a medical marijuana card
more than five percent of Oklahoma
residents now have a med card and that
results in more than seven thousand jobs
added in the past year Illinois its
medical market grew to such an extent
that six thousand jobs were added in the
last year we just saw it grow open its
met its adult use market forty million
dollars in sales in just the first month
Florida we saw about ninety three
percent year-over-year growth in sales
in that state thanks especially to the
first time introduction of smokeable
flower introduced in their dispensaries
here's what we see in terms of the top
ten employers around the country
California obviously is still by far the
has the most workers but look at how
close Colorado is I mean the 5,000
worker difference here's the thing and
David downs may speak to this this a
little bit after me California because
of the sunsetting of its collectives law
in 2019 a lot of jobs that existed in
the legal space went into the non legal
space so we actually had to Ratchet back
our estimate for legal jobs in
California by about eight thousand we
had to do something similar in Michigan
where new tight regulations came in to a
market that was completely unregulated
prior to that and we ratcheted back by
about probably 7,000 jobs in the state
of Michigan now we expect those jobs to
eventually come back
more stores are licensed as more
municipalities allow stores to open in
their region but it's a it's a really
interesting thing I mean if California
and Michigan had not lost those jobs
instead of a 15 percent gain in 2019 we
would have seen about a 23 percent gain
so those two states accounted for a lot
of a lot of lost jobs there's another
thing I want to a couple states I want
to point out and draw some attention to
Massachusetts we saw more than 300%
growth over the last year they're
supporting now about 13,000 legal jobs
but Massachusetts like a handful of
other states there is still a massive
amount of opportunity in Massachusetts
Massachusetts has what 13,000 legal jobs
there are about 7 million people in
Massachusetts there are about 7 million
people in the state of Washington
Washington now supports about 23,000
jobs or so so we see Massachusetts in
that market as being basically just
maybe half of what it could be there are
I would say there are the number of open
shops in Massachusetts kind of is in the
dozens
whereas in Washington State we have more
than 300 licensed and open shops and so
we expect the Massachusetts to keep on
growing in the next year or two
Oklahoma again just an absolutely
incredible boom especially in a state
that is so culturally and politically
conservative there are a lot of
activists out there in other states
looking at Oklahoma and taking a lot of
inspiration from what they see there
there are folks in working in Idaho I
know radical Russ Belleville is out
there trying to get a medical marijuana
bill on the ballot in Idaho and folks in
other more conservative states are
looking at Oklahoma and saying oh my god
if they can do it in Oklahoma we can do
it in our state to Florida
Florida has more than 300,000 registered
medical marijuana patients they saw 93%
growth over the past year
they're selling I think 19,000 was the
number about four weeks ago I just
checked I think they're up to about
twenty one thousand twenty two thousand
ounces of smokeable flour sold every
week now in Florida Colorado in
Washington this number surprised us
because we thought of Colorado and
Washington is very mature markets who
would sort of Plateau
you know after what have they been in
business now six six full years but we
saw eight percent growth in each of
those states it's it's pretty incredible
and a couple things we thought were
going on one was that just simply the
slow eventual movement of people from
the illicit market to the legal market
is going on but then also anecdotally
basically because you know Leafly is in
Washington State and we see this
ourselves what we're seeing are a number
of consumers who are outside like the
classic marijuana consumer demographic
coming into the space they're coming
into legal stores for the first time
because those stores have been there for
a while their neighbors are shopping
there they're feeling more comfortable
about coming in but more than the stores
they're finding products that suit their
lifestyles and their health regimens I
know a number of people who never well
maybe not never smoked marijuana but
smoking was not a part of their of their
life but now they've discovered a five
milligram mint or they've discovered a
10 milligram gummy and that does work
for them that does help them relax at
the end of a long day that does help
them you know enjoy a movie on Netflix
and they feel more in control and it's
very discrete they can keep it in their
pocket or in their backpack it doesn't
smell so I think the the the evolution
of cannabis products has really helped
to bring in a number of people into
these mature markets we had just this
past week we put up an article on leaf
Lee called Kali sober what is it why are
people doing this right
well Kali sober is essentially the idea
that
you're essentially leaving alcohol but
you're not leaving all substances you're
leaving alcohol choosing not to drink
but maybe you're mixing a little
cannabis in here and there and that
article absolutely took off for us we
just saw click click click click click
click click click click
I mean it's January new year new you or
I guess it's February now but new year
new you right but that was that was sort
of eye-opening for us like wow there's a
lot of people interested in this concept
of you know mixing in cannabis in a way
that is healthy and suits them and maybe
help them help them put down the drink
or the bottle a little bit I know that's
that's happened for me in my life a few
states to watch that we're looking at in
2020 the Great Lakes region all of these
states are pretty amazing they're to us
here on the west coast I think maybe a
little quiet but Ohio you know now we
estimate has about 4200 jobs saw two
hundred seventy three percent
year-over-year sales growth the two
seventy three percent doesn't match the
job growth there's a little bit of math
involved here because the year-over-year
is capturing but the sales actually in
2019 but the jobs number is based on
where the market is now in January 2020
in other words maybe they sold 10
million in January of 2019 and 60
million in January or December of 2019
so the market really is at that 60
million a month a month figure Illinois
again a huge market already but a lot of
opportunity there Illinois is in a
situation where they just opened their
adult you stores selling 40 million
dollars a month if that keeps on and we
expect it to keep on you know that's a
four hundred and eighty million dollar a
year market Illinois has a chance to
sort of enjoy a bit of the Colorado
effect and what I mean by that is
Colorado when it opened in 2014 because
of its central
location it drew people from around the
country who wanted to experience a legal
cannabis store for the first time we saw
people driving up from Texas we saw
people coming in from all over the
country and they were going to Colorado
instead of Washington because I live in
Washington I love the state but we're a
little far out there you know it takes
it takes a while to get there
Illinois has a similarly central
location it's surrounded by five
prohibition states five and those stores
on the Illinois border are doing very
very well
and they're going to continue to do well
as more visitors go up to Illinois to
experience what we've got Pennsylvania
another kind of quiet state this year
they really bloomed in 2018 but again
they're continuing to grow their medical
system over there here's where I get up
on my soapbox and bring out a call to
action and ask you to take this number
take your state's number and do
something with it again the coal mining
industry hugely powerful timber in the
northwest hugely powerful I'd like to
see us in the cannabis industry come out
and as one of our panelists mentioned
here before be proud of the fact that
you work in this industry let people
know let people know there are others in
this industry I live in a congressional
district that's not in Seattle it's
across the water in Kitsap County and my
congressman is the gentleman named Erik
Kilmer Derek Kilmer represents my
district which has Bremerton which has a
Naval Shipyard they're the Naval
Shipyard jobs in Bremerton are
sacrosanct to that region like they are
they symbolize employment and good jobs
for a lot of people so when federal
budgets come out and those jobs are put
at risk
Derek Kilmer steps up he holds press
conferences he holds he leads protests
and he defends those jobs very publicly
now what I like to do is I like to
contact Derek Kilmer or his staff every
sick
months or so and just check in and say
hey I'm out here I work in the legal
cannabis industry Washington State we
have about 23,000 other people in this
industry those are good jobs those are
full-time jobs and hundreds of us are in
your district we vote I vote I'm a
loudmouth I tell other people I tell
them about cannabis I talked to them
about what you're doing and right now I
see you're not a co-sponsor of the more
Act you're not even a co-sponsor of the
state's act you're kind of quiet on the
federal on the on the congressional
banking bill I'm just kind of curious
aren't can I ask you when you're going
to step up and cosign one of these
initiatives to defend my job and the
staff members will say oh we're working
on it where you know the congressman is
very interested I'm like yeah it's a
good job it's legal I'm proud of it help
me out here
so please take this information do the
same spread it around get that number
out there it can become a very very
politically powerful number I'll end by
saying just simply we exist we matter we
count those who aren't counted don't
count this is why we do the jobs report
and if you want to see more about your
state go to Leafly news and we have the
full report up there this morning we
posted it 8:00 a.m. we have a
state-by-state we have a state-by-state
appendix that will tell you more about
your individual state and what's going
on we're gonna post an article by David
downs on Mondays about specifically
what's happening in California why and
where those jobs were lost and why we
think they're coming back in 2020 thank
you very much and go out there and be
proud of your job
Bruce Barca one more time that was
excellent
thank you Bruce