before we go to lunch we have a quick
special guest who wants to come out to
talk for five minutes this man is an
international legend he's written for a
high times magazine he's published
umpteen
different books i don't know if that's a
word in english and spanish many many
different books about cannabis and the
cannabis culture uh the ganja guru the
wizard of weed let's hear it for ed
rosenthal
where is he
i told him
right he came a long way too all the way
from oakland california berkeley
california he's like 8 million years old
now so
right and we should all aspire to be old
stoners by the way
old stoners always more fun than old
drunks
no all right some of you like to do this
where's ed is that his own column
[Music]
hello everybody
we'll try it again hello everybody
[Applause]
isn't it great to be able to go to a
convention again
you thought that you were tired of them
right
when they ended and now you realize
you're addicted
so
you know
everything that
the government and uh the antis said
about cannabis
turned out
to be
the the reverse of what they said
so they said that cannabis
cannabis leads to dangerous drugs
and
as i see it
marijuana leads to hashish
but
in new york city
where marijuana is now legal to smoke
anywhere you can smoke a cigarette which
means you can't smoke anywhere so
but
in new york city
now if you have
a
prescription for
opiates
right before it became legal and was
only illegal
medically
if you had a prescription for opiates
you could uh get marijuana from from it
so it turns out that opiates lead to
marijuana
and
that's good
now
there's only you know
i was brought in as a special speaker
because they realized i was going to be
in barcelona during
these conventions
and
they didn't really give me a subject to
talk about
but i want to talk about the most
serious subject
and that is you know
the people in prison all over the world
for marijuana
both here in europe
in many states in the united states
of course in asia
and in the united states while there are
people becoming billionaires
from the marijuana trade there are other
people languishing in prison for 20
years or more
same thing in europe and france it's
terrible the police
have seemed to be acting more violent
violently than they have in many years
they're trying to get their last licks
and i guess
germany there's opposition to
legalization
here in spain
police are acting perhaps
unconstitutionally
and
you know there are human
their
human suffering from that
and
we're
we're here at this convention it's
really a trade convention
and we're doing business
and there are people language and
languishing in prison
just for this
and so
i'm not going to be talking about how to
cultivate today you know you can buy my
book and learn how to cultivate
but what we have to learn is compassion
and that each of us
in the trade anybody who is making any
commerce in it
has a personal obligation to help
get these people out and there are
organizations i'm not going to go
through all the different organizations
in the united states there's an
organization
called
called last prisoner project that very
successful businessman uh steve d'angelo
who also was a yipi
is doing and here in europe there are
any number of organizations
and so
i'm imploring that
everybody who's here
you know
some people have money
other people have time
but it's one or the other money or time
if you're involved in the trade you owe
it to get out your brothers and sisters
who are languishing in prison
thank you
[Applause]
and it's true we have to remember that
cannabis legalization started as a
social justice project before it was a
way for people to show up and try to
make millions of dollars being
capitalists so let's always keep the
spirit of social justice in the spirit
of freedom and the spirit of fairness in
our hearts as we do all this business
and with that said
ramos aquaman let's go have lunch man
it's time