I introduce our piano that's like that's
gonna want to thank ICBC again for
having me
these conferences just seem to get
better every single year and Alex and
his team did a really great job
so my first panelist is George worth he
should be fairly well known and enduring
cannabis circles he's the leader the
German association Dutch Dutch for
Bergman no he was gonna screw that up do
I transfer Ron and he's been obedient
since its founding in 2002 he's also a
former local politician with the Green
Party please welcome George worth he
should also be well known to Germans in
the audience as he was a member of the
Bundestag until 2017 as a social
democrat he was also an adverse drug
policy spokesperson and yes please say
hello to Burkhart next up we have Susan
Chanel she's very well-known to me she's
the patient advocate for over a decade
she's currently the government relations
director with Pastor Branson she's also
a former city councillor so please say
guten talk to Susan spa quick started in
the industry was in the main cooper
dispensary scene much like myself he
went on to become CEO of M&amp;A Canada in
2015 which was a company that was based
both in BC and in Ontario and he's
currently well I still with the lost
organization as well which will give it
to a little bit and he's now the company
X based out of Switzerland so please
welcome
so we've got a little bit of a longer
introduction in normal - because Lobby
for cannabis is a really weird thing
when most people think of lobbying you
think you're gonna have to try and
convince a politician to do something
that's probably not going to make the
government a lot of money and probably
not going to make people feel better
people think of Big Pharma they think of
big tobacco when they think of lobbyists
and with cannabis it's sort of the
opposite you're trying to convince a
politician to do something that will
help a lot of people and make the
government a lot of money and they still
don't actually want to do it it's kind
of like arguing with a two-year-old or
that expression about playing chess with
the pigeon doesn't really matter if you
win they're still going to knock over
all the pieces of [ __ ] all over the
world is very kind of heavily Canadian
and German we're going to go through
very quickly the lobbying challenges and
issues that we have in Canada going from
fully illegal to fully illegal and then
we'll kind of delve into where we are a
Germany and what the specific issues are
here and how we move forward from there
so my own background was in lobbying in
a federal government that absolutely
hated cannabis I then tried to lobby a
provincial government that didn't really
care one way or another I then found
some city governments that absolutely
here the federal government they were
actually willing to give some licenses
to illegal businesses that worked out
pretty well because within six months
that government was no longer in power
and we had the Canadian Liberals who had
won on a policy of legalization at that
point distribution was given to
provinces and some different provinces
we're taking different approaches in
Ontario they decided they wanted to run
all of the stories themselves and they
were just going to shut down all of the
existing privately run details which is
why I went to go work with them MJ and
we started lobbying in Ontario and now
Ontario does help private retail but it
also sort of resulted in a government
getting kicked out in order to do it
yeah client you want to come and tell
that story yeah thank you very much for
having me guys yeah so Ontario Canada
although MMJ Canada was based Canada
east to west in Vancouver Nelson BC and
in Ontario it was really tricky and on
because Damien said the the structure in
the format was kind of already in place
due to the due diligence of people like
Jamie in Vancouver and in British
Columbia but it seemed as we opened up
M&amp;J Canada's in Ontario the government
was right in the middle of an election
and a lady named Kathleen Wynne who was
the Premier of Ontario at the time
wanted to put it in Elle CBO's which is
government-run liquor distribution store
our style model they wanted to call the
OCS or Part B the C CEO at one point
they then changed to the OCS but then
has power changed it went from the
Liberal Party to the Conservative Party
were then Doug Ford said he wanted to
privatize and have an open and free
market which at the end of all said that
never even happened either unfortunately
there ended up with 25 licenses and
certain restrictions so in the very
beginning of MMJ Canada which I've been
speaking here now this is my third year
if anybody was here before we were very
mark identity medical cannabis
dispensary so I spent a lot of my time
dealing with police raids you know
conflict resolution and I realized that
no matter how much of a standard that
you set for a government or a brand you
are gonna be painted as the same brush
when you're in the illegal in the listed
market I then started logging
municipalities and I asked Jamie to fly
in because she was my government
relations director at the time and I was
struggling with you know a lot of the
aspects of Ontario and it was becoming
frustrating so Jamie kind of came out to
fly out with me and work with the city a
Hamilton which is my hometown and we
started lobbying the city councillors
and speaking in front of different City
pardon me you got the city you know the
regulator view the city regulators and
it got to the point where we're actually
making a lot of headway with the city
municipalities and at one point I was
like wow Hamilton is going to give us
temporary licenses and this is really
mingkun we might be the first city
besides Vancouver ahead of the time for
Ontario that might produce these
licenses but unfortunately as I realize
now which is a mistake that I made
CEO of Edmonton Canada was that I was
lobbying the wrong people as much as the
municipalities had say as Jamie said
there was one municipality in all of
Canada that decided to really
essentially allow these licenses to
happen before legalization or jerk
searchers as a few a few yeah very minor
Ontario there was none at the time and I
really thought I was going to break
ground with Hamilton and then the
province came in and they literally just
squashed it so the issues that I had and
I realized was that I might have been
lobbying the wrong people I feel that
you need to include well in Canada goes
you know municipality provinces in the
federal I realize now that if I was to
have to redo it again which I will never
do it again but if I had to I would
start with the province in the federal
and then worked out of the municipality
because there's only so much the
municipalities can do any went do it
against them a second for punishment
yeah so back to be see we had some
cities that were on the board we had a
province that was fairly progressive we
had federal legalization we had
succeeded in giving smaller licenses we
succeeded in getting edibles and
topicals coming which were all major
issues and then I would move forward we
found that all of the issues came back
down to the cities again Susan you were
a councillor in Squamish which was a
small town in a progressive province
under legalization is what kind of
challenges the game next and what are we
doing now thanks Jamie that's an
excellent question
so municipalities in British Columbia
have no access to taxation so it's
really interesting that Clinton spoke
about their multiple levels of
government which i think is pretty much
global you have different regulations
coming out from the feds and different
regulations at the problems and they had
basically split the taxes between the
province and the feds
so the municipalities have no access to
taxation from Canada's yet they are the
ones that are dealing with police bylaws
land-use struggles allowing land use for
cannabis so at the City Councilor
I recognize I was a closeted canvas user
because I was a politician but I have to
become an advocate for the industry
because we had a massive industry in
Squamish much of our economy came from
him even though we could prove it and I
work in a clinic that deals with cancer
patients and my patients were driving
down the highway to access their
medicine
we had no dispensary laws we weren't
licensing anything and I knew
legalization was coming and I thought
this is a giant policy hole we have just
we have no dispensaries we have no
access to canvas for patients and we
have no land use for cultivation
although I didn't realize how big
cultivation was because I can really
enter in as an advocate for the industry
I started writing bylaws and it's funny
because much of my bylaw work was based
on Jamie before we have even met based
on the work that Jamie and Clint had
done in other regions and I started
writing bylaws and I instead of going
through staff and saying this is how
this has to happen and can you please
write something I just presented the
bylaw and in two weeks we voted on it
of course it failed because there wasn't
any education and it wasn't legal yet
and so I had to pass it two more times
and in order to pass it the third time I
had to change the regulations to be
pretty prohibitive for cultivation so we
put in numbers that work based on any
science or facts they were based on
federal regulations in the United States
for 200 meters setbacks for any cannabis
business so if you were a dispensary or
a cultivator or any sort of extraction
business you had to be to intervenors
from other businesses were 12 kilometers
long so it's you could basically have
five cannabis businesses and all of
those licenses got taken up with
dispensaries so we still have a massive
illegal business and we still have no
taxation and can in British Columbia and
in all municipalities so the work that
I've started to focus on now as
I ran for mayor and I failed to get in
as mayor because we also have populist
politics in Canada now and lobbying for
candidates afterwards became my passion
because access to full botanicals access
to the plant I'm also work in science so
access to the plant for medical research
and understanding where the full
spectrum botanical does it is incredibly
important for many reasons lobbying the
province has become so that we can
actually have a tax share of
municipalities and be able to pay for
our RCP and our bylaws and so that but
not municipalities feel like they have
some skin in the game if you're not
gaining any resources there's no reason
to move forward with policy so speaking
to politicians and explaining the
economic benefits I've tried to build
some economic models I've tried to
explain the importance of modeling the
economics of it and not just talking
about patients and medicine because for
me it's recreation and that's equally as
important it's it's medical but not just
absolutely well and all of these pieces
fit together so we have legal hemp we
have legal medical cannabis we have
legal recreational cannabis
we've got edibles and topicals coming
we've got smaller licenses that we've
been wanting and now we're fighting to
be able to grow good cannabis Organic
cannabis we're fighting to be able to
actually grow an agricultural product on
agricultural land so that's sort of the
issues where we're at now Burkhart was
some of those patterns he's probably
pretty familiar to you
one of your main objectives when you
were in said it was to give cost-free
access to patients to cannabis you were
pretty successful at that he removed
some of the bureaucracy that was
involved Canada invented healthcare and
we still tax medicine we're still not
doing it right what were the challenges
for you to even get to that point and
how are you successful in one of the
outstanding issues
she cannot say it's also this computer
kisara mockingjay at an Indian I'm
feeling the stone the food's good sighs
no to be política hour at nine different
visa lien Ben from Austin superfluity at
was superseded in hot weather needs to
do say that the vacant daughter has not
yet as manga and avi muslin I mean dig
in the missing guns and lights there in
Kannada reason oh we are in deserve a
battery audit emotional side films under
a CC on in application departed after
Halloween obviously sued for this even
cannabis mater legalism and young man an
important material to gaya unexpectedly
so by the first certain diseases from
political philosophy um does Atlas
individual combed the anime items on
victim Anunnaki income as cancer heart
is your anguish last May Lavinia often
born they are irritating the politic
this and he talked with each becomes a
fatwa on what the Mosman delivers a
shock Illinois often the Macomb Illinois
the expect new position or cadets and
kind of advance into account English in
a politically at hospitals ten and
published by Java and a too often Summa
and in Springer good so that's not
forgive was more coconuts as nish
chemistry at which are completely butter
we were legally they mentioned in patent
in this in Victor Mukasa families
wouldn't be a good as costly one
ambience exact on the fiscal hoon that's
all good so as it went on
thus had is a sinful former gang
designed is made its initial assessment
doesn't become kind of leadership
marathan Deutschland is illegal
get complex so name evently the part in
a tradition of in to confirm listen
Vivian made legalism for cannabis only
in vivid as magnesium but uncommon
naturally if from Canada the understand
the system become attribute editor
Finland Zuzu BSN company unkind or does
deserves introduced devious kumata only
the Fox in conservative
the politician that locust and Elizabeth
in
technical English others on campus
audience boos man can glide and by the
success which the girls move in Niger in
case Mitch McConnell malaria zombie
standard session for goddess politician
own business Australia Dmitry what is
motel the infamous Mowgli is the season
for the big endorsement on your mood is
payment he owned by design the envy of
Australia was with happen that's
continued shifter too much fortified a
community moment
under the windows happening the gas
under look at autumn city home as to of
no minutes away from the sabbatical
you will and that was that's been my
experience as well and kind of haven't
had success by working with the smaller
governments but as Susan said are gonna
end up having to deal with most of these
issues anyway they're the ones spending
the resources George you've also been
involved in this fight for a very long
time what are some of the biggest issues
for you right now and what are some of
the tactics that factory Jennifer friend
uses to to actually try and make change
well about the tactics accidentally I
googled the word lobbyism
last week another reason not because of
this panel here and Lobby isn't means
make political contact
to get something to get something
decided on for others for association of
people for network of people somehow
whatever network that is political
context but also public relations work
to convince people and that is what we
do all the time since 2002 since German
cannabis Association exists that what
were the main things and the public
relation thing is in one part over our
own channels I think we have the
strongest social media channels at all
I'd say I've found no other NGO in the
scene or Amnesty International or
whatever as strong as we are every week
pushing out which new people and that
made us really strong
every time when there's something to
take actually when we call for action
every time we were very successful for
example 2017 we had the strongest
petition in the Bundestag of the year
calling for legalization and I can
mention lots of other things like that
we were really on the forefront when it
was about asking people for something
and we see the results we see more and
more people in the public public opinion
favoring legalization when we started
when I at the first the first Paula
Ebben - 2010 it was 19 percent of public
in favor of legalization since 2014 we
make it every year asked people and a
representative Paul and was now talk to
some 14 it was 30 percent last year it
was 46
so we are arriving slowly at majority
and there is something we need to
convince politicians as we heard before
we don't have the majority to get it
right through now right I think that's
ok because that's part of the Democratic
game somehow we can't think politicians
should do the right thing just because
it's the right thing when the people
don't want it so we have to have that
majority and we so will in a bit and
also the same thing is when you are
politicians when you look into the
parliaments when I started doing before
the end of the 90s only the Green Party
was for legalization then the Left Party
came at the pole that the Liberals came
at the boat now the Social Democrats I
hope are soon in the boat
Buchan is one of the guys leading the
way to that point and then finally
everything comes together the nice day
will come to legalize also in Germany
yeah well then it takes education it
takes constant effort and it takes
thinking outside of the box some of the
kind of more interesting things that
you've done that or not may be typical
in other jurisdictions is you went a
million euros on a TV show and turn that
into Europe's first cinematic anti
prohibition campaign you also want to
pole to be able to talk to Angela Merkel
how did that go and what did you say to
her yeah also actually two times it was
a little bit I think Oh bah idea when he
tried to get contact to the public oh
the internet internet community asking
questions and the best voted questions
he would answer do something that's
something Mac I've tried also first
thing was via YouTube ask me questions
the 10 most voted questions I will
answer
so we asked why don't realise marijuana
and out of six thousand questions this
was number one and she too outside and
the answer was well not very informed
like well we can't recognize it because
of cultural reasons I call this our
cultural comedies and cannabis is very
highly addictive and so on and then she
tried it with an on platform not
question this time but suggestions she
said what was good for the future
Germany the 10 best voted suggestions
I will him personally invite you in my
office and so on we were on place to or
of eleven thousand suggestions and so I
was first come up with lobbyists talking
to the German Chancellor and at least I
convinced her to call for expert panel
and several answers of the first round
were very bad informed so please ask
some experts and at least that Chile did
nice well I mean and I mean this is you
know there's a lot of moving pieces to
this you know where could have mentioned
earlier that there was initiatives in
the 90s well Canada tried to legalize in
the seventies and the next days we don't
know you can't do that you might know
okay all right and then nothing again
until 10 years of courts saying you have
to fix this and the government doing the
worst possible job on purpose because
they didn't want it fixed right Burkhart
you again so this is this kills me a
little bit Canada is is one of the
things that we're very proud of is that
we're a country that invented
national healthcare when we've had legal
medical cannabis for over a decade
we still don't cover it the way we cover
other medications we actually tax it
we've added more tax on to it that no
medical patients have to pay and they
can't get back which is not in line at
all with Canadian culture when you want
to talk about traditional cultures and
values this was again I mean focus of
your work and you were very successful
but as we've discovered with everything
else has never really done so what are
the other specific issues that you feel
around medical cannabis in particular
that that really need to be addressed
here in Germany
as whether [ __ ] we get us into a
party with meat in Slovenia I mean
wouldn't it be our final program would
have also bought about the second moment
even asking the tough videos enough
politics Atlanta yet dr. Lee Anne Klein
blue song boom zone mislead English the
in all the hope they met is a spider
I'm from Calais no longer zetsubou so
again as mr. Armitage Anita's problema
gift da matta Spanish and a lose on our
data sets mrs. mom when I had a mansion
imitating shutter - game come on put it
adopted sighing the average teen it
everything visits our own via the front
on this because it seems another percent
a new person new North who knows could
go honest or not Nast higher heart on
Jimmy's even is a potential and here on
Indies music and it's a hard Boston or
perched on trodden on the sphere by
defeating political entity these songs
on the server of data strands
I'd stay near their unbelief in second
life table did orders from mrs. Carter
that servicing a lot of non political or
videos nah it's in multiple that's
Olivia what's illegal is Eva slag well
as Morton if this valve in Amityville is
at the butter of it alongside felony
fire owners conference on does not
vanish ninety human society also the
national political and that's not the
cannabis politic amazing shuttin in the
open the Mushaf name of the Internet's
nine in Nevada creamy indeed arson the
more tending Boston and Selena meet via
an illegal abortion on a star if you
come on the idea right or converse an
export import but first massive loss
bottom of another productive observe
complied me impish statements talking
once in Eatonton honest
to motivate political service only
victor lifetime garbage dish
Mukwonago after shopping diesel allen
nationalism society or demons one in the
internal form a homogeneous
international father idea was I did was
a politician's it of the own Islamic
doctrine and say 50 Boston a diamond I
never taught Sigma's as I has gotten
right a bone from televisions manatee by
the fog reveals a muscle car abandoned
factory the certain silicon of Allah of
eternity more in to the porter life to
whom for under the pervasive Konkan
Venice TV Internet's not even given via
India marketing education its reasons
for failure it makes me very happy
because you know in Canada and most
other jurisdictions that we've seen
medical has been thrown under the bus
they're not trying to fix medical there
are no politicians standing up for
medical so you know hopefully you guys
get that right so that we can look to
you and go okay that's how we fix our
system this is the other interesting
thing that I find about cannabis is
every jurisdiction that you go to says
what we're different when we're not like
that other jurisdictions oh they're
loose and we're not we're a very EMS K
when you actually look at all the
jurisdictions they end up following the
same pattern how it plays out there's
sometimes a little bit a different hue
in the shape but it all ends up being
the same pattern sometimes it may take
ten years to take one step sometimes
that step will happen in a month but it
ends up sort of following the same
pattern and one of the things one of the
reasons why I love ICBC and coming to
conferences around the world is that
when Vancouver decided to license
illegal businesses they didn't do it in
a vacuum
I had prepared a report for them and
showed them what happened in California
cities when a city decided that they
were going to regulate cannabis for the
benefit of patients and for the benefit
of their communities they had really
good roles that work just fine until the
states came along and screwed the month
and then the states we've kind of come
along screw him up a little bit but he
had compared that other cities that were
trying to fight it and we were
discussing this in the green
a little bit George about how they you
know the more that prohibitionist try
and actually clamp down on it the worse
it actually gets for everybody it
becomes a little bit more of a wild west
scenario it becomes harder to track
things down and front from just a public
health perspective it makes a lot more
sense to have brick-and-mortar locations
where you can go with look or to have
testing regulations around cannabis or
how you can grow it but do not go too
far with it
George where do you think we are next
what do you think the next fight is here
in Germany and how is that going to be
affected by or affect the nations around
you well there are a lot of things we
have to care about at the moment some
very concrete problems on the medical
base it's not that everybody gets
reimbursement from medicine even if you
have a recipe about one third of the
proposals are taken mother adventurin
insurances the prices are very high for
one gram it's more than 20 euros per
gram and German pharmacies which is
German will critique our trip somehow
not easy to get all this we have the
soft shortage problems and so on so
there are many details we are fighting
for and also things about the
criminalization of consumers the
driver's license issue is a very big one
in Germany because here a lot of sour
people lose that driver's license
because we have here the limit of one
nanogram THC per milliliter and that is
very very low a lot of leading and ever
and they were driving ever
I will never be night away with Germany
everything so that is an issue I don't
know how fast we come forward but that's
a big issue for us to push a lot of the
criminalization as such we are every
year we have a new record it's a it
sounds like a rail we are coming it's
going forward in Germany but the
repression is still rising so that's
also an issue and maybe we have a
majority in the parliament soon about
that it's a little step well as far as
legalization but when we say well if you
have got 10 grams people donate or take
it as a donor can say misty mana or
something and I was gonna just play
little pine and that's it and no record
and so on maybe we come further on that
front
and as Bach had said the cities to play
a big role in Germany because he and the
German drug war we have a loophole it's
an idea that the scientifical model
projects are possible and that's how
Germany tested 10 years ago or 15 years
ago the distribution of heroin and that
was very successful and now doctors camp
is quite harrowing and that's the same
idea for cannabis and when I said we
come closer to majorities also the
political field we see now majorities in
cities the first little province with F
majorities cornpone utilization but what
yet in the boom stack and that might be
the right tool to bring power from
bottom down like grassroot thing like in
the States is that's the interesting
thing
what jurisdiction you look at it came
from the bottom up and it's when
studying people at the top goal okay
we're gonna make the rules that
everything starts kind of going sideways
Clint you're in Switzerland now what are
some of the challenges that are going to
be there and how does what Switzerland
does affects what goes on in the rest of
Europe well it's one it seems to be a
little easier for manufacturing
industrial hemp CBD as a great now
you're free to grow and manufacture
industrial heavy CVD as long as it's
under 1% I've noticed that our one
partner Tobias Jenny who's fortunately
in Tel Aviv retail he is the founder of
the medical cannabis Association in
Switzerland so he's been working with
the state and her different competitions
and from my understanding Tobias is
explained me very well that there are a
lot more communicative than Canada was
there hasn't seen as many as near as
many issues as I went through being a
completely grey market and to the the
way it's viewed in Switzerland
regulated so it's a lot more easier on
us to operate and to work with the
government I'm kind of excited to see
what happens with Switzerland and the
THC testing in the next few months and
years to come but again it's a lot
easier than what was happening in Canada
just to touch back onto what Susan was
saying you know the municipalities
didn't have any money coming in through
taxes it was one of the things that
really frustrated me the most in Canada
when I was working with it that you have
these people that want these counselors
and the municipalities to help but
they're you know has also a counselor
unique city tax money coming in to grow
infrastructure roads education you know
harm reduction sites and when there's
nothing coming in for them it makes it
really hard for them to step on your
side for lobbying especially in parts of
Canada each province is you know
extremely different
we're summer really proactive and some
are in Ontario at the time really wasn't
although my city of Hamilton was I
really wish there was more people like
Susan who from a councillors point of
view although she knew
that there has to be tax coming in and
you know a benefit for the city for it
to make sense she played a major role in
advocacy so did Jamie and what I've
noticed the in Canada which is actually
kind of impressive some of the best
lobbyists cannabis and ain't talked
about a little more for females and
they're really good at what they do it's
awesome and you know it's counselors
like Susan - people like Jamie when it
comes to the lobbying aspects that I've
looked up to for a long time lobbying
was not my wheelhouse there was a reason
why I've dropped champion - Ontario to
help with me because I'm somebody that
wears my heart on my sleeve I speaking
about mental health and cannabis a lot
more than thank you anything else so I'm
quite passionate and I'm very vulnerable
to getting defensive and kind of coming
across with a little bit of fire so when
I wanted to do what I wanted to do in
Ontario I knew that I had to reach out
to someone and you know you hear a lot
of the power Corp cement and strong men
and all that and I always reach out to
the females I felt like the females have
been doing the strongest in logging and
in all of Canada and making the most
effect and again I'm super thankful for
people like Susan you black Jamie Shaw
all these people doing things and they
should be given the credit they deserve
because they're the ones leading the
forefront for this
I actually just wish that our Parliament
had more politicians like Burkhart I
actually cared about patience um because
again this is an issue that we've seen
everywhere Washington says well we've
got medical program but you know you're
not really allowed to sell it so all of
these businesses pop up and they're
illegal and they're selling only to
people that the state says is allowed to
have cameras but they're not allowed to
sell it and then they suddenly go okay
you know what we're gonna do
recreational cannabis so all of those
now medical ones are now a legal and and
again that's sort of a pattern that we
keep seeing so I hope we definitely do
not see that in Germany Burkhard what's
your take on how what Germany does
affects what goes on around it what some
Burghley devices is that going to have
an effect on Germany in any way plug de
Luxembourg village violent it's always
had some badonkadonk Luxembourg got a
franchise it's era in fish lungs is it
the butter in the opiate of battling
murder
hinata Kazuko what our exits in part of
under supporters política de gankelaar
known established is look nice the
pharmacy shambhavi the fafsa game and
the so finish wonders of in da da du is
also have the unveiling of Columbia and
in the political media Ivan Assad in
Sofia Alice go to the visitor gets movie
of this button opens a home business
knows
yeah well and and it's for me I love the
different jurisdictions doing different
sort of different things because that's
how you can sort of see a Miss does work
or this doesn't work if everybody does
the same thing it takes a lot longer to
get anywhere and Susan all kind of with
you just before we go to a quick Q&amp;A and
what are your thoughts on what comes
next in terms of
global Lobby Thanks
excellent question I really feel that we
need to focus on more of the vertical
integration it's not just about the
cannabis and the cultivation that
politicians need to realize this is a
huge economic generator for their
municipalities for their provinces and
for their country the country that makes
it legal across all of the vertical
change the ancillary businesses and the
economics surrounding cannabis is
enormous this entry prohibition you
don't add sorry exiting prohibition is
exiting prohibition for any industry
it's only happened a few times in
hundreds of years
so products leaving an illegal market
into a legal market it's massive
opportunity as you all know explaining
that and modeling it for politicians and
being able to speak the same values as
politicians have being able to research
in advance what the politicians are
looking for and being able to speak to
the level that the level of government
needs to understand so whether it be
economic benefits or medicinal benefits
cultural benefits financial benefits
it's all really important and there's so
many there's so much lobbying to be done
and it's going to take multiple
communities and also cannabis users need
to vote that's massively relate for
hours about as we covered topics very
very quickly in bio and there are any
questions from the audience I'm sure
there is a question or two what's here
to gain from the panel that was
fantastic
[Applause]
of course exactly our right now so I
just wanted to assure Linda you weren't
wrong and lobbying local politicians you
have to remember when booze was illegal
we had all the win areas in the dry
areas one of the biggest problems now
while we managed to you know go after
the federal government that control
provision the provinces distribution its
local governments that decide where your
store is going to be and not and so on
and that's a big problem in a lot of
areas and also landlord-tenant sorts of
things so you're really going to figure
out who's in charge of what in terms of
the lobbying to focus and just like a
quick thing about the impaired driving
thing you all have to remember that well
of course the Janie's case she's always
over five nanograms but most of us if
you only smoke once in a while it'll
stay in your system for 90 days so
remember that if they pull you over
officer it was three months ago
yes and just because this deserves a
shout out lobbying work is one piece of
the puzzle and we would not have been
anywhere near as successful if it wasn't
for leaders like John Connolly who
fought for 30 40 years
yeah I would like to understand where is
precisely if there is an inquisition on
the real pile of an adoption we heard
this morning that there is from
education to do for the clinical doctors
they not know exactly what cannabis is
doing and they they are reluctant to use
it and on the other side we can see that
there is most probably also an education
to do for the politician to push the
head different new law so on the other
hand we see that Canada is quite
advanced in such process I'm wondering
if the Canadians doctor are different
from European I presume that they are
not well educated so probably the
question is where to put the focus on
clinician or on politician everywhere
well one of the issues that we're having
now is that some of the strongest
blowback is actually coming from Medical
Association's meanwhile there's doctors
like dr. mark where we've been
spearheading this and there's research
for a long time and they can't even
convince their peers of stuff that we've
got weaves of research on so I mean it
literally it takes six multiple fronts
it's not on one front more and it's a
full spectrum of technical and that's
not a usual plant that's given as
medicine so it's a bit of a drug looking
for a disease as well because the we
haven't had access to do research and
yet the physicians fair enough they're
being told here's a drug we don't know
when it's good for but it seems to cover
a lot of bases and they don't know
dosing they don't know how it is given
so the education for medical
practitioners is massive because there
is research now that supports use of
cannabis but again is it spoke is it
faked how is it adjusted what kind of
exam
and that so many questions still around
this absolutely Greg that was fantastic
thank you so very much
you
the lobbying discussion in particular is
difficult and there's some issues in
this industry that are persistent and
have not been solved yet and I think
it's fair to say that everybody on this
panel believes that in some way some of
the larger industry issues in part can
be solved by technology or at least
greatly aided so I'm gonna throw this
question out immediately what and where
do you think technology of whatever kind
can help to continue revolutionising
this business and if those of you guys
don't do like Storz and Bickel is that's
who's sitting next to me so I'm gonna
throw it to you quickly because
everybody knows your vape and your
international yeah thank you very much
madam yes my name is Jurgen beaker from
sauce and pickle we are producing
vaporizers our first revolutionising
technology was in the year 2000 when we
product volcano vaporizer on the market
before the time you had to smoke it yeah
more or less or to eat it there was no
no as a viable way so this was a one
revolution but what's today is very
normal
everybody knows vaporizer tons of
products out there so it become a very
mainstream I believe the application
form will be in the future more
revolutionising we see all this
concentrate vaporizers it will go
forward in this direction we see our
alternatives like capsules but you can
in chess so I believe they are the
technology will go forwards
can I just add a little plug here I mean
vaping is seen as like the future not
just of the cannabis business but a lot
of other medications a lot of other
kinds of things right I mean yeah in
theory it's possible yeah whatever can
but cannabis is have a little bit
special of because of this
decarboxylation process THC a
transformed into th see it there must be
other substances still found what can be
viable for it so what about the rest of
you so and please you know introduce
your firm quickly where do you see
technology helping to revolutionize the
business is it sales as tracking is it
you know just knowing what you're doing
where are the things that you guys see
technology revolutionising the business
end
thank you
that works hi my name is Jeff Keene I'm
the CEO of a company called or a product
called 365 cannabis but it's actually
based on I'm a Microsoft dynamics
platform an ERP platform so the way we
feel we're gonna help revolutionize the
space is actually taking something that
works outside the industry and bring it
in so we're looking at the cannabis
industry like every other industry
that's out there I think the cannabis
industry in markets like Canada and in
the u.s. started out thinking it was
unique in every sense but from a
business process since it's like a lot
of other business it's Agri its food
process manufacturing its distribution
warehousing and in the US and now
starting to be in Canada is also its
retail so rather than look at it and say
how do I solve my problems in cannabis
for those things we're bringing a
platform from outside that does all
those things and applying it to the
cannabis space and then this term seed
to sale that comes out there in the US
and Canada where you're compliant if you
do all the right business processes and
you set the system up properly then
you're automatically going to be
compliant and you your seed to sale that
you hear so often in US the US and
Canada
anybody else have some feedback here
yeah absolutely so hey hello everyone my
name is Aida Sethi on the CEO founder
groomers consulting the way that
technology has actually revolutionized
the industry in my eyes is that it's
helped us scale this helps us automate
it's helped us accelerate
personally for me you know I I'm
launching a software called Odyssey it's
focused on licensing and permitting for
cannabis businesses in the US and it's
it's really accelerated and scale the
process of being able to do that even
though we can't fully automate it and I
think that you can equate to you could
equate it to something like you know the
turbo tax or LegalZoom of the cannabis
industry and it's focused on a lot of
the pre-license aspects of getting these
entrepreneurs licensed getting them up
and running but I've seen everything in
my 25 years of doing this I've seen
everything from you know just these the
CD sale tracking him
control systems all the way to like
robots AI drones inside cultivation
facilities that are spotting things like
disease pests and controlling these and
automating it and so we're gonna see the
same thing when it comes down to drop
shipping medic medication eventually so
it's really interesting to see how
technology is really taking this to the
next level and I can't wait we're really
excited to see that so I'm going to jump
here a second so you see and I agree
with you technology is helping to
normalize as well as automate routine
processes that have also in part slowed
down this industry is absolutely and we
have yet to see some of the best out
there I mean as we go through this
innovation period it's almost like a
Renaissance period of Technology we're
seeing more and more and more come out
every single day and everybody's just
really taking it to the next level so
it's really exciting
so hello my name is many I'm the chief
product officer and interim CEO of
namaste technologies we're a Canadian
company were fully vertically integrated
ecommerce platform in Canada
specifically we have sales only licensed
which essentially forces us to be a pure
play a technology pure play company we
leverage technology to enable
optimization of the user experience and
we deliver solutions such as education
telemedicine applications the ability to
purchase cannabis online same-day
delivery
journaling etc and we can talk about
each one of these technologies or siloed
assets separately but my bias is and
it's gonna be very hyped is around that
artificial intelligence and one of the
things that were focused on is to try
and understand how we can leverage AI to
help people find the right product for
them and actually brought one of our
lead machine learning engineers with me
so that everybody can harass him and see
I'm not just making stuff up but that
those just like the FinTech
industry was really changed where you
had people who were very very passionate
but we're doing an understanding
regulation and using technology to
change that industry and we still see
that impact since 2009 till today
FinTech is still changing literally
we're in the infancy days of technology
and cannabis combined so so anyway I
mean medpay for those who don't know
what it is it's not many feet of
advertisement you can come to our booth
what we were using blockchain and we're
actually I mean no matter what the
technology is I think here whether it's
hardware or software there are ways to
use existing technology to automate
processes there are ways to use new
technology to push the envelope there's
a whole bunch of innovation that's
coming out but one of the things also
that struck me about this panel was how
international it is right so you have
people here with international
experience and technology certainly
across oceans is different and a lot of
us are looking at the compliance space
one way or another how about just shout
out where are where do you think the
international cannabis industry in some
ways has started to reform or put
pressure on or change the cannabis
industry in other places and how does
this get Mistry now being international
play into the revolution and
revolutionising idea of tech in its
application where do you see that happen
yeah I am we have to the last four of
months we distributed into 19 countries
around the world so it's very
international and it's everywhere
available and of course with this
technology you have tend the way how you
can consume cannabis in a medical way
you have 10 an episode you can track all
that and so it's the technology is
really a nowadays distributed worldwide
in a very fast way but its comply is
different from country to country right
yeah exactly and of course we are
European country we are here a medical
device manufacturer on a medical device
manufacturer means that he needs to be
have a quality management system
yeah it's called traceability what is
called see to sail on the other hand on
a device and destroys ability if you get
back defective device which is a very
number you must be able to track back
but you purchased every single part you
built in and where you have it so - so
there the requirements are relatively
high and they are different from country
to country for example we don't have a
medical device in the USA because the
FDA is not ready to
a medical device then if you go to
Israel you have of course also other
requirements labeling in Hebrew in
Arabic can also little bit challenging
stuff like that and the latest compliant
thing we got is the gdpr
the channel directly from the escape or
downs which control no privacy yeah yeah
privacy laws so this gives you also an
answer compliance seeing what I think
from people from North America they are
not ready for the GDP I as far as I can
as I can see of course the law it's less
than a year old but it's a really a it's
a strict law and it's a really highly
punished law and it will be followed it
so I think it will also affect a lot of
people who touch Europe in any in any
way these their products there's some
compliance coming up I'll take the next
one kits an interesting question on
compliance because so we do business in
Canada US and there's a number of
international companies in Colombia
Jamaica Australia Denmark that we're
dealing with right now in the cannabis
industry but the platform is already
international so if you look at the
platform work we're using for ERP is
already almost in every country in the
world including Germany just not in in
the cannabis space so the Canadians when
they came into the space with their LPS
and we came in a few years afterwards we
saw the legacy of this was they their
compliance to them was just in my
complaint to Health Canada and I'm
meeting the regulations so I can keep my
license and they didn't think about
compliance in any other way so now all
of a sudden the Canadians are coming to
us and asking us for GMP first of all I
think they probably had to look up the
the acronym as most of us do good
manufacturing process which in order to
export your product from Canada to
countries like Germany you have to prove
that you are a GMP processing facility
and the Canadians weren't thinking of
that at all so it's I think in some ways
the international space has a way to
benefit from what was already learned in
the US and Canada not do the same things
look at it as a business that has to be
compliant as a versus a compliant
industry specific to cannabis that has
to run a business and there's
everywhere gdpr GMP FDA requirements are
not in the US yet but they're coming so
all these things have to be in place
they're public companies now trading so
now Sox compliance and how your
financial reporting goes so we actually
had to employ which I didn't think I'd
ever have to do running a software
company as higher compliance chief
officer just for us to handle not only
what's going on in cannabis but also the
compliance is coming at us from
everywhere else I'm gonna push this one
to you right so that's a discussion
about what can technology do to
revolution revolutionize the industry I
think sales and advertising is certainly
there right
however controversial and I wanted to
throw it in that direction because you
know the question is about how
technology can be applied to overcome
some of the bigger issues whether it's
compliance or laws or etc and certainly
sales online the discussion of the
industry press online 2014 helped push
forward a whole bunch of things how do
you see this working how do you see this
technology discussion changing
regulatory frameworks that are still
holding the industry back like
advertising or etc so so that's a very
important point to remember that
everybody's very afraid of compliance
gdpr and they're very worried about what
are we gonna do with it but essentially
if you look at it it could be a huge
opportunity because the existence of
gdpr raises the bar and allows you if
you build systems in place to comply
with that allows you to create moats
around your business so for example part
of gdpr and I'll get to the advertising
sales point a moment part of GDP RS is
security by design or segregating data
not collecting data that you shouldn't
if you don't need it for true processing
so for example one of the things with
automatic processing of data is that
it's not exposed to humans so you can
segregate it within the system and then
you're protected from a compliance
perspective you can automate a lot of
the requirements that gdpr has and then
you create those modes around the
business and and you use that as an
opportunity specifically around sales
and marketing that's really interesting
because I spent the morning talking with
a lot of CB d producers and suppliers
here and the one thing that everybody
spoke about is like we cannot advertise
we cannot sell our our products online
or so we've not advertised a product so
now even there was a pan
previously that spoke about the exact
same point and CBD let's take it as an
example in many countries many countries
is completely mingle however the big
advertising networks like Google and
Facebook adsense double-click etc those
are the ones that don't allow you to
advertise and guess what happened to
Google on GDP or in France discussion so
I just want to come back to you though
cuz I think your system actually helps
people comply by automating it literally
by using the legal form so you're kind
of combining those two do you want to
talk a little bit about that yeah sure I
mean you know just as you were stating
about you know the different countries
to have different laws or they're just
coming online or becoming aware and
educated just in the state of California
alone it's like that it's like the whole
world are all worlds policies in one
state so as we go from city to county to
the state level it's all different just
like you go throughout the United States
it's all different so we've had to find
a way to kind of jump that based on best
practices we know that the FDA is gonna
step in eventually just like you have
you should always be focused on good
manufacturing practices or good business
practices that's a very important factor
when you're coming in and exporting to
the EU as well because if you're not
compliant then you're not going to be
able to serve that market I think that
uh when it comes down to it when it
comes down to technology let me ask for
a quick how many people in this room
right now are in a start-up mode for a
tech company or in a tech company right
now how many people anybody great
awesome so we are not limited as what
I'm saying with technology you can
license that technology you can take
that technology to other countries
you're not limited like cannabis is
limited and for the fact that we are you
know a technology firm or able to
actually serve more markets than our
counterparts who are in the cannabis
industry trying to get license to sell
cannabis and that's that's the the thing
that we always need to compare that to
in my opinion you said license the
technology to others is AWS right AWS
started as an internal solution for
Amazon because they couldn't find
something that met their needs and now
it grew to a ten billion dollar a year
business because they every who here
doesn't you or uses AWS in their
business right so
I think so I think we can all agree
right that in some ways technology is
revolutionizing the industry because
it's normalizing it it's saying this is
just a commodity or it's such our soap
but as a way of a lead-in I saw a lot of
hands go up there are a lot of people in
startups and we would like to now open
the you know the field for questions so
if you have questions please go ahead
and bounce them back to us because one
of the things we were talking about
before we came on here is I think I'm
one of the few people actually who's
gone through the German incue bation
system there are opportunities if you
are starting to look at applying
technology and want to apply technology
in this revolutionary business where you
can start to enter the market in new and
different ways in part by normalizing
that in part by saying I'm not just
dealing with cannabis as this crazy
plant I'm dealing with a narcotic that
has to be that's an off-label drug that
has to be approved or etc or I have to
track plant for debt data so I think how
would you say that and and you're gonna
I'm gonna pick on you again how would
you say that technology has changed the
equation in terms of normalization if
that makes anything for example you have
to get you have to go through insurance
approvals there's a medical equipment
provider you're the only person on stage
has to go through that so technology is
also adding a different level of
compliance to you as well is that
revolutionary to you for example yeah as
a medical device manufacturer of course
there are out there are a lot of medical
devices so it's not so important if it
is for cannabis or for something else
you need to follow the medical device
rules and they are there and if you
comply you comply and there's no reason
then to decline any allowance to it on
the insurance idea we have tried to get
here in Germany
generate recovers to get on there is a
list hits metallicity ever you can get
on then you get a tender doctor can
prescribe it and the patient get it
reimbursed but unfortunately we have not
reached to get on this list yet there
are still too many hurdles and they are
still unsure and they fear that they are
get a lot of prescription for it but on
there we are working for and hopefully
soon we will we will have to yeah and at
least we can work together on that
question so any of it I think for
example
you for example are actually in a
licensing and processing approval
discussion correct yes correct I mean
you know essentially again it comes back
to their regulations at the state level
in the US in this case in in Germany or
other areas if they were to do licensing
it would be I think that obviously the
government levels so we what we do is we
sort of analyze when when regulations
come out you know regulations are
shifting and changing theirs is dynamic
compliance I like to call it really
because everything this whole space is
very dynamic so when it comes down to it
we have to really navigate these
processes but if we can accelerate it
and lower the barrier of entry and put
you know promote more diversity and
bring more players into this game you
know and really get it to the point
where folks can really innovate we are
gonna see a hyper jump in that space in
terms of technology in terms of how you
know folks actually operate and so we
want to ensure that first that you guys
get permitted and regulated and
regulated and licensed and then there's
ongoing compliance partners that handle
everything else because everybody's
focused on that section as opposed to
the pre licensed section so that's where
our focus is but again coming back to
technology and how it's changing the
face of the landscape there's things
like the Internet of Things for instance
IOT where we're seeing IOT manage like
how the plants growing you know check
you just know there's like full
automation on this right and so as a
business owner that's trying to scale
and serve a high demand in this
marketplace things like that are pretty
important I mean it lowers the the cost
associated with it we're able to really
magnify the ability to grow this plant
exactly the same way over and over again
which is consistency so we have a
fracture supply chain now on the global
level but you know just the base of the
US or just based on the state of
California it's still a fractured supply
chain so we're not able to get the same
consistency of products because
businesses are scaling and this is a
plant that changes it's it's you know
it's consistency over the course of time
as you scale it or add nutrients or add
different lighting
all right different management
techniques on the planet so it's really
interesting to see how technology
shaping that but most importantly is
that just innovation is gonna this isn't
never stop it's gonna happen over
and over again just like with the
internet when it first came out so I
like to compare to that because that's
how fast this thing is moving right and
so I would HIGHLY highly recommend
taking advantage of that absolutely so
so I'm gonna throw this out is there
anybody with questions right now who
wants to ask the panel anything where
can we keep going
okay I'm sorry do you know I think you
had a specific issue that you wanted to
bring up in terms of I think that you
were sort of talking about the fact that
two toward take it to the next level
that of all of us in some ways from a
technology panel or technology solution
but just I just generally lessons
learned right come in contact Lee coming
coming coming with it from a platform
that already works in other industries
and coming into the cannabis space into
North America first of all the
international space has a
once-in-a-lifetime opportunity to set
their business up from the ground up not
only because cannabis is new but the
businesses are new and setting it up the
right way with technology and making
some of the right decisions most most US
companies that are in the space have
probably gone through two three four
different iterations of solutions
whatever they tried in the beginning
didn't work they're now on to you know
multiple others and and from our
standpoint this is where we're now
coming in from the outside saying you're
in agriculture you grow in greenhouses
people have been growing in greenhouses
for decades hundreds of years and
there's already software out there that
does that for you so why are you trying
to apply brand new software to something
that's already established out there so
we're kind of coming at it from a
different way saying you're in supply
chain management that does agriculture
that does food process manufacturing
distribution and potentially retail so
for us we're not looking at it having to
introduce something brand new because
the space requires it we're trying to
normalize it by saying it already exists
out there don't go make the same
mistakes that the others did where
you're buying software from the ground
up that isn't proven anywhere yet but
just trying to find itself in the
cannabis base because it's going to get
out scaled as you normalize the business
out there all those other things start
to hit you the normal business processes
that every other business runs in and
the end you're you're here to make money
on these businesses it's not just about
you're in the cannabis industry and what
software will work for that well see and
and and this is where I'm hoping to
introduce a little bit of
you know controversy here so you know
obviously your bed pays using a new
technology called blockchain right and
how do you integrate that into a new
industry while minimizing risks and
attacking the issues that you're
attacking well one of the ways that
we've decided to go forward on this is
actually blending this so we're holding
workshops where we're bringing
stakeholders together who aren't
necessarily tech geeks but they're
business people with problems and
they're coming together and they're
discussing them and that is how we're
starting to I think also start to pin
new technology processes and
re-engineering into a new business which
it very much is here as much as we are
I guess re-engineering processes so I
think that this for us the Cannabis of
vertical has given us a way to address a
larger problem that is faced for example
by the chronically ill people who need
to get expensive medical equipment
pharmacies people who are touching this
ecosystem but didn't necessarily have
another way to touch it but but I'm
gonna throw something also up here
because everyone's talking about this
the whole enabling ash aspect or not
enabling aspect especially when you
throw in privacy and all the other
issues about online sales right because
online discussion about this industry I
think has very much lead to greater
legalization as much as governments have
not maybe gotten the regulation right so
far but clearly I think the online
discussion and Technology does lead to
online sales would any what do you like
to take a and dive into that as and also
from the enabling and also the privacy
perspective
yeah I can talk about the online aspect
of it I mean it the at the end of the
day that's where the industry or all
businesses are going to write because as
humans we are lazy we want the path of
least resistance so if I'm able to sit
at home and if we look at the full stack
of the cannabis industry if I'm able to
get a prescription without leaving my
house and then buy a volcano without
leaving my house and have it delivered I
will likely prefer it over having to
leave get in my car drive through snow
see a doctor and go to a pharmacy pick
up the product etc so from in regards to
ecommerce right obviously I'm quite
biased so I can continue talking about
that aspect for for a while but it is
something that is driving this industry
forward well let me let me be a devil
advocate is it isn't ecommerce or is it
telemedicine I mean I think that there
are two aspects of this is the
telemedicine there's the e-commerce
there's the do people feel comfortable
not seeing a doctor our regulatory
agencies in particular when you get into
the narcotics side of this is gonna say
yeah the years of schedule to you and
you don't have to come and see a doctor
anymore is that realistic Germany you're
gonna today I read that you can get then
you can get online to a doctor and you
can claim to be ill for your business
and yeah this is a new system who is
available to you but it's very
controversial the doctor doesn't get
paid yet by the way there's some issues
yeah maybe and as a general remark about
compliance because it was here about
fearing compliance or I I think it's
very important to be compliant that
saying I think every managing director
CEO must take care to be compliance and
especially in this field because on the
one hand you don't want to get extra
hurdles because you are treating
something with cannabis but on the
younger on the other hand you order do
not want to get to be very favorite
because it's gonna have a sensing you
can you don't need to be compliant
because it's cannabis both sites you
don't want to see you want to see you
don't want to get extra hurdles but you
also want not to get any easy way on
some angle let's move your bit being on
the compliance because I think
technology can also you be used for
research right and and sort of the big
data data gathering aspects I think of
basically all of what we've decided I
mean I think what's interesting about
you guys is you're moving I mean more
and more into a world where you can
gather information online for example
through the bait I was soon right I
don't want to say but but regardless I
mean there's there's definitely this
whole discussion now about digital
health in the cloud and privacy issues
how would you I don't it touch on that
one yeah we we actually built let's some
were the problem right the problem is
that a lot of people use cannabis but
there is no way for them to actually
measure if it's helping
them or not so there are not a lot but
quite a few companies that build
solutions to address that we are one of
them there's a great company that that
is out here today
strain print that does the same thing
and essentially allows people to track
usage and the impact of products on
their symptoms and initially at least
that's when we release this we're like
no one's ever gonna give us any data and
we were very surprised to see that
actually people were very forthcoming
they weren't Germans that were they
right no there might be driven right but
the people who have very very
forthcoming with the data because there
was a lot of value that was created in
exchange for that date too so that's
something that is is actually moving
forward in the idea of being able to
collect real data from real people and
analyze it and generate insights has
value across the entire list you want
for patients for example or able to
recommend what strains are right or
wrong for them for the industry were
able to help growers understand what's
popular what they need to grow because
of growth cycles for device
manufacturers they can understand what
temperature's people are using is it
conduction convection based what are the
most popular models etc there is so many
different elements that can be used that
are valuable for both parts of the
industry so it's something SOLAS we're
training abilities so hands up how many
people involved here in the startup side
are using technology in education hands
up how many how many are using it in
compliance how many are using it for
medical processing okay anybody else who
wants to speak up I mean we really are
trying to encourage technology companies
to come forward and talk about their
experiences because we can all learn
from each other I mean I will say that
my experience here has been actually to
sort of use some of the stigma around
this plant to actually get people to
agree to start to use new technology for
example I mean if people agree Lea this
narcotic and yes we need to track it and
no we can't really do this because gdpr
says we can't follow this etc I think
that that does also create a new
opportunity to apply new technology in a
new way to fix problems that are
affecting this industry as it normalizes
and potentially other pieces of a larger
vertical have any of you had experiences
without that you would like to talk to
actually I'd like to have come back to
you you know what you stated about how
there's nothing new here guys I mean
like at the end of the day the tech
there's technology out there it's not
about reinventing the wheel it's about
making that wheel way much better way
better than what it is because here's
the thing like the technology we
developed it was really kind of out of
multiple different pieces we took the
best of several different pieces of
technology they worked in our field and
infused it together into something
that's brand spanking new right and the
same thing goes for a lot of these
different factors it's like you don't
need to create anything new even unless
it's something that has to be created
new so encourage you guys to look out
there and see and do a lot of research
because before you spend all this money
or your investors money for that matter
on a lot of different things that you
that is already existing just do a lot
of research first because there's a lot
of things out there that already serve
that purpose we were seeing a merge of
all these different industries merged
into the cannabis industry from all
different fields that includes you know
medicine that includes technology that
includes agriculture that includes
retail that includes supply chain
tracking that includes all different
logistics and transportation I mean
there's so many different things happen
globally that you're just gonna take
from all those different industries and
then apply your own kind of sort of
style to it right and I also want to you
know real quickly you know talk talk
about this hotel medicine aspect of this
or just working with patients and
gathering that data you know I have a
friend of mine his name's dr. Len May
he's based on Los Angeles if he runs a
company called endo Canon Health now
what endo Kennett health does is they
take your 23andme data and translate it
the information into what you need for
you what would work best for you in
terms of cannabis products right what
would work worse for you in terms of
causing stress or anxiety or different
things like that really really cool
technology but this way you're able to
get highly targeted patient data that's
that's that's really amazing and so you
know exactly what works for you because
what will work for one person may not
work for the other person right
so it's really important to see that
it's pretty incredible and I'm gonna
jump into here I said so the difference
in privacy the approach to privacy from
a technology perspective is a very very
different depending on where you are I
mean if you're in California home of
Google and we don't care about privacy
and I'm gonna say that because they've
just gotten a suit here and you're in in
France they don't and I you know I think
that there is a wide opportunity here
but I think that that is one of the
issues that we see is that privacy and
the understanding of what privacy is
aware that data can go and who can have
access to that and why is a discussion
that I think the cannabis industry in
general and patients and doctors should
step up on I mean weird we're in that
space we don't believe that private
companies should have as much
information about people as they do and
we see gdpr to your point I think as a
way of setting a much higher standard
where patients actually have control
what they don't and that in itself is
something that we can enable with the
use of technology
while giving industry more information
that they ever possibly could have hoped
for but it is completely anonymized
because of the way that we approach it
so maybe that is one of the ways to talk
maybe we can talk about a bit about
privacy because I think this is a huge
huge discussion that is not often talked
about because people a gdpr doesn't
matter it doesn't affect my business in
in Germany or in Europe right now at GDP
our violation 1 GDP our violation they
continue 4% of global sales so if you
think about just the cannabis
perspective of this beyond the fact that
private sea as a medical discussion
should be baked in tin all of us this
particularly can hurt a company has
small medical sales here in Germany but
a global footprint for example so how do
you think that and I'm gonna I think
maybe in this a little bit early because
I want to speed things up and make sure
this conference moves on but how do you
see technology influencing the privacy
conversation and I would say if you want
to add in the cannabis industry fine but
I think that technology can be used to
highlight that so for example you're
gonna you know are you making plans to
give people their own personal cloud
access for example or
you know in your industry are you
thinking about the fact that yeah I've
got a you know these are their privacy
aspects on the on the on the b2b side
that maybe we haven't thought about I
mean I think that is from my perspective
meaning that is where I spend a lot of
my time thinking and planning and
working but I don't know I'm just jump
in there because I mean what you just
said is so complex depending on where
you are so we conduct business in the US
there's over 30 states that we're having
to deal with if you know we deal with
Canada we the data that we take from our
customers is not our data it's that we
put it into Azure it's your environment
in our model so the data is yours we
just have to help you manage it and in
Canada the data has to stay inside of
Canada so you've to technology company
we have to put platforms up everywhere
that comply to that requirement that
really has nothing to do with cannabis
has more to do with with the data side
of it so privacy relates to the consumer
but it also relates to your data
everybody's coming to us looking for
aggregated data on your business not
just from what you're selling to
patients but you know what products are
selling it every other industry has
aggregated data that they're looking at
if you if you come from the hotel
industry every Hotel knows how busy this
hotel was last night what the occupancy
was here as it compares to everybody
else and what the average room rate was
and this industry needs to know the same
thing what products should I be selling
how much how much does it cost me to
produce that product how can it be more
efficient and you have to share the
aggregated data as a community so that
we we can all get better at it so then
then there's the privacy of that
information so we we don't give that
data out that has to be you guys
providing that data amongst yourselves
and then a community setting itself up
with that aggregated data gets used okay
so I think we're being signaled from the
side here that we're running out of time
last call for any questions you can
catch us later there is good hi sulla
Frank cleaver botanics conversation is
very interesting because we launched our
online shop in UK but the plan was to
produce two apps one for Android one for
iOS and connect the Shopify into the app
so when we sell a product
we want to capture the information from
the customer how they used it and how it
can help for us to choose the next next
product but the GDP odd thing you talked
about is very interesting because we
already starting to sell not just in UK
or Germany in France and how do we sort
of manage that is a thing that I have no
idea I wonder do you have any come talk
to us later but yeah I think okay the
rule is privacy by default or privacy by
design so you have the tracking you have
needs to be disabled but you are able to
ask your client that he shares the
information with you it's still possible
you just need to say why you want
wanting the data and be collected what
kind of Tidy I want to collect it and
you need to ask for permission and you
can do the same thing patients can ask
for it back - that's the other thing so
it is complex yeah it's it's GPR sounds
scary but it's quite simple as long as
you give consent and there is a reason
for you to have that consent which
sounds like you want to provide better
service your customers just build your
privacy policy in a way that gets that
consent and then you can do pretty much
whatever you want as long as you define
yourself as the data controller in that
matter short answer is complicated
any other questions and see us later - I
have a quick question when you talk
about AI and all these things how do you
deal with implicit biases or the
challenges you have of gathering quality
information because you can make the
smartest machine but if you tell it dumb
[ __ ] it's gonna be a dumb [ __ ] good
question like you know garbage in
garbage out I think that's right that's
the same basic right
the expert evidence in the Vancouver
dispensary case was that patients want
to see the product smell the product
like going to the grocery store and
buying your groceries so how do you deal
with that
you have a license to sell online Canada
only allows that I think you in Shoppers
Drug Mart the only ones who have it
medical patients only get it in the mail
and they complain that it's in the
container they have to open it up
sometimes there's some problem with it
they send it back so it delays them
getting there
medicine so that the evidence from the
patients and an expert doctors of burkas
from the states was that this was a very
important part of delivering medical for
medical patients so I'm not sure if the
drone can come and drop down and give an
option and go back up and you can pick
or how you're gonna deal with that
technological well especially in it I'm
sorry but in Germany actually that's
illegal so you have to go to the
pharmacy and the medical I guess culture
here I mean the output takers are
trained to actually mean that's why they
want patients to go to the pharmacy to
literally have the pharmacist who is
trained in this handover that drug but
to your point there may be regulatory
issues that say you can't do it as
you're doing in Canada which affects
other signaling seized a sale for
example but then you're gonna also in in
terms of access issues if you're too
sick to get to the pharmacy but those
are places where technology can in fact
begin to start to connect them but as we
find privacy issues all are all the way
along this because it's not just a
product that you can buy like a regular
commodity product this is still
stigmatized so privacy is in the room at
every single point actually I think it's
gonna be based on preference I mean if
you prefer to have a dropship to your
front door than okay but that'll never
replace the retail experience are you
going in there and smelling different
things the only thing it will do is
enhance it right and so we're seeing
enhancement of that retail experience so
in Vancouver is a lot different than
Germany and that's the evolution from
medical to rec that we're seeing as well
right if you're coming from a North
American perspective you're already
going well isn't it just like alcohol
and why can't you buy it and consume it
like you do alcohol and the
internationally was true it's still
talking about it medically and what is
it you know is it a medicine is it you
pick it up in a pharmacy can you get it
online so I think if you look forward a
few years you're gonna see that same
change happen that's happening in North
America as it tries to embrace it in a
recreational adult use way and have a
retail experience around it yeah you
know what said you about Canada I'm
sorry to drive you but in Canada it
seems like the privacy aspect was not
really brought up until it went into the
recreational market which is an
interesting twist I thought anyway but
but that question in regards to
brick-and-mortar versus ecommerce is
we shouldn't even be talking about it
right it's the same question that was 30
years ago in regards to of 20 years ago
in regards to e-commerce in general and
now you see ecommerce growing endlessly
and malls in the u.s. nothing to do with
privacy was talking about the consumer
experience of choosing a product without
being able to touch smell and understand
it and that's a classic question of you
know weed is different and we're gonna
go a little long because I'm getting
passionate now weed is different than
lumber or a blender right you don't have
to smell a blender you don't need to
look at the crystals on a blender right
you want to smell your weed you want to
look at it you maybe want to talk to the
person about the genetics and you want
to know something about the grower and
how it was grown and different always
get that experience
no but that's immature and that's the
maturity of the industry right because
right now I think that's because
inconsistent product might be coming
through and you can't get the same
experiences it's not you can give five
different growers the same cut and come
up with five different styles and five
different smells of five different
effects all from the same weed so it's
really hard to you can get another why
make a or a double Bock or whatever it's
very hard to get different to make sure
people are consistent the blue dream
from one person is different than blue
dream from another person and it's you
and here's the other thing right so I
mean I know that this discussion is
saying there's no Pratt were fewer
privacy discussions in e-commerce but
there are actually a lot it is there a
question there was another question I
think what time is it though because
we're running super late