so we're gonna be talking about
regulations today if you if you're
familiar with Vancouver you'll know that
it's a bit of a maybe a word I can't use
on stage it's a bit of a mess in terms
of regulations and it's a good thing
we've got John here to help us go over
that so John I'm gonna kick it off by
asking you what is the legislative
framework and role of the provinces
local governments and other bodies such
as the BC Agricultural Land Commission
since legalization in October 2018 thank
you I think we have 23 different
countries here so it's we thought it
would be useful to sort of give you the
different framework that exists in
Canada but after listening to Laurie I'm
reminded of the family motto which is
history cannot be denied and we
obviously have history repeating itself
just as what happened with alcohol the
bottom line being local governments are
the the problem that you have to
overcome in order to get the the market
to really take off anyway in Canada
criminal law is a federal power unlike
the US and so that explains a bit of a
difference why you've got all your
states now making it legal historically
you had all your state's making it
illegal before your federal government
and now it's unwinding so the criminal
law power is federal and what we've done
here is we have legalized a little bit
we have decriminalized a little bit with
a ticketing scheme that kicks in after
the legal part and we have kept in an
awful lot of criminal law so the
cannabis Act and the cannabis
regulations are still criminal law the
federal government says it's still using
the criminal law and it has allowed the
provinces to be involved in distribution
so production various rules to do with
promotion and advertising and all of
that as as was mentioned earlier taken
from the tobacco industry is controlled
federally
the province now controls distribution
and so that's the dispensaries and as
you may know from a certain case where
her lady allowed the people to come to a
garden party the police three plants in
public view was in realistic rate that's
right you're not allowed to do that so
but then you've got local government and
so not only towns cities municipalities
of course zoning licensing all of these
sorts of things but also we have the
agricultural land commission for example
which is a provincial body that recently
said we don't want to be involved in
applications for people wanting to grow
cannabis any more it's a designated farm
use if you're in the negra cultural area
so we're going to pass to the local
governments the power to decide various
questions about whether you can do what
you want to do because now you can only
grow in soil for example since last July
if you've got a building in the
agricultural land reserve already fine
you can produce inside that building but
if you don't you can only do it in soil
and so greenhouses are going to be the
way that people will be able to do it so
then you'll have a place like Richmond
BC where the airport is which will say
we're very jealous about our industrial
uses so you can't do it in an industrial
area you have to do it in an
agricultural area so you have all of
these conflicting positions being taken
by either different bodies or local
governments and to do whatever you want
to do in the cannabis scene you're going
to have to a give notice to local
governments and get their permission or
approval or support so just like in the
old alcohol days we have wet areas and
we have dry areas and it's going to take
some time in order to get them to move
along in Abbotsford where I am there
and where I live in mission it's like a
wait-and-see even though we've had
people involved in the industry in and
around the area for an awful long time
so that's the basic framework I could
obviously get into a lot more detail but
well thanks for explaining that John you
know given given all of that I imagine
and I know for a fact you know British
Columbia Vancouver in particular has
been a pretty important place when it
comes to recognizing you know medical
need for cannabis so my next question is
for dorri dorri in what ways has
legalization impacted your medical
customers it should be on already I
think at the dispensary you managed
downtown well the customers are being
largely ignored by the government
program while they take this
wait-and-see attitude and they'll review
it in a few years because so many stores
have been closed down in such quick ways
without any contingency plans whatsoever
they're getting to meet a lot more sick
people while they wait in line for their
medicine which is a problem for sick
people because one of the reasons we
wanted so many dispensaries open was so
that people would be able to get quickly
served and have time with their their
dispenser and that's being taken away
from them they are being told that they
can just get their needs met at a legal
store and yet if we ask Andrew what's
allowed on his shelf today compared to
what was allowed or what he had on his
shelves before it would be largely
different and people's needs aren't
being that they're not able to get the
lotions and creams in the manner that
they got them before and
and the prices are not affordable for
the kind of people that I serve in my
dispensary Andrews not allowed to have a
dispensary so don't call it that it's a
it's a a you know a cannabis retail
outlet though dispensing goes on behind
those doors it's not allowed to be
called that
so there's no compassion allowed to be
you know though they have it in their
hearts they're not allowed to serve it
in their store and and that's that's the
part that that people are fearing for
right now is who's going to take care of
them where are they going to be able to
go and get the cookies and the lotion
and a little bit of love that they're
looking for every day because it's not
just about weed on the shelves it's
about love and caring that also happens
with these people while they're getting
their medicine so thanks story 100% so
Gordon or Andrew part of me Andrew
you're on the other side of things and
I'd like to know yeah I have haven't
gone through the transition and
receiving your license to operate in
Vancouver what are some of the
opportunities you see for chiaro and
other legal retailers in British
Columbia yeah thank you thank you and
everyone this morning you know
opportunity abounds we're really at the
ground level here and we can really go
up from here I mean if you're watching
the numbers at all
you know British Columbia with 19
million dollars in sales since
legalization is a figure that should
really draw a lot of attention to really
the issue at hand here
you know Dorie speaks to you know well
established an entrenched medical market
here that has expectations and needs and
you know the current regime isn't
serving those needs we're in a period of
transition we have to acknowledge that
as well you know it takes patience and
perseverance and sacrifice to move
through this transition area fees I
think about it as myself as a medical
patient and the situation people are put
in and you know I have pts
see and I'm I recall just serving so
many people that you know had conditions
and illnesses where this was their only
option so my heart goes out to them I I
am encouraged every day though by the
amazing people not only in this room but
in our community and and around the
world that are pushing hard for cannabis
you know we owe it to them to get this
right and I'm incredibly encouraged by
the fact that we have done it before and
we will do it again
and I brought I was you know thinking
about this question Amanda and I brought
a poem by Richard Kipling called if and
I'm just gonna read a small segment of
it and I find it incredibly inspiring
because this is so poignant to where we
are today if you can keep your head
about you if you can keep your head when
all about you are losing theirs and
blaming it on you if you can trust
yourself when all men doubt you but make
allowance for their doubting too if you
can wait and not be tired of waiting or
being lied about and don't deal in lies
or being hated don't give way to hating
and yet don't look too good nor talk too
wise if you can dream and not make
dreams your master if you can think and
not make thoughts your aim if you can
meet with triumph and disaster and treat
with those two Impostors just the same
and this is an important line here and
this is what really struck me to share
this today is if you can bear to hear
the truth you've spoken twisted by
knaves to make traps for fools or watch
the things you gave your life to broken
and stoop down and build them up with
worn-out tools and I think about that
then I think about dory I think about
John and I think about the patients in
this community that I can't have that
conversation with anymore and it hurts a
lot every day and I talk to our retail
staff about this and I go you know we're
still empowered we can still be
inspiring we can still connect with
people provide solutions you know Adam
Green black came up with this great line
of the last lift conference he talked
about creative compliance and that's
what I'm pushing towards at chiaro and
that's what I'm pushing towards in my
work with akers the association of
Canadian cannabis retailers
reuniting we're invigorating we're we're
bringing this this train home again and
it's gonna take some time it's not
perfect this is a process and it sucks
most of the time to be frank with you
you know to see what you've built broken
and have to stoop down to stoop after
all we've built and sacrificed and
proven right that is probably the most
tragic part of it all but again I'll
incredibly encourage we've done it
before
we can do it again we're gonna continue
to do it you know we're building strong
relationships with our supply chain that
are gonna be responsive to this need
we're holding the government accountable
we're continuing to advocate this
message isn't being lost for those of us
who have transitioned I know they're
working hard you know again extensively
they can't always share all the
information they want to but the power
of anecdote the power of research the
greatest victim of prohibition is now
coming to light you know the power of
this room I'm incredibly encouraged so
thank you so much for your honesty and
for that I might need a second so my
next question is for John John can you
tell us about a specific appeal in
Vancouver involving Karuna health some
people in the room might know the name
and the way that dispensary sort of fits
it to Vancouver bylaws how does this
intersect with the constitutional
question of reasonable access for
medical patients well I should have
mentioned in the opening the federal
government has kept control over medical
and so while health constitutionally is
a divided field between the feds and the
provinces they've kept control so we I
incorporated the BC compassion Club
Society I was 1997 so more than 20 years
ago they had rave reviews from all of
the task force's and everybody that's
ever looked into it and holding it up as
a good model and then of course the
federal government came along it didn't
provide for Medical dispensaries in the
cannabis act or regulations and so there
is going to be another court case
that seeks to declare that a genuine
Medical dispensaries compassion clubs
are part of reasonable access you should
understand that here in Canada the
Constitution provides in Section seven
that you have the right to life liberty
and the security of your person and the
right not to be deprived thereof except
in accordance with something called the
principles of fundamental justice and
the court first way way back in 2001 the
Ontario Court of Appeal and more
recently the federal court trial
division and a lard confirmed that the
federal government has to provide
medical exemptions for medically
approved patients to prevent the
violation of the security of their
person having established that what they
did in the past was to do that
arbitrarily which is country to
principles of fundamental justice so
constitutional rights are involved when
it comes to medical so the city of
Vancouver
much to its credit passed by laws to
enable Medical dispensaries among others
and but some of them weren't able to
meet the rules such as being 300 metres
from the nearest school thing another
compassion club or dispensary these
sorts of rules and so ultimately an
injunction was brought to shut them down
so again I credit the City of Vancouver
for unlike Toronto using the police
right at the outset to shut everybody
down and using the civil process here
instead of the police to have the issues
resolved in a civil manner but in any
event these were the the ones that
couldn't meet the requirements of the
bylaws called themselves Medical
dispensaries and interestingly the
government didn't challenge that so it
went to court and we counter petitioned
to say that they were part of reasonable
access and we had a patient we had a
patient running a club we got standing
we did the full argument and everything
and then
the judge decided not to decide the
constitutional question which we're
appealing and the appeal is set for
sometime in November I believe but
basically the court ruled that the
bylaws were valid and that these folks
had to comply with the bylaws and that
heaves it would be unwise is the way he
put it to decide the constitutional
question so there is a better way to to
handle that issue and that's going to be
another application in the federal court
trial division to seek that type of a
declaration and you've probably heard
something similar is going to occur with
respect to these limitations in terms of
ten milligrams and the edibles and the
extracts and so on because you know that
medical patients in Canada since the
Smith case had to saw is here somewhere
was the main council established that
medical patients are entitled to possess
cannabis in any of its forms they're not
limited to dried cannabis but they have
to make it themselves and so again many
of them have been waiting for these
dispensaries to be able to provide them
with high-end extracts and so on that
they require for their medical condition
but the government in its
shortsightedness is worried about novice
users consuming too much or accidentally
taking too much as opposed to giving
priority to prevent the violation of the
constitutional rights of medical
patients to ensure that they get what
they need in order to in some cases
survive and so basically the Karuna
appeal is there I'm not optimistic that
the court of appeal is necessarily going
to grab the issue so we're probably
going to have to relitigate it in
federal court along with the extracts
issue thanks John that's a really nice
way to segue into my next question for
dory so some of you in the audience may
know that on October 17th of this year
regulations in Canada are going to
change so that we can have edibles
extracts and topicals
run into the mix so Dori
given those new regulations how do you
foresee them you know you know the the
regulations on the recreational market
part of me impacting medical users and
consumers overall I see you're
unwrapping some goodies over there for
us well I am I understand that
everybody's use of cannabis is different
and everybody has different needs I also
understand that we all learn in a
different way too and so I wanted to do
something that was just a little bit
visual to help you understand this
concept so I'm going to make the case
for and against ten milligram cookies so
if we have all of our cookies have to be
10 milligrams and I need 200 milligrams
this is how many cookies I'm going to
need to eat at once that's a lot of
cookies say this is 2300 calories in
cookies they're 130 calories each
where's the room for broccoli if we're
just eating cookies like this so the
issues that I see are all this excess
packaging we already know that that's an
issue I see obesity diabetes and a host
of other medical problems that go along
with expecting people to eat all this
sugar chocolate flour all the other
ingredients that go along with this too
to get somebody up to a 200 milligram
dose so I said I would make a foreign
against if all of our cookies were 200
milligrams and we have the lightweights
we would need to be serving pieces of
cookie
this is one cookie cut up into 20 pieces
this morning this can be satisfying for
somebody that's on a diet and only needs
the 10 milligrams but it's not it's just
not a reasonable way to have people pack
their cookies around so it's okay to
have a 10 milligram cookie clearly
labeled but I think it's okay to have a
200 milligram cookie clearly labeled
just like a 500 milligram cookie clearly
labeled so I I hope that before October
17th comes along that people start to
really contemplate what this 10
milligram dosage is gonna cause because
this isn't just a medicinal problem this
is a recreational problem as well some
people five milligrams they only need
this and they're going to be high all
day long
some people would need to eat five times
that in a day to even start to feel it
so let's not cause another health
problem while we're trying to save
people from cannabis for that
show-and-tell it's very effective my
next question is for Andrew obviously
you know consumers in Vancouver we're
pretty spoiled and you know we're used
to being able to access a wide variety
of strains of products
how can regulated retailers compete
against the entrenched market in
Vancouver yeah that's a it's a great an
important question the short answer is
we can't flat out they have better
quality better variety they have a
consumer base that knows who they are
our [ __ ] waited in that transaction
process so you know I'm not trying to
compete against the illicit market you
know that's a that's a natural
progression that'll happen over time
when you start you know looking at some
of the established markets in the States
this takes five seven years to start to
see that erosion and
to happen through transition and it has
to happen through integration so that's
what I try and focus on as a retailer
I want that market in our market
providing products and building
solutions and helping with the dialogue
and moving the needle on key social
issues because they've been doing it the
longest and if we don't get that
intellectual talent and that human
capital into the cannabis pool in the
regulated environment then it's gonna be
a pretty insipid pool and it's not gonna
be you know meeting the needs of
consumers so I don't try and compete
against that I try and integrate I serve
as a director of acres and and we really
work to advocate and lobby government on
important issues to help integrate the
legacy market into the regulated
environment and that is a vital mission
that over the next three to five years
is going to take a concerted effort of
all of us in this room and all of us in
this country and community to really
push for because you know these people
helped build the opportunity we have and
if we're not responsive to that a just
because you know we need the talent and
B because it's really owed if you know
through this process of legalization to
help get people through and you know as
someone who has transitioned
successfully you know I want to use that
open door to to bring others with me and
to really build positive and purpose
purpose momentum behind that you know
there are larger existential threats in
our industry and I would say and I know
the government you know is working hard
and I have empathy for regulators but
you know the BC LDB is actually more on
my radar for competition than the
illicit market is to be honest with you
they don't have a cap on the number of
stores that they can have in British
Columbia they can pay their frontline
staff $30 an hour they can do revenue
sharing with communities those are
distinctive advantages that if you're a
community that's sitting on the fence
about cannabis I mean that's a much
safer more ostensibly stable option to
choose from and we're seeing that
starting to happen in communities across
the GBR d so for me I'm focused on on
those things and on the regulations
themselves I mean you know I try and
compliment Minister farm worth when I
see him about the progression we're
seeing with the LCR be and you know
applications are starting to get through
we got 63 license we got 68 in AIP we
got
300 or more under community review so
those are encouraging numbers were way
behind but we're getting there but
window opacity I mean this is for me
like almost issue number one you look at
D stigmatizing and naturalizing and
integrating cannabis into the social
context in a meaningful way
having opaque windows is not achieving
that at all and you know I look at you
know operators you know Jeff at Muse
people were walking by didn't even know
he was open that's tragic when you look
at the amount of investment and
infrastructure and training that goes
into building a regulated retail store
in Canada it's a tremendously daunting
experience so you know again for me I'm
looking at the BC LD be actually more
than I'm looking at the illicit market
it factors in obviously when you look at
you know online there's a big big market
there and you know we operate in two
provinces and Saskatchewan we have shops
in Saskatoon and in l'orange and an
online sales there are pretty dismal and
that's the kind of you know word on the
street with most of the operators
because again everyone's getting what
they need online they're getting the
topicals they're getting the edibles
things they really really want and need
I'm excited about the Phase two products
coming in because that's gonna make a
big shift create a big opportunity for
the regulated retailers to help meet
some of that market need and help that
market transition over I'm concerned
that it's gonna be the same dynamic out
the gate that it was with flour and oil
where it's not gonna be great out the
gate it's gonna be a lot of challenges
and an uncertainty on the supply chain
in terms of consistency but you know
we're gonna get there we're gonna keep
pushing keep advocating this is not
perfect it is a process and we have to
keep our stakeholders engaged and
educated on that and so you know we
really work at chiaro to keep that
conversation moving forward in a
positive purposeful direction you know I
don't want to whine and complain
aimlessly we really have to focus on
what our needs are what our goals are
work to build a community and consensus
and cohesion around those and go get it
you know we've done it before we made
legalization happen
I mean I'm incredibly proud of that
being a part of that movement in that
momentum we got a long way to go
it is not perfect people are hurt people
are not getting their medicine and and
there is a huge entrenched market that's
not transitioning because they don't see
the opportunity yet
and so we got to advocate for them keep
you know pushing the needle on making
sure we're reducing those barriers to
entry creating more viable sustainable
business opportunities for them to see
in front of them and you know looking at
the regulated environment right now
that's a big challenge so again we just
got to stay positive and purposeful keep
pushing it and an offer that
personalized service to consumers you
know they'll keep coming back if they
start getting some rapport and
relationship and so we're focused on
really training our staff incredibly
well to build strong relationships at
the counter and that's gonna build the
rapport and the referrals we need to
weather the storm here in the next few
years awesome thank you I really
appreciate that point you made about
competing with the LDB definitely yep
so John another question for you we
touched a little bit on on creative
compliance now with the BC cannabis
control and Licensing Act doesn't apply
to medical cannabis but the definition
of a cannabis store in the Vancouver
bylaw includes a compassion Club what
should the compassion Club and Medical
dispensaries do in Vancouver to prevent
being shut down well as I think was
mentioned earlier the government here
clearly was hoping that medical would
disappear and go into the rec stores and
there wouldn't be any Medical
dispensaries that's clearly what they
intended the City of Vancouver again in
putting its bylaw together created a
category that was a compassion Club and
so while some of the dispensaries have
been it was at 30,000 dollar fee the
compassion clubs only a thousand dollar
fee and they also have a Wellness Center
that goes with it and so on so again
Vancouver was foresight had foresight in
terms of the plan and what everybody
expected the feds would do originally
and provide for Medical dispensaries or
compassion clubs so the community safety
team is the group that is now from
various police agencies going around the
province trying to close people down if
you don't have an application going
through the provincial system for a Rec
license and they were telling
the compassion Club and others that's
what they should do if you've got your
application in it's my understanding
they'll leave you alone as it's going
through the process so bearing in mind
that medical is still controlled by the
feds one of the licenses under the
cannabis Act is a you know got a license
to produce a license to process a
nursery license and so on one of them is
a license for sale and there's a
subclass license that's to sell for
medical purposes so my position has been
and I've taken this up with the
Community Safety Team that the
compassion clubs and true Medical
dispensaries are not recreationally the
provincial act expressly says so that
it's doesn't apply to medical cannabis
so I'm having them apply for a license
to sell for medical purposes and I'm
saying as long as they're in the process
applying for their license to sell for
medical purposes which they've been
doing for the last 20 plus years you
should also be leaving them alone and by
the way if you do go in there and try to
shut them down remember you're going to
be interfering with the constitutional
rights of medically approved patients
and they will have a remedy for the
violation of their constitutional rights
if you do that so be it aware that
you're dealing with a different type of
entity now again the Vancouver bylaw
expressly has a definition of a cannabis
store interestingly enough in the Karuna
case they were trying to say that their
prior definitions simply allowed the
compassion club to be an advocate for
medical as opposed to actually providing
cannabis but the definition of a
cannabis store now in the bylaw clearly
includes a compassion club interestingly
enough and clearly makes it makes it
clear that you can sell cannabis for
in the case of a compassionate love for
medical purposes but we need to get that
federal license first so we do have a
good argument I think here in Vancouver
to try and get the federal license in
order to get the city license as a
cannabis store but as a compassion Club
so that hopefully we'll see that develop
that's again if they turn us down we
will be looking at the courts in order
to try and remedy the situation so it's
always encouraging to hear again from
Laurier Jax what you said about
California and I've heard this from
others how they do prioritize the the
medical in the stores and are able to to
run them both together here
unfortunately they've just left it as
wreck and they haven't made any
provision for the medical and we will
continue to battle away in order to get
this sorted out one way or another
thank goodness for John never diligent
I've got one last question for Andrew
and then we're gonna open it up to
questions from the audience I think you
started to touch on this a little bit at
the end of your last answer but being a
retailer in this new market what are
some ways that retailers can add value
beyond the transaction especially with
such tight regulations yeah and they are
they are definitely tight and daunting
out the gay right now it's really hard
to get you know a message that connects
with consumers out there because you
really can't connect with consumers it
seems but you know again this idea of
creative compliance comes to light you
know we're not gonna play the passive
role in this and just kind of you know
accept the fate here you know we're
gonna create opportunity and you know at
kierra we've been focused on really
building a strong relationship with our
supply partners that's where it starts
I've always been a firm believer that
our first row of customers is our
suppliers and so you know we built an
educational alignment program that's as
vested on four key pillars we look at
the customer education and customer
experience first you know you start
there if you empower people you know you
inspire them they become not just your
customers they come they become your
advocates and they can go out there and
do
work for you in terms of you know
galvanizing regulators and voting with
their wallets and hopefully voting you
know for changes in provincial and
federal regimes that are opposed to you
know what they're trying to pursue and
their vision and values and that
educational component in the store
extends to really again building that
relationship with the supply chain again
you know so many patients and in the
legacy market we're so connected to some
of the suppliers and those stories and
the people and purpose and passion that
help and help build those products and
and and created viable solutions that
actually save people's lives so you know
we're going back and really digging deep
on our supply chain and really creating
that intimacy of exchange and learning
about the people and the processes and
the passion behind each of the products
are on the Shelf you know we don't try
and be a convenience store either I'm
not there to just you know puke products
on people because that's the aim to sell
as much as we can we really have a
curated assortment that really speaks to
the needs state of a well defined
customer demographic and then we really
look to build that narrative with the
customer in terms of explaining how
these products are manufactured and
process and the care and intent that
goes into that and we talk about where
it comes from you know I have the great
privilege of going on tours of some of
these million-dollar facilities and it's
tremendously encouraging to see the
energy and the vibe in them and we I
want to translate that into the retail
experience again talking about the good
work these companies do I had a chance
to go out and visit our friends at seven
acres in Keene Garden Ontario they have
an amazing vibe but their community they
really cultivate you know excellent
craft cannabis and they have a vision
and a purpose that again translates well
in the retail environment they have
great products as well great turf
profile nerf Enid's it's really good
stuff a lot of the time despite a lot of
the challenges with packaging and all
the other stuff that we're all we're all
upset about you know the second pillar
of that which is equally important is
community investment and involvement so
we really look to get out in the
community be proactive again as I
mentioned I serve as a director of acres
I'm out there advocating lobbying
working with regulators and
decision-makers at all levels we can't
stay passive in this we have to keep
engaging you know as elections come and
people change there's a lot of curiosity
we're at that crescendo point the
conversation still
you're in people want to learn about
this you know the the stigma is abating
itself slowly in the eyes of a lot of
municipalities they want to learn about
cannabis they want to hear about the
value of the regulated environment and
how that can help improve public health
and safety and address the the concerns
around the illicit market by providing a
path for transition and really you know
protect the interests of young people I
mean that's those are messages and and
and and metrics that we can actually
deliver as a regulated retailer and then
the third pillar that we really position
ourselves around in terms of creating
value beyond the transaction is staff
education again your frontline staff
right now if you were retailer that is
your lifeline you will live or die by
the relationships they create at the
counter because the product quality not
in all cases but most of them isn't
there yet people don't like the
packaging getting ID'd at the front
sucks you know you're 68 years old
coming in getting ID'd you forgot like
it's absolutely ridiculous sometimes but
you have to take the care you have to
take the consideration you got to build
that conversation you can't take it for
granted we're earning relationships all
over again so we're literally starting
from scratch and and you have to have
that that humble you know stay hungry
attitude in this business because you
cannot rest on your laurels you can
really expect nothing you have to build
it all yourself and you have to do it
with the community around you so I stay
well integrated with all of my retailer
partners as well I go to all their grand
openings spend a ton in their shops if I
can that first day I went out to the
city grant the city cannabis grand
opening on can athon can be an eight
spend 200 bucks just watching that stuff
fly up and down that tube if you've seen
it it's absolutely awesome so I'm
talking about my peers I'm out there and
engaged in a positive light we don't
have time to be covetous and competitive
right now we have to build confidence in
the market again and we did that pre
legalization by sticking together as a
community and we're gonna do that again
and we focused on training our staff to
be able to deliver those messages get
out and be active and informed about you
know what's going on in the environment
and really the lifestyle integration
component is well for a lot of consumers
who are new to this you know how do i
transport this according to the legal
framework how do I store this at home
safely as a parent you know we have
those conversations with our customers
at kiaro and then finally and this is
probably
the most important pillar of it all is
data and information exchange so right
now we're learning again this whole
process over and over again you know
every now with the Phase two products
coming in it's going to be a whole
galaxy of new questions and uncertainty
I'm excited for the challenge of course
because I know it's going to meet the
need of a lot more consumers and give us
an opportunity to buoy our businesses
again and get some more revenue but but
at the end of the day you know we're
really vested in in continuing the
conversations and building understanding
with our supply chain with our local
stakeholders with our MLAs with our MPs
you know with our other fellow operators
and and and again you know everyone in
the community that's contributed so far
I mean you have a place to come and have
a quality exchange at chiaro and we're
incredibly excited to keep stewarding
that in a positive purposeful way thanks
very much
very well said all three of you I'd like
to open it up to questions from the
audience I think we have about five min
about five minutes let's hear it one
more time for the panel that was great
does anyone have a question anyone
Bueller Bueller apparently they were so
informative that you don't have any
questions it's very comprehensive would
be the word here we go good morning
thank you guys so much for your time
closer okay
so I'm from California and if I
understood correctly you mentioned that
you guys are limited to ten milligram
doses per product does that correct as
far as medicinally the proposed
regulations are that you won't be able
to have more than ten milligrams of THC
in an edible in a discrete unit so you
could have a attend
milligram unit or two fives for say next
or inedible but the extract you could
have capsules in in a container again
but it can't exceed ten milligrams of
THC whereas a topical it's up to a gram
with no package size on the topical so I
would say recreationally that's what the
proposed limits going to be medicinal
we don't have a limit on on our doses we
can go to the doctor and arrange with
them the Ahmet the daily amount that we
need and that we can get a
recommendation for that and have a
medical license that allows us to use
more than what a recreational person
would be but because there are no
mechanisms for medicinal patients to get
their medicine other than this what
they're proposing in the new
recreational stores they're saying
medical people just go line up at a
recreational store and all your needs
will be not that and that is not the
truth so if we make our own cookies at
home we can do what we want to with as
far as the dose level goes but if we
need to have somebody else make a cookie
for us a lot of my customers that come
through our people that don't have a
fridge and stove or a mixing bowl to
make a brownian and they rely on us to
have the clean kitchen and the
standardized dose ready for them at a
reasonable price for them to be able to
consume on a daily basis and they
sometimes they don't they don't even
have a cupboard that they can keep a
dozen cookies in for so they have to be
able to come and make a daily purchase
and they can't afford to buy this many
cookies if that was what they were
relegated to right and so I'm very
passionate about the medicinal side of
cannabis and so I'm curious as retail
operations how are you guys getting
innovative and providing solutions or do
you just have no solutions to offer
medicinal patients that come into your
stores yeah I think you know the power
of anecdote when you are so limited in
terms of speaking to the efficacy of
cannabis E or cannabis is important you
know sharing that personal testimony as
much as you can
in a credible and genuine way and again
you know we're really focused on you
know encouraging that as much as
possible within the framework and you
know again the research is out there and
you can point people to that even in a
regulated retail environment you know
again the greatest victim of prohibition
was the research and now that's coming
to light all around the world
you know it's undeniable the proof and
you can point people in that direction
and you can empower them to look at
those resources make up their own mind
make an informed decision and come back
and and choose a solution offering
that's best aligned with that with
what's available in the retail
environment and then we can you know
through events and an engagement outside
of the you know designated for wall
retail environment you know work and
partner with people who are educators on
a whole host of different fronts whether
its medical therapeutic recreational you
know we can participate and and sponsor
and be a part of events like that to
help to help push that conversation
forward to keep that portion of the
community and there's a large number of
them and you know even us as
recreational consumers over the course
of our lives will be impacted by injury
illness and stress we'll have to use
cannabis in different ways as we're
encumbered by that so again the the
power of testimony and anecdote you know
really pointing people towards the
research and then you know helping to
support educators that are out there
talking about cannabis and more than
just a recreational sense that's what we
do to help them empower consumers when
we're so limited right now hi my name is
Shari Bennett I own a company called
let's talk cannabis I work on the front
lines with people in with pain severe
arthritis seizures cancer many of my
clients are seniors who are getting
their cannabis from their grandchildren
and they would like to get it legally
and they're having a constellation of
obstacles I whether one takes cannabis
recreationally or for medicinal reasons
it's it's our bodies don't know the
difference it's medicine cannabis is
medicine
and I want to know that I want to
understand how what would it take to
change the law aren't the courts gonna
be just clogged there must be already
right now because many of us when we
when we understand that every human
being has an endocannabinoid system and
that many diseases are a result of a
deficiency of the endocannabinoid system
this is a topic that affects every human
being right sorry question is like what
do we have to do to change the law to
change the regulations what do we have
to do how many more years will it take
you know well I wouldn't say the courts
are clogged certainly we have I used to
get people calling me every day with
being busted for cannabis I was called
to the bar in 1972 and it went from a
few hundred people being busted a year
to ten thousand mostly for simple
possessions we don't have that anymore
we don't the there's very few people
who've been charged under the cannabis
Act so but what you're talking about is
these constitutional challenges and they
do take a long time we have the national
academy of science engineering and
medicine surveying all of the studies to
do with cannabis throughout the world a
couple of years ago and concluded that
notwithstanding the difficulties in
doing the research there is conclusive
evidence that cannabis is effective for
chronic pain what are the people dying
on the streets from today being
prescribed oxycontin and other types of
opiates becoming addicted and then
getting going to the street when their
doctors cut them off and getting a dose
of fentanyl
we know that cannabis we now have double
blind placebo based gold standard
studies that show that cannabis is one
of the best exit strategy drugs to get
people off opiates so again it's
unfortunate you would think with the
evidence that's available that the
government's would be running to do
something we may have to go to court in
order to come
them again yeah thank you so very much
we're out of time I'm sorry let's hear
once again for the panel that was great
[Applause]