uh all right coming up for our next
panel I left my my program in the thing
there you go looking toward the future
uh of cannabis research here to lead
this discussion is the Chief Operating
Officer of the telman group and a good
friend of mine and he's here for us
right now let's hear it for Justin
[Applause]
TBI uh
all right how's everybody doing today
can you hear me okay excellent excellent
well um we're excited to be here and
talk a little bit with you about
research in cannabis let me introduce
the two uh co-panelists here Ry s do you
want to come on up and uh and then Bo or
Bo we're happy to have you here forgive
me for brutalizing names I'm um happy to
do it there's a couple of mics grab
yourselves a seat could you guys give a
warm round of Applause and a Welcome to
our panelists here thank you
much all right we'll we can do it in
order that works that
works all
right thank
you okay well uh we are in a an
interesting uh period of time I'm sure
you've been uh hearing throughout the
day some of the things that are evolving
and changing in the regulatory framework
with regards to cannabis and uh one of
our sort of guiding principles uh here
with the thean group located here in
Slovenia is that the research in the
world of cannabis has been sort of
limited and biased by the uh the legacy
of our uh prohibition and our regulatory
approach and now as we move into a more
modern and an
open-minded uh approach to cannabis we
hope to see a a opening a broadening of
the approach to research in cannabis and
uh and also an increased investment in
that so that means that there should be
some new things that are possible that
haven't been before um so first you know
it's a it's an optimistic view it's an
idealistic view I'd like to First just
ask the panelists um in your experience
uh do these changes
regulations uh mean that there will be
um new opportunities in cannabis
research or how would you like to see
these uh potential changes in regulation
affect that um I can talk for Slovenia
unfortunately we don't have yet uh the
new
regulation but I hope as Government
promised uh we will have it soon and I
think it will be also easier to uh
research the plant the Cannabis is
actually very much uh
research plant most research plant on
the planet but still we are failing on
the preclinical clinical trials and real
life uh data you know we have
high uh I don't know science and all
that but it on the field of medicine
nothing changed actually in the last few
years this is our goal so you you
mentioned that the cannabis plant is one
of the most studied uh plants uh in the
world and yet you you say that the the
real relevancy and applicability of that
um data and the science doesn't really
uh impact medicine and and its practical
use what would have to change um in
order for that to first we have to
change narrative and uh you know uh uh
about uh cannabis as it whole because uh
until when the mainstream professionals
or medicines is a priori against the
Cannabis you cannot do really changes uh
then uh another big thing uh is how to
convince the industry to support
cannabis research we know the Pharma
industry is supporting clinical trials
all all over the world because they have
their own benefits uh but in the area of
cannabis research you don't really get
any
funds not the state funds not in
Slovenia and mostly Europe so this
should change as soon as
possible and what about you um you want
to tell us what your experience is and
how the regulatory framework is or isn't
encouraging research and and what kind
of changes you'd like to see okay in
terms of it depends from country to
Country I know better the situation in
Portugal so Portugal was first country
in Europe to legalize the production of
Canabis and processing of Canabis for
medical
purposes this law came in July
2018 but it was of course a slow process
first it came as a surprise many people
didn't believe it that it would be
approved it was of course there were two
or three companies already ready to
start one of done till big multinational
but then local companies a few reacted
fast to start
producing but it was just they were just
growing no real
research we as
also say that in Portugal science means
European money no European money no
science private or
public and so 2018 this was at the end
of framework at Horizon 2020 so money
for research was
ending and the new framework Horizon
2030 was coming and there is always here
at that period between the end of one
framework and beginning of next and to
make it worse so on beginning of the
Horizon 2030 framework it came pandemic
and everything stopped
it uh and with pandemic everyone start
talking about the recovery and
resilience plan that somehow made
investments in the framework of horizon
2030 to delay meaning that first the
recover resilience and Recovery money
came that despite this was decided in
2020 only in 2023 start arriving to the
European countries and it's still going
now the good news is that the 2030
Horizon um monies programs it started
now now we see it happening so there are
lots of gr
submissions and I can't say to my
surprise immediately but thinking better
yeah it was happening now because these
monies there were no grants for research
for many years since
201819 but now that there are these
grants submissions in Portugal I see
that several companies are investing in
research uh goes from technology it can
go to growth growth technology
production Pro processing but several
Growers and processing companies are
actually uh submitting grants to do
preclinical
studies
so it's happening you know these
processes never go widely massively some
companies they are to lead they are
Beginnings they
pioneers and has these companies are
putting these new projects with PR
clinical tests so private sector working
with medicine schools with Pharmacy
schools they will bring more in future
so I think it start happening
um this is Portugal in Germany now also
with legalization and this is Germany
things I think will go much much faster
uh also with Horizon 2030 there we will
see definitely preclinical studies
going clinical studies it's another
division we are not talking about
investing a few hundreds of thousand or
even one or two million it's big big
Investments then it will be required or
governmental really governmental
programs or the Far big farm industry to
come seriously into this but it's
happening I think it's starting there
will be big developments on the years to
come I just want to add Justin uh you
ask which kind of legislation I want I
want to have
legislation which would not uh limit the
you know uh
research and uh so the science can be
real science and not as many too many
times today uh politically correct
science and then legislation should
follow the real science otherwise we
will not you know otherwise we are in
catch22 for a long time thank you for
that understood um apologize because I
realize um I didn't give you guys an
opportunity here to to let the crowd
know um and the people here know what
you actually specialize in and work in
and so as a moderator I'm sorry I didn't
give you a chance to introduce
yourselves there it's such a big family
here at uh at the events that we do
sometimes we get very comfortable and
familiar with each other but why don't
you just real quickly for a minute um
let folks know what your work is in
cannabis and where that might um
influence your view on
Research uh our main work actually is
for last 10 years to follow kabinet
products which which are used by uh
patients from any Market black gray or
regular uh Market uh because this is the
only way that you have really good
insight into what is good what is not
good what helps and what not helps uh I
hope all those research as I said will
be legal very soon uh because the real
research should not be limited you know
by bureaucratic uh obstacles which
is uh actually the biggest problems
anywhere among funds of
course okay how about
you okay so complicated to Define my
company we are in business for 42 years
and we started by being Distributors of
analytical equipment we were founded by
PhD students from chemical engineering
but since beginning that we were also
doing was development of certain Key
Systems for people doing research
usually chemist departments chemic
engine departments biotechnology
departments Pharmacy schools so we
always
been also a kind of um not manufacturers
because we always developed
prototypes but somehow extraction became
always something that we were looking a
lot for and with legalization in Canabis
in
2018 uh
companies working on this area and
wanted extraction equipment we were the
ref so they start calling us to supply
equipment for extraction this is how we
entered in Canabis so we are in Canabis
by the technology not by the science of
uh the Therapeutics of Canabis we are
going there slowly but we entered by
technology so this is how we enter then
we expanded to post Harvest but in terms
of research and development we kept on
just expanding our knowledge and our
Technologies on all downstreams
processes of extraction and also more
extraction techniques we were initially
just CO2 superal for the extraction and
over time we start having ethanol
solvent L um and now also either carbons
extraction and all on streams at same
times because we are an ISO 90001
certified company and recently in
meantime we got ugp certified lab and
even more recently it was this last
quarter we got a license to do research
in Canabis because we were selling and
developing equipment but we could not
test equipment in the house we had to go
to the customers because we could not
have Canabis not even hemp in Portugal
hemp is more forbidden than Canabis
actually hemp in Portugal is fiber and
seeds flowers is a residue to be
destroyed so finally we got the license
for R&amp;D meaning we can have Canabis in
house and we can test so this
immediately we increas it the number of
technologies that we are
developing and with this new framework I
mentioned between our own projects and
together with uh universities and
Canabis companies we submitted for
Grants and with grants or without grants
we are going forward with the research
projects
um and it's expanding so it's
growing um in meantime we are also
getting um a certification in management
of innovation so we are going developing
very seriously these R&amp;D uh R&amp;D
Department in our company in which 80%
of work is Canabis
related and uh may I add I forgot to say
that our Institute is also uh cooran
organizing seminaries and uh education
courses on the faculty of Health
Sciences about cannabis because if we
don't start to teach you know new
students about cannabis yesterday not
tomorrow we will not have Professionals
for 10 years uh then we help also or
helped some startup
companies uh and with this cooperation
we also joined the space exploration we
were sending some
samples to the space you know you have
to follow somehow the so we are active
on many many fields great cannabis in
space that certainly sounds like
something new in the field of research
so uh there is a theme here though that
um we could reiterate we you you
mentioned again you know cannabis being
the most studied plant and yet we hear
how people involved in the industry um
uh as a matter of practice are unable to
conduct the research most relevant you
couldn't even bring in you know biomass
material from Cannabis to to figure out
how to extract it within your business
uh you have a difficulty um sometimes
being able to obtain material to to use
in the the practice of medicine and so
though it has been really studied and
has been really researched it hasn't
been done in the context of what's most
relevant and important um as we look as
a cannabis industry to move forward I
think that's got to be the emphasis in
our communication from the industry to
The Regulators about what needs to
happen um so can you point out maybe
we'll start with you um one piece of
something that's kind of new um and or
exciting to you a piece of research or a
development of a new technology in um in
in your part of the field of cannabis in
you know either extraction or
postprocessing
can I speak can I speak about
two as long as we have time good so well
uh we have to Fields is post Harvest and
it extraction purification so in post
Harvest and this is a quite Hot Topic
because bioburden
reduction it's a very serious
problem I I speak about lots of Growers
and say we will not have contaminations
I never had a contamination everyone
lies everyone has
contaminations and this is not us this
is Europe we have to count that are very
well defined limits everything has to be
analyzed it doesn't matter if it is gacp
or if it is GMP it has to be analyzed
limits are the same so when we have a
crop that is contaminated what to do
with uh people are using typically
radiation by ionizing um radiation B
gamma radiation Electron Beam or
x-rays um but this always affects
quality of flour loss ofin potential
loss of cannabinoids and flow oxidizes
get brownish there is a less of quality
and even worse in terms of Market
Commercial aspects in Germany nowadays
flower that is irradiated so that is
subject to ionizing
radiation it has to be Market as IR
radiated product and and people don't
want to buy
so there is new techn and all the other
Technologies even without having to put
on label like uh termal processes by
radio frequency or microwaves or plasma
or ozone all of these oxidize and flow
is affected but there is a brand new
technology American technology using
cryo pasturization
basically they freeze instantly to very
very low temperatures cryogenic
temperatures with leak nitrogen with
these microbes uh um molds bacteria is
killed instantly and flower doesn't
suffer it keeps all thein keeps all the
cannabinoids and even all these
pathogens that are eliminated that are
killed because this is a process in whe
there is a flow of nitrogen always
passing all these let's say corpuses of
these dead pathogens they are that are
very thin particles they are swept it
away so when packet this material will
not give that
smelly taste or on on moldy flavor so
you get high
quality and um you get a very high
quality product even starting with
highly contaminated product this is a
huge
advance I follow these bioburden
reduction Tech Technologies and this is
absolutely the very very big step this
is next Generation bioburden uh
reduction uh in terms
extraction especially thinking medical
cannabis we go to German pharmacopia
that recommend say say say the
recommended technology CO2 extraction
meaning super critical fuid extraction
so at high pressures and temperatures
above ambient like 35 40
45 this is not a must but is a
recommended one and I agree that gives
you the GLE the best extracts at least
in terms of Purity and in in a
controlled way but we are traditionally
using dry flour when we look for other
techniques more in recreational like
hydrocarbons extraction that use fresh
frozen flowers so these extracts can
reach in tpin which is great because
fresh flour is far more tpin than a
dried flour this is great but then there
are problems of contaminations residual
residual solvents like propane and Bane
on the extracts to take them out that
means go away and in Europe it comes
legislation and limits is very easy is
no measurable residual solvents so this
doesn't go well with the highin content
if you have to put under VI L of time to
decreas now there are new developments
in CO2 extraction not in supercritical
but using cryogenic temperatures again
but not so cryogenic like 0 to minus 20
- 30° Centigrade so we have liquid CO2
with small amounts of Co solvent this
allow you to extract not from dry
flowers but also from fresh flowers
Frozen fresh flowers and so you get the
best of both worlds you get a very high
Purity extract very potent extract
coming out of the extractor potency is
typically of 80% even if you are
extracting from
hemp and with a huge huge tpin potenti
concentration too exciting um so in in
both instances um you're you're looking
to get cold with Excuse me to do uh to
to have these new advances um uh Bojo do
you have something that you'd like to
speak to about um in the field of you
know medical application that's a new
area of research or do you want to tell
us why you're sending samples to space
um something
uh yeah about space you know um space
exploration last uh years it's uh quite
interesting story from China to USA and
India and um cannabis is uh one of the
plants who can which can
withstand uh high dose of of light
radiation uh very high and let's see
what uh damage can do or will do the
cosmic ation on the uh on the plants
then we also send some uh other cannabis
products to space and we want to test
then what is the difference if any when
those products come back uh from the
space so we don't expect anything we
will just uh follow the science or let's
see what will happen and maybe next year
on in next two years we will be able to
tell you more is there any conversation
about people being able to use cannabis
in space not yet but you never
know uh actually they uh it would be
very good for the uh astronauts because
of the all symptoms they can get like
anxiety or depression or whatever so
very good idea Justin okay but it might
be a little while before we see any
pictures of anybody with a joint in the
space station joint necessarily you have
other Administration Ro extracts extract
indeed indeed um and G how are we doing
on time you about three minutes and then
questions after no no okay got it well
then let's let's take a moment to some
things up um really quickly because the
the field of research in cannabis is
actually so big um that we could you
know in this moment just talk about a
couple of small aspects of it obviously
we're we're looking at at um the way
that these regulatory changes can
encourage um or limit research but when
you look at the plant itself um cannabis
produces at this last count something
close to 140 phyto uh cannabinoids it
has well over uh a 100 terpenoids
there's a a whole number of um
flavonoids that is approaching that as
well as amines and am Ides and a whole
bunch of other phyto compounds over 500
in total that this one plant produces
okay now those interact with each other
those interact with each of your's endoc
canabo system in really unique ways and
a lot of times when research is done
that it starts with the supposition well
if we give cannabis to this person is it
effective for this but in fact I've just
mentioned that there's 500 different
variables you have to look at and
potentially control for to understand
this genotype this choar and and all of
the interactions with a person uh unique
uh conditions that have to be looked at
and accounted for and we're not even
talking about the
agronomics uh of how you grow and
cultivate the plant the extraction or
postprocessing um and then the many
industral applications far beyond just
medicine so the field of cannabis
science is actually really F and though
it seems like we've studied a lot you've
heard from folks here in the industry a
lot of that research hasn't been
directed into how we're going to really
utilize this plant to get all the
benefits out of it so what's new in
cannabis research will actually um a lot
more research that's what's needed
investment in it from a public and a
private sector and also investment in an
open-minded approach that just doesn't
look at things in really simple terms um
black and white cannabis good or bad
um and so hopefully that's the evolution
in the industry that we'll we'll be
taking forward appreciate your guys' uh
time and attention here I think uh and
gu's going to take us away can you
please uh give our panelists another
round of applause and thank them for
their time being here today fantastic
thank you all very much and if you have
questions I'm sure you can ask them cuz
we're going to take a 15minute coffee
and pastry break we have coffee and
pastries in the next hallway