okay it sounds good right now there's a
lot of uncertainty in CBD we're kind of
facing some uncertainty with the FDA we
got a legal farm bill my three panelists
today are gonna help us kind of figure
out some of the patchwork of what's
going on out there on the federal level
here everyone's looking at CBD is a big
opportunity I think everyone in this
room has some connection to cannabis CBD
is sort of popped up in the last you
know few months as a federal
legalization and farm bill is come
around and I think a lot of us are
finding ourselves now kind of running
parallel businesses and trying to figure
out how we take advantage of what they
think is going to be a twenty two
billion dollar market here in the US my
esteemed guests here are David Branson
he's a super lawyer is focuses in
trademark and IP law we're gonna have a
little bit of discussions around how to
protect your business with both
trademarks and patents Chris who's son
and he is business development and sales
operator for X elixir
licks and all and they are a global
distributor of CBD products manufacturer
vertically integrated kind of all over
the place and then additionally I have a
onyx lip he's from pure cannabis
research those guys are a Swiss company
who are growing really fast they've done
a lot in two years and I'm just gonna
give my guys a chance now to sort of
introduce themselves and talk a little
bit about their businesses so David why
don't you lead us off okay thanks thanks
Mitchell and thanks to Alex and the gang
for having us all here and putting this
together
love ICBC and so my name is Dave Rothman
I'm from down the road San Diego
California by way of New York originally
and once upon a time I was just a trade
marketing copywriting innovation lawyer
in San Diego with a lot of clients in
all kinds of different industries
electronics clothing music TV film
everything you can think of restaurants
and then about ten years ago or what I
like to refer to as 70
marijuana's dog years ago somebody kind
of clued me in that this industry was
rapidly developing and it dawned on me
that I should figure out how to take my
skills from those other industries and
apply them to the cannabis industry and
start learning everything I could got
involved with normal first and bunch of
other organizations and little by little
by little over the last 10 years we've
been helping clients all over the place
develop intellectual property IP is the
umbrella term for copyrights patents
trademarks trade secrets domain names
we've been helping people develop
strategies for in this industry for how
to work within this complex legal system
which is very bifurcated and divided and
that's in a nutshell Chris hi my name is
Chrissy song I'm the director of sales
marketing for Alex and all we distribute
CBD products and 42 different countries
we've been in business a little over
five years and are out of Colorado
primarily our headquarters but have
offices in Japan Europe and Australia we
primarily focus on developing
high-quality delivery systems to make
sure that people get high-quality CBD in
them we've come out with several
different new delivery systems that you
can come see at the booth including
micro encapsulating full spectrum oil
into a powder so you can mix it into
your drink and completely water-soluble
up to liposomes and high-quality
capsules and dog treats and an amazing
new skincare line that we just launched
but primarily what we're focused on is
can being an innovator in the market
from growing from production from
quality and from testing and from
transparencies aspects thank you
I'm Yannick which is flew in from
Switzerland two days ago
Switzerland is the country that's known
for chocolate the Alps and more recently
wheat its cannabis CBD cannabis i'm from
the breeding company under managing this
one but i'm representing the holding
which is a it's going to be an
interesting topic after it's fully
integrated to holding
varieties breeding all the way to the
sales were selling from Switzerland to
you to European Union but also
internationally were the biggest company
in Europe we started two years ago it
all took off and now we're selling
flowers flowers a cessation products
we're selling dietary supplements CBD
oils and we're doing white labeling
private labeling bulk orders worldwide
that's the story from my side looking
forward to this talk cool I think a
first question I want to start with is
for you two gentlemen who are in the
production end of this business and I
think audience might be curious about
sort of what products you guys are
producing what's selling well and sort
of the diversity of products and CBD
that you guys work with specifically
sure so CBD is like you've mentioned
early just this burgeoning business so I
think a lot of different products are
still being created out there what we're
focused on is dietary supplements to
help people take it in their day to day
life and invest in their health and find
ways to take CBD that fit into their
normal everyday life the powdered or the
micro encapsulated powder that we talked
about earlier is one of our newer
innovations to make sure that happens so
you can just take some of the mornings
from the afternoon some right before you
go to bed and take a little single
service serving size that kind of mix
into whatever you want to put it in
exactly so we have different flavors
throughout the day you know berry citrus
cocoa things like that but the idea is
that you're it's something that somebody
can add to their protein shake or their
oatmeal or their tea or their coffee on
a regular basis and just make it just
like all the other biohacking things
that people are doing to find better
ways to live and use natural plants to
give their body the information to heal
themselves I think for us we need to
distinguish two markets one is to
business to business market which is the
prevailing market for us internationally
there we as the largest producer in
Europe we clearly go for bulk products
we go for privately
and white labeling on on the whole
spectrum starting from flour cessation
products below 20% THC so it's really
nice flowers but they're federally legal
similar to the farm bill that has passed
here in the states all the way to seep
the oils and isolates terpene fractions
etc etc in Switzerland we're also
selling more dietary supplements to farm
seeds
we're having a few thousand points of
sales I know this sounds like nothing to
you guys here back home for a email
people market is it's quite a bit and
there it's also business to customer and
more so these tobacco cessation products
with up to one percent THC because in
Switzerland the law is not like these in
states with 0.3 percent THC but 1
percent meaning Switzerland's turning
into this hub of CBD production there's
different varieties we can grow it's not
hemp it's really this cannabis type with
a low THC and we we have the whole width
of products started with 50 sealed kind
of felt the market testing the waters
seeing that some are really worth it
others we've we've dispatched talked a
little bit about some of the ones you've
tossed aside some of the products that
you've decided not to pursue absolutely
we will resume those but for instance
the CBD infuse beer since it's a
considered a noble food we stopped and
we gotta wait for laws to change to to
bring us back onto the market we've had
some were selling candies these days but
for instance some CBD pace we stopped
doing so and we just had to focus on a
few things because we were organically
financed and we just can't do can't do
everything David maybe I'm going to
circle back to you and and have you
talked a little bit about how people who
are coming into the CBD space I know
that the USPTO Patent and Trademark
Office has said pushback against
cannabis in the past what what does the
farm bill mean for cannabis in the
future when it comes to patents and
trademarks great question
we don't know for sure yet exactly what
the farm bill is going to mean because
the law in general moves slowly and the
Patent and Trademark Office moves slowly
so for example on a good day if we filed
a u.s. trademark application today and
I'm talking for just this moment about
trademarks as opposed to patents so it's
the Patent and Trademark Office one
office but you can think of it as
there's the patent door over here and
the trademark door over there and
they're not the same and they don't
treat cannabis or cannabis related
products the same way but if we filed a
trademark application today for a brand
name you know Dave's Naturals okay I
want to file a trademark application
today for Dave's Naturals for any
product whether it's cannabis or not if
I file it today it's gonna sit in a
queue an electronic queue for a minimum
of four months before a trademark lawyer
at the trademark office even looks at it
so farm bill was signed December 20th of
last year if somebody filed a trademark
application for shampoo containing CBD
that's compliant with the farm bill
let's say if that's how they described
it whatever that for Dave Naturals for
shampoo containing CBD that's compliant
with the farm bill they filed it that
day or the next day that application
isn't going to be looked at until
ironically 4:20 at the FDA least and
probably longer because of the
government shutdown and so we don't know
yet we don't know capital and capital K
capital n capital o w we don't know what
exactly they're gonna do we think I
think my office thinks others of my kind
think that they may allow trademark
applications for the first time they've
been prohibiting they've been excluding
trademark applications for anything that
is cannabis contains cannabis or touches
cannabis such as a testing facility or
trimming equipment for the better part
of
the last five or six years they've been
very very prohibitive we think that now
certain types of products that contain
CBD that complies with the hemp bill
hemp deriving the farm bill hemp derived
CBD with less than 0.3 percent THC not
ingestible I'm thinking so not tinctures
not edibles
but topicals shampoos conditioners
patches where no health claims are made
that's going to be pretty pretty
important may get through so you're all
in and you're all if you're in this
business or thinking about getting in
this business or this industry or this
this movement you're risk takers so
we're thinking it's time to take some
risks and try these trademark
applications don't wait we why wait for
four or five six months and the reason
we're not more sure is because although
the farm bill seems to decriminalize CBD
the FDA the same day the Food and Drug
Administration the same day that the
farm bill was signed the FDA issued the
Chairman chairperson of the FDA issued a
statement that essentially said not so
fast you're not sure I think there's an
important distinction to make there
between laws and regulations that we
passed the law now regulators are
stepping in to try to sort of steer the
ship when it comes to how that law is
interpreted and how its executed on on a
product level I think one of the big
lessons that we've learned from the FDA
and and the announcement you're talking
about is that you have to be very
careful about making health claims yeah
because there are not the studies to
back it up FDA is its own approval
process for that and that process takes
time it's it's not gonna happen
overnight so I think people who are
thinking about running a CBD business
here stateside there's gonna be a little
bit of an uncertainty from the federal
level and ultimately you they want you
to be really careful about making health
claims you guys have anything
on that well I think it's very important
what you just said that that federally
it's legal and the FDA what they did was
mention that now as a dietary supplement
there's a pathway for CBD to become
regulatory ly approved right and so
they're working with us they're working
with the hemp roundtable they're working
with lots of different organizations to
make sure that they figure all of this
out because it's not that they don't
want to do it it's that all the
different stores and people that report
to them or ask them and they work with
on a daily basis or saying what do we do
and so now they're trying to figure it
out so we're all trying to work together
to help them be able to figure it out
and each individual state with that
information from the FDA is now making
their own different regulations but it's
this isn't DEA this is an ATF this isn't
it you know they're not coming for you
and they don't care about anecdotal
evidence that that's not that's not
what's going on but I think another very
important thing you need to that you
made a distinction on is making claims
and making claims is something that
isn't just a CVD thing right I mean the
FDA jumps on all sorts of industries
that we all see on late-night TV for for
making all sorts of claims and I think
it's very easy for people in our
industry because CVD is such a powerful
thing to go to that low-hanging fruit
and start making those claims and we
really need to police ourselves now to
make sure that we're all saying the
right things and we're all being ethical
and moral not just following FDA and
legal guidelines I know that Nick I know
that Nick had some of the stuff in his
presentation prior to this about the
whu-oh and Europe maybe Jana could just
talk a little bit about how the the regs
are different Europe it is a different
approach European Union and Switzerland
take as long as the varieties meat is
0.2 percent THC level in the European
Union or this 1 percent in Switzerland
the plants are regulated in the sense
that it's perfectly legal like any other
crop like maize like soy you can grow it
you can sell it
and what claims is concerned the only
limitation is that we are not allowed to
put claims on CD products but there's
ways around it we have registered
dietary supplements you just need to
find those unfortunately the loopholes
we're working with the authorities with
the regular regulators we founded a
syndicate on cannabis in the European
Union to bring forward and to bring
progress but currently it's
unfortunately kind of funding there the
ways through and the loopholes and
that's how we can do claims but we
currently refrain from doing so because
the laws changed quickly and as it is
here with the states it's with the
countries in Europe it can be that one
day you can sell and the other day it's
over yeah and so here in California I
think many of you may know that the
dispensary system and the manufacturing
systems here do not allow any hemp
derived CBD products so essentially in
our state regulators here on the hem
side are pretty far behind in terms of
building the brock bureaucracy and regs
and issuing permits and and so many many
hemp companies here stateside are going
to different different states Oregon
Kentucky North Carolina where they're
really embracing this business and
trying to fast-track it I think we've
also seen if you look at Oregon
cultivation as it as it sort of
commoditize is a little bit more a lot
of the farmers in Oregon have been
pivoting really hard to CBD because they
can move from a small canopy to hundreds
of acres and it's been a it's been a
boon for them and I think that's gonna
be their opportunity I know they were
lobbying to try to export cannabis a to
Oregon I kind of think that that's a
slim chance of happening but they can
produce CBD flour and hemp there and and
export it it's not still stopping
certain to incidences where truck gets
pulled over with CBD flour and somebody
gets arrested or because they a local
cop isn't gonna trust your paperwork
it's looks smells and quacks like a duck
it's duct to them so I
Oklahoma right yeah exactly so that kind
of stuff does happen and and I think
there's a lot of really smart people in
the dispensed
your business here in California and
they know what works and they're making
sure their clients get it whether it
comes from hemp or whether it comes from
marijuana and knowing the difference
between the actual legal definition of
what hemp is and the actual botanical or
biological definition of what hemp is
and providing what is beneficial to
their clients it's unfortunate that it
seems that a regulatory system is trying
to regulate something they don't
understand and so I think it's up to us
here in this room and and throughout the
state of California to continue to do
that we're providing our hem cvd
products throughout California it's one
of our largest states and while it's
unfortunate that most of the
dispensaries can't carry our products
currently today we're working closely
with the state of California to make
sure that it does but you can get it at
the grocery store you can get it from
your doctor you can get it from the
acupuncturist the coffee shop down the
street so it makes only sense that
people going for what they for what they
need should be able to get at the
dispensary - it makes no sense could you
guys maybe talk a little bit about the
different delivery systems I know that
Kris you guys have sort of a unique play
in this can you guys talk about some of
the other ways that people are consuming
this and and where the opportunities are
in that currently given especially given
sort of the FDA is sort of talking more
and more about food products and stuff
of that nature
sure well Yannick has a lot of different
delivery systems that he's talked about
his pre-rolls and he's very innovative
over in Sweden and throughout Europe
we're very sorry Switzerland overs my
completely my mistake additionally we're
working on a lot of different delivery
systems I mentioned a few times our
micro encapsulation process very proud
of our liposomal CBD but probably our
flagship product is our expand its the
most raw form of the CBD oil that we
provide in an airless delivery oral
applicator that people just love and so
they're taking it the most natural
version of the CBD product but we know
that not everybody wants to take their
CBD in the same way so we're trying to
find different ways to fit because
one of the hardest questions I'm asked
as a sales and marketing guy is what's
your demographic you know who's your
ideal client well with CVD it's like
everybody from eight to eighty right and
and trying to narrow that down we're
doing that by product sets finding a
delivery system that helps you know and
fits that demographic and that need and
filling the needs to make sure that
somebody doesn't have to look at a big
giant scary white syringe and say how
much do I take and you know the size of
a grain of rice like what and that
doesn't make any sense and so trying to
figure that stuff out for people and
help them get really good
well-thought-out delivery systems and
products you got anything to add there
in terms of your delivery systems and
sort of what'swhat's working yes the
delivery systems are closely linked to
claims because back home were not
allowed to do claims on CVD and but
we've experienced from patients
reporting that the SE candies or
sublingual drops work much better far
better than things they ingest also
what's very important to us is to go
with full-spectrum extracts because from
experience and from reports these are
far superior in terms of the efficiency
than the isolates that's that's kind of
our experience we're working together
with patients and hospitals more so
outside of the European Union because
within it's quite difficult we'll be
bringing new products soon to the
markets not to the state tip but anyways
you can ship worldwide so maybe but it's
more the claims that are limiting it
than the delivery systems cool I want to
skip back to you David here for a minute
I want to talk a little bit about the
difference between a USPTO LA and
California law when it comes to doing
business as sure so the difference
between California law and federal law
it again keeps us keeps us awake at
night trying to figure out things
different keep everything separate or
understand the differences so we've got
the federal system which for many years
the
that on the trademark side again on the
on the trademark side has been very
restrictive when it comes to trademarks
for cannabis products or anything that
contains cannabis or anything that
touches cannabis and I draw that
distinction again because people say to
me often well can I get a can I get a
trademark registration I can't get it
can I get a trademark registration for
my clothing product if it has a pot leaf
on it and the answer is yes it's not the
pot leaf on the product that triggers
the refusal from the Patent and
Trademark Office it's the product itself
if the product is cannabis such as
cannabis or contains cannabis no you can
call it you know again
Dave's Naturals not have a pot leaf on
it but if it contains cannabis or is
cannabis it's gonna get rejected or you
can have a product that has a giant pot
leaf all over it if it's not doesn't
violate the CSA it's gonna sail through
so the trademark office has had this
prohibition for years they in fact have
five or six lawyers who I informally
referred to as the pot Posse who are
specifically assigned to looking at all
trademark applications federal trademark
applications that appear to have
anything to do with cannabis and they're
very smart and they're very
knowledgeable and they're carrying out
their job as they are told to do their
job and the irony is the reason you can
walk through the Patent Office door and
get a patent for cannabis or a cannabis
product but you can't get a trademark
for a product that contains cannabis is
because the trademark law specifically
says words to the effect of thou shalt
not issue a trademark registration for
anything that is illegal so that puts
cannabis under that the CSA and nuclear
weapons in the same category where there
is no such sentence in the patent laws
so that's why you can walk through the
patent door and get a pen now we go to
California which for years and years and
years and years followed the federal law
no trademark applications for cannabis
products or anything that touched
cannabis until January 1 of 2018 a year
ago and the law changed in California
and the California trademark unit
Sacramento now accepts trademark
applications for products for cannabis
products or that products that container
touch cannabis so long as they are
compliant with California law so you
have to be able yeah basically they
don't ask for your BCC license in other
words the state trademark unit does not
ask to see your BCC license when you
file a trademark application they ask
you to sign your application under your
trademark application or in a penalty of
perjury they'll take your word for it
and they'll leave it to litigation later
on down the road with a competitor if
you sue a competitor and it turns out
you falsified your trademark application
to get your trademark registration the
kind of trademark unit in Sacramento
will leave it to the courts to decide
whether you fraudulently got your
trademark registration but you can get a
trademark registration in California I
would say make sure you have your BCC
license in your file so you can show
that if you ever have to down the road
so there's a lot of companies in the
cannabis space with the same name that
that's a common occurrence you see it
pretty frequently that some of the names
or we have seven clients and on my
little firm that have Humboldt in their
name and we've had to put pictures of
the names and the pictures of the
operators like on the and the post
office yep to keep them separate
everybody and their brother wants to use
Humboldt emerald-green
can or canna
and it creates confusion in the
marketplace you might recommend people
go a different way I think I recommend
people go a different way yes I do the
more clever and creative you can be the
better off you are so the classic
example that I like to use to help
people understand this is Apple is a
dictionary word word you can find in the
dictionary that makes it seemingly
generic but when applied to computers
and small electronic devices its unique
because apples are not computers and
small electronics of
in the real world so Apple is a
trademark for computers and small
electronics is a 10 on a scale of 0 to
10 zero being the worst ten being the
best however Apple as a trademark for
applesauce or apple juice would be a
zero because in that context it would be
generic say you want to be as clever and
unique as you possibly can
mrs. Fields Exxon Kodak Xerox Famous
Amos those prot those trademarks those
brand names help you identify and
distinguish your product from the
competitors product and they stand apart
on the shelf and in the magazines and
all your advertising and they're easy to
remember and they say nothing about the
product yeah and then occasionally you
might get lucky and end up being a
Kleenex where a Kleenex where you wear
your brand name becomes the thing that
it actually although they have to spend
millions of dollars a year advertising
that Kleenex is a noun not a verb yeah
they don't want you they don't want
people going to the store and saying
where's the where's the Kleenex aisle
they want you to go into the store and
say where where can I find the Kleenex
brand tissue paper exactly cool cool I
guess I want to switch back to you Chris
I want to hear a little bit about the
challenges of sort of taking a CBD
company global from from sort of I think
you know I think yeah everyone needs to
start somewhere but finding global
opportunities obviously is a is a
challenge could you sort of talk about
your guyses journey a little bit from
from where you guys started and have
where he ended up going global sure so
Alexson all was founded by Paul bending
him who has been in the hemp industry
over two decades he brought the very
first hemp bar to the UK the 9:00 bar
and he's been innovating in the imp
industry and growing in the industry
ever since so he did a lot of the heavy
lifting for a lot of people in the
industry including us and so when he
decided to found
Alexson all because so many people
wanted CBD five years ago and there was
no way to get it so
what we started doing initially was
importing CBD I'm working or from Europe
we had farms yep so we had to import CBD
from Europe initially because they
wouldn't let us grow it here in the
United States and when they finally let
us grow it here in the United States we
quickly moved to be able to do that so
we have farms in Colorado growing it and
it's difficult I mean you mentioned
earlier esct acre I was very very
privileged to be able to work with Paul
and Gabe who have been risk takers
because they saw what good CBD could do
in the world and they saw the impact
that hemp can make in the world so by
taking those risks and being innovative
and understanding that good will went
out they they were invested a lot of
time and took a lot of risks and there's
been times that you know it didn't look
good for the CBD world and when we went
public a year ago January going through
the legal process and not just
backfilling and you know reverse merging
into an existing company but actually
going public on the Australian Stock
Exchange explaining to lawyers and
explaining to finance people the risks
that we took importing CBD and creating
our CBD and all those type of things are
are challenging you know and they they
gave me a lot of the gray hair I have
today and definitely have been worth it
though every second of it and every
minute of it's been worth it and we all
work really hard and and are a testament
to though the work that the people that
came before me I mean the very first
cannabis trade show I came to was ICBC a
little over five years ago great and so
it's it's been it's been amazing awesome
I guess this questions for maybe both
you and Yannick how do you guys compete
with the big dogs
if this thing becomes federal legal and
well it is but when when the when the
regs shake out and we start getting the
General Mills into the business or some
of these other major companies coming in
like how do you guys how do you guys
compete with them how do you compete
with wholesale extracts and isolates
coming out of China you guys just talk a
little bit about that it doesn't feel so
much like competition to be honest too
say we started small and which is two
years old and then we kind of start
producing people started demanding we
started growing and there's few things
to our success one was the vertical
integration I know there was this debate
before whether it's smart and not to be
vertically integrated for us we have
this family cultural constant exchange
between the various companies and this
was one thing that's helped us at the
same time we've been diversifying and
specializing which is near impossible
this was thanks to the growth and lastly
we have the strategic alliances to other
continents to universities law firms etc
etc and this kind of helped us sustain
in the market and there's such a large
demand there space for many more cool I
think we're gonna take we only got about
five minutes left so we're gonna open it
up for some QA if anybody wants to try
to get any girls attention I'm right
here man alright let's hear it again for
Mitchell the whole panel on CBD which is
everywhere it's like I'm the presence I
got a quick what do you do when I guess
it doesn't matter to you but when they
ban CBD in like New York where you can't
put it in food and stuff anymore have
you seen a dip in anything or so the
city was it's banned which is a pretty
cool sensational headline on a news
article but what CBD what they're
looking to do is follow regulations that
they think are coming from the FDA and
not allowing people to put it into a
commercial food or like a cocktail so
that's the regulation that they just
brought in but you can still buy all of
our products throughout you know in New
York and we're still shipping in New
York so they're just working through
those regulations and we work really
close with the state of New York to help
them start to figure out these things
and it's just a knee-jerk because
everybody wants to it because the other
side of it because you really have to
have a 360 view New York is also the one
handing out the licenses to grow hemp
everywhere they're handing out licenses
to
extract him you know they're really
investing in the EM community so they're
they're just not talking to each other
yet and once they do it'll all get
worked out it sounds like they're
fumbling through interpretation of
federal law right do you think that the
FDA should be the entity to regulate CBD
or should it be left to States or just
hippies or so FDA the FDA is a great
organization for us to be able to work
with I think they're looking for to
education to figure it out and I think
the individual organizations in each
state absolutely should be able to
figure it out their own - and we're
working with each one to help them we
have a you know a giant spreadsheet on
each state and we're always working with
them with our different lobbyists and
different organizations - to make sure
that they know what's going on yeah I
think everyone in this room here can
help also by engaging their lawmakers
and regulators if you ever have an
opportunity to have those conversations
um I think there's also a deeper need in
this business for data studies and I
think the more that we can convince our
institutions and science organizations
and health organizations to study this
and lobby groups and lobbyists crews the
better off the better off we're all be
in the end and rally your mother your
father your grandmother your grandfather
your aunt and uncle because so that your
legislators see that it's not just a
certain demographic that is pushing this
but that there are like real adults in
the room health benefits up and down the
entire spectrum of the show and how many
have a mother father grandmother or
grandfather who in the last year have
said something like oh my girlfriends
and I just love that CBD stuff yeah
it's phenomenal seek the dialogue with
everyone yeah I guess I guess the point
there is we all know somebody who's
benefited from it but that's not enough
for the FDA we need people to study this
we needed to be done the right way you
know and and when we get there I think
the whole thing will grow better with a
lot less pain so I have a quick question
so um I am working with jetty extracts
who's traditionally been the THC space
we're looking to now we're looking to
create jetty CBD so
my job has been like procuring where to
find distillate we're having trouble
finding folks that are able to actually
produce whole plan full-spectrum
extracted distillate better that that
protocol after extraction has less than
0.3 percent THC you know not the dry way
but the after so you know like someone
like us who's looking to do like 20 you
know kilos a month on going you know not
only is that a sourcing issue but also
I'm wondering what you guys are seeing
in markets like core power yoga or you
know different you know health food
stores cafes if we're trying to go into
the vapor out which hasn't been
traditionally as popular as like the
tinctures or topicals
what are you guys seeing as far as the
interest in that why has it more why
haven't worn that because I'm coming I
feel like am I missing something I feel
like we're kind of first to market to do
this but I'd love some kind of context
from y'all I'm not an expert in this but
part of what I think is nicotine I think
that has a big big effect on vaping in
general I think the FDA's made that very
clear to that they see nicotine vaping
is a big problem especially in with
youth usage and some of these other
things that the nicotine in vape pens is
powerful and additionally you know
vaping is an exercise one hand you've
got THC the other hand you've got
nicotine CBD it's a different delivery
method that I think these guys could
also talk about in terms of all the
different delivery methods that are
coming on there's space for it but maybe
you guys could add I think I think
you're exactly right on I think it's an
amazing market I think you should be
going full force into it and I think
that the the risk that we talked about
earlier is nicotine but that people are
associated with nicotine but mainly that
big hesitation has been ATF that you
that product set has to be regulated by
that three-letter organization and the
CBD industry already has so many other
three-letter organizations coming after
them that they've been hesitant to pick
one more but I think it's an amazing way
to get CBD into your body and I think
you should talk to me after and we'll
make sure that we get jeti because I
love jetties sushi
so let's let's make sure we get daddy
some good CBD fantastic time for two
more hi my name is Sean Blackwell and I
am actually from Idaho and I have a I
have a Facebook page
that's called legalize hemp in Idaho
it's actually still illegal in Idaho and
we we had a bust
in southern Idaho recently they got my
face on the news cuz people started
asking me questions
what is marijuana as opposed to hemp
because Idaho obviously is not
interested in marijuana at all and
making it a really great place for hemp
to be grown because there won't be any
cross pollenization so a lot of people
don't really think about that because
that's gonna be a huge issue camp coming
up I want you to like elaborate on like
the legalization in states like Idaho
and also like the fact that it will be
beneficial for a state like that because
of the lack of cross pollenization so
you're talking about a growing hemp in I
know so what you're talking about
which is it is still definitely illegal
in Idaho right growing it right we were
talking about that busted green room
right so grow growing it and obviously
that's a big source of income social
revenue source of of ways for to revive
our economy here in the United States so
I'm really happy that all these
different states are starting to
legalize it
I would love Idaho to grow it because
finding areas like Idaho that have land
that you could easily certify organic to
grow is hard to find because there's
lots of states that are legalizing it
that don't have hardly any land that you
could certify organic because they've
been growing tobacco or cotton or or all
sorts of things on it that have GMOs and
pesticides and things in it so I'd love
Idaho to do it and we're absolutely
working with the hemp around table we're
working with the hemp Industrial
Association we're working with all sorts
of organizations to help move those laws
along so I think it's only a matter of
time before it happens so thank you for
doing the work that you're doing there
and and just hang in there it's gonna
it's going to happen soon
let me ask two
guy I'm over here sitting down my feet
hurt hi so I to his point about cross
pollenization like I'm all for Idaho
growing him because you know we grow a
pretty good weed out here in California
we don't want your boys and our girls as
I laugh that was a good job you
understand what I'm talking about
because him pollen can fly up to 30
miles sometimes and if you got a
recreational grow five miles from a hemp
grow all of a sudden you've got problems
and so please PLEASE legalize hemp in
Idaho and Nebraska so they can grow it
and we can just grow good we high panel
my question is sort of bringing it back
to basics a little bit I think that a
lot of people don't really know what CBD
is versus cannabis and the general
market outside this room and I'm
wondering if there is any effort to
educate people out there in the public
as to the benefits of CBD not on a brand
level but on a basic level so that
people can go out there and look to
buying it and actually know what they're
buying it for maybe to give you some
insight how we've done it back home is
we started with the cannabis farm and
we've grown cannabis publicly meaning
cannabis a low THC and people could just
walk in there were information banners
we've been giving tours to police to to
the government etc etc it's a it's
absolutely amazing I was there a few
weeks ago it's Alex
this is how we've got this media
coverage to to represent CBD make people
realize what its benefits are how they
can use it might be an approach you can
go for afterwards the other speakers one
is from Switzerland Ben from Canada
trade that will give you more insights
on the whole regulations and Swiss
market European market so you might want
to stay put with him so absolutely we're
alright we're working on education on
our end as well we're working with
lobbyists we're working with hospitals
we're working with colleges working with
States to make sure that everybody
understands that CBD
is an amazing product and that hemp is
the difference between the biological
definition from hemp and the legal
definition of him because you know I
think earlier you said the difference
between CBD and cannabis which is not
really the case
CBD comes from cannabis obviously in the
CBD that we sell comes from cannabis and
it's the legal definition of hemp which
is a cannabis plant that has less than
0.3 THC in it
so we sell that so you're talking about
the difference between industrial hemp
which is really much of pretty much a
beanpole that is really used really
grown for its stock that's it's just
like breeding dogs in a different way
it's a chihuahua to coordinate feed corn
yeah that's all the time we have let's
hear it once again it's a fantastic and
enlightening panel