well hello everybody it's great to be
here hope you had a great morning and so
our panel today is mainstreaming of CBD
so how does the product become a
mainstream product one might ask it
generally starts with the trend that in
the best case goes mainstream a
particularly strong trend is a hype
which is the situation we have with CBD
currently but will the current CBD hype
turn into a sustainable consumer trend
that is going to be one of the questions
we have for today but before we delve
into it the four panelists will
introduce themselves Chris please I'm
Chris yuseong vice president of
marketing and communications for Alex
know we are a Colorado based company
that also has offices in Europe Japan
and Australia hi I'm Phil I'm one of the
founders and CEO of can amigo our
company is based in Austria at the Lake
Constance and we mainly produce high
quality CBD products and also grow and
sell hemp plants because in Austria it's
basically legal to have every kind of
cannabis plant it doesn't matter if it's
a CBD or THC genetic and this is what we
basically do hello everybody my name is
Roman du Rena I'm chief business
development officer at company farmer
hemp farmer hemp is company from
ljubljana slovenia we say for our
company that we control from the seats
fills to the final consumer products and
we are considered to be one of the most
innovative company in developing
healthcare products based on CBD hello
I'm Kyle Kahneman from part of on
Germany I'm a lawyer I'm in the field
since two years and I'm consulting CBD
and medical cannabis companies in all
regulatory and legal issues well that
was great let's delve right into it then
so so CBD is taking the world by storm
but one has to ask the question who is
the consumer behind this demand Chris
what do you think is there a typical CBD
consumer out there
this is probably the hardest question of
the afternoon because our demographic is
anybody 8 to 80 any mammal almost right
that can take CVD right because they all
have an endocannabinoid system so is the
app who's the average consumer anyone
with an endocannabinoid system however
we have to develop individual products
that speak to those individual needs in
those individual voices so it's more in
the delivery system the marketing and
the messaging that we're able to fit
those individual needs from a European
perspective Roman and Philip would you
agree yes I will agree because there's
no typical CVD consumer everybody buys
it so we regulate ourselves to sell the
product at age 18 but from from 18 to 80
you have everybody the younger people
maybe bite for muscle regeneration or
anything and all the guys come for aroma
and also talks next and and and these
things are sold so it's a very bright
bright consumer Roman do you have
anything to add our experience is
actually the same because but what while
we were a bit surprised we have our
internet portal sales and we were
measuring some aging so it is only to
present ourselves but our average
consumer was 35 years old which was to
me surprising young so we have all these
consumer types all these different
products new product developments are
rapidly increasing so let's take a step
back how would you cut carrot and
categorize it how would you give a
beginner friendly take on all these
products which categories do we have
maybe Philip or Chris it's how Chris
told before it's more a thing former
from marketing because it depends to the
customer we also have two grannies which
comes in and you think maybe the
capsules or the oil are best for her but
she's asking for flowers for smoking
this also can happens so I think how he
said you should place in the development
some
products for different types of
consumers but you never can say that
this is fixed so we focus on delivery
systems we want to make sure you get the
most amount of high-quality CBD for the
high quality people we use a liposomal
product to make sure that it you feel
the effects really fast for those that
need those right away we have a topical
for those that want to put it on that
way we have capsules because people are
just used to taking pills you know we
want to make sure that you develop the
way in the delivery system that you're
going to get the most impact in the way
that you'll take it if you look at the
production method and all these
different types of intakes what you can
have with CBD do you have to think then
I'm gonna produce it like this to this
mean or does it not matter in any case
maybe Roman we have different sort of
production depending on our final
product for example I don't know we are
now stressing for example creams with
glucosamine for the joints you know this
is special technique is all the recipe
and then we have special I would say Co
partner with the GMP facilities so you
know each product is a bit unique and
what we learned for is also with all the
consumer products stability studies are
quite demanding so we have to be really
I would say focusing and really takes
time it's not that easy
so the demand we heard is rapidly
increasing at which rate is it
increasing would be my first question
and also is it possible to meet this
demand as a single supplier I mean
obviously we have a u.s. perspective in
the European perspective on this but can
you give any insight to how rapid this
demand is I can see Roman I mean I can
tell in our case our company last year
grew times 3 almost times 4 of course we
new categories new lines and coping with
this is you know managing your working
capital
having the right capacities well-planned
for us is also important I would say
traceability continuty so will it trace
each product so in building is at the
same time so it takes really all the
resources of the company because you
know you can do if you do something fast
you can do it wrong
this was our experience so we're a
global company and we're deliver to 42
different countries so our perspective
globally is that we've secured source
for five to six times our growth from
last year which was five to six times
the year before so we're absolutely
looking to be able to supply the the
increase in demand that seems by best
aspects everyone's saying somewhere
between 16 and 20 million in the next 30
years is billion in the next 23 years
which is I'm in a matchable number when
you realize that just last year it was
only a billion right and I feel weird
saying only a billion but 22 billion is
a lot bigger than that so everyone has
to scale and everybody has to grow and
that's why everybody in this room has an
opportunity to really be a part of that
Philip have you got anything to add from
your perspective yes for sure I can say
the demand is rising up very fast it's
also I think because of the media the TV
and so on because people get informed
about cannabis again it's coming back
through to the humans and also the the
guys talk to each other and we see a lot
of times the customers come in our shop
and they are informed before because we
are not allowed to give some health
claims or anything the CBD but they know
it before they come so you see about the
internet the media or anywhere they hear
about and they want to try it and eight
from ten come again and buy again so
this is a nice rate maybe also a
question for you directly now Philips so
you have Ewing the demand is increasing
in a fast race you're you're still a
startup if I may say a small company how
does your company deal with the
fast-moving nature if you're such a
small company
what do you focus on
I mean sudden increase in demand and
also the regulatory obstacles will put
on workload onto your table how do you
deal with that I think it's important to
make a good product line for yourself to
see that you can give for every kind of
person something special but I think
there are so many products that people
are often overloaded they don't know
what they what they should buy because
they are not from this topic they are
not out of the cannabis industry or they
haven't been smoking before so they come
in and sometimes they are overloaded
with different oil concentrations I said
okay should it take to 5% to 10% to 20%
I don't know so I think it's important
to hold the product line small and good
and so you can can have something for
anybody and build a good Network it's
also important for the for the b2b and
so you're able to deliver nearly
everything what's your take on this I
would agree with my colleague on my
right about the consumers I think what
is unique in this business and we've
been in business for thirty years that
actually I have never met so well
educated consumers they study they study
the the stuff on the net
they're very educated and they're very
loyal so this will be my point that if
you deliver the right really what you
say consumers will stay with you okay
Chris how do you see it from your
perspective yes I believe we are dealing
with a more educated client than we were
dealing with five years ago or six years
ago and absolutely we're learning and
learning to help feed the need that
those educated and buyers have but I
think the bigger opportunity is those
that have no idea what CBD is I have no
idea what cannabis is never heard of an
endocannabinoid system and are just
looking to feel better to meet a need
that they have and what we're doing is
working on our messaging and our
packaging to just offer that you know I
want to sleep better I want to feel
better
I want to get rid of information I want
to get rid of pain and then create a
product that says that that we don't I
think one of the challenging things in
our industry is that there's a certain
segment of our clients that want to know
the percentage and the genealogy and the
seeds and where it was grown others just
want to know is it good is it going to
help me where can I get it and we have
to be able to speak to both those type
of clients so it already came through
and some of the answers and now we're
moving on to the regulatory question of
this panel kai you're gonna be up in a
sec but basically so we have hindrances
for example not being able to talk about
it health claim issues and so forth and
which registration is important in this
context what would you say kai what
what's the homework that has to be done
when selling a CBD product first few the
most common product we have at the
moment is the the supplement so it's a
supplement to your normal diet and it's
labeled as a supplement then you have to
notify your product in the supplementary
register and you have to label it
correctly due to the you supplement
directives and you have to give notice
that it's out of reach of children and
you have to have you have to name the
the main ingredient and you have to do
that pretty correctly and then you can
sell it as a supplement the the other
way is so they are the problem is that
you can't make a health claim that's I
think this is the the biggest problem
for the industry because if you have a
nice brand in a nice shop and the
consumer comes in and asked what this
for I can't tell you what that doesn't
make sense you know so in the in the
future the companies have to work on on
that and the you legal framework offers
two options you can apply to get into
the EU health claims catalog or you can
register your product as a traditional
herbal medicine then you of course have
to prove the the effects or the health
claims
you you want to make you have to some
research some studies and database on
that too to be able to register as some
kind of this product yeah
so hearing that wouldn't it basically
make more sense to go the pharmaceutical
route so you are able to talk about it
to the consumer also thinking about the
consumers interest in transparency in
this context wouldn't that what's all
your opinions on that question I mean if
you make if you make a health claim and
even if if you if someone else makes a
health claim for you on your product UN
danger that you your product will be
deemed as a medicine according to the
medicine act like a presentation
medicine present at once that's nine
metal and yeah that's that's that's the
risk you you you and you if you have if
you want to become a real medicine like
according to the AMG the medicine law
then this is very complicated this costs
a lot of money's clinical studies trials
possible double-blind et cetera that's
over the top I think because it's just a
supplement it's just it's intended for
homeostasis for being balanced and not
for curing diseases so we have to
actually you have to work and find a
workaround in in that okay Chris yeah I
don't think it's as complicated as that
I think that it gets more complicated
because people want to make claims
because they want to tell you all the
amazing things that they've felt that
this plant and this product has done but
the reason CBD works is because it gives
the information to your body to help it
heal itself and if we just explain to
people that this aids in the relief of
temporary sleeplessness this supports
you being able to have less inflammation
in your body if you use the right
vocabulary in the right words as the
guidelines of the different regulatory
bodies bodies in each individual country
it's easy where it becomes hard is when
people say it cures this my dog now
walks
those type of things are you don't you
and that's the challenge and we're one
of the only major CBD companies there's
not received a warning letter from the
FDA in the United States because we
follow those guidelines 100% and it's
very important that we do that and as an
industry and as a community that we
support companies that do that and we
don't follow the easy route the
temporary route of a quick sale because
we want to say this one thing and if we
just learn the education and learn the
way to say it it's it's a lot simpler
woman do you have anything to add yeah
we we don't use claims as you know we
sell cosmetic products we have the plans
to upgrade to some medical device which
we need some studies but this is back to
the point you know we should consumers
are educated you know they do study so I
think that we should just I would say
guide and education you know was calling
admissions so this is the right way
we should not say we should not use hard
work words but we know how you know
Europe is very precise with you sexually
so let's get a bit more specific on that
one so best practice you selling it but
you're not allowed to talk about it how
do you do it Philip this is a very good
question
it's how I told you before the most
people come already informed to the shop
but for sure a lot of times the people
come in and tell you about their issues
and if it helps or not but you have to
say you can cannot give any answers for
this because you're not allowed you're
not a pharmacy you're not a doctor you
can try it for this this is what you can
say maybe some other consumers or
customers already have an experience
with the same topic and they talk to
each other this is also an a possibility
but do people understand it when you say
you're not allowed to to inform about
some health claims or anything they
understand it and they just try it and
when they try it they come back how do
these consumers educate themselves
outside of your shop there so they come
educated who how do they get the
information
do you have any ID on that I think you
can find a lot of in the Internet the
problem in the Internet is that there
are a lot of informations which are not
founded just opinions and then and this
is a problem I think so we need more
official website official organizations
where the people can inform by
themselves ok anybody anything to add so
let's address this specific topic novel
food in this context because it's been
in the media a lot in recent weeks how
do you guys live with the novel food
regulation at this point maybe it's the
same with the FDA approval that stands
in the room how do you go about this
Chris maybe from the FDA perspective
please sure so the FDA in the United
States and the novel foods here in
Europe is different regulatory boards
run those and we're working closely with
each one of those to make sure that we
already meet all of the guidelines for
those in our manufacturing and
distribution and testing processes and
we're working with them to make sure
that when available we'll be ready to
get those certifications but until that
point nobody said we can't move forward
so we're acting business as usual and as
they ask for more information about our
products more information about the
industry we're providing those we're
working with lobby groups we're working
with industrial and industry groups in
42 different countries to be able to do
so Kai from a legal perspective what
would you recommend companies in regard
to novel food how would you what would
you say to them if they want to set up a
business now on CBD yeah we have seen a
lot of new developments in the last
month regarding novel food
it started in Austria as Ministry of
Health in Austria advised the governor's
to enforce the novel food regulation and
then there must have been some
discussions on bilateral political in
Brussels and they decided in January to
change the noble food catalog before
that it was if the percentage of CBD is
higher than in the original plant
so it's this left room for
interpretation and nowadays it is all
extracts from from from or canopy no
it's ex-fix
extracts are novel food so what is what
is an extract yeah what's the definition
what's the interpretation of an extract
and then you can yeah you need to
solvent if you if your extract some some
solvent method or some some solvent
stuff and then you start the extraction
process it's still as I learned it's
still how planned then but you change
the percentages so you enrich and you
you you make you you make it more from
from the stuff you want and you you get
the stuff out you download and at this
point you are in the nobler food
directive the normal food directive is
applicable there to your to your product
so and we see that in the bvl next door
is the Food Authority of Germany it's
they published in a new entry on their
web page where they explicitly say if
you're in which your product with CBD
it's it's noble food so yeah I don't
know what's going to happen the next six
nine month we saw the example in Austria
the the Ministry of Health and
instructing the governor's to enforce
the novel food directive you can read it
in on the Food Safety Authority in
Ireland on that webpage if we get in our
cases of extracts of products you think
X 2 it's there we'll go after them
but they also say and this is yeah the
bottom line I guess right now which also
I have published in his paper in their
paper if you find a method which which
allows you that you have the full plant
and you don't you down in which
something like you like to count press
like a traditional manufacturing Prak
practice you on the safe side and you
can use that product
but what I've learned also is that
companies don't like that because the
oil which uses extracts is easier to use
is consumer friendly or people like it
more to use it's it's not as dark and a
sticky and it just looks nicer and it's
not as complicated to use a code press
method so yeah but the future will I
think we will have some some some
developments in the next near future on
how the authorities react on that
problem so maybe Philip and Roman a
question for you next so we have these
regulatory obstacles what do you do when
you get confronted with a new situation
do you have workarounds for this what
would you recommend yes we have grants
in the first step Ostia it happened at
first there we had to change quickly the
declaration just as a flavor product
again how it was before some years ago
but this is just just a short
perspective I think you have to change
the process after after producing for a
longer timeframe but also we have a an
exciting I to to the new regulation in
this market because I think how Young
said it's about six nine and six to nine
months and we will know more and till
this time we have to have workarounds
how I said and there are different ways
to do it different declaration different
declaration cold-pressed stuff and these
things yeah this is the same like in the
whole market you have to stay very
flexible at the moment because there's
no good regulation this null food
situation actually has been the same
almost for year and a half it's about
the execution of the null food how you
know so we were aware of this a year ago
so simply we do not claim on the back we
are food supplement because then your
null food so there ways how to white you
know you can market some products as a
topical uses or cosmetics and you know
you have sometimes vitamin C which you
put on the skin or you put belong the
tank you know is very this is how we do
it and in some cases you know we have
purely cosmetic products creams which
are in C P and P portal so we know it's
it's a cosmetic product so it's not only
you know you can we have many products
we do not have any food supplement has
anybody applied for the novel food
regulation yet know a lot but we know
they were of one of the first companies
more than a year ago was one Czech
company we know this was seems from
March last year so he's a quite some
time okay I want Stan it's from 2016 and
they even haven't passed the first stage
they which means they couldn't provide
the toxic toxicological and survey that
the product isn't harmful to the
consumer
so we heard from Chris Chris is in
dialogue with the FDA in dialogue with
the regulatory bodies now from a
European perspective we all know the
European industrial hemp association was
at the uau Commission recently people
are trying to find a dialogue if you
look at the media though it sometimes
seems as in them how should the industry
take action against these obstacles in
your opinion how should the industry
organize themselves to make the product
accessible to a wider consumer range
sorry I know about the European
industrial hemp Association you know
they do efforts lobbying that you know
this would pass and that cannabinoids
would not be a novel food art in certain
milligrams per day we fully support this
and I think they've been quite
successful but I'm not a regulatory
person this will be the only comment
from this side hi what's your opinion
how should one organize oneself I
suggest some decent litigation on this
so that you you can you can continue to
distribute your products the authorities
would have to issue a distribution ban
official distribution ban and you can
take legal remedies against this
distribution ban and they can only issue
an immediate enforcement so that you
really have to stop to sell these
products just in case of of a danger of
the consumer and as we now see BDS has a
good safety profile the World Health
Organization published the CBD report
last June and they found out that there
are no side effects they gave people
over 3-month 300 milligram to fawn and
milligram per day and no side effects
shout shout up so this can't be an
argument so you can distribute your
products until the end of the pivotal to
the final legal decision and that may be
can take three four or five years so I
think this will be this will be sorted
out about litigation if the if the
company's doesn't down the nerve another
food directive doesn't stop the
companies then it has to go to court if
you look to the UK still Europe UK
cannabis trade association is
instructing a law firm to go and take
action Chris do you think that's the
right approach to instruct a law firm to
take action or do you think it should be
more I don't know a nice dialogue on
that area well I know for us we work
with the European help Association we
work with the cannabis associations we
work with the USF authority we work with
just about any trade association out
there because we know that there's not
enough being done right so whether it's
legal action whether it's lobbying
whether it's going to your different
political representative and knocking on
their door I think more of that has to
happen I think we all have to internally
regulate ourselves and we have to
internally
cooperate and help make sure that the
people that play well together do well
and the people that are trying to force
their own agenda don't that's great now
in the description of the panel there
was also the competition from Big Pharma
was in there is do you have competition
by Big Pharma and how does it reflect on
your daily business let's start with
Phillip maybe here at the moment I can
not say that we have a competition with
the Big Pharma because the reason why
people buy these products is to go away
from the Big Pharma to go back more to
nature and to natural producers so when
we produce it in in Austria we have our
hemp fields and it's all organic grown
and the people know it and it's
transparent I think they'd like to get
more suction product than final medicine
from from the pharmacy but it's up to
the type of customer also Roman do you
have big farmers a threat we don't we
don't see them as a threat I think this
could be opportunity because they will
focus on some other aspects where we we
cannot compete and we don't want to
compete with them we have our experience
where we already cooperate with fight or
Pharma producer fairly big one so we can
work together
Chris how is it from a u.s. perspective
I think globally that any pharmaceutical
company that wants to come into the
market is only going to help educate
help normalize and help get more people
using it
I'm currently epidemics is a $32,000 a
year pharmaceutical I don't feel any
competition from somebody that's going
to sell at that high level and be a you
know basically a pharmaceutical drug
like to his point people are looking for
natural alternatives to give their body
the information to heal itself they're
not looking for another opioid right no
to take a step back from a wave maybe
from the regulatory topics so the panel
is called mainstreaming of CBD now it
was just a very obvious question but
still what is
your outlook on this how will the market
develop will CBD become a mainstream
developer but product in your eyes
absolutely it has to it's one of the
most innovative most effective things
that's come out in history right it's
been around forever and we're just now
starting to realize the effects of it
thank you you know to those that
discovered the endocannabinoids system
and you know all the people that have
been pushing the cannabis agenda for
decades and we're all standing on their
shoulders and I appreciate all the work
and fighting that they've done to show
the medical benefits of the cannabis
plant and now it's only getting to the
point where it's normalizing where
people just it makes no sense that this
isn't the same as craft beer because
right now you know just imagine if craft
beer came out as a trend at the same
time prohibition ended right that's
exactly what this is right
our new craft beer is coming out exactly
when Prohibition ended and it's going to
be normal and everybody's gonna take it
and you're gonna grow it in your own
backyard you're gonna make it and you're
gonna buy it at your own grocery store
and you're gonna buy it from your doctor
and you're gonna have all sorts of
different flavors and find ways to get
it and it's just gonna be completely
normal
how will the intake be Chris will be
sipping or smoking CBD whichever way you
want
for me I love the topical Zinner
liposomal product because it just works
so fast because we have Martha Stewart
apparently doing some developments
jellybean CBD is in the air all these
news flash has been about I appreciate I
appreciate again people looking for
innovative ways to take CBD and and I'm
sure my my pen a fellow panelists have
some input on this and you know I love
that Martha Stewart is bringing this
more normal right
but we all know that a jelly beans not a
great way to take something that's going
to help your body right it's it's a fun
recreational way to take some other
things but CBD is probably not the best
in my opinion I agree with this we
directly see it with our customers
because it's not just a trend I think
because they come one time to try it but
they come again and they say it from
10.com
again and so I think it will normalize
how I say in Europe not so much people
know about CBD now but this city market
is running and it's growing very fast
and I think it will normalize we just
will see how the how the regulation will
happen roman that cannabis was called 1
million plant back in the history
because you know we started to make
robes for the sailing the end of food
and each part of the plant was used CBD
just on top of this I think is a
revolutionary I think this process
cannot be stopped I think that
regulating would help us as well
organize producer because what we found
out a lot of I would say producers which
are now not consistent which are not
fair to the consumers but I think sky's
the limit and we just go should work
together and focus in the future ok
wanna add anything how do you think the
market will develop from a legal point
of view maybe as well yeah the the the
interesting question will be how the
authorities will deal with another food
directive in the next 6 to 12 month we
haven't seen any I've no real cases on
on distribution bans or anything like
that
I had to CBD sample imports which were
stopped at the customs it in car school
one with with the the reasoning that CBD
is medicine and the import license
wasn't there so then they examined the
product and realized oh it's only it's
only a 30 30 milligram daily intake so
it's not the relevant for a
pharmacological effect and they stopped
the proceeding and the other sample they
had health claims so they could say ah
it's a medicine it's a presentation
medicine and we we keep we keep it we so
that's the only two cases I had but it
would be an interesting would be into
you have to see what what's going on the
next 12 month this will be an
interesting period I'm not quite sure
where we are on time you are very close
we have time for a couple of moments
let's hear for the panel thank you for
your attention for maybe two questions
one or two questions one or two anybody
have a question brief question no no all
right I have a question what what is it
gonna be full of CBD like you could put
CBD in a cream and a soap it up can we
have CBD infused strawberries or
chickens or beef jerky or coffee like
what's the limit is it gonna be in
everything we're just gonna put it in
the water what are we gonna do yeah I
hope that you folk that we continue to
focus on the high quality delivery
systems so that it's bioavailable and
people actually get the effects of it
and it just doesn't pass through our
body I think it's very important that we
continue to focus on full-spectrum oils
and really look at the science of bio
accessibility and bioavailability so
that will direct what we put it in I
have a comment to Kai I would never ever
expect that you will be able to register
traditional her parameters in the
product with cannabis this is impossible
because you need a 30 years of tradition
and you will never prove it I was
involved in over 100 applications of
registrations and this is not the case
this is not possible that's why there's
an exemption in these paragraphs but you
don't need 30 years and not necessarily
you need 30 years at least you need 15
into you and even this 15 need to be
connected to an indication and an
illness and post it's not there I don't
think you can say that I don't think you
can say that there that I don't think
you can say CBD is not connected to an
indication for more than 10 or 15 years
thank you so um we actually I'm
wondering I feel that CBD is super
popular in a certain group Gweneth
Paltrow lifestyle world because I keep
reading only in that context about CBD
so why do you guys think that is why do
you think it's popular with the planet
Skaro
personally best well she told me no no I
mean so to be more precise I feel it's
very popular in this world around
lifestyle yoga consciousness fashion so
kale yeah thank you for me what I've
what I've found is that people are
looking for alternatives and that group
that market share is looking for are
alternatives they don't want to buy
pharmaceuticals anymore they want to
biohack they want to neuro hack they
want to improve their lives they want to
invest in their health not their
sickness so that's why they're making
these decisions and that's why they're
moving forward and that's why things
like Gwyneth Paltrow and I think just
recently just in timber Justin Bieber's
wife was talking about it and it's all
over the place
right and yeah it's not what I don't
think one of the Kardashians have talked
about it yet but still its overall
overall CBD is is moving into the health
and wellness space which is much bigger
and much more impactful than dealing
with indications oh yeah and I think the
trend is basically going back to the
nature stuff and I just think that this
kind of people when I can say it like to
support support this trend and this is
why it happens is there a way to ensure
that you're getting quality CBD I mean
because now you look everywhere you see
CD this CBD that is it hemp derive is it
made enough at like how do you know that
you're getting
bioavailable or good stuff or quality
you just see they just it's almost like
they just throw three letters on a
package and expect you to believe it
like how can people figure out what's
good you
exactly right that's that is happening I
haven't seen any of that in this room or
this community or no one here will do
that but absolutely there are people
that are using CBD as a marketing term
like they did acai berries way back in
the day and CBD is much more than a
movement or a fad like that and it's
more like the new aloe vera and it's
going to be in a lot of things and it's
going to be there and you would
definitely want to know the quality
where it came from most of the company's
up here all of them provide their
certificates of analysis online so that
you can see the high quality that's
available there and additionally you can
read about it and see who's
participating in these different
organizations to move it forward that
are participating with groups like this
and where's all of this being grown like
is it all hemp derived is it all being
grown somewhere or yeah I mean you don't
have to tell me no I just this is what
we do as a company you know we as I
mentioned the beginning we control from
the field seats to the final product we
are for full transparency
you know certificate of analysis MSDS
whatever you call it and this is this
how it works on the long term because
you can find the products with the CBD
tag on but if once you analyze you will
find hardly a trace of CBD these things
are happening
we have farms throughout Europe and in
the United States we grow in both places
and we're growing him that was my next
question do you think that there's gonna
be like a huge global expansion of CBD
hemp and maybe like Portugal or
Macedonia or some of these not just
Canada oh my god I think every third
question I got here is I'm growing hemp
where do you want to buy it so
absolutely people are growing it all
over the place I think the challenge is
because hemp is such an amazing planet
it takes all the amazing things out of
the ground that it does really good
things for you but also if you don't
grow in the right place it takes all the
crap out of the ground it brings it
right into you so you have to really be
careful of where that source is coming
from there where you're getting and and
back to this sorry no hem now is being
used in everywhere we build houses it's
reducing automotive industry I don't
there was a study what Hamm does for
environment you know
fifteen tons of carbon monoxide per year
is cleaned by one hectare of hemp you
know I mean these are this is this is
public data so we should support hand on
all aspects not only because of the CBD
that's a good point we have time for one
more question and then we're below hello
everybody so my question is around when
we're talking about CBD we're really
talking about the the flower that does
not have the THC in it a lot of times
we're not specifically only focused on
on the CBD there's also a lot of other
cannabinoids that are not mentioned that
are included in those in those in these
full-spectrum extracts underlying about
yeah so with cannabis there's there's
very specific effects that you'll find
with various strains my question is
really around the idea of strain hunting
in the CBD market and what are the I
just anecdotes on that topic seem like a
really interesting area of discussion I
just can say that Europe is much
different than the US because you have
control strains and the seeds and I
think Europe is not competitive here
with Switzerland and US and I think this
could be potentially a problem in the
future but yes this is this is the thing
that we have a catalogue of strains
which we can we are allowed to use and
in some countries you have to chance to
select out of this seeds but in a and
now that countries not so in Germany for
sure not your chests allowed to bring
out the seeds and harvest what you got
all right thank you all very much let's
hear it for our panel I'm sorry I don't
have time
but I'm sure you could talk to them in
the hallway that was fantastic
Philip Rebecca Romijn Chris and hi
[Music]