unless you've been really living under a
rock and you're involved in the
following not involved and fall in the
international scene you may not know
what blockchain is but the next speaker
is an expert on the matter she is an
ex-marine expatriate who's stationed
here in Germany who writes about
cannabis and business news and breaks
stories here in Germany and her company
medpay Rx is an innovative blockchain
company and she'll tell you what that
entails so please give a warm welcome
for ms Marguerite Arnold
[Applause]
thank you all
I mean I'm after lunch from the act but
thank you all for making it back thank
you also thank you very much to Alex and
team for making the sophomore year of
the ICBC
what it is right can we have a round of
applause they have worked their butts
off right so yes my name is Marguerite
Arnold and I'm here to give you a very
quick easy deep dive in 15 minutes on a
new technology called blockchain and how
it is going to disrupt our already
disruptive business and it is going to
it's gonna be big there are lots of ways
to think about this right but one of the
easiest ways to begin to understand how
this technology works and how you can
apply it in what you do is to understand
that it is a protocol so the geeks in
the audience who know what tcp/ip is for
voice it's what makes your handiwork
right or those people who understand
what HTTPS is which really allows you to
type in google.com as opposed to a
string of numbers in your browser and
have that website come back those are
protocols this is what blockchain is
it's just a little bit more geeky and
it's coming out of the banking industry
in particular and it functions along a
pretty simple idea kyc now for the
uninitiated and audience and the people
who are still asleep this is not a new
brand of cannabis flavored sex jell-o
they maybe you should it actually comes
out of banking geek speek and it means
know your client in other words you need
to know everything about your clients so
they're not a terrorist and where they
live and what their bank account is at
but within the context of what
blockchain really is going to be beyond
banking it really means being able to
understand and verify if not
authenticate many many different points
of data in a complex ecosystem without
necessarily having all of the knowledge
that you would traditionally have or
think that you need and if that sounds
like the cannabis business in general
yes
and that is exactly where its eyes face
but again this is kind of abstract so
I'm going to give you a little bit of a
fun example about how to understand this
kind of verification in this kind of
environment so I've already told you my
name and you can both hear and see me
whether you think about that or not
those are three different independent
verification points that tells your
brain you're here in Berlin and not on
Mars and if you're on Mars we'll check
in with you later
some of you yes also know me as an
industry journalist and if you don't you
can google me that's another kind of
independent verification I'm also a
blockchain enthusiast if not expert but
where does that come from so let me give
you a little bit more information that
you can also verify via very different
ideas and channels as I say to all of my
German friends yes ich bin ein
amerikaner in flew clear of on Trump I'm
an American refugee I'm actually the
very very old German family that I can
trace back close to a thousand years to
actually come back here to live and
that's really cool but I did grow up
I did grow up in an unusual family no
that's not me in the picture that was a
good friend of my dad's my two paternal
uncles were people you probably know or
heard heard of one of them was a guy
named Peter Drucker you know the father
of business and the information worker
and the other one deciphered the Dead
Sea Scrolls so it was interesting and
and this was a little fella that I met
at the age of eight the father of that
is a guy named gray Walter he was one of
the early early pioneers really in in
robotics and cyber kinetics and where a
lot of this has come from and turtle I
met this guy when I was eight years old
he would scuttle around on the floor
came in order to go to like plug himself
back in the wall when he ran out of
juice and I met this guy at the age of
eight when the world was just meeting
r2d2 for the first time so I think that
this was love at first sight but beyond
that that's kind of where I've worked
and I've taken elements of this from
banking and technology that I've worked
on and and and the kinds of industries
that I've pulled together of my life to
try and bring together what I'm doing
now but if you want to think about what
blockchain is at its fundamental level
it is a language that allows robots and
computers to alt and occasionally humans
while they still let us to all talk to
one another in a new and different way
and they also it also allows people to
connect very different sources of data
and people and enterprises in a new kind
of ecosystem all blockchains also use
coins or tokens or smart contracts these
terms are used interchangeably and
increasingly it's not up to you to
define what those are it's other
compliance systems and i'ma get it to
that in a second but this make no
mistake about it is the backbone
infrastructure technology between behind
IOT which is the Internet of Things it's
going to be interacting with with AI
it's going to be responsible for all
sorts of automation drones I joke about
that one's coming soon it's a wild stuff
but how do you use it and as cannabis
executives
OMG and
thing to deal with right so so which
blockchain do you use as their a couple
right there's Bitcoin which was a block
team before it was a coin there's a
theorem there is ether they're all
different and which cyber currency
because they're all tied to those I'm
gonna make it easy for you cost speed
and energy efficiency are the three
things that you should immediately be
looking for because ultimately all block
chains also use electricity so at every
hop of the node they're using
electricity to do something so you're
looking for that as well
but what you're really looking for right
now because the block chains that are
out there are pretty impressive already
is what are called taps now this is just
you know short term for distributed
application if you've taken a look at
the pretty front end it looks like a
regular app the difference is that we
are not tying into any sort of
centralized system this is all
decentralized from the back and I'm
going to show you a little bit about the
engineering but beyond the technology
you've got to look for what that gap
actually does does it do something that
solves your business problem and if it
doesn't keep moving this is the back end
a very artistic representation of what
our system looks like the doctor here we
never issue a coin as medpay rx we never
issue a coin we never sell it it's never
going to be available on any exchange it
cannot be stolen because it's not worth
anything in the traditional idea we have
taken the idea of what a prescription is
it's a contract between multiple parties
and two payers and we've set up a
banking system to allow that to happen
we never transfer medical data on this
what happens is that the doctor is the
issuing bank
they're the ones who issue the coin and
it goes first to the insurer who
hopefully not only underwrites it but
approves it it then goes to the patient
who is able to copay and forward that to
the bank while pushing well sending a
push notification to the distributor to
tell you guys you know the real-time
information about where your product is
in play and where is it going we deal
with rebates as well and I can give you
more information if you want to stop by
the booth the idea was not to promote
medpay but i want to show you the
difference between what we're doing and
an ICO because I'm sure you guys have
all heard about this too so what is an
ICO
an ICO is just Geek Speak for an initial
coining sometimes they're called TG tte
events token generation events it's
basically the same idea a private entity
or even a nonprofit or a government if
she's a coin it could be for term a
raise of money it could be for a
community etc but the moment that you're
charging a customer for that coin for
whatever it is that you're doing it
you're in the financial space and
everywhere now no matter where you are
that is federal banking law that you
have to be in compliance with so I'm
gonna back up here second this has to be
in compliance if we rolled out correctly
with German banking Jeremy banking
privacy and medical privacy law this is
prescriptions that's the idea where
we're putting a digital focus in process
on a system that has already been
established under compliance this is
something that for the financial geeks
in the room looks very much like a stock
issuance right because that's what it is
and that is why this is also so
incredibly dangerous right now for this
industry especially in the United States
for reasons that include everything
about you cannot have a bank account and
in other places you have to make sure
that this model is also in compliance
with everything else that you're doing
so there's nothing wrong with this and
in fact this is a very smart way to
raise money for things like drones I
mean I joke about this all the time
right drones are going to be paid for by
cyber currency a lot of the top
companies are raising money for them and
all airspace is going to be controlled
low-lying air spaces can be controlled
by blockchain systems which are going to
be paid for by rent with cyber currency
and airspace does in fact have a value
however crazy that may sound in that
particular kind of instance great but
then what are you going to be carrying
so in other words all of the steps that
you have to go through for a successful
IC o----
you're going to have to go through to
raise money successfully via other ways
anyway so if you do and I
see oh you better be in compliance you
better have a good lawyer you better be
working closely with a bank everywhere
so those are the those are the issues
it's not that they're necessarily all
bad it's just that they're very
dangerous if you don't know what you're
doing so the takeaways because I'd like
to end this early because I know there
are some questions if you're looking at
this in trying to evaluate blockchain
for your business I would stay away from
the hottest greatest cannabis blockchain
out there and there are a couple out
there they could be great they could not
be right look for what the gaps do on
that existing blockchain do they solve
your problem do they not are they
compliance are they in compliance and
are they in compliance in all the
different industry verticals that they
are acquired to be in compliance with I
use a banking app that allows you to buy
cannabis for example in Canada you're
gonna have to make sure that your users
are over 21 those are kinds of ideas
right as my late uncle Peter used to say
technology is just a tool and it doesn't
solve your problem why bother with it so
look for that too and icos and token
generation have their place but just be
careful
so on that note I think I'm going to end
this and open it up for any questions
there might be and go from there do we
have a question or to anyone who just
raised your hand I can see you have a
question about the bit chain of the
blockchain what kind of see where oh
there he is over there
okay I'm coming I've eaten a lot of
bread I think I have gained some weight
lots of cake thanks a lot for that very
informative presentation would you maybe
in regards to the ico have any source or
credible good information that you could
recommend about about what like where
you can find out if you're doing it and
are you doing it in Germany swiss-based
Swiss bass okay so the Swiss actually I
mean again there that's wit Switzerland
and a couple of countries in the Far
East are actually good places to
actually do icos but here's the next
problem so the rumor in Frankfurt last
month was that no German bank would be
accepting ICO funds no matter where
those funds were raised and for what a
purpose why because even if they knew
the identity of your of you and all the
people you were getting money from they
could not trace the source of the coin
remember these all of these are
anonymous coins they couldn't appear out
with the coins are so the German
authorities are not really hip to this
and if you're going to be doing business
in Germany raising money by an IC o----
is that's one of the things you have to
consider if you're going to be doing
business in Switzerland if you're gonna
have one of these things happening in
Russia with the funds or maybe Singapore
or etc but the banks are a lot more
interested in this kind of activity then
where are you going to spend those funds
and that's one of the problems
downstream with us so that's just an
issue just mean there are people who are
doing it successfully but you just have
to be aware like how secure are
blockchains or bitcoins or whatever
they're called from like government
intrusion like what's to stop some
government from just shutting everything
down and then everybody's out well I
mean that's that that's actually a
couple of questions but let me just
answer this first one on government
interference in cyber currency the
Chinese government actually has just
moved in to stop exchanges and they
don't like ICS very much either if you
think that this is out there and not
regulated and they can't do it yeah they
can just cut the switch off they can do
a lot of tracing all of the cyber
currency that is traded in the United
States right now has got to be listed on
these exchanges and the IRS when you
sell them looks at this you know as a
capital gain I did
it's changing quickly so again be
careful alright thank you very much it's
all the time we have we really really
appreciate it Margaery let's hear it
again and I'm sure she'd love to talk to
you more in the hallway can I just
mention one last thing yes so those of
you have not signed up for this fill
Senate Ella is running that he's
organizing the German patient roundtable
and it's an idea that's intended to work
with all its here and but do it in a new
way you haven't signed up for him please
go see him it's about patient access and
it's really important but thank you
again all of you Thank You ICBC thank
you for being such a great audience and
please come me come and see me in the
back write questions thank you again one
more time thank you
[Applause]
you