we've got a real heavy hitter today that
I'd really wanted to speak to you guys
he's a he's a really we're going to talk
about all the bunny Kai's in the
industry and who's who's who's raising
what and what's happening and all the
venture funds there's there's one group
that really stands out among the rest
Arcadian and we're fortunate enough to
have the founder of Arcadian here too
you know
who's basically been through it all and
now can talk about what's the analogy
for foreign and international markets
and what's happened domestically
we're really lucky to have him here he's
a former quarterback of the Philadelphia
Eagles and he is an extremely
accomplished young man he's only 37
years old and I'm really excited to have
him here please everyone give it up for
mr. Matt Nordgren you guys great to be
here Alex thank you wonderful event you
put on here bringing so many great
people together feel privileged to have
the opportunity to speak to you today
one also thank ICBC the staff i've had
an opportunity to meet several of you
now in different venues you do a great
job and Berlin Wow thank you for hosting
this and having us really fun experiment
yesterday which was put on some Nikes
and just ran around the city had never
been here before really excited to just
get in the culture and ask people
questions the first thing that struck me
was just the amount of construction here
I mean it's insane how much is being
built right one can only attribute that
to potential tax revenue from cannabis I
guess and then Alex told me this has
been going on 20 years so it's a it's a
really interesting environment one that
I think will benefit from our industry a
lot just like the rest of the world and
like to see Berlin taking that step my
name is Matt
I run a fund called Arcadian exist in a
private equity group running a large
family office out of Los Angeles which
years ago we determined we were in the
right place at the right time and
sitting here today feel pretty good
about that fact I think California is a
market that we can prove businesses at
scale the name of the fund y Arcadian it
means rustic or rural which applies but
also to proceed without worry which I
think all of us in here have a certain
level of confidence that you need and I
think as investors you have to have even
additional confidence when you're
putting a lot of dollars to work in this
space one really interesting question
I'd like to pose to the group here just
so I can get a little bit of an idea who
we have in the room but I think also for
the rest of the room raise your hand if
you are involved in running an
opportunity or operating a business
well great about half the room thank you
what about how many people in here are
in search of an opportunity or investing
into an opportunity or a group of people
that are really good at something raise
your hand please
Wow
good number of invest okay everyone who
raised their hand first turn around and
figure out who those guys are we've
officially started dating you just have
to know who's who and so for me you know
knowing what kind of audience you have
is really important too and it sounds
I've got a pretty diverse group in fact
Alex told me I think there's 40
countries represented here I mean that's
pretty phenomenal really excited to have
such a such a big group of people but I
think you can boil it down to investors
and guys who have opportunities good to
see there's both here in my walking
around in Berlin yesterday another thing
happened I was looking for a gift to
bring home and ended up buying this book
that was on Jesus and God I couldn't
read it because it's not in my language
but ultimately I knew at that store
was so I felt like it was kind of a fun
gift to bring home during doing that the
guy asked me what I was in Berlin for
cuz I'd said I was never here and told
him why I was buying this gift I said
I'm here for cannabis business and he
told me he said you're buying a god book
and you're in the cannabis business that
doesn't seem right and it was an
interesting pour because I got to
explain to the guy that even in the
Bible there's about 11 or 12 verses that
in some way talk about this plant being
something that would be acceptable with
words like what's put on this earth
Smith for the consumption of mankind
right this was not designed by us
interesting conversation there which led
to something else that I want to talk
about before I get into the business of
cannabis why are we all here we're here
because there's something about this
plant that actually works and resonates
with people what is that what is the
opportunity let's strip everything away
and talk about why this works it's
because that plant which was given to us
from the dawn of inception you could
take everything back to algae fungi
bacteria you can reverse-engineer this
stuff and figure that out I am a God guy
personally but I think science is pretty
well proven that we all came from algae
fungi and bacteria in the very early
stages of all civilization that we know
today
this plant happens to produce something
that our body naturally produces and
that's the cannabinoids right so if you
think about this it's so natural it
works with our body perfectly like a
puzzle piece that exists in the world
that is created naturally that can do
wonderful things for us so I think you
have to think about this business and
really strip away down to the science
what is the plant and the plant is a
technology people think of this is going
to be commoditized one day and maybe the
whole plant ends up being somewhat of a
commodity and prices drop but the plant
technology the science the the the bio
science that chemical properties in the
make up the make up the plant are where
the real opportunity is figuring out how
each of those interact with the human
body and what you can do
to benefit the world off the back of it
really interesting story that I think
you guys would enjoy our one of our big
investors got married in the Vatican
recently and in order to do that you
actually have to disclose everything
about your life to get approval to be
married in the Vatican he had to
disclose the fact that he produced a
large amount of cannabis very
interesting point Pope issued from the
Pope's office issued a statement that
the Pope has no problem with cannabis
this is like the most I can't wait for
this to hit the papers and I'm one of
the owners of High Times and cannabis
cup and I hope we get to publish it but
this is a fact
this just came back we he was allowed to
get married in there and the official
statement was in moderation we have no
we think about cannabis just like we do
alcohol and tobacco great I can't wait
to go back to Texas and tell all my
Christian conservative Republicans there
that story the point of all this is
before we can really understand the
business I think you have to understand
what this plant is what it can do at the
science level what where the plant came
from and why it's been withheld from us
for so many years it's not created that
way it's business it's Pharma it's
politics there's other reasons that
haven't allowed it to be available now
the world has a voice and it will be
what are you gonna do to capitalize on
that opportunity while doing a great
thing in talking about some of those
cannabinoids there's about 125 or so in
the plant we still don't really know a
lot of research has to happen for us to
feel comfortable but I think that's
coming and we haven't had the resources
to do it which we now are THC CBD we
talked about a lot in here what are the
ramifications of those two isolated
cannabinoid molecules don't forget about
CB c CB g CB g a CB n ste
a CA th cbcb da
every one of these has a tremendous
effect on the body cbv appetite
suppressant it's one of my favorite
thing to talk to new cannabis people
that want to learn about the plant
there's actually an appetite suppressant
molecule in there like who would have
thought of that but that exists so what
is the opportunity I see the cannabis
opportunity in three main phases the
first phase and every market sort of
that we've studied starts this way and
kind of grows at its own pace depending
on politics but eventually they all kind
of grow the same way in order for there
to be an industry have to have
cultivation have to have some sort of
retail and have to manufacture it I see
that as always as phase number one as
that starts to scale which we see now in
the United States and through Canada or
starting to see consolidation you
eventually do see prices respond
accordingly which would be decrease
phase two which I think happens just
after you create the basic fundamentals
of a new industry is the servicing
aspect once you have the plant in your
market once you have a place you can buy
it whether it's physician or a retail
establishment what about the data how do
we understand our consumer what about
customer retention how do we continue to
use it use that information to service
our customers what about media events
what about different kinds of software
that exists in every other industry with
the stigma around this one those big
companies don't feel comfortable
addressing the cannabis industry until a
point in time so I think you have a
second wave of opportunity in the server
seeing an ancillary category the third
ends up being off the back of that once
everything gets figured out in the
industry the machines built now you have
brands all sorts of opportunities off
the back end I kind of think about it
like gold mining right it's a typical
example you hear a lot in this industry
go back to the gold miners right there
has to be gold for there to be a
business right without cannabis we don't
or cannabinoids however you get them we
don't have a business but ultimately
those gold miners need picks and shovels
and boots and jeans in order to function
Levi's jeans for example started that
way and is still around then ultimately
you have to have a consumer for the gold
you got to have a ring you got to have a
watch right so I think cannabis industry
can be seen in similar phases you have
to have the gold you have to have ways
to run the business and then you got to
ultimately have a variety of consumers
to utilize the product within those
categories I think you have three
additional markets to address which is
medical we talked a lot about that in
here today because this is a medical
market you have the over-the-counter
market nutraceuticals and then you have
recreational we've seen this evolve in
every market as well similarly to the
different phases of the industry that
grow in the market you end up having
regulations set in that typically put
products in those three categories if
you can meet a certain level of
regulation no pesticide problems things
like that and you don't have any further
study
well now you probably have a
recreational product that you can infuse
in anything in the grocery store based
on a very low hurdle of regulation the
next hurdle might be such that you have
an over-the-counter product product that
you can charge a little bit more for has
gone through a certain level of study
but ultimately not enough to be
qualified as true medical product true
medical product will be the third
category where you have to go through a
rigorous amount of clinical trial
research and study in order to be
approved at that level of regulation so
I think you ultimately also see a
variety of levels
of product what does that ultimately
mean I think that means that every
person on planet Earth is a cannabinoid
consumer one day no disrespect to Henry
Rollins who said he's never touched it
before earlier no disrespect to the
gentleman who was just here hasn't
smoked in 20 years but I do think that
everybody when they understand the
science of this and they understand
where the industry is going I do think
you will see cannabinoid in every
product in every grocery store in
America think about b12
what's b12 well you all love it Omega
fish oil all these wonderful things that
have been proven to do some pretty
interesting effects for the human body
will happen in cannabis to those
cannabinoids I mentioned earlier you
might see c-23 who knows what they're
gonna brand it is but it'll pass a
certain level of regulation if it's just
medical it'll be a certification you
could put on a product because you can
isolate it and extract it now you can
infuse it in literally anything in the
grocery store then you could put that
brand on it so I do think that everybody
has the cannabis as the new salt
somebody said in my class one of my lot
of speeches and I thought that was
actually pretty interesting to think
about this way right I mean fungi
there's actually 10 times more amount of
fungi on planet Earth and there are
plants people don't realize the
symbiotic relationship that the fungi
has in the roots with the delivery of
oxygen and nutrients and all those other
things cannabinoid is a very basic human
element that we produce ourselves that
we can naturally get from the
environment so I think you have to look
at how big this industry can be and I do
think it will be everywhere in the world
at some level how I go about
investing in this space that's the
question we had to ask ourselves in
phase one things that require a license
things that touch the plant we felt that
the opportunity for that is in some
markets and most markets federally
illegal not something we could do in the
family office so we decided to look at
Phase two which was those businesses
that get built around it what we decide
to do from that standpoint was focus on
companies that have been around for a
number of years and have revenue growth
and can certify that they are in
compliance with federal law so we became
a good place for the industry's most
successful ancillary companies to come
to in order to receive capital but also
a big private equity firms experience on
what it means to provide growth equity
and then how do you prepare yourself for
the next phase a lot of our companies
are starting to mature high times we'll
have an offer on NASDAQ very soon
similar thesis with the rest of our
companies you get a company that's at
scale get liquidity get public currency
have some form of consolidation and then
you go out and try to provide capital
and other resources to other in other
businesses in that same vertical in
order to scale high x has no it doesn't
think it's the end-all be-all for
everybody it services a very specific
type of cannabis customer but the good
news is if you subscribe to the theory
that cannabinoids is the future then
that means every single person fits in
the cannabinoid category and everybody
has a different profile so everyone has
to be catered to differently now high x
can provide capital to those companies
and ultimately let them all grow in
service various demographic and
geographic regions so I think you're
going to see a lot of consolidation in
this industry you're seeing it right now
on the plant touching side think
valuations are as high as they'll be
over this next year or two and then I
think you see two three four years after
that consolidation of all the ancillary
companies and then two-three years after
that I think you started to seek
solid ation of brands one interesting
thing I think I always try to point out
based on all the things we've been
talking about the wide use of this plant
is that everybody's skill set is
transferable to cannabis there is so
much business opportunity and those of
us that have gotten in it early I think
have the most likelihood of success but
ultimately we want to encourage
everybody to be in this industry whether
you're graphic designer a tomato farm or
a finance person this industry requires
all of us in order to make it work the
one thing I can say based on that is
that I think the companies and the
people that I've seen not do well are
the ones that aren't very niche focused
it's very easy to get distracted in this
industry because there's a lot of great
things to do but I do think you know
what we're looking for and we're
investing in a company as somebody who's
solving a very specific problem at a
very high level right there is no
regulated business in the entire world
that you can do everything they regulate
it for a reason and it will be separated
into various points along the supply
chain
I think this industry will be the exact
same mostly because they like to tax it
but they also like to just regulate it
and keep control of things so I think
you have to solve specific pain points
you have to be really really really good
at something I don't think you can do it
all in our companies and our CEOs have
been proven to do that very well
what are some of those companies well I
can I kind of break the industry down
into a few segments you have production
you have cultivation you have
manufacturing phase one the ones that we
like to look at in the second phase our
business software business services
social media online media print media
vaporizers and accessories production
equipment and supplies HR data there's
an immense amount of industry that needs
to come into cannabis in order for it to
grow properly those are the type of
companies were looking for what's
interesting enough that happens is these
companies that are a couple years down
the road
for example let's use a company called
BDS analytics that were involved with
they're a point of sale data company
point-of-sale data exists everywhere
else but it doesn't exist in the space
because the big players Nielsen in the
United States for example doesn't feel
comfortable servicing the space so I can
go into a company and look at a company
that's got two three years of proven
revenue that I think is probably worth a
10 12 15 multiple based on what happens
if you're not servicing cannabis and
Nielsen was going to buy you for example
but because they service cannabis for a
proven business we'll get a five
multiple six multiple seven multiple we
basically get a 50% discount on a proven
business that has no legal constraints
and if we guess right and that company
ends up being the market winter when
Nielsen and those companies are ready to
buy I guarantee you they're big enough
they don't care the price they know they
have to have market share and they'll be
willing to buy the market so then you
have to ask yourself what companies
aren't attractive on an exit and what
are and that's ultimately a funds fund
manager and a fund investment committees
decision to try to sort through for
example banking banking is a major pain
point insurance major pain point the
likelihood that those don't get solved
is very low also the likelihood that
they want to buy an insurance or a bank
business
that's been around a couple years and
cannabis is also pretty low because
they'll be able to offer those exact
same products so from an investment
standpoint we decided not to pursue
those because of that factor although
they are pain points lots of pain points
just have to figure out the ones that
ultimately have value at the end of the
day we want to want to leave some time
for some questions but why am i up here
talking to you about all this I think
the answer probably is because if you're
gonna have chips in this space everybody
in here probably has a unique skill set
or a reason why they're in it having
exposure to a fund which I run one
there's multiple great funds there's
another investment group here Nick who's
speaking tomorrow his group's great
there's there's about 10 other funds in
the United States I think are at our
level all of them can give you exposure
to the space in a hedged way can get you
access to lots of great resources and
brainpower ultimately only making
whatever it is you decide to do a better
strategy by having a big shop with the
machine built around you to help grow
that business so I hope you do decide to
talk to somebody who runs a big
investment shops but focus on this space
because I do think it helps everybody
with whatever they're trying to do
individually really excited to be here
again I want to make one last point
which is I'm a whole plant guy and I
love the whole plant people and I'll
never change right that that's that's
sort of how I came into the industry as
being that type of consumer but look at
the United States market it's estimated
there's about 25 million consumers of
cannabis United States market 325
million people there so if we have an
objective to get this plant in the hands
of every single person we're gonna have
to understand what that means if this
room had a hundred people based on the
American numbers today which is a pretty
good market to scale thirteen percent
our current users or potential users of
the flower so
need to service that community that's a
lot of people 25 million is a big number
but there's 300 million other people
that will be new consumers how will they
be introduced to the cannabinoid crop if
you walk to room 100 people ninety
eighty seven other people would be very
tough to say hey you should come to
cannabis and just enroll at this plant
and smoke it now guy like me probably
would try to argue that but ultimately
it's about making sure that everybody
has a product that they're comfortable
with so those other 87% of people what
are we going to create for them is it
inedible is the topical is it a
sublingual I don't know but the
important thing is that everybody has
access to this cannabinoid whole plant
and business guys are trying to find
other ways to do that I hope we can all
have the same mission which is move this
industry forward thank you for having me
I met so let's plan for two more
additional questions I think then the
next panel is already starting so are
there any questions okay
hi Hendricks from where or where we
currently in Europe if you compare the
u.s. to Europe in terms of private
equity or venture capital great question
and the opportunity for investment funds
is really there because of the
institutional investors aren't really in
the space yet so I think even in America
you don't have that for Europe but
you're in phase one right you're trying
to still figure out how you're gonna
grow it where you're gonna sell it how
it's going to be manufacturers so you're
kind of in that first phase so depending
on the market the opportunity is just
where the market dictates Mexico we
helped write Mexico's policy we know
there's a handful of families that are
about to be announced that have that
they're at square one they're gonna
import from Canada for six to nine
months the likelihood that they need
services is not very high right now it's
a few years down the road so I think in
Europe you know your steps beyond that
but you're getting to the point now
where you want to understand data right
we heard people talk today about Germany
there's a business here and there's
20,000 but no one knows the data behind
them so I think the opportunity in
Europe is you can still get your hands
on great licensed businesses at a decent
a decent price and you can be on that
side there's but I do think the real
opportunity is in the next wave of
businesses you know I you can't even
find hardly a vape pen in Europe it's so
crazy right you know in California which
is the other benefit actually about
being in California you can you can test
businesses across every vertical in this
industry at scale right you have 35
million people you have 200 something
million that come through there every
year we've got a great market to test
any philosophy at massive scale to see
if it's gonna work so we like to use
California's a bit of a testing ground
which I think we've done and then I
think the next step for us we are
launching a European fund right now in
order to take everything we've built
here into the European market off the
back of the growth of the basic part of
the industry
that would be time for one more question
sir okay last question please yeah
Francesca Empress pharmaceutical
Switzerland yeah I got a question but
it's not for pharma stuff because
actually we're talking since the
beginning about just a business of the
buds I mean the extracts everything but
we're not speaking about the
opportunities on the business on the old
plants you know because actually the
point is you might know it financially
speaking actually as well for design as
well for materials bio plastics and
fewers and I mean that's a lot of
opportunities not just on buds I mean
the amp is like pork you can take out
everything you want even the roots we
can say over here in Europe with the Sun
most in the south we can say that
actually the plants reach 4 meters I'd
right even even 5 even 7 so the roots
are really big so you can even take
words out of it really right word so you
can make everything out of it so I mean
the financial potency of the business
should not be just concentrated into
buds but everywhere else because there's
a lot of job to do there's a lot of work
to do as well a lot of my friends are
working in Europe and as well worldwide
to develop a lot of materials new
material new resins new stuff to do be
bio tanks I mean so that will be really
huge stuff to do if everybody over here
you know just yeah I think that's that's
part without going into all the business
opportunities that's exactly what I'm
trying to express up here which is the
massive
of opportunities exist which are talking
about in fact I have a friend in the
industry who actually put together a
business plan and I don't know if he got
in front of him or not but he's trying
to put it in front of the White House to
say hey if you're gonna build a wall
why don't you dude out hempcrete at
least right hey deucey and it's a bit of
a joke but again right if if we could
ever get there who knows but hey
laughter is the best form of medicine
cannabis certainly could be a medicine
in that regard but I agree with you and
I think that we should all walk away
with that thought that there are so much
business opportunity it's not just whole
plant that's the people who are
advocating it today understand whole
plant benefit to them but as this
industry moves forward I challenge you
all to think about what is the consumer
look like today what does it look like
tomorrow what does it look like five and
ten years from now because it's a
completely different answer an
understanding what hemp can do with its
byproducts understanding you know the
the the cannabinoid profiles and what
each of them can do that's where the
industry is going so if anybody in here
is running a business that's at scale
that meets our criteria I'd love to know
yeah we're looking for great
opportunities we've been able to raise a
significant amount of capital a lot of
people want exposure to this space we've
got great smart people that are happy to
help dig through all those opportunities
if you're looking for exposure to this
space we are a committed capital fund
and always keeping that open so love to
talk to you about that too my email is
Matt at Arcadian fund really thank you
for all your time and just love
everybody's passion and enthusiasm in
here for this industry
you're never Matthew with the Arcadian
fun
[Applause]
you