all right our next panel is on media and
marketing in the Cannabis space and we
got a lot of Heavy Hitters from all over
the world for this one and to lead this
panel he's the head of nicotine and
cannabis research uh for euromonitor
international let's head for Shane
McGill Shane McGill
[Applause]
[Music]
okay
hi everyone
we've got a very shy and retiring panel
for you here
Economist media and marketing firstly
before I begin just to help the panel
can I just do a show of hands to see
who's actively currently marketing a
cannabis product or service so if you're
actively currently marketing one okay
and those of us I guess are planning to
do so right and who's intending to be in
the space
the rest of you guys are just observing
and are you marketing to the final
consumer or B2B those of you who are
marking final consumer thumbs up
B2B
okay cool that says a lot so you guys
have a sense of what's going on so I'm
going to ask you to do the hard work for
for me uh so if you guys can
Alex in San Francisco where I'm from
California and I've helped build a lot
of Legacy brands in the Cannabis space
from both sales and marketing
perspective both as a consultant and as
an employee at a bunch of different
brands that have made big progress over
the last couple of decades in the space
so I'm really excited to share
everything of my experience I have a
master's in education and I'm a teacher
so this is really important to my heart
and so thanks you all for being you know
lifelong Learners with us awesome thanks
Mr Stephen hello there my name is
Stephen verbique it's nice to see a lot
of friendly faces here I've been
speaking at ICBC since the the origin as
well back in Berlin I'm the CEO of hello
cannabis we're originally based out of
Canada we're vertically integrated our
main foray was into the medical cannabis
Market we still have a clinic that is
operating to this day under the goodbye
opioids hello cannabis campaign with
over 7 000 patients we advise numerous
countries internationally as well as
help with legislation as well as
marketing initiatives and how to be able
to regulate educating doctors and
educating doctors Pharmacists and
producers and patients alike we were
fortunate enough to be able to have a
brand and a presence to be able to open
up the very first legal cannabis store
in a G20 nation that was federally legal
that was under the brand of hello
cannabis we opened I believe that was
three and a half years ago we since
expanded of course but I I do truly
believe that the medical aspect is is
near and dear to my heart and the
marketing campaigns and initiatives and
rules and regulations vary dramatically
between the two particularly
internationally so I'm happy to be able
to share some advice and guidance on
what worked and what definitely did not
work and I urge you not to do the things
that definitely didn't work they have
repercussions for sure we'll get into
that okay Michael can you give us a
quick introduction tweets my name is
Michelle Norwood I'm based in Berlin I'm
my profession my professional is a I'm a
freelance journalist I'm working writing
about cannabis since 20 years meanwhile
um besides I'm a book author I published
the first German book on cannabis
extraction
and I also run a quite a successful
YouTube channel on cannabis so I'm also
what they call an influencer nowadays
and
and due to that I'm also very involved
with the sponsors and who yeah I'm a
brand ambassador for other for Hawaii
which is one of the biggest German
import companies for medical cannabis
owned by the sanity group
and you know besides that I also do a
lot of articles for vice magazine and
other cannabis and mainstream public
Publications
oh yeah this is awesome thank you so
much for coming it means a lot for me
um I am Simone Espinosa I founded uh
created and founded a media
for the Cannabis community in Latin
America it has grown quite a bit since
the we're turning 10 years this year so
it's a super
um big for us and that media thank you
that media gave birth to a fully
integrated Supply change with
distribution and marketing and Retail
companies that kind of uh are part of
this ecosystem it has worked very well
for us now we're expanding through the
rest of the Spanish-speaking cannabis
markets and communities Landing into the
US hopefully soon we had some Traction
in California and Florida really
interesting markets cannabis are Spanish
speaking wise so yeah we've had a blast
I wrote a couple of books also we do a
lot of content for underage prevention
in schools local schools in Chile Where
I'm From hopefully in the rest of the
countries coming soon
and
um yeah I think that's it that's it you
can Google involado it's it's pretty
cool I'm really proud of that project
okay thank you we've got a panel with a
really pleasingly diverse range of
experience here and I thought what I
could do is maybe start with some of the
problems and then we'll work into
Solutions and maybe end on a more
positive note so you know we've got
okay we've grown an industry here where
you can't do things that you can do in
other Industries you've got a mix of
different approaches channels you've got
restrictions that vary across different
markets and so on so again an open
question could I ask you guys just to
talk about you know what are some of the
big problems challenges that you face in
your own sort of part of the industry
and maybe begin to talk about how you've
addressed some of those and we can kind
of go from there who wants to start on
that one
um do you mind if I jump on this quick
yeah go ahead all right here's a fun
audience participation one here
um with a show of hands how many people
know of the company kke or what it
represents anybody
I didn't literally zero okay with the
show of hands how many people know the
name Wiz Khalifa
love it okay so kke's Khalifa Kush
Enterprises which is Wiz Khalifa's
company
so this kind of shows exactly how much
an impact
um Wiz Khalifa has had in the Cannabis
industry under kke
nobody's even heard of it
uh we had some very interesting
situations in Canada where immediately
we wanted to have celebrity endorsements
for all of these products
um I'm sure there there has to be an
example in some other country but um so
forgive me if I'm being overly
presumptuous here but I don't know of a
single celebrity that endorses a
pharmaceutical prescription product you
know like I don't see Bill Murray like
like saying like I like Viagra you
should take it too you know it just
doesn't happen and unfortunately a lot
of these companies in Canada were
throwing millions of dollars at
Celebrities thinking that they could
endorse these products at that time it
was only medical it was not recreational
so you had celebrities that were
endorsing a product that's only
available via prescription which is
essentially never happened before
and you can see right now how big an
impact is it was and I won't throw them
under the bus he's a friend of mine but
the the gentleman that was running the
company that did that wasted a cool like
2.5 million dollars on that to have
literally zero impact for an
international rap artist that I don't
know he's probably got like 100 million
followers or something stupid like that
I don't know I'm not an influencer
um and what we did notice is when things
transitioned to recreational a lot of
those marketing rules transitioned from
both medical over to recreational as
well and this is what I found
fascinating because when you start
looking at recreational things you
really you should be able to have
celebrity endorsements you should be
able to have people that say like I
prefer I prefer Heineken over this right
and that happens very commonly in in
Canada it did not right
um anybody here's another fun one
anybody know the company lbs
I do all right so we have two two people
that's Snoop Dogg lbs is Snoop Dogg
Leafs by Snoop
so like how strong is your marketing
campaign when the whole name and entity
behind it is stripped right down to an
acronym there's no value there
so it's it's rather interesting when you
start looking at these rules and
regulations I highly recommend steering
away from
um endorsements with respect to
celebrities
um they like getting paid I've not seen
a single one of these work that's
probably the biggest mistake that I've
seen major companies make if you uh
heard me allude earlier I said there are
serious repercussions these
repercussions forward to the tune of
over 10 million dollars and in my
opinion was critical to bankrupt this
company thanks just to compliment that
that comments
um I think that it's very interesting
the difference between uh celebrities
and communities even though they both
absolutely massive Traction in social
media especially is not the same and the
quality of the follower or subscriber is
not going to be the same and the the uh
their disposition to or their
availability for engaging with whatever
content is coming from there it's gonna
switch and transition very strongly even
if it's the same follower from Snoop
Dogg that's watching this content in his
platform or if it's in a different
platform that is an actual cannabis
community and I think this is very
important to Define and I think we're
going to come back to social media for
sure Luna what are the biggest
challenges you face in terms of the work
you're doing well that's a part of it
right because in California we sell cool
and how is cool sold in the states and
in most of the world it's on social
media and we've had major issues with
the terms and conditions not being
favorable on Instagram not being able to
use hashtags not being able to consume
on camera not being able to getting
Shadow banned or blocked from being
searchable
um you know so I think that in a lot of
ways it that the to your point too it's
this is not a normal consumer package
goods and I think that that's the
biggest takeaway is what I've learned is
that people really need to stop looking
at this like a
a static easy to process finite thing
cannabis is a magical mysterious
mystical plant medicine and this
approach that's this copy and paste
approach of all your Sops from whatever
you know tobacco or alcohol distributor
you used to work with or whatever sales
book you were taught 15 years ago
whatever book you read it doesn't apply
here and I think that what we forget
sometimes is to really listen deeply to
your point listen deeply to where it's
going to land and also be honest about
the fact that this is still only going
to be able to be seen in very specific
ways maybe to the on the YouTube channel
if YouTube continues allowing it but the
bands make us have to be really creative
um you know Simone talks a lot about you
know humor and bringing that into it to
make things more shareable and we can
talk about that too but I think that
that's the biggest prevention for us to
normalizing and and removing the stigma
is that we're not getting access to
mainstream in a way that's not the same
typical messaging of the Snoop dogs The
Wiz khalifas the um the Willie Willie
Nelsons it needs to feel really
thoughtful and not just something that
is just you know putting a square peg
into a round hole we need to be really
really thoughtful about it and I think
that that's what it's lacking is there's
a lot of eagerness and arrogance without
real data behind it which is what you
specialize in well we try
umika so you a lot of what you do is on
YouTube so can you kind of talk about
you know to Luna's points some of the
challenges that you have with your work
on YouTube and how you you sort of try
and mitigate those and overcome them
yeah let me say I I must say I have
YouTube and Instagram and it's it's
quite the same but for me it's for me in
personal Instagram is a little bit
easier YouTube is more streak when it
comes to cannabis but I have a
restriction on both channels which is uh
about two reasons for it on the one hand
we have the restrictions of YouTube of
Instagram of the platforms which are not
transparent at all that's a big problem
nobody knows what we're dealing with
nobody knows the rules so I actually
it's a kind of Lottery if I upload a
video and I always hope it's not being
related or something like this so and on
the other hand in Germany we have a very
special situation which makes the
marketing uh quite difficult because
cannabis is a legal medicine and federal
uh uh on federal basis so
um it's also cons it's considered as a
legal narcotic and you're not allowed to
advertise for legal narcotics not at all
so what do the companies do because we
have meanwhile nearly 200 strains in the
pharmacy and everybody wants to
advertise for this trade they want to
book influences but influencers are not
allowed to sell
advertisements to companies for legal
narcotics so you have to be tricky you
know you have to be tricky when it comes
to the invoice you have to reach even
when it comes to the video to the
posting because you're not allowed to
advertise but you're allowed to mention
the medicine so what they do they call
they also focus on patient on patient
groups you know because patient groups
are very safe to advertise with but it's
not advertisement it's not official
advertising so it's but it does not it
does not work in the classic way we used
to advertise velocity I come from the
from the magazine business originally I
used to write and be Chief editor for a
chief editorial several cannabis
magazines and um
that doesn't work anymore so good you
know if you don't have social media it's
very hard to do advertising or to to uh
to promote a product in the in the kind
of position well I think this goes to
Simone's remember we were talking about
education Simone you were talking the
way around this is don't be salesy it's
it and it shouldn't it shouldn't have to
first of all weed cells itself did I say
that yeah that sounds small you said
just make it so that it's not it's like
you you're doing it for Education where
it's undeniable that the purpose and the
intent was to educate
because that's really the empowerment
that's the true influencers is I respect
you guys and if I see you using
something I trust that it's good because
of your legitimizing validating
pre-veting it's trust and relationship
so that's how you've been getting around
it like my advice is always don't
hashtag anything don't tag anyone who's
Shadow banned don't smoke on camera and
Simone actually really inspired me he
was like it's not really about that it's
about being really conscious and
building it out do you I mean I don't
know if you wanted to speak to it but I
think it's brilliant no thank you very
much for those words I didn't say that's
not true yeah no no but
um I guess the point is that at this
when we started we focused on education
and it happens that I was I was a script
writer for a comedy show back in the day
so I was writing jokes for a living I'm
super funny don't worry it will come it
will come
and but we realized that it was a very
hostile marketing environment back in
the day we realized that guidelines were
not going to play in our favor so we we
figured this out when people laugh they
will share the content so that's a way
to hack the algorithm that will not show
you on any feed basically that's what's
happening all our media is done already
I'm Shadow Bonnie if you like look for
me in on Instagram or anything we won't
appear unless you like write the
specific username for all of our
platforms but we still grow every every
week we grow a couple thousand followers
and it's like more massive and and
stronger in in different platforms and
this is because people are sharing the
content especially because it's
educational we always try to teach
something if it's how to use a vaporizer
or a bond so be it we will take a big
sleep and get super high on camera but
we were showing how to use the bong and
why is this better or worse for you on
or what should be aware of when using a
bong or a vaporizer like like straight
forward information and we make it funny
by being kind of a honest and genuine to
all the feelings that you experience
when doing this yes I think that's very
I think there's a really important point
about authenticity there that I do want
to come back to but just before we go to
that maybe just to take a slight step
back because it seems to me when we do
have a lot of people here who aren't
actively engaged already in marketing it
seems to me that there's a bit of a
paradox around social media because on
the one hand you guys are saying it's
the most important element but on the
other I've seen people say before you
need to avoid social media try and drive
people to your website Etc so they're
both true though but I know two things
can be true at the same time yeah but
but how do you you balance those things
and then I guess more concretely if you
guys are going to use social media or if
people here are going to use social
media what is the best social media
platform for cannabis in your guys
opinion so again I don't know who wants
to to kick off labeling do you want to
have a go with that one I mean
definitely to your point the website
right you can own it you can update it
you can shut it down you can you can see
how the dwell time how where they're
going from what page to what how long
they're staying there what they're
slowing down on it's a really awesome
resource
um also it just gets them to see your
branding and your voice instead of it
being you know through the LinkedIn
filter through the Twitter filter and
obviously a lot of you guys know um I
think the hoova app is actually pretty
cool
um but LinkedIn really is the only place
that's not Banning us I can use hashtags
with cannabis I can share stories not
worry about being policed and there's
people on LinkedIn that are really in
the B2B space it sounds like that's
really relevant
um I find that that's the best place to
stay away from some of the lower
vibrational energies people who really
have their stuff together are on
LinkedIn they're coming to these
conferences and in a lot of ways I think
that that's the to your point about
doing both you know there's the consumer
brand acknowledgment on the social side
and then there's the legitimacy with
other sophisticated professionals that
want to see people that really know what
they're doing and and care about making
this happen because there's a lot of
talk and not much action and we got to
get this going like if we don't do it
it's going to be all kinds of other
folks that are not going to do it right
and so for the people who've built it
let's let's do it right can I compliment
those and this is just like uh when you
acknowledge that your website it's going
to be a free platform for you to kind of
do whatever you want in this space and
and when you're navigating these
difficult Waters of kind of the social
media or kind of in social media uh how
many of you guys like publish written
content in your websites to look for SEO
positioning
all right so all of us should be doing
that if we are aware that our that we
all our websites should have a Blog
space and how many of you are are aware
of chat gbt by this point on are using
it in your okay this is a huge trick for
us when you prompt DPT for SEO
positioning or SEO enhanced cannabis
content this is the way that you can
easily position your website even
without showing the actual content but
you can you can go into that SEO ranking
easily now uh with these tools so what I
would recommend is to work on that uh
block kind of a space in your website
using this new uh AI
um software or AI just AI sorry but yeah
that's that's a trick that we are now
using and it has helped us a lot to
especially e-commerce yeah you could do
a whole other session probably an AI and
cannabis will come in there I think yeah
let me say uh I'm doing cannabis content
I think I started on YouTube my first
channel in 2006 at that time Stoner
content worked very well meanwhile
Stoner content does not work at all for
two reasons on the one side we have all
this restrictions on the platforms but
on the other side people want to have
serious information about cannabis they
don't want they don't want to see the
storage stuff anymore you know of course
some young people are still successful
with this you know but people who are
really interested in the industry people
who are interested to be in a legal
industry they don't want to have this
Stoner stuff they want to they don't
want to see it and I wouldn't say
there's a best platformer for my content
but I can I can tell you the more
serious my I make my content the more
research the more time I invest in my
content the more followers I have the
better the best impact is the good
content in my eyes yeah so there was
that pointer and authenticity and and
sort of you know making sure that
whatever you're releasing and whatever
channel is is real and speaking to the
consumer so Stephen I know you guys do
events and so on like how do you keep it
real in terms of of what you try to do
to get the message out love it um I'll
approach this from a little bit of a
different angle I'm kind of more of a
looted I'm not very active on social
media and I'm kind of the front-facing
guy at these types of events and uh more
or less doing the a lot of the back end
work and it's funny when I hear educated
and power it's like it's stripped like
straight from our training manual I
truly think that those two are those are
the two most powerful World words that
can be used in almost any industry
um here's a quick example on a marketing
technique that we do when you start
getting front-facing now like like I
said we open up the very first retail
store and uh uh in Canada we did just
out of this one store 14.7 million
dollars worth of sales in one year we
were processing about 650 people today
and you bet your ass how's the best damn
salesman there and that's that's
something that I absolutely love and
when you have 600 skus and you have
somebody that comes in there and they're
just like wide-eyed and just
bushy-tailed being like Oh my God
there's [ __ ] weed here sorry for my
language
um it's it's really special and you want
to be able to refine 600 different skus
to something that they actually want and
not trying to be the be all and end all
the cannabis
so back to education and Empower us five
open-ended questions and I can drill 600
skus down to about five or six and
they're the ones that are making the
decisions right you were asking them
questions it's like you Choose Your Own
Adventure book you and you end up at the
end result based on your decisions
and that's where you can in my opinion
is really the strongest form of eye to
eye marketing that results in them
promoting your customers become your
promoters
I don't need to put my like semi-pretty
face like all over speaking eloquently
doing all of these things to be able to
attract attention I train people that
are able to actually authentically show
the passion that they have otherwise we
don't hire them obviously basic
competency needs to be there yada yada
yada hiring practices are important I
assure you but when you're able to
actually educate people and Empower them
to make decisions it opens up an entire
different pathway in their break they're
the boss not you and all of a sudden
they feel empowered they feel educated
they feel more knowledgeable they walk
out of there with one a product that
they very likely are going to enjoy more
because you helped guide them down that
pathway and then all of a sudden they're
your influencer
if you looked at how many people were
tagging hello cannabis there were 25
stores in Ontario province of 14 million
people we had people driving literally
two hours passing by four other stores
to get to my store that's a fact people
taking a city bus across Hamilton which
is like 30 kilometers to get into our
store instead of walking distance there
we had the same products
same products
it is seriously as simple as educating
and empowering building an actual
experience around this experiential
marketing I think is absolutely critical
I'm we don't we use social media but
it's really through other people at our
stores we start running real events we
did Magic the Gathering we called Magic
the gunging I think that's a stupid name
but it's hilarious and we sold out
we have 40 people playing a magic the
car Magic the Gathering card tournament
you charge a front fee and we put it in
the back room and like
probably shouldn't be putting this on
though
yeah the cat's out of the bag anyways we
did it screw you AGCO please like this
is really important like there were
simple rules that you can do where you
were able to kind of just touch that
line of legality but I'll stand in front
of a judge and be like please explain by
having a car tournament here is against
the law like there's no illegal gambling
here there is no excessive consumption
that's happening here we are bringing
like-minded people together with a niche
market that they actually enjoy and you
bet your ass that every single person
that was there was filming was talking
about you combine 40 people in all of
the social media
tagging what's not us doing it we're not
getting Shadow Man
right you had 40 different people saying
like this is the coolest thing in the
world like I I'm smoking cannabis and
I'm playing a magic the Gathering
tournament that's the authenticity piece
right well yeah I mean authentically
Community I guess is the same whether
it's a digital one or a woman in the
real world so Linda I know you do
Advanced networking as well what's your
experience with boats or how do you go
about I mean for us it's it's showing up
and doing good work we all know that
there's a lot of business to be had but
not forgetting the people of color that
have been hit by the War on Drugs not
forgetting um the women in the Cannabis
industry they're getting pushed out it's
International women's month yesterday
was International women's day so we
really want to you know have good
campaigns that center around black
history month so for example every day
we posted on our story a different black
cannabis company that was owned by folks
of color to support
um this month we're doing all kinds of
work to feature women one of our dab
rigs goes to donating to the pollinator
project to conserve bees we work with
veterans groups we do really flexible
financing for small craft businesses and
farmers in California that can't afford
to buy Hardware their cartridges or
their disposables up front and we can
help work out flexible terms so this
authenticity and this this you know to
your point the the building of the brand
loyalty where everyone becomes an
evangelist that's been huge when I
helped start Jetty extracts one of the
first cartridge companies in California
back in 2014 there was not really a
compassion project like the shelter
project which we were giving away
unlimited cannabis to anyone who signed
up for a program that was fatally or not
even fatally ill but had severe illness
usually cancer but we worked with
everyone and we did we customized to
your point you know it's like what
exactly is your goal is it a teacher is
it CBD what's the ratio and people were
when we went into clubs we weren't the
cheapest we weren't the most well-known
but with that story that helped them
understand that their budtenders had
something exciting to tell the clients
when they walked in this is what you're
supporting you buy one you give one
you're doing more and you're building
love and health in your life while
you're doing it for for yourself for
other people and I think that that's
part of what our events do we do first
Friday we're in Venice California near
the beach so there's an art walk be
first Friday we open up our offices
which is just a court you know it's
looks like a corporate office and the
whole Community can come in and learn
about dabbing these are people who don't
have to pay anything they're just right
off the street and they get to they'll
walk by throughout the month and be like
hey I Aspire and call up to our office
because we're accessible and we feel
real people are tired of fake
storytelling they're tired of being
marketed too they're tired of having
their intelligence insulted so I think
that this authenticity thing is is not
only to to have longevity in the market
but to actually gain people's trust
which is I think the hardest and most
vital thing to actually be successful in
the Cannabis space yeah so operating in
good faith I think is what I'm hearing
you're someone who straddles the line
between media and marketing you work as
a freelance journalist you're also
um you know working in influencing and
so on there's a question around
authenticity there I guess as well you
know how important is it that those two
things stay separate how do you manage
the kind of relationship between
marketing media Etc
um
I told you and when we talked before
this is what I sometimes Miss in the
Cannabis industry is the grade of
professionality we have in other media
because I can be I can do some criticism
I can consider some uh topic critical
critically but still uh the the produce
of that product can advertise in my
magazine or on my channel which which is
uh you know there's no contradiction in
it and
um what I'll miss a little bit if if you
have customers they expect to influence
your content and that is very that that
does not work on the long range because
people are sick of this kind of
marketing and what we talked about so if
you if if you do this unhonest marketing
if you're not honest with your marketing
here you won't be influenced a long time
you know you people will not trust you
so this is very important that they're
in the Cannabis industry we have the
Great profit of professionality like in
other industry that you can do critical
content but still have Partners from the
industry and they don't they are not
upset if you write a critical article
about this one's trade because it's just
not tasty you know and you can and you
can still be a partner of that company
but this one's train is just not tasty
you know and they they shouldn't try to
influence that I know we have the same
problems in the in the US I used to work
for two platforms from the US you know
and they know there were the same
problems and I always hated that and
told the people please consider it on
the long range you have to build up a
credibility and reputation you know and
this doesn't work if you know say that
that we deserve that the tastes like
hell and makes you helps but it doesn't
doesn't take good and good in the test
Boot and then and doesn't doesn't help
no it doesn't lose your pain you know
I'm sitting beside one of the most
authentic people in cannabis in in
Europe and he's he's right here no
disrespect please but this is as
authentic as it gets
um from from brain all the way to his
shell it's something that I think is
extremely extremely important
um hiring influencers to promote a
product was a big thing in Canada and it
lasted less than a year and it was like
it was deplorable like it was so
flagrantly obvious and deplorable and
I'm I'll put that on the record I don't
care and many of these people are
friends of mine because they're popular
sorry not to interrupt you but this is
what is just happening in Germany and
this is also why I tell the people you
cannot books train reviews you know you
cannot book it you know sorry yeah you
you nailed it completely the first ones
are just like oh like there's a really
famous person that that we know that's
got like a hundred thousand followers
and smokes weed all the time or like
like please forgive using using this
term but like like uh an attract like a
hot babe you know you just need like
very strategically oh that's something
we haven't talked about stop using sex
to sell weed thank you thanks sorry if
that's just an American problem but it
is so old and boring is that Beyond even
offensive it's just not interesting like
we've literally just said like there's
there's booths where it's just like four
attractive women that know absolutely
nothing about cannabis and uh you you've
got a conference with the vast majority
being being male that are just flooding
over there and I'm sitting here going
like what like yeah I'm speechless and
I'm a guy that likes speaking no I use
my Latino magnetism to kind of sorry so
imagine how hard it makes it for women
who actually know their stuff about
cannabis when that becomes the the
Baseline is that if you can just hire
for the beauty then people assume that
all women in the space are just hired as
models it's rough
um I I do got to give one very very
quick shout out back to I'm very against
this sex sex cells in
unauthentic marketing for sure but I I
got to give a big shout out there's an
interesting trick that a colleague of
mine that was actually just speaking
previously Alex revich who represents
loose Brands they have Edibles that are
penis shaped by the way and uh I he he
jokingly said and I said I got to give
you a shout out for this
um sex does sell in many ways but if you
throw cannabis in it like just look out
man
and it's quite comical because in Canada
we can't even have anything that is
Catered towards children like you if you
have like a marshmallow that's like
Lucky Charms or something like that or
anything catered to a very subjective
term which is like excitement or if you
take if you take cannabis you are going
to feel better which last I checked you
do anyways
um we can't Market to that and they were
able to actually get a health Canada
approved medical product that is a penis
shaped animal and you can see the
dimples on my face right now they're not
lying it's bloody hilarious
it is absolutely hilarious and it's used
as medicine they did this like I all
that you I'll let you speak to him for
it everybody has I'm talking about it
right now and people are listening right
that's marketing and in my opinion this
is not using sex to sell but this is a
basically like it's a little bit of a
middle finger so the marketing you know
I guess the problem comes when everyone
starts doing it but I mean on that
bombshell we've got about nine minutes
left in the panel so I want to throw it
open to the audience because we want to
make sure that you guys have a chance to
ask the questions that you guys want to
really hear about so can we get who's
gonna go first
for Shane and everybody on the panel
yeah
I'm sure you have a lot of questions
who's got a question and please when
you're thinking about your question keep
it to one or two sentences and make sure
it's okay go ahead please be brief we
don't need to hear the whole global
history of cannabis
uh before you ask your question we're
all relatively familiar with it that's
all I was gonna say thank you thank you
questions
apparently you have given them all the
information they need there must be one
question at least one thank you
I wore my comfortable shoes I wanted to
walk around and everything here we go
thank you very for a very stimulating
talk
um in terms of marketing and social
media platforms I what are your thoughts
on Tinder recently announcing that they
allow it but from what I've read it's a
bit more complicated than that what can
you tell us about that
are you saying that it's a selection
when you're in your dating profile to
say 420. we can see where your mind's at
girl
that was just PR if you actually look at
it they just want the advertising money
but they're not actually more friendly
to cannabis and they kept up the bands
they just are saying that they're gonna
accept money but they're still gonna
have to go through the same the same
rigmarole they're just it I think it was
to look good but if you look at it
they're not cannabis friendly they're
just willing to look at our money which
is what everyone does no they're not
they're not trying to be revolutionary
don't get lost in the headline they
don't they do not care about cannabis in
Chile we use a grinder or they use a lot
of grinder but they used to sell drugs
there and a lot of people use my face to
sell weed in grinder that's just my
goodness but I think it was funny face
they were smart people use a lot of
things
man I thought it was Mark I mean I mean
we really should be aware of the fact uh
that we talk about the product even if
it's legal where advertisement band will
be ever average most countries with
legalizing cannabis will have an
advertisement ban I mean maybe some have
a total advertisement ban in some other
countries you may advertise up to a
certain level but in general we're
talking about a product which will need
never be free to be advertised like
Coca-Cola or something like this sorry I
mentioned pharmaceutical the cocaine
back in Coca-Cola sorry sorry sorry
my Tinder is on right now if anybody's
looking to Ross wife right now that
buddy I'm less than a kilometer away
because any other questions yeah there's
a question here and the question there
we're gonna go here cool
first thanks for mentioning about sexism
in the the media because this is very
important and I hope everyone
understands very well what we're
speaking about and second I would like
to ask about advices on how to educate
people in terms of media and like in all
General things because that's what's
really important now and for the future
because for people that really doesn't
know about THC or something like this
they just judge or they really like if
they don't smoke they don't know about
even like Health part of the canops
world so it's extremely important for us
that works with media to show up like
how to educate these people that it's
not intro the the smoke smokers like
group let's say I'd love to tackle this
if you don't mind with respect to the
educating empowerment one of the biggest
platforms that we started was the
goodbye opioids campaign I'm an opioid
Survivor after a surgery I've got 17
screws on my feet that's why I have
these wonderful in case anybody wants to
make fun of me but um uh it's it's
really truly about education we did that
you start that at the top right I'm face
to face with all these different doctors
78 different doctors refer patients to
my clinic if you're able to educate
people at the top as a trickle-down
effect and you don't even need social
media for that so you spend you gather
up all the data you're able to get
somebody that's able to speak to the
same level of them to be able to educate
and Empower them that trickle-down
effect happens all the way and it
happens even in my Corporation with
respect to educating you Empower all of
my senior staff they then educate and
Empower all the managers those managers
then educate and Empower all of the
employees and those employees educated
and Empower every single different
Citizen and patient alike so it's it's
about really getting to the top and
being able to educate and Empower real
influencers not even outside of social
media and there is a plethora of data
both medical and recreational on
different cannabinoids flavonoids
terpenes how they different how they
interact with everybody if you want to
dive into all of the stuff like like eat
your heart out like let's go it's like
my biggest passion and like clinical
trials research reports like we have
literally over 3 000 research reports
that we've compiled both on on the
medical basis you take that data you use
that to educate people you Empower them
to be able to educate other people and
so on and so on and so on and you know
first can I ask I have a quick question
hi I'm easy to spot
um
one of the challenges though because
okay we we have we have access to all
this data and all these files and you
know it and I know it I got an Instagram
you got an Instagram you can post till
you turn blue in the face right I mean I
got 71 000 Instagram followers and if I
post a weed meme Instagram loves that
and I get thousands of likes but if I
post some sort of thing about
real cannabis you know here's a picture
of some cannabis or here's some this is
what these different terpenes do they
kind of squash that one absolutely and
so how do you how do you reach beyond
that is the question how do you get
around that where's the documentary
doesn't everyone love watching movies
get your get these folks to me what
you're saying is where people come
before but the app that comes first is
the why that's why that would be my
answer is get them to watch us get them
to watch giving RSL or CBD to a to a
child having a grand mal seizure Leaf
the bubble you know what I'm saying have
them have a story told of of and pop the
bubble leave the bubble and pop it that
once they see the why then they're
fascinated by the research but there's
documentaries out there there's many
documentaries like it this now cannabis
or there's Beautiful Stories I think
that it has to start with the story of
people seeing that this is not a joke
this isn't about us wanting to get high
this is a life-saving intervention that
has been grown and cultivated for
thousands of years by indigenous people
and women that's the other thing this is
our Birthright this isn't something new
that's why it's crazy to me the people
of color in the in the United States and
all around the world are extra scared of
this it makes sense that black and brown
people don't want to get involved
they're not mad at the plant they don't
have an issue with the plant they don't
want problems with the boys yeah in my
eyes it's also very important uh if
you're my cannabis content your
orientation is menstrual media you know
you want to reach out you want to leave
the bubble so look how my social media
works and to use the same tools like
mainstream media make serious
then you leave the bubble you know I
have experienced that with a few uh with
a few not only with a few videos you can
leave the bubble but you have to be very
you have to be taken serious and not to
be taking what I said before taken as
the stoner you know exactly
Stoner content exactly and so there I
noticed there was a lot of B2B people
here and all of this is completely
applicable too with this educating and
empowered right
um I would say like Instagram is
basically B to C right like you're an
influencer it goes directly to C so when
you start looking at B to B which is
what I was talking about with respect to
talking to a doctor that's B2B and then
they're B to C right so if I educated
them I Empower you
for to buy into cannabis and to buy into
all of this you then become the
influencer that's b2c my job is B to B
I'm B2B all day long and I love this b2c
stuff but ultimately I'm using b2c to
talk to B to B sure
yes hello my name is Michael I'm an
attorney at law in Germany and I was
wondering how does the industry in the
states
um deal with the fact that the law
regulating the the advertisement on
social media how does the industry
um pushes its interests into let's say
the legal text since I have something
here um from Canada it says unless
authorized under this act it is
prohibited to promote cannabis by
presenting it or any of its brand
elements in a manner that Associates
yeah vague it's like it's everything
it's everything to to me's point it's
like it's not they're not even
transparent about it so we have people
that are part-time they literally
they're spending money and every day
having a right to Instagram to get
unbanned like it's they're doing it to
Tire us out this is the problem with the
system they do not want us to heal
ourselves it's big Pharma it's it's a
military industrial complex all of these
things it sounds conspiratorial but
that's to Simone's Point keep bit light
keep it educational keep it funny when
you see the Nike Swoosh you don't you're
you don't see a picture of a sweating
person playing basketball they're not
saying what they are if anyone goes to
HQ it's one of the best clubs in
Barcelona their sweatshirts just have if
you know you know on the back that we
don't need to overtly Market this I
actually appreciate that we need to
operate a little bit in the shadows
because this plant deserves a little
shade it needs a little protection it
doesn't need to be as exposed and as
exploited as a Coca-Cola to the example
I think it's smart that we're rolling
out plant medicine in a thoughtful slow
way because it deserves that we don't
want this to be a green Rush we've
already seen what happens it doesn't
work everywhere green Rush sucks be
careful no one wins really best thing is
to broccoli uh emoji on Instagram you
know meanwhile nobody uses this one for
broccoli anymore because cannabis is
totally banned in the Emojis and you
know when everybody is kind of forgot
all about them and we are old
you're not about the broccoli emoji I
forgot I forgot about using the problem
you won't mention the eggplant all right
I think
you got claps on that one bro
but look let's hear it from the panel
we're just about out of time let's hear
for Shane and Luna of the week thank you
very much
I don't know just thanks to everyone
thanks to the promise thank you so much
I want to take a selfie everyone in the
audience real quick we're gonna take a
quick stop we love doing this everybody
and uh appreciate appreciate you all
being here um feel free to grab us and
feel free to talk everyone say we
Ave
hey