uh we are very proud and excited to
present here to discuss medical cannabis
in Germany he's the partner at Dentons
and he's the head of the European
cannabis group please welcome Peter
[Applause]
humberg yeah thank you very much for
this kind introduction ladies and
gentlemen after lunch on a Friday the
13th uh it's always difficult you may
say it is not it can be lucky a lucky
day or it can be a difficult day uh for
me it's a lucky day because I have the
pleasure to speak for such a wonderful
audience here about the medical cannabis
developments in Germany and coming back
to difficult uh I don't know whether you
have listened recently to German
politicians because they are using the
word difficult very often also in the
connection with cannabis and if you look
into what they really mean what
difficult means it looks like it's a
synonym for either
unacceptable out of question or
outrageously stupid so if ever a
politician is used difficult you have to
really look what he is meaning and
having said that I would like to make a
couple of remarks before I start my
presentation
um about our discussion which we had
earlier today the question question was
from one of the of the audience say use
the other microphone maybe you can't
hear me this one might be easier for us
to hear this one's a little a
little yeah try that okay wow good
wonderful you hear me better great uh I
think somebody asked of you should
Slovenia copy the German model uh the
answer is that would be
difficult uh
because they are they are you have to
differentiate between the recreational
part of course and the medical part the
recreational part and thank you very
much uh my my dear friend that you left
the medical part for me this afternoon
uh the recreational part which you so
nicely outlined today uh is a step
forward but not what actually everybody
wanted uh and I will come back to that
in a minute but with respect to the
medical part
uh it is from my point of view a good
model to look at and in the next 30
minutes I'm going to show you a little
bit why it is a good uh model to look at
even for Slovenia it has a number of
advantages and I would say it is really
a success story since we started with
the legalization of medical cannabis in
Germany back in
2016 the other part the recreational you
know uh as as I said it's difficult uh
you may not uh copy it in any way
besides the fact me as a lawyer I would
never advise on copying something not
even the law it would be like I would uh
actually uh recommend copying the German
employees invention act which is the
most elaborated most difficult act
regarding this topic to a Japanese
employer so looking at it having look at
the advantages and of course then use
them and Slovenia is now on the move
into the medical cannabis Market into
the medical cannabis field uh it may be
worthwhile to consider what Germany has
done so here's the outline what I what I
would like to discuss with you this
afternoon first of all a very brief
review how did it all happen why why is
actually Germany so now in Europe in the
Forefront
of the medical Canabis market then of
course we have a look what has actually
happened since 2016 what has recently
happened uh since the legalization of
recreational or partial legalization of
recreational cabus uh in Germany and
then of course we look into the
potential problems which this all may or
may not cause in the future also take
into consideration that we have
elections next year and the government
may change you may have looked at what
has happened in Germany politically just
recently so there is a likelihood that
the current Coalition will not be in the
represented in the government next end
of next year so having said that let's
have a look into the
development before the year
2016 uh there was the possibility for
medical patients to apply for an special
permission to use cannabis as a medicine
for the treatment of their
diseases uh one of those patients
actually started to or wanted to grow at
home the hom grow model uh and he got a
Sease and desist order from the Barm
which is the federal uh medical
Authority very much like the FDA in in
the US and he went to court and in June
2016 the matter was taken up by uh the
highest uh uh in April of 2016 by the
highest administrative Court in Germany
and they allowed him to cultivate
cannabis for his treatment at home which
for at that point in time was a
nightmare for the legislator and they
came up with the respective rotes and
regulations for narcotic
or the use of a narcotic meaning
cannabis as a medicine in June
2016 in March 2017 it all became legal
uh and since then and that's now I think
the important
Point since then cannabis can be
prescribed as a medicine and why has
that been so outstandingly important
number one uh it has been defined as an
extemporaneous mixture we were talking
this morning about finished products and
the development of finished products and
finished products as you know need of
course a marketing
authorization and for a marketing
authorization you need costly clinical
trials uh with the consequence that if
the trial fails you have lost a
significant amount of money and of
course also reputation for that specific
product and it can only be done for a
certain indication so the importance of
the definition of cannabis as an
extemporaneous mixture cannot be
underestimated because as an
extemporaneous mixture and it come back
to that in a minute you do not need any
kind of clinical
trials The Physician can prescribe
cannabis for the treatment of his
disease the patient gets a prescription
goes to the pharmacy the pharmacist is
preparing the product according to the
prescription and is handing it over so
no need for cl trials no need for
marketing authorization as cannabis in
Germany is defined as an exmor mixture
first important Point secondly there is
no limitation no official limitation at
least on the therapies which indications
we have that in the UK as you know we
have a very limited indication for which
cannabis can be prescribed that's not
the case in Germany in Germany each and
every physician can actually decide
whether cannabis would could be used as
a treatment for the disease of that
specific patient and he can select today
out of 400 different flower products
which are on the market in order to
treat the patient second very important
point and last but not least this
product the extor mixure product does
not need to go through a price finding
process with regard to the reimbursement
for patients you know we have a
very detailed health insurance system in
Germany so everybody has a health
insurance and these products these
treatments with cannabis are going to be
reimbursed by the health insurance
companies upon a specific application by
the patients together with the
Physicians to be
reimbursed at in the Years 2017 and
following our on 60% of these
applications have been granted uh and
the health insurance companies have
reimbursed the patients for their
treatment today we will look at that in
a minute Everything Has Changed on that
but that way are the important points uh
which uh actually led to uh an increase
of patients an increase of prescriptions
since
2017 in April 2024 as I just mentioned
and Kai has outlined this very nicely to
today uh the K the new cannabis act came
into force and with that the medical
cannabis act which contains also of
course new provisions on the medical
cannabis prescriptions and we will look
at that in a
minute so what are the significant
changes since
2017 well there are new prescription
requirements what has Germany done with
the partial legalization for the
recreational market and we mentioned
that this morning whether Slovenia
should go into the right in this
direction as well and I think you have
mentioned it here jper this morning in
your presentation Germany has taken
cannabis out of the German narcotics
act it cannabis is not longer uh a
narcotic it has been transferred into
the Cannabis law in the new cannabis law
that doesn't mean that you can do
everything with cannabis right now
because the same limitations which we
had before with some exceptions which we
have seen on the recreational side this
morning apply to cannabis as well so you
cannot actually freely trade it you
cannot actually sell it you can grow it
at home as we have heard this morning uh
and of course these cultivation
associations are going to be established
and of course hopefully the the pilot
projects scientifically controlled pilot
projects will be established but what is
important is is that this this decision
has an influence on the medical
Market why because now Physicians are
not going to prescribe a
narcotic uh with which is significantly
more difficult than prescribing just a
regular RX product so that has changed
since the 1 of April this year so very
brand new that every physician can
actually now prescribe cannabis as a
regular RX product it's not longer
narcotic so this eliminates of course a
number of bureaucratic requirements not
only for the Physicians who actually had
to register with the B form to prescribe
to be allowed to prescribe Canabis but
also for the pharmacies of course they
have to safeguard the Cannabis it's
still a a product which has certain
requirements but uh it is it is not
longer a
narcotic the next big issue and that has
an impact on the future businesses which
we will see as well is that the
requirement for cultivation medical
cannabis in Germany has been
significantly
changed uh you may know that after
2017 the bform the federal health agency
or medical agency has tendered out uh to
the public uh the possibility to
cultivate medical cannabis in Germany
and three companies actually finally
succeeded in that long winding process
who actually were allowed to cultivate
10.4 metric
tons in four years which mean 2.6 tons
metric tons per year plus a threshold
additional threshold of
10% which is compared to the actual
consumption we will see that in a minute
is a fraction of what is actually needed
in the medical Market this has been
changed which means every uh producer
who thinks he is in a position he can
actually cultivate cannabis can apply
now to the Cannabis agency to get a
license for the cultivation of medical
cannabis which of course we all know is
not easy because of the quality
requirements at least the security
requirements they will not be
loosened and all those three who
actually won the tender back in 2019 if
I'm not mistaken taken all those three
have already applied to increase the
quantity for the cultivation of cannabis
in Germany for the medical market and
have all been granted as of today
respective permissions to increase
significantly the production the
cultivation of their medical cannabis
products which will have a significant
impact on the market as well in
particular for those exporters from
Canada uh the Netherlands and other
countries I come back to that at the end
of my
presentation so all this
has a significant impact on the medical
Market as you see so it's not only since
April 1st we have a partial recreational
Market all the decisions made there had
an impact on the medical Market as well
to its
advantages I have uh now three charts
which I would like to show you the first
one is uh the comparison between the s
imated Demand versus the actual import
of medical cannabis unfortunately the
actual figures for 2022 and 2023 are not
yet available I have other data which
are a little bit more actual than these
ones but what you can see is actually
that uh the respective demand which the
so-called bundus opion shell which is
actually Department of the the German
Bay Farm uh has actually
estimated uh because this has to be and
that's important also Al for Slovenia
you have to actually indicate to apply
to the incb the international narcotic
control board uh for getting permission
to import cannabis for medical purposes
you cannot just order it so the
government in in this case through its
respective Ministry or through the
respective agency has to apply for the
importation of cannabis into the
respective local market uh and gets it
usually
granted uh so there is it's not a big
hurdle but it's a formal process which
each country who's going to import
medical cabus has to
follow and you can see here that the
originally the estimation was
significantly higher than the actual
Imports uh but uh in 2021 it already
leveled out uh and it will probably be
leveled out but significantly increased
for the next years so if you look into
that here now I have some more actual
figures which are the Imports of
cannabis by quarter from the year 2017
to
20124 you see a significant increase
over the years in kilogram uh and in
2024 in particular in the second quarter
uh we have significant increase the
figures uh estimated for the third and
fourth quarter 2024 are even
significantly higher why I will show you
in a minute what kind of impact the
recreational changes had on the medical
market and last but not least these are
the number of prescriptions within the
framework of cedary Health insurances
these are only those patients
prescriptions which you are registered
with their health insurance which who
get reimbursed today and you will see
that in a minute we have a much more
self-pay Market which has been increased
over the last couple of months uh and as
such that is a figure which is only
looking into those patients who have
actually been reimbursed by their uh
health insurance companies and you see
that there is a significant increase uh
we are uh this prescriptions not
patients but today I think we are
looking into what I would say around
100,000 patients uh currently under
treatment with medical cannabis in
Germany which to a certain extent is for
all those who are in the business little
bit disappointing because everybody
thought the market which would be higher
but nevertheless it is by far the
largest markets uh in in Europe with
over well I would say 100,000 patients
if you look into the other markets it's
29,000 patients for Italy Netherlands
around 9,000 patients and Poland 5,200
that is of course also due to the fact
that there their prescription policy is
different so the sales in the medical
Market in Germany are actually to be
expected around half a billion in 2024
which is I would say already significant
increasing by estimated four
approximately 4% per year I believe it
will be probably higher and that market
is going to hit I would say in 2029
though 5 years from now from my
expectations uh the 1 billion uh Euro
Mark Mark uh this is very
conservatively uh
calculated so coming back to the latest
developments and we are now in September
2024 so such uh developments just took
place between first of April and now uh
the medical cannabis Market has
significantly increased
of course through the facts which I
mentioned before the change in the
prescription uh
requirements uh and what has happened
actually is that shortly after the uh
legalization of recreational pabis there
were it platforms created it platforms
which are bringing together Physicians
patients and pharmacies
so today actually a patient can actually
book uh an appointment with uh a
physician via this platform he can use
tele
medicine uh for his
consultation and is getting then an
electronic
prescription either directly to the
pharmacy or back to him and then can
actually uh get his cannabis even with
without having a physical appointment
with a physician delivered to his
doorstep and if you look into the
various different platforms there and we
are advising five of them uh there are
of
course some means which may be at least
questionable for example uh some of them
are using Physicians not in Germany but
outside of Germany within the European
Union for example in Croatia where the
requirements for a tele medicinal
consultation are
significantly losen in comparison to
Germany so he doesn't even has to see
the patient he just files in a
questionnaire uh with uh all his data
and is getting the his prescription or
even not but most of them are getting
the prescription to deliver it to him he
can then actually go to the online
pharmacy file his prescription and gets
the back to deliver to his
doorstep uh I have here citations of all
of three cannabis companies these are
importers or Distributors which is
canash Kiva and Canam medical and you
see that they have a significant
increase in business so all the facts
and figures which you saw on the chge
will be significantly higher in the
third and fourth quarter
2024 alone Canam medical actually
forecasts a 7 to 10 fold increase in
sales so you can say well are they all
patients or do we see kind of a shift
from the recreational Market into the
medical
Market uh probably yes uh but on the
other hand to make it easier for
patients to get a prescription is a good
thing there's no doubt about that and I
have been in the pharmaceutical industry
for many years and and uh I'm I'm
definitely one of those who supports the
use of medical cannabis as an
alternative medicine for various uh Inc
diseases for various indications and I
think we are definitely going in the
right into the right
direction uh whether the prescription
policy which is so liberal currently in
Germany for the prescribing cannabis
will stay in place for the next years I
can't tell you because the authorities
are already very much looking into these
kind of it platforms and distributions
of cannabis however uh this is all
legal because we have uh respective
Arrangement between the European member
states that of course a physician in a
different member State can actually
prescribe cannabis for a patient who is
residing in in another state uh whe
whether this has been foreseen here or
not is a different
question
so if you look into what has happened
since further what happened since then
uh is that 80% of the current cannabis
prescriptions are
self-pairs the ratio was totally
different it was 60 to 40 u in shortly
after the legalization of medicinal
cannabis but now it's really 80% our
self payers uh which is which is
surprising or not surprising very much
depending how you see
that um what is also important is that
the so-called GBA which is the federal
joint committee which is the highest
self-governing body within the German
Healthcare System will loen the
requirements of applying to the health
insurances before the treatment this
cannabis will start so
which is by the way kind of strange
because there is from my point of view
no other RX product where patient has
actually to file an application to his
health insurances to get reimbursement
first before the treatment starts so uh
there will be now a group of Physicians
probably those specialized groups like
Physicians who have are specialized in
in pain treatment where this actually
requirement will be
waved so last but not
least despite the partial
legalization uh there are currently as
we said this morning no ways to buy
recreational Cannabis freely in Germany
which for my point of view would be the
ultimate solution in order to fulfill
the arguments for legalization for the
the legalization of cannabis which is a
of course uh protecting the use uh B to
deliver better products to the
recreational users and C to attack the
black
market um however this is not this is
still on hold as we all know because of
the legal requirements or the legal
hurdles which the European commission
has actually established within the
European Union and of course Germany
didn't want to go to the European court
of justice they if you may remember they
J the German government had just big
losses before the European Court of
Justice the first one was with regard to
that uh car fees or uh the respective uh
payment for using the German autobound
also for pro private cars uh and the
second one was with regard to the
storage of personal data for a longer
period of time so they didn't want to
risk again losing before the European
court of justice and as such actually
went back to that Recreation partial
recreational system which we saw uh this
morning
however uh looking into what is going to
happen in the
future these two questions I think are
imminent the first one is Will
legalization lead to patients buying
cannabis for recreational purposes
instead of medical cannabis or will both
industry be able to fully uh coexist
well we saw that in in Canada after this
I would say full legalization where
everybody can actually buy every ad can
buy uh cannabis in a uh in a licensed
shop uh the medical Market went not sign
significantly but went down here in
Germany through that system which we
have implemented for partially partial
legalization of recreational cannabis in
first of April the opposite was the
case so well obtaining recreational
Cannabis through fewer bureaucratic
huddles of course has its it's uh its uh
benefits however ever whether is going
to be in the future is difficult to say
uh the approach which you heard this
morning of various European countries to
try to change that policy for
recreational Cannabis within the
European Union is the right step to of
doing that last but not least will there
be any changes with regard to Imports of
medical cannabis will they decrease
drastically uh the answer to that is yes
I think so more and more and of of
course all those cultivators which are
already present in Germany uh more and
more cultivators will be coming up
to cultivate medical cannabis in Germany
with the consequence that the more you
domestically
produce the less you are allowed to
import though the incb is of course
monitoring not only the Imports of a
country but also what the country
actually self- cultivates and I can tell
you that these three cultivators already
are looking into significantly
broadening their portfolio with other uh
plants with other uh seeds which they
are going to import in order to really
be competitive on that market with the
consequence that if they come to the
market which will be in due course then
of course the import quota for medical
cannabis will be reduced which has a
significant imp impact of course on the
respective exporters from of course
Canada the the Netherlands and
others having said
that the situation with regard to
medical cannabis from my point of view
is a model which I think to a certain
extent can not be copied but can be
implemented by others it is a success
story with respect to the changes in the
recreational Market I would say they
have
been difficult thank you very much all
right let's hear it from Peter harber
[Applause]