okay uh thank you very much for coming
in from the food and the
Sunshine um so this panel is about Media
Marketing in the legal cannabis industry
uh some of you guys may be aware that
this is the 40th anniversary of the
minor strikes in the UK and uh here on
this panel we've got some uh experts who
have been working at the callace of
media and marketing in the Cannabis
industry for many many years probably in
some cases for longer than they want to
to remember I'm going to ask them to
introduce themselves in a moment but
just before we do that uh and just for
their benefit can we just have a show of
hands in the audience of those of you
who are currently marketing a product or
service in the Cannabis industry right
now and of those uh consumer
product or B2B so more B2B I think and
then those of you who are thinking of of
launching a product or
service okay so a couple okay so um well
before we get started can I ask the
panelists introduce themselves maybe M
we can start with you uh just in terms
of your background and and your general
approach to to marketing and media in in
cannabis yeah uh my name is Michael
knote I come from Germany I'm a
freelance
journalist uh writing for vice magazine
other magazines published a book about
first German book about Canabis
extraction and I'm running a YouTube
channel about cannabis education since
uh 15 years meanwhile no 18 years I'm
running this YouTube channel so uh yeah
I'm quite uh deep into cannabis
marketing I used to be when it was
illegal and now that it it's uh legal as
a medicine I'm also very uh busy with
cannabis Marketing in Germany since
2017 great thank you so much Patrick can
I ask you to introduce yourself U my
name is Petra marinko I come from
Slovenia um I'm the CEO founder and
owner of Nabi brand you've probably
heard of uh we've been on many shows
here and uh we choose a bit different
approach on how we want to sell our
products how we want to present our
products and I'm really happy to be here
and share some of our stuff with you we
started this uh six and a half years ago
s years ago and um my background comes
from architecture so I uh
chose similar architectural approach to
building a brand and building uh and
making products producing products so uh
I don't deal with electricians and
Carpenters anymore so uh and I started
doing this uh with chemists and
cosmetologists and medical PhD doctors
so it's kind of a same thing with
different packaging so happy to be here
thank you so much Shimon hello thank you
so much for coming um I'm Simon uh
Espinosa I flew from Chile and uh 10
years ago we founded what it is what it
is today the most watched cannabis media
in Spanish worldwide it's called
Enola um we create content educational
content and we use humor I have a
background in humor I will be funnier as
the soon as this go don't worry have
patience we'll get there uh but we use
humor as a tool to um make our content
approachable by a community that has an
urgent need of tech technical
information educational information both
in B2B and b2c uh and we are one of the
largest uh digital communities in the
world for cannabis yes thank you s and
you've just come stra from the airport
right so if you start to fall asleep
I'll I'll punch you
um so I think in in in the first place
I'd like to go to again a more general
question I think we heard this morning
already that you know it's an
interesting time for the industry I
think some people would say a
challenging time you know regulations
are not moving perhaps as quickly um as
some had hoped revenues again that
Revenue growth is moderating to some
extent across different markets
categories Etc so the first question I
guess is in terms of what that means for
marketing how does Marketing address add
that issue what has changed in the last
sort of 12 to 18 months around the way
you you address or approach media and
marketing and and maybe patri if I can
start with you from a brand perspective
um how are you kind of approaching it
currently in terms of the current
atmosphere and context in the
industry um from Brand perspective we
started uh when we started it was a lot
of thinking of how we should do it
because there were so many
limitations and um we were
definitely not wanting to address the
influencers with only one reason because
we didn't want our products to be second
best the next time when other people
come and pay more or or uh pay different
amounts of money that we did so that was
a big no no for us so how do it then and
uh it was really interesting step
because social media bursted so much and
there was no other way to to do it and
the covid was in all this time so there
were no shows and nothing like this so
we choose uh a different uh approach and
the for local for I would say local for
Slovenia we used approach to go to mass
Market MH so we were in selling in
hundreds of hundreds of shops in
Slovenia in every village you could buy
Nabi products and that was the biggest
way to uh for us it was a really nice
way to be presented somewhere and to to
um to show ourselves to to get noticed
so brand awareness is something that
people should get and it's hard for to
to to be noticed if you're not there so
for Slovenia this was a really crucial
thing and we have a shop in lublana also
which is a really we we we got the shop
for marketing reasons um it turned out
that it was also a good selling point
because of all the tourists and every
people there um and regarding uh abroad
we choose shows so for example shows
like this AC uh
IBC we we're here always we just had a
joke back there when hi you're still
here and
congratulations which is kind of a big
thing in cannabis business when you
survive from year to year we managed to
survive and we developed really well in
these times um and also thankfully with
this kind of events we are able to
present ourselves as a partner that is
um worth doing business with and that we
show ourselves in different perspective
that people see uh that we differ and
stand out standing out as I mention now
uh is something that is really important
uh in this kind of business um we try to
stand out with packaging that we use we
try to stand out with ingredients that
we use with the approach that we have so
it's kind of finding a way to differ I'm
sure that everybody here knows what I'm
talking about and everybody there um
that is really important to um put a
point on yourself and say okay this is
something that we do and it's different
from everything else you have this is
the most challenging thing to do in this
kind of business but um I think we did
pretty good job till now yes and I guess
the more challenging the industry in
general becomes the more important it is
to be distinctive Etc I think we can
maybe come back to that uh Simon from an
agency perspective and again in in terms
of a more constrained environment and
and challenges that the industry face
how does that play out for you from an
agency perspective how can you
contribute uh and what kind of problems
are you solving for your for your
partners
um yeah um I think it's it's a great
question we've been talking about this
for for a bit now and I'm sure many of
us if we are company owners in the
Cannabis industry wherever you're from
you've suffer quite a bit chances are
these past years have not been the best
for our industry so exclusively talking
about a marketing perspective in this
area we've seen um marketing budgets
shrinking many people aren't able to
allocate as much money or assets or
resources on marketing which means also
that they are letting go of some
specific markets that require that
marketing campaign set in place for them
to be able to capitalize over those
efforts on over the immense effort which
is building a brand in this space and in
addition to that we've seen all the
restrictions that come from everywhere
now I think Michael have a really good
point on on a really good pers
perspective on what's happening in
Germany but we've also we all known or
we've all have our accounts taken down
in social media I'm sure like you've
seen that going it's hard to get any
kind of cannabis content out there
without being highly restriced Shadow
bun or uh just taking down so we've
found some things in this in this very
intricated uh maze they're not stable
though it changes because like the
guidelines for social media change so it
is challenging and it requires for us to
be updated and it requires for us to be
you know uh flexible also to be
everywhere to understand how different
platforms work so so but we what is also
very interesting for me in this um
crisis I would presume it could be like
I don't know if that's such a dramatic
word but it is it is it's been hard so I
know like we all seen it and we all have
friends in the space so we know how it
is um but it's also a really good
opportunity for companies that are
looking into the marketing space
understanding that many other many
companies that had in house marketing uh
branches are not going to be able to
continue with that so uh a lot of uh the
resources are moving to Outsourcing this
marketing resources so it's h an
interesting opportunity for companies
that are moving there to have high
margin assets to provide for our
industry so I would say those are the
two main areas in which we've been
developing and investigating these past
few years trying to be a better asset
for our fellow colleagues MH very
interesting so M I know you have
particular experience with social media
and so on and I want to get to that uh
in a few moments but just before we get
to that and sticking with kind of the
theme of challenges um there may be
people in the audience uh who don't know
exactly what will be possible or not
possible in the German context moving
forward um once we have kji and so on so
can you just talk a little bit about um
I think largely what won't be possible
in the German context but just so we're
all clear on on that from a marketing
perspective it's I can say it in quite
easy words uh we used to Canabis used to
be a part of the narcotic act which
meant that you were not allowed to
advertise for cannabis but which in
reality meant you were not allowed to
advertise strains but companies were
allowed to advertise the brand which is
a a smart marketing uh approach uh had
uh was needed
to let me say Focus certain straints but
it's it's possible it was possible and
now that cannabis is out of the narcotic
act and into the new cannabis act it's
not unregulated but it's out of the
narcotic act and into the new cannabis
act but when it comes to advertising
it's actually the same like before like
it was in the narcotic act but the new
law mentions for example influen which
was not mentioned before in the which
which we call pharmaceutical uh uh
advertisement law we have a
pharmaceutical advertisement uh uh
Prohibition in Germany it's not allowed
and but pharmaceutical companies are
allowed to advertise for their company
for their brand and actually now for
cannabis for recreational Cannabis it's
all the same but influencing is included
so uh we have to find uh of course nice
uh smart worker rounds in my eyes uh
which means brand should focus on their
brand uh I have a nice example for the
alcohol brand for alcohol branding for
example uh all the big beer companies
they sponsor spots event spot uh spot
events but it's not allowed to advertise
for alcohol on sport events of course so
what are they doing they bring out the
alcohol free brand which has the same
logo like the alcohol brand or it's red
instead of blue and then it's uh allowed
to work to advertise for alcohol-free
beer on a sports event and uh I must
just come come back to Petra and I have
to contradict a little
because um drama if if any company does
their marketing themselves we wouldn't
sit here so in my eyes also on a small
level in nowadays a smart influencer
marketing a smart social media it
doesn't have to be done by influencers
but the smart smart social media
marketing has a very big impact what I
must agree on that in a small country
like Slovenia you have a lot of other
marketing strategies which you can use
because it's a small country but
compared to Spain or to Germany it
wouldn't be possible to do this kind of
marketing what would would it direct
trade marketing is different difficult
scale yeah so I want to give Patra right
of reply on on that so Petra can you
just talk a little bit about how you use
social media and maybe some kind of key
tips for for anyone in the audience
about approaching social media as a
cannabis brand I would agree uh with
what you had to say Michael um
because maybe I said influencers um a
bit hard it's a bit harsh to to to get
it to all influencers because I was
addressing to the paid ones that are
selling one product today and the other
product tomorrow so this is the only
uh thing that I was addressing um but
there are many ways to use influencers
in a smart way like you said and
uh combining your I don't know ideas
with a really known person or or doing
something with that it's completely
different thing so um for us our um uh
social media approach was a bit
different and uh also marketing approach
uh regarding how we will present that
our products are really good um so we
choose the approach to to tell people
about the feel that they get from our
product not what this product does but
you you you you you you try it and you
feel it and you will feel it and um it
it was a bit different because everybody
was saying about anti- wrinkle this does
this and this does do that and every
product has claims on what it does we
couldn't say anything about CBD so how
to do it if you cannot say anything and
we choose to talk about the Feld and
it's showing off that we are um gaining
a lot of followers just because we are
talking about the fields different kind
of fields so how could you sleep um how
how do you dream if you can sleep for
example is one of our um things with and
you get a product for that and uh it
doesn't say that it will help you sleep
but it says it in a in a different way
so uh this was kind of a um way that we
tried to to get through all the the the
Banning that happens and so on and
people actually share our content that's
I think uh Simon will have a lot to say
I follow Simon and his every where and
everybody's um sharing your content
which is really interesting and he has
so special approach so it's kind of
again to differ and to stand out that's
all the magic it's almost like patri if
it sounds like you're using poetry or
something to to to be distinctive and
and ask people see on you use humor a
lot in in the work that you and your
agency does and the the point of that I
guess is not just to be funny it's
because that enhances the quality of the
interactions you're getting on on the
social media sites and and prevents or
protects you a little bit from things
like Shadow Banning and all that sort of
stuff is that is that correct yeah uh it
it has many layers I would say uh and
thank you for your words um what we use
actually what we're based on is science
it's all fully educational content and
that's something that can Transit and
and move through social media without as
many restrictions as like other
marketing content for cannabis products
this should be very well known by this
point educational content if it's uh
marked and tagged as educational content
have like way more chances to not be
Shadow Bann or deleted from at any given
platform that being said humor has also
like a different perspective and and and
some many other layers for starters um
we know that we cannot uh paid for
promotion so chances are that if we have
a cannabis account a Canabis social
media account we're going to need
organic following and organic engage
engagement this is something that's also
basic and should be very well known at
this point that all your resources need
to be allocated in this form of uh
distribution for social media content or
Audi visual content for that matter and
then this is something that that it's a
little bit more hard to measure but I
think it our experience can tell us that
there's something else in our community
that is uh something a little bit more
untangle but not less real uh which is
our own culture and our own culture has
a comedy background that has been lying
there forever it was comedians who were
among the first activist for cannabis
just as much as like the hipop urban
culture as well but they're they've been
there and we have and I I would I I
would uh say this for for all of us I
hope I'm right I'm not trying to uh put
words in anybody's mouth but um I think
we have uh predilection for for uh
laughter and we look uh for um health
and for for for a medical experience
also in laughter because it has helped
us uh deal with a lot of what
prohibition and stigma has done in us
and and comedy and humor it's a
therapeutical form of culture as well
and I think that like that's not
necessarily explained uh but it's
something that is also like lying there
and is inherent to our culture and we
tapped into that and we noticed that
when you laugh you share and that's
something that you cannot pay for in
like advertisement so that's an
interesting tool that we've been using
and we' we try to make science funny uh
we try to make it approachable we try to
talk to our community in a very genuine
way the way we are uh and this is also
very important and should be very well
known by now after we've seen what
happened with uh celebrity brands in our
industry we all we've all seen it right
there are exceptions of course but we
all know what happens there so being
like legit I would say or or genuine and
coherent to the community something that
that humor does very well for us and I I
guess it might also be the case that
cannabis users have a very high
detection level for inauthenticity as
well so I mean speaking of being
authentically yourself M can I ask you
to just talk a little bit about your
experience with social media some of the
challenges you've had and how you kind
of it's an ongoing process I guess in
terms of of continuing to try and get
your message across and be heard Etc uh
when it comes to cannabis there are a
lot of challenges there are legal
challenges uh there stigma there's
stigmatizing challenges so all in all
and I would say you have to be a
Storyteller influencers or they have to
be a Storyteller you have to build a
story around your brand around your
product the people people want to listen
to and uh not the product has to be
really in Focus you know it has doesn't
have to be in Focus the the most
important thing is your story you know
and of course the product has to be
mentioned and everybody has to know what
it's about your story but the story is
much more important than the rest and
this is also what I say we are good
storytellers as influencers you know
you're comedian so we we are
professional storytellers so if anybody
of your companies has a good Storyteller
who can act in front of the camera make
him your your social media influencer if
your company doesn't have one you should
really think about social media
marketing because social media marketing
is the most most U um attractive
marketing uh the most successful
marketing at the moment and it will this
will not change anymore I used to be an
author I used to uh publish a hemp
cannabis magazine in 2004 we started and
that was a very s successful model
meanwhile all cannabis magazines are
fighting to survive you know and uh even
micro influ influ ERS have an income
while the big magazines struggle to
survive so there is there is no way back
and because cannabis is so limited uh we
have to tell stories and in the stories
we have to avoid everything why cannabis
is stigmatized so and and influencers
now to do that they are Professionals in
that so if you need a product to be uh
promoted legally and with a nice story
asking professional influencer to do
that direct question I guess how often
do you find yourself Shadow ban and when
that happens how do you deal with it how
do you make sure it doesn't happen in
the first place meanwhile I have more
problems that a lot of my customers are
Shadow
banned I'm kind of experienced I I I I
know what what I can do in social media
and what not but my customers they are
not as experienced as I am and for
example on Instagram I had three
customers being shadowbanned within the
last three month then I can of course
not fulfill my contract I have with them
so I also say if you are my customer you
also have to care about your own shadow
bands and how you act on social media as
a company because if you spend money on
influencing and your own account is
Shadow band The influencer cannot do
anything and this is very tricky so uh
this is not uh a lot of people think
because they have a private Instagram
which is running quite well okay I I do
my I do my business Instagram myself and
uh no you have to this is a real
professional job and even I employ
people for my Instagram account and for
my Facebook account and for my YouTube
account because it's a very very uh
complicated and and and it takes it's
complicated and takes a lot of time to
run it and you don't see it if if if if
you click on my account you don't see
that but there's a lot of work and money
behind it and uh this is why uh
influencing is not so cheap as uh a lot
of people expect that not as easy as it
looks obviously so we've got just less
than 10 minutes left so I just want to
make sure that we we get some questions
from the audience if there are so if you
can put your hands up uh anyone wants to
ask so there's one
here it'll happen there you go let's
hear it for the
panel you had a
question uh hello um I'm coming from a
legal background here when you plan or
brainstorm on advertis ing on social
media do you usually look at terms and
condition of Facebook Instagram and what
do they say on cannabis or CBD or
because that's that's something you
always need to look
at as an influencer for me it's hard to
communicate with them there are also no
uh strict rules or no real rules about
cannabis marketing because every country
country has its own law so Facebook
YouTube uh m and you Google they decided
to make their own cannabis uh uh rules
which they do not really communicate
it's only about soft drugs you and I
know what I'm allowed to do and what I'm
not allowed to do but I cannot look it
look it up in a book so I have to find a
trial and error and uh meanwhile I I I'm
I'm expert in the trial and error
principle and I don't get I I didn't get
a strike for I think one and a half
years and I didn't get a shadow ban for
I think on Instagram for a year so but
only because I'm experienced and there
are even words here are not allowed to
use now it's It's Tricky so uh TR and
error because uh the big companies don't
do not commun communicate about this
topic with the influencers they just
don't communicate I even tried it with
the manager who's really good well
connected to YouTube and even they
didn't they didn't talk they didn't
answer his uh his requests uh from I'm a
professional YouTube uh uh manager so I
have no idea there's a uh a dispensary
in
Colorado that you're not allowed to do
TV ads of your dispensary so they made
tv ads of the businesses next door to
them everyone around them yeah right
like come and get a pedicure it's right
next door to the
dispensary right come and buy a sandwich
from this place it's right next door to
the
dispensary so that that actually worked
uh we have a question over
here hi again I am graa the founder of
can Portugal and uh I just want to uh to
remind that when it comes to the
marketing in the legal industry we need
to think that where we are has one of
the biggest ways to promote cannabis in
the legal um uh industry because we tend
to forget that
forums um uh conferences Expos fairs and
so on uh and this is not fair because we
are all together and we are sharing our
histories and we are doing such a good
job giving this huge contribution for
the marketing uh in the legal uh
industry so I dare to ask a big Applause
to Alex Rogers who has done such a good
a great job doing this
marketing um and helping all of us uh in
improving our businesses thank you so
much thank you that was wonderful here
we
go uh I'm Max Kobe with abstracts thank
you Michael and panel for sharing your
knowledge it's great to be here my
question for you guys is we're
constantly challenged with the shifting
rules on Instagram and things and so we
think uh adding you know stars in
between Cana not spelling it correctly
might help us I'm just wondering if you
could grace us with maybe your top three
tips to avoid getting shadow baned
do you want to disclose that information
M try try to avoid the the ver cannabis
try to avoid consumption in front of
camera and try to avoid anything that
might be seen as that it's uh addressed
to minors or children anything even the
pet or or or something in the picture so
those three things I noticed on my
account that if I post a a silly
cannabis meme right Instagram doesn't
care they'll they'll send it out to
everybody but if I post a picture of
cannabis and say I got this from these
people then they're like hey hey hey hey
you can't do that so you have to find a
way to be roundabout you can't just be
like come buy the [__] over here and
humor as you say humor humor humor's big
hum so we we reach over like 2 million
people every month and we have
consumption camera and we use the word
cannabis and um what was the other thing
you
mentioned we do all those three I'm sure
children children children too yeah but
but yeah what what we do also is we T
our content as educational cannabis
content and we ensure that it is
educational we also um uh like Target
for over 18 before it's published we
don't let YouTube to do the work for us
because then you get like uh revised
which is I'm I don't know who I'm
looking who was who made the question
like and then um we also ensure that as
Michael noticed also is not focused on
the product or the Cannabis specifically
so that the content is not like a
promotional content for that but it's a
story or it's around something that
congregates you and this is also very
important because it generates creates
way more engagement with your community
when you're actually giv something that
uh helps whether it's a tip for how to
grow your cannabis or a tutorial on how
to uh use a vaporizer or how to uh roll
a joint or any of those things something
that provides a useful tool for our
community it's going to go a long way
because we don't have any tools we don't
have any resources that's what's some
what's common in our communi that we
don't have the information education
there is no universities there's no um a
lot of authorized sources to get
information so every oh nice someone
brought a
dog good for you though um I'll take the
dog question what you're saying though
that question is kind of
rough I will answer in barking no um but
yeah using these elements providing
useful tools providing education assets
for the community would generate a
deeper engagement and you will know and
find out by yourselves that the the how
deep is this gap of knowledge that we
are we're missing and we're eering as a
community all right one last one right
here can can I add some yes please um
you didn't like my answer I loved your
answer and I agree totally with that but
I would like to add something and that
would be right poetry like you said
um poetry I think it's something and let
people feel feel what you have to say I
think that's one of the things to do on
Instagram or Facebook poetry is good
okay what one last question right here
I'm sorry poetry is good Chicago um are
you guys talking to chat Bots AI chat
Bots right now number one and number two
what is going to happen with their AI
influence on your work in terms of
marketing of cannabis let's say the next
two to 5 years someone that sounds like
one for you correct me if I'm wrong
that's a really good question we we
didn't speak about AI but it's it's a
major thing of course I'm sure we've all
aware of what it can do for us in so
many aspects there's an AI for
everything now uh generating SEO uh
what's the word optimize sorry SEO
optimized text for cannabis without
using the word cannabis could be one
thing uh but I can speak about our
experience as company so as soon as like
the first uh GPT came out I I hired
someone to to actually um train our
stuff in AI so we're using it on daily
basis we actually use uh to create video
that has cannabis backgrounds
self-generated or so so we are using it
now and it can be very helpful to uh
avoid mistakes when creating content for
for starters I don't know if that
answers the question that you did will
it ever write poetry though is the
question what will it ever write poetry
I I've asked like I'm I'm a writer
myself so I I I try to do some poetry in
GPT and still sucks I'm sure it's going
to get better but it's it's really bad
poetry so far so I you're safe me not so
much no but as long as we use it in in
in a creative way I think it can be can
be a lot of help we are using it right
now and we have a few shows that you can
see how we use it it's not the the
content it's it's a tool
right check high as hell in Spain
Barcelona is very nice I don't have the
rest it's the beginning of work I think
I was riding a hiou I was trying to ride
a hi cou hi cou hi
cou uh I think we're out of time let's
hear it again thank you very much
everyone for Shane and Petra and Michael
and and
Simone I need I would like more food
there you go that's the end high as hell
in Spain Barcelona is very nice I would
like more food boom or the topest are
great there you go that's the way it's
more depth that
way all right this is the international
cannabis business conference barcalona
batro or I guess what you say those do
do I don't
know
batro I just like to say it batro I'm
just going to walk around saying that
all the time B gu B