it's the M&amp;A panel and we've got we're
talk fill of industry heavy
for you here I will give you a quick
introduction and actually take it out to
all these folks that'll take a minute or
two to tell them or to tell you guys
about themselves and their companies so
we've got Paul Brockman I'm sorry
Patrick Brockman yes the other one so
we've got Patrick Brockman who's the
executive chairman of passions Patrick
you want to say a couple words about
yourself here and what you guys do over
at passion Pasha is I think Canada's
first prohibition-era brand house where
our approach to the market was to gather
the legacy growers the brands that were
on the shelves of dispensaries prior to
legalization at the same time we took
advantage of the new regulations with
Health Canada to allow for a micro
cultivator or a craft grower to get in
the regulated economy so we bought a an
LP and instead of growing flour were
entering into supply agreements to
purchase that flour from craft growers
across the country so we're the largest
craft brand housed at the same time
we're aggregating all of that production
that is currently supplying 90 percent
you know of Canadians needs so that's my
latest a year ago I was part of a
company called doja cannabis I was a
founding director and we got really
lucky it was a lifestyle brand and I
smoked my first joint in grade 7 and
I've loved cannabis I've made money with
it and they'd love with cannabis and
it's been a really great experience and
so canopy came knocking and gave the
shareholders a you know a huge win and
so that's kind of my latest thing I love
cannabis and I love the culture that
created this industry and I've taken an
approach that is focused on that
community and helping them transition so
that they can really take back that
industry that was stolen from them so
that's me
thanks Patrick and then we've got Bobby
cause Hayley from hard assets Inc I am
come out of the real estate in the fine
art worlds I started investing in
cannabis five years ago mmm with my son
it was at that time cultivating about
5000 feet he now has licenses in LA and
we've made investments around the world
in what I call an ecosystem so the
underpinnings are technology science
innovation and I'm very interested in
women and their companies and their
products and often invest in them
one of the women she's interested in is
our own Jamie Pearson as CEO of Bank
Corporation hi i'm jamie pearson the CEO
of Bank Corporation bang is a publicly
traded global house of brands we started
with our award-winning chocolate bar
developed by a master chocolatier and
have since evolved into over 100 SKUs we
are currently distributed in nine US
states and nine foreign countries our
Canadian partner it was on the previous
panel Neil within diva and they've got a
booth next door there so go check them
out bang is really has a global vision
for where cannabis can be and we're
executing that vision strategically and
M&amp;A is a huge part of of that process I
am the daughter of a cultivator he's
been cultivating 55 years I'm a
second-generation cannabis person but I
made my way in business in real estate
and finance much like Bobby I was a real
estate investor for 25 years doing those
deals going to get money for deals was
came easy to me I have real estate
investments in three countries so I've
learned how to navigate rules depending
on you know where we are the culture the
finance rules governmental rules so
deals were coming across my desk in the
real estate space that had to do with
cannabis and obviously having a dad in
cannabis
and you know being a business person in
the cannabis space I started seeing
these deals come across my desk and
realize there was an opportunity for me
to get into cannabis directly and saw it
for the opportunity that it is it's it's
going to be the next big global thing
and we are all there or pre-prohibition
but we can't put the genie back in the
bottle
people are getting addicted to those tax
dollars and starting to see what
cannabis can do not only for
governmental organizations with funding
but also we're seeing opioid addiction
rates go down and domestic violence go
down and we're starting to see the real
benefits of this magical plant and also
the benefits in the environmental era
that we can start assuring in if we're
going to be responsible so a little bit
about my story a little bit about bang
I'm excited to be here
and I'll turn it over to you so then
we've got Paul Paul Peterson CEO
co-founder of next leaf Paul so I've
been in the industry for about six years
now I was initially at working for
peace' naturals we were the first
producer in Canada worked with the
founders to sell the company to Kronos
group and started next leaf it our focus
was to acquire and develop extraction
technology that we felt would lower the
cost per milligram when you're looking
at CBD and THC as ingredients and
obviously very excited for 42.0 products
we just announced today a deal today
with Bev canna
are now exclusive beverage partner so
very excited to start commercializing
some of our distillates and high purity
oils through our manufacturing partners
that are now starting to come online
very cool thanks in just for a little
context again I'm Dean Arvid
I help run a couple entities one is
Wagner demas which is a company that is
developed and patented pre-roll
technology we operate with the licensee
called urban in California which rolls
the most joints in the world and then
we've licensed our technology to Aurora
here in Canada and then the other
companies but calm which is a delivery
and online retailer so I'm also I'm an
investor an entrepreneur sort of all of
the above
just to give you guys a little bit of
context and sort of jumping right in
we've we've got two investors here or
operator investors that are based in the
US and myself that makes three then
we've got a couple Canadians right so
first question is how does the structure
meaning if you're private or public how
does that affect M&amp;A activity from the
standpoint of each of these companies so
kick it out to Patrick first how do you
look at based on how that company is
structured and where they are how does
that affect sort of your view of them
structure from my perspective is is you
know looking at management and you know
what what kind of control this
management have and how much you know
that management group has invested and
then outside shareholders is key you
know for longevity I think those are
probably the two most important I don't
know that you know issued an outstanding
you know really is is that relevant but
that's my take structure interesting as
a I'm an investor without a fund this
time so it's just my own money so I tend
to look very carefully at management and
I tend to usually want to work closely
with that management on expanding their
opportunities sometimes it's helping
raise some or cap
more often now it's cross-pollinating
but I've just hit a little interesting
thing that I'm going to speak about even
though it's quite private I've been
invited on the board of a public company
so some of the companies that I've
invested in I've brought to management
and we're negotiating very tightly for
some of those companies so when we talk
about structure I don't have a deal
structure to bring these investments to
the company and I'm now thinking and
wondering and I'd love any counsel for
many of you is what do I charge for my
services since I haven't gone on the
board yet and I'm acting in fact as an
investor broker to bring a company a
whole company into the mix of a public
company so I'd love counsel on that I
don't have an answer this week Jamie so
bang went public on through an RTO on
the CSC in July before that obviously we
were privately held company and our I
think our pre public life was very much
developing our strategic plan once we
went through that going public process
which was very painful and if any of you
are planning to do that please come talk
to me but seriously I learned a lot from
that process and it took it took a lot
of a lot of people a lot of lawyers and
a lot of paperwork that you know in
retrospect caused us to put a strategic
plan together that's that's very focused
and now our M&amp;A look is focused on where
are those margin and revenue a creative
opportunities where the fit is perfect
for what we need to grow bigger so we're
we're not only looking to grow our top
line and our bottom line revenue and
we're looking to grow our distribution
reach and we're looking to grow our
brand recognition reach and we're
looking for companies that aren't
looking for somebody I get a lot of this
oh I have this great idea and basically
what they're saying is I developed a
great product I need
and I need you to run my business for me
because I have a great idea in cannabis
but I don't know how to run a business I
don't know how to do marketing I don't
know how to you know get distribution
and they basically want to bring me
their great idea and help me help me
make them successful we're looking for
the same thing we're looking for
companies that have a value add for bang
that fill some of the gaps that we have
so that these these acquisitions are
strategic and fit well with what bang
has going on we've been a CPG company
since day one we have been putting
consumer packaged goods in the hands of
consumers around the world for 10 years
so we're very clear about what we need
and what what lanes were going into we
just acquired a beverage company called
red ace organics if any of you read that
press release we're excited about that
because it's professional athletes it's
Olympic athletes that are using these
products because they are you know the
new buzzword is app to genetic
functional beverages Redis has been
selling these products in in you know
the large chain distribution centers
like Whole Foods sprouts Amazon for
years and has this massive following of
athletes that are using these products
because they work so we saw that as a an
a creative acquisition for bang because
it fit some holes that we had in our
distribution plan and so that's what
we're looking for prior to going public
we just looked at every deal as we were
kind of figuring out who we wanted to be
now we're clear about who we are and
we're going after it so I guess that
just to clarify and then we'll we'll
take it out to Paul and actually maybe
back to Patrick after that but I'm
talking about do you as a public entity
look at pub COEs or private companies
more favorably when you're looking at
M&amp;A activity so does that actually
impact your decision-making yeah I mean
on the willingness of management in a
private company to engage with you so
but I think effectively yeah you didn't
want to target something private you do
yeah Jamie I am a big believer that you
just look for the win-win opportunity
and where there's a meeting of minds
where you've got management that's
really in sync with goals and aligned
with I think the philosophy we're not
looking for a money grab and we're not
out there just trying to gain top-line
revenue we're out there really looking
for like I said those are creative
acquisitions that make sense for us and
if they're private or they're public I'm
gonna take a look at them and your deals
for stock or cash or both depending in
real estate you know it you every deal
is its own animal and you got to figure
out what works for both people so what
I'm hearing is essentially it's
irrespective of the wraparound it's it's
about what they're doing and the team so
Paul do you agree though a publicly
traded company merging or acquiring
another publicly traded company we're
investing in or that gets very notated
yeah Paul you want to chime in I'm just
gonna say you know for for structure we
always say that you know there's a lot
of froth out in the market today if you
look at you know valuation or market cap
versus of a publicly traded company
versus a private there's not a lot of
fundamentals that make sense right now
there's a company with a 900 million
dollar market cap that did $20,000 in
cannabis revenue the first six months of
2019 right won't mention the name but
you know I think I think what what we've
seen in this industry is that is that
there's a lot of companies that have
been structured to be publicly traded
companies that the full retail investors
the end of the day this bubble is going
to pop in the sense that a bubble of
creates created when you can finance a
company on storytelling but the good
thing is I think we're getting to a
place where were you know having
fundamentals to driving your business
and being able to put out a product that
that consumers want at a price that you
guys can make money at is something that
it
is going to make sense when we look at
acquisitions we look at we look at
privately you know private companies we
look at technology that's come out of
the the legacy market in BC I think
we've been very successful in working
with operators and and entrepreneurs
that maybe have needed help to to
commercialize their their technology and
I think this is the thing that we love
about British Columbia is that there's
some some great operators and some very
experienced cannabis people in this
province that we're really having fun
and and for us we've been focused on
intellectual property so not just
acquiring technology but filing patents
around us and with the all Trias and the
consolation brands of the world we think
that intellectual property really allows
the small guys to to force the bigger
guys to play nice agreed and so Paul you
make a great point that right now there
is sort of a flight to quality we
started to see that sort of away from
these sort of bombastic like just really
headline-grabbing
sort of optical business models and
really really inflated valuations based
on top-line revenue are you guys seeing
right now are you guys seeing sort of a
in focus with your companies more for
sort of profitability gauging engaging
potential M&amp;A targets by their evide and
not top-line I think there's gonna be
really two at least we've seen some
acquisitions in the last 12 months but
going forward I think that still many of
the big five for example or overpriced
overvalued and they're still going to
need to fill in their back in their
balance sheet backfill it with new
assets that can support that valuation I
think that you're still gonna you know
see that happening they're gonna have to
justify that but yeah I mean everyone's
skating towards revenue and you know
with a limited market that Canada
presents you know really the only choice
if you're capitalized and structured
well is to be looking at
USS assets that are cash flowing they're
legitimate and just look at the you know
there were two acquisitions today you
know big so they're happening but
they're all US assets right now because
that market is under regulated relative
to Canada so it makes for a safe haven
for capital so you've seen the you know
if anyone's here looking for money I'm
sure there are you know in the in the
Canadian market there's just been a you
know a giant sucking sound and it's you
know the sound of money
you know headed south and as it's that's
where they want to be because regulators
are off our backs and people can
function you know much better relative
to the Canadian markets well so under
regulated relative to the Canadian
market still very regulated but I think
at the end of the day look it's the
consumer market it's a very mature
consumer market and there are companies
making hundreds of millions of dollars
off of like in actual revenue running
their businesses yeah I mean look I
don't eat like the California market is
roughly the same population as Canada
there's you know six or seven thousands
lysed and licensed entities in
California now and they you know they do
it quickly we've got like what two or
three hundred you know got retail you
know the numbers from retailing it's
like we represent thirteen percent of
the population in in Canada Alberta
right across the border they're like I
think like four percent they've got half
the number of licensed retail outlets
for the whole country because the
government is off
you know entrepreneurs backs so it's
more successful and there's more
cannabis being sold in in Alberta who
would have thunk right but that's the
relationship between efficiency capital
and the markets is where government is
not intrusive you see progress being
made and people being able to you know
create healthy safe products you know
that don't have a lot of garbage
packaging on that people want so your
question essentially if
restate it and correct me if I'm wrong
is putting it in banks perspective is
bang making different decisions now
because there's pressure on the for us
to be looking for bottom line revenue as
opposed to doing these you know
willy-nilly acquisitions looking for
top-line revenue top line aesthetics yes
I think from from bank's perspective we
put together a really strong executive
management team we're all shareholders
so the duty that we have to shareholders
is a duty we have to ourselves we are
all very interested in bang being very
successful so when you come at that
question of are we looking at bottom
line revenue yes we want to improve our
cogs we want to improve our top-line
revenue we want it to filter down so
that all of us are making more money
that isn't just because we have a
responsibility at the end of the day to
people you know there's a lot of people
trying to do these quick turn
investments and there's a big short game
when you are in a small cap stock that
you're watching because you know you
make this great announcement your stock
goes up and then people sell and because
you don't have that much volume trading
that one sale can affect your stock
price it's a very tenuous game that
we're in but we just keep saying I tell
everybody that works for me don't look
at the stock price make good decisions
because at the end of the day if you're
running a good business and you're
making good decisions the stock market
becomes a weighing machine as opposed to
a you know that short-term you know
market has spoken and I want I want our
company to be heavy at the end I want us
to be you know the biggest baddest
company we can be but that's banks
perspective and I know it's unusual but
to answer your question out in the
marketplace yes I'm seeing a shift I'm
seeing these big companies and the
smaller you know mid mid cap stock
companies are no longer just playing an
M&amp;A game they're not they're not gaming
it anymore
we're starting to see a push for bottom
line revenue which I think will benefit
the industry you know all the way
through it's a sign a maturity I think
we're at another stage also we went
through a big investment cycle and we
sort of set
the standards in the industry what I'm
seeing now is my investments are
maturing there are opportunities for
them to grow and partner with others or
whatever but now I'm starting to look at
the Israeli scene I'm investing in a
number of laboratories I have a honey
product that will take a long time but
will come to market so I think that
there's another shift that's going on we
saw the run up of the Canadians of come
becoming public the stock market but now
for the investor crowd like me I think
we want to see what's new and how do we
integrate it and what we have and where
we think the market is going the market
is absolutely going to be a consumer
market but we're also producing
high-quality low-cost products for seven
billion people in this world and I think
we as an industry have this
responsibility to take care of everyone
not just the luxury market not just the
craft market this is an international
product when one more I think point on
that is that we're having conversations
internally on the executive team that
there are a lot of really good brands
out there that are making excellent
products that aren't going to make it
they're under capitalized or they
they're in a state where something the
moons aren't lining up for them and so
we're also watching those brands very
closely because we know that they're
going to be opportunities for us to you
know come in and not contrary to what I
said before where I want brand I want to
do M&amp;A activity that's a that's actually
beneficial to bang or plugs a hole or is
a natural fit but we're also looking to
and seeing really smart people with
really good brands that aren't going to
make it we're you know we've got our eye
on them too and I think that's another
shift in what's happening in the in the
investment space yes and I think that in
these investments that I'm making it's
sometimes not just the product but it's
the talent the talent and the passion
and their ability to pivot so you bring
in that IP to the company to my company
and it can be utilized in other products
and services well synergizing across
of all your entrepreneurs absolutely so
let's take it out to sort of a different
facet of of how the industry is growing
let's talk about different products in
verticals that right now you guys see as
sort of the fastest growing the commerce
what verticals suppositions specific
sectors in the space we hear a lot about
beverages and that's been obviously
something that's been out there happy to
start with Paul on this one you have
something for us but yeah you know what
for us we've really looked at
intellectual property as being an area
that I think there's gonna be a lot more
focus on in Canada at least it's all
been about growing plants because the
2.0 products haven't been legal when we
look at other industries biotech life
sciences Pharma intellectual property
tends to play a big role in in M&amp;A
activity but also in shareholder value
and I think for us we've said from day
one let's not reinvent the wheel let's
go out there and acquire intellectual
property from guys that have built it in
an unregulated marketplace and let's
let's further develop it let's scale
that with it with our engineers and and
and file intellectual property around
there we see all these downstream
formats that lead to more mass-market
appeal being what I think a lot of
companies are gonna be really focused on
whether that's through acquisition or
developing those in-house and even your
example with the joint roller that
you've license to Aurora I think it's
these new formats that maybe companies
don't have that expertise or they don't
have that technology in-house that
they're gonna go to another market
whether it's the US or elsewhere and
look at licensing or acquiring it and I
think the the new formats at least in
Canada are gonna really change I think
how cannabis is consumed but when you
think about where cannabis needs to go
today to it to where it needs to go
you know let's call it ten years from
now is is mass market appeal isn't gonna
be in in the the plant being smoked it's
gonna be in all the nonsmoker pools that
the baby boomers and sort of today's non
consumers get comfortable with consuming
throughout
so I absolutely agree and yes Paul
alluded to sort of our IP on the on the
pre-roll side and we actually use that
IP as a form of non-dilutive financing
when we licensed our tech and you know
got an eight-figure some back with the
royalty from Aurora so uh it's right now
I would very much agree me being a bit
tainted but IP is something that I see
is something that will differentiate
beyond what right now is on the market
which is which are essentially a lot of
commoditized solutions
everyone's selling the same things it's
just how do you do it a little better
Jamie your point we we always quote this
famous Henry Ford saying where he said
if if customers had asked me if I had
asked customers what they wanted they
would have said a faster horse he
invented the car obviously okay so we're
saying in that regard we customers don't
know what they want because they they
don't necessarily look at the
environment and think what's possible so
our job is to see what's possible and
those low barrier to entry delivery
systems are kind of a no-brainer the the
European American Canadian consumer
already alters their brain with beverage
they already used wine and beer and
alcohol to relax so we you know I try to
picture my mom out there with a dab rig
and a blowtorch and she's probably not
going to be dabbing and and neither am i
just so you know I did it once with my
dad it was not good and I'm not gonna
dab over again but but beverages I hope
yourself know to some yeah and if you
ever want to know just come ask me out
it's it's it was unpleasant but the
beverage side of things I think we can
all wrap our brain around and I think
the beverage companies are trying to
figure out how do I think in fact Bobby
you now we're talking about this in Palm
Springs last week it was how do I go
drinking with my friends
and I want to have two or three
beverages and get high I don't want to
get drunk so how do I do that because I
like the way cannabis makes me feel and
I want to go have that social experience
and I think the companies that are
figuring out how to do what consumers
want and do it right probably with IP
when bang spent an IP company that's
what we how we've spreader our message
in our footprint is through licensing IP
the same way Wagner Dimas has we also we
see skin care you know beauty products
men's grooming we've got a couple of
female skin care line and a men's
grooming line coming out because that's
a low barrier to entry people are
already doing that and in dog treats and
things that they do with their pets if
we can figure out a way to enhance
consumers lives in a way that's already
accessible and easy and that they
understand I think the most important
piece though is that the products have
to work and I think that's where to
Bobbi's point we have a responsibility
to be using good active ingredients and
the products need to be safe and it
can't just be lip service it has to be
what we're really doing I think the
other thing that I'm on a quest for is
to solve problems so for example I think
that osteoporosis is a gigantic problem
in the world when you think of people
over 50 and the disintegrates the diets
that we use and so forth and how it's
breaking down bones I'm looking at
endometriosis and other glaucoma other
issues that are international issues for
the population that we can solve with
cannabis so it's not just a consumer
game but it's also solving the problems
that we all face in some way with a
female plant very truthful
Patrick Science and Technology have
agree with everything that's been said
I'm most excited I'm a flower guy but I
recognized in the beverage category that
I if you can create a new up takes you
know technology so that you're getting
high you know in three minutes and you
can continue in by Bing
you know without getting you know higher
but I think that means that the beverage
has to have a rich cannabinoid enriched
terpene recipe and because that's what I
want in the cannabis experience I don't
want just a THC so that's technology and
I think that's you know one of the
really exciting things I really think
that we're in the infancy of an industry
if you want to you know you use a
metaphor as a ball game I think we're in
the third inning and it's just starting
there's so many incredible things that
are gonna happen and you know we look at
the euphoria that's been in the cannabis
market over the last couple of years but
you know that's that you know at the end
of the day there's still millions of
people that are gonna be you know
consuming cannabis so that markets not
changing we're just looking at the stock
market and all of that the underlying
market is people and products that you
know provide a meaningful resolution to
you know health issues I mean at the end
of the day this is like a beautiful part
of mother nature and this is a gift and
so it's our obligation to share that
gift you know in our individual way
whether it's technology and you know
brands and products so yeah that's how I
see it agreed and so actually that's
when we start to take talking about how
we convey this message and how we
educate inform so a big part of that are
sort of mass communications channels and
that in the u.s. is challenging and in
some ways in Canada is even more
challenging right the restrictions on
marketing advertising I guess
I'd love to
a quick some quick input on on how that
sort of fractures the entire playbook
here the restrictions on messaging right
now in our industry relative to most
anyone can say anything in their space
we can't this is probably one of the
most negative parts of the cannabis Act
and the regulations in Canada it's just
it's a huge blow to the industry and you
know as as businesspeople were artists
we're creating you know something that
we have for the rest of the world and
then you've got this body that's saying
no no no you can't say that you know
look at this wrapping that they're
making you put on this theme it's the
worst thing in the world yet they're
making this you know these are the laws
but it's not what we would you know we
would choose if it was us making the
regulations it's because it's them
making the regulations you know an ex
police chief you know like he was the
guy that was appointed to you know head
up the you know the discovery of
regulations and you as a prohibitionist
so what else are you gonna get so it's
just you know in a decade the people
setting up on the panel you know at the
next ICBC in Vancouver in ten years
we'll be talking about the old days when
it was crazy but it's gonna get better
it's just gonna take a long time here's
what I would say about you know branding
and obviously it's it's very restrictive
in Canada on what you can you can put on
your packaging but the reality is that
the best weed that's ever been sold in
this province is coming from a clear
plastic baggie and the reality is that
product quality sells itself a I think
actually the the regs disproportionately
affect the big producers the guys that
have found a way to work around you know
celebrity endorsements and they've got
the rapper's and and and everybody else
on their label but you know it's hard to
sell schwag when you can't do the same
type of marketing that that you know big
alcohol and big tobacco and big CPG
could do so it really comes down to
what's inside that packaging and I think
we've seen some you know craft producers
small LPS that have that have done
exceptionally well over the last five
years and I think we're very excited to
see you know companies that can put out
a great flower and now soon in a few
months a great 2.0 product that that
will get consumers to gravitate but it
is going to absolutely be very difficult
to build a brand I think you're gonna
see a lot of brands actually get created
in the u.s. to get brought to Canada not
that dissimilar from other from other
from other things yep that question
brings me back to Palm Springs last week
where I just will tell you I'm so
grateful to be in this industry and you
know five years ago six years ago
whatever it was when I got into it I was
I was nervous about it I'd come out of a
really conservative spot and bottom line
is I saw the future in Palm Springs and
it it blew my mind and if you have a
chance you need to look up the knocks
doctors see it's a family of doctors
Jessica
Rachel and Janice Knox there and there's
two more doctors but the three women
were there was a women's conference
there endocannabinoids one of them was a
anesthesiologist the other one was a
Integrative Medicine they're all three
physicians there's five five Knox
physicians in this family they are
figuring out they all went back and
figured out that the endocannabinoid
system has receptors in the heart and in
the brain we all know this but we all
know that we don't know what we don't
know yet and the future of CPG the Knox
doctors are gonna bring us there because
what's gonna happen is we're gonna start
to understand oh I have infertility
problems or I have Crohn's disease or
something autoimmune and there is some
endocannabinoid reason that because we
don't have access to this research that
they're going to be able to say oh keep
your cb1 receptor needs to get this
endocannabinoid or this terpene but
you're trying to get pregnant so let's
make sure we're not doing this to you we
don't have access to that level of
research yet but it's coming and I
these women are superstars go check them
out because they are going to lead the
decisions in this nation to figure that
out and that's what's coming right now
we're talking about marketing and what
we can and can't do with marketing
I think it's information that's going to
drive consumers that's going to drive
marketing right absolutely and we're not
just talking about logos it's to be able
to compel folks to understand what's in
this product and having hands tied is
brutal it's it's unlike any other
vertical and I'll say beyond sort of
that high level messaging you know
you're also talking about being blocked
off essentially not have access to two
massive platforms social media Google
who everyone's got access to but us and
that's a massive problem for us in the
US as well so we're it's not necessarily
you know regulation or health
disclaimers we get that as well health
claims we all have people that say I
can't sleep without cannabis but we
can't make health claims about our
products but we know people are using it
for anxiety pain relief all of these
things we can't talk about it so we
can't give consumers good information
about dosing and usage and health
benefits because we can't talk about it
we can't have access to platforms so I
just want us to think bigger as an
organization well as an industry really
it comes down to giving these folks just
the opportunity to choose this sort of
natural product versus you know other
solutions that are being pumped by other
industries that's what we don't have the
right to do right now in my opinion to
the degree that we should anyway we're
talking about Canada and the US but I
think we need to look at this as a
global industry and a global set of
products that we're developing as brands
that will be used everywhere just
setting the stage but Bobby it's it's
all emanating from the US and Canada so
they're all gonna run into the same
issues when their market matures to that
level so if we execute on this and start
to solve it in the US and Canada those
solutions and will emanate out I think
when they adopt I look at it in two
right now and currently and for the
foreseeable future entrepreneurs are
going to be frustrated by regulations
and regulators in a decade many of the
regulations that are obstructing us will
be gone but the beautiful thing about it
is that and brother Marley taught us
this is that cannabis represents the
truth and that's why it's been you know
part of the Prohibition agenda to keep
you away and keep keep us away from that
which represents the truth they want to
segregate us so that we're actually not
seeing reality and seeing the truth and
so it's out and that's what's happening
now and it's saving lives it's changing
lives it's making people wealthier and
happier and getting them off that [__]
that you know big farm is pushing on us
and is protected by you know through
regulations but it's just a matter of
time the truth is out I think if we've
quoted Bob we've got to end it at that
because I think it's it's not gonna go
past that but I'll say this
it is hard it's gonna get easier but
everyone's getting their legs now you
build your company when it's hard
because it is hard and you persevere and
you get it done and that's why you're
all in this room doing it when it's hard
and you guys will get the benefit of
that we all will with that said we've
got a couple more minutes and in Gayo
right here one more time for meeting the
entire panel
all right
who's got a question question question
anyone have a question you've all been
super well informed nothing very
comprehensive all right that's fine with
me I don't care though here yes yes oh
there you are I didn't see you scooch in
scooch in make a hole oh I haven't
spoken on one of these before
my question is to Patrick so I know that
pasha Browns is very they really look at
the culture of cannabis where it's come
from the community how would you
encourage small retail business owners
that don't have ten years you know to
put money in to the business and wait
for the payoff great are you are you
opening a store I have a license and I
my mom and I owned its store in
Abbotsford okay and it's great market
right now it is okay and you're asking
I'm asked how to navigate how to
navigate it yeah I mean because you're
saying the payoff is gonna say ten years
it's it's miserable yeah yeah better
actually no I'll be honest retail is
going about retail is gonna be miserable
tilray just paid seventy million dollars
like last week or the week before for
twenty locations in alberta because um
Brennan is a very smart guy and he's not
waiting for it he's going after a market
that exists today you know I
are you still are your doors open still
are key you're great we're closed I'm
not even just asking for myself I'm
asking for the community of small
business owners the the business
community that's represented the gray
market they're survivors they're smarter
than you know the the regulated group
because they've been having to dodge and
weave for you know all this time and
they'll keep fighting yeah
don't like I mean I say my t-shirt stay
gray and keep the lights on and wait you
know wait let Health Canada and
regulators prove to you that they're
actually doing what they're supposed to
which is opening stores and letting
people grow and you know just like you
know go toe to toe we I mean all the
change that's occurred in Canada is Kirk
and John you know and the lawyers and
Rob Lori's here as well like you know
these are the people that have really
made the effective changes but it's been
the community funding it you know and
and keeping it all alive that's why
we're in the position we're in right now
it's not because Harper and and Trudeau
actually care see you you guys you guys
are in a place where it's essentially
it's what California has done and it's a
massive regulated market now but it
started you know you guys call it a gray
market we didn't really have a name for
it it was just what it was
since you know 1996 when prop 215 came
out the medical market and a lot of
those survivors are now running some of
the biggest compliant operators in the
state so hang in there thanks for a
great panel I just wanted to ask all of
you as you're considering brands that
you're looking for one of the strangest
parts of the shifting sands of Canadian
commerce right now is the fact that the
whole medical industry seems to have
been swept under the rug or normally
forgotten so I'm wondering in the u.s.
especially where you have more states
that are medical and recreational how
many of you are looking for brands that
have medical orientation versus
recreational I think that
as states have in the US have opened up
either regulated or fully legal that the
recreational market is is both medical
and recreational so if I'm buying a
medical product and I'm in a legal state
that sells recreational just by my
product that way I believe and and I
think that we haven't we don't have the
same differential in medical and fully
legal that we had a couple of years ago
and so I think it's involved what I'm
saying is I believe it's an evolving
story and that yeah I don't think my
medical brand in Canada if it's emerging
as valuable in the United States you
know it's gonna be legal federally so I
do believe we need medical products as
we were talking about so that that's a
great point yes we need medical products
we need to solve ailments and diseases
and it's our responsibility as an
industry to take this female plant and
find that research and do it and
struggle with it and bring it to market
however the overarching idea there is I
think exactly what patrick said in my
opinion there is now a it's blurred as
far as do you want it medical or do you
want it or someone looking for you know
medical sort of driven products or or is
it is it recreational we're in
California it's far and away the biggest
the biggest market we don't look at it
that's not a question for us medical
from banks there's only one market yeah
from banks perspective I don't know the
statistic I'm sure somebody out there
can shout it out but there's a statistic
that says some large percentage of
recreational users are using cannabis
for medical reasons so you don't need
the brand I think to Bobbi's point to be
medically oriented because the consumers
deciding what they're using it for
whether they're using it recreationally
to get high with their friends or
they're using it to sleep or they're
using it for pain relief I think the
brand has to be compelling and
has to be safe and it has to provide a
service that people are looking for but
if you orient it medically I think
you're leaving a lot on the table I
wouldn't bet I wouldn't recommend it MJ
biz and new frontier data did a study
and they came out with a report called
arc types
it's very available I don't know what
what the cost is these days but it's not
a lot but it's a very valuable report
because its segments older users and
different types it's a study that I have
never seen before the industry was
astonished and I think you should all
take a look at it because what we're
seeing is we're seeing many many many
different niches in the buying public
and those niches will become forces as
we do our research and deliver more
products to market I believe thank you
so very much I hate to cut everybody off
a we're way over time one more time
super great