thank you for making it here this
beautiful morning where we brought
Portland Oregon's weather with us our
first speaker is going to talk about
some high-stakes cannabis investment
opportunities around the world the
United States Air Force taught the man
several languages he's brought his drive
energy thirst for knowledge to the
cannabis space over 15 years experience
in the cannabis commercial field
he helps cannabis businesses investors
from all over the world if you're
serious about investing in cannabis and
you want to work with somebody who's in
the business for the right reasons and
is in it for the plant and will give you
straight advice this is the man the CEO
3c please give a warm welcome for mr.
Nick Easley guten morgen we gates tear
it gets good so I was hoping they'd have
a little something stronger up here for
me this morning really appreciate
everyone's time to come from the United
States to come and share some of this
information it's kind of a kind of
paramount the European Union has so many
opportunities right now that are barely
beginning and with half a billion person
population without a legitimate bona
fide program yet you have so much room
to grow thank you I just uh just
prepared this this morning yesterday was
really impressive I was going through
cards last night I talked to people from
17 countries last night like a normal
conference it's like oh this state this
is going on but to see how many people
have come together for this industry is
really really impressive
so hopefully this works out that's me
Niki's I'm originally a farm kid from
Wisconsin was in FFA and did agriculture
right out of the high school essentially
the military recruited me to be a
linguist so I speak a few languages
unfortunately not German
Spanish a few indigenous languages and
was in the service for about four years
and got hurt and was 22 didn't really
know what to do I had a biology degree
and flipped a coin and decided to go to
Colorado for a ski season that was right
after medical
started and Colorado s you know is kind
of like the Amsterdam of the United
States and actually kind of the world
because even Amsterdam's original
program was nothing like what happened
in Colorado so over the years from going
from you know farming the Midwest to
military to Colorado right at that
perfect moment I've been able to see how
the industry has really grown so from
small medical producers that could grow
their own cannabis where there were no
dispensaries no commercial cultivation
and then Colorado we were the first
state that ever really had to grow up as
an industry and licenses for cultivation
and manufacturing and distribution and
then you had to have a grow license in
order to have a dispensary and then 2016
or 2012 happened in Colorado where
essentially proposition 64 was regulate
marijuana like alcohol and we were the
first state to legalize I don't like the
word but recreational marijuana adult
use responsible use marijuana and we did
it by regulating like like alcohol
last year in Colorado we did one point
six billion dollars in sales and that's
just direct cannabis sales that wasn't
all the ancillary products and services
surrounding that since that time we now
have Alaska Washington Oregon California
Nevada Colorado and soon to be
Massachusetts states that anyone who's
21 or older can go and buy cannabis
flower vaporizers suppositories infused
adult lubricant products edibles you
name it so when you think about that
potentiality coming from medical and
even knowing this is a very very sacred
medicinal plant and there is the
business component with this we're
seeing time and time again so many
companies that are starting and have
these visions of making all this money
in helping the patients but they don't
have business acumen and they don't put
together their companies correctly or
they don't understand taxes they don't
understand regulations they might know
how to grow the plant or make a really
good hash or how to have a good
dispensary for retail but they don't
know business and never having worked
now with almost 200 different clients
around the world we've seen time and
time again what are the tell-tale signs
of a good company or
bad company so just just to kind of
mention here I'm not a lawyer I'm not a
CPA I'm a biologist a farmer and
actually now a venture fund manager I
manage three venture funds as well so
I'm not giving legal advice
I'm not giving tax advice this is purely
business guidance here to help your
businesses be it here internationally or
in the States to start to grow it's
really hard because we always consider
there's like the US market and then
everyone else but I for years been
considering this to be a global Empire
that we're building and even in the
United States you have to think about
each state as an individual country I
can't grow tomatoes in Oregon and bring
them to Washington even though they're
legal in Oregon and they're legal in
Washington I can't cross that line here
like having health care cover cannabis
you know having like the first federal
legal program of Canada where they're
going to have adult use this summer
incredible but then when people got all
excited were gonna have all these
dispensaries around Canada no one
remembered this little thing called the
LCBO it's the largest liquor store in
the world and it's owned by the Canadian
government and the Canadian government
really they made some interesting
policies to where most of the provinces
they're going to be running the cannabis
dispensaries so a lot of Canadian
companies in LPs thought hey we're going
to do all these dispensaries but then a
lot of the places they wanted to they
cannot so those rules and regulations
are some of the things that we're gonna
mention here today
also since I do raise copious amounts of
capital I just have to this is not
general solicitation I'm not in the
United States so I don't actually have
to say this
we're always raising money but this is
not like I'm not offering securities
here but if you send me an email and we
talk for about 30 days then we can
definitely offer securities like I said
in this industry my only problem from
going from years ago of like do I have
enough rain water for my tomato crops or
do I have enough like alfalfa for my
goats now it's like do I have enough
millions and millions and millions of
dollars to invest into the right
companies that are scaling taking market
share that are gonna have significant
exits and returns the worst thing in my
life is when I see great portfolio
companies and cannot raise quickly
enough to satiate those requirements and
there are great companies out there in
the you know
States and internationally and there's
the ability for international investors
to invest into the United States and the
United States investors to also invest
globally not just through the Canadian
public market which we're going to
discuss so you know this is I I always
want to start with like what not to do
this industry has countless examples of
what not to do not paying your taxes not
following safety standards using really
bad pesticides and having recalls and
violations over and over and over again
I mean our industry came from the gutter
literally like we were in an illicit
market and people god bless them the
caregivers who would cultivate this
plant illegally and get it to patients
who needed it for profit or not but like
those people they care took this plant
and brought it forward for us to be able
to use for business now but now it's the
purpose of using business to make this
plant better more affordable more
sustainably produced safer and to create
sustainable jobs in tax revenue where
you think of essentially the cannabis
industry what we've seen in the United
States in those six adult use markets so
far is that alcohol sales have gone down
13.7 percent and it's like well as
marijuana better than alcohol it's like
well a lot of people have fixed incomes
and like only so much money for fun
money a month so if you have like let's
say make two thousand euros a month and
you have five hundred extra euros a
month for like fun for beer for parties
well once cannabis is legal and you can
buy joints and you can buy vaporizers
your limited amount of capital you're
gonna be buying less alcohol that we've
seen also like opiate use like one of
the worst like more people died like in
the united states of opiate deaths than
like all of Vietnam casualties combined
annually so like opiates like
pharmaceutical narcotics like very very
addictive in some states in order to
actually have like medicinal cannabis
like you can't have opiates in your
system or vice versa if you actually
have cannabis in your system like you
can't actually get your pain medication
so they're almost forcing people to use
these opiates I mean it's an endemic
that no one really talks about but we're
seeing that opiate deaths are going down
almost 10% in states that have legal
amount
programs and that's 31 states last time
I counted I think the United States has
50 states
you know plus/minus but yeah like 50
states 31 is over 25
so that means half of the states at
least have a medical marijuana program 6
have adult use 7 with Massachusetts
coming and then 8 with Maine coming
Washington DC is also legal like legal
for adult use but since there's this
little thing called the Harris amendment
in the United States capitols right
there they wouldn't pay for like the
roads and schools essentially if they
opened up adult use stores this year
there's gonna be three more states on
ballot initiatives that are going to
have adult use cannabis soon to be 20%
of the United States 21 or older you can
buy cannabis I own companies and in
parts of companies that we now in like
Las Vegas have 24 7 dispensaries like I
was at one at 3:17 in the morning and
there were still like 25 people waiting
to get in so cannabis is an amazing
plant but if you don't do the business
right you don't have the right capital
you cannot scale and grow and that's
really one of the things I'm going to
mention here where you can see like down
the line it's an investor like what what
are market sectors doing what are the
companies that are scaling which ones
are really taking market position where
is a new market and based on their
population density disposable income
like locations or for a medical
marijuana program very very important
you must know what the qualifying
conditions are in a medical marijuana
state or country so for an example if
they don't have pain or PTSD as
qualifying conditions in the United
States that's almost 92 percent of all
medical cards that we've seen so that
means if a state only allows like
glaucoma a mask cancer aids like I'm
gonna have 8 percent of the potential
clients and clients well patients but
then my patients are my clients my
clients are my revenue my revenue is my
business and my business serves patients
and clients so if I can only have 8
percent of that or in some states like
0.2 percent of that population like in
Minnesota only a few conditions
New York Florida it's not going to be a
robust market and it's an investor I
found I cannot invest into medical
marijuana program
unless I have enough qualifying
conditions that'll support the business
unless I know long-term the legislations
going to change but what I've also found
for all of you in this room if you're in
this business you're an advocate you're
not just in business this isn't just an
opportunity you have a massive
responsibility like for this plant for
the plant that like past generations
like brought forward for us for tens of
thousands of years breeding like hemp
humph like that's like the the Great
Dane of the dog world and then like
poodles you know like little itty-bitty
dogs that's like the cannabis we bred
them for certain reasons just like
apples or tomatoes like what would
happen if you took a bulldog and a shih
tzu and like made a baby get some
right and that's where like if
you took a hemp plant and like a really
good cannabis plant that this one's way
low THC this one's way high THC you're
gonna get something in the middle and
then it's no longer legally hemp and the
diversification of the genetics pool
like Gregor Mendel stuff like back here
the genetics are so important like if
you want to have a kid who's Michael
Jordan but they're like four feet tall
you can buy him the best shoes you can
put them in the best basketball camps
but they're never gonna be Michael
Jordan you make the best business you
have the best team the best market but
you have bad genetics equally they're
not going to be Michael Jordan so I've
really like to look at like what of
other companies done they've been
failures and it's an investor maybe 20%
of the time I'm interested in past
companies because past companies in the
US probably didn't structure correctly
have all these past liabilities when you
buy a company you buy all the baggage
like the assets all the past problems
all the past lawsuits those then come
and transfer to you so something we're
gonna mention that's so important like
from the adult world is called like I
call it DD but like due diligence and
how do you do diligence on a market that
barely has any data like I own one of
the data companies based out of the
United States it's like Platts
mcgraw-hill what's the price of corn
today what's it gonna be tomorrow how
much does it cost to grill corn what's
the cost is gonna be and like what we've
seen with cannabis in these states that
allow multiple licenses not just like
Germany's original 10 or Arkansas's 5
when you can have Oregon Washington
California Colorado Michigan these
states that have
five hundred a thousand cultivation
licenses there's lots of competition and
competition is good in business but also
competition if you're on the down side
of it it will crush you and if it's
costing you $800 a pound to produce
indoors and like a ten thousand square
foot facility and I have a four acre
greenhouse producing cannabis for less
than $100 a pound all in compliantly
that's higher-quality
we can't call it organic in the United
States because that's a federal term
that's federally illegal so we have to
be a little careful there and it's this
moment that when you have the
opportunity to come in and make a new
company and do everything right good
lawyers good consulting good capital
like you have a strong shot there but
you have to insulate yourself from that
downside so not sure if you guys are
going to know this one but if you do you
can call it out anyone familiar with
lake kenny loggins like Top Gun highway
to the dangerzone it's kind of like my
analogy for this industry it's like this
is a danger zone and there are
patients suffering and there are
horrible things happening and a lot of
the products that people are buying and
selling like are very very dangerous
it's not the cannabis that's dangerous
it's the pesticides they're spraying on
it it's the 22 pounds of coal per gram
of cannabis indoors that it takes of
electricity to produce one gram like
every single light a thousand watt light
bulb if it takes you know the US
Department of Energy says about 2.2
pounds of coal per hour to make one
kilowatt of electricity so every
thousand watt light five feet by five
feet is 2 pounds of coal an hour 12
hours a day for the photo period you're
like wow that's like almost 30 pounds of
coal a day for one light for like one
plant for plants 12 plants depending on
how big they are and the environmental
part is so huge on this but from a
business standpoint that's huge capital
expenditures your operational
expenditures are higher so something
that's really unique about this industry
that this is the first time in the
history of business that doing the right
thing like environmentally producing in
greenhouses when you can not just doing
hydroponic with salt based derivatives
or bad pesticides because you designed
your growing properly like you actually
make more money like when you pay your
workers well you design your facilities
well you invest in you take the capital
you need so this danger zone like in the
United States it's federally illegal
like what I do is federally illegal but
state-by-state like we have this thing
called states rights each state can kind
of make their own laws and a lot of the
the states in the United States have
gone like this to the federal government
and for patients initially every single
marketplace in the United States started
as medical and then the six have seven
soon-to-be eight have transitioned them
to adult use and still have medical and
medical has like low taxes just normal
sales tax but then adult use has all of
these excise taxes sometimes almost 40%
like 11% for the state 20% for the city
in the town all the little donations all
of a sudden at the end of the day adult
use you go to buy a joint you're like
eighteen fifty or like twenty seven
dollars but then a medical joint might
be five dollars and each states a little
different so this danger zone that we're
gonna talk about you know kenny loggins
you know watch Top Gun I think you'll
get the references there so you know in
the United States we've got like Jeff
Sessions are angry little like troll or
like Keebler Elf they column like we
used to have this thing called the Kol
memorandum that said if states follow
eight specific rules they can
essentially have a medical marijuana
program we also have this omnibus last
year they brought Dana here from
California one of our great Senator
Representatives and he and Earl another
one from Oregon which thinks Oregon
people they have a bill that prevents
the federal government from spending
federal funds to prosecute state medical
marijuana programs I as an investor or
an operator I don't have a single
sentence of protection for recreational
marijuana and recreational marijuana
will be legal here in Germany someday
I'd give it five to eleven twelve years
like it's not a matter of like if this
is gonna happen it's a matter of when I
mean it's more and more medical research
efficacy and something that's really
unique to government's is tax revenue
and like my expression here and if
you're in the gubernatorial space I
regards but like tax revenue is heroin
to a government and like people that get
hooked on opiates or like heroin they
will steal their mommas TV and pawn it
to buy more drugs the same thing with
the government
we'll do anything they can to protect
their tax revenue because that's their
lifeblood and in Colorado we've of that
1.6 billion dollars last year we did
half a billion with a B in new tax
revenue in Colorado for new jobs hands
on jobs we have about sixty eight
thousand badge like licensed employees
to touch the plant but then you think
about all the plumbers electricians
carpenters lawyers consultants marketers
branders on and on and on velocity of
capital $1 in cannabis spent is 7.1
dollars of additional capital created
the highest velocity s you know
capitalists we've actually ever seen and
tracked and right now like trying to
navigate this space in order to get a
license every single place you have to
have real estate and that real estate
typically can't be too close to churches
schools parks daycares addiction centers
all these weird requirements and it has
to be zoned correctly it can't be
commercial maybe it has to be industrial
maybe they say it has to be in this
little business part compared to that so
if you don't have real estate you don't
have I say that to make everyone
understand that real estate is half of
this game I pay off real estate in about
three years you guys normally pay off
real estate you get a mortgage mortgage
the definition is until death like when
you can pay off real estate in three
years
something's happening correctly so when
you're finding your real estate and
choosing that space like that's the
place you're gonna plant your Lance
license flag and be able to actually
apply but these license applications be
it in Germany be it in Denmark be in
Jamaica be in LPS and Canada be it in
the States they're all different and
have very specific requirements
sometimes are challenging sometimes are
complex convoluted sometimes there's a
lot of corruption sometimes the
government will rescind and take back
all the licenses seem that now in two
states three countries so a lot of the
new states and governments are getting a
little bit more cautious realizing
there's this little thing called
lawsuits and litigation like back in the
day was like now litigation skyrocketing
so you have to insulate and protect
yourself from that downside and that's
why I say find good lawyers to structure
your contracts structure your deals and
follow their guidance most of the time
sometimes they're a little too
willy-nilly and like oh don't take risks
you gotta take risks if you don't take
risks
you're not living and navigating this
space anything outside of like having
the right amount of money having your
right application having the right real
estate that's this one little place
that's not the danger zone but it's
still the danger zone because it's a
controlled substance in a country like
Germany or Denmark or Canada when it's
federally legal the danger zones not
it's bad but in the United States it is
that's why we've learned that real
estate is not growing cannabis or
manufacturing extracting it's not
dispensaries real estate is separate the
building separate the lights the
fertigation the tables the trays the TVs
in the dispensary the counters that's
not growing selling marijuana
so like you'll have a property
management company that buys all of
those hard assets and insulates them in
a company in the United States good or
bad we have this little thing from the
Supreme Court called citizens united it
pretty much means that like a gmbh or an
LLC or an ApS a company is kind of like
a person and people in the united states
have like these things like these
unalienable rights like freedom of
speech that's why like companies can
make massive donations to political
campaigns as an individual but it's also
like able to like insulate different
people doing different things so you
have one person one entity one company
that owns the the real estate owns the
lights does all the build up the
electricity everything other than soil
nutrients the paper for receipts in a
dispensary count like everything other
than the cannabis itself are directly
used to cultivate manufacture or sell it
is then leased to the company the LLC
that actually has the license so if that
company has a problem that can't seize
my assets and then I charge very high
lease payments very high rent and suck a
lot of capital out of that company
making tons of money into a company
that's not subject to the same taxes
legally and your corporate veil is
critical here find good lawyers to do
this good accountants but when you do
this you realize that 70% of the money
you need is an operator isn't even
cannabis money but then in our world
banks institutional capital will not
make those investments so knowing these
structures even in Germany even in any
country you have to know how to like
you've got to know the rules to play the
game so if you're going to get into this
space and you want to get into Germany
you want to get into Colombia you want
get into India what are the rules
governing the place where does their
current policy laws and ordinances and
how long is it gonna take for some of
those things to change and if you have a
significant business interest there or
would like to how do you take this
little thing called like a lever out and
actually apply force and leverage to
actually make that program legal so if
you are a business owner remember I said
this isn't like not just opportunity its
responsibility all of the nonprofit
organizations in the United States drug
policy Alliance Marijuana Policy Project
Americans for safe access great
nonprofits that helped to get medical
marijuana legalized you have to support
them you have to donate because the
reason that you're here today is
actually because those groups did their
job and got more and more legal more and
more businesses so got to stay out of
the danger zone
poor guy the other day had a little
problem in the states if you know who
this is you know I'm talking about
there's this funny show called Silicon
Valley on HBO and it's like about
startup companies and like soon-to-be
Facebook's and things like that and
there's this character and he has this
little incubator and we always say we're
looking for the Unicorn like investment
this magical mythical thing that like no
one's seen the Facebook like as
multiverse capital or Sequoia Capital I
try to find unicorns and I want to find
them before like I want to find a baby
unicorn in the forest and no one's found
yet and feed that Unicorn the best food
and like make it the best unicorn in the
world because out of all the companies
if you have something that's like no one
cares about a million dollars but like
you do start to care when it gets to a
billion or beyond that when you look at
Zuckerberg like last week all that's
happening thirty-three-year-old just
sitting in front of like Senate House
committees defending something that's
pretty much every single one of them use
their grandkids use like when you start
a company you're thinking about exit and
if you don't know about exit strategy
you don't need to have a company it's
not just I'm gonna start a company and
do this for years that sucks like it
gets hard you need more money there's
all these pressures and problems how are
you gonna sell your company how are you
gonna get more investment into the
company you don't want to be cleaning
the toilets every single day I mean I
cleaned some toilets in an office in
Colorado last week I was like I came in
there's a meeting there's a dirty toilet
it's a CEO sometimes you do that but you
don't want to do that forever and
hopefully you hire good people and scale
and
eventually sell your business or your
business goes public or you do an M&amp;A
like a merger and acquisition which even
earlier we were mentioning how mergers
and acquisitions are kind of like MMA
like mixed martial arts fighting like
those cage fighting like when you do and
merge your acquisitions like that but
we're always looking for the Unicorn but
the problem in that everyone thinks
they're a unicorn and the realistic
truth is 99% of them are not actually
99.9% of them or not so if you make an
investment into a company as an investor
this is where we're a little different
that company has a 99% chance of failing
even if it's your company I mean today
or this month I had four companies that
turn one turn five a couple more turn
four a couple more turn three it's
always fun when you get past that five
year mark or a three-year mark or you
have a significant investment come in
but it's not just like money's flying
like in order to be a unicorn it takes
the structuring unique competitive
advantage in order to do that so the
things I look at when I'm creating a
company or evaluating like an investment
opportunity anything from you know
twenty thousand dollars to twenty five
million dollars is the space that we've
worked in for size and investments I'm
always thinking like what's the market
risk like what happens if the state or
the country takes away the licenses or
the market changes and we can't make
certain products what's the product risk
if you're making vaporizers and you use
glycol or flavor additives or it has
pesticides and it gets a recall the
brand damage will crush you so it's like
what are the risks associated with this
product like cannabis drug driving like
there's all these things in Colorado
there was a really unfortunate case of
like a college student committed suicide
he had eaten a lot of edibles and back
in the day in Colorado you could sell
like a thousand milligrams chokolate bar
like of THC there's a lot like
California like all these huge things
these Kiva bars that are just enormous
and people when it's the first time
trying a product it's our responsibility
to provide them a quality experience
because I'm not selling products I'm
selling the experience that those
products are going to induce in my
clients and that that experience needs
to be enjoyable from the moment they see
my logo walk into a store like how
they're treated in the store how they
see our website like that experience
from how the product is how they feel
the next day
that's why you have a responsibility to
your patients to your clients to create
high quality products and not have risk
and the last one is team risk at the end
of the day you can have the best
financials in the world the best
intellectual property patents on all
this cool stuff then the damn giving my
money to you and that's why I like
investors at the end of the day they're
giving their money to us by doing due
diligence to then invest into the
companies that we know that we're giving
it to the people and if your team is not
strong if you're an individual and you
have an idea you're not investable
because it's not protected you got a
couple people if you have a great idea
like you need a like to bring in like a
CFO financial person and an operational
person good legal good people actually
execute on that vision so I always
analyze teams so if you're in this how
do you actually become gravity and bring
other people towards you if you're a
good cannabis grower like you know that
idea like master grower doesn't mean
master business person like if you're
great at growing cannabis but you don't
know business you'd better find some
business help is like master grower
master up every single business
that's been cultivation that has had
horrible failures or run by a master
grower and God bless him but they didn't
maybe go to Wharton they didn't go to
Stanford they didn't have business
classes they don't understand LLC's
deductions depreciation and if you're
not using banks which there are banks in
the US that Bank for us you have so much
risk and liability so how do you get
good people as part of your team is
something that's always really critical
to understand you know so from a Esiason
in like I wanted to talk a little bit
today about like anti anti fragile so
when I'm looking at investments or
market something that's a little
different that I want you to think about
is fragility like you know a nice and
then like if I were to take my phone and
pour water on it it's gonna break it's
fragile it's done now if it's robust if
it's strong enough like I could pour
water on it nothing's gonna happen but
if it's anti fragile if I hit this with
a hammer and throw it down the stairs it
gets stronger and better every single
time so in the market like I deal with a
lot with public companies and private
companies and looking at like what Wall
Street traders did back in the day or
now even shorting companies knowing
there's a bad company we we do market
regulation through and
if there's a bad company we can short
stocks like borrow stocks short their
stocks if we know something's gonna go
bad it crushes those but if you bet
wrong like you'll actually get crushed
and destroyed so like be very careful if
you play in that space like I've had
great days but then there's some days
you're like I wish I didn't wake up this
morning but then the next day if the
news comes out then it's good again but
you got to be able to maintain that
pressure so you want to find a place to
where it's like you're anti fragile if
the market changes it doesn't crush you
it makes you stronger or you have
options against some of your hedge bets
so like I said 99% of companies fail and
biologically like Leo Wilson he said
like 99.9% of all species that have ever
lived are extinct and like we're kind of
here in this like present moment like
the dinosaurs other than like when big
meteor had about 70 million years ago
like we got a few dinosaurs left like
birds and a few of those but most of
them just died off and then here like
mammals all these things have evolved
the same thing with companies if a
massive thing happens how do you know
that you're not gonna be affected if you
have an investment into one company and
there's trouble you're done so that's
why like I invest into portfolio
companies lots and lots of companies
that pass our due diligence and I spread
that out amongst them so I diversify
risk but you have to do due diligence on
each and every investment opportunity or
opportunity is at the end of the day the
worst thing that you can lose is
opportunity costs like you got one time
one life and thank you for like giving
me about 30-40 minutes to like share
some of my things with you with your
life so you can do better but like you
don't want to waste your time time is
the only thing like we have and it's
like the present like a gift Christmas
like it's the present moments all we got
so how are you gonna use it and this
industry is like once in a lifetime the
dot-com boom that happened is very
similar Canadian companies with
valuations of 150 to 250 X revenue is
ridiculous
but like you look at certain things
there's good things too you go public
you have a press release you make a
hundred million dollars in a day I would
love a day I can just raise a hundred
million dollars as a private fund but
like there are advantages to being
public but there's downside too so you
have to be very very insulated from risk
if you are going to have some of those
opportunities you know you can see it's
like on certain curves like when things
are going up it's great when they're
going down like that
what crushes companies how do you
insulate from risk so that if there is a
bad day it doesn't crush you or like
your other companies do well or if it's
bad for this company it's actually good
for your other companies so why I like
Ninh is like he was an investment banker
and like stock trader for years and
years and he went into philosophy and
then started to realize the philosophy
of investing and it really one of his
best messages it's like on being anti
fragile like be anti fragile or die and
if you're just one company you have to
insulate yourself from all those risks
from like your team quitting on you from
your product like getting recalls or
like causing problems or not having
enough you know capital or the market
changing that's why you don't go into
all markets but if it's good why not go
into a few markets at the same time
because then if one fails you're still
good that's why we diversified out of
the United States four years ago because
it's like well if the whole federal
government goes bad I have to provide
liquidity to my investors so we need to
have more diverse markets and there's
more diverse opportunities and this
plant needs to be legal everywhere it's
just at the end of the day this is a
very sacred medicinal plant I was home
schooled by a botanist for a couple
years in middle school and did a lot of
like field sampling and it's just such a
special plant and it's not ours like
we're holding it for future generations
and the businesses we're creating the
day will be like the Pepsi's and the
coca cola's of the world but not
everyone's gonna get to be that but
everyone thinks they're going to be so
you really and I put all the puppies in
here just cuz some of some of my talks
at downer so I just wanted to keep
everybody like happy like with pictures
of puppies sorry you know you've seen
Shark Tank you've seen some of these
things there's all these little
companies just getting crushed I mean
every day I mean probably a week I'm
going through probably 20 to 30
investments a week and maybe two to
three of those move over to a pile that
I might look and then push to my
investment committee there are so many
opportunities but it's easy to see when
you've had the experience with hundreds
of companies and markets what's good and
what's not and at the end of the day it
all comes down to the team because even
if the markets crap a good team can
change a market I've seen it time and
time again but you have to scale like
what's that accent how are you gonna
plan this how are you gonna get
liquidity for your investors how are you
gonna make money yourself because at the
end of the day it's not just about the
money but like the money's nice but you
gotta use the money to build the
business
constantly like on this one just like
the Indian philosophy of like keep every
dollar in your company for a thousand
days you must keep doing that keep
reinvesting reinvesting this is not
going to slow down or stop anytime soon
so if you want big impact you want big
profits don't suck
number one rule like pretty much and the
number one rule with me and my investors
is like don't lose investors money
number two C rule number one like that's
the number one thing you have to focus
on you do not want to like piss off
investors because they actually have
backing and will come after you write
good operating agreements like write
good contracts very very important when
you think about a little plant and like
just you know seeing the denmark world
it's like you see a little plant and
then now it's turning into
pharmaceutical products like everything
that we know in the united states that's
medical and recreational will merge into
one thing someday and then there's this
other thing that's called like pharmacy
like big pharma like IP like specific
titration medical research like body
mass index to where this product does
this almost every single time the value
in those like i've diversified into a
lot of investments on that side there's
gonna be more and more and more of that
but eventually in the US cannabis will
probably be under like the atf Alcohol
Tobacco Firearms cannabis all the fun
things you know so I'm a surfer actually
like skipped a meeting right before my
flight to go surfing because there's
some good swell in Malibu I live really
close to there and you know this is a
place called rink cone and you see all
those little dots it's this amazing
Point Break and when a waves coming in
it's just like everyone's trying to get
into the market everyone wants to catch
that really amazing
once-in-a-lifetime wave but you can't
catch it here on the right you can't
catch it on the left there's ten other
guys paddling for it how do you know
where to position yourself for when to
catch it how to paddle and then when to
pop up I use that analogy of like in
investing there's lots of waves and some
of them suck like you can see it
sometimes right that's just gonna be
like a closeout and just crash other
times it's really big here and you're
like if I catch it right there I can
ride it all the way to the right but all
waves - you gotta know when to exit and
get off the wave like one of my favorite
little Topanga point like you ride a
wave too early gets so shallow and then
you like fall and like break yourself so
it's like you got to know when to exit
the wave - and like s risk you can't
just get knocked out with like a
surfboard those fins the Blake it's
dangerous so like how do you catch a
wave how do you choose a company how do
you choose an investment and it comes
from like sitting on your board and like
watching out there or like us with our
data companies and analysts I've got
homies up on the shore with like
magnifying glasses like looking out in
the ocean like hey there's a good wave
coming in like 30 seconds everyone else
sees the little ones close to them and
they like go for those I'm just sitting
there waiting I'm not wasting my time on
these crap little waves like I'm waiting
for those good ones but I like to like
catch a good one exit and more and more
and then with more and more investors we
catch more and more waves and then it's
good for everybody
you know from Colorado that's where I
got into this industry I love
backcountry like snow snowboarding I
didn't obviously being a CEO now I don't
have as much time but it used to take me
sometimes five hours to skin and climb
up a whole mountain and I'm not talking
like a ski resort with like the chairs
like I was a backcountry instructor
avalanche instructor mountain guide and
it would take clients out but then for
myself like we would climb these
mountains and then just like the fresh
powder turns ARF I mean it's like better
than sex drugs and rock and roll
combined like better than surfing even
because it's like you're riding a whole
mountain and you know Louie dog and I
it's like when you get those first
tracks those good investments it's great
but you got to go out if it's really
dangerous avalanche conditions I don't
go out like I know I die and if you're a
company you also know you're gonna die
so it's like one of the days that are
good do your research do your homework
do your due diligence find good people
look at all of the other failures that
everyone's doing and realize like what
not to do like and always be crushing
it's not about closing it's about
crushing like every single day this is a
once-in-a-lifetime opportunity and I've
done this you know almost lay out 13 14
years now I'm not stopping like it's not
about like do this for a few more years
and then like retire or like you know go
get a job selling cars or something like
this is it and if you're in here and
like you're not 90 and you're not like
eighteen or two like this is the only
thing we're doing and if you're in this
room I think you realize that and it's
not about if you grow cannabis or know
anything about that what did you do in
your past business life are you a
pharmacist are you a doctor are you an
investor are you a marketer how do you
take those past industry skills and like
leverage it to cannabis because cannabis
needs marketing cannabis needs real
estate can
this needs all of those things
compliance directives I had a guy five
years ago in Colorado he he ran a trash
company was a friend of mine he's like
Nick how do I get into this and like I
have all these producers that have all
of this like plant material they have to
shred it with plant shredders and kitty
litter and soil and make it
unrecognizable before they put it in the
garbage a lot dumpster like maybe come
up with a company where you have these
little bins and like pick them up and
like you do all the shredding and just
take away the risk and then you don't
have rotting plant material sitting
around
I mean he's now doing like four or five
million dollars a year doing garbage for
the cannabis industry and just shredding
their plants and now he's thinking about
scaling that and licensing that to other
states like there's an idea for
everything in the space but you have to
be like know how to execute on those
because like everyone wants to jump into
this but like you got to look before you
jump in I see tons of companies they're
just like we're gonna do this and go for
a license and like we're gonna start a
new dispensary in downtown Colorado in
Denver but there were tons of them
they're like this isn't you don't get a
5,000 square-foot grill in Colorado
anymore or Oregon anymore or California
anymore it's like you have to know what
timing in which market just like which
mountain to climb which wave to catch
which company to start and which ones
just to like realize or more of a risk
and a liability than an actual asset and
like we all want to jump and have fun
together and you always have that one
friend or that one company that sucks
and like you like laugh and giggle at
them but like we're all in this together
and it's such a big market it's not like
I hate other investors I hate other
consulting companies I hate other data
companies I a lot of my competitors I
actually buy their data like we're all
in this together and then sometimes a
position for me is like too big I can't
do it all it's like who else am I gonna
go to like piggyback and work together
on projects so it's collaboration like
whenever you look at a society that had
collaboration versus competition they
last 3 times longer same thing actually
with matrilineal societies female
societies you never have to question who
the mother of a child is right makes a
lot more sense if you keep the mother's
name
they also last three times longer
because they have intergenerational
connectivity like they're thinking about
things differently like some cultures
the men got to choose if they got to go
to war but the women got to choose if
they got to bring weapons a little off
topic there but diversify very important
so yeah I've gotten 26 states so far 11
countries where I've been active
of still active and like I said I talked
to 17 countries yesterday and some of
them it's like I already know your laws
in programming it's horrible others it's
like there's not even conversation
others it's like oh you're one of those
for license holders in that country
let's talk here's my card like what
stage of this are you in because we
design we do every step of this process
and good teams like you got to find
those good lawyers those good investors
those good consultants to help you with
your part of the piece and like if
there's great partnership potential look
for it but like build a company for
yourself initially and learn from
markets like each individual market like
when you see like all the different dots
where you know this isn't like within
the last year I've been to every one of
those those dots there I've got a couple
offices in the States we don't talk
about the states there's too many dots
it's happening like it's not like is
this gonna happen no it already happened
it actually you've kind of missed the
boat on a few markets already but there
are more and more markets the United
States is small in population compared
to the rest of the world and there's so
many opportunities so yeah that's right
Oh perfect well timing well part I I
didn't even they gave me a laser to I
was excited about it to use it but I
never did you cannot you can amuse a cat
later
well again I really appreciate the time
to share I know some of this is
challenging to hear but like when you
fight the truth alleles and this all
comes from real-world experience so I'm
not sure if anytime or not but we'll be
around all day wish you all the best of
luck and success and remember do this
for the patients but do it with the
business because then you can help more
patients thank you Nick easily everybody
mix easly fantastic always be crushing
you