to discuss novel food in the EU we've ex
uh We've assembled an expert panel and
to moderate that panel for us the
director of regular regulatory Solutions
at Laurence Stevens please welcome
Ricardo
Jala you want a
water please take your conversations
outside close the
door please
so um morning everyone I just wait until
last people to leave the room as they
carry on their conversations about
cultivation in C in Germany which I'm
sure from sitting on that so early days
even though uh the law has just changed
I think probably licensing is only 24
months away from really actually seeing
someone grow something in Germany but
Peter's in the audience maybe he can
advise you on that uh when it comes to
Germany but yeah look thanks for joining
us today this morning we're going to
talk about novel Foods um it's still
very much novel when it comes to CBD in
the UK uh and in Europe and Canada but
I'm I'm pleased to introduce uh CA schur
a lawyer and um investor with many years
of experience in farma and biotech and
been in the Cannabis industry since 2016
if I'm not mistaken and founded the
European medical cannabis ass
Association in Brussels in 2019 which
I'm sure she'll she'll discuss and to my
far left there um uh constant Mah who's
joined us all the way from Canada um and
has trained as a food scientist and has
been in the industry for about 15 years
so we're very very much um pleased to
have him on the panel and then myself um
as I was introduced I'm a a partner of a
law firm but a director of our
regulatory Solutions I've been a lawyer
for about 17 now plus years I've been in
the Cannabis industry for about four and
have advised clients in both the
medicinal and the CBD and wellness space
not recreational yet because UK is not
like Germany so can't discuss those ones
otherwise I'll get in trouble with the
authorities so CA yes what's on our
plate in Europe when it comes to canono
yeah or
anything well I think the situation is
um very very mixed and I know the
audience is a little bit maybe more
recreational but when I received all the
congratulations uh like weeks ago ago
about the development I was a little bit
astonished because I thought okay what
for
exactly uh sitting here also as an
industry uh representative for the
industry is pretty nothing in so um I
thought like wow okay there's some
associations they are nonprofit no
profit no loss no taxes um okay this is
a way to go but uh we will see how it
will develop and also you know the
budgets of such kind of an association
okay you can make your Easy Math 500
people let me say 500 euro membership
fee we are at
250,000 so anybody who even run a
charity organization as also I do
250,000 is not much money if you have
also to grow and to have uh people
engaged for the growing Etc so we will
see the development how this will go so
of course the other option was okay is
maybe something in the novel food area
or is it the food area I think we see
through Europe that Edibles are
tolerated um this does not mean that
they are legalized but they are
tolerated in several countries and uh of
course you don't know how things are
going on so you know this we know that
CBD is of course under the focus already
of the FSA we know that there were about
150 applications 19 remained um and I'm
really not an authority batter but but
when you see the movement of epsa and
the time they need to evaluate something
it is pretty painful we have even
probiotics still in evaluation which we
already know since denona and Nest that
this is something which is favorable for
your well-being and your microbiome and
still we do not have an assessment there
so this is why my hope to have for CBD a
quick reach um is not very
optimistic um but I think another
situation which is of course developing
is um the ban of being a
narcotic and I think this is a very
interesting approach because it was a
political not a pharmacological decision
we know it all but if you have food and
you have until now the bar the barrier
that you cannot mix it with a
narcotic which was okay we everybody
understood but it is now not a narcotic
anymore I think I will be very
interested in the legal argumentation of
the authorities how to deal with that
because the foot um uh Administration
Authority is presently refused cannabis
of course due to being a narcotic uh
their web page did not change yet and of
course the European side on cannabis is
very critical um we have still even
countries who did not approve medicinal
cannabis yet especially East countri so
this is where we are in discussion with
the governments um in Romania Etc to to
lift that ban um to train them on the
situation and also to give them
information from other authorities like
B Farm the survey was maybe statistical
uh not really excellent but I think it
brought a lot of information which maybe
one Authority can adopt from another
Authority the same was also for the
Spanish hearing which is now on going
where we commented as well so there is
things which are moving but it is
something what you have to consider to
be on a long run it is nothing which we
can solve I think in one or two years
and I think that's quite interesting
from a European perspective in the sense
of I mean for the audience and we're
both C and I European obviously I'm from
the UK so the continent Europe not part
of the EU uh I'm just lucky I've got two
passports but anyway the um for those
that are not part of Europe novel Foods
was has been around since 1997 so
basically if it's not been in your
dietary System since I think 15th of May
1997 if I'm correct it's seen as novel
so if we got water's not novel right
this has been in our dietary system
forever um in May I or February 2019 if
I'm not mistaken uh Europe or Brussels
decided that CBD was novel in an
extracted form not hemp seed oil
compressed but on CBD itself was novel
and that's why novel Foods is is
relevant for Europe and the UK cuz even
though the UK left uh with brexit we
adopted the same uh philosophy and so
basically anything with CBD had to go
through what your application process as
you said so in the UK we we basically
carbon copied um that approach however
there was a hybrid model the UK thought
that they'd be clever because of brexit
so whilst we were going through our
transitional period which was in back in
2020 what we said was and I think if I'm
not mistaken around about the 13th of
February 2020 the food standards agency
in the UK said look we adopt the
approach by Europe to say that CBD is
novel and you have to submit a novel
Foods application however if you're on
the market so basically if you've been
selling that you something that you
shouldn't have been selling at that time
you can continue selling but you've got
to submit an application once we open
our portal which was 1st of January
2021 and you've got to submit an
application and you've got to submit the
application before the 31st of March
2021 originally though they said they
would validate all applications by the
31st of March they then changed the
goalpost because there's someone here in
the audience a client of mine that was
involved in a couple of these
applications they had over 800
applications and obviously the food
standings agency had never dealt with a
novel Foods application because it was
all through epsa previously so they
thought oh Dar we're not going to be
able to validate all of these
applications so they changed the
goalpost it's said submission point so
if you'd submitted your applications by
the 31st March 2021 you could continue
selling then what happened was they said
we're going to have to validate
everybody and we have to be very careful
with the language and I think this is
where a lot of our friends from the
States and Canada and those that weren't
part of the European discussions at the
time confuse words with validation and
for authorization because they're
completely different so validation and I
don't want to bore you guys with as I'm
a lawyer because no one's paying me for
this discussion so there you go I
usually charge for this but no I'm
joking but no what I don't want to bore
you on on on on the legal side of it but
basically validation is a tick boox
exercise so basically have you submitted
an application does it contain all the
relevant Parts have you submitted all
the information including testing and so
on so forth and how when when that data
is going to be readily available if so
that's a valid valid application so it's
validated right that's as basic as I can
get to then it goes through the
regulator checking it and seeing if it's
safe and all the various toxicology data
reviewing it and then you get
authorization and that's in Europe
that's the only time that you can sell
once you got authorization so now that's
clear in the mind in the UK they said no
once you're validated you can carry on
selling and then once we authorize you
great you can continue if you're not
authorized then you're off the shelves
that created one a hybrid model but also
a monopoly for those that were already
selling illicitly and they shouldn't
have been which meant that investment or
other opportunities from the states or
or Canada couldn't bring in a product
where maybe they had the safety data
maybe they already had a product that
was selling that had no THC they could
know they could submit an application
but because they hadn't been sell
selling pre 13th February 2020 in the UK
they would have to wait until they were
fully authorized a bit like in Europe so
it created this Monopoly which I had
massive arguments with the food SS
agency because I said that's not your
role as a regulator your role as a
regulator is to ensure that consumers
are consuming something that is safe you
shouldn't be creating this infighting
between the industry so where are we now
since all of that in the UK we've now
got a public list of those that are
I would say a few that have been given
that
validation the food standards agency is
still saying on their on public list
awaiting evidence I checked this morning
just as so we I gave you a proper proper
uh idea of of how many products on that
list
12,15 products on that list um of which
I don't know how many companies because
obviously as you can imagine some
companies have variety of SKS and
product lines and so on and so forth
in one
way it's a good thing I think for and
I'm not saying this cuz I'm a UK lawyer
I I'm I was completely against the
process so I just want to make that
clear but in one way it's been
beneficial because at least those
businesses can continue selling and
earning some money because they' had
invested so much money into their
product and the ones that probably still
there are probably the ones that are
going to continue still being there for
longevity subject to the regular giving
them that final certification that they
authorized to continue selling subject
to those products being safe um so
that's the that's the the screenshot of
where we are in the UK and I'd like now
to introduce constant again because
obviously you know he's he's a scientist
from the food industry and he can give
us some insight of where Canada is now
and maybe the journey that Canada's
taken because fundamentally us here in
Europe and the UK a are always looking
at Canada and the US saying your leap
years ahead but are you when it comes to
food uh just after hearing how you
described um the UK and the approach
that um the UK is taking on novel Foods
um I do draw some similarities but there
are there are Stark contrasts between
what the Canadians are doing versus um
the UK so um you know Health Canada uh C
FIA they always get a bad rap in Canada
because they always seen as you know
overregulation and in some situations
that is correct um but I I think that
Health Canada and their approach for
Novo Foods or just Edibles in general um
sounds to be probably a very good middle
ground to ensuring really the ultimate
goal is the consumer safety uh making
sure that there's the food products that
is uh out in the marketplace is safe for
consumption there's no contaminants
there's no micro um and that your
consistent quality is is met uh for
every different batch that you produce
um so the approach that Health Canada um
takes for uh approving uh novel Foods is
that um for producers um let let's take
it from like a producer who's never done
Edibles before but they but they want to
uh so what they would need to do is they
need to establish their their food
safety program um prerequisites such as
your preventative control program to
ensuring that every step of your
manufacturing process controls and
mitigates the risks to an acceptable
level uh so that would be your chemical
contaminants heavy metals um apoxin you
name it um to to micro levels and health
Canada doesn't dictate which uh
pharmacopia you can use so there is
actually quite a bit wiggle room
between um between different testing
standards uh that might fit better for
your product category if that makes
sense so um for instance the EP
pharmacopia versus that of USP uh EP is
quite a bit more stringent in terms of
uh micro requirements uh so you'll see
uh a lot of Canadian producers actually
choose the the less sorry uh choose the
less uh stringent of the the pharmacopia
um when you're registering new products
as well uh it's actually on the burden
of The Producers to ensuring that their
products is safe um so through your
pcps uh once you've done that then you
do your final testing to make sure that
it's homogeneous so your cannabinoids uh
all that stuff is consistent B the batch
um once you've have that you just keep
it inh house you don't really need to
present it uh then you submit a new
cannabis sorry notice of new cannabis um
product to health Canada now this is
where we do things a little bit
differently in that Health Canada
doesn't technically have to put a rubber
stamp on your new product to say that
this is approved now you can sell they
give you a 60-day
window of the time that you submit um
for an
nncp uh and then after that 60 days
automatically you can you can start
selling so it's kind of good in a sense
that it leaves the responsibility and
the ownership of the safety the
commercial
commercialization and as as well as the
quality of the product up to the lp and
that uh sorry licensed producer and if
that licensed producer produces
fantastic product it's consistent it's
also safe uh we can pretty much
guarantee that it's it's going to have
no issues down the road um but we're
also seeing issues now where you know
people do these ncps they wait to 60
days they start selling but then Health
Canada comes in because they get a a uh
a market complaint saying that this
product may not be compliant to certain
regulations
um the
most the most recent issue that came uh
within Canada uh is the edible extracts
um I don't know if which one of you guys
here are Canadian or not um but
basically what happened was in Canada
you're only allowed to have 10
mgram um of uh THC within your finished
product retail product um whereas these
companies kind of found a loophole and
classified these as extracts as opposed
to Edibles uh and the xtrax requirement
is you're allowed to have way more THC
with in your finished product um so
unfortunately Health Canada
um stood fast on their determination
that these particular products uh which
are like lenes things that typically in
in the past when it's not infused with
cannabis uh is more seen as kind of like
over-the-counter
um like Health Products um like cold
remedies that kind of stuff um there's
other products in the Marketplace as
well um that was caught with like the
mixture of melatonin with cannabinoids
you know the justification for smlp
saying that melatonin is a uh
stabilizing agent but really it's it's
an active ingredient and in the in the
eyes of Health Canada when you have an
active ingredient such as melatonin um
you must have um
uh a d number constant that's quite
interesting because obviously I don't
know if the audience has picked up on
this but you've been talking about
products that contain THD as food
Edibles right in the UK and Europe we've
only submitted applications that contain
CBD because recreational is not yet
legal obviously it is now in Germany I
don't think and I could be wrong here
maybe C just a side question here how's
the European food standards agency going
to look at an edible that contains THC
because that will still have to go
through a novel Foods application right
yeah I think for the for the fset would
be an easy one because of course the
German legislation does not apply for
the European regulation so for them it
will be still of course a narcotic and
will be uh seen as that and I think here
the the door will be closed very quickly
but in in similar
terms Germany if it's a food product
follows novel Foods so if it's an edible
that's THC it would still have to have
novel Foods authorization if it was
going to be sold as a food supp of some
sort yes and I think this is where you
know we we uh we have the difficulties
this that we do not have pharmacological
arguments what was put now in place but
political and of course FSA is not
listen to listening to political
arguments on that way so we have here
now of course a disruptive situation
with Germany and the European Community
this is why the legalization let me say
is concentrated on clubs and not like an
uh commercial trade business um because
then we are still in the shenen and um
which is at the end uh replicating the
single convention word right and so and
the reason I raised that as a as a point
of discussion just for food for thought
using novel Foods Food For Thought for
the audience really is because you have
to think about this CU obviously I don't
know who's in the audience but I'm sure
there's entrepreneurs and and and people
that are looking to invest in businesses
or or maybe continue with their business
just because Germany's gone Recreation
doesn't mean that we're full-blown
recreational because again like all of
cannabis you've got variety of products
that you can create and what and I try
to read a lot of what's happened in
Canada the good and the bad stuff cuz
Europe doesn't really like Canada when
it comes to cannabis they've done not
done some great things uh obviously
present company excluded but when it
comes to where the recreational market
and and this may be something for you
just to just a tou
on we all see the news that everybody's
trying to ban smoking generally and
that's tobacco and nicotine and you know
what that looks like I've I've read and
I could be wrong so and you're from
Canada maybe you can explain that when
it comes to recreational Cannabis it's
the same thing a lot people want to get
high but they don't want to actually
smoke something to get high they want to
eat something right and or they want to
experience another way of getting high
so is that a general Trend in Canada as
well yeah there's a lot of restrictions
in Canada and it it varies provincial to
provincials um what the requirements are
and what you're what you are and you
aren't allowed but the general rule is
you're not allowed smoking uh anything
uh inside a building um a public
building um and within X number of feet
or meters from from an entrance um so
with that and there's also that stigma
to cannabis that you know even though
Canada has been full legal for for 5 6
years now um like full recreational uh
there's still that stigma that the
Canadians are still trying to overcome
um and Edibles and even Vape products um
it's a good alternative where you don't
need to have that cannabis smell uh the
pungent uh cannabis spell especially for
professionals um who you know like to
partake but they obviously don't want to
have any sort of negative um you know
thought process from from people EX if
they walk by them and they sell them
right um so yeah like to your point I I
think I think there is a push towards
more Edibles now you're seeing a ton
more Edibles launching every month um
there's uh so I I think there's a
there's a justification for that and
it's because people um more
professionals uh wouldn't want to you
know smell like and I I think it's a a
younger generation as well don't
associate
with smoking I mean I'm old enough to
remember watching movies where people
used to smoke on screen right or even
smoke on planes and that whole culture
is gone and I think that's also changed
for you know producers they are also
producing something that they know that
culturally it fits with their younger
Generations right so I mean it obviously
feels that Canada and something that
Europe still is far away from is food
products that contain THD cuz we're only
talking about food products contain the
can have you know CBD so we're still far
for from that process and I think you're
right it's until it's not seen as a
narcotic from the foods perspective then
it's hard to see how that's going to
happen any day soon I'm not sure how
much time we've got because there's no
timer on us so
um I could leave some questions now for
the audience before I can continue I
might have a few but if there's any
questions from the
audience um
uh there's no guys with mics they've
left we B we've bored we've bored the
organizers on food there we go they've
all left the building yeah do you have
an idea of uh how long this could take
to have the first uh novel food
authorization on CBD we have for example
some synthetic applications where you
have no risk of d they've returned to
the building the first
ones and the and the first yeah the
first ones uh are the assessment is
expiring this year so uh we were really
wondering if this year something will
come out or it will take longer thanks
thank you I think I can take that
because for I think this is the
complication of the FSA because epsa is
not one body but contains several
subcommittees so to bring it through
this kind of let me say ODC of bodies is
this is why I'm taking and this is why I
mentioned the sample of the probiotics
you know which is so clear for us for
more than 25 years and still you know we
are not having valid claims um although
you know so many um even big companies
nestly supplied uh a lot of data so I
cannot predict anything as a good lawyer
I will not tell you uh give you any bad
promises no the situation is still open
and you all know that CBD was meanwhile
even under control substance uh which
then has been stopped fortunately
because there was also no
pharmacological reason for that so I
think the situation is Still Remains
unclear and we are delivered to the
mercy of the
authority okay I got it I got it get out
the way you're taking my
job let's hear it for ca ca thank you
thank you look at
that hi thank you very much um my name
is Marine um I wanted to ask uh 2 years
ago was it 3 years ago there was a
Polish Court uh which decided that hemp
Leaf extracts are not novel food uh this
made quite some waves um but
unfortunately I haven't heard anything
is there a reply from the the FSA uh
rebuking it or yeah but hemp is not a
problem hemp never been a problem seed
is not a problem this everything is
allowed well it is a problem in Germany
we have a lot of cases where people are
not allowed to sell because they say
there's still novel food in application
it is they get they get they get the the
letter I can give you later the the page
of the um of the Authority for food and
there's clearly stated that seed that
hemp is not a problem SE I'm talking
about the leaves and the flowers okay
because the I don't know if everybody
get grinded there was a um um one of the
biggest chocolate brands R sport has
created a cannabis chocolate which was
of course based based on on hemp they
had the the Cannabis Le in front they
made a kind of few batches but then it
disappeared I don't know why if it was
some kind of admonition because they
said um I don't know so uh just threeory
but they made some chocolate which was
of course with hemp and not with
cannabis so as one of the biggest
chocolate brands I don't they are not
very risk uh adaptive so I am sure that
um there was some clarification that
that this is possible and of course we
have hemp oil we have yeah I was just
going to add to that so the flour like
in most of European uh countries and in
the UK when it comes to food it's a
controlled substance so on that side of
things it's very difficult to say that
that's not novel as a food so I I
haven't seen the Polish um uh discussion
from 1997 stated from the
EU yeah okay look we've got to be
careful okay as I explained right at the
beginning if it's not been in there was
a big big case that went before Brussels
before uh 2019 that um tried to quash
the notion that CBD wasn't novel now I'm
not I'm not arguing for that or against
it I'm not a scientist that that
discussion happened that discussion
actually came from the uh UK it was
actually the CTA and I think um I
forgotten the European um counterpart
that put an application or or statement
to Brussels to say CBD is not novel it's
been in our dietry system uh and so on
and so forth hemp's been around for
hundreds if not thousands of years and
they lost I don't know why they lost I
wasn't there I didn't argue the points
but they lost on a technicality I
believe I could be wrong and it was it
was after that that they made the
announcements at CBD as an extracted
form was novel and if if it was going to
be contained in food it had to go
through this novel Foods process all
right I hate to have to cut you off but
we are over time let's hear it again for
our wonderful panel Ricardo X CA
Schubert constant
ma this is the international cannabis
business conference Berlin 2024