this was very exciting we don't always
this is often up and overlooked and
overlooked facets of the cannabis
industry due diligence is very important
you have to do your research you have to
know your facts you have to have a plan
in place right so we're gonna bring up
our moderator she's the managing
director of FTI Consulting right they
work on cyber threats they work on how
to be in compliance with the anti money
laundering laws right all the fraud all
your supply chain issues all your due
diligence they work on that you can work
with them I'm gonna introduce it right
now let's hear it for the one and only
Elaine Carey
[Music]
[Applause]
good morning thank you for your
attention or for joining us today so I
know people sort of their eyes can glaze
over when you talk about due diligence
and compliance they're like oh no not
more of those things we have to do but
I'd like to and I think my panelists
will join me in saying that it has a
different you can look at it a different
way
ie to protect your bottom line to make
your business stronger to make it more
viable and also in the future if you do
want to you know when it becomes legal
federally if you want to cash in on that
these are the things you have to do but
you you have to do it just now just to
make your business survive what you know
just stand out from all the rest as I
always say to people as my I have an
investigative background if if somebody
else business is is softer they're
cutting corners places that's where the
regulator's the authorities are going to
go and the bad guys as well to
infiltrate because it's easier if you've
crossed all your t's dotted all your
eyes you're a much safer much healthier
business and that's what we're here to
talk to about today which is the
financial operational regulatory and
reputational risk that you need to guard
against and it's not it doesn't have to
be heavy lifting or really really
expensive I do this for clients I do due
diligence backgrounds on the clients to
give to investors or vice versa
we I've done anti-money laundering
reviews for financial institutions that
want to bank my cannabis money thank
goodness they're willing to begin to
talk about it done it for armored car
companies that want a bank so there is
interest out there but you've got to do
it the right way and I think we've
brought together a pretty interesting
panel that covers the entirety of those
risks we start with Barnard next to me
Barnard is from immerged law group here
in Portland and they're the very first
law group to get into the business and
have deep experience in a variety of
issues that you face from land use to
corporate structures to tax to
employment to HR and probably things
I've forgotten
Barnard will tell you about and next to
Barnard is my colleague Lincoln Eckhart
who is evaluations an appraisal expert
and one of the things I like about
Lincoln is he's also a native to
Portland but I very early on we started
doing cannabis services at fti which is
a little unusual because we are a
publicly traded company we called up
Lincoln and said can you value a
cannabis company even though it's kind
of a start-up and they don't have a lot
of formal processes and procedures and
maybe their books are in crayon I don't
know or on maybe a Excel spreadsheet
because I'm sure done it before so these
are the kind of people that you need to
we what we want to do today is give you
some concrete takeaways and the last
panelist member Matt Murphy is a
vice-president from chiron life sciences
and Matt brings two unique attributes to
our panel today one he's actually
running a cannabis company that's based
in Canada but doing work in Colombia as
in Bogota Colombia and to Matt as a
retired DEA agent who was on the
diversion side I worked in
pharmaceuticals for more than 25 years
and I think particularly helpful to have
Matt today after the DEA move CBD from
schedule 1 to schedule 5 the other day
so I think hopefully he can provide some
unique insight into how that happened so
let's start with you Bernard what are
some concrete things that companies need
to do in terms of being in compliance
with the law but then aren't aren't
going to just sink the ship at the very
beginning by getting if you might say
expensive legal advice but that helps
them grow and prosper sure thank you
so that expensive legal advice is tough
a tough target to hit sometimes but in
terms of in terms of being able to cover
your bases on the front end without
sinking the ship as Elaine says
I the I think the kind of the most
productive and and and the the most
productive approach is to is to identify
the categories of issues that you're
dealing with so it emerged there's
emerged lagu the firm I am with there
are a number of corporate lawyers with
deep securities law background and so if
you're starting a company and you're
looking at raising money from outside
investors it makes sense to be meeting
with someone like that even if you're
not yet ready to you know form a
corporation or what have you and that
way you're getting off on the right foot
another area that that matters is
obviously the licensing end and right
now in in the licensing environment in
Oregon you're often talking about going
through a process that can take many
months and in there are there there
might be twists and turns along the way
as the industry and the regulatory
environment continues to develop and and
and you're not going to want to lose
time because you kind of went down maybe
went down what seems to be a wrong track
in retrospect there are there are also a
number of areas that that at least a a
cannabis business person that is
relatively new to what we used to call
kind of above ground business practices
it can make a lot of sense to be meeting
with meeting with an employment lawyer
to figure out what steps you need to
take now so that you're not dealing with
a potentially expensive problem maybe
just a few months down the road
and and then and and then of course
their land use and and and local code
and zoning issues and and then there's
there's my area which which is tax
issues and and that's an area where I
guess tax professionals often kind of
privately gripe about always being
brought in to transactions late the
reason for that is oftentimes you're
brought into a transaction and then you
kind of have a if an only if moment you
know only if the you know we had been
having this conversation three months or
six months ago you know we could be
talking about a much a much smaller tax
bill but in terms of the discussion
you'd be having with a tax person on the
front end you'd be talking about well
what sort of business entity are we
going to use are we going to be using
more than one business entity when we're
when we're trying to pencil out our
financials
what is this tax code section 280a issue
and how does that really work
and then and and you might you might end
up setting up a very small business that
you know in your context make sense from
a tax perspective or you might be
setting up a multi entity structure with
kind of specific with specific goals in
mind you know maybe maybe protecting
risk-averse investors from potentially
adverse or expensive tax consequences
flowing through to their personal
returns or you might be you might be
looking at ways to allow your business
to have access to the kind of expertise
it needs without the compensation you're
paying those people being non deductible
because of 280e
or you might be looking at ways to
ensure that you know when you
when you renew your lease for example
that you don't you don't end up losing
you know a $300,000 tax deduction just
because you didn't plan ahead in how you
set up your lease so if if you're
sitting down with with with an attorney
or different specialist attorneys as you
kind of learn the lay of the land if
you're sitting down with them on a kind
of a brainstorming a planning level and
then you get together with your team
after you've I guess educated yourself
somewhat in that environment then I
think you're you're going to find that
not only our taxes much it'll be a much
less expensive proposition but you're
also going to be able to manage those
taxes in real time and not get behind
the ball and then getting to the due
diligence portion of things you're not
going to be having a potentially awkward
conversation with an investor who or a
potential buyer down the road who comes
from a world where tax compliance is is
is is taking for granted and is just
expected and who might start to wonder
what other problems you have simply
because you have some unaddressed tax
issues thanks Bernard Lincoln you we've
seen all these mega valuations coming
out of Canada that could make anybody's
eyes get stuck with dollar signs in them
because it just looks so wonderful and
but at the same time maybe fantastical
one of the things you'd said to me is
value is all about pricing risk can you
explain what you mean about that and
what you see it what you think about
these sort of if you will sky high
valuations going around and is that
going to stay there forever I think it's
important to bifurcate the the public
market from the
ivenn market I think in Canada you have
seen some sky-high evaluations applied
to cannabis businesses I think there's a
couple of reasons for that one its
Canada it's a different regulatory
structure obviously to the companies
gone public when a company goes public
it's really bendy wrist
oh by a large magnitude and there's also
a lot of hot money that's moving into
that sector so it's it's not a typical
to see you know some of these cannabis
companies of Canada publicly traded they
were trading at 100 200 400 times
revenue when you come back to the
private sector you look at what's
happening in transactions in the private
sector you see much more pedestrian
multiples I'd say there's a recent
transaction in Washington State of six
large retail operations is sold at one
times revenue or point seven times next
12 months revenue it's a far cry from a
four hundred times revenue I think a big
part of that is really what what I want
to hit on in terms of the due diligence
considerations which is valuation
essentially is a pricing risk exercise I
mean your bet you're basically pricing
risk value equals the present value of
future expected cash flows not the
sexiest thing in the world but that's
that's how you value a business or any
asset you look at you know what are the
expected future cash flows and you
present value those cash flows back to
present you know to today that present
valuing exercise is that you use a risk
adjusted discount rate so you've kind of
build up a discount rate based on the
risk that you see in the asset or in the
business with cannabis companies you
know one of the challenges are there's
already sort of systemic risk that are
there essentially because of the
regulatory environment because the
public perception because of other
factors you already have a risk premium
built-in when looking at cannabis
companies I think to the benefit of
owners anyone is in you know operating a
business and in the cannabis industry
the most critical thing you can do is
try to de-risk when you're thinking
about potential exit down the
trying to raise capital from outside
investors whatever you can do to de-risk
the enterprise it's a direct correlation
between de-risking an enterprise and
increasing the value they're inversely
related right so if you have systems in
place processes in place if you have
money mad cash management systems seed
to sale systems in place you have
contracts with your suppliers with your
wholesalers or retailers whatever aspect
of the industry you're in
if those contracts have been you know
vetted by lawyers are written by lawyers
and they've been validated your
financial systems your accounting
systems all these things that sometimes
seem sort of mundane and not of great
entry especially trying to build a
business you're focused on your
customers you're focused on your product
or whatever is the service that you're
providing you're not necessarily too
concerned or thinking about the more
mundane aspects of the business well
when you go to a point of trying to
raise capital or get a value assigned to
this asset that you're building that
your that you that you own it's all
about it's all about you know that that
de-risking process that an outside
investor can come in and look at your
business and say okay you know
everything checks out I don't see any
red flags here though that that process
and that creating that system in place
that enterprise will directly pay off in
terms of increased value as Elaine said
she first are talking about valuing
cannabis companies and she had a you
know said of client what happens they
just have some spreadsheets and all
their financials are basically just a
couple of Excel data sheets and that's
all they we really have as documents to
look at with his business yeah you can
certainly value it but the risk premium
you're gonna apply when you vet when
you're present valuing those cash flows
or whether you're using a market
multiple is directly correlated to the
to the quality of the information
another really important point is people
I mean you can have great financials at
least you know financial statements you
can have these systems in place
you can have these checks and balances
built into your operations to make sure
that your you've minimized risk but
really what would an appraiser or what
an investor is going to look at is a
quality of management I don't care what
industry you're in that's probably the
single most important thing so as you
look to build or expand or partner with
other companies or you're bringing
outside people to help build your
business just as Elaine alluded to
earlier something that she does is does
due diligence on people do deal with due
diligence on your suppliers your
wholesalers whoever you're you know in
your in your chain of operations just
make sure you put forth the effort to
really research who it is that you're
working with because that's something
that's gonna be very important to a
potential investor and as I said you
know everything you can do to to have a
a low-risk well-documented well
insulated infrastructure will move you
when you go to raise capital or sell
because it's gonna have a direct impact
on what you know what you basic and
achieve in the marketplace for your
asset showing you how devastating it can
be if you don't know who are you're
involved with your partner's other
management etc we had a case recently
where I was doing an anti money
laundering review at a credit union in
California that was going to Bank
cannabis and we were talking about
whether or not they had had actually
terminated any clients recently and they
said yes they had had two gentlemen come
in there was a partnership of three
people two people had come in recently
and they said they were completely just
ashen-faced than they were just so
downtrodden and they said we had to come
in and tell you personally that we just
found out our third partner had been
sanctioned by the SEC and they knew
exactly what was going to happen which
was their account and they were they're
one of the few people that was lucky
enough to actually have an account in a
bank and the bat and the account was you
know they realized what was going to
happen the account was closed
they were back to zero all because even
though they were partners in a business
they hadn't looked closely enough to
each other to figure out what their
prior history had been and whether or
not that was going to impact the
business and boy did it so turning you
to you Matt yeah you're the one person
has very hands-on experience
can you tell and I also know that you're
very familiar with a lot of these
systems because you and I have talked
about CD sales tracking systems which
was a good how important that is can you
talk to us a little bit about the
concrete steps that you tell people to
take and that Chiron has taken to
protect the company and and then I guess
the other two points I'd like you to
make are one about diversion because
obviously that was your history at the
DEA you were a diversion expert and how
you help people deal with that in their
cannabis business and of course we need
to hear from you on the holes schedule
one to schedule 5 for CBD that's a whole
mouthful for you to take on yes so to
talk a little bit about my background as
Elaine mentioned I spent over 25 years
as a special agent with the Drug
Enforcement Administration and I'll just
answer the question you're all thinking
because I get it all the time so how did
you end up a DEA agent in this space
it's really been a pretty seamless and
easy transition for me because part of
my job responsibilities back in the day
if you will was when he was at the
beginning of the opioid epidemic I was
on the front lines of shutting down
first internet pharmacies where people
could go online and order a prescription
drug by googling hydrocodone without a
prescription web sites would come up
they would order vicodin and they
basically filled out an online
questionnaire that would be sent to some
doctor who could be sitting on a boat
the Bahamas who just hit click click
approve approve and what happened was
though that would be sent to an online
pharmacy Muslim or in Florida that would
just fill prescriptions and send them
out FedEx UPS all over the country
and the Ryan hate Act was passed that
mandated a face-to-face doctor-patient
visit before a prescription for an
opiate could be issued so the reason I
bring that up is because that was the
early stages of the opioid epidemic I
was at headquarters at the time it
worked with a guy named Joanna ZZ 60
minutes did a big report about that
because of things that happen that
shouldn't happen but when pain clinics
or oak internet pharmacies were outlawed
pain clinics became the norm because
they had a doctor on site and then this
issue just got worse and worse and worse
so when 60 minutes did their piece I was
interviewed as well and was on camera
what's happened over the years is I've
determined and and and believed which
I've heard much talk of here today which
I'm happy to hear that I believe and
many others do as well that medical
cannabis can be an alternative to
opioids everybody in this country I'm
sure everybody in this room knows
somebody who's been touched by the
opioid epidemic whether it's a friend of
your child a child or friends of yours
we all know somebody opioids and I was
running again I've been there opioids
and my far as I'm concerned of bad drugs
and they're dangerous and they're
addictive and people die so with with
that medical cannabis I believe is is a
good alternative written articles about
it as far as my work with Chiron I was
approached by another agent that I
worked with chi runs a company that is
the first seed to sale medical cannabis
company to be operating in Colombia and
Colombia legalized medical cannabis
about a year ago so I was recruited by
Chiron to come in and stand up there
compliance and regulatory division and
what I've done is brought basically de
A's rules and regulations as it pertains
to regulating the pharma industry for
controlled substances to the cannabis
space the reason I think that's
important for the
folks in this room is because as only
you mentioned yesterday I'm sure many of
you know maybe some of you don't
DEA rescheduled CBD oil from a Schedule
one to a Schedule five controlled
substance which means that the Code of
Federal Regulations that are enforced by
DEA as it pertains to controlled
substances will now be applied to CBD
oil and I think and I've thought for a
long time that that is just basically
the start of prohibition ending as we
you know CBD oil which has a very low
THC obviously if any THC content at all
so methey a has already done so as far
as D scheduled so I think that this is
how this prohibition ending will evolve
from CBD oil to that medical cannabis
and we'll see where it goes from there
so when that happens I think the DEA
will will take over regulatory for the
industry at some point I mean that could
be a big leap for me to say but I do
believe that the same regulations that
are applied now to controlled substances
for pharma companies will be applied to
the cannabis space the good thing about
that is it will bring consistent
regulation to the cannabis industry so
instead of in Oregon where it's the
alcohol commission those folks that were
here earlier and other states where you
have it's it's the Health Department of
Health well whoever it is it regulates
the industry in every state it's
regulated a little bit differently and
as the industry evolves and the
government evolves and prohibition ends
you'll see consistent regulation I think
throughout throughout the industry which
I think will be a really good thing and
as the folks mentioned on the panels
prior that you know saving the industry
it sounds like saving the industry in
this state means that you need to be
able to export to other states and and
maybe other countries and obviously
consistent regulation and prohibition
ending is going to bring that a long way
as far as the due diligence
we apply the due diligence standards
that are in the CFR to our regulations
in Chiron seed to sale in technology
that can advance and monitor seed to
sale is very important serialization
technology very important there are
software companies out there that you
may I don't I'm not sure if an are gone
if you're mandated to use one company
for reporting to the state if is that
the case here and in which company do
use Metro metric okay so some states use
bio track THC which is a company that
we're familiar with and I think a lot of
that has to do with both compliance to
prevent detect diversion but it's also I
think you know for tax purposes for
reporting so that they can tax the
growers and whatnot but operating in
Columbia is a very unique and spin and
creates circumstances very specific to
the region but we I think that the same
same methodology can be applied anywhere
I mean we're starting we're starting a
company from scratch building a grow
operation on the equator and and you
know again because of Columbia being a
narco-state in the past with people like
Pablo Escobar and kingpins and cartels
it presents a very unique set of
challenges for us that you may not have
here in the United States of course
because we're you know we're a different
society but when you drill down into
what it takes to operate a successful
regulated industry the same challenges
apply in Colombia that or anywhere in
Latin America South America that apply
here in the US so it's as Elaine
mentioned and my colleagues mentioned
here it's about the due diligence is
about you knowing your customer knowing
your suppliers knowing your vendors
doing that due diligence on on those
folks to ensure that they're not
involved in activity that may
bring adverse action against your
license and that's that's very important
to know the people that you're in
business with because that can lead to
big problems for you in in your
operation and and as another gentleman
on a panel previously said you know
asking for forgiveness is not an option
so it's important whether it's your seed
to sale technology or it's knowing your
your vendors and suppliers that
everybody is is well vetted and and
you're doing business with people who
are legitimate as opposed to gray market
or black market folks so they come today
cover I think Renard what what are you
would you say was the biggest legal
mistake people make in terms of getting
their cannabis businesses going I've
seen indications now that litigation is
beginning we're partners may have
started off with a handshake and then as
the business grows they begin to fight
and then there's no contract or no you
know no corporate bylaws etc what are
you saying that begins to trip up
companies and cause them the most grief
you know they that would actually be an
interesting question to poll lawyers
working with the industry and they did
in my case and and I think with a number
of the attorneys I work more closely
with that that that kind of failure to
formalize what are in essence legal
relationships is is very high on the
list I think oftentimes there's a
reluctance to a reluctance to go down
the path of I guess reviewing all all
the ways you you you maintain a business
relationship with someone whether it be
a supplier or service provider or
whatever or quite likely a business
partner
and going down that path of identifying
those areas where maybe you don't maybe
see eye to eye or maybe want to be once
one thing and the other one wants
something else and so I think there
there can be an both a learning curve as
as businesspeople become familiar with
concepts like formal contracts but also
maybe a reluctance to have some of the I
guess more more pointed discussions that
you need to have on the front end and
then of course over time if you don't
have a document that you and your
business partners or you and a you know
another person or business can refer to
to figure out what the rules are and
what the deal is then then the
relationship can start to drift and and
and and and just like just like personal
relationships you know unless unless
there's a kind of an effort at that
point to kind of bring things back in
line with with with an arrangement that
works for everyone then then you can
have those very expensive issues where
you know a healthy business is may be
damaged or maybe needs to be liquidated
because some of the key owners aren't
getting along so yeah I just want to add
that's a really great point and my
practice does a lot of litigation
support work so we do a lot of
valuations economic damages work in the
context of litigation I'd say one of the
number one reasons that you see people
in litigation around value of businesses
is that the shareholder agreement or
wherever the operating agreement was I
was constructed was was poorly written
and poorly executed every business is
either gonna be sold or it's gonna just
you know liquidate at some point there's
not really any other outcome for
business so putting forth the initial
effort in the beginning to really make
sure you define terms around value and
ownership and what happens upon
different exit scenarios what happens
upon you know an owner's death what
happens upon shareholder dispute of one
type or another is critical because you
know I'd say no exaggeration 50% of the
litigation work I see is due to poor
agreements and someone you know there's
a falling-out between business partners
and then there's a fight because it
wasn't clearly spelled out how the
shares or how the interest the unit's an
LLC for example should be valued and it
creates massive headaches super
expensive and it's you know but I'm so
just to your point I mean making sure
those agreements are in place and really
well-thought-out in terms of defying
like is it you know fair market value
do you have consideration of shareholder
discounts minority level discounts
discounts for lack of marketability all
these terms that appraisers use every
day obviously most business people
aren't necessary familiar with them but
just think about you know that that
question of value and what happens upon
some sort of exit okay and and just
because tax is kind of my area I will I
will without getting technical observe
that the the a common result of of maybe
being slow to address tax issues may be
in part because we as individuals you
know we kind of think about tax once or
twice a year as April 15th approaches
and then maybe as the the extended
deadline approaches it you if someone's
running a business say for a year or 18
months dealing with all the complexity
and and and so on and hard work that's
involved it if they're not if they're
not looking tax issues almost in real
time kind of on a monthly or maybe
quarterly basis which which can require
maybe being a little bit forceful with
one cpa who might be used to clients
that think about these things once a
year if you don't do that then you the
company can maybe just be starting to
become established you know maybe some
some people in the business are starting
to feel like they're hitting their
stride a bit and then you get to tax
return time march/april whatever and
then you suddenly realize you have a
$200,000 debt that you didn't know you
had before and maybe you just made a
business decision
two months earlier you know maybe you
just entered into a deal based on the
idea that you thought you had $200,000
that maybe now you realize you don't
have or or maybe that kind of issue
flows through to an a risk averse
investor so then at that point you're
getting the the email or the phone call
from the investor after they just had a
very tense and uncomfortable discussion
with their CPA or maybe their spouse and
and that that addressing the these
issues that type of issue on the front
end can be helpful but it's very common
that people aren't able to do that are
either abusing any intellectual property
problems coming up and maybe resulting
in litigation I've seen it bits here and
there but I don't know if you've dealt
with those yet they're coming for sure
yeah they're coming they're coming I
haven't dealt specifically with that
issue yet but I've been reading it you
know obviously it's in the it's being
discussed and the IP valuations in this
in the cannabis industry are you know
are very significant and there's a ton
of a lot of these operations or
businesses the value really is in you
know the IP whether it be a license or
you know trying to a brand a trademark
any sort of process I mean there are
patents being issued and and I think
there's gonna be litigation coming from
you know claims a patent and fringe
but but to answer question I haven't
done anything specifically in that space
but I believe it's coming Lincoln do you
have any thoughts on what businesses can
do to identify IP that's going to be
worth protecting or going to be valuable
when they get to a point of potentially
selling the business yeah I mean I think
that's you know I think if you have if
you're let's say it's a product or a
brand that's getting that's driving
value I mean certainly you know is you
know have someone look at that question
for you and there's certainly IP is
valued every day and you look at a
business and you kind of allocate value
from the different assets in that
business one of those assets key
categories is intangibles which covers
you know patent and IP or other
intangibles but you know if if you
believe you have something of value that
is not a tangible asset there's a reason
why you're able to generate returns or
earnings it's a good chance it could be
in an intangible asset having that
identified and patented or trademarked
licensed in some way secures that that
comes transferable that asset now can be
transferred to a buyer without that sort
of recognition or trademark or legal
protection a buyer's not going to pay
you anything for it because it's no
there's not there's no guarantee that
they'll be able to maintain the value of
that asset so I just you know if you
think that you have a business that has
intangible value you're thinking about
you know bringing in outside investors
or an exit scenario it behooves you to
have someone help you understand
quantify that and then talk about with
an attorney obviously you know how to
license it how to protect it because you
know a lot of businesses a large
percentage of the value is locked up and
that intangible value mat what I know
you do some reviews of cannabis
businesses
for operational and security problems
what sort of things do you find that
people overlook in those situations that
cause them problems on those two fronts
security and record-keeping are probably
two the the main issues I think that
that can get folks in trouble in regards
to compliance and reporting but when it
depending on whether it's a dispensary a
grow operation or what your business
operation tails we like to look at
cannabis operations is the way you would
probably fortify in the u.s. a bank with
CCTV coverage and and I'm sure that in
Oregon there are certain criteria that
are mandated by the state I know the
regulations are onerous and as far as
the the CCTV biometrics for employees is
very important I know somebody mentioned
earlier about background investigations
on on employees and ensuring that they
they don't have any felony drug arrests
is is important diversion as it pertains
to employee theft and and loss is very
important we we through that through the
technology that's available that we're
utilizing and tracking and tracing you
know from seed to sale you know it's
important to be able to put your your
fingers on a plant at any time during
the production chain during the supply
chain as it moves as it moves through
the growth process so protecting the
operation from outside infiltration is
obviously very important as is employee
theft and diversion and I think that you
know obviously this industry is is very
you know it's a new industry and it's
evolving and credibility and legitimacy
are very important as we move forward so
that the folks that are the
naysayers out there don't have a leg to
stand on in regards to your operation
and being legitimate credible good
neighbors good in the community you're
working within is very important because
right now there I think there are there
are there are believers in there a
naysayers just like anything else so I
think that it proves everybody to to be
good corporate citizens and be good
neighbors and to make sure that you have
the most robust security and compliance
program that you can both to protect
your own license and of course to
prevent death diversion or loss from
occurring as well
I know a good number of businesses out
there and some some some businesses that
that I'm familiar with have had these
issues arise arise where they discover a
diversion issue or they discover
something about a particular employee or
business associate do you have any
thoughts on how best to move forward
with those situations when they come to
light I think you know if you have an
employee that stealing first thing you
need to do is terminate that employee
obviously and depending on on the scale
of the diversion and the theft you would
want to notify authorities regulatory
agency I think that if you just and this
is how it worked with the farm industry
as well if you determine the diversions
taking place before they do that's much
better than being told by an outside
entity that you have a problem with in
it's going to be a lot worse for your
operation if a regulator finds a problem
that you didn't know existed and that
happens in the farm industry all the
time and it's not good when it comes to
fines and adverse actions against their
DEA registration so if you have an issue
within your operation and you can
talk to the regulators and bring it to
their attention say hey this is what
happened but we dealt with it and this
person you know we notified local
authorities persons been terminated and
of course being able to determine
exactly what that looked like
from a theft and loss perspective
reporting it should put you in a good
place as far as where how you're viewed
by the authority as opposed to them
coming in finding there's something
wrong it's something missing and things
are missing now you have to find out
which employee you have a problem with
and then of course you could be dealing
with significant issues against your
license and so it's always better to be
ahead of that I would say and that's
about due diligence about doing audits
about inventories and hopefully that you
know the software tools that you use
will assist you greatly and and that
aren't you taking thinking about time
for about one more comment we're running
out of time sure just this is sort of a
a a lawyer comment the in a lot of these
situations in a lot of situations where
people discover employee theft or a
really any number of I guess anxiety
producing scenarios which the industry
is familiar with given its history it's
it can be very important to take a deep
breath I think in my view and to meet
meet with your attorney or at the very
least kind of have an internal sit down
within an organization and discussion
but me but but meet with an attorney and
kind of talk through what's going on and
the potential implications and start to
figure out how to address it in kind of
a methodical way and the reason I say
that is because so often it seems like
these these situations arise
and then because a company or an
individual takes sort of an iterative
approach you know maybe having a having
a discussion amongst the people in the
company other than the person that is is
a bad actor and and that maybe only
later then having a discussion with them
and then being undecided as to whether
there's a way to remove that person from
the company because of these these kind
of iterative approaches and maybe even a
bit maybe a little bit too much of a
focus on what are the authorities going
to do if when they find out because of
that you can end up with a scenario
where it looks worse than it is or it
looks like maybe more people in the
company were involved in the bad acts
then then really then really it should
and really it needs to we have one
questions we have one question and then
we'll wrap it up let's hear it again for
the whole panel everybody I my name is
Roberto Robles I'm from Oregon I do
transportation policy and audit work and
what we found in the state of Oregon
after the Columbia River Crossing
debacle when we dropped the ball on
building a new bridge to Washington
because their data modeling systems were
inaccurate so I want to ask you guys to
put on your risk audit policy hats and
look at the Cannabis systems at the olcc
and are there gonna be any hidden
skeletons in data accuracy data
transitions for how we manage those data
systems because right now we could be
exporting our knowledge we can't export
flour but we can export our knowledge
and so I'm really concerned about the
state of Oregon's ability to manage
these databases well we do have experts
that are data analytic experts that look
at that sort of thing and figure out
where
data is going and what you've got there
but it's a very technical question and
probably not one we can answer fully at
this point I one of my colleagues from
emerges is is here that might be able to
speak to some specific specific issues
there so I'd be happy to introduce you
great thank you let's hear it again for
a lady Harry and the rest of the panel
that's FTI Consulting I'm sure they'd be
happy to talk with you bore outside the
halls and once again let's hear a name
[Applause]
[Music]