all right to leave the next panel on uh
policy reform and the industry he's the
founder of the international cannabis
business conference series he's been an
activist and a mover and a Shaker in the
Cannabis industry for 30 years at least
and he's here for us now uh and he lives
in Slovenia let's hear it for Alex
Rogers
thank you and let's give a big round of
applause for whom guy obilum the
wonderful MC ICBC
you know it can't be a totally boring
conference when hungayo is the MC so uh
and thank you again Peter really
appreciate you man
um so we're going to talk about public
reform in industry and I have some very
esteemed guests with me here to my right
is Gaspar fishkovich he's the chief
compliance officer for the Tallman group
and we have uh the deputy mayor of
lublana in the house Boston
uh Boston very uh very nice to have you
here man really appreciate it and we
have uh
radish radisha radish radish thank you
thank you and uh and bojadar is one of
the long time activists in Slovenia and
to tell you the truth we won't even be
here at this Gathering right now if it
wasn't uh for beauja down so let's give
our esteem panel members around
foreign
so there's a few different aspects of uh
policy reform and Industry industry when
it comes to Slovenia this is a a very
hot topic right now it's obviously why
we're here
um we're fortunate enough to have uh
analogous models to look for or look to
uh like Germany uh like Switzerland like
certain uh other countries in Europe
right now that are moving forward
obviously Germany's the big one
I want to start with you
um and just what's your take right now
on what's going on
in in Slovenia and uh what what what
how do you think we're what's the most
important thing things that you think we
need to do to move forward as one of the
uh if not the original uh granddaddy of
activist streets activist
um
yeah it's a Slovenian double entender
but uh
um but uh what's your opinion on the
matter uh right now in Slovenia
uh
as most of the world or Europe we still
have very confused uh and very old
legislation about everything so it's
hard to do any research uh back in 2000
we accepted the law about the
criminalization of use of any drugs
including cannabis but after this
actually got worse
so we are now
tried to
because
before the 2000 it wasn't really a
criminal offense it was just not
accepted but the society
but when we implemented that law then
actually it started the criminalization
of users so it's the same like in the
states your world until then it was okay
but unfortunately this criminalization
or destigmatization of cannabis went all
the way to research and the research was
never prohibited until the single
convention actually but for research you
need certain you know documentation for
Ministries and bureaucrats and so on and
you could not come true you heard the
story of Professor Neibauer about the
you know clinical study where he cannot
move forward for years and I really
think it's not okay so I think that we
should change the whole legislation on
the field of drugs not just cannabis
because we do much more harm to people
than they have benefit of it prohibition
being a failed policy in general in
Casper uh can you can you tell us what
are some of the the uh I guess statutory
hurdles one might say in terms of the UN
and the eu's perspective on this and
what are some
what are some hurdles that were that we
and other countries might be facing
right now in Europe when it comes to
modernizing cannabis policy
yeah uh so as already my colleague
explained uh it's it's really hard to
we generally speak like about
legalization but it's it's something
that's really hard to achieve because we
have the on the UN level we have the 61
and 71 and 88 convention which all
basically prohibits cannabis for all use
except for medical and research
of course we have the EU legislation
with the schenken agreement being the
the biggest one which also prohibits and
recalls to the U.N conventions uh then
of course every member State already
also has its own legislation which is a
bit different so there is no one
cannabis legislation in you in Europe or
in in the member states even though we
have two let's say legislative steps
above it
um the U.N and the and the in the
European legislation so it's
it's a bit confusing also for the for
the researchers at the end for the
consumers uh and I think it's not okay
so so what's this idea so what is okay
as far as I understand is doing for
research and medical purposes
uh Bojo could you explain a little bit
what that entails what that means yeah
if uh actually Slovenia already adopted
cannabis into
into drugs which are accessible to the
medical system back in 2017.
but except professional bar and maybe
one of two his colleagues you cannot
find a doctor who will prescribe
so and nowadays I think because of this
situation the patients are even in in
worse situation that was it was 10 years
ago and in a verse that it should be
because
with uh
the stigmatization of cannabis and with
the attitude of Ministry of Health or
better to say bureaucrats and minister
of Health doctors uh
do not dare to prescribe cannabis
because they can have problems so this
is a big mess I think it's all over the
world
and but I hope that Slovenia as many
other countries will follow German model
which is I think for the time being
best what we can achieve inside the
European Union and with I think
followers as usual I'd actually like to
talk about that in a little bit um
because there's what what are we going
to do uh what policy uh will we abide by
uh will we get behind to push in
Slovenia to modernize its cannabis
policy but there's also the big question
of how that's going to happen uh Boston
uh you you you know Politics as well as
anybody I reckon in this in this country
For Better or For Worse and uh you know
like like
how do we do it I think there's a lot of
you know up to this point we're hitting
certain walls and certain things you
know what are your some some of your
suggestions of how Dynamic we can be in
terms of uh getting this achieved
without knowing exactly what we want to
achieve but what's what's some what's
that process kind of look like
oh well thank you I'm glad to be here
um I don't know if I know Politics as
good as anyone I'm in politics for four
years now too much of course but
um law is always resembles of a resemble
of interests so it always depends what
the interest of the populations our
population are and what the interest of
the governing party or the uh government
is and usually you have some real events
that resemble in legislation or you have
legislation that imposes action to
people what I've heard now we have
people to use
marijuana or cannabis and we have
doctors that could but they don't
prescribe it so we have this double
problem uh even if you get knowledge out
that it can be useful we should use it
or can help in many aspects you always
have bureaucrats and bureaucrats are
made and that's something that's not
only for known for Slovenia a status quo
so we don't change anything we don't
take responsibility we can't be hurt or
punished or sanctioned and that's almost
this is almost a cultural thing it is it
is but it's not only
um in in Slovenia it's a general problem
so what we have to do is we have to get
knowledge out
um
conference like this is great
opportunity of course
following other people's examples if
Germany could do it
can do it we can too because we're in
the same
Union so I think that's the best
approach if
my personal opinion and I'm not here as
Deputy Mayor to be frank I was warned to
emphasize that
even though I can't even inhale to be
honest
um but um
what I think the good approach would be
my honest opinion if uh political party
would say we will decriminalize that or
we will make it really liberal that
would be a political suicide so what we
what has to be done in the backstage
they should agree on the positive
effects they should let's say stimulate
conferences like this and afterwards
come with a political legal solution
that would be my advice
yeah so and in the past in Slovenia it
hasn't uh been that way a lot of the uh
propositions coming from from uh the
activist Community have not necessarily
coalesced well with the the political
aspect of this would you say that's true
um by all means and not only in this
area everywhere if you don't get real
pressure from from the people from the
water voters then you have to have some
other incentive for the political
parties to get into the boat so I'm
curable what so what do you think that a
consensus would look like what is the
incentive for people to change this this
this ever so coveted status quo well if
I'm again honest money always money so
um you know I was in the right-wing
government even though I'm not uh right
political
uh let's say a lover but I always said
we had this covet
applications and my statement was we
give 10 euros to everyone they would
give all personal data for free I met
for free for 10 euros that's what we
always do in the stores We Gather points
you know loyalty points we give out our
personal data as if it's nothing but if
a government imposes that that's a
negative thing so if we give money to
the people we get direction the same is
here if you give money to the people and
people are also in the government
regular action yeah well I really
appreciate your candor uh yeah let's
give it up
we like to hear that
you know
I wasn't gonna say my question was
rhetorical but uh
uh it's awesome
um so now let's talk about a little bit
maybe what's Transylvania do bosia
you're talking about uh doing the the uh
following the German model
um gospel what what would you say that
is what do you think some of the best
aspects of the the German model are and
this is quite a poignant uh uh question
especially after Mr Holmberg just spoke
so yes so regarding the German model in
my honest opinion they're like first
pillar model
is is the wrong approach so their second
pillar which would be the pilot project
that is in my opinion the the better
option and it's uh it's credential the
same project Switzerland is taking
um and it's in accordance with the EU
regulations and the European regulations
because it falls under research
um so I think that would be the best
approach and we can we could then
research because nowadays the question
even still is is cannabis a bad drug is
it good is it bad how does it affect
people how does it affect absenteeism
traffic safety and so on and so on and
those are the things that really could
be tested so even to get some of the I'm
going to say false information out of
the way because there's a lot of it out
there
um for example I just heard one a couple
of days ago I was reading a report for
2022 and it said that the Road Traffic
Safety really decreased when a country
adopted cannabis so I said well
where can you check that and I said okay
so Netherlands should have like a really
bad traffic safety and the European
Union actually tracks the traffic safety
accidents uh and the statistics is that
Netherlands is about 40 percent better
than the Europe European average so
obviously it doesn't maybe a spurious
correlation yeah
what do you think I just want to add
this you know kind of the regulation of
cannabis is very popular I think in
Slovenia since last 15 years every
government before the election promised
big things you know there were different
law proposals
but when this party or this Coalition of
parties come to the power you know they
all forget it but we are also unlucky
maybe because we have frequent change of
governments you know not the whole
mandate so it's usually two years if
they are lucky three if they are very
lucky for
and in such a weak political system then
the bureaucrat says bhushan said are
leading the uh the dance you know and
I don't know we cannot solve problems
with the same people who who made them
so the first thing is to I think to
change those people who are in charge
for drugs and so for 30 years
I think we take from what Borgia just
said and whatan said before
I think it's the people who need to put
pressure on the politics and they can
also deal with the administrative uh or
the administrators and because I think
putting people like Professor Neibauer
or other people who are treating
patients real life patients with heavy
disease and telling them listen we have
this patient who we could help but we
cannot because of some bureaucracy this
is how we will apply pressure to the
politics and then things will change so
Boston do you agree with that yeah
absolutely because people can relate to
those sets stories and they don't see
you know junkies in metalcore they see
these people that need help uh so that's
most certainly the way the way to go but
I have to correct or add to the my
previous statement I wasn't talking
about corruption in bribes
don't mix that yeah I know I know I
thought about it later it's it's the
it's the economic incentive that's
important it's the same with Texas we
all know if we lower taxes if we had I
don't know 10 flat rate companies would
come Slovenia we all know that if I talk
to anyone left right they all agree but
it's not apocalistically good thing to
say or to go into the Parliament and say
look we will lower taxes because we will
have lower invoices our tax
um Authority but we will have more
invoices that's something we all agree
but we can't put it into the parliament
because it's not holistically okay to
take less money from the
from the reach at the end of all from
the old yeah and I definitely know what
you meant when you said that the
economic incentives that because that's
what happened in America that's how we
legalized in America I've been an
activist since 1993 when I met Jack Hare
and he he took me under his wing and I
started uh and I was a activist a
volunteer signature gatherer on the
Street and our narrative at that time
was pushing cannabis for a human rights
civil liberty issues we didn't push it
for for money or economic incentive back
then we were activists and we thought
well this is a plant and this is our
body and you shouldn't be locking people
up for years for this and that's that's
kind of where we were coming from from
for years until what and then what
happened was you had a lot of big
organizations come up after California
came in for medical
and just giving some context of how it
happened in America a little bit not
that that's the same analogy here but
there is crossover
um as we're legalizing in America
uh
up until the so there was before the
recession it was a human rights civil
liberties thing that's what we were
pushing we had big organizations like
MPP marijuana policy project and uh uh
drug policy Alliance and uh they were
they gave they started giving big money
to campaigns that were starting to do
state campaigns like you're in
California they could give you a million
dollars they had some billionaire
philanthropist whether it was Peter
Thiel or George Soros those are two of
the philanthropists behind those two
groups
um they they started giving money but
the but the narrative was still human
rights civil liberties it wasn't until
the recession in 207 208
that the really hit the fan uh in
America and around the world and we
really the the MPP the top activists
they took it they saw an opening now
we're going to push the economic
incentives of cannabis and that that's
going to be our number one thing because
it's political strategist you never want
too much messaging it'll get it'll get
convoluted it'll dilute itself so there
they started pinpointing on the economic
issues uh uh specifically and that
unfortunately it's still fortunately and
unfortunately it's still that people
sometimes tend to forget the human
rights aspect of of of cannabis and uh
just just individual liberty in general
however I agree completely because we
saw that's how that's what broke the
glass ceiling in America is like when
these municipalities and jurisdictions
needed extra Revenue they knew they
could easily get it by legalizing
cannabis and that was employed in the
strategy for legalizing cannabis let's
say in Colorado you say well well 10 of
this tax or more I don't know exactly
what it is it's arbitrary I don't know
it will go to the schools you know so
all of a sudden you have school we'll go
to the police so now you have police and
schools lobbying for uh for for your
Camp campaign and like I said it's not
the exact same comparison here but I
think that uh uh you know and I even
think the human rights aspect is still
okay to bring up in Europe because you
have this classic harm prevention
strategy over the years you're not
incarcerating people for personal use
generally in Europe whereas in America
traditionally in some of the Southern
more conservative States you can go to
jail with a joint there's people in
Louisiana right now who are rotting it
away in jail for for personal uh use
another country another uh States also
so I would uh agree that this is this is
about economics and uh and when you show
people when I say people I really mean
institutions uh the money they know they
can they know that it's it's a it's a
big party and they're and everybody's
included and one last thing I'll just
say
is uh there was a time also in America
and this is very different from politics
in uh in in Europe we have legal bribery
in America it's called lobbying
and it's the most corrupt way
to to deal with politics and uh and I've
done many I'm the first person ever to
do a bipartisan fundraiser as that I
know of in America with two Washington
congressmen uh Dana rohrbacher you were
there dog
the Jerry Garcia suite at the Hyatt in
San Francisco we did how apropos for all
those who know the Grateful Dead
um but but the first bipartisan
fundraiser right with uh Earl
blumenhauer the 40-year congressman for
uh hero from Portland and Dana rohrbach
or the Republican yet he was a
Libertarian Republican congressman who
was the is the hero of America he's I'm
not sure if there's any one politician
ironically enough he was Republican uh
that did more for you might have heard
of the rohrbacher uh blumenhauer
rohrbacher far amendment rohrbacher was
the one that if you couldn't change the
law he could reappropriate the funds
that were allocated to the law so
there's allocation and there's
appropriation right so it gets allocated
then it gets appropriated well they
stopped with the rohrbacher fire
Amendment they just said in a medical
marijuana states you cannot raid uh uh
uh you can't re but you can't use any
any law enforcement can't use any
resources for medical marijuana when
it's clear state law so they'd have to
be real criminals going against other
Rico stuff like embezzlement and and
whatnot so it's a slight digression but
the point is is I was there when the
politicians wouldn't want to touch it
only a few people like rohrbacher and
blumenhauer were down and so we started
this cannabis constituency and this
whole lobbying movement and then next
thing you know I'm raising fifty
thousand dollars for the governor of
California
this happened right away like over two
year period would you say uncle like it
was like they wouldn't touch it the
politicians didn't want anything to do
it and next thing you know we're doing
funder we're doing fundraisers you know
and shaking hands and wanting to take
showers afterwards you know sleeping
Sleeping with the Enemy right now that
being said I don't think Slovenian
politics are the same I think I think
Bojo I would ask you or or gosh did you
have something to say on that guess I
just wanted to add that
in contrary to U.S thinking especially
in Slovenia we also have to tackle
beside the politics aspect also the
public image of cannabis and we need to
work on improving that because I think
it's it's still a lot of people like
Western mentioned are still considered
cannabis like this bad illicit drug that
is being smoked on the corners you know
by by people they don't consider it that
it's actually
a medicine gonna use that word that it
helps a lot of people or a lot a lot of
really sick people and to improve the of
the image of cannabis to get a PR
representative for cannabis to to
improve the image in Slovenia and that I
think is the first step uh besides the
politic aspect yeah and I think that's
part of the political aspect because
that's like the politicians don't want
to touch it and the next thing you know
you're doing big fundraisers for
congressmen and senators and governors
and you're like it feels like a little
Allison a little bit Alice in Wonderland
but the cool thing is I've seen this
happen in three different jurisdictions
California Oregon and now what would be
done in in Germany
um by getting people together and and
forwarding the industry and I know that
that's happening in uh Slovenia now but
but Bozo what it so so you say there's
the obstacles within the the uh the
bureaucracy uh the long time
administrators is there what Ministry do
you think is what Ministry can help the
most what Ministries will be involved
when legalization does happen or
normalization and and what Ministry
could you name it is holding us back the
most right now uh yes the the most
problematic Ministry on on this part is
Minister of Health
uh but we are very unique because uh you
can grow cannabis for uh for food for
fiber and so on and I don't know why
they have jurisdiction
on the you know the the Cannabis why it
could be agricultural or of course I
don't even never uh understood why we
have any law about uh industrial hemp
and those things because uh hemp for
production of seed and fiber is is
excluded of a single one Convention of
61. so it's not part of it but still
bureaucrats of
somehow succeed to complicated
you know but I think that key is
now it's uh you know put together all
the industry and science but when I
started to
almost 20 years ago I already realized
that actually the education is the thing
where we have to move forward
so we started to
organized the
seminaries you know scientifical
conferences back in 2014.
uh but whenever we have anything to do
you know with medical chamber or
Ministry of Health
they do they have done everything to
stop us
you know on this or other ways so
but I still strongly believe in this if
we want to change narratives towards
cannabis we're still organizing
seminaries for doctors nurses
and I often joke that we have to educate
also journalists because you know most
of the journalists until now or when
they where they seek the information is
Ministry of Health National Institute of
Public Health
but there are people whom I would not
trust at all you know on their you know
that we in Slovenia where we have
already treat that because of cannabis
and it's uh generally known that nobody
died ever of cannabis but still National
Institute of Public Health that three
deaths and when you go you know it's it
it's a bad light for a cannabis and
everything so again we have to
to
get rid of those bureaucrats who are
really there for 30 years and they stop
every move back in 2016 where Parliament
accepted the decision that they should
Ministry of Health prepare all legal uh
you know
basis to introduce cannabis to Medical
system today's
2023 so it's seven years and nothing
happened
Boston what do you think about that how
are we why don't you just tell us how
we're going to get it all done now
Boston
well one of my first meetings to the
ministry
I told them we need
let's say a state
electronic inboxes and I was told it can
be done and I said there's a
one-man band who did it 10 years ago in
the private sector how is it not
possible and the answer was look
Minister ministers change we stay
that was the answer so uh if I I
understand bonjour we should change the
bureaucrats but it's not possible we
should just be
that the policy should be strict should
I know put out the legislative proposal
and execute it that that's it so and the
same bureaucrats will do it but just you
have to give power to the people above
them so that they have the authority do
you have any hope that the bureaucrats
would would change that we could that
that's
the realism is deceiving palpable
um yeah well that's I that's good and so
if you can't beat them kind of join them
you got to coalesce is that kind of make
it make incentivize everyone to make
this a win-win for everyone yeah that's
that's real or just present them you
know with with everything sort of they
just need to sign off you know present
them with a I don't know a draft Bill
present them with the studies and
everything because I think a lot of them
are probably going to agree well just
lazy so don't don't have to do anything
and it's this has been so about this for
so long and so long and why change
something but the knives are coming out
I have to I have to emphasize they're
not lazy it's a bureaucratic state of
mind if I change something I take a risk
I take a risk I'm responsible because no
higher ranked public officer will take
responsibility for the lower one it's
not in our culture and that's the
problem so if they have strict rules
they follow it but imagine every time
you get to the administrative unit
there's a line a person goes
bio and gets in front of you are you
happy you know are you happy with the
bureaucrat who let him or her in no even
though they have a let's say a life
reason why that person should be in
front of you you don't accept it you
personally don't accept it because you
have rules and rules should be followed
and bureaucrats learned that they were
so often criticized for doing reasonable
things against some general rule they
just follow the general rules now and
it's something that we impose to the
bureaucrats and now we suffer from that
same consequence that's absolutely uh
fascinating and yeah gosh we're going
back to what you said about uh uh what
can we take from Germany I agree I think
the best model that we have right now to
push forward in Slovenia is the pilot
project model and uh I think the fact
that Slovenia has a rich history of
research and development with a lot of
things you guys are a very smart
Innovative country and I think that is
uh slovenia's biggest exit court right
now is research and development and
intellectual property and I'm just
really glad to be here on this ride with
all you guys you beautiful gentleman up
here thank you so much for this great
panel can you give some Applause for
these guys
thanks guys so much
[Music]
I will open it up to questions right now
if anyone has any questions for our
esteem panel members uh please shoot
yes thank you very much it was indeed
very interesting but uh what were my
thoughts listening to why we still don't
have all these issues sorted out with
cannabis my question for you was then
okay but how do you evaluate the role of
pharmacies in this big picture are they
our allies
are they making it more difficult
because they see it's kind of a
competition with them if you grow our
own medicine in our backyards so what
are your thoughts on this
thank you
as far as I know no pharmacies have any
problem to reduce cannabis into their
you know but they just have to have
first chance it's strict rules
maybe Pharmacists and Pharmacy faculty
is even further than Medical Faculty
and they are more open than medical
sphere of of the same system actually so
I don't see any problems but we have so
confused
legislation and you know uh
23 years yes since we adopted this Drug
law and still we don't have any how you
say Arctic
you know those
lower acts so it's 23 years actually the
law should not be functional if I know
well but they do it so
uh we have to bring orders as soon as
possible there are
uh some tries for years but you know to
change medical system it's not easy and
introducing the Cannabis into a medical
system is a big change for them and
I I would I would say that you have to
distinguish producers and sellers
producers can see you as a competition
sellers never they sell and if the
margin is higher the register sell your
product than the other people so and
regarding home grow uh I think we saw in
Canada when we had companies like tilray
who were lobbying against the home grow
because they thought it would deplete
their their revenue or people wouldn't
go to the dispensaries then we actually
find that that's the app that we
actually find that's the opposite though
that's not whether you however you feel
about home grow it just because someone
can grow a few plants in their house it
doesn't actually mean that dispensaries
in the area will will do less it has
means that they could actually do more
Revenue because the market is so primed
you know you can only grow one or two
strains but you go to the dispensary and
it's you know and where I'm from and
it's like a kid in a candy store and I'm
that kid and it's like
and it's like well I can't make shatter
or I can't you know I can't do that I
don't make dabs I can't make this pill
with perfectly five milligrams THC and
0.05 you know it just once the market
gets Advanced the home growth just
becomes a novelty it's like hey look at
my couple plants I I can save a little
bit of money you know or I could trade
it for something else whatever it is
that's how it happens in Oregon you can
grow plants and plants and plants in
Oregon but I don't know how many
billions of dollars we did Justin in
Oregon in Revenue uh this year so I just
like to make that point about homegrown
so we can still keep to the human rights
uh civil liberties aspect we have
another question
thank you
you got a question God nobody's got a
question yes my question is what time
will the shuttle be here
Shawna will be here for the party that
big shuttle those darn shuttles um
everybody wants to go to a community
yeah okay magnifico's tonight at the
castle it's gonna be I don't know how
we're gonna stand it here it's so
amazing
um so it's eight eight uh 8 45 8 45 the
shuttle the shuttle goes and and don't
forget to tip your waiter and donate
what advice would you all give people so
people want to be politically involved
you know people want legalization in
Slovenia what all can they do they could
vote they can threaten I mean uh discuss
with their politicians what what else
what do you need big festivals or
rallies or protests like what is the
most effective way here in Slovenia
I believe that conference is like this
like giving knowledge to the people the
professionals and also the the general
public
um the the news gets out that people
know about it uh and I think step by
step this is gonna gonna get better uh
we don't have the processes in America
with the pressure on your representative
and so on uh so yeah just getting the
knowledge out to the people and that's
how it's only gonna get better
just
yes
I just wonder why you're saying a
homegirl for against a company in Israel
we have a only only company that is
providing a cannabis to the pharmacies
and this is only the way their patients
could buy the Cannabis but in Canada
they allowed to whole grow grown whole
but very few patients are really did it
a majority of the urban population has
is looking for a product already had
been made and available on the shelves
in these different strains in Israel we
are now trying to to convince our
partner that I'm a advisor of Israel
Israeli Committee of parliament for
cannabis regulation to permit to to have
a home grow with a good quality will be
assessed and and the company could could
Supply cannabis for the patients
together business Pharmacy so Pharmacy
should not concurrent with a company who
should be a supplier because before
reform we had only companies apply
directly to the patients and now they
could bring it to the only to the
pharmacy Pharmacy has a margin about 30
percent this is a large amount of money
coming to the pharmacies and the
patients have a very
huge difficulty so the the we do not
have a optimal system of regulation in
the world there is no optimal system but
I I but we need to have a a computation
corporate system that permits people to
buy it from the supplier from the grower
and from the pharmacy by their own chase
this is a human rights thank you yeah so
that wasn't a question that was a
statement but it was something that I
basically thought I kind of already said
when I talk about this home girl I
believe it's a human right also to have
to grow cannabis to grow any plant to
grow mushrooms if you have if you really
will okay I don't I think whatever God
gave us to grow in our backyards we
should be able uh to grow but one step
at a time my lawyer's freaking out right
now he's like no no don't say Mushrooms
but uh uh these are all healing plants
we have to give back to a spiritual our
spiritual intelligence a lot of people
don't talk about what spiritual
intelligence is we know about academic
intelligence social intelligence but we
really have to get back to a spiritual
intelligence where we have just more
feeling and empathy in community in
general and come from the bottom up and
not the top downs and if I just want to
I want to talk
[Music]
I just want to add to Ilya I just don't
want to mix the medical sector and
public health sector and personal use
and human rights
I always say if on any field it is you
know now very popular my body my choice
so it should be also on the field of
cannabis yeah I agree that we also had
in our session on science so to divide
to have different laws for recreational
and for medical and uh I would just like
to add to uh
of what shall we do in Slovenia now I
think that uh as we heard at the opening
our president of the government and our
Coalition now is willing uh ready to do
something about it and it's a moment
that also all we just try to go directly
to the government to the representative
of the government and demand that and
what to also organize such a meetings
with within Slovenia within our
politicians like you know let's say the
city the city government the the mayor
of Ljubljana and so on and to to move
this idea forward and what the
politicians wants in the Civil Society
and here we have for example the
association of oncological patients in
their the director here so we have also
uh Europa Donna so the patience of
breast with breast cancer and they
should push along with us to the idea
and carried out to politicians so to
transfer let's do it tomorrow let's do
it okay let's do it I'm ready I love it
do we have time for one more is it
that's it we gotta go I'm sorry I'm so
sorry we're out of time
yeah it's 2 45. I know you we run a
tight ship you would think you were from
Germany
everybody
[Music]
[Applause]
I'd like to remind you all that the
shuttle bus leaves at 8 45.
for the castle
from in front of the hotel
and wear your paths bring your pass