hello and good afternoon it's lovely to
see you and it's a great privilege to
host a conversation at ICC I have a lot
of respect for Alex Rogers and I think
this is one of the best cannabis
conferences that happens which is why we
have made an effort to come from Canada
to come and be here today so whenever
I'm asked to host a panel I find that
it's an opportunity for me to learn
about something that I don't know about
and I seek out experts who have the
knowledge that I don't have to study the
subject and then to come and share with
you so I didn't really understand the
complicated nuances of the German
landscape for positive for physicians
and patients and I wanted to understand
it also with global lens on what the
experience is for both physicians and
patients and these are the experts that
have been teaching me and now we're
going to share with you what our
conversations have been so I would love
to first introduce to you mr. Burkhardt
Leonard on the far end here yeah I am
learning that he is a bit of a hero in
these realms in terms of regulatory
reform so mr. Bernard was a member of
the German parliament until 2017 he's a
member of the Social Democratic Party
and he was responsible for the budget of
the Federal Ministry of Health and the
drug policy spokesperson for the Social
Democratic Party but he played a
decisive role in shaping Germany's drug
policy for the past four years during
his time in the in the Parliament mr.
bleonard was instrumental in the
development of Germany's law on medical
cannabis one of the main objectives he
had was to give patients access to
cost-free
medical cannabis and he is directly
responsible for making germany's medical
cannabis legislation more patient
friendly and less bureaucratic in
several key ways right before it was
passed which we will discuss
on my right is dr. mark where dear
friend and colleague dr. ware has spent
over 20 years researching uses of
medical cannabis and teaching other
physicians how to integrate cannabis
into their clinical practice
he is canopy growths chief medical
officer and is responsible for the
company's clinical research arm canopy
health innovations and spectrum cannabis
he is an associate professor of FEM in
family medicine at McGill University and
continues to practice pain medicine at
the McGill University Health Centre he's
also acted as a key adviser on medical
cannabis policy to the Canadian
government in 2001 and he is recognized
globally as a leader in medical cannabis
research he flew all last night to get
here mark has been travelling and
working a lot around the world with
governments and physicians lately and
were very lucky for him to have made the
effort to come and be here with us today
thank you and to my left is dr.
Sebastian Schulz who's the director of
communications and marketing for
spectrum cannabis in Germany his
research is focused on the philosophy of
neuro cognition with a special focus on
the psychotropic effects of cannabis
he's published many articles and three
books regarding his research and he has
been working intimately with the medical
cannabis market since it began in
Germany so I'm curious to know how many
of you live in Germany okay and how many
of you are from other parts of Europe
okay how many from North America aha and
do we have anybody from Asia in the room
oh hello Asia I have to reach you and
did anybody make it all the way from
Africa no okay how many of you are from
a country that has some kind of medical
cannabis legislation okay I hope next
year that we see more hands in the room
and
let's see where the ladies are how many
women do we have in the room all right
excellent thank you and do we have any
physicians in the room a wonderful
lovely to have you and is there anybody
in the room who has been working with
patients in Germany helping them to
navigate the process here do we have any
patient advocates in the room no okay
ah wonderful I would love to speak with
you afterwards please yeah
always a real passion for talking to the
people that are helping patients to
navigate the process so things are
changing rapidly in terms of reform
around medical cannabis around the world
and in Germany and I always believe that
it's really important to take a look
back and to have an understanding of
where we came from as we're looking
forward into our future so we are going
to start with a little bit of a history
lesson about how we got to where we are
in Germany so mister bleonard would you
tell us a little bit about how medical
cannabis became legal in Germany tell us
a bit about the catalyst and what the
process was like if you and uncle d-frag
of each team up with katya in latin and
water yet Suzanne hasn't been assured to
see it's in what is in translate and
Watson listened but it needs of listens
English pleasure the Serie 15 Verdun and
there's a 51 Venetia of torch of balaam
can be the shifting business
the Misses in BB geographies and all in
Villa Medici know it's been Kanye West
in politically since Schaffner and in
photos and Watson Madame team confront
yet one on which identify set in the
image cannabis medicinal cannabis want a
argument wrong politics to tune on
familiar and relative Chanel claw
unleash the sympathize this medicine and
that's endorsement English yet sent a
unit along a song lips just long ago
shifted a madam the end wanaka botanist
when the
in these are links to power you idiot
before stunt so I thought into heights
in this fight or zips on the shanks are
bending Wars and slips a tune name is
Angus Edson Mahan as I said Mowgli even
vida cannabis in the minutes in
uncertain as much village in aguas and
quality on through the insider here in
Mohave ami are under see the USPD we get
bonus lee yong-gu photo bonus agree on
two thousand rights and Chonga hopped
off and i'm child ever given countless
volcanic Lasseter on in Den Bosch HD for
support minute exits a diminished
because Etsy didn't patent demolished a
menorah that side málaga clark tom
valley gana just vitae a fan word mercy
of our clashes your anger van tom and
that's up the austin imagine a moon rock
garden or had mitigation HD you know
diesel percent know hunter struts um
happen without the skies ethnic much as
you wish to harm the politics aside
inaudible cassettes nam liftin dingus on
tats minister the English the Honda
Suzuki fatigue on our let endless vast
assistant in the Alex the to power your
Kumar Tom let sanity and sports bar and
leash task reached a lob Tom the Santosh
non thanks why passion Zahra cannabis
unborn love noon on the icon bar for an
child
in the beginning it was forces if you
were hope need foster incontinent does
the son may a lot if you light a game
would the indium gettin in
often but Conan cannabis unborn often
they suffer dad walked and dying jetsam
Mahan on stunts in scientists in vicar
gang visits endorsed non done
automatically Arden his good iron
referenda involve escape longer the
button and her own vision shaft leisure
book light song and let's understand
quasi the NAFTA and Shia dog was son
certainly isn't on any bonus song muster
on be softened Epson Takahama danfa suit
and the Hong Kong so that's a few when
that such function yet though
for Androids duska said Saturn wound up
what centigrade Suleiman and Bundestag
advised that's how angry zetsu cannabis
rain in Deutschland that's it Shawn it
was at least all just given us a darkish
after it's why our way and cuffed when
what is SR pull the zoo Mohandas
Cosette's so it's kind of for ahsha and
wash I give up chick man dimension yeah
I'm not eating for him interviews no I'm
that's why yarn Humvees the missing the
specimen reform even above ahamill
status across a orange of mine
Guzman afar Wong at Salem Aveda Guyana
degree shifted at SU yes cucumbers by
Shawn marketers feel feel under than a
moment on a door Shan Shan the happiest
Marx was Cindy for China the year exist
even on the scope cope fundamentalist
the I scoot exactly top ones in land
homes at Scone if he knows inform guten
week we Nixon's in Denver is the ocean
of marvelous vida my god sedan fuel
entities given it he owned and
embolizing he invent area that kinda
feel is mayor foster an hour and my
right that says li-fi is airfield
systemic or even also have Deutschland
in the finish Alice gets good does it
entire that's about our encounter thank
you so much and also in the final hours
before the proposed law became
legislation you fought very hard in the
last hours for a couple of very
important changes for patients and thank
you for that
Sebastian you have been navigating the
medical framework in Germany since it
became law two years ago with a
particular awareness of the patient
experience and I'm wondering if you can
speak to us about some of the unique
acts aspects of the German medical
cannabis landscape yeah it's very
important for me to start with the
perspective of the patients because I
agree very much with work our bleonard
that this law is a huge leap for this
for this country and for a lot of
patients we've we are now seeing we're
all sitting here so it enabled a lot of
patients to get access and it's when I
hear about the details of what you told
me it's it's an amazing process and I
really can value much more when I hear
about the details of how it came to that
law how much you move there for the
patients though in the last two years
it's been a very painful experience and
to get access to cannabis this was
because I give you only a few aspects of
that process the thousand patients who
had managed to get special licenses
before the law was came to place it was
we had like around a thousand patients
who got special permits these were not
just renewed so they had to go run
through the system again and some of
them didn't get their medication and
didn't get approved by doctors so that
was that was really painful for them the
other patients who were then able to
access a cannabis were bounced back from
their doctors many of them were rejected
because the doctors of course they
didn't know the new law they do know how
to prescribe some of them just wanted to
know how do I do this
you know what's the DOE saying what's
out there so in the beginning it was
really hard for them to get to their
medication the prices went up for
cannabis we're going to talk about the
reasons later a lot of the patient's
only received private prescriptions so
you could say a price is why would that
matter to the German patients they get
reimbursed no they didn't in the
beginning only thirty percent of the
applications went through the insurances
were slow to understand the new law
probably and they rejected a lot of the
applications so for for many patients
that was very frustrating and then of
course we heard it before supply was a
big deal we all the LPS coming in here
everybody who'd distributed cannabis had
we all had supply issues the market
exploded and so is some really we were
able to give
medication to a lot of people to give
medical cannabis to a lot more patients
but it was not easy to give give it to
them consistently and having having it
all avaible everybody available so I
think it's really important to have that
patient perspective and to understand
the German market because it also it
shows you how much frustration was there
how much criticism was there and there
there definitely need to be some
improvements can you tell me about two
things I would love to hear more about
regress and also your ability to
communicate with and educate and support
patients in Germany yeah I would like to
talk generally a little bit more about
the regulations so in Germany and then I
will pick up the requesting yeah so in
Germany every doctor except for dentists
and veterinarians is allowed to
prescribe cannabis it's effectively a no
label substance so it is classified as
an ingredient to a medication which
gives it that status a problem with that
is that pharmacists then have to make an
identity test and put a hundred percent
price margin on the product which makes
cannabis exceedingly expensive in the
international comparison here so it's
like 22 euros a gram or something around
that approximately depending on how it's
handled the other thing with so it's
it's a no label drug it can be
reimbursed and basically the law states
that it has to be reimbursed except for
exceptional cases where the medical
services of the insurance say no that's
not a case where we reimburse so that is
a very special situation the regressed
situation that you were talking about is
one where doctors we heard that a lot
from doctors they were afraid to
prescribe I mean many doctors didn't
want to prescribe for reimbursement
because they were like ooh we have to go
through they also have to go through a
non interventional forum where they have
to make observations about patients so
they have paperwork to do
and it's a difficult process to go
through the application and they were
afraid then also we heard that a lot
from doctors that they would get a
regress problem that would mean that the
doctors actually for their patients they
get the applications to for them to get
reimbursed but later the insurances
would have the ability to come back to
them after a year or so and to evaluate
the prescription patterns and say hey
you're prescribing a very expensive
medicine so maybe we're taking away the
money from you that you've that you've
taken out of the health system so a lot
of doctors we haven't seen that
happening yet but in the beginning that
was a big factor for doctors where they
were like whoops we are not gonna do
that so that blew me away when I learned
that that if if the insurance agencies
assess that a doctor is over prescribing
cannabis and is taxing the insurance
system too much they can go back and
personally take that money out of a
physician's bank account that's a pretty
serious deterrent you have a comment
please go ahead phalanx and the problem
it should have severe moment at said if
you harm is really nobody intention as
gazettes give us a lead again vascular
lab city Thomas was - if any savvy
16-point is just ipad center since the
ostia appeared sign must at some bogus
tuition as before I didn't does this
investigar boomed in the earth Gaga or
that said he had a MMD car and a song
son heber July stand off the enemy won't
and don't have such passion orange
relish voted on AIM de Kostner statin
boutique is that Sophia's a human
version of and backfire as this finish
and sophistication
boom to be wrong is that some that at
least as a niche embedding study I
understand come get in there terapy
thigh-high disasters yes Messiah percent
I lived in Lyons Waco shutting ham
before than cannabis Saturday in Europe
account in Russia vision indicate zone
the slightest the stir in Dakar
antipathy nine songs also on an
authority the Hindu monks confident MD
car
it was Absalom and we heard that is
investiga pond the infield naturalistic
evidence under study notes and
art of a nakatsu no visitors I'm comin
r14 a resort a snitched imposition fired
by he build and Merkley schmuck tiendas
errors in applying contours in the card
as volition each dollar emblica
endogenous teller in a palliative
medicine piranha extreme quotes again
Amy induced an MD car after satisfying
accomplices lowest under the gutter
point in them father
M not a therapy fight not their niche
hasta appear tied aim of the pond in a
palliative more Krishna answers that in
the medium D person who had guns now in
infertile
aunty Holcomb that's kind of Assad argue
that interns even discuss fear was thank
you do you have yeah just a comment and
that these are extremely valuable points
and I now seeing the German mark how it
unfolded I can see how much of an effect
of a positive effect those last changes
you made you just mentioned had I just
don't want to mention two things so what
I said the no label situation is of
course if you look at mushy lumps or
elephants coulombs talk professor
rothman shuang's talk it's great because
a doctor here is not bound to
indications so and we know that there's
such a huge wide spectrum of illnesses
and indications where cannabis can help
but if you want to understand the
dynamics of the German market then you
have to see this there is this wide
range where you can prescribe the
insurances have to cover and now the
insurances came back in the last year's
to say oh wait the evidence situation
for some of those indications is not
really really there so that this is you
you understand the dynamics of the
German market really well if you see
that no label situation and
reimbursement and and we will circle
back around to talking more about
evidence thank you both of you
doctor where you have been teaching
about the use of medical cannabis in
clinical practice for decades and I know
that you have been working in many
regions around the world recently as
countries are evolving there
framework around medical cannabis and
I'm wondering if you can speak a little
bit about the physician experience sort
of the worldwide physician experience
and how it may differ from what's
happening in Germany Thank You Hillary
I think probably instead of contrasting
it with what's happening in Germany it's
important to say that around the world
the one of the single biggest challenges
to the adoption of medical cannabis as a
therapy is the fact that physicians are
the ones who have to write the
prescription or the authorization they
are the gatekeepers to this therapy
rightly or wrongly in some jurisdictions
nurse practitioners have this ability in
others there are other health
professionals who can do this but by and
large around the world it is a health is
health care professional or physician
who has the responsibility to decide
whether this is an appropriate therapy
for their patient based on the guidance
that they receive from their government
based on their regulations but the vast
majority of physicians have no idea
what cannabis is how it works what the
endocannabinoid system is they are
remarkably uneducated and that's a
phenomenal barrier the challenge to
educating physicians to putting
endocannabinoid physiology in medical
schools in teaching practitioners about
using cannabis is there's no government
incentive for government to do this the
medical schools aren't stepping up and
putting this into their curricula it's
falling on the industry to provide this
education and that creates another
problem because the industry is the
cannabis industry is coming on the back
of a long history of pharmaceutical
companies having behaved rather badly
when it comes to teaching physicians
about their medicines taking them for
expensive holidays and paying their
wives to come on their trips with them
and taking them for fancy dinners and
spending money on these physicians
knowing full well that that kind of
behavior would influence their
prescribing practices this is now being
regulated against and we're hearing
stories of big pharma companies being
punished and being being fined and in
some cases even being taken to court for
some of the practices they've done with
respect to physician education so how is
the industry supposed to respond to
educating the people who are supposed to
beep riding as medicine that's a
phenomenal problem its global and I
think it requires a really interesting
the role of the nonprofit networks the
role of the patient advocacy
organizations somehow building an arm's
length between the industry and the
doctor so that the education gets where
it needs to go
but isn't seen as an incentive or a
payment to the physician to prescribe
there's some really dodgy practices
happening out there
and I think we have to be very careful
that in the name of educating physicians
we aren't committing the same crimes
that our predecessors than the pharma
industry have have committed thank you
so Sebastian is talking about the hunger
for more clinical research I mean that's
true in Germany and I think it's true
you know in many places around the world
in Canada we have approximately 1% of
our population is registered legal
medical cannabis users and if that was
the ratio was the same in Germany that
would mean that we would have almost
800,000 people in Germany and we're
currently at 40,000 people in Germany
approximately that are using the legal
system so I'm wondering if you can talk
a little bit about the acceleration of
research that's happening around the
world and what you see that's coming on
the horizon that is going to fill some
of these needs sure so it's coupled with
the physician education because when you
speak to and I speak to roomfuls like
this but they're all physicians I mean I
think there are two doctors in here we
need a lot more meetings where the room
is filled with physicians and not as
much business guys I no disrespect
intended but those are the people we
have to be speaking to but they will
always stand up and say well there isn't
enough evidence where's the data where
are the clinical trials where is the
proof that it works I heard a panelist
earlier just saying you know it works we
know it works you know it works okay but
the doctors don't think it works they
aren't being given the data in the same
way so we need to design ways to get
evidence to them which will then help
them make these decisions so the
education is one part but supplying the
evidence is the other there are sort of
two main ways of doing this one is
through the standard randomized control
trial and that's a double-blind
an experiment where people are put on
either the drug or placebo and it really
is considered as the gold standard of
therapy but these studies require very
very tightly controlled products for one
thing and they require a lot of time and
a lot of expertise and to invest in the
kind of data to get drugs into the
clinical trial and into the pipeline
where they're approved as medicines
costs tens if not hundreds of millions
of dollars to get there so there has to
be an investment in that and I think I
predict that in 1020 years we will see
far more cannabinoid medicines approved
as therapies and that's going to change
the story completely but it's going to
take a long time to get there
the other thing we can do is actually
provide patients with access to cannabis
products and track their real world
experience and this idea of real world
evidence is actually being now reviewed
by regulators as a significant way of
evaluating the effectiveness of drugs
and and while other medicine not just
cannabis but other drugs as well and
there's - and make concepts here one is
efficacy the clinical trial will tell
you if the drug is efficacious or not
but doesn't tell you if it's effective
effective is a real-world situation is
it working for patients at large and
vast majority people using cannabis are
not clinical trial subjects they are
people with other problems other
diseases taking other medications who
party wouldn't fit into the standard
clinical trial so following these
patients as real-world evidence studies
open-label studies this is the second
arm of research that I think we can do
and this satisfies two major problems
one is getting patients access to the
products and getting data to help inform
physicians in future educational
programs so I think that's the approach
we need to take in terms of developing
evidence thank you
canopy has undertaken supporting quite a
lot of research and there's two
particular projects that I'm wondering
if you would share with us about one is
I'm wondering if you can talk about the
professorship at the University of
British Columbia and the clinical
science that's happening there and
second I'm wondering if you can talk a
little bit about the research in the
long-term care facilities Thank You
Hilary so sure I'll touch quickly on
these two major issues
Canada and they're not the only ones but
they're they're very sort of front and
center in the discussion one is the use
of cannabis to help reduce the the
opioid abuse epidemic the opioid
overdose crisis whatever you choose to
call it it's a massive problem in North
America thousands of people are dying
every month and it's really a crisis of
epic proportions there's a potential
that cannot cannabis and cannabinoid
medicines may assist in in changing the
direction of this epidemic
professor MJ Molloy and his colleagues
at the University of British Columbia
received a grant from canopy from the
University of British Columbian from the
government of BC very much led by
Hilary's leadership I should add that
this this gift to dr. Miller's team is
enabling him to spend two and a half
million dollars on evaluating whether
cannabis can be helpful in helping
people wean off intravenous street drugs
crack cocaine methamphetamines opioids
you name it there's a potential there
and this is happening at the street
level where they're going into the
communities most affected and helping
administer this needs support this kind
of humanitarian crisis needs this kind
of intervention so we're very proud to
support that the other big issue is the
nursing homes where people with agitated
dementia as people in elderly care
long-term care facilities are being
asked or their loved ones are
approaching the this the units the
centers if they can put their
grandparents their parents their loved
ones on cannabis because they think it
helps them reduce the dementia and the
agitation help them sleep and these are
also people who are taking pretty strong
antipsychotics at benzos opioids to
control them and help them sleep at
night there's good anecdotal evidence
that this is helping but we're proposing
to follow these people by administering
properly cannabinoid therapies and then
tracking over time in a real-world
manner what is the experience what are
the medication use patterns profiles
changing and this study is ongoing at
the moment so two very different
populations but by taking compassionate
approaches we can provide medicines to
people but also track what happens in
the real world thank you can't be
actually
canapé actually developed a new
administration form in order to be able
to work with long-term care facilities
we created soft gels which is
essentially little capsules because the
folks administering medicines in
long-term care facilities didn't want to
deal with inhalation or oil the medicine
needed to be stored and administered in
the same way as all of their other
medications where which drove some
innovation on our end which is very
exciting thank you so we hope that there
we can see that there is evidence on the
horizon that's coming to continue to
give clinicians the you know what they
need to lean on to feel more comfortable
using cannabis in their practice but
there are some other factors that are
potentially going to be accelerants in
the landscape in Germany that are coming
up can you speak to that please yeah for
sure
first of all of course we're expecting
the supply situation to get a lot better
in the near future of course because we
have to deliver GMP products it's not
and I see that a lot from patients we
have very limited abilities to talk to
patients because of the German
advertising laws we basically are
restricted to talking to pharmacists and
to doctors healthcare practitioners but
it's what what they don't see is that
GMP facilities have to build up first
that we have to construct them that is a
very complicated super high-tech process
we have a facility now in Odense and
Denmark that's gonna deliver a lot to
the market and others are building up so
so the supply situation not only in in
terms of quantity but also in terms of
having various firmly having various
varieties of cannabis internet flowers
but also extracts and other products and
that will completely change the market
of course a second thing is that we see
the insurances approval rates going up
and I think I would like to add
something to what Mark said real-world
evidence what in a situation were the
insurances have to cover no label
substance so to say and they are like
well we're covering now costs for
somebody who has fibromyalgia and we
don't see really the evidence out there
we will have to introduce also
socio-economic data I mean showing in
the country that cannabis can save costs
and we see that already from the
Canadian market and from the US market
that in many places for years and years
the Co medication went down we have
Studies on that and so we can show for
those places that yes patients who are
using cannabis are using less other
substances and are less costly for the
system so that's gonna be very important
for the German system what we have done
also if we compare the Canadian and the
German market we have to always remember
and this is one of the most important
point points and I keep on telling
people like a mantra the Canadian market
started 15 years ago or longer in 2001
and so we can use all the experience and
the world so the recognition of cannabis
as a medicine is a completely different
stage now worldwide and we profit from
that we brought in dark Canadian doctors
here to teach German doctors about their
experience really on a very how to do
level and that helped us a lot and
there's gonna be other not only clinical
and other evidence coming in but a
socio-economic data will be generated
here so there are a lot of factors that
will even accelerate a market where we
already have seen an explosion of
patient numbers just let me add one last
comment about the number of 40,000 that
was published by the handles blood last
year data health related data in Germany
are very sensitive so these are really
rough estimates we really can't extract
exact numbers from those data because
mainly also because many a doctor's
private prescriptions and we can't
really track them so we don't know if
like 50 60 80 % of the prescriptions
that are being done here are private and
we cannot really track those
thank you so mark some of the growing
pains that Germany is going through
around the medical cannabis landscape
seem to echo some of the things that we
experienced in Canada and now in you
know Canada with almost 400,000 licensed
legal patients we've seen an incredible
increase in the past couple of years and
I'm wondering if you can speak to the
factors that you think really stabilized
and encouraged more physicians to start
using cannabis in their practice why did
we see such a big uptake in the last few
years I think a couple of things
probably happened there was there's if
you look at the trajectory of Canadian
cannabis patients over 20 years it began
very very slowly and the trajectory
really only began to pick up in the last
five to ten years and it happened at the
same time as there were changes in the
regulatory framework which allowed for
there was a time in Canada when you only
had one producer there was only one type
of cannabis for a while it was
restricted to 5% John Connor a party
remembers these days very well one kind
of cannabis grown in underground mines
in Flin Flon Manitoba I mean this was a
limiting factor to just adoption
patients didn't like it they needed more
access so over the last five to ten
years we saw increasing numbers of
suppliers we saw ranges of products and
I think that ability for patients to
have access to a wider range made them
more engaged in the process the second
thing was that the government began to
allow the companies that were licensed
to produce cannabis to make oils extract
soft gels and alternative forms of of
cannabis products that weren't just
cannabis flour which of course was
associated with smoking even though
there are medical devices approved as
devices for delivering vapor to patients
in Canada but this have built this
availability of other form factors I
think was another thing for many
physicians a soft gel or an oil that
contains so many milligrams of product
per milliliter is a much more easy thing
to think about as a medicine than a gram
of dried flower at 18% THC and 1% CBD
for most physicians this doesn't really
mean much
they don't get what many doctors
probably don't know what a gram of
cannabis looks like but this idea that
they could have gel caps and oils and
bottles and syringes where they could
administered more titrated doses I think
this was a big factor then certainly
surprised many of us that the patient's
also responded to this and it was around
the end of last year for the first time
that we saw the sale of oils and soft
gels actually exceeding the sale of
dried flower in Canada and the sale of
dried flower tea started with dropping
off so patients were responding to this
it appears to be working for them but of
course it's a relatively new thing
stabilizing it and making them
reproducible is another challenge as
anyone who does this work will realize
making it into a pharmaceutical capsule
is still a little bit of a ways away but
under the Canadian regulations it was
allowed it's possible and I think that
was a big change thank you ok one toward
another accelerating factor that I see
in Germany is now the dot the first
adopters here using using full-spectrum
cannabis flowers and extracts or first
they looked at the meta data and they
look at the situation now they are
seeing patients coming back to them and
saying oh this helped me with this and
this and this and this and this and that
so they are actually seeing the cases
and we had we talked to many of them and
so for doctors and they have a lot of
weight on their shoulders in Germany
because and that I forgot to mention
that before they really prescribed the
product in Germany it's not like they
give you a prescription for medical
cannabis they actually put down the
product that you're gonna get in the
pharmacy and so for them it's a lot of
weight on their shoulders and now they
hear it from German doctors they hear it
from German doctors that this works they
are seeing the cases and this is gonna
accelerate I think in this year this is
gonna accelerate because it's it's
becoming tangible now it's not just like
Canadian experience and the meta-data
situation it's really there it's coming
yeah I just want to support that because
I think word-of-mouth is tremendously
popular or turn tremendously powerful in
this approach doctors talking to each
other they're not getting this interim
from their medical schools from their
associations from their their various
syndicates there they're hearing it from
each other and when they try it and they
see a few patients that benefit and if
they know how to do it properly they
then see these differences they talk to
each other and I think a lot of the
growth arabs something like 17,000
physicians in canada now who have
written at least one authorization and
that's about 12 15 % of the canadian
physicians not because they're being
taught about it by the industry or by
their medical schools but because
they're learning and telling each other
about this and their patients are coming
and telling them so that's a kind of a
groundswell of education that's
happening just from pure experience and
many patients are learning the same way
right patient service supporting each
other once a day what a day that's a bad
news it's given spots us of a controlled
fish dish that's why I am the last song
the hum different water under Stella
there's a farmer's my English Lee my
daughter's this vitae belongs under
water duty yet to come out games order
that's the standard Pam I need to knock
about roughly to mark it just for all 50
saw by the ever new young kids we
missing and a giant 400 signatures her
ID is a boom tube or a fasten the
stariha start let any tech is that given
a front welcome treat octopuses on or
season afoul of sue Julian and Vasquez
chief or the Hobart Savini
Indian bolide of almost made an asteroid
on the under point the fogger from
Foshan var on the ending and mine ending
of Covey's and has been the strategy
furlong and fun - only Vega providin
while it is a four song for the evidence
for the globe footage card unwitting
coffin or da mr. Musa Gazette it hits
langsam 'innahu world of the idea
vomiting - chiffon dress with Donegan's
under those two twin become um asana
foul nataliehyde right over in speeds
under and yet sea and ocean dr. Fonda
and so calm and that's negative Guardian
thanks father
that's why and finish drinking more -
Anita's with the Anglican assets in the
olive oil before Nirvana does a small
village another bit of punk unavoidable
news we given get status on Georgian
sauce - the Internet's Nalla thambi
legume - friend
and Tyler design you know enhancer shown
Volcom of activity on the Iron Chef song
vite again vas a estar de anza javadi's
internet scene and the groom committing
Balkan normalized all natural Acharya
individual on Gazette's give aversion to
that's the finished candy Bundesliga on
Victor Shaw within harden off name on
Vida Mitch vulnerable on mr. Blaine are
speaking of new laws speaking of new
laws there is a new proposed bill in
your Parliament and I know that this is
not a law that you have written so you
might not like it as much as you did the
last one but I'm wondering if you can
speak to us about the proposed bill and
whether and what you think that what the
implications will be for patients and
physicians and what you think the
likelihood is of it becoming law of a
second sentence Minister for climate and
fire position was in full and rich
ditched their supporters and of targeted
prizes they are taking the support a
cartouche larks so Abaddon that's right
affirmed by Anna for America theone most
annoying and caucus chair and as this
one doesn't shown buta he will demand of
my name's or mine for Jacques varnished
as a lactam Antoinette Lisa to pave
order at each command want ish I am
feared hidden on dolor de batalla she
adds the Apache Accardi the octahedral
re politics isms wound on to cook me
percent in fact theater war heart as was
in the poem to demand Envy its own
targets if they even can or vote Obama
denying Gazette's and one-man camera
Vida Gazette wits 518 boom when they
come is good we have the opposite soon
yet no Magna for Schlegel blocks that is
of an autumn that is a mess Palomita
shift above FLE and a left side of his
energy pack wattage in the MV Agusta
specimen quinella baisama Hong Kong so
now the game on Jets Vida and immune but
a quality in the merits a NASA won't
want all high Tec are guarded si palace
my nose visits were for irony so in of
achieving big ozone wanna tisha Timothy
Phoebus Agra five over Gantner flight OD
problema dzong their Canton cousin does
it cost inch time
if gargola add symmetrical s the fog
were in a boutique we blame the event
hall often constants it's in Venice cats
effort Orchestra is on don't own a team
and are on MTV famous opinion currently
on con or Dannemora akuto home Jetson
poinsettia often acceptance Louis
another Korematsu it is refute or had a
bargain on this dimension yet a moment
and here her lease in Kenai Chevron's
antsy
yeah I'm itís tuition it Carter Stein as
I said is a c-plus candidates only de
Ian Norman short Candice me - well Gary
might have come near Dundee problem amid
at Walsh merits and etc does this in the
others VESA one of these offending was
not so hunter as desserts gave up on the
head if McGovern Stasi politicked our
business in zebra and that's that's a mo
not not a shockwave is no thank you very
much mister bleonard
I think it's an incredible thing that as
a part of the German law that health
care insurance has been covered it's one
of the things that we're still fighting
for in Canada for patients to be able to
afford their cannabis and I think that
that particular aspect of the
legislation that you're responsible for
um you've shown tremendous global
leadership and you have set the standard
for hopefully the rest of Europe and the
rest of the country that I hope will
catch up with your vision so thank you
is all of the time that we have I want
to really acknowledge and thank my
fellow panelists who are incredibly busy
creating medical cannabis access around
the world who have been working on it
for a very long time thank you very much
for joining me today and thank you we
maybe have time for one do you have time
for one question he looks very excited
maybe two questions you guys both look
excited two questions hold on
thanks very much and so at the MIT PR X
I that workshops were bringing in
doctors are bringing in pharmacists
manufacturers
Uber's etc etc and I'm often thinking
you're talking about how to advocate but
there's a company like yours do you
actually have a blueprint that we can
actually follow here in Germany how to
take the steps to actually go about
organizing the doctors and educating
them is there a blueprint that already
exists that we can follow I'll go back
pre canopy to my McGill days and we
published a paper in a journal called
the clinic clinical pharmacology and
therapeutics we actually published what
we call the cannabis curriculum which
was a kind of a step-by-step guide of
what doctors should know about the plant
and biology and the endocannabinoid
safety efficacy Beauvoir so there's
there do exist these templates the way
in which you deliver that to physicians
depends on the jurisdiction a lot of
doctors like to learn in small groups so
they can talk to each other and exchange
information and ideas some like to learn
online so the idea of having online
webinars or modules that they can go and
check in it's really important that
these programs be accredited by their by
their governing agency so they get
credit for doing the courses this is
often a huge currency for them and this
actually speaks to the government's
willingness to inform them because if
they can get you know twelve CME credits
for having done in to medical education
they can tick a box that says yes I did
some training I got some CME credits
which is good for my medical board that
shows that I'm getting my C Emmys and
I'm learning something cool and new and
for a lot of doctors this is a totally
new and exciting area so when they get
into it they start going holy I had
no idea this stuff was doing what it
does and then you get you've got another
excited person to lead the discussion so
just creating the focus anyway that they
like it so that it's accredited and
comprehensive should do it oh the
troublemaker I was going to say this
isn't intended as a cross-examination
question if it was I would say isn't it
true that mark I'm used to you defending
me and having my back not being not I
just wanted to comment on dr. wares
remarks about research and so on I've
learned as a lawyer
that there were but some 10 royal
Commission's of inquiry going back to
1893 the Indian hemp spec Commission up
to our least our Senate what in 2003
there's 20,000 pubmed studies up there
that you can access online and
significantly I think in terms of the
opiate crisis the national academy of
science engineering and medicine
surveyed all of the existing studies
commented on how difficult it has been
to do the research but said
notwithstanding that there is conclusive
evidence that it is effective for
chronic pain so what is the problem
doctors in terms of you know there is
the evidence sure we can always do more
studies but as you pointed out the
doctor Malloy and the group at st. well
at UBC and st. Paul's is doing a
tremendous job and have reduced opiate
deaths so far so come on medical
profession get on board the medical
profession you're expecting politicians
to have common sense which is hard to
find all over the world it's got nothing
to do sorry I didn't mean to interrupt
but you know it's very frustrating for
everyone throughout the world I think
there was a question in there which I'll
try and respond to and I always do is
reflect the fact that yes the National
Academy of Sciences engineering medicine
conclusive evidence I'm fully aware of
that but I can point to five other
meta-analysis systematic reviews that
concluded that there is no evidence the
cannabis treats pain so doctors will
choose the story that they think sits
there narrative and this is the problem
they're looking at the same studies it's
the same body of data it astonishes me
that you can have groups and some of
them came out of out of Germany some of
them are the European pain Federation's
they've come come out Australian groups
have come up with these conclusions that
suggests that the evidence is not that
strong so you have this conflicting
opinion out there and doctors are still
polarized I hear you the evidence
appears you know quite comprehensive but
it's not the clinical trial stuff and
they will always point to the lack of
randomized control trials that's still
the currency that they need to speak
that's the lack of evidence that they're
talking about in Sebastian what's the
last word I just want to say two
sentences to both of you basically in
Germany I think it's really important
also because of what Mark said before
that we give balanced information that
we are very careful not to seem to
advertise not to exaggerated claims so
that's as a general recommendation to
everybody out there here there's people
are specifically skeptic about the whole
Pharma system and pharma companies doing
damage and I think that's what we are we
stand for to give out balanced detailed
and well to be well informed and that's
that's something that you should always
consider doing here in Germany I think
and that there is Eliza from cannabis at
Columbia this is a question for mr.
Schultz why is it Jacana is so expensive
in Germany you said that pharmacists
they have to add double the price why is
that well that comes because of the
classification of cannabis as an
ingredient so it goes to the pharmacy
and the pharmacists have to do an
identity test and so according to their
statues they they put a hundred percent
price up charge the new law is supposed
to bring that price down also we don't
know how that's going to happen because
there's no specific thing that's written
in the draft of the new law but I think
there's a big political will now to to
get the price down off of cannabis in
Germany because like I said it's it's a
gram of medical cannabis flowers now
cost in Germany around 22 euros or so so
that's that's a lot listen you can call
me I know a guy did it for you like 12
euros I mean no you don't call me like
you know just send me a message I'll
relay it that's it thank you all very
much let's hear it again for this
wonderful fabulous panel