so my name is Josh Holloway I'm from
serious greenhouse solutions were based
in Boulder Colorado I've been working in
the cannabis industry since 2009 I'm a
dispensary owner indoor grower and we've
then developed this greenhouse that
we've been selling for the past eight
years and developing I work with a
partner who is German he lives in
Colorado as well and our goal has always
been high efficiency in growing using
sunlight as much as possible because
it's what the plant wants and it's the
most efficient way to grow as far as
operational costs so I'm gonna speak for
a quick second about the building's what
we do what we think is the most optimal
way to grow cannabis and then Jim will
step in and talk about how his group
controls the interior environment of
indoor grows as well as the greenhouse
what's quite relevant with our
greenhouse and his system well back so
real quick we have a hybrid greenhouse
design that I'll talk about climate
control just very simply well let Jim do
that and then a few featured project so
you get a feel for what it is that we're
doing across the u.s. Canada and now
dive into Europe Australia and South
America as well
our goal is high yields highest quality
and lowest operating cost possible we
see it here we don't deal with GMP in
the US yet but we will but we're quite
aware of it and we design our buildings
to be able to be GMP certified but the
goal in the end is the highest quality
cameras that we that we can grow in the
United States are in Colorado
specifically cannabis is being grown for
about a thousand dollars a pound is the
wholesale cost and we find that our
growers are getting up to fifteen
hundred dollars a pound just because of
the quality of the product so there's a
real differentiation to be had and it
shows itself financially if you are
growing a really high quality product we
find the Sun allows that to happen
controlling the greenhouse itself is a
really more difficult process but
necessary to to create
high quality cannabis this is just a
quick slide to show a traditional
European green house versus something
that we're doing it's a highly insulated
structure it appears that there's less
glazing but often times there's more
light we allow as much par light as
possible and also full UV through our
glazings unlike an indoor grow the
greenhouses that have full UV have
really high quality cannabis more
cannabinoids more terpenes more
flavonoids the plant wants UV and you
can see it in the quality of the product
that comes off the plant our design is
we call it an offset gable we face
themselves but the goal here is that we
actually are insulating so we can grow
in cold weather climates whether it's
northern Northern Europe or we are high
in the mountains in Colorado we can
still maintain very steady temperatures
but it also allows us to have very
controlled so if it's warm and it gets
cold we don't see fluctuations in the
greenhouse the greenhouse functions very
much like an indoor burrow room very
small swings in temperature and humidity
but still allowing that natural sunlight
we also have supplemental lighting at
all times we say it
worst case scenario where an indoor grow
so you have a standardization best-case
scenario your full Sun four to five
times more light than an indoor grow
would have with zero lighting costs
part of our design with our south-facing
greenhouse and our solid facing north
walls is that we can harvest light so in
the winter we are low on light levels
here in Germany you'd have less light
obviously than you would in the summer
what our greenhouses can do is if that
light misses the plant if it goes over
the plant it will hit the north wall of
a greenhouse and actually bounce back to
the plant so we see growth heading
towards the north which is not normal
but we've designed it to harvest light
to optimize lighting levels as much as
possible to reduce operational costs and
keep the plants happy this is an example
of a custom green greenhouse that we've
built in Boulder Colorado this is 22,000
square feet or 2,200 square meters it's
broken into
five greenhouses 420 square meters each
with an insulated head house that has
processing offices indoor veg these
things are flexible but this gives you
an idea of what we're looking at to the
left is the south and so we orient the
greenhouses towards the Sun the right
side of those structures is north we
insulate them they can hold heat and
harvest light screenhouse has 90% light
transmission full UV and when the Sun is
out there's 20 we measure lighting in
ppfd for the most part and there's 2200
ppfd whereas the best grow room might
say it has a thousand but maybe it
really has 600 or 700 so we really have
high light levels in these greenhouses
we're constantly evolving with the
glazings that we're using this is the
most important thing it allows the light
into the greenhouse we work with a
Japanese company Asahi glassed and have
an ETF II offering which is up to 96%
light transmission with full UV in
colder climates we can do a double layer
of that that gives us some insulation as
well as up to 90% light transmission we
work with a German company called Evonik
for an acrylic glazing it has a higher
insulation value than traditional
glazings 90% light transmission for UV
and then for a lot of the hemp growers
will use a polycarbonate which is a
plastic and plastic cannot allow UV
through because it would degrade but UV
actually promotes THC production so for
a lot of growers in hemp who don't have
the most stable genetics just yet
potentially Polycarp it's a nice option
because it doesn't allow the UV through
the buildings are actually quite
flexible based on what you're growing
and how you're growing this is one of
the most important parts when we get to
cleanliness control is that we keep the
structures as smaller spaces so these
might be 3,000 of 5,000 square feet 300
to 500 square metres and we'll break
them up into multiple units you can add
as many as you want but this allows us
to control biosecurity if you get a bug
or a mold or mildew or something we can
keep it in one house and it will not
spread unless
you spread it actually physically
yourself we can also maintain different
climates in each house and that'll be
something that Gemma can talk about but
depending on strain we can have a warmer
drier room or a cooler more humid room
or depending on stage of growth in the
flowering process we can actually allow
a younger flowering plant to have a
warmer environment with more humidity
and as flowering progresses towards the
end we can actually dry the room out
slightly but it gives us an operational
cost advantage because we don't have two
cooler or dehumidifier as much depending
on stage of growth we also do design
vented greenhouses many of our hemp
propagators will vent a greenhouse it's
significantly cheaper to use outside air
for GMP certification it's actually much
more difficult to impossible but in the
States
that's not necessary if it's all veg
growth and there's no flower and we're
only working on propagation a vented
greenhouse sometimes can be a good
option for cost savings more and more
though we are moving towards sealed
greenhouses completely closed
environment minimal venting just for
human occupancy which could be maybe 500
CFM one fan necessary just for humans to
be working in the space but for the most
part these are completely sealed
environments high co2 high light and
very controlled and we do a lot of our
control based on vapor pressure deficit
again we can maintain stable temps and
humidity co2 retention odor control is a
big thing if we're building in urban
areas or industrial zones odor can be a
major issue with growers may be the most
difficult issue to deal with when we
seal the greenhouses we have way less
odor problems GMP certified high
biosecurity because we're not bringing
in outside outside air what we've seen
in in the US with the hemp market now
taking off is that vented cannabis grows
are taking male pollen from outside hemp
grows and seeding which isn't a total
disaster if you're processing but you
have less lower quality product and
you're making less money
this gives you
control complete control over what's
happening inside your greenhouse and
then again vapor pressure deficit is how
we control the greenhouses I don't know
if that many people know about it but it
gives us a range of temperatures along
with a ratio along with a humidity
temperatures can fluctuate as long as we
take humidities with it and the plants
don't feel the difference they can
optimally pull water and nutrients
through and transpire climate control
which controls our light depth systems
our fertigation systems are heating
cooling and dehumidification systems are
getting very smart so we work with we've
developed sequence of operations in our
greenhouses it's flexible these are
software based controllers they're
viewable on your phone you can check
them you can even control things on your
phone but most importantly we track all
data in the greenhouses everything
that's happening every piece of
equipment that's on when it's on how
long it's on we can see what's happening
and then we can go back and look at that
data analyze it make adjustments moving
forward we can find what we've had a
really good harvest and completely mimic
that with the same strain with the same
eight-week run of climate controls and
it allows us to really dial in what's
happening in the houses this isn't
really a guessing game anymore we know
what's happening and we can mimic it or
we can adjust it to make it better and
these are just a few examples this is a
4,000 square meter or 40,000 square feet
hemp greeting facility that we just
built in Oregon each house has different
hemp pollen being thrown he's producing
seed for farmers the too far to the
south houses our climate mimickers if
they have light depth and full climate
control so he has he's in Oregon but he
has a client from Florida he can grow
his hemp in a Florida climate based on
Florida daily lighting the integral
humidity levels and everything else a
farmer from Florida can come here step
into that greenhouse and he says here's
your Florida crop this is this seed
grown in Florida conditions so he can
mimic any environment in the world in
the greenhouses and show his clients
what's happening when the other hate 8
houses he's breeding
see this is a another hemp propagation
greenhouse this is a vented greenhouse
it's the same style but slightly
different this is at about 7,000 feet of
elevation 22 2,300 meters of elevation
year-round growing cloning seed breeding
but very controlled and highly
successful and this is an inside shot of
one of our newest cannabis greenhouses
but as a little series plug of what we
do we produce in the US we have
manufacturing in Europe as well and we
believe we have the most controlled
greenhouse available on the market
our clients are proving that out every
day with incredibly high quality product
the lab results that we get back from
the flower that is being produced in
these greenhouses is like nothing the
lab guys have ever seen after eight
years we get this often we have never
seen cannabis like this before and the
biggest thing is what we do is we we
design a structure but then we we are
along with the growers for their
hopefully entire lifetime of growing
we're always learning always tweaking
and pushing and this won't be sitting
yeah well babysitting but also but also
they learn stuff that we don't know
because we're not operating in the
houses so they tell us things and so now
I pass it to Jim Jim is more on the
climate side and he can talk about how
they're controlling the climate in
houses like ours and others thanks
it's thank you guys
[Applause]
hi I'm gem I'm from an erotic knowledge
ease
we provide environmental solutions to
greenhouses and indoor facilities it's
super important what they are doing
because the technologies we provide we
depend on the structures as well for
them to actually be in great use so
having good isolation and having good
design and structure is super important
for the technologies to work at their
best capabilities inside so you need to
adapt the whole hall from the structure
the construction to the endgame
everything needs to be intact with each
other I think and we also focus a lot on
efficiency in energy saving in in light
and also in water water and we make sure
that there is a lot of redundancy in the
greenhouses or in the comb indoor
facilities we also focus on increasing
the yield and the quality of the product
the technologies we provide Able's you
to grow a whole year and our background
is actually agriculture and we've been
in cannabis this last couple years we
have manufacturing in Europe and our
offices is in Switzerland and in
California and we also filter the air we
cool the air so everything about the
climate inside we try to tackle it and
our technology Able's you to control
absolute humidity and control
temperature without changing the
temperature we can control the humidity
and humidity has a major role in the in
the plants so over time it can be very
rewarding or very painful to to have
bacteria
and fungi and other modules so what we
do we we we take the humidity out and
discharge it and we also clean the air
while we're doing this with our liquid
desiccant system and VPD is super
important
simply put it's the pressure on the leaf
and the the more pressure there is that
the less transpiration will happen and
the less transpiration which is let's
say sweating the plants the absorption
is also related to all of these so the
absorption will be less and why designs
get good quality corpse crops is because
of the absorption rates they get so
controlling the humidity is it's super
important for for the plants inside and
biohazardous this is a I'll talk about
the patented technology we have we do
mostly a closed-loop systems sealed
completely it's very important to have
an exhaust and also control cooling and
heating and humidity at the same time
these are some designs we have done in
in Europe and in the States
you can see we we do multi rooms multi
zone control so some of the rooms can
have different point views and even in
the same room you can have different
machines acting differently so the end
of the room can have a different cooling
and humidity level then then the the
beginning of the room so these are all
up to clients custom how they want to
grow you can see more designs and
like I said we manage air quality we
designed a silencer now because most of
the regulations are getting stricter and
sticker so people around like in Florida
and in Zurich they complain a lot about
smell order and they complain about
noise so we we try to tackle this with
Auto trapping in our machines which is
quite hard to do actually because order
is a molecule as well and we control
water molecules in air but we've been
showing great progress on other trapping
as well and while we are doing this we
also filtered air sterilize it so you
don't need extra filters or or anything
in the greenhouse I'll keep on going
this is one of the grow rooms we built
so here you can see many air to handlers
so all those air handlers can get
different comments and you were talking
about data collection it's super
important all our technology also
collects data so you can learn what our
how your air circulation was how much
humidity levels you were at and how much
energy you were spending and you gather
all this and then you can have a better
analysis of your climate these are some
of the machines we our machines go
outside so we don't take space inside
and we we are a little more industrial
size so we we handle really big places
you can see the silencers on so these
these guys order trap dehumidifier cool
heat so it's like a one-stop HVAC
solution we seen that all the
technologies inside the greenhouse or
facility indoor facility needs to
interact with each other
which becomes a little messy sometimes
to use many different technologies from
many different companies and try to
adapt them all together can cause more
risk and problems so we do
loved machine which can provide all of
this with justing one single brand we
also control the the machine and our
systems come with climate control inside
we also can track this through an
application and anywhere from the web
login and you can also control any other
electrical devices inside through our
software which is provided comes with
technology and we also control co2 if it
needs to be controlled by tanks or by
burners we can add coolers and extra
heaters and we can also go modular so
you can if your facility is small first
and you have a modular design in
structure you can grow the equipment
while growing the structures which is an
advantage for for people who doesn't
want to start really big thanks I was I
was just gonna point out that we we've
worked with growers in the past to
Colorado is a dry place where we live
it's permanently dry two years ago we
had a really wet May it rained almost
the whole month most growers were not
set up for that at all they were using
vented greenhouses and almost all of
them lost crops if they were in late
flowering in May all lost to powdery
mildew and so what a what a controlled
environment does off the bat with your
initial design it's really more than
anything an ideal growing environment
but more so it's insurance that
regardless of what's happening outside
in the environment you are going to have
the ability to control the interior
environment and not lose a crop some of
those guys who lost crops might have
lost half a million dollars and product
in that month which might have paid for
half paid for the upgraded build-out
that they could have or should have done
in the beginning and so this is really
an insurance
see especially when you're planning with
for your business to know that you're
not going to have a catastrophic failure
because you are ready to handle any
environmental thing that might come your
way is a huge benefit for your
operational success also collecting the
data enables you to to go to that date
of points where you are in trouble to
show that your conditions were actually
not causing the the problem because you
can go to if the dispensaries which in
you you see now in California this is
happening a lot millions of dollars
worth of products they're getting
recalled so the the growers can actually
fight for their rights if they have the
data enhance they can go to any day any
time and and show the conditions that
was growing this is also super important
for for growers to be able to to to show
the conditions of the climate which is
collecting data so I think it's quite
important also to show the energy levels
that you know that's getting used
we had a facility in in in Florida and
using a HVAC system from somebody else
and getting all these technologies
together at the end the energy costs and
the energy levels go really really high
and you know using efficient
technologies helps a lot with with and
quality of the product and how you get
to that quality much of this goes back
to initial planning and this you know
the more you plan in the early stages
the better off you're going to be with
the success of your project what we see
is in in Colorado indoor growers with
average HVAC controls are growing
between four thirty to fifty cents a
gram
a lot of our clients in the greenhouse
with a with a well-designed
HVAC system that's designed for
operational efficiency are growing for
us the last two cents to Graham in the
greenhouses part of that is because we
don't use light very much part of that
is because we have optimal conditions
because sunlight along with good
environmental controls so the plants are
totally out yielding what you might
normally see in an indoor grow and all
of those things bring down operational
costs so as wholesale prices drop over
time which they inevitably will the
greenhouse growers have a guaranteed
product at a low operational cost that
they know is gonna keep them in the game
longer whereas the guys who started
indoor which is maybe a thing that's
happening in Germany and how it had to
start in Colorado at the time the indoor
grocery that going out of business or
transitioning to a more controlled
better engineered designed greenhouse
situation the the initial investment
sometimes can be higher in in in let's
say ETF II is we actually recommend ETF
II a lot in the Middle East it's
actually a really really good product
it's better than glass and but it's a
little bit more expensive if I'm not
mistaken and it's it's it's up to up to
us to actually show why why the initial
investments are sometimes can be higher
and really important in in the long long
term I think this is what the growers
and people who wants to get into this
business should really think about and
plan it you were saying planning is
super important you should really know
on how advanced you want to go because
whereas in innovation goes it's not
stopping every day there is something
new coming out and and it's up to the
growers if they want to adapt that or
not so I beg you you use the innovations
you know more and more now early on in
Colorado these were smaller
roars we're just trying to get into the
game for as little money as possible and
then survive and more and more now what
we see is much more organized business
groups who aren't as frightened to spend
the money but still concerned but it's
way more established now and so we see
people who are way more willing to make
the investment when we show them what
the outcome is and what the
possibilities are with the right
building and the right and the right
mechanical which is you would you agree
if I said which is mostly fully sealed
houses it is the best product I would I
would say most most most of the time or
fully controlled greenhouses you know as
in the egg sauce as an as an everything
so yeah we have so if you know the story
of Oregon right now Oregon has a huge
amount of outdoor or maybe greenhouse
grown cannabis that is ok quality that
is just sitting there like they say five
years worth of product yeah yeah more
than anybody they yeah they have like
four times the amount of weed if
everybody in Oregon was an everyday pot
smoker they would still have too much
weed right so I've offered to go up to
help but but the the idea there is
growing okay cannabis at this point is
really not a business plan at all it's
it's a it's a way to fail and so those
people who did not make the investment
in the way they're growing are paying
for it really like with everything they
have right now whereas the clients that
we have who've spent the most money
where people say this is actually you're
going way overboard it's ridiculous what
you're doing are getting 30 to 50
percent more wholesale per pound for
their product because it's such high
quality and when it comes out of the lab
results it shows that at such high
quality that's great that's fantastic
thank you both very much do we have time
for some questions you have a question
or two anyone have a question everyone
has used all of their words today well
thank you so very much Jim and Josh
let's hear for Jim and Josh I was very
enlightening very educational