thanks Anthony and
well see see that you've probably seen
before on the end we have Jesse sweet
who is the director of the
administrative policy and process for
the state we also have Amanda bore up in
the middle there amanda is a marijuana
program policy analyst and then we have
Danica hips Minh who is the director of
statewide licensing so let's welcome
them up to the stage please okay so I've
got some questions prepared where we're
kind of put them on the spot and find
out some of what I know is burning in
people's minds first I'll just give you
a little background if I see a lot of
familiar faces people that have been in
the industry for a long time over 25
years ago when I was discovering
cannabis getting out of high school and
learning what I liked about it for
recreational purposes then my mother
came down with cancer and my best
friend's mother got HIV from a blood
transfusion and in the 90s HIV was still
very mysterious and we weren't
understanding what was up and people
were afraid to hug or kiss her or and I
I knew a little more about it and and
was very involved with trying to help
her feel better he was a very good
friend of mine and and then both of our
moms were going through this traumatic
period we lost his mom and my mom
survived twice breast cancer and as a
been around a long time still trucking
along and we're both one was pro
cannabis and one wasn't and my mom had
never smoked cannabis and ever been
around cannabis and did not want me to
be around cannabis so it was hard for me
to come at her and explain how
beneficial this could be mom I see this
as helping people I have some good
friends that took me down to San
Francisco on a trip and introduced me to
some crazy wild guys that were talking
about hemp and and cannabis and some of
you might know jack herer is heard of
Jack God rest his soul give Jack a round
of applause we miss jack
[Music]
and crazy ed Rosenthal who taught me how
to grow cannabis when I did know how so
I could try and provide my mother with a
product that was gonna help her get
through her problems for the last 25
years or so I worked with voter power
the organization and Anthony Johnson was
there with me in the streets with
clipboards getting signatures to put a
medical ballot on the Oregon initiative
system and and we did that and
eventually got the original OMA past and
through voter power I learned about what
medical clinics meant and what outreach
meant to patients and what we had to do
to help these people and it wasn't just
my mom it was everybody's mom and
grandma and uncles and and brothers and
so we worked hard to try and get focused
on that they really taught me how to
organize and rally around these people
to get them what they needed on the
product line and to teach growers how to
provide for patients and provide for
their family members which is the key to
this whole system working so we started
doing clinics I eventually left voter
power started Southern Oregon
alternative medicine were in about 16
cities in Oregon I started Arizona
alternative health I had an uncle down
there I went down and wanted to do the
same thing for people they're very tough
state in the beginning let me tell you
but it was it was tough I mean I
remember getting spat on and and people
wanted a fist fight because we were
getting signatures to put cannabis on
the ballot and and Southern Oregon was
not you know the most friendly area even
though that's where some of the best
cannabis in the world was grown in the
woods we'd often wait for hours to go up
and have to by the time I'd go get an
ounce in the woods by the time I got
home it would take a whole day and the
two people that would introduce me to
the next people to get it and never met
the guy and I mean all of you remember
these these early stories of how we got
our cannabis and fell in love with it
and and I fell in love with it and I
blew blast for a long time
and was just wanted to do anything close
to the industry but helping people and
seeing the satisfaction and watching
people's lives be better that are
suffering through traumatic illnesses
and traumatic times in their lives
losing family members and getting
through that was the biggest part of
my life and been the joy of my life to
work with patients a few years ago a
friend of mine in Southern Oregon I have
a restaurant down there a friend of mine
came in that had just been appointed to
the olcc as chairman Rob Patridge who's
not with the agency anymore but was
elected by former governor Kitzhaber to
handle that stuff and he came to me and
said hey he was a former prosecutor so
he was a Klamath DA and all he knew
about cannabis was going into a farm
cutting the plants down and arresting
everybody on site so there was a little
bit different angle for him to come and
and told me hey I don't know anything
about this we got to do this we helped
me do this and so that's when we started
forming the rules advisory committee and
getting a lot of great people in the
industry that have been around a long
time that understand how it goes and one
thing I can say about the agency is
they've done
absolutely their best and with limited
resources and limited funding to not
only pay attention to this massive
undertaking of creating a regulated
market around cannabis which is you know
what a long strange trip it's been I
often repeat to myself it's just a trip
to see where we're at to see an
organized convention like this organized
business people getting involved and
taking it to the next level is super
exciting there's a lot of challenges I
think the agency is doing a good job of
with what they have to hear us and they
did a statewide listening tour in the
beginning and went around and really
wanted to hear what we thought it should
look like and some things turned out the
way we thought they should be some
things didn't and I think we're learning
as industry people some of these things
are for the best the tracking system
sayings that we never did when we were
growing for years keeping track of what
nutrients we were using or what what was
potentially a better strain than another
you know it was all just not organized
now we're organizing these things where
were able to operate in the open which
is great I think you know the black
market was the way it was the black
market was how people made money that's
how we had to make money to be able to
make medicine for people the day Pfizer
starts making pills for free then then I
would say growers should be able to grow
for free so this new introduction into
where
medical patients and medical growers are
gonna be able to participate in the
recreational system and we're going to
talk about that a little bit Steve
talked about it a bit it's a complicated
thing to make people understand
something we've been doing in the
program for over you know around 20
years now all of a sudden now it's a big
shift and patients and growers that are
in that realm don't deal with the
changes as easy as others so we're
trying to find some balance in between
and I think Oregon by far and people
have heard me say this before but I
think we are the number one state in the
country that has legalized cannabis and
protected our medical patients and
growers far beyond anyone elses programs
and you know I mean that's a big deal
it's a big deal to know that these
people sitting here even they don't have
to they're not dictated necessarily to
care
they're dictated to do something about
what the legislature says to do but I
know these people I know them personally
I know they care I know they do want to
find a way for us to be able to take
care of our patients and keep them in
the mix Rob Patridge understood that how
important it was to take care of the
people who this industry was built on
this industry was built around sick and
disabled people and the growers and
caregivers that were compassionate
enough to take it on and risk
imprisonment a lot of times so I think
where we're at now from where we've been
is light-years I think we have a long
way to go with great legislators we have
some of them here I'm sitting with us
that are keeping our voices heard at the
legislative level which gives them the
tools they need at the administrative
level to make these things happen some
of the frustrating things we've seen as
a multiple license holder I've got
stores I understand the challenges of
stores I understand where farmers are
and we got to pay our crew at the end of
the harvest season we know the
challenges around stores being too many
stores a lot of us feel like there's too
many and so those sort of the kind of
things that we have to be vocal about
and I encourage you to be vocal with
your legislators and the legislators you
know that are in the realm of this stuff
senator Pierzynski is sitting with us
today been one of our great champions
let's give him a round of applause
really quick I just
Floyd has been awesome and really
hearing what the challenges are and
staying with it a lot of letters leaders
have kind of come and gone we've lost
our committee that was a group of
legislators deemed to kind of handle
this stuff and now we're back in the
open waters again and it has to be
included in something that they want to
do and they have obviously constituents
that want many things handled you know
land usage things cannabis is not the
top thing for every legislator so the
fact that people like senator Pierzynski
still find time and and realize how
important it is that we shape this
industry the right way and that happens
through what he does at his job and it
lets them do their job and you know we
can get that middle ground and I think
we're getting there I see I know
businesses are struggling it's a really
challenging time we're held to one state
I mean you have an open market concept
in a single state for sales I mean once
federal change happens is really what
we're all kind of hovering and waiting
for and unfortunately a lot of the
smaller outfits which is who we want to
support we want those small family farms
and I do think there's a future people
ask me all the time I'm a small business
how am I going to compete with those big
dollars coming in from Canada you know I
think we're in a microbrew industry you
know we really are it's a it's the new
era of where that mom-and-pop product
that organic farm those things are
important and those are what consumers
are looking for so if you have a small
business you have a small farm brand
yourself well I always say it's really
important you to stand out on the store
shelves that's how you're gonna get your
product out there there is a lot of
people growing flower but flower is
selling it is selling and once we get
more licenses on and they're working
vigilantly to get that done the new
processors that come online the new
product lines that come out you see how
many products are in the store now would
go into a 7-eleven or go into a liquor
store or whatever reference you want to
use there's a lot of room for product
development and that's really where that
cannabis is gonna be eaten up so as we
create new oil lines and new product
lines and all these great ideas that
people are coming up with we're gonna
see that reduction happen even in Oregon
I think we're gonna see cannabis
starting to be eaten up more and it'll
drive the prices back up a little bit
once we go
federal legal obviously that's the
launch point so right now you're
preparing yourself for what's gonna
happen you're preparing yourself to be
relevant on a national marketplace and
that should really be your focus right
now is doing your product doing it well
and knowing how to scale when the time
comes I assume when the time comes and
we can't ship out of state we'll look
back at the rules and regs around how
big a farm can be and we'll go from an
acre to potentially 20 acres or whatever
it takes as we see that product able to
move right now we keep that acre that's
not gonna be like that forever
eventually you will be able to grow you
know massive fields of cannabis as the
demand will be there where right now
we're just kind of held to this state
and it's a like a hovering game so we
just need to hang out I don't want to
see I've really it discourages me to see
people giving up I know it's financially
difficult not to in some instances I've
dealt with all that myself but we got to
hang in there because those ideas that
you have and those products are the
future this is the end of prohibition
all over again
if you look at those signs and what's
happening you'll see this is how it went
not everybody made it but a lot of
people did make it and it's not the same
it's not gonna be a big corporate shift
I think the small family farm and the
small product manufacturer definitely
has a place so I'm looking forward to
see how that kind of turns out so stay
in there hang in there and then let's
give these guys a little bit of heat
here so a couple questions that I got so
Danica I'm going to put this one to you
from what I've been hearing quite a few
like the violations could have been
avoided by licensees reporting changes
to olcc can you let us know what the
common violations are and what licenses
need to let olcc know
is that on
tryam andis
it's not better that's better there you
go okay there's no secret that this
market is an incredibly dynamic but
difficult phase right now we took a very
free-market approach in Oregon here so
over the last couple of years a lot of
licensees coming on board and I think it
was not unexpected that at some point
there would be somewhat of a glut in the
market too many licensees too much
product prices go down and businesses
are struggling there's a lot of people
that are trying to bring on new
investors selling out their businesses a
lot of consolidation going on or trying
to scale up or scale down their
operations within the premises that
they've licensed all of that are things
that require licensing attention it's
one of the reasons why we shifted a lot
of our focus from new applications to be
able to serve those existing licensees
and help them get through this this
phase of the industry but that is where
we're seeing a lot of businesses that
are not following the regulations and it
is it is concerning because in order to
keep this market dynamic continue to let
it evolve and grow we need to be able to
make sure that we are vetting the people
that are coming into it that we know
that premises that are being licensed
and we know what's happening on those
licensed premises so all of those things
making changes to a premises making
changes to your business structure
selling your business all of that
requires olcc pre-approval and that's
what we're really not seeing a lot of
right now we're seeing a lot of people
come in after the fact and frankly a lot
of those things can actually be
cancelable offenses so if you are a
licensee or you know a licensee please
help us get the word out that you know
we're there to help you we have a
process under which you can let us know
that you're making those changes and we
want to get them done for you as quickly
as possible but it does it is something
that you need to contact us first work
through that process and do it the right
way
okay great one thing I think you know
and I talked about a little bit about
licensees or I think it is important to
let the agency know when these changes
happen it's super important to let them
know ahead of time I think there's still
some fear of people maybe making changes
that they're not ready for and I want to
get the message out that people need to
call the agency and let them know if
you're having a problem you need to let
them know they
know about it if you're having one topic
I've been talking to them about his
camera issues we've had a lot of canna
Guard and a lot of the companies kind of
disappeared and left a lot of growers
and and other licenses in the lurch what
do you think you know is the best method
for people to communicate with the
agency because ultimately that's what we
want we want people to call talk to you
guys about the problems they're having
and know that they're not going to be
put on the chopping block
when it comes to that right email that
you can send any question to it will get
to the right person we have staff that
read every single one of those emails we
have a call-in line that I don't
remember the number right now but we can
get it if you we have a booth here so
please stop by and get any information
that you need it's we really want people
to call and ask
there is no too small of a question out
there we can usually help you work
through whatever process whatever issue
you've got if you just contact us I
think that's important for people to
know
thank you Danica I think it's important
that people know that the agency is
ready to work with you they want us to
be successful they are not here to
prevent us from being you know
successful and I see a lot of fear with
clients I work with and people in the
industry that you cannot at this point
see the agency as the enemy in your
process and they understand that there's
fears around that so I encourage people
to reach out to the agency when you have
in problems let them know what you're
having make sure that you're keeping
good records of everything that's going
on and you'll find a way around that and
they'll help you find a way around that
it's gonna make your life easier and
you're gonna sleep better I promise
Jesse I got one for you buddy has almost
Susy been able to make it to most of the
outdoor producers who are harvesting in
this new operation good harvest and are
you finding common violations when those
people are going out to those type of
sites and does olcc plan to do similar
good harvest stuff with the indoor
growers and not just the outdoor
producers
as Steve touched on we're out there
doing harvest notice inspections we have
done approximately 60 of these
inspections so far and I think we're
looking at about a 70% successful
compliance rate and what we're seeing
when we're out there is not necessarily
problems with the harvest or the harvest
notification process itself what's more
common is we're seeing operational
problems things like the fencing isn't
in place or you know growers are drying
in a facility that's not approved and
doesn't have cameras things that we
would have caught in any kind of routine
inspection and the the harvest
notification process has I think been a
really good tool for our staff to to get
organized and get mobilized out to those
growers who they in many cases haven't
visited for quite some time and what
we're seeing mostly falls along the
lines of people who just aren't paying
enough attention to compliance and the
operational standards that we have in
our rules this is a really really tough
industry you know it's tough for a lot
of reasons that that you all know
banking taxes competition it's also
tough because we have put forth a lot of
regulations and and we know that and
we're working with the industry to to
get people compliant to get them to
where they need to be and in some cases
when we can't get people there we have
to pursue license cancellation I'll
reiterate what Brent said you know
there's the saying ask for forgiveness
not permission that does not work in
this industry it simply doesn't you need
to ask for permission
as far as indoor growers you know we're
focusing on the outdoor growers right
now because we are in harvest
we've got a large amount of product
coming down in a very short window I'm
going to use the rest of the year
following this harvest season to start
getting out and making more contact with
the indoor growers so that we can do the
same types of premises inspections to
ensure that they're operating in
compliance great yeah that's a lot of
work it's a lot of work with a limited
staff I've seen them do some pretty
amazing things with not very many people
okay Jesse Jesse we were talking a
little bit ago and kind of describes
himself as the designated driver at the
end of the night that's the only silver
one in the vehicle he's got a really
hard task there's a lot of these things
I throw at him constantly we're trying
to figure out how to make what we've
done forever work with what they
understand they need to do it doesn't
always make sense we don't always
understand how that looks but they're
trying to understand and they're trying
to find a way in the regulatory process
to allow us to do our job when we looked
at some of you may have saw the big pile
of burning marijuana that I had a couple
years ago kind of went national Bob and
Tom called me about it but it was all
about moldy cannabis and what that
looked like and in the beginning a lot
of these rules and regulations came from
what they knew metric came from Colorado
they only understood indoor grows they
wanted us to cut a whole plant and hang
it upside down when we harvest once I
showed them what plants look like they
understood why that probably wasn't
going to work you know out ten pound
outdoor plants don't do that not without
a smoke crane so but they came down they
came to the farms we did tours of many
farms and saw what that looks like and
why there is moldy material and why we
do have waste on a farm and this is a
farm this is a farm like any other farm
we have lots of biomass that we end up
burning getting rid of that goes on the
ground and it's not a valuable product
that we're trying to send out to the
masses through the black market it's
it's waste and they understood that and
the rules now reflect that and that's
how the whole process has been going
through showing them what's happening
they want to see what we're talking
about and that's why this communication
is so important giving them ideas of
what your challenges are helps them find
a way around
and that's why I try and stay so active
and letting them know any information I
can that's gonna help them do their job
better which makes our lives much easier
when things are running smooth so Jessie
I'm gonna throw one more at you buddy it
seems like the OCC has been holding
quite a few rules advisory committee
meetings as we did on the sales limits
recently what are the main topics you're
focused on and when should we expect
some kind of finalization in the rule
process so to answer this I'll start at
the beginning in late 2015 the agency
adopted close to a hundred pages of
administrative rules before we issued a
single license
so obviously that first rule package was
not perfect we have undergone since that
time major revisions in the legislature
and the agency and its rulemaking has
devoted most of its resources to keeping
up with the legislative changes rather
than going back and fine-tuning that
base package based on what we have
learned from both our staff working in
the field and from input people in the
industry so we're going to have a very
broad package of rules coming through
this fall it will likely be adopted by
our Commission in December we have a lay
Commission and they are the final policy
makers staff like me draft things and
suggest things to them but they
ultimately guide the policy so the those
rules will focus as I said on a number
of refinements some of the major subject
matter areas are volatile processing we
need to make some refinements to our
approval process to make sure that those
processors that are using volatile
solvents are doing so in the safest
manner possible we're looking at
reforming our waste rules there's I
think a good bit that we can do there to
make sure not only that the waste rules
really make sense
for for growers and processors but also
that they make sense in terms of
mitigating opportunities for diversion
we have identified waste as one of the
the key areas where items can be
misrepresented in metric and diversion
can occur we'll also be looking at
refining a number of things around our
compliance areas you know what what
licensees can and can't do when they're
under suspension for example under what
conditions would we restrict a license
rather than cancel it it's a fairly long
list and as far as the calendar goes we
will be putting out a public notice
which will say in much more detail what
we're considering and that public notice
will go out in November I believe which
begins a two-week public comment period
and it's really important that people
who have an interest in these rules pay
attention to that public comment period
you can sign up for automatic email
updates on our website and they will
tell you exactly when that public
comment period is but too often we go
through this rulemaking process that's
required by the law to be an inclusive
public process we finish our rules we
adopt them and then three or four weeks
later I hear from somebody in the
industry that says this rule that you
just did is nonsense it doesn't work and
it's really difficult for the agency
there's to receive the input and make a
meaningful change at that point the time
for meaningful input is in the public
comment period that's when it's going to
be very useful for us to hear from you
so I would encourage everyone who's not
signed up for those updates
sign up for the updates read the rules
carefully when we put out our notice to
devote the time you know if you have an
interest devote the time before the
rules are final and that's the way that
you'll be the most effective advocate
for your interest the old if you don't
vote you don't get the it's the
same thing
we got to get our voices out there
you've got to let them know what's going
on these these public comment periods
are so important to show up to and make
your voice be heard because there's
things that not everybody thinks of I
don't think of everything there I know
there's so many challenges that we're
facing in the industry it's really
important that we communicate that to
the agencies so they can try and fix it
and make it work better so please be
active please be involved in that
process so important so Amanda I'm going
to shoot one back at you on medical
stuff you know there's a lot of question
around Medical there's a lot of fear
about transitioning in getting people
tracked getting people in the system I
think there's still a lot of questions
about how a card holder can access
medicine in the new system and what that
looks like and give us a quick rundown
on kind of options that people have
coming into that space okay definitely
so I think I want to start at the retail
level at the retail level a card holder
can receive product free of charge
they're also not taxed on the product
that they purchased at the retail level
and then they can buy a what are called
medical grade products and so those are
products made at a higher concentration
limit or a higher potency limit than
recreational users so I think what we
hear a lot is you know people who used
to be growers who now are recreational
producers and they want to be able to
give their patients medicine are people
who used to be their patients I think a
really simple way for people to do that
would be able to work with a retailer in
their community transfer the product to
the retailer and then the retailer would
give the the card holders that product
for free or at a very low cost if that's
what they decided to do so I think it's
really important to highlight that that
connection can still happen without the
typical grower patient and relationship
and then also or did you want to put in
well I just want to interject I I know
and this involves retailer we talked
about retailers retailers we have a lot
on us this is one of the things that
that we need to decide to participate in
if you're a retailer and there's people
going around there's several groups
trying to get some good programs started
for patient access some free patient
medicine we've
we've talked to farmers that are willing
to donate we need retailers involved in
that that's where the point of access is
for those patients so if you're a
retailer you need to make it available
and when someone comes to you and says
hey we're working on a patient access
program we'd like to list your store as
one of the stores patients can come to
to get free meds we have a lot of people
in this state that can't afford to buy
meds they're living on us on a monthly
check they don't have the money to buy
meds I don't care how cheap it gets in
the store it's not in your budget when
you when your top priorities are food
and medicine and you know and keeping
your heat on so we need to get active we
need to be involved and you need to stop
shy here all I hear from the people that
are starting these programs steve marks
been adamantly working on trying to find
a way to to find that compassionate
venue and it's got to happen at the
retail level it's where it has to happen
so retailers if you're here we need to
we need to be involved I need to be
involved we need to make sure that we're
giving that vessel for these people to
be able to get their medicine it doesn't
take a little bit more storage space to
have just a basic product that is your
giveaway for that month or something
that you can donate to a cardholder we
have to take care of these people we
have our own struggles but we can't
forget who these people are and why
we've been doing this for so long and
how important that is and that's where
it's got to happen that's where they
have to be able to keep track of what's
happening so we can give away free
medicine at the stores we don't have to
be taxed for that we need to take
advantage of that that's a great
loophole I call it a loophole but it's a
great venue and a way to get medicine
out to people you know I mean that's
where it's at we need to get it out
there and they're finding a way to do it
but we need to step up as industry
people and donate those products from
your farms donate those products from
your cookie companies whatever you're
making you can be involved this is
something that we need to continue
throughout this process is taking care
of our sickest and most needy folks in
this state so keep it up and so
legislation passed recently allows for a
Noel CC licensed processor to apply for
an endorsement with olcc so it's
something that you would need to fill
out a form to
endorsement for and be approved before
you were to able to do it but it would
allow a processor to take in Flour
material from a patient directly and
process that and then give it back to
the patient there are limits to that but
that is an option you know what we don't
want people to be doing is you know
processing in their garages or doing
things in unsafe ways and so what this
does is it allows a licensed processor
to be able to run that material and turn
it into a product directly for a patient
and then also producers olcc licensed
producers can apply for an endorsement
so it'd be the same thing filling out a
form and getting approval and they can
grow from an additional area of plants
for patients only so it's called a
medically designated canopy so really on
all levels of the license system there
is a way for patients to be able to
receive product and be able to have an
affordable medicine great thank you
you know I think that says it all we
need to start getting a little more
involved on that and remember these
people I know we're busy but we need to
remember them so what I want to do now
is give an opportunity for you to ask
some questions of the folks we have up
here there will be some time after two
one-on-one things but if we have some
questions in the crowd I think we're
certainly right let's hear it for the
panel one more time here we go oh by the
way all the questions please be brief
and no rambling that's always okay thank
you my question is for Jesse sweet and I
would just like to know well this is a
two-part question one how many
registrations you have received for the
20 pound transfer and number two when
that's going to go into effect so I'm
getting hand signals from the audience
and I believe the answer is 14
and I'll finish it off just because we
recently had a meeting on it and Jesse
wasn't able to join us because he had
another meeting but we will with about
between 10 and 15 applications and and
what we're doing right now is we're
working with the cannabis tracking
system with metric to be able to make it
so that transfer will be allowable in
the system one of the reasons is taking
a little bit of time is it due to grower
confidentiality we have to make sure
that we don't loosen the blocks between
recreational and medical too much we
really want to keep that on in the
forefront and so we're working on
getting that done as soon as possible
but what's your your guys's safety in
mind as well I have a question I I have
a company a seed to sale company and we
have four different licenses and we've
been doing this for a few years and I
find the renewal process to be really
bureaucratic and I'm wondering if you
guys are working on streamlining part of
the renewal process if you haven't had
any changes you know one of the
questions about have you ever had an
exception it's like yes three years ago
we had one so just you know if you
haven't had any changes are we working
on streamlining that not only to limit
your bureaucracy but ours as well
because it's a lot of work for us so the
short answer is yes absolutely I mean
it's definitely been difficult on our
end as well one of the biggest reasons
why it has been a member some process
for licensees is because of the volume
of changes that have happened both
legislatively and with our rules over
the last couple of years so somebody
license really early on by the time they
get to their renewal there's been a
number of changes in the requirements
that we just need to verify that they
meet those those current standards
there's also a lot of change going on in
the industry and we're seeing that at
the renewal time that's the time that
people are changing their tiers or
adding business partners or looking to
sell their business so it has been
cumbersome both for licensees and on our
end as well I think we finally have
gotten to a space though where we have a
pretty streamlined pack
pretty stripped down requirements just
making sure that there are no changes
and we're looking to get to a place
where we could almost have an automatic
type of renewal so that if there isn't
been no changes it can be just
instantaneous it is yet another area
that one of the reasons why we have
shifted our licensing staff over to
focusing more on those renewals we know
a lot of businesses want to make those
changes and so we need to get them
processed so that was the longer version
of a but yes we are working on it I
think we're actually getting into a good
space so that hopefully people that have
gone through that very cumbersome
process in the last year the next time
they renew it's gonna be much much
faster and easier yes I first of all I
thank all of you for your hard work and
dedication my question is along the same
lines as the previous question
referencing director marks August 30th
the memo that stated that there are two
investigators assigned to work on new
applications my question is are there
any additional personnel or resources
being applied or hopefully in your
future to be applied to processing new
applications to reduce the now 12 to 14
or longer month waiting period for a new
application processing appreciate that
question you know we asked for as extra
resources to help out Danica's licensing
team during this session we got some
during the emergency board time to help
move forward with the applications we
are not going to get any more relief
from staffing in the near term our
budget is set we only have a finite
number of folks so and as Danica
explained we're really looking at
getting those renewals moving forward so
it's gonna continue to be slow for
licensees it's one of the reasons that
we communicated out there because you
know we know people have a ton of
investment move in Florida I want you to
have realistic expectations about what
we can do I don't know what's going to
happen in the legislative session next
year when they look at us for our next
two-year budget
what we're gonna need and how they see
our system as you know we've got a lot
of supply in the hydro reports been out
there's discussions about ways to
moderate the overall system
we'll probably we're gonna be doing a
supply study on that and looking at that
as well we're not gonna make direct
recommendations legislature we may
provide them with ideas about how to
manage a large supply and the license
issue so I don't know what resources are
really gonna look like in the future
either so I think it's just we got to be
real with people about where we sit and
I don't think he can have the
expectation that suddenly we're gonna
bust loose and have a lot more folks to
then Licensing in the near term Mike but
relight growth systems federal
government has a long history of farm
subsidies after last season's incredible
market correction a lot of very
knowledgeable talent grower families
suffered all kinds of losses is there
any opportunity on a state level LLC sea
level that's really experienced you
several years of incredible tax revenues
of diverting some of that back to
farmers or back to people in the
industry
to support this nascent Oregon industry
so I'll take that one I think there is I
don't know where they want to apply it
but we've already seen you know who
legislature put some of those dollars to
work in an enforcement side right they
provided enforcement dollars criminal
justice Commission I think there's
discussion about how do you maybe
subsidize some number of patients and
the medical system that are indigent
with some of those dollars there is
requests I hear about having like a farm
subsidy program I don't know that that's
going to fly but I do know it's an
active conversation you know you are
generating a lot of dollars sales in the
last couple months have been continuing
to go up in terms of tax receipts so I
don't know how much of a and give I
certainly do think that
there's a strong interest in general
research medical research in general
research around the cannabis side
there's also this interest and how do we
support a broader nursery system and
we're going to need that I think
eventually maybe it's happening out
there but we haven't seen that nursery
endorsement really taking place where
you could have maybe more strains and
because now you have to realize your new
production inside the system we really
do need to make sure that those plants
are available and grown so people can
plant their crops in the future Adam so
the answer is there's some money there I
think some of it will be directed
towards the cannabis industry but I
can't tell you where it's all about the
dollars I can say we've watched a lot of
them having to use liquor staff on the
cannabis side and we really need to push
and talk to your legislators about
making sure that the allotment goes they
need more money they don't always say it
but I see it they need more money to
make this happen we want faster
turnaround times we want that it takes
staff there are limited people we've got
a limited you know this this guy's
deemed with taking care of all the
packaging and labeling that's a big
undertaking when you got so many product
lines coming in so they need more money
but they're held to what they have
budget wise so they've done an amazing
job with what I've seen them do just to
be able in size jump right back in here
because I do want to talk about one of
our main priorities one of our
efficiency points
you know our licensing system worked
well for us to get you up and running
we've produced over 200 million dollars
of tax revenue with that initial system
we put in well that hasn't worked well
for us for doing these renewals it's
failing us as failing Danica's team you
don't see that but this has really put a
lot of pressure on licensing because we
don't have that automation employees
we're looking we're gonna migrate out of
the system we are and they didn't do
anything you're wrong they helped us get
to where we are we're just in a new
product a new provider and when
you work on the policies that help that
move quicker so that you know we'll have
some efficiencies there so on behalf of
the agency we need some help with
getting our IT requests in place and
building that up that'll help you I have
a quick question I'm a little different
side than product it's more on the
service side are there any plans to
create a certification program similar
to Washington as the medical
certification program to recognize
consultants knowledge beyond that
tenders that kind of thing so what I
think the question refers to is a
program in Washington where they have
certified consultants who are actually
present in the retail as far as I know
there's nobody considering this type of
thing in Oregon I serve on the Oregon
cannabis commission and there are a
couple other members of that commission
present in the audience today that
Commission has been considering ideas
around provider training around employee
training which I think would be designed
to achieve the same type of goal that
the Washington program is shooting for
but doing it in a slightly different way
those are just proposals right now the
the cannabis Commission needs to
finalize its recommendations and those
will be coming out later in the year all
right thank you thank you very much
let's hear it again for the panel's
unfortunately that's all the time we
have for questions
[Applause]