we're going to talk about raising
capital it
moderated by Dean Arbit he's been a
trailblazer a trailblazer in cannabis
and cannabis related media he up found
smelled the truth which is a big website
on SFGate in 2011 and he currently he's
still the publisher for that and he runs
a lot of other different companies and
he's fantastic let's hear for the one
and only Dean Arbit everybody Dean Arbit
[Applause]
thank you for the spirited welcome and
and Alex as always he's not here but
thanks for a great show and a really
really good lunch by the way so this is
the investment panel something that is a
very hot button sort of item right now
and we've got two great experts we've
got Tedrow and arthur quan i don't want
to bring up what we're gonna do is talk
about investment and the need for
investment is as we all know so if you
plan to scale in this space right now
things have sort of reached a different
level and as we're seeing with big
private equity starting to come in and
obviously big money North in Canada
where federally they had their standing
allows them to raise massive amounts of
capital we've seen Constellation Brands
come in and dump four million dollars
into canopy blowing that valuation up we
see tilray of popping it over evaluation
of basically making them a bigger
company than in American Airlines and
other very large concerns over there
which underscores the need for if you're
going to compete you need to be able to
be well capitalized and we've got a
couple great resources here that did
that bring very different perspectives
to investors the
because these are the folks that will
help you raise money and they're the
folks that will help you make sure that
you do it compliantly so I'll just have
Arthur first just say a few things about
what you do in your company the can of
Income Fund okay hi my name is Arthur
Kwon on I'm a Canadian I run a private
equity fund up in Canada called Kenna
Income Fund we got started earlier this
year by way of background I was a former
investment banker for 18 years in Canada
so can i Income Fund is a diversified
cannabis investment fund we we invest
across the entire value chain of the
cannabis sector so cultivation
extraction production ancillary services
and dispensaries today we have eight
investments in our portfolio and we're
actively looking into the US right now
awesome and then we've got Ted Rowe who
is a legal professional and someone very
well versed in in the industry here in
Oregon Ted a little bit some about
yourself your practice testing oh there
we go
my name is Ted Rowe I'm an American I am
a practicing attorney based here in
Portland I've been representing clients
in a variety of industries for over 20
years I have been representing people in
the cannabis industry for well over 10
years now I also represent foreign
companies sometimes that are investors
sometimes that are involved in cases
already in the United States I
specialize in business and intellectual
property excellent thanks so Ted we'll
go right back to you
so I think something that really
interesting about your perspective is
that you work with different types of
entities clearly and in investment
circles there's a huge line between
being a company that touches a plant
versus a company that engages in an
ancillary business that does not so with
software platforms pipes Hardware do you
have do you are there different
strategies for approaching investors
based on the type of business that you
run that's an excellent question because
sometimes I represent businesses that
are seeking capital and sometimes I
represent the investors so I have a
perspective from both points of view I
would say with ancillary businesses
we're dealing with something that's
essentially unregulated and I mean
unregulated in a way that is no
different than a non cannabis business
so how you approach investors in there
are there are going to be some
similarities for example some one of the
things that you're going to want to
ensure when you're looking at investors
I'm sure Arthur can speak to this as
well is that you want to have a proper
valuation of your company and and I can
speak about this later if we like about
some of the brief regulations that
you're going to need to comply with SEC
regulations even to sell securities sell
stock in your company essentially but
one of the big things I see a problem
with frequently and it's across the
board whether it's ancillary or direct
cannabis businesses is an improper
valuation done with of your company and
this creates a couple of problems one is
it's hard to have an investor take you
seriously because they know what the
businesses are worth and so if you're
coming in substantially overvalued it's
hard to attract investors to begin with
number two is it creates actual legal
problems
are you well if you over value your
company and then people invest in it you
have a potential pretty high likelihood
actually that you could buy into what's
called the minority shareholder lawsuit
where if you can't deliver on the
numbers that you're talking about which
is very hard when you over value a
company that minority shareholder is
going to sue you and as a corporate
officer you have a duty a fiduciary duty
legal duty to minority shareholders so
that's one thing to keep in mind another
thing that is different in how you
approach investors from whether it's
ancillary or cannabis related is are
they permitted to invest in your company
to begin with and we had a we had an
interesting discussion in the green room
before we came out about this and that
is if it's an ancillary service anyone
can invest in it it can be a foreign
national it can be someone from another
state however if it's a direct cannabis
business if you're if it requires a
state license as a producer retailer or
wholesaler or processor for example in
Washington not only can foreign
nationals not you can't even can't even
be from another state you have to be an
Oregon resident I'm sorry Washington
resident Oregon has a much less strict
scheme however that being said there's
nothing in the regulations that permits
it it just doesn't not allow it if that
makes sense and but there are problems
for example we have to get background
checks to be a licensed in the in a
direct cannabis business in Oregon how
can organ do that if it's a foreign
national what makes it tough is if
you're for instance a a company that's
regulated you've got
you got to do background checks if you
have a public company for instance
that's on your that owns more than 20%
of your company then technically
everybody from that public company all
the directors would need to get
background checks for the application
for a grow or a dispensary so that's a
little prohibitive but those are great
points to let's maybe shift a little bit
to one of the interesting things having
a Canadian you guys are the guys with
all the money right now and access to
capital being what it is there are a lot
less companies actually making money in
cannabis in Canada relative to the US
and so right now we we spoke you've got
several investments in Canadian concerns
and right now you're evaluating
opportunities in the US no that's that's
right you know the the interesting thing
about the US market that we're finding
is that a lot of companies that were you
know we're evaluating either in
California or Nevada or Florida they all
have revenue and and most of them
actually not only do they have revenue
but that's they have positive cash flow
and that's a bit of a refreshing change
from in Canada so for example there's
about a hundred and twenty ticker
symbols on my screen right now of
cannabis and cannabis related companies
on either the Canadian Securities
Exchange or the Toronto Venture Exchange
or the big board TSX but I you know most
of them are at the preview stage and you
know in our portfolio of companies only
two of them are in revenue so so that's
why we like the US market so much and
we're actively seeking investments I
mean you know there's certain foreign
investment requirements that we need to
follow but there's a lot of capital in
Canada
Arthur are there specific verticals or
segments of the business that you guys
find more attractive yeah so the almost
all the companies that were evaluating
evaluating right now are vertically
integrated or they have multi licenses
across multi states that seems to be you
know the area that's attracting the most
amount of capital so it's no surprise
that you know there's been a
proliferation of US companies doing our
TOS or reverse takeovers onto the
Canadian Securities Exchange so you know
we all know about Mad Men green thumb
industries I'm aware of at least eight
other US companies that are filing
they're listing statements or prospectus
is to become listed on the CSC right now
so it's it's a it's a very hot market
very much so so we we actually discussed
and I think in in both sort of comments
there I think valuation is a big thing
so I think maybe to come back to that
and we can sort of both yours as far as
opinions or their multiples right now
that we're seeing that are sort of
prevailing how you value your business X
amount of income equals this value or
revenue okay yeah so when we look at
evaluating a potential investments we
look at three things so the first one is
the management team and the board of
directors you know what have they done
before their track record their
backgrounds then the second criteria is
in generally speaking we look at the
business plan you know what segments of
the value chain they're in whether we
see it as and what's their niche or
their competitive advantage in that
segment and lastly we look at valuation
and it's no surprise that the the
valuations are just insane in the public
markets and we you know we see quite a
lot so so when we're evaluating
companies
in Remy you what we typically do is we
apply a some sort of financial metric so
maybe ev2 EBIT or price to cash flow or
price to revenue and we take a discount
of that to the publicly traded
comparables if a company is pre-revenue
then that's a that's a general rule of
thumb where we we need to be comfortable
with the management team and their
ability to execute on a business plan
and if they're coming to us at say a
pretty money valuation of X million we
have to justify that and with a company
that's you know that doesn't have Remy
you the the financial metrics go out the
door then it's it's more of a
qualitative judgment on management as
opposed to a quantitative peer
quantitative measure and probably you're
leaning on you know scarcity or sort of
other variables there that make that
offering unique yeah did you have some
insight absolutely I agree in large part
with what Arthur said I've seen one of
the largest things that you discussed
that's important to my clients when
their investors are the management team
and definitely my clients have had me do
checks on background checks on board of
directors of companies before they put a
penny in but that being said and I agree
also that with existing companies that
have an existing revenue stream it's
somewhat easier to to approximate
valuation you know you have hard assets
you have your P&amp;L you can look at to
start giving you an idea of the value of
a company beyond the the more esoteric
valuations of how how much do you trust
the directors of the company to affect
their their business plan I think the
real problem exists when it is a
pre-revenue company when you're even
more difficult when it's a pre-license
company
in this industry where you have a
start-up you don't even have a license
yet how do you value this company and I
think that's a real question I think
what it ultimately comes down to when if
you set aside the value of the
particular individuals involved in the
business and look at just dollar
valuation how do we do this
I often advise my clients when I'm
representing that not the investors but
the other side the business raising the
capital to look at just like when you're
selling or by owning buying real estate
you look at comps so often we will say
okay we don't want overvalued the
company but we don't want to cut our
legs out from us we want to be right in
there something realistic so we can look
to comparable businesses and what kind
of revenue they're doing to kind of fill
in that X in the equation although there
is no magic equation that gets you to
the answer what ultimately you're gonna
have to do is do an appropriate
valuation based on comparable businesses
what they're doing in the comparable
market because what a cannabis retailer
does in Seattle is not what they do in
Portland is not what they do in Miami is
not what they do in LA it just isn't
so it has to be you you have to use
comparable numbers and you can't kind of
over blow this but a start-up might be
much more valuable if they already owned
existing real estate because there are
all kinds especially from foreign
investment because if the foreign
investor doesn't have to invest in real
estate there's a whole federal law they
don't need to comply with them to all
say this actually as from being an
investor in an operator one thing is
looking at investors and trying to
derive a valuation as a company I think
it's also really really important to
look at the kind of investor and how
strategic that money
went coming up with the value can that
investor do anything else for you can he
open more doors is he going to be there
after you execute and commit to round
two rounds the following rounds and so I
think there's there's a lot of sort of
sort of beyond how you measure that the
proper investor and a sort of a
strategic part and going forward I think
there's a lot of things that you look at
from the other side as well as a company
that that's looking for funding and what
number I'd be comfortable with given
what that investor is and the other sort
of resources that they bring right no
absolutely I agree with that you know
it's it is a competitive space up in
Canada for for both capital and good
what I would call good deal flow so for
example one of the companies that we
invested in is a consumables company
they're positioning themselves for the
when that segment of the market becomes
legal up in Canada and they you know
they were being courted by several other
private equity firms including us and
one of the reasons why they chose to go
with us is because of the strategic
value that that we bring to the table
you know we were pretty well networked
in Canada we can open up a lot of doors
in terms of their distribution and
dispensaries strategies and their
manufacturing strategies so I think it
you know from from the company's point
of view you know you should always look
at what type of investment dollars and
that's why you know for a public company
that are that's raising capital in
Canada there's a tendency to to bring on
you know the fast money the the guys
that are in it for a short term trade
whereas on the private equity side you
know the the companies that we're
talking to are more interested in you
know the the type of money the strategic
value that the investors bring to the
evil not just dollars that's that's an
excellent issue that you raised and
since I'm I'm assuming I could be wrong
but most of you are businesses wanting
to raise capital and not investors
looking to invest in cannabis businesses
so I want to say this as well and that
is don't think that you're the only one
who has to have the background checks
done you should check out your investors
you should know who they are you should
talk to other people who they've done
deals with you should know their
motivation and one actually in Ted you
know what a good point is if if if
anyone is worth their weight they'll be
happy to give you resources on folks
that they've done deals with and well
those folks should obviously you know
obviously be proponents of these guys so
they should that's something to ask
absolutely and if there is a
circumstance where you're asking for
essentially deal references and they're
unwilling to give them that is a large
red flag and I don't care what they're
promising you that is a that is a
serious red flag in and I'm not saying
just drop the deal but I would be very
wary about moving forward without
additional information that being said I
also want to let you know that there you
there's more than one way to raise money
for your businesses the two we've talked
about one of them which is essentially
equity investment but that's not the
only way of doing this you can structure
these deals essentially any way you want
and one of the large ways of doing that
is debt financing or essentially
obtaining loans and actually when I'm
representing companies like yours rather
than the investors I tell them to I tell
them to kind of steer away try to steer
away from equity investment as much as
you can rather than maybe do a one-year
loan that it's called a convertible note
it converts to a
to equity at the end of that year
because if you're doing the loan in the
name of the business for example and the
you say you're a producer and the in the
crop fails or and the business ends up
going under you also don't want to have
personal liability for you know a two
million dollar loan but at the same time
you need to know who you're doing
business with because does this investor
have eyes on taking the business over
you know business is business they say
that for a reason and and you need to be
sophisticated businesspeople and your
strengths may lie in other areas
processing retail production but this is
what I start I started one night when I
first started lecturing at these things
years ago and I talked about tax
consequences I said I understand that a
lot of people who started in this
industry were operating to a certain
level of illegality for a long time but
now that it's in the light everything
has to be on the up-and-up
you got a pair taxes you got to pay your
property taxes employment taxes you got
to comply with your regulations these
licenses are extremely valuable and you
don't want to do anything that's going
to jeopardize them but that being said
look at all the options available to you
and not just one when it comes to the
issue of raising capital because debt
financing is a perfectly legitimate way
of raising capital for your companies or
you go up and you win the pitch at the
ICBC like my folks over there so here's
what we want to do i I think that
there's they're business owners here in
the room and and we're sitting here
because investment is some interesting
stuff and I think there may be some
questions out there so I think we're
getting kind of down to it and I want to
make sure that if there are questions
out there that that we can address them
so take it out
wait wait let me bring the microphone to
you everybody well no it's easier it's
part of these gettin paid he's we're
taping it right also it's part of my job
description yeah yeah the Union rule sir
in this Oregon marketplace which in the
last year is turned into people really
needing to cut back and get smaller and
get tight and get you know much more
control over their costs and get control
over the actual amount that can be sold
in this Mart in the market how then can
you think about evaluation when you're
looking at a traditional thing I can
multiply our Viva de I mean if you're
being because of an artificially
restricted marketplace the amount that's
actually able to be sold is restricted
how do you think about if you're a small
time you know we're a small farm and
we're looking to get outside investment
and we have to put a valuation on
ourselves how do we ourselves think
about it in terms of our brain trust in
terms of our equipment in terms of our
proprietary ways of going knowing that
multipliers sometimes you know show
things the wrong way I mean that's
that's one big number one of our
problems well starting on that because I
think it's a great question but I don't
think it does anything to actually
really turn any of the the numbers
upside down at all I think you're still
market share and I think it's par for
the course because your competitors are
dealing with the same issues right so
there was a race to the bottom your guys
that the the price is here that you know
the bottom fell out and but you guys are
all dealing with it right and at the end
of the day you still have numbers you're
still you've got product going to stores
everyone's margins are down everyone's
numbers are down but at the end of the
day if you have market share here when
then when the market goes back up your
margins will rise I think obviously a
big part in something that folks do know
serious investors do know about the push
for Oregon to be an export state and
that's clearly something that you all in
this state really need to fight for
really need to fight for and in all your
competitors those are comps I would
argue that you have more comps than
other markets do I understand your
problem isn't that the comps are all
down but that's not the he's just trying
to find the data the information how do
you find like doing what you talk to
people like you you need to talk to
people but that's not the only asset
that you have you talked about one
potential revenue stream that can
potentially I'm not saying it can but it
potentially can cross state boundaries
and that is intellectual property you
can license processes and that can be a
revenue stream for you and and IP is one
of those things that can be more easily
valued than the entire business but I
understand I'm talking about I got my
weed it's worth less now and how do I
value that but yeah so as a business
owner if you're looking for outside
investment but you're worried about
valuation and multiples of EBIT you know
said there are other
non-dilutive investment vehicles so you
know loans are just one of them but you
know I know of three Canadian companies
that are offering royalties to US
businesses so gross overriding royalties
of gores is one secure convertible notes
or convertible debentures so there's
other avenues outside of equity where
you need to place a value on your
business to access capital that's a
great point and also you don't want it
that's the one thing is right now if you
do have to raise and valuations or being
depressed then actually debt financing
it's a pretty good way to sort of hedge
against that yeah more questions and
Gayo the past administration had a
hands-off kind of
with the current administration is there
any concern of the feds coming in and
making some sort of headways or waves I
guess I can speak to that there has been
well Jeff Sessions did say that he
wanted to take a more active role in
curbing marijuana industry cannabis
industry in the United States that's
absolutely true the Cole memorandum
still exists though there's been nothing
else that's overridden that that being
said we had a discussion earlier where
we were talking about foreign investment
and what effects that could have what
could come into play in the United
States with regard to foreign investment
into a direct cannabis industry and I
talked about it's called a 18 USC 1952
it's a federal law that prohibits and
criminalizes the promoting distribution
and there's all these adjectives of any
illegal activity and since cannabis is
still listed in the Controlled
Substances Act
technically foreign investment could be
viewed as a violation of that law not
being said as far as I know it's not
being prosecuted but that doesn't mean
it won't be and and given the current
administration I fell let's put it this
way I felt safer under wealth in general
under the Obama administration so sure
just in general you think
hello there so I'm currently actually an
Oregon laboratory of I'm I'm the oldest
laboratory in Oregon for a test cannabis
and I'm seeking expansion I've been
warned that if I get investment money
from Canada
already been some people that have done
this and something about not being able
to cross borders and come across or vice
versa because of the investment can you
do can you help clarify what alright
that's about yep so you're absolutely
right I mean I'm aware of several
Canadians that have been banned for life
from entering into the u.s. because they
have either invested in a cannabis
company or smoked cannabis or try
cannabis and even you know myself I was
just seeing this too dead in the green
room when I came from Canada I I
actually brought two phones you know my
real phone that I put in my luggage and
then a burner phone in case I get
stopped at the border but that's the
risk that you you know as a Canadian
looking to invest in US companies you
you have to you have to take and but you
know what I can say is that you know
there's there's that has not in my mind
deterred any Canadians from looking into
the US you know there's there several
financial companies and investment
companies that are all actively looking
into the u.s. because you the one thing
about Canada is that while there's no
shortage of cannabis companies like I
said before most of them are at the
pre-revenue stage and if you look at the
multiples that these companies are being
traded at it's you know it's it's very
lofty
I've never heard of that before though
so I think that if you go so at the
border if they ask you for what you do
you don't tell them cannabis yeah
well I don't think he said you should
lie and he just said but not don't if
you're if you're in production you can
tell them you're a farmer and they still
have that be a true statement go ahead
and do your thing
see what happens it it's it's a funny
story I just told them I just told them
I was attending a conference and they
were like which conference oh yeah the
International Canopus business
conference and then they're like did you
bring any cannabis no you guys got
pretty good weed here at Vancouver and
they're like enjoy your you enjoy your
vacation sir so that happened when I
left Berlin too so I mean I don't think
you need to let on that you're a million
dollar investor and a bunch of cannabis
industries or whatever but you know if
you're just coming to town to throw a
conference that they're throwing they
can't sweat you too much I don't know
who knows what this American
government's gonna do that's all you
know what's ironic about this is that
the US has been promoting programs for
many years that that solicit investment
from foreign nationals so they're called
a eb-5 programs where this is a really
large thing in China it's a way that and
it's a way to fast-track somebody's
immigration status in the United States
they can become an US citizen within a
couple of years if they I think it's
five million dollars for certain under
certain projects or ten million dollars
under others but I think that we are
doing our own country to service by not
allowing this kind of foreign investment
into u.s. we could be bringing in
substantial what it does is it brings
forth the how fractured the the the laws
are between state and federal because
when you've got a Canadian coming from a
place where federally what he does is
legal and he's coming to California
where you know we pay our taxes or
Oregon where we pay our taxes and we pay
for our permits and you know we're
vested in in this industry yet it's
still a crime because of the federal
level the federal layer so it's just
part of the goofy nature of where we're
at and that's also why banking is what
it is as well so these are just hurdles
and they'll make it stronger I guess
more questions I own a building and I'm
having great difficult I'm having great
difficulty in refinancing the building
because originally the building didn't
have anything that had to do with
cannabis now it does and so what's your
suggestion on how to finance the
building without going too hard money
lenders who charge you an arm and a leg
and watch your leg as well I can I can
speak a bit to that I I had a client in
an identical circumstance what she's
talking about is essentially theirs
because the banking industry is
regulated federally they have
essentially told banks that if they
financed directly finance operations
that house cannabis industry companies
they can lose their licensure under the
federal banking regulations so you know
you're not you're not gonna get
financing from US bank or Chase or just
so completely put that out of your head
there you're in a tie I won't lie to you
you're in a tough situation outside of
self financing hard money lenders or
putting up sufficient allowed but even
then even if you had sufficient
collateral you simply can't get
financing from a mainstream bank there
are well there there was for a while
what Merchants Bank and Bank was doing
it but they weren't and for many years
now they did it for a little while but
there's no banks as far as I know in
Oregon that will do what you need to
have done what do you do you yeah so
private financing I can jump yes so up
in Canada
we have a couple reads so real estate
investment trusts that focus on cannabis
real estate vehicles like that there
ones here but obviously you can't do
that because they are they state
operated their state operated or they
private no other private okay but they
they lend against real estate but that's
essentially what he's describing what
you're describing is hard money lending
right you know and really that is your
option and that's one of the reasons why
those rates are so high because they
know they're the only option yeah so
I've met with Canadian companies as well
according me but from what I understand
from what you said that that's something
that I shouldn't even touch I didn't say
that and especially under these
circumstances I think you would be
that's one potential Avenue for you
because you don't own a well let me take
the fact are you okay shopping center
yes but you need refinancing of a
company that is not a license holders is
real estate just real estate so ya know
if she's taking if she's taking money
from the Canadians for real estate you
can absolutely do that
that's that's what I need to do that you
can absolutely jack in fact that yes
that's one of the great things that I do
want to tell everyone is you can get
break up you can break up your company's
a bit and get foreign investment by
saying allowing them to buy the real
estate and then you pay them uh your
lease it's just a sale lease pal right
exactly exactly yeah you have a hard
asset that it US lending institutions
have a tough time with but not Canadian
ones but that's that is permitted you
you absolutely can do that I think in
the end besides finding investors who
are interested in your businesses please
please please consult with lawyers
I'm not saying me I mean I'd be happy to
speak with you but talk to a lawyer
retain a lawyer because these are very
technical rules that you could easily
violate without ever realizing it and
the penalties are relatively severe I
think one more in the event that someone
did get an investor let's say we have
the company and you're getting invested
into where's the money going to go into
if we're having these banking issues
already where we're gonna be able to get
your money in to be able to work it with
the company that we are built so so why
one of the opportunities that we're
looking at is a vertically integrated
operation in California and so I asked
them the exact same question and you
know like Ted said you can't go to Bank
of America or Chase or Wells Fargo but
what they said that they they do they've
been doing business for the last eight
months with a credit union in California
and they they said that the this credit
union has a don't-ask-don't-tell policy
and that's and that's what it seems to
be working for them so so generally it's
a lot tougher to get financing from a
bank but you can play around and you
need some redundancy like have multiple
bank accounts I think that's how most
most of us do it
you get shut down you got to have
another one yeah yeah and I think credit
unions are a good option if you if you
can if you can get it but I think this
also suggests that it's everyone's
responsibility here to tell their
friends and everyone else to contact
there's us congressmen senators about
changing the federal banking laws that
allow this to be operated like any other
regulated business because that's we're
paying the same taxes
even more of them yeah guys I think
that's it that's it that's our time
thank you guys so much hear it again
Dean our Bert the rest of the panel and