so we're going to move right into the
next panel also this is our last panel
before lunch and when you get lunch
don't forget to get a chance to go check
out some of our exhibitors and maybe
donate to the Lions Club uh flood fund
right the ICBC is going to match up to 1
000 Euros so if everybody puts in a
thousand Euros we can drive Alex
bankrupt all right
um which we shouldn't do because he
flies me out here okay coming up now
discuss harnessing research to move the
industry forward to lead this panel to
moderate uh he's a researcher at the
research institute and the faculty of
Health Sciences at the University of
Ljubljana let's hear it for Roman
[Applause]
so welcome to the panel about research
and Industry which I'm very excited to
moderate especially because if I
remember correctly from previous ICBC
meetings which were held in Berlin in
Barcelona there was a conclusion made
that cannabis Industries is one of the
last emerging and fast-growing
industries of 21st century and if we
just quick look into the numbers in 2021
the legal Global Economist Market did
more than 13 billion euros in revenue
and the legal Global hemp Market did
almost 4 million euros in European Union
the legal Market is estimated to be
worth up to 130 billion euros by 2028
and it's likely to become the world's
largest market in next five years
so we see there is a lot of money
involved in the Cannabis industry and we
who work in the research field we know
that research is all about the money
um and it's it is it is also known that
there is no growth of any industry
without developed in financial stable
research sector which can produce Next
Generation products
this and this brings me to my dear guest
panelists here we have uh four two from
Slovenian research and academic sphere
um assistant professor Andrea chernak
from Slovenian Institute of hop research
and Brewing Luca bitesnik from
biotechnical faculty and then we have
two companies bands are representing
Genesis and Clement from planze
and my name is Roman stukel I'll be a
moderator of today's panel and just to
Quick introduction if we can start with
the slides
so I'm a researcher at Research
Institute in the faculty of Health
Sciences where our main research
activity is related to analytical
identification and quantification of
secondary metabolites in the cannabis
plant and for this purpose we developed
a methodology and one year later science
still ongoing cooperational agreement
with our industrial partner research
nature Institute we have to say that we
our collaboration was very fruitful from
the start because we have a opportunity
to work with very International
prominent people from research field of
cannabis here on the picture you can see
Dr Hornby who sadly passed away last
year but you can also see a professor Dr
Ilya Resnick and also professor hanosh
um
our current activities related in in the
faculty are related to education we also
think that education is very important
uh in the field so together with our
partner we are organizing educational
seminars in our faculty through the
center of lifelong learning and in
approximately 30 days we will have
already a third edition and I would like
to invite all of you knowledge seeking
people to come and join us in on the
event we also have a credit points for
doctors and nurses
but our research activity is related to
a collaboration with biotechnical
faculty and also with Ben's company
Genesis in both cases we are responsible
for analytical support
but we also started to doing mapping of
whole Slovenian mapping of products
which were industrial and unindustrial
and last year we also had a privilege or
we were invited to show some preliminary
results in Ghana World Congress in
Medellin Medellin Colombia
okay so that will be from my side but
before I give the word to other
panelists I would like to ask one
question which I guess ask a lot and I
think many of you would like to know the
answer to I know Andrea and Luca that
you are working and your organizations
are the only one in Slovenia in the
research field who I mean research in
breeding who also have license to grow
THC strains for research purposes which
you will show in a minute and we know
the gene modification and genome editing
presents fear among many of us due to
the lack of the knowledge on any other
reason but for example breeders around
the world are already using uh Gene
editing to eliminate or nearly eliminate
production of THC in the plants but I
would like to know from you if your
research work on breeding also includes
any Gene modification technique
uh thank you for question we are in our
breeding program we're using different
biotechnology biotechnological methods
and approaches like different molecular
markers genotyping tissue cultures and
so on we are using also crispr for in
hop science but not yet in cannabis but
we are looking forward for these now New
York regulation which is focused on new
genomic techniques which will be
approved as I hope as soon as possible
great
yes thank you for the answer for the
question so basically the answer is
quite similar to Andreas
we don't
use anything for genome editing but we
use some molecular techniques for
support breeding so yes molecular
markers for sex determination or
genotyping but as I know there is a plan
in our research group to use crisprcas
on cannabis but this would be just for
research purposes nothing for commercial
okay so the moment you there is a gm3
plants growing cool it's always nice to
know okay so we will start with the
panelists presentations and after we go
to the questions first from me and then
from the public
so please
so hello I'm coming from Slovenian
Institute Institute for Hope research
and Brewing
since let's say the first relative cut
to cannabis is hops you can imagine that
we can use our Decades of experience and
methods and labs and all other
facilities for very useful breeding in
cannabis industry as well so I'm a
planned breeder I'm always a professor
at the University in Ljubljana for plant
breeding I have a okay I'm the first
author of more than 10 Hub varieties
which are also plant protected and we
have American Paint patent as well so I
think that we can really have successful
breeding program in cannabis as well
my two topics which I would like to
expose are one the first is more linked
to uh to varieties which are growing
outdoor so we just realized years ago
that in our varieties for outdoor
growing are quite different in between
the population so since there are
population varieties and in three
varieties Carl Manola selected and
Finola selection we found 11 different
phenotypes this is meaning that there
are they can be morphologically
different so our idea was that we can
find let's say a correlation between a
red vine and high CBD perhaps in some
variety and then can just easily we can
phenotype these plants select them and
have a new variety which could be used
for outbreak outdoor growing So based on
then we have done a different
analysis we were focused as you can
imagine on the main types components of
both groups and out of that base
basically based we then sequenced also
our some spots in the DNA from different
phenotypes and we use different uh so
genome sequences which are now available
and we were focused on more than 40
different traits we and we found let's
say correlation with uh High
correlations with perhaps THC synthesis
the gene which is mainly included in THC
expression so this is one of the PHD
thesis which is growing doing on at our
Institute together with the faculty of
so biotechnical faculty and the faculty
of Pharmacy as professor struckel before
mentioned and show our first let's say
scientific articles the next one is
we are very proud of that because this
is a completely a combination between
private and public sector so we have
very good cooperation with fitochemp
this is Czech company which is focused
on getting different products from a
cannabis plant together with as I
mentioned the University of for pharmacy
and farfermit the company from Ljubljana
so our main goal is to create new
new cannabis varieties indoor we have
allowances Roman already mentioned so
our goals in our breeding program are of
course high yield to centralized
compound compounds high THC and high CBD
our first goal is high THC so we are
working indoor as you can see we have
now few Generations we are using
molecular markers you can see for sex
determination that we can be as much as
possible
efficients we are doing our first
Crossings we have very promising first
results for high THC values and now we
try to also feminization because we are
trying to of course we have the variety
which can be sold with by using seeds or
water clones what is really painful for
me as my point of view is that at the
end we need to destroy all these perfect
material which could be really used for
different kinds of clinical research and
I think it was mentioned also
before from the other panelists that our
legislation needs to be let's say move
forward in this kind of work as well
so we are using different feminization
as I mentioned cuttings in Vivo then
also in vitro techniques for different
genotypes which we are using and we are
using our accredited laboratory for
chemistry at our Institute to determine
all these mentioned compounds uh before
so thank you very much and if there are
any questions I don't hesitate to ask me
later on thank you
please look at this
hello
um yes I'm working on PhD thesis I focus
on cultivation of
hemp and medical cannabis and I'll
present you our work in a
few slides
everything is done under supervision of
assistant professor Marco Fleischmann so
our best research revolved around
negative propagation and selection of
mother plants of ham varieties for CBD
production
we studied four varieties with 30
genotypes per variety
we evaluate the mother plant branching
using three different pruning techniques
over longer period of time we evaluate
the rooting ability of the root system
so basically how one genotype is used
useful for vacative propagation by steam
cuttings and we did analysis of
secondary metabolites based on collected
data we select the desire the genotypes
with desired traits and save it for
later research
now our attention is round two cannabis
grafting if you don't know what grafting
is this means conjunction of at least
two different plant parts together to
form a grafted plant
and
we are studying how different rootstocks
affects the science so how different
root system affects the upper part of
the plant so each the basically the
whole plant and we are studying the
morphology physiological parameters and
biochemical parameters of the plants
and right now we are also working in
breathing or we are breathing new
varieties we are working on CBG genetics
and CBD the ultimate goal is to develop
feminized seeds of industrial hemp so
for production in Slovenia we are
crossing for CBG the foreign CBG
genetics so they obtain new ones with
CBD we are
preliminary crossing the high CBD
genotypes selected genotypes with
selected
Industrial Hemp genotypes and the idea
is again to get a feminized seeds of
industrial hemp
thanks
[Applause]
I think Benson has video too
sure
uh hello hello everyone my name is benza
Matias I'm the CEO and founder of the
Genesis sfr uh it's a Hungarian company
let's say startup so four years old The
Innovation company
um we are involved in both upstream and
the downstream space utilization which
means that our basic research was
related to Mars
in in order to we were cooperating with
the jetpapers and laboratory of the NASA
if you know this department they are
responsible for the Mars rovers
development and many other analytical
technique in order to detect Organics on
the on the planet Mars so that was a
open call like four years ago and we
were at the Latin American station in
the Cotopaxi volcano a suggesting to the
jet prep person laboratory the most
viable analytical tool which can be used
for Mars research so we made our own
experiments in this world channels and
also other research groups were involved
in this decision but the choice was a
microchip electrophoresis based
instrumentations so when we established
our own first that was a spin-off and
after we make another entity in Hungary
we use the same technology this which is
coming from space for this microchip
electrophoresis microchipelectrove is a
really big family and basically it
serves nowadays medical purpose in human
medicine they use this for cancer and
diabetes too early detection
using mainly glyconic structures they
are free sugars oligos groups and we are
using it to get information of the
protein stress level before the visual
symptoms appear why it's important for
us it's important also for the upstream
and also for the downstream utilization
in the US stream because of that we can
provide a proper Health monitoring of
the of the plants and space
basically for the people who are
involved in Pharma business it's not new
that most of the big discoveries
happening in the International Space
Station especially in the Russian cabin
because the the big Pharma companies
sometimes rent the place for research
the researching was like one one month
basically we also get an opportunity
thanks to the huner Hungarian astronauts
program we will launch our own
equipments to the International Space
Station for two purposes one is for
human medicine and other for plant
utilization so let me talk about a
little bit about the downstream space
technology because that's why we are
here and that's why we receive this kind
invitation and opportunity is that we
are developing different
species-specific modules to detect early
stress in plants and the previous years
in the previous seven years we were
focusing on tomato
indoor application after we went outdoor
and we were measuring mainly Maze and
sunflower in over 600 hectares we
started in Hungary and now we are
expanding our partner programs in
Slovenia as well and since this year we
are new in this medical cannabis
business or our current project is make
a single run separation for 14
cannabioids with a portable device it's
a microchip electrophoresis device which
I can compare mostly for hplc which you
can use it's a liquid separation based
technology but it we don't use any
moving Parts in the device so that's why
we can bring it outside without
significant effort and calibrational
recalibrations these device must be
calibrated after every 5 20 000
measurements and also about the
manufacturers so our main line is a
glycanic research
um it's basically in the molecular
analysis and we receive information of
the of the proteins protein health so we
already started to build up our database
for the macro and micro elements uh
deficiency so we can compare these
changes in this glyconic structure
compared to that so the farmers not or
the grover not only receive information
about what is the element composition
what is the the element which was
uptaken to the plants already but also
they will have some reference database
and it also serves as a decision support
tool in terms of the leaf fertilization
and other terms
can be really useful
um in the indoor applications we are
going back to the lab because now we are
testing thanks to the the nature
research research nature Institute of
Slovenia thanks to bonjour we receive
opportunity to validate our Technologies
with also with hpsc methodologies which
is more well known in the analytical uh
industry so we are comparing our data
sets with the hplc results and also this
aim or aim for this series also get it
to the national standards with this
microchip electrophoresis technology we
have a kind of easy way in order to do
validation because this technology is
coming from the capillary
electrophoresis and the capillary has a
very well
um Publications I mean in the literature
is very well known and most of the
people
aware about this but the hpsc which I I
think is is in a wider range of of this
industry so with the microchip
electrophoresis uh we're trying to get a
bigger range of individuals who are
using it because of its sustainable
features I'm talking about the less
chemical usage we are talking about
micro liters per samples when we are
using also the other relegends which are
involved in the sample preparation in
the measurements are very low and not
talking about the energy usage like also
if you can compare a big machine like
hpsh on the table and compared to a
portable device it can be obvious that
the it has a really minimal energy and
and the chemical demand we came up with
a brand called Geno plant so at the
moment we have four modules on the
market for plantless search and now
thanks to a cooperation We are
continuing for soil measurements for the
same technology so we are very grateful
for the opportunity to test all devices
on this market and we already made a
great step already in this year I think
because of we started single around
separation of these 14 cannabis also we
are trying to expand our portfolio in
time of methodology and serving real
Market needs thank you so much for for
the opportunity thank you it's great
thanks
we'll move on with Clement and his
company planze
hello my name is Clemen
and I would like to present our new
technology that we developed for a
cannabis plant cultivation it's a stem
infusion system
so when my brother and I started a
company we were
very interested in how to increase yield
in cannabis growth so when we started
the the the state of the art we came to
conclusions that they're like so in in
the world people can grow cannabis with
crazy yields right now and more or less
it has plateaued so what we realized was
that the reason why cannabis cannot
yield more is the two main factors one
it can only do as much photosynthesis as
it can no matter how much light you put
that's one limitation and the other
limiting factor is that it can absorb
only so many nutrients through the root
system so no matter how much you
fertilize it will only absorb so much so
these are the two main drivers that
drive yield
so
um for this with this we we thought
about what if we were able to deliver
energy and nutrients directly into the
plant stem to avoid the leaves to bypass
the root system
so this technology
um
was done already on other agricultural
crops but with
reimagined it and developed it
specifically for cannabis cultivation so
it consists of three components one is
the infusions device itself that
attaches directly to the plant stem then
it's a pressure splitter because you
need to provide these nutrients into the
plant Under Pressure so we have a
pleasure pressure splitter so you can
apply this to multiple plants at the
same time and then we developed our
proprietary medium that contains water
and only compounds that are naturally
present in the plant stem so it's we're
not adding any chemicals to it so
um how it works basically after the
plant has gone through the vegetative
stage uh you so after it has been the
regime has been switched to flower
um you attach the the infusion system to
the plant and and you leave it on until
the end of the growth cycle it's in the
heart until the Harvest so there is
nothing else you need to do so the
device then slowly injects nutrients
over time uh through the uh under under
the pressurized system
everything else stays the same so the
flowering regime stays the same the
fertilization regime stays the same this
is basically an add-on to the operation
and what we found was that we did two
larger studies
one was with biotechnical faculty Luca
was actually part of that study we are
publishing a scientific paper towards
the end of the year from the study and
we did another study uh with a
professional grower who is also here
today with us you can talk to to him
directly also so where we looked at how
this technology impacts their regular
growth line so in both cases we were
able to show 25 percent increase in
in dry and wet flower biomass and we
just last week with analyzed also the uh
the cannabinoid content with hplc and we
realized that also the amount of
cannabinoids stays the same
proportionally so concentration of
cannabinoids stays the same or is even
slightly increased so in this in you get
20 five percent more flour with the same
or slightly higher cannabinoid
concentration so this can significantly
boost
the profitability and the production of
of uh
cannabinoids and and cannabis flowers uh
additionally we observed no adverse
effects for the plants so uh plants
stayed healthy they even looked a little
bit better because they had because
because they receive water as part of
their infusion system so they were less
sensitive to uh the watering Cycles so
they they stayed more upright throughout
growth
um
okay so what at this stage we are
looking to expand this technology to
more professional Growers so if this is
an exciting technology for you or you
are looking for ways to increase your
yield uh yeah please come and talk to us
we are both here uh we are doing uh
Pilots now with couple of organizations
so uh yeah happy to to do one with you
as well
thank you everybody for these nice
presentations
I think we still have time for some
questions from me which I prepared
um we will start
Andrea one of the main goal of your
project I saw is on the presentation is
to increase the yield and also the level
of secondary metabolites in the plant
what are the actually the main
challenges you and your team is facing
with your research group regarding CBD
and THC strains
uh thank you yeah the main thing is that
cannabis plant is quite heterogeneous so
whenever you're doing Crossings or
feminization you can expect different
kinds of plants but we have experiences
from Hop as I mentioned as well it's
comparable in that way all the other
techniques can be used as I mentioned
different markers which are available so
this is main thing which are we're doing
what is our let's say more or less thing
which I would like to expose it that
when we will have a let's say new
variety it's still not the legislation
so far in Slovenia that we could grow
that plants in under civilian conditions
which is strange in a way because from
the ministry we just get the info let's
say some time ago that in Slovenia in
general we could produce just let's say
a few grams which is needed in for
Slovenian patients which is a ridiculous
ridiculous comparing to that let's say
if we make a comparison we we are the
fifth producer of hops in the world and
we are exporting 98 of it so why
shouldn't we we be exporting country for
cannabis flowers as well so this is more
or less the thing which I'm thinking as
a breeder we will have very good variety
for our for course for our customer but
we could grow now they are preparing the
the places in the countries which are
let's say a few steps forward regarding
the legislation like Germany Czech
Republic and I hope that Slovenia will
be there as soon as possible I think we
will follow very soon you also mentioned
that you're trying to present I mean to
make a product from the partner in the
industry and I would to launch it
commercially so how do you assure the
standards and which cannabis products on
the market requires let's say from the
field to to the final product on the
Shelf yeah we have for this outdoor
growing we have jacp already certified
then we have a credit date lab and we
are in the process for getting GMP as
well
so we are looking for a few different
kind of Standards which are needs to be
used to and also we have ecological
plans and so on so we we are quite uh
well educated in getting different kinds
of certificates as well I think it's
necessary
um Luca you showed us a little bit
different approach that Andrea's team is
using uh the grafting of happy is a very
new method I'm not sure if the Growers
know it yet or use it frequently so
could you explain us what are the
advantages of grafting in hemp and maybe
what kind of benefits can we expect from
these grafting plants
yeah drafted plants can give us many
advantages over the traditional cloning
core by the steam cuttings
I will start with it's normally that we
have a genotype that is really perfect
it can have a not profile and all the
all the singles are metabolized but it's
near nearly impossible to regulatively
propagate it so it's a problem to to get
the roots of the cuttings so with
grafting this is really eliminated or we
can really increase the propagation
of selected genotypes this is like the
first thing I would say but we selected
rootstocks so desired root system we can
increase the overall yield overall Vigor
of the plant the plants are more
healthier the stronger
overall like the yield of flowers or in
Florida senses of square meter is higher
but with desires or some rootstocks
could influence the activity of
secondary metabolism which means that
overall yield of secondary metabolites
would be higher but yeah if the higher
secondary metabolism is present in the
plant means that from the start from the
start or even late in flower the plant
is more tolerant to pests and diseases
we selected root stocks some root stocks
are totally resistant to plant to so
important diseases and we can eliminate
the problems with pathogens great great
he also mentioned that you are Crossing
High CBD genotypes with different
Industrial Hemp genotype what is the
purpose of this Crossing
so we started from
old plants right now are on the field
like the really good genetics of CBD are
hot how to say like
the the federal limit is 0.3 percent of
THC normally on the field it's THC a
little bit higher than 0.3 our idea was
in the first place to to cross it with
Industrial Hemp to reduce THC levels to
0.3 that's a challenge I guess
yeah if you want to to have a high CBD
level it's really really a challenge
what do you say what do you mean when
you say hi how much
so above five six percent yeah
CBD okay yeah
um and the other goal is we saw it from
the field that many farmers cut the the
plants down early in the end of the
season because of wet bad weather
conditions because
normally really good genotypes of CBD
mature late and
okay now our idea is now to
produce a faster flowering strain
to
to obtain variety that could be Harvest
early in the autumn
okay nice uh Ben said
we'll move now to you so you're
developing with some microfluidics and
you also mentioned that you are
cooperating with European Space Agency
uh but tell us how is your technology
also applicable in the space and since
we have two breeders here on the panel
how can you transfer your methodology to
the grower or breeder
a question and we highlight in in the
video in this this portable feature with
the with the space research because yeah
um
why it can be used in some remote places
and in microgravity uh because of the
capillaries so all of the separation
happens in capillaries so we don't have
to like generate artificial gravity or
or that's why the the selection was you
know narrow to the microchip electrical
phrases development so that's why the
space research it could be also
passively working with HPS because it's
also you know like liquid separation but
there's much more moving parts and you
know it's much more complicated to to
set it up in the International Space
Station so that's why the microchip
collector phrase is so about the black
the laboratory or their own Plantation
and they want to have measurements on
the field without like hiring some
experts yeah
yeah okay maybe a second question from
the analytical point of view which I'm
much closer to so we know that cannabis
plant has a long THC CBD and CBG also
present many minor cannabinoids which
occasionally present challenge to detect
them or identify them so my question
would be about the sensitivity and
accuracy of your device and what are the
actual benefits as you already said a
few of them for the user oh yeah uh it's
because if it's an analytical technique
like the accuracy can be comparable to
HPS or even a little bit but you know
it's hard to explain because that svr
comparing pixels to theoretical plate
numbers but we are talking about exact
matches on four decimal
um let's see in hplc case where and the
peak area is also um the the repeated
Peak area the differences of derivative
Peak area determining the accuracy so we
are in the LOD we are talking about
vam in the kanabits between 1.1 to 1.7
started with a CBD to the THC
microgram per milliliter so yeah it's
like a six decimal uh error margin yeah
and the matches are four decimals okay
okay thank you uh Clemen
um your technology technology which you
are developing is a steam infusion for
the plants which is in a way
biostimulant but as a grower I would be
very interested in the financial scheme
when using your technology
we know that probably industrial Growers
usually have
finances and they have money but what
about home grower can they afford your
technology
yeah so uh to calculate the let's say
the return on investment of this
technology we use the two examples like
maybe the first example is uh using an
uh
from the numbers uh larger German
grower of medical cannabis that has
let's say more than thousand plants uh
selling let's say the final product at
the German average gross price we showed
that the return on investment is uh a
hundred percent so what this means is
that for every uh Euro that they put
into the device and the medium and the
technology they get two Euros back in
the first growth cycle
so the return on investment is pretty
rapid as the 25 percent increase in
yield is quite a lot it's different for
CBD there because of the price of the
flower
um it's uh the the the return is slower
for the home Growers so our device is
completely modular so you can use it
from one day one pla growing one plant
to Growing hundreds of thousands of
plants uh the device is stack so
basically connect it's the same device
it's just connected to to form large
chains
so for home Growers they are usually
um so the the calculation is actually
using different numbers in the end is
very similar because they uh um they
typically if they are looking to sell
they sell for a larger price than what
the German average gross price for large
manufacturers
of course for them just having one
system is the price is also higher but
but we always say when we are developing
this technology is that there should be
one growth cycle that pays off for the
investment and uh yeah so far for
medical we were able to so it's
mentioned for everybody even for the
single but did you mention the price
what's the price of the depending on the
size but typically so for uh the for one
cartridge that is used for one plant for
one growth cycle is 20 Euro uh that's if
you just buy one but then you also need
to have the device so the system the
pressurized system this is a one-time
investment that then lasts for for yeah
for many growth Cycles okay thank you so
I think we are ready for the questions
from the public if there is a time for
maybe one or two questions because
everybody is hungry or do does anyone
have question
hunger is outweighing your need for
knowledge
all right well there it is then
uh let's go eat let's hear it once again
for our panel thank you
Dr stucco and everyone else very
informative
they're gonna open that door right there
in a minute and we'll have lunch we'll
be back here at 1400 for more panels
please go visit our exhibitors over
there and uh and donate to the flood
Relief Fund as well and don't forget the
party tonight this first shuttle bus
leaves at 8 45
and bring wear your badge wear your
badge so you can come to the party
tonight all right enjoy lunch we'll see
you in about 90 minutes