hello we're the last panel we've made it
we're it's 5:00 p.m. on a Friday and
you're all still here which is very
exciting we're gonna try to keep it
Lively we're gonna have a pretty
informal conversation we know it's the
end of the day and folks have been
learning a lot and conversing a lot and
we've we've all we've all had a long
days but we're excited to be here
honored to be up on this panel I'm gonna
ask each of my esteemed colleagues up
here to introduce themselves and say a
little bit about who they are and who
they work for so why don't we start at
the end hi i'm jamie pearson I'm the CEO
of Bank Corporation we are a house of
brands we started with an iconic
chocolate bar that's one over 8
High Times Cannabis Cup s-- 22 awards
for our portfolio of products and I'm
happy to be here awesome thank you good
afternoon
chanita penny I am the principal and
founder of budding solutions I also lead
the minority cannabis Business
Association so in addition to consulting
hey thanks in addition to consulting I
am a partner in a cultivation and
processing operation in Pennsylvania and
also a business in Oakland awesome thank
you my name is Kevin Haller I work with
a keen consulting that was a spinoff of
our CPA firm we ultimately opened a keen
to address some needs we saw when
working with clients to address
compliance and internal control and just
very excited to be up here today
great thank you um could Emily can I
have a bottle of water thank you sorry I
had one and then I lost it and I know
that I'm gonna I'm gonna need it so I
appreciate that thank you
is everyone else good great so i am
lindsay robinson i'm the executive
director of the california cannabis
Industry Association we are a trade
association based in California we have
almost 500 members representing over
10,000 employees across the state and
growing every every day every month we
have been around for just about six
years and our primary goal is to lobby
on behalf of the industry
to essentially help policy reform create
policy reform and regulatory reform that
allows your businesses to be treated
like any other business in the state and
as any of you know who are operating in
California and our members know this is
a very difficult challenging task
California's complicated and convoluted
and over-regulated and we're exhausted
and stressed out most of the time but
but optimistic still optimistic and one
of the reasons I was really excited
about being on this panel is because we
get to talk about a positive things
right strategic partnerships I think for
all of our different businesses really
enhance what we do and these
partnerships are our core many times to
how we to how we work and how we are
successful so we're gonna dive into it
today we're gonna leave some time at the
end for questions we're running a little
bit over but hopefully you all will
stick around with us and if you have
questions we're gonna have about 10 or
15 minutes at the end so again you know
as Debbie said with the last panel this
is a group of experts and we're really
excited to showcase some of their
expertise and knowledge but also I
encourage everyone to try and connect
with some of the panelists after and
especially at the party this evening so
exciting ok so one of the things I
really wanted to chat with each of you
about is to talk a little bit personally
about how you got into the industry and
sort of what your your inspirations are
so feel free to take a few moments Jamie
and and tell us tell us a little story I
got into the industry about five years
ago which is which is interesting
because my father was a clandestine
grower my whole life so technically I
was in the industry whether I liked it
or not because I had to know when to
bring my friends home you when it
smelled like skunk in the garage and
when I couldn't and I found that
annoying growing up was a college
athlete did not smoke marijuana was anti
marijuana and then I'm also the cousin
of the DJ in Cypress Hill who lit a
joint on Saturday Night Live when I was
in college and so had the poster child
of marijuana
that I grew up with about five years ago
I got sick I smoked marijuana at the
behest of my nephew it it fixed me
instantly and from that day forward I
was no longer anti marijuana and mugs
and I were investing in real estate
together for about 15 years and he had
me review one of the first contracts
that they were asked to look at and
coming into the marijuana space and then
I told him I wouldn't sign it and I told
him why I won't mention who the company
was that was trying to get Cyprus to be
their spokesperson and one thing led to
another and he asked me to represent the
band and I started off in the industry
as the marijuana manager or agent for
Cypress Hill and through that
partnership
I found bang and one thing led to
another and now I'm the CLO everything's
possible great thank you for sharing
that shemitah
I love cannabis and so throughout my
corporate career actually a little bit
earlier than that throughout my college
in the in corporate career I was always
just a closet consumer I grew up in the
corporate supply chain and transitioned
my IT consulting business to serve the
cannabis space so lending my background
in project management international
marketing and operations management to
the industry was my goal I wanted to see
this industry look like every other
industry that I worked in from a
professional and standards point of view
and so I saw the opportunity about five
years ago when Maryland legalized
medical marijuana and have been on a
journey from Maryland to Pennsylvania
and now out to Oakland since great thank
you Kevin so on a personal note I've
been involved in the industry for 25
years professionally in the last four it
kind of started when San Jose
consolidated the industry and only
allowed for 16 operators
one of those operators happen to be
really good friends with the managing
partner of our firm and so we just kind
of by dumb luck fell into that working
with that client and it was wonderful
because I had such passion for the
industry to get that experience to learn
with them and to kind of tackle it from
a professional perspective in doing so
we saw that there was an incredible need
to help these businesses really flourish
they don't really have the
infrastructure dialed in at first and so
we really kind of spun off our business
a keen to kind of address a lot of the
needs that we saw within that industry
in terms of navigating compliance
documenting internal controls policies
and procedures helping them develop all
that framework to capture accurate
information to make decisions to help
get financing so it's just been
incredible how this just kind of came
about to us and just really helped us
build the expertise and really get
involved into this industry that's great
thank you and so I think many of us have
a personal connection and personal story
about why we work in this industry right
how many of you have have something that
touches you personally about cannabis
right how many people do you think that
work in say real estate or the alcohol
industry are super expired by by that
industry I think that that's part of the
uniqueness of folks who work in the in
the cannabis space and something that
hopefully where we're utilizing as a
strength in order to inspire our
businesses inspire each other and build
strong partnerships around that so I I
would love to hear some of your stories
afterwards I have been working on policy
reform in the cannabis space for
probably how almost 15 years first as an
advocate and cultivator and then more
formally in working on with a number of
nonprofits so I spent almost a decade
with the Marijuana Policy Project which
works on national issues federal issues
but as well as state medical adult use
legalization through ballot initiatives
and the legislature so
that is that's my background and now I
get the the privilege to work with CCI a
and and one of the things that I think
is so extraordinary about the
opportunities that that I've had and
that I've worked for is the partnerships
that we've been able to create so first
with CCI a and then also with the
Marijuana Policy Project because really
nothing happens in a vacuum so I'd
really love us to we're gonna dig in a
little bit you know first I'd like folks
to kind of talk a little bit about the
current business that you're in and
really kind of dive deep in terms of the
the business model and then to think a
little bit about what some of those
strategic partnerships are because they
can take many different forms so I want
us to to really dig in because I think
we each have a unique perspective on
that so she need a why don't why don't
we start with you this time so when my
consulting practice strategic
partnerships are critical to achieving
our clients goals if we're applying for
a license it's necessary for us to form
partnerships with the community to gain
their acceptance for us even operating
in that space we have to work with the
state to of course submit an application
that is merit-based and competitive
enough to win a license and so it's not
something that I can do alone as a
one-woman show and so strategic
partnerships are critical for that work
in terms of my entrepreneurial endeavors
strategic partnerships have allowed me
to actually own a piece of the
businesses that I'm working in as a
consultant it's one thing to be paid for
your services but then you walk away
from you know something that's going to
grow up to hopefully be you know really
big and so I've been able to go from
just consulting for a fee to actually
exchanging my talents and skills for
equity and it's something that I
couldn't do because I couldn't
necessarily write a $500,000 check or
you know say I'm going to fund this
million-dollar project but with the help
of good folks that bring you know other
resources to the table not only fine
but also their background perspectives
experiences in other industries and so I
think that's been something that I've
leveraged to not only grow my consulting
business but then also the project that
I'm partnering on yeah that's great I
have a couple thoughts on that that I'd
like to circle back to and a little bit
but Jeanne wood what about you
well bangs made our company based on
strategic partnerships we exploded onto
the scene in California in 2010 we've
got a nine year history of award-winning
cannabis edibles and CBD products we
were bringing CBD packaged goods into
California since 2011 so wins when our
CEO Scott really saw the opportunity to
expand the brand nationally there was a
barrier to entry in most of the legal
states because it would take a million
dollars to get a license you know in
let's say one state but you do that
times 50 conceivably you can see that
it's impossible to spread your brand if
you are in control so you had to find
operators in those states that had the
wherewithal to get the license be good
operators and had an interest in taking
the brand into that state so finding a
strategic partnership just to expand the
brand was one thing but where we're at
now that were so far down that path is
we what we say is we used to you had to
take what you can get and now you get to
get what you want in our partnerships
because the industries come so far along
now we are partnered with people like in
Deva in in Canada which is a publicly
traded company our licensee in
California is Origen house formerly can
a royalty which is a publicly traded
company our licensee in Florida is true
leaf they they manage about 75 or I
should say have a stranglehold of about
75 percent of that market those are
companies that came to us and said we
want to represent and partner with your
brand so we were able to build a brand
footprint with our strategic
partnerships that have allowed us to
grow our brand
across the nation and now we're now
being distributed in Germany leishan
Stein Austria Poland Canada and we're
expanding into some other countries
right now it's really exciting and we're
gonna go public in about three weeks we
could not have done that had we tried to
control everything on our own bangs
really a testament to strategic
partnerships so strategic partnerships
to me
I just really honor the business owners
and entrepreneurs that really built the
industry that we have today there's
people that have been in this space when
it was you know you couldn't really talk
about it and there are operators and
they've been pushing the envelope and so
I just have tremendous gratitude for
those individuals because we're all here
because of that the associations as well
they put money towards lobbying so again
we're all sitting here today because of
the efforts of those that built this
industry and those that are supporting
and moving this industry forward on a
personal note I was diagnosed 18 months
ago with MS and it's because of their
efforts that I have access to CBD and
products which helped me deal with my
chronic back pain that's happened as a
result of my diagnosis so just
tremendous gratitude and I want to thank
you know the association's and those
that have built this industry and now we
kind of I look at it like we have an
opportunity to kind of pay it forward
and so that's what you know our business
kind of spun off to kind of help
businesses thrive so compliance as
Lindsey had brought up is is is it's so
from so many different angles there's a
lot of red tape in which operators have
to navigate so we kind of help them
follow have documented processes in
place in an effort to kind of address
the compliance issues that they have to
help them with financial policies and
procedures to ensure that they're
capturing accurate information so they
can make business decisions to grow so
the partnerships are incredible and
there's many partnerships we get through
being part of these events one thing I
like to be for my client is as a
consultant I don't know everything so I
have to leverage the other service
providers and professionals that I meet
at events like this so it really takes a
village to kind of help our clients
really grow their business and so I kind
of love meeting everyone within the
different aspects of servicing this
industry so that we can kind of you know
if a client says they have a certain
need I can find a person to kind of help
fill that need for them yeah that's
great I'd love to think a little bit
about strategic partnerships in terms of
what chanita was mentioning earlier
either investing or equity shares of a
company and how folks can can grow those
you know those relationships and and and
find strategic partnerships that work
for them and their business do you have
any insight absolutely I mean in
addition to the business side of things
I think about the work that we're doing
with the MC ba to support and strengthen
the social equity programs and economic
development in every community and
strategic partnerships are really
critical for that we've seen great
examples in other industries of
companies stepping up and developing
small business and entrepreneurs and it
lends itself to innovation you know and
and really growing and strengthening
those companies one of the examples I
love to reference is Unilever's
acquisition of the sundial brands this
is a an immigrant into the United States
who was basically making soap in his
kitchen and he was using his mother's
recipe Unilever with all of their
infrastructure and institutional
knowledge and access to money could not
lock down the very lucrative black
business black health and beauty
business and so even when black women
couldn't find these products in
traditional outlets and big box stores
like Target and Walmart they would
purchase online and so sundial
I mean they were killing it and so
Unilever acquired this company
significant acquisition but in addition
to that they he demanded a strategic
partnership that would support
development and and support
entrepreneurs especially women of color
and so they contributed 50 million
dollars to the New Voices fund and the
New Voices fund develops other minority
entrepreneurs especially women and so I
think it's important as I am going out
whether it's consulting and helping
other folks build their businesses or
the strategic partnerships that I'm
forming or the work that I'm doing with
the MC ba to look at industry and and
help share that story as a real example
of how the industry can get behind the
initiatives that we are fighting for you
know we put policies in place to ensure
access to this industry to ensure that
there's a place for folks that haven't
been impacted by the war on drugs but
we're not putting any money behind them
and if one of the you know most
significant barriers to entry is access
to capital we have to start there and
the industry itself will be more
valuable and more prosperous through
strategic partnerships that support
sustainable endeavors diversity and
inclusion initiatives and equity in this
space okay yes thank you for those
points I would love to talk a little bit
more about the associations so I'd love
for you to expand on the MC ba in just a
little bit but I wanted to get Jamie's
perspective on on working with investors
you know or our partners in in a
significant way that would make them a
strategic partner do you have any
insight to share on that I have a lot of
insight to share on that that's been
happening with bang for the last few
years we've got some of our investors
sitting in the audience that we met at
this very event in Kauai last year
through them they've introduced us to
other people that we've connected with
and I do feel like when there's
synergies or when you can compliment
each
there's needs everybody wins and I think
that's one of the things that bang looks
for in a strategic partnership is if you
have a need that we can fill and we have
a need that you can fill you know that's
obviously where a partnership starts
from but then you also have to like each
other at a at a basic level you have to
know that everybody's gonna get along
and play well in the sandbox and you
know I think to chanita spoink if you're
going to make a strategic partnership
and if you're out looking for a partner
it's you have to be looking for ways to
actually include the people that don't
get or don't have a voice or don't get
to play in the sandbox and I'm one of
the things I'm proud of with bang is
we're out there looking for exactly that
so we've we've made some strategic
partnerships that are you know like Kim
Rivers in true leave is a woman owned
business women represent a larger
percentage of ownership and executive
positions in cannabis it's still not
representative of you know population
we're not there yet
I think of Ruth Bader Ginsburg saying
she'll be happy when there's all women
on the Supreme Court and people say what
she says well we don't question when it
was all men right you know we're looking
for inclusion and we're getting it in
this industry but but bangs out there
looking for it
so out of our entire executive team
everybody's a woman we have women of
color except for two we have two men on
our team I'm really proud of that so
we're out there looking for ways that we
can act actively find people that are
doing good things you know sustainable
packaging and just you know helping the
environment helping you know people that
don't have a voice and I think that's
I'm really pretty like proud to be
sitting here with you because I love
that you said that Kevin would you like
to add to that yeah so Capital is a huge
thing in this industry it takes a lot of
money to set up as
successful business and so one thing we
like to do is to be a strategic partner
for our clients you know one thing I
like to always say is I want to be the
wheel and I like to leverage other
service providers to be spokes again I
don't know all the answers but I want to
be able to help my clients to really
grow to the next level to obtain capital
you have to be a strong business not in
just what your product is but you have
to have strong financials you have to
have reliable financials so you have to
have audits so you know those are things
that we kind of offer to our clients as
well as helping them with the internal
controls and processes to be able to
properly navigate and capture accurate
information to address compliance
regulatory requirements you know even
filling out a proper tax return 280e is
a killer in this industry and so how do
we properly navigate that and so really
I look at strategic partnerships is
absolutely crucial in all levels for all
of us to help businesses get stronger
and grow to connect the investors with
the businesses so they can grow and so
really we like to work together with our
clients to kind of help them obtain that
capital so they can really move to the
next level so yeah I would like to
circle back to associations I know that
she need to talked a little bit about
MCB a-and and as you all know I work
with the California cannabis Industry
Association and we're a traditional 501
C 6 so we're a lobbying group and I
think about strategic partnerships a
little bit differently because we we
have partnerships obviously with our
members right we represent them and we
work with them and and to be honest
that's where all of the expertise and
the policy you know platform and
legislative priorities that all comes
from our members so I really like to
think of our members or clients you know
as our strategic partners because
there's there's that give-and-take of
information and sharing and and I I
would I know so much more about how
their business is
function and the issues that they're
facing because of their ability to share
that with me which is great but I also
think about strategic partnerships with
the legislature and with the regulators
and the amount of time that we have put
into building relationships with those
entities and how sometimes they go
sideways and they're they're not as as
strong as we would want them to be or
they don't hear the real concerns of the
industry but then other times we're
incredibly proud of those you know those
relationships because there's a real
give-and-take there in terms of us
sharing the expertise from the industry
with them and so we see great
opportunity with that you know when
we're working with a legislature that
comes to us and says hey I'd really like
to have a bill that regulates cannabis
in this way and we say hey have you ever
gone to a cultivation site and seen
cannabis growing do you do you know how
its harvested do you know how its
processed you know what extraction looks
like and when honestly four or five
years ago most of the legislators that
wanted to be a part of the conversation
and have bills with their names attached
to it and and be you know part of
regulating they did not have that
experience so that that piece of it I've
been really grateful that we've been
able to build those relationships and
share the expertise from people who are
actually working in the industry to
build what I consider to be strategic
partnerships and you know sometimes like
I said they go wrong we have legislators
that introduce bills and language that
we are absolutely not supportive of and
that they're going to create more you
know regulatory headaches for the
industry right the goal is is that we
would like to be treated like any other
industry right and not regulated to
death
California is dealing with some real
growing pains right now in this regard
but I think it's important to think
about partnerships in many different
ways so I know we've had some
partnerships that have kind of gone I
won't say sideways but have caused real
consternation and we've had to fight to
remedy them and so I would love for any
perspective that you have on a strategic
partnership that maybe was fruitful at
one point but has gone a little bit
sideways
and then we can talk a little bit more
about associations well I'll tell you
things happen so quickly and you have to
foresee and plan for you know a number
of scenarios and so for the MC ba we
just really don't have time to expend a
lot of energy around things that aren't
working so we're we're very quick to say
hey this isn't working let's go in a
different direction and it's been really
rewarding for these strategic
partnerships to result in things like
our model legislation and so for the
last three years we've brought together
you know a group of folks 30 to 40
individuals that represent industry
policymakers regulators activists
medical professionals and we've spent
you know two days together saying what
would an ideal adult use bill look like
what does a municipal ordinance look
like what is an a municipal ordinance
look like that will ensure equity and
access and diverse business types and
things of that nature tax us a tax
structure that lends itself to real
community reinvestment as opposed to
collecting taxes into a general fund and
then spending them on you know big
industry development projects as opposed
to education or healthcare or or any of
the other things that are needed in
these communities and so the strategic
partnerships that we have and just great
relationships that we have with folks
like DPA SSDP MPP it's been helpful to
us in our cause our company partnerships
have allowed us to do a lot of
programming around education provide
resources to folks Marley natural and
privateer was a great relationship that
allowed us to go and do expungement
fairs in Seattle and Portland we we had
an opportunity summit last year that was
a direct result of a strategic
partnership with Hoban law group and
University of Denver we are really
excited to continue our partnership with
state associations like CCI
and really excited about some upcoming
work with new organizations like CTF and
so we're going to continue to work with
folks that are interested in pushing
forth the the general agenda but that
are also concerned with making sure that
no one's left behind ensuring that folks
that look like me that have been caught
up in the criminal justice system just
don't have a million dollars to bankroll
this amazing idea that they're
represented that they have connectivity
to the larger and-and-and you know more
prevalent operators that are you know
multi-state and even international and
so again strategic partnerships with our
individual members our company members
and then other associations are how we
get our work done yeah
Jamie we go into every strategic
partnership hoping it's going to go well
I would say we've had some that have
gone really really well and we've had
some that have not gone really really
well and some of the ones that I look
back on and they haven't been successful
they started off you know with the right
intentions and I think what's important
when you when you enter that partnership
I always say write your divorce before
you get married because when you're in
the beginning of that process and you're
getting ready to join forces everybody's
in the ether of the excitement of the
deal well that's when it's really easy
to actually sit with them and say well
okay let's talk about all the ways this
can go wrong and get it on paper and be
ready to know what its gonna look like
if you have to part ways because the
reality of being in business in the
cannabis industry it's complicated it
changes all the time people have
different expectations in their heads
when they join into partnerships so as
things change and evolve it's easier now
and we've learned the hard way you got
to be able to cut loose quick if things
aren't going well so it's sort of like
beasts you know be slow to hire and
quick to fire what we're trying to do
now is really write our partnerships in
a way where they're not as painful to to
you know separate from if they don't
work because the reality is
they don't always work we've been lucky
because the ones that we've done we've
learned a lot been doing this for nine
years and we've been doing it majority
the majority of our efforts have been in
partnership situations because we have
all of that experience in there we've
been really lucky because we've honed
the ability to figure out also how to
ask good questions of ourselves because
if I know what I really am looking for
if I know what I really do need and I
know where my pain points are I can ask
the right questions to make sure that
we're actually we don't just like each
other and want to do business together
but we're actually going to be
benefiting one another and there's going
to be a result for me and a result for
you that we're both expecting so you
know I would say in all of those the
ones that don't work are painful and
some more painful than others and I'm
sure you all know what I mean by that
but the ones that have been successful
make it worth it so I would I would say
even though we've had some some
partnerships go south strategic
partnerships that win-win when it does
work it's a beautiful thing that's great
thank you so I don't really have many
strategic partnerships that have gone
bad but there is you know I want to
bring up again you know working with
clients you know things will be going
really well they're really liking
everything you're bringing to the table
the value re adding and then we get to
the topic of 280e and then I look like a
bad guy it's very hard for us as
accountants to help clients properly
navigate that because they don't like to
hear what 280 really is nobody nobody
does and it's hard cuz they all look at
me like I wrote the code and and and
it's just like no my job is to make sure
you stay in your lanes okay
I disagree with the rule I know a lot of
my clients use that almost as their
strategy for how they make business
decisions and I try to change their
perspective just like look let's focus
on what it is we're doing and how we can
grow our top-line and manage costs but
don't have a tax law
DR what you're gonna do not everything
is cost of goods sold because you're a
cultivator it just isn't the way it is
so I have to be the bearer of bad news a
lot and and that's kind of hard to kind
of bring that to the table but again I
just try to tell them that look this is
about really building an empire in this
space and what you need to do is follow
compliance and the regulations and
that's why I say this is a very
expensive industry to kind of get into
and you just got to hold it out until
that is lifted and eventually it will be
lifted I don't know when but I do know
that as long as you can kind of
successfully navigate that and just
withhold that's when you're gonna be
sitting pretty you don't want to go
under over aggressively bypassing any of
the rules and right now the rules are
strict and I would just recommend
everyone do your best to follow the
rules because that's going to keep you
open we all know there's going to be an
inevitable consolidation within this
industry and it's those that are really
following compliance and doing things as
red as they can within the states in
which they're operating that will be the
last one standing great well I know we
do want to move into some questions so
I'm gonna ask each of the panelists to
share something that they're that
they're really particularly proud of and
it can be based around a strategic
partnership or an accomplishment but I'd
love to hear a little bit about
something that you're particularly proud
of and I'm gonna start with you Kevin so
I'm just proud to do my part for this
industry to thrive I'm very passionate
about the cannabis industry I'm excited
to see where it goes and so I just love
that I'm doing my part and it's great
when you know I work with the client and
we're doing things and and really help
them dial in some framework that they're
seeing the value and the other day I
just had a comment we wouldn't be where
we're at today without you and those are
the things that just make me feel
incredibly proud and this is just an
industry Bayt built by incredible people
and I'm just thrilled to be part of it
it's incredible who would have thought
that today we'd be where we're at I
would have never guessed and it's really
because of associations and
entrepreneurs and business owners that
have paved the way so thank you I like
that that's great
today I am most proud of a strategic
partnership that was born out of a
relationship that I formed in the
advocacy space
amber center of super nova women who was
based here in Oakland and I have spent
the last few years bouncing ideas off
each other from the east coast to the
west coast around what social equity and
economic empowerment truly looks like
last year we came together and we now
have a license for a non storefront
retail delivery business here in Oakland
or in Oakland and we are also incubating
a social equity delivery licensing and
so you know we didn't have a big budget
backing us but we realized that as we
built our business that we could help
another business another person who
needs not just a check but actual
support in navigating this industry all
of the hurdles that are you know come in
the way of just starting up operations
but also making sure that our voices are
continuously heard at the city level to
ensure that this program is further
developed you know it's not enough to
just say hey we're giving you a thousand
square feet and so that is incubation of
a business it's not you know you need
real support you need access to capital
and you need folks that are committed to
developing and seeing these businesses
thrive so today I'd say that's my the
proudest the strategic partnership that
I'm good that I can think of right now
Jamie for me it's definitely the deep
friendships that I've developed over the
five years that I've been in the
industry you know coming from real
estate where it's really a dog-eat-dog
situation we're all fighting for the
same houses we're all fighting for the
same deals I found that the cannabis
industry you know not to get all kumbaya
but the reality is
I come to this I come to the ICBC and I
run into people that I haven't seen for
a while and it's like running into an
old friend and and now I realize they
have really become my friends the people
that I'm doing business with we are so
like-minded that that's what I'm proud
of is being able to build the
relationships that I've been able to
build in such a short amount of time
that are really really deep friendships
that I know will continue if I jump out
of the industry or not that's what I'm
proud of that's great well whether we
like it or not we're all part of this
movement right this this greater entity
that is slowly but surely changing the
world and I think it's extraordinary
that we get to think about business and
regulation and partnerships while also
always thinking about social justice and
and really continuing on the legacy of
folks who who have been fighting for a
really long time to finally end
prohibition and we're getting so close
you know I mean I look back at January
first in 2018 and I cried really hard
that day and then I was like oh wait
California's a mess
but it's still you know like that that
is still the motivator I think for so
many of us and I hope that we never lose
that I know that we're gonna maybe move
further away but I hope we can keep that
core and keep that that excitement and
that trust with our strategic
partnerships because really when we're
able to leverage those partnerships to
elevate our association or our business
or our brand let's hope that we're also
elevating the folks that we're working
with us that's where I think we have the
most growth potential and the ability to
change the world so let's keep that in
mind we are at close to end if there are
questions let's hear it one more time
for the panel though lives each Anita
Janie Kevin it's fantastic I just popped
up out of nowhere
you're good at that we have time for a
couple of questions for sure anyone
anyone