next up strategic partnerships no matter
what products you have whatever service
you provide the right partner can make
all the difference whether it is
in-house or somebody you work with I'm
going to introduce the moderator the
street of partnerships panel she is
really a pioneer in Southern Oregon
she's a CEO of Sun breeze Inc a
family-owned seed to sale cannabis
company please give a warm welcome to
our moderator moderator miss Bree
malarkey everybody none of us need any
strategic partnerships right everybody
knows everything and they've got
everything perfect so I just want to
take a minute to introduce our panel
we've got some great people here from
Oregon and beyond just to tell you
really quickly about myself and then
we'll kind of pass it on I'm an
herbalist I've been studying plant
medicine for over 15 years
and Beyond herbs and plants really
wanted to embrace the ultimate mother
plant cannabis and opened a medical
dispensary in 2014 a product line and an
herb farm so that's really knee but
let's go on and introduce the rest of
our panel so please say your name and
just a quick history about who you are
hi I'm Pete Ram and I'm from Colorado I
was a co partner in roots Rx and
co-founder we have six stores
recreational stores we have three grows
one outdoor to indoor and a small
medical store hello everybody thank you
my name is jim winner I'm the president
of shadowbox farms we have a 35 acre
farm and Williams and a corporate office
here in Portland Oregon where we run all
the administration of the company
hi I'm Jordan Wellington I'm the chief
compliance officer at simplify we're a
regulatory compliance software that
helps cannabis businesses really follow
the regulations and kind of stay in
operational compliance and then my night
job is I do public policy and government
affairs in the cannabis regulatory
market I do i implemented legalization
on behalf of the state of Colorado and
now do public policy with NCI a and
really cannabis businesses all over the
country on regulatory matters perfect so
it's kind of joking we all can't be all
things and when we work hard to form our
organizations we have to look and
identify what are our individual
strengths and what are our weaknesses
and that's a hard thing for a lot of
people to address so we thought we would
start by talking about how each of our
organizations were formed and where we
look for strategic partnerships in our
formations for me I'm an herbalist I'm a
visionary philosopher I'm customer
service I am the team development kind
of vision person but a really big
weakness for me was the business office
the financials the accounting and lucky
me my business partner and husband is an
ex CFO and controller in the utility
industry so when we formed our Herbal
Products company it was a real great
partnership we really balanced kind of
the front of the house in the back of
the house and have a great balance but I
wanted to open it up to the panel in
forming your organization's what were
some of the strategic partnerships that
you guys all look for in how you formed
your organizations so I was really
fortunate I lived just down the street
from Aspen Colorado and as many of you
may know Aspen is a fairly affluent
community and because of that I had had
a small medical concerned and in 2014
when we started a recreational business
basically went beating the streets and
came up with my now partner I should say
my very
just recently ex-partner and he came
from Wall Street hedge fund background
and really brought a different or a
really unique perspective on how to run
a business and was very complementary to
what I did which was grow cannabis and
sell cannabis and so to have somebody
with a real solid financial background
really made our company dynamic and
really let us move forward well I'm kind
of the cannabis virgin I've been in the
industry for 10 months my background was
I ran a tech company here in Portland
prior to that I ran school abroad and
most notably I helped mark models build
Hollywood entertainment I got into
cannabis because I really hated the
hypocrisy of what was happening and I
thought I could make a difference our
company was well on its way we were
about two years into it when I joined
although we were a case of maybe too
much money and and not enough thought
and so we really over the last year have
been in a process of rebuilding our
company and so the strategic
partnerships were critical to what we
did in this last 11 months most of our
agreements most of the things we did
were very old school they were on the
back of a napkin with a yellow crayon
and we had to put solid structure in
place in order to grow where we wanted
to do and and have the foundation we
were operating without a mission we had
no values we didn't have a vision
statement we had no brand and so
establishing all of those things over
the last month our investors like to say
that we remodeled the houses we just we
chose to live in the house as we
remodeled it but those strategic
partnerships are the only way that we
were able to survive and that's with our
attorneys that's with our PR firm
that's with our vendors everybody
through there it's creating those
relationships and those partnerships of
those people which was so critical to
our success today Hey
so I guess in founding simplify the
compliance software company that I
worked for now
I was literally nothing just a policy
nerd that had done a lot of government
affairs and kind of advising cannabis
businesses on operational compliance and
had this vision an idea for a software I
just had no idea how to create a company
or found a company or raise money or
build any kind of tech platform one of
the things I like to say is we're
simplifying and the first one of the
first things I learned about the tech
companies you're supposed to make up a
word but it has to sound like another
word when you're like starting a tech
company so I literally knew nothing
about anything I just had this vision
and understood cannabis regulation at a
very fundamental level and so I was very
fortunate that Christian Cedarburg the
partner of the law firm I I still work
with had a friend who's now our CEO
Marian and we sat in a conference room
one day very casually and he was like
you can trust this guy he's retired he's
sold five companies already all tech
platforms for the most part explained to
him your idea and our company was born
that day and he's like I'm coming out of
retirement to run this company and so
the first strategic partner that I think
I found and like a lot of people have
said is the kind of into your gang the
balance to your equation where you know
not I know I can't do everything there's
a lot of things in our company I can't
do and finding those people that are
really able to kind of complement your
skill set and balance out even at the
very initial phase before you even start
figuring out who your lawyer and who
your accountants going to be you need to
think about your executive team here
your top people and who's going to
balance out the skills there and then
you bring on additional strategic
partners to kind of compliment those
folks now I think that's a great point
especially for a lot of us that are
founders and have a vision is
recognizing you know who can compliment
that and sometimes that means that even
though you're the founder you're not
meant to be the CEO to run the
organization to have it become a healthy
entity and I remember once somebody
saying just because you're a really good
plumber
doesn't mean you know how to run a
plumbing business so just because you're
a great cultivator doesn't mean you're
gonna know how to run a cultivating
business so go to what you love because
you're gonna be doing it 90 hours a week
give or take
so put your heart and soul and where
your passion is and then surround
yourself with really powerful people
that can help you get that vision out
there so sometimes that's hiring the
right people to join your team and
sometimes it's going outside of your
organization and really looking for a
partner maybe an independent contractor
a key you guys already hit on all this
attorneys software companies you know
especially in the the land of compliance
we're really relying on a lot of third
parties to really make sure our
businesses are successful and for me
when we really wanted to launch sun-god
medicinals finally up into the Portland
market I really needed a delivery and
logistics company I really believe in
account management you know it's an
herbal products company extracting 50
different herbs and plants there's a lot
of Education that we need to provide our
bud tenders and people out there in the
market but I needed a logistics company
to actually deliver those products when
we chose to partner with dream field up
here in Portland because they could help
me get that product out there but still
keep my Account Manager vision going can
you guys give up everybody in the
audience maybe a little example of a
strategic partner that you've chosen
that was outside of your area of
expertise and how you made that decision
so I was again real fortunate I had a in
Colorado several different legal firms
that we could have gone to you for legal
advice and had talked to several people
about the best people to go to and we
ended up with a firm that has done
amazing things for our company and I
can't say enough about having good legal
representation if you're getting into
this business it will be one of the
cornerstones of your bill
it has to be and you have to have people
that you trust and people that you can
depend on and people you can call on a
Sunday afternoon and go how am I going
to deal with this so I would say for me
that was one of the most important
strategic partnerships we were able to
for him oh my gosh there were so many
you know in in tech your circle is very
wide and what I found in cannabis it was
very very got an error or an error and
there was a lot of distrust and when we
were trying to build partnerships it was
like well I'm gonna need to be paid in
advance or I'm gonna need this it was
you know didn't realize how many people
had gotten burned and I saw that as an
opportunity I would say probably the
biggest strategic partner we have is
with ffv extracts we were really good at
growing we have great genetics we can
produce a lot of marijuana that's all
wonderful but being able to turn it into
other products and so I think building
that partnership with that with an
extract company and you know they wanted
to date for a long time before they
would do business with us and one of the
commitments that I've made with all of
our vendors is we pay our bills and we
don't overextend ourselves and we pay
our bills when we say we're gonna pay
our bills and I go through with my
Director of Finance every week and we go
through a P and we pay our business and
I think they were pretty surprised by
that I think that's really important
when you're developing and building
strategic partnerships that that you
don't burn people and that you you keep
those tight and you build those
relationships because they will pay huge
dividends down the road I guess I get to
come at this panel from kind of two
different directions because sometimes
I'm the strategic partner and sometimes
I'm looking for a strategic partners so
I guess just to be different I'll take
the other angle is when I'm acting as a
consultant when I'm what I'm providing
policy guidance or government affairs
work from the consultants perspective I
think it's it's important to understand
that it's it's really a relationship
that needs to be bilateral and early
ship that needs to function bilaterally
not just in an economic sense but in an
interpersonal sense and so you know my
my high level thought here is that what
you really need to be doing is find the
consult and find that strategic partner
that makes sense that fits in with the
ethos of your organization with your
personality and understands where you're
going there's a ton of consultants in
this space I think it's you know one of
the con going jokes in this industry is
how quickly the consultants kind of seem
to multiply and grow and and the
unbelievable number of them and it's not
that and a lot of them are great people
but you have to find the one that fits
you and understands your brand and
understands your value and fits in with
the way you want to run your business
because that kind of relationship you
know a lot of the guidance I need to
give to clients when I'm in that role
and in that world is not what I would do
in that situation right it's it's
helping them make the decision for
themselves not what Jordan thinks is the
best thing for free for them but what
they would think the best thing would be
for them if they had all the information
that I have so I'm trying to provide
them with information tried them with
pertinent information but provide it in
a way that that is useful for them and
useful for their decision making which
means we have to get along we have to
know each other we have to share similar
values to some extent so that the advice
you're getting isn't coming out of left
field but really coming from a place
that holistically works with the way
that you view your business and what
you're trying to accomplish
so the next thing I really wanted to
bring up and all of us definitely
understand this is government and
regulatory partnerships and some of you
in the room are probably thinking what
is this lady talking about they are evil
they're bad they are forcing us to be in
a certain way and the way I look at it
is we are all the government you know we
live in a republic and we vote for
representatives to represent our
interests and we have opportunities to
be involved in either legislation and
the laws that are in our local
jurisdictions or our state level not so
much at the federal level but we still
represent you know vote for
representatives but what can we do when
then different agencies are tasked with
implementing those laws and the
opportunities to influence the rules and
regulations to implement those laws
and I'm talking beyond olcc but maybe
Oda with hemp regulation or licensing
our scales or licensing our food
establishments or OSHA whose ensuring
that we have good worker safety and many
of these different agencies out there
really want collaboration and really
want to be a part of a public-private
partnership because they do nothing for
any of us if there is discourse they're
the ones trying to make sure that human
health and wellness is protected and the
goals and the vision for us as a
collective group are manifested here in
Oregon so for example recently we
partnered with OSHA and took advantage
of their consultation program and
invited OSHA into our facilities and
they actually have a program that if you
invite their OSHA consultants in you are
immune from any fines for a certain
amount of time and they tell you all the
different things you could be doing to
better protect youth the health and
wellness of your associates and your
employees and to let you know if you're
breaking any laws which I really think
was amazing and so as all of us him and
ha about olcc and the rules that rules
changing all the time I just want to
encourage everybody to really involve
themselves with different regulatory
agencies so you know maybe you guys can
I'll give an example of how you've
really worked with government affairs or
within your own organizations so
probably a lot of you folks have done -
I was a actually the first recreational
store and several municipalities but
I'll give you an example of one and it
was our first recreational store I went
in you know locally to the local
government or the county government and
I was like you know hey I'm here I need
to get local licensing and stuff and
people weren't so happy and warm and
fuzzy about me being a cannabis guy and
and trying to get like local licensing I
got the paperwork and left and I was
like geez you know that was pretty
pretty cold reception I got so the next
time I went in I went to a local
restaurant that makes great homemade
pies and stuff and I brought a pie and I
sliced it up and I said to the reception
ladies it was the planning department
where the cannabis czars basically of
this county sliced up the pine gave some
to the receptionist and gave some to the
guy that was going to be the cannabis
our wasn't quite named yet but we knew
we identified who he was and and that he
was going to be the cannabis are for
their county and we sat down and we ate
pie and I I know it sounds simple and
almost contrite but it was such an
icebreaker and to break bread with folks
and to sit down and to you know be on a
personal level with them really made all
a difference in the world starting that
relationship and from then on you know I
was a pie guy and everybody expected
either doughnuts or a pie or something
every time I walked in and it worked
like a charm so I would I would tell you
that the the the the takeaway from that
is that these are all people they're
they're all in a lot of cases great
people they're they're public servants
for God's sake so treat them with
respect treat them with dignity treat
them as you would you know a neighbor or
a friend and you'll be surprised how how
well those relationships go and I love
what you said in the sense that we have
to have these folks as partners and the
more they're in our facilities the more
transparent we are the better we're
going to get along with these folks so
just don't be adversarial with these
people you will it will serve you in no
way shape or form
make them your partners treat them again
with respect and dignity and
and it will go a long way for you great
common human kindness yeah it's I always
remember your please and thank yous we
learn it as kids and then we forget it
at about age 20 life I think that I have
you know Josephine County we've really
reached out to them we do the litter
cleanup along the roads and and do all
the the maintenance along cedar flat
road and we work with them and when we
walk into that into their offices
we're always welcomed and we're not that
you know big wreck up there on the hill
and I think we've really worked with
them I think the olcc
you know I all get the olcc memo we were
hit with a pretty big fine we used to
operate under the the guise of you know
beg for forgiveness and we don't do that
anymore and you know what they were
great through the whole process was it
embarrassing sure I certainly doesn't
fit our values of operational excellence
but we were never treated rudely and I
think that was our relationship one of
the very first things I did when I
started running the company was hired at
we have a compliance officer who his
number one job was to be embedded in the
olcc and know everybody and be able to
know the regulations and if I had a
question I wanted to ask it and know it
right there and not have to have
somebody go research it and I think
having that relationship with the olcc
really attributed to that so I think
exactly what you guys all said they're
not your adversary they're actually your
partner and you'll get to success a
whole lot faster with pie then you will
invite
I mean think in in all of the
experiences I've had around that that's
definitely consistent with what I've
seen from a regulatory perspective right
building relationships with regulators
is is kind of critical but it's
important to understand that that this
isn't just a local game right it works
its way all the way up through the state
and even even to the federal government
I you know I look at cannabis
legalization in the end of prohibition a
little bit differently than a lot of
folks given the nature of my kind of
initial engagement that I was just some
some policy nerd from New Jersey that
moved to Colorado and the state was like
you go figure this out and implement
legalization and I had my little
brothers back home being like you better
not screw this up for the rest of us and
so my my prison my first really
emotional reaction to all of this is is
is not that it's a right actually and I
think it should be but today it's it's
not even a privilege it's a
responsibility it's a responsibility
that we we have to everybody else that's
not living in a free society at least as
it comes to cannabis prohibition and
doing things the right way and that
involves really changing kind of hearts
and minds and and stealing almost like a
military term and understanding that
what we're trying to do here is kind of
convince the people from outside the
cannabis community that that cannabis
legalization is a good thing that
prohibition was not the appropriate way
to structure and regulate society in
control society and that cannabis
businesses can follow regulations they
can follow the rules they can lobby and
change laws of Congress so it's you know
following the regulations in building
local regulations so you can get answers
from olcc and things like that are
incredibly important right now the
narrative is that cannabis regulation
works if that narrative shifts and
businesses stop complying with the
regulations if licenses start getting
pulled left and right and violations go
up its we're gonna see the tide turn
we're gonna see the the people who are
not part of the cannabis community being
like well those people couldn't be
trusted we gave them a chance and you
see that same thing going all the way up
through the federal government and when
you go I don't know how many
into n CIA's Lobby days but to actually
go down to Congress and actually meet
with people and show them the face of
the people running the cannabis industry
it's a lot easier to be like all those
cannabis people are criminals when
they're just some kind of face
faceless person you know they don't have
a name they're not human they're
dehumanized in their mind if you go
there and sit down across from them and
really meet with them
it's a lot harder for them to think bad
things about you right because they've
met you you talk about your kids you
talk about your family you talk about
how you're just like them you're a good
person trying to do you know the right
by the people in your life and so you
have to build those relationships at the
local level through PI you have to build
relationships with compliance officers
at the state level with the olcc to get
answers to your questions and you have
to actually engage the federal level to
help everybody move this forward and
understand that this is beyond its even
beyond a business necessity it is a
necessity for our movement it's a
necessity to end prohibition it's assess
'ti for our entire industry to survive
absolutely that was great thank you I
really appreciate that and I think all
of us in the room have kind of had that
feeling of being the beginning of
legalization here in Oregon we can't
mess it up you know our dispensary in
Southern Oregon and little gold Hill was
the very first one to get a moratorium
lifted and I had to work really really
hard with the city government and every
single one of them that voted for our
license then faced a recall election in
the community for allowing us to open
and they all held their positions so I
was really excited about that I was like
oh no I got to do this right because
then Medford is not going to open up and
Grants Pass isn't gonna open up if I
make a mistake here so having that
ownership and that feeling of that you
know hey we can open this up and I think
we've done a great job here in Oregon
and I'd like to think that our great
testing model and our organizational
structure between us and the regulatory
agency are models that other states are
potentially using in benchmarking
benchmarking with olcc and all of us and
I know that you're doing a lot of
consulting work and some of the stuff
that's happening in Colorado so now that
we have our organizations formed we have
great partnerships and we have great
consultants and wonderful employees and
we are working really well with our
government
another big strategic partnership that I
really think about is branding and
promotions and how to get your brand out
there which is really important
especially I call it the Goldilocks
principle here in Oregon we have to
produce just the right amount for our
citizens or prices plummet or there's
risk of people exporting without
permission so what can we do to really
promote our brands within our
communities
and for me that was public relations and
I looked at a few different PR firms but
I just personally felt that outsourcing
that I really couldn't really keep that
vision consistent with our company so we
actually decided to just recently hire a
brand manager in-house but can you guys
share with us a little bit about what
you've done for branding and marketing
and strategic partnerships and really
getting your message out there in the
community again we were very fortunate
because we have the resources to do
in-house marketing and because we were
vertically integrated it made it very
easy for us to tell a story and at the
end of the day I think marketing boils
down to a story and you can create
whatever story you want as I was telling
the panel earlier our story is and was
that we have a grow in Leadville
Colorado which is the highest
municipality in the lower 48 so in
effect we have the highest legal grow in
the world and that if a budtender says
that to to a guest it rolls right after
that right and they're like well what do
you mean the highest grow in the world
and then you know there becomes this
conversation about this grow and
Leadville Colorado at ten thousand two
hundred feet and that that starts to
brand and and by doing that and by doing
it on a literally
guest to guest level the word gets out
and as you guys know the best way to
brand yourself is by someone else
branding you and by someone that has
tried your product on those guys are
great the bud tenders are great the
product is great the facility is great I
feel you know safe warm and fuzzy when
I'm in there and I walk out with some of
the best product I've ever had so that
in my mind is is a strategic branding I
wouldn't call it strategic branding I
call it grassroots branding and I think
for us it showed very well for our
business and again we were able to open
six doors and be very successful so that
would be my take away in Brandon no I
think your customers are strategic
partnerships right if you're doing it
right and you're really able to get your
mission through and they're very
passionate about what you're doing
they're gonna go out there and and share
with other people so part of your
strategy is being very true to the
vision and mission with every touchpoint
I think that's so important right
because you can spend so much money on
outside marketing and outside marketing
people as we all know there's 50,000
people that want to be your marketing
representative out there and stuff but
at the end of the day it's you it's it's
what you have in that jar and it's what
you're able to prove a and educate your
guests to and if you're able to do that
you know responsibly and in a in a kind
manner it goes a really long way yeah I
couldn't agree more
I think though the foundation is the the
values of your company and your mission
today when mr. Belushi was talking about
being Stewart's of the cannabis industry
that's shadow boxes mission we are
Stewart's of the cannabis industry and
when I first started with a company we
were trying to roll out a new product
and we I don't know we talked for two
months and they couldn't agree on what
the packaging was gonna look like or
this and it was very obvious that we
couldn't make those decisions because we
didn't know what we were we didn't know
what we stood for
and we even went out and hired a
marketing firm and they didn't know what
we were and they didn't know what we
stood for and I've heard it a hundred
times in different meetings oh we don't
have enough time for that we don't have
time for that BS or we can't afford that
well you can't afford not to do it you
have to slow down you have to decide
what are you about what do you stand for
because you stand for something or you
stand for nothing and what is your
company going to represent what are you
gonna represent what are it so that your
employees - what are they why do they
work for you it's all of these pieces
connect and then you can talk about a
strategic partner but if you go out and
hire marketing firm you think they're
gonna fix it before you've done that
homework before you've built that
foundation you're gonna spend a whole
lot of money and you're gonna spin
around and you're at the end of it
you're not gonna know what you stand for
and so I think there is a step before
you go strategic partner in the
marketing realm is and and there are
agencies out there who can help you do
this work if you don't know how to do it
but there and that's a good investment I
had the good fortune of doing it a few
times in my life so we saved that money
but we took the time and it took us
about three months and we did the
homework and we brought the team in it
what did we want to represent what were
our values what was our stake in the
ground our TrueNorth that we wouldn't
deviate from and you know it was
fascinating about it is it began to
resonate and the employee started to
regurgitate it and they started to talk
about it and they started we have this
really pivotal moment in our history of
our company is we had to extract er
machines that we prematurely bought we
had a horrible break-in one of them got
stolen
we had one left with some various parts
and we had an opportunity selling but
the person we were going to sell it to
wanted it to be a cash deal and wouldn't
fill out the IRS paperwork and at the
time we really needed the money we're
talking about $125,000 we really needed
the money and out of the mouths of babes
our office manager said it just doesn't
feel right and that's not part of our
values I think if we do this to him
we're not being good
Stewart's and it stopped me in my tracks
because I was focused on the hundred 25
grand and how I was gonna figure out how
to deposit a hundred thousand dollars
I wasn't thinking about and out of the
mouths of babes and that's when you know
you got it and and then we engaged a PR
firm because we were able to show them
our brand book we were able to show them
what we what we stand for and when that
begins to resonate through your whole
organization we were able to launch five
new SKUs from January till June we
couldn't get one done but we were able
to do five because it's very easy we
know what we stand for we know what our
brand is and we can get into a room and
we can do it pretty quickly now so I
would say that's the foundation if you
think you don't have time you better
make time especially before you engage a
PR firm or a marketing firm that will
take a whole lot of money from you this
has been a really a new problem that
I've had to face in my career is how do
you brand yourself and in the cannabis
industry I think whether you're selling
B to C or B to B I think is Peter noted
it's really a grassroots effort we've
taken a lot of different approaches as a
cannabis compliance software company
everybody just thinks we're an inventory
tracking company anybody that ever hears
us it's like oh you're just like MJ
freeway oh you're just like green bin so
you're just like flow hub depending on
which is the the talk of the town at the
moment and and we're not anything like
that and explaining what we do is
complicated and and and how what our
value is is kind of tricky because
people don't like compliance they don't
like to follow the rules they didn't get
into cannabis because they like
following rules my opinion is everybody
in the cannabis industry is
anti-authoritarian and well yeah it's
it's true I am too I just want everybody
to follow this one set of rules that's
it
ignore all the other ones just just just
just just the cannabis regulatory rules
listen to those so we can legalize
marijuana what about what about the OSHA
part worker safety business regulation
stuff just not government this is from
the government affairs guy or the drug
laws maybe listen to some other ones hey
Jordan do you mind if we open it up for
questions because we only
eight minutes left and I want to give
people a chance to I cut you off a
little bit for this no you must have
been very thorough well I know that you
know there's a lot of different kinds of
partnerships in business and we only
covered a few is anybody dealing with
any partnership issues or wondering if
you should do something what I do if it
doesn't work out yeah I mean you set up
a partnership you sign the things you do
your due diligence and it's still not
great how do you extract yourself err so
they're an employee you terminate no
fair
if it's an independent contractor make
sure you have a good in contract and
indemnification clauses to try to help
you with that and if it's a regulatory
agency then you're backpacking Europe
that's that's my approach but what if it
doesn't work out with any of your
strategic partners so inner circle folks
you know that core people that run your
business it's a marriage at the end of
the day it's a marriage and in your case
it is a marriage so that's what it has
to be and and be very selective about
that marriage right you know you know
date someone for two days and go hey
let's get married right you date someone
for six months a year year and a half
two years before you go hey you know
what I really like you let's get married
so be just unbelievably selective about
that inner circle and I would much
rather have a piece of the chain or a
piece of the pie missing and not be able
to function in that area that have
a real adversarial situation especially
within that inner circle so just be
advised take your time you gotta like
the people you're working with we have a
saying in our business no
so there you go I think do a lot of
people really rush business formation
just really taking the time to have a
good operating agreement good
communication of goals involve a really
good law firm unless you have those
skills yourself because the more you lay
a great foundation then you can really
move forward from that
I think they'll always go every they'll
they'll always go bad at some point some
relationship will always go bad in
business and we have a rule and it's act
in the highest sense of right and always
be respectful and with those when you do
get to that point there's a way to be
respectful and I think that's what we do
and you know as far as employees go we
hire adults and treat them like adults
and and that's the way it is and then we
also expect them to act like adults but
you do get to that point where sometimes
you have to say you have to break up and
I think having high emotional
intelligence being able to be respectful
and try to understand the other person's
point of view and if you act in the
highest sense of right you can usually
get through those that's great I mean I
think it's so important to understand
that you know you never want to be a
bridge burner especially in this
industry it's so small it's so familial
people know each other and people these
relationships I mean they go back a very
long time and even new ones seem to be
deeper than in other industries that
I've worked in that that there's a sense
of connection and community in cannabis
that doesn't necessarily exist in like
the oil and gas industry or something
like that and so you know you have to
understand both how to be a good person
when you are breaking up with somebody
you know you don't want to be the bad
breakup guy that's not good in business
it's probably good in any facet of life
as well but you also want to have an
exit plan right and I don't think that
means every relationship you get in you
don't immediately start
how am I gonna get out of this but if
you do find yourself in a partnership
and it's not working for you you know
you need a plan on how you're going to
you know and that relationship so that
it's done in a manner that's respectful
a manner that's mutually beneficial and
so that you're not kind of screwing
yourself along the way right like if you
fire your lawyer because you're
aggravated with your lawyer and you
don't have a new lawyer in place or
someone to take all of that paperwork
from them like you're gonna need a
lawyer at some point and if you don't
have a new one you could be picking that
your next attorney too quickly you could
be picking your next director of
cultivation whatever it is and so you
know understanding you know sometimes if
our relationships not working even being
upfront about it hey like I think at the
end of this quarter you know we should
part ways so everybody has a notice so
you're not jumping the gun on somebody
but at the same time you need to put a
plan in place of a succession even if
it's you leaving your organization there
has to be some kind of a plan of what
you're gonna do next
that's far any questions questions from
anybody there's one I think if you're
loud
for me it is really understanding our
vision as an organization and
understanding that we're putting
consumers first and everything that
we're doing and then being a great
communicator people that can really go
back and forth and you know don't
snowball and be willing to come in and
communicate I'm looking for people that
have longevity and loyalty and able to
communicate and kind of move forward so
those are the things I'm really looking
for in my associates I this is gonna
sound really strange but I look for
people that have long term relationships
and I mean that on a private and a
business level so if I have if I'm
dealing with someone and they go yeah my
best friend I've known for two years
that's not a good indicator for me but
if they have you know several friends
that they've known for 30 or 40 years
that has some real teeth to it and has
some traction for me you know I look for
emotional intelligence when I'm hiring
for employees we try not we do a pretty
thorough interview along with a panel
interview so that we are getting
different points of view on a candidate
not one person's making the decision and
then from a business perspective I look
for references I look for you know
there's usually enough data out there
all right look for relationships that
I've used in the past yeah I mean I'd
agree with all that especially the
values and finding people who fit your
values but but I think you also have to
leverage your network and your
relationships and you know find out what
you can about these potential
individuals through your friends or or
or talk to your friends in the industry
and figure out who they've used for
those kinds of situations in the past
you know I for me a recommendation from
someone I trust is a lot more important
than anything someone can say in an
interview an interview as you pointed
out can not really be indicative of
reality and so you know
you want to talk to someone they've
worked for someone they've worked with
in an industry this small you should be
able to find somebody somewhere along
the line that you know or someone that
you know is seven degrees of Kevin Bacon
away in one way or another and find
somebody who can really give you the
skinny on what's going on behind the
scenes I think that's it for our group
and the next panel is coming up and
thank you guys for listening
[Applause]