oh it's about that time in half the room
didn't clear out so obviously I'm not
back home in California welcome to the
4/20 session on that note and definitely
thank you for all that are hanging out
for the final session here with us
so a quick introduction about myself I'm
stoked I finally get to be a moderator
versus a panelist so this is the first
time for me in five years
my background in the industry originally
grew up in Northern California so it was
always around the craft in the culture
interesting enough studied chronology in
college so wasn't necessarily the path I
was originally gonna take but that's a
whole other story now currently in the
head of the herbal category for Bovada
and formerly director of media at a
little tech company called weed maps out
of Southern California and then okay
kind of a big one but and then before
that started with a friend the first
mainstream news site called the cannabis
out of a Denver Colorado back when the
first adult use market started but
enough about me we'll jump right into
our panelists and we will start with
ladies first if that's okay gentlemen so
we'd like to start off with a Tyler
Sally if you could tell us a little bit
about yourself and your business I have
a cannabis brand called juices 22 it's
well it's a lifestyle brand and
underneath the lifestyle we promote
cannabis and we have multiple products
that we are going to launch in different
states across America and eventually
internationally yeah awesome and then
mr. Charles Feldman also from the states
are beginning to troduce yourself
Thank You Charles Feldman I like to say
my cannabis career started about 25
years ago I was a federal prosecutor in
Southern California that wasn't enough
for me so I had to join the DEA and I
was a task force commander for the DEA
this is you can start sometimes the
audience actually boos me right about
this bachelor number three I think you
asked to leave the stage I was exactly
speaking to the lapel autoloader did
narcotics prosecution also after that by
then I'd had my fill of government
started my own law firm we got into
cannabis about ten years ago working
with some high net worth clients and now
I like to describe a little bit of
atonement for me personally being able
to now work on the other side of
cannabis being able to use a lot of
those skills that we used early on in
the in the war on drugs environment to
help our clients navigate some really
difficult international regulations
international landscapes so it's been a
very fascinating journey for me both
personally and being part of this in
enormous social experience now I work
with a international strategy company
navigating cannabis and hemp all around
the world whether it's capital funding
marrying up those two partners or
actually just building a good workable
strategy that produces profit so tiny
little bit thank you and a good segue to
Emmanuel kotzen from humph media all the
way across the pond coming from Germany
yes thanks a lot my name is mano
McCutcheon about twenty five five years
ago I started making click initiation
work for cannabis and after a few years
I noticed I have I have to generate some
kind of job and to go on legalizing or
we found a company called again to a
Soviet and Soviet is the publisher of
the biggest hemp magazine in Germany
also this is no 20 years ago and in on
those 20 years a lot things happened a
lot of adventures women
mastered and we are now in a very
interesting position on the German
market with a medicinal cannabis
legalization and a lot of possibilities
too we we're still hoping one more
cannabis coming from Canada but also
from all of the planet please send your
product to Germany and then we'll bring
it back to this side the problem with
Vincent jollity out of New York and LA
hey guys
co-founder of show products we start in
the industry with extraction equipment
most notable brand we have is rosin tech
products we kind of completed the circle
to incorporate about 1200 SKUs of
ancillary products and we have
distribution in Czech Republic widel
ahora Mexico in LA we truly are a global
company and we service multiple
countries every day of the week and our
goal is to kind of unite the cultures of
the world through cannabis and create
some long-lasting brands in the process
indefinitely last but not least we'll
bring it back home to mr. Darren Gill
thank you so my career in cannabis
started when I was 16 and I thought
growing weed was as simple as buying a
light and a grow tent off of ebay failed
miserably at that spent 11 years in
global manufacturing and supply joined
Deloitte focused on M&amp;A where I helped
on both sides of some of the largest
transactions that have taken place in
the kind of a space and then much like
this at a panel met the former CEO of
namaste technologies fell in love with
their story and their model around
partnership and currently their chief
strategy officer awesome thank you sir
so we'll kick it right off there's some
interesting topics in the green room
with us someone started talking about
politics I don't know who chose that
topic but we definitely will get into
something a bit fun and strategic
partnerships this is something just on a
personal front is is a huge factor in my
mind coming from the media space some
similar to what Hoff has done quite
successfully on the other side
on I always saw a huge success in
collaborating with other brands
especially like-minded and those that
have similar core values and beliefs but
it's huge in order for everyone to move
everything forward in this industry so I
think kind of bouncing off to to Vince
to start here the question that we have
to start off with is what makes
partnering in the industry a win-win for
all parties involved well it's not
always a win-win it's definitely not
always a win-win you got to be careful
who you partner with because there's a
lot of people that aren't interested in
a win-win so I would say aligning your
interests and aligning what both
companies are looking for their core
values at the end of the day if you can
align the values of both company of what
they're looking to accomplish and keep
those aligned those are the the best
partnerships that we've had so far when
our interests are aligned that's when we
usually run into some issues with going
back to the contract and trying to hash
things out usually when your interests
aligned you don't really need to
reference your contract that often you
have a open communication and if there's
any issues that arise you can call up
the other party and try to work it out
because at the end of the day if you
guys are both aligned you're trying to
move forward you're not trying to create
road bumps and hiccups for the other
party so I would say just aligning your
interest would be the the biggest thing
and also the same question for you Tyler
one thing that she's doing right now is
cross licensing which were required to
do being that we are not federally legal
in the u.s. so you con questing' into
new states what would you say are the
things you look for in those
partnerships as you expand your brand
usually if I'm when I try to build
partnerships I want to make sure that
the company that I'm going to go in
business with is somebody or a group of
people that not only bring innovation
but they also bring that operation side
so I need somebody that you have to be
able to see the vision with me and help
me move further as well as whatever you
bring to the table
you have to be able to want to grow
bigger and see past whatever we're
hiring me for and I think that's the
most important thing because you can't
really plan for the next 10 years but
you can plan for how or who you're gonna
be with in the next 10 years then from a
little different angle Charles you know
we hear a lot of acronyms as we get into
these partnerships rather [ __ ] use and
NDA's and the rest of it but from a
legal standpoint what are some of the
things that you recommend for even the
simplest partnerships
I mean partnerships are marriages and
sometimes in business they're even more
important more devastating more
rewarding than some of your own personal
relationships so I've always tried to
advise my clients look at a partnership
from a very personal perspective look at
the context of what you're talking about
are you similarly situated or is one
unequal to the other partner what is
your exit strategy I'm always preaching
you know from the very beginning of that
partnership how are you gonna exit when
are you gonna exit what does that look
like for you what does that look like
for your partner you know are the two
aligned making sure you've done a real
proper vetting it's a lot of it is just
common business tools that you should
bring into this industry no different
than you would in any other typical
partnership then Emmanuel yours is a
little different and I think we've
actually had a partnership before in a
past life at one of my companies how is
it internationally to do partnership
especially when some things are lost in
translation and obviously laws as they
pertain to your country versus another
country that you might be working with
an entity yet yeah before getting into
contact I try to find out if my partner
if my possible partner is really aware
of the legal situation of this product
this is for me a key question because I
see a lot of companies which have really
good products that might be they are not
really 100% sure if they are legal or
not and I'm ready to overtake a part of
the risk but I would like to know before
which part of the risk so in the
international cooperation I try to find
partners who have knowledge a heuristic
knowledge about their products and also
an opinion about it and I ask them also
if they have at least one lawyer who
confirms it yes you know do to have an
idea about if something is legal or not
this is the biggest problem in European
community officially we have the same
law the same directives but I have 27
different languages also it's 29
altogether in 27 countries police
officers registration offices which are
talking total different interpretation
cultural interpretation and I cannot
expect an administrative officer working
for the French government to accept a
German stamp you know I have to redo it
and redo the process of legalizing
my product or my theory so what this is
a key question for me about if it's
legal and we say we try to stay on the
legal side then the exit strategy is not
that risky I would say and then back to
you then one saving the best for last I
promise so as far as partnerships from
province to province maybe even from
province to state any sort of feedback
on best practices there well I think one
of the things you know around strategic
partnerships is to make sure you find
somebody that fills a gap and has an
actual value proposition for you so one
of the things we're trying to do at kin
Mart is position ourselves to help LPS
that aren't necessarily interested in
the processing and sales aspect but
really focused on cultivating
so we actually had a press release even
come out today that talks about how
we're now into the BC government and
looking to expand into other channels
we're in a unique position where we're
not a cultivator ourselves so everybody
in this room potentially is an industry
partner for us to be working with what
we do is basically act as the middle
agent to be able to help you get
processing services get the product
packaged make sure it's compliant take
you through the testing and work to be
able to bid into the government's we
also have an e-commerce platform so we
partner with a whole host of LPS and
Industry folks to be able to sell direct
to consumer medical cannabis and so you
know being able to get into those
channels do the bid lists I think if we
look at the way any other public sector
has gone you know health care being a
great example
you went from hundreds of suppliers
trying to supply the health authorities
to they've got three or four main
distributors that they're working with
now so we're able to go to the
provincial governments to any of the
partner companies with a catalog
offering of all of your brands because
we're not interested in competing in
that space great answer and that's
something I'd say as well for us we we
don't just target one segment of the
actual industry and that's beneficial to
your point because everyone in this room
can be a client you know definitely on
the b2b side but still a great factor
and you segue into the next question
perfectly and I'll pass this on to Vince
we'll go in order here so for your
company and specific events and your
little diverse as well what do you
actually bring with your respective
products to the table and what is the
ideal partner that you would say it's
that the ideal partner really it varies
in what sector of our business we're
talking about but for an ancillary
distribution side which is our strongest
division right now I would say a strong
brand product so a lot of the consumer
goods in the cannabis space can be kind
of chintzy and non branded type items in
the smoke shop market particularly I'm
talking about like consumption type
devices so what we strive as partners is
we're not looking to
to distribute the the bottom of the
barrel type products we're looking for
actual products that have branding
marketing budgets a sales team presence
at trade shows bringing more to the
table than just a product great great
response because that's the same thing
we're looking for as well in Tyler
likewise but again you know the fact
that your cross licensing and expanding
and already I believe in three states
but looking for future states and future
countries what are some of the
challenges in finding that ideal partner
being that that laws and regulations
vary and even demographics and
geographical factors play in as well
it's I kind of like that it's different
each place because then I can have my
products be specific to that city or
state wherever I am at and I think the
best partner that I can have is someone
who can provide what they say they can
provide whenever I need it a lot of the
times in cannabis I feel like there's a
lot of hype a lot of people will say
okay I can give you this as this and
then when it comes down to it you might
not get the product that you originally
agreed upon or it might not come tasting
the same we're looking the same so I the
most important is someone with
consistency as a brand that's what I'm
looking for but I think going
state-by-state for me I know that in
Arizona they're more focused on a
medicinal side with nursing home
products for people with a lot of
ailments and stuff like that
whereas in California it's one of the
biggest markets but you can get anything
you can go on the recreational side
where it's just more chilling or you can
also get a topical for your back pain so
I think having a brand that goes
state-by-state is important for me
because I can have unique products in
each state as opposed to just being
generic completely across the board
perfect and what kind of morph this a
little bit because a lot of people don't
know there's 40 countries around the
world that if either legalized or
deregulated a good example is Portugal
that technically be scheduled all drugs
and then launched a medical cannabis per
but Michael we've talked about Olivia
the International what are some of the
challenges you have as far as working
over borders and understanding this kind
of segues a little bit of what we were
talking about some of the laws and
regulations that you're having to deal
with from from obviously market to
market
yeah well as I mentioned before please
you have such an advantage in in the
u.s. in the North America of one
language imagine you you should print
your your flyer in 27 languages just in
the european community with particular
officially it's the same regulation but
you will find out different country
different translation different
interpretation so of course we working
worldwide what we try to concentrate on
the countries which we understand better
because some some countries are really
difficult to be understood from the from
the and but what we can what we see of
course different countries makes it
easier to to registrate and to get in
business in this moment we see germany
is more or less a consumer market we're
waiting for the products even it's not
easy to to pass the border but if you
pass the border like it was on a panel
before i can confirm with a german stamp
within the european community you are a
lot more comfortable to go somewhere
else with with your product than with a
stamp let's say from from a small
country with one exception my big
recommendation really have a look on
Luxembourg they have announced they want
to have the full regulation
and I took just eight weeks ago to the
Minister of Health
HM Snyder he was just on the trip to
Canada to have a look how it's working
here and I told him yeah please also ask
those who working with it because they
also already developing one step forward
don't make the same mistakes and each
country needs also a regulating system
which across to the to the local yeah
conditions we cannot compare Laxton work
with with German but and this is the big
plus we have no borders anymore between
Luxembourg and Germany and France
Luxembourg is a great place to go they
have a strategic position you can reach
each point of the European community
within 24 hour with you your parcel so
when they regulate the right way you
have a really wonderful hub in the
European community in the center of it
his usage also to supply Germany or
France yeah and I think that's one thing
he's talking on for those who didn't get
the memo that Luxembourg did allowance
announced legalization of adult use to
come into effect hopefully by 2022 but
the fact that Canada has been quite an
influence right and some of the things
happening globally being a Commonwealth
country France has announced a medical
beta program Ireland finally has come
around of course to England announced as
well so Charles and some of some of the
legal things that come into play because
all of us have talked about dabbling in
the international some of us already do
of course what again are the challenges
that you see even logistical e with
doing business even just across the pond
over to a place like Europe that's a
great question I think most of what my
strategy company that I'm a part of we
talk with clients the most about is just
context
the international community is so
exciting there's so much sex appeal to
it being an international brand but
unless you truly can grasp the context I
mean just listening to some of these key
experts talk about practicing on an
international scale it gets really
complicated you know how complicated is
just in your own jurisdiction where you
operate right now whether that's a local
city or Providence or a state when you
move outside and you're crossing
international borders and you're dealing
with international drug control treaties
and UN and who some of the speakers
talked about it earlier it truly gets
complicated and as my you know fellow
speaker here is talking about if you're
a company that is really focused on
compliance and being a hundred percent
compliant in whatever whatever area
you're operating in truly grasping that
context is vitally important as you
continue to grow and your success grows
that level of compliance becomes even
more important you've seen a lot of
great companies make considerable
revenue they're there on this upswing
and then have some real compliance
hidden skeleton you know in their
background that that really makes that
difficult to continue that level of
revenue growth so another question and
we obviously know some obvious for the
Canadian market I would probably say
lift for for the US it's definitely MJ
biz I think even for Emanuel maybe
spannabis or Mary Jane or Kenna fest but
what are some of the other places for
individuals in the crowd that are
looking to establish strategic
partnerships or grow strategic
partnerships what are some of the places
that you would recommend to search out
these contacts in these companies short
of a Google search is there any sort of
Secrets that you might have and you know
what could those be that have really
helped you out again we'll start with
you there and if that's okay yeah no I
think the biggest place assault me out
is looking through your own personal
Network
I think the degrees of separation within
this industry are fairly small and you
usually know a guy who knows a guy very
similar to back in the day so you know
it reach out to the folks around you
there's a lot of companies that have
been Trailblazers and being a
trailblazer is great but the risk you
take getting out in front of the pack is
getting burned so learn from others
mistakes you know roll that into what
you're doing and develop a sound
strategy and approach that it you know
really requires focus and picking the
verticals that you want to take on and
really own and looking for the right
relationships around you to be able to
help fill in the rest of the gaps
because as we've seen time and time
again no one company can do everything
well very well put and we'll continue on
down the line with events a little bit
of your feedback as well I think he said
the words out of my mouth the only thing
I would add is know your strengths like
really you have to be honest with
yourself what am I good at and what am I
not good at and you have to find someone
who's good at what you are not good at
it's not gonna work after that I guess I
would I would continue to add the
vetting process I just think it is so
important especially in a lot of the
work that I've done either legally for
clients or helping clients build
strategy is truly vetting the
information that you get it's a great
industry it's got great people in it
but like any other industry there are a
lot of snake oil salesmen there are a
lot of people who are just looking for
the quick dollar or whatever that may be
so I constantly again go back to just
common business practices like it would
be in any other industry that that
information know who you're getting
involved with know what that background
is if it's coming from the legacy
community know what that means
I mean truly know what is coming forward
as you as you build out your
your business wants to add more yet puts
time into it into making that connection
we investing from the first day of of
our existence time into international
networking because we know exactly this
is a global market and then first ten
years we need to find out who is really
active in Europe in our neighbor
countries and you know all we on a level
to invest a lot of time running around
the planet from shore to show I can by
the way recommend really I CPC you
events because it's b2b and I'm very
happy about a Berlin event because the
whole planet is coming to Berlin and it
saves my travel costs thanks for this
and which is the real interest very good
chef yes and but I cannot recommend one
special show or a secret show there are
debt many popping up we have at least
fifty in Europe going on I was four
months ago in Ukraine uh and I was super
surprised by the high quality of of the
convention there but of course you
cannot predict that and the market in
you Crona is very far away please don't
don't think next next day you can make
return on investment but super
interesting countries super interesting
possibilities but you have to invest
time and to develop trust to our content
I just want to add that like the
networking at the events I think I know
you said other than the events but the
networking at the events is really key
especially like for three years I
basically from 2015 to 2018 I didn't
have a home I went from trade show to
trade show I didn't stay in one place
for more than six states I have it
booked at my calendar I didn't stay in
one place for more than six days over
that course of three years I built a
worldwide network that I leaned on every
day so so that network that I continue
to build and be at the astrayed shows is
really my biggest asset in this industry
because like he said like we really are
like a degree of separation from someone
and if
you ask around about someone someone
else knows whether they're good they're
bad what their strengths are what their
weaknesses are so I would just say that
people out through the industry it's
still a small industry it's still an
intimate industry it's still not that
many of us at the top or players in the
game so just lean on your fellow network
and and that's what would be my advice
and I just want to add one thing around
the whole vetting but I think it's
really important you know there's a lot
of advisers and everybody's an expert in
this industry vet your advisers as well
it makes them an adviser exactly it just
became a kind of advisor yesterday
exactly you know I think one of the
things that I've seen time and time
again personally and other companies as
well is all too often the way you ask
the question will change the answer you
get so also make sure what you're trying
to achieve and that you're asking those
questions the right way because it'll
often you know you can talk to five
people and get five different answers
that's spot-on and I think exactly what
Vince what you're talking about yeah
those of us have been on this circuit
and the same thing I've been on for five
year I did 30 shows my division I had
268 shows but 30 of them I worked for
the exact same reason you speak because
you have to get out there you have to
build your network in your network has a
net worth right that's exactly what
you're saying so if you are a company or
an entity that has the vests ters that
want to get into this industry look for
someone who does have that network
because it is such an advantage an
exponential advantage to move forward
and I think a few things we talked about
in the green room Tyler mentioned it's
interesting because I compared a
partnership to a marriage just just like
what was said in the green room as well
but Tyler said you know I'm also looking
for what I don't want in a partner and
it isn't any different than your
personal life you know I explained just
my little second cousins they're now 23
but I said you know you don't go through
life knowing exactly what you do want
you realize what you don't want and it's
applicable in so many situations in this
one very much just as much so definitely
all excellent feedback kind of say going
into how does a business in in this is
definitely a little while because it's
applicable different to individuals on
this board because some of us are
focused on widgets on tangible goods in
others
are not intangibles right services
versus goods but a good question is you
know how does a business generate net
profits and actual valuations in the
global space and and I think we'll again
we'll start the opposite end with a
manual first sorry but I did not
understand really a question so yeah so
you obviously so you offer a service
let's say more so than a tangible
product so where do you actually pull a
net profit or a positive out of that
from a partnership yeah what what we
really can office a net profit is of
course our possibility to advertise and
to marketing within our network so each
partner can really profit out of this
and it's an easy thing to drop this in
into a partnership and this is like yeah
we can we can repeat this and we hope
that our partners see the effect are
growing just faster this is this is a
big advantage and through this through
this possibilities of also being very
open with with this kind of services we
generated a lot of of cooperation might
be just small cooperation but spreading
the information about your product about
each product it it makes a nice
situation a nice mood for maybe making
more together very simple thing it don't
cost a lot from our side and makes open
doors for sure definitely in Charles I
know it's may be a slight variance on
this question for you but maybe even as
a third party as mean that individual
from a counselor legal side what things
do you you kind of point out as far as
where it's rewarding for both parties in
partnerships
I think it's for that question with a
lot of times we're value-add because
we're telling you what you don't want to
hear having been from the complete other
side of this industry having fully
embraced this industry in really looking
for ways that we're not just making
money but we're actually helping you
accomplish what it is you are out to
accomplish it's not always easy to do
and it's there are a lot of yes people
out there we're just going to tell you
whatever you want to hear that's great
we're gonna make millions of dollars
we're going to change the world we're
going to cure cancer and not all of us
are gonna get to do that and really
being able to have professional services
around you that are true that are honest
authentic and are going to tell you
things that you don't want to hear I've
found has been real value to our clients
have saved them lots of money time pain
energy along the way great and then
Tyler obviously from a cross-licensing
or brand partnership the benefits there
I I feel like my role on the brand side
is to help educate as much as possible
and D stigmatize I think that's if
anything a brand can do is help the
cannabis movement move forward in a
positive light so that's my biggest
mission in anything cannabis is to make
sure that I'm teaching people how great
this plan is but I'm also getting rid of
all of the negative that we were
originally taught
great I think for for us on the
ancillary distribution side our biggest
value at is that we we have a sales team
with current relationships with over
5,000 retail shops across the globe so
when we do identify a potential product
that we think fits into our catalog we
can bring that to to the doors of many
shops very quickly but the other thing
and kind of what he touched on is that
we're very upfront if your product
doesn't work we're gonna tell you this
is wrong the boxing's wrong this doesn't
work and like not in a negative way but
we we offer like a brand acceleration
program also so we'll help you if we
think there's value there to to reformat
your packaging or readjust your margins
and whatever is wrong with the product
that we don't think is gonna work we'll
adjust it so kind of giving you the
truth on whether your product is gonna
make it in market or not perfect so you
know I think two years ago the way I
would have answered this question is a
lot different than today when you had
easy access to capital and you could
sneeze the word cannabis and raise five
million bucks in a room the fact is in
today's market where you know there's a
lot of headwinds and a lot more
challenges at getting access to capital
there's really three things that I think
about and it goes back to focus leverage
and choices and focus to me is pick
where you want to fit in the value chain
what you really really want to
specialize on and execute that business
plan have a strategy you know I think
like we've heard other panelists talk
about how are you gonna get out of this
business what are you going in why are
you doing this and really have those
things defined and written down and they
may change over time but making sure you
stay true to your business plan leverage
is once you've invested in something
make sure that you find new ways of
leveraging that investment so for us at
Tan Mart we were originally a
direct-to-consumer e-commerce platform
for medical well hey great we've got
this facility I've got a license that
can do processing and sales why am I not
selling into rec how can I use this as
an upsell to other LPS about you add
service and the other one is choices you
know sometimes it's a very exciting
industry you're gonna get opportunities
coming out you left
right and center but picking and
choosing which ones you're gonna take
and ultimately being able to say no and
walk away from opportunities to stay
true to your business plan is hugely
important because you may miss an
opportunity here but you may run out of
capital bandwidth or just energy to
execute on the other parts that work a
fundamental part of your business when
you start it off so I think you've got
to really stay true to a strategy once
you've laid it out and and this is you
know not to sound like a strategy guy
but when you plan something out for 2 to
3 years
there's a reason you're going down that
road and shifting every week or you know
two months because something new and
hots come up isn't the right way to
execute on a business that's spot-on and
actually have a good example of what
you're talking about you know we're
again very big on strategic partnerships
at Bhavana and we found that we're
growing out of one partnership but we
found someone that takes that place
almost with the 10 acts as far as what
the attribute from both sides it's it's
not one-sided but it's a very good point
don't feel like you're constantly locked
in and what a lot of us do because the
industry is still small enough all of us
know this I mean the fact that that
there's relationships up here from
different countries is a good example of
it but don't lock yourself in a lot of
these are gentleman agreements a lot of
them are handshakes hopefully not loaded
handshakes you might establish an NDA or
again an MoU to work together but
leaving yourself an open end or some
sort of clause because all of a sudden
someone's business strategy changes
yourself included and you need to be
able to adapt and move the ship
accordingly right no it's been a huge
part of what we've been trying to do
with our direct-to-consumer
relationships you know we made a choice
we launched out and we had our own
branded product we realized if we're
truly trying to be an industry partner
and partner with LPS I can't have a
competing product when I'm trying to
sell yours we made a conscious decision
to stop that work so we can focus on the
relationship with the LPS because that's
what was important to our business
strategy spot-on so this gets the next
question a little more detail and then
I'll give an example you know for us
above it I'm very fortunate that we've
got a phenomenon R&amp;D team so one of the
things that we do when we partner
because everyone we consider partners
not customers for success but we
actually offer a service where
we do leak down tests on LPS packaging
right so we want to make sure to
maintain the quality and consistency of
the product maintain that moisture but
obviously we all know air and and light
is the other two things that further an
expedite the degradation of the plant so
that's a specific attribute that we
bring to a partnership is there one
specific attribute that you kind of have
as that ace up your sleeve that you find
pulling out and putting on the table
more often than not and we can go back
down the line no definitely I think for
for us the the biggest ace up our sleeve
is that direct to consumer access and
the fact that we take care of customer
service technology development and
product distribution those are the three
areas that we want to play and that's
where our focus is so from from that
portion that's that's the strongest
value add that we bring to our partners
I would say also our distribution
network of direct-to-consumer and also
the fact that our team has our finger on
the pulse our team is extremely
knowledgeable depending on which sector
of our team but we have a lot of
knowledge and our finger on the pulse in
the industry so knowledge finger on the
pulse and our distribution network we
our strong suits
produces our I feel like our biggest
strength right now is marketing and
making sure there is a positive brand
association with our brand and just
getting the name out getting everywhere
and making sure that people will see
doose's and immediately know that they
can trust us and that's something that
we've been trying to push for a while
and I also feel like there are certain
products that I know I need to find the
best version of this because there's the
market is flooded with the greatest
vapes but I need to know which vape is
the best vape and I feel like that's
something that we've really tried to
figure out is what are the best products
for us to get involved in and how to get
those products as many places as
possible without like over saturating
the market I have no idea what the
question is was our our strengths so in
my game Jason your ace up the sleeve
far as for your specific business that
you bring to the table and negotiating
strategic products I would say for us
said at GPS that global it would be
authenticity so whatever we're going to
talk about whatever we're gonna give you
is gonna be authentic we're not gonna
sell you something we can't deliver
we're not gonna promise something that
is unreachable we're not gonna build a
strategy that is that is ridiculous
it's truly gonna come from a very
grounded place of authenticity
I've seen so many consultants out there
who truly come from the last failed
three businesses and so now they're a
consultant so I agree I don't know who
said that down they're like eh bet your
professional services absolutely
whether it's your lawyer your accountant
your consultant make sure you know where
they're coming from and where this
advice that is you know supposedly so
expensive where where that's coming from
and why yeah it's difficult to answer
because in order we have know 20 years
of history was with this business and
it's not easy to when we started it was
easier to exact define we we want to
spread the information and we overtook
some some kind of leadership in this
information building information
spreading in Germany and as the S
approached as the market became bigger
the challenges became bigger so our like
main topic is still to keep keep ahead
with the information because we build up
a huge database of information about
regulations about products exactly
persons players organizations and et
cetera a huge data collection in fact
and we trying really to to update it
daily
and to gather more information and a
totally no go for us is when our partner
cannot tell me our a story about his
product when is a soul less product I
cannot sell it I cannot promote it I
need a story yes and this is a no-go if
you just have a price list that's that's
two less for for me we need some real
story behind it yeah I agree I think the
moral of the story is definitely do your
homework and we don't mean to pick on
consultants but all of us have come
across them I had one in LA she is an
industry expert looked at her LinkedIn
she's a Pilates instructor last year I
don't think we mean to pick on ya have
knowledge but yeah it's consulting and
you're out there pretending to be a
consultant like I'll pick on you like
don't don't be there don't be giving
people false information like you will
call you out at one point like come
across someone that knows their
information and pretend to be a
consultant and cool well I think some of
them they they pull from their
experience this one in specific said
well you know I've been consuming
cannabis in size 14 I said well I've
been using a restroom since I was born
and I'm not a urologist you know I just
so you guys know I was in my college
town for 10 years I did not get a doctor
but that's exactly just do your homework
is what we're getting out I think that's
kind of the overarching message here is
do your homework when you come into a
partnership
this isn't tinder you don't just swipe
right you're not just DTF you're not
just down to have fun this is something
that's so Polly hopefully somewhat of a
long-term we gotta get a little
lightheaded a day you guys if you
haven't smoked you should so it's one of
those things where you you just have to
take it serious though think of it more
of match calm or farmers calm whatever
you want to actually do a little
homework get a little background get to
know um it doesn't mean you have to be
married with them forever this is the
2000s but still at least dude ill do
diligence and and if not vince will call
your ass out
so let's segue into some Q&amp;A we'll keep
it a little light we definitely have a
few minutes I think for questions and
Mike's gonna be coming around let's hear
for the panel
more time does anyone have any questions
Bueller Bueller
[Music]
all right all the way well you have to
sit so far away man it's called exercise
a long day I wore comfy shoes that's the
important thing
question for the panel wondering what
you guys see is some of the most
strategic and important strategic
partnerships that you can have right now
in the industry and of course this could
go company by company so please it could
be an image or it could be an
overarching for us all starting as
packages packaging the packaging
division companies like a pack and two
packed push bottles Green Lane some of
the biggest players there are obvious
partners to us because it's like
chocolate and peanut butter right so it
just makes sense you know that's where
our product typically goes so ya know
for us it's focusing on value add
services so you know we've got a
relationship with Shopify we've got a
partnership with my friends at Bovada
we work on accessories so we work with
Green Lanes so you know we've got a
strong ecommerce platform we've got
relationships with a whole host of LPS I
think we've got the widest product
selection for medical cannabis available
anywhere right now on our website from
LP and SKU count and we're continuing to
grow it and you know sign new partners
up every week for us it's strong
products strong brands that we can
distribute those are what we're looking
for and then on the extraction equipment
quality processors for us it's making
sure that its quality flour or whatever
we're getting we need that's like the
most important thing to me something
that I will smoke something that I'll
give someone else to smoke but I need to
be able to trust the grower and I think
that's the most important relationship I
have as a brand is to be able to have
flour and say yes I believe in this here
try this
please we love the growers I would say a
an actual strategy a roadmap to profits
so if you don't know from where you are
to where you're trying to go and you
don't have a roadmap of how you're gonna
create actual net revenues then you got
to rethink your business plan
that'd be the simplest way I can answer
that yeah it's not easy to add something
on it I mean strong brands the quality
of the grass is really very very
important for the consumers yes and
might be don't give up the next day take
take your time all to perform for some
users still a lot of market and if the
first plan isn't a success there's still
time for another one I think we had one
more Oh is there one more oh I didn't
see sorry the practice in your baseball
practice myself
underhand base will switch myself barren
or sweet hi this questions for Darren
just wondering do you do pre-rolls at
all is that something you guys are
processing absolutely and my friend
Aaron and the back there can help you
with that okay go keep it simple yeah
thank you all very much and again for
Lance and Thailand Vincent and Darren
and Emmy and Charles