journalist activist german citizen and
all-around great person let's hear it
for margarite arnold
um there are a couple of people who are
going to be joining us here
don't be shy don't leave me out here by
myself
come on where's my panel
there they are come on where's my panel
there they are
the boys they're so shy
i think we're still missing one where's
clint
[Music]
clint's still missing clint is still
missing do we wait
do we start
i think we should start we should have a
conversation
is everyone enjoying barcelona this is
my first time here isn't this awesome to
be back yes clap yes can we hear a round
of applause for the awesome team that
pulled this off icbc rocks right okay
good so um i'm also hoping that we're
going to wake all of you up because it's
been a long awesome day of networking
and whatever but i want to have your
input so i think somebody's got a mic on
the bottom but if not just get up and be
loud the idea is is we're gonna have a
discussion about supply chain strategies
that could drive legalization right and
we want to be really creative about this
in an environment in europe for those of
you who don't know
where
a case called the the can of vape case
in france actually drove a decision
about cbd
on an eu level and actually picking up
for the excellent panel that we just had
with with everybody um before the last
speaker that's actually i think
the suing discussion
and the import export discussion is one
of the best ways that i would say legacy
cannabis and and i would say maybe
cultural cannabis
can have an impact on the corporate side
because if your case is in the news and
you sue and you win
you know that's a pretty big impact on
you know corporate cannabis from an
import export perspective regardless as
a result of that situation
obviously one of the issues in the in
the market right now is when you import
and export across borders there are a
couple of very interesting conversations
that open up both whether what you're
allowed to do from a legalization
perspective like cbd across borders and
then eventually thc and maybe even niche
markets so what i'd like to do actually
is open this up with the first question
about this what is your feeling about
as i would say the strategy of sue the
bastards as you're importing and
exporting even if you have to defend
yourself is that an interesting way do
you think to drive markets as well as
legalization
um i'll be happy to go first
sue the bastards is not really the
european strategy on many things we like
to align ourselves with certain
standards and certain existing uh
structures and try to find a smooth way
in and if [ __ ] hits the fan you can
still you know protect yourself and and
sue if that has if that is an option but
in the end of the day i believe to be
able to open this industry be it on the
cbd the thc or in any other
part of the industry we should really
try to find existing standards existing
products that are aligned with those
products and then find a way around that
and then really align yourself with that
because in the end of the day
suing is
it's another strategy so maybe not the
first one to go with but
keep your interests
in line and protect yourself yes is kai
in the audience for those who don't know
there's a lawyer who is suing the
government over the hemp question maybe
he would disagree but regardless so what
do you think about that
so
my first reaction is that if i look at
the canadian market the whole cannabis
act in canada started from the suing
people suing the government to allow
them access to medication
so yes i mean
the thing is the
that i think that the cannabis market in
in europe in general basically not only
in europe around the world this is what
i called
swiss cheese because it's more horse
than cheese
and
there's no
certain body of regulation
certainly not about uh
moving product from one country to
another
that
that organize it so you can see like if
you're going back to your first
suggestion of suing the buses you can
sue the german government but it won't
change anything about holland denmark or
or lincoln change so
um
i've got a question for you though but
what about then if let's say you sue and
lose and then you appeal i mean that's
you appeal to the eu level right because
that's really where you want to go but
you have to sue at a country level first
well again i i agree that swing i mean
the the
major thing that suing will will give
you is coverage in the news and
basically bringing that the cannabis
into the main
[Music]
conversation so people will talk about
the notification people will talk about
in radio show talk show etc so you will
have some kind of audience that are
basically going behind it
but
i think
the
the point of suing is that you have to
have an issue
i cannot sue the government because i
want
i can sue the government if i want as a
person something that the government
doesn't allow me but i cannot sue
the government based on
imaginary crowd
so that's right but put to your point
about this i mean the whole point about
this is it is swiss cheese and the
people who found themselves in those
lawsuit situations
did not do it on purpose right they
ended up thinking that they could and
then they
got caught and then sued and then that's
how they won
right so so my question is has anyone
have you guys ever been involved in that
kind of lawsuit or
personally not but like i said i mean
the whole system in canada was based on
people suing the government for one
thing then the government
obviously lost the case they had to
change some kind of regulation
then people found you know they were
allowed smoking people someone smoke
sued the government how can you force my
seven years old child to smoke
and obviously you want the case so
that's how the government initially
eventually kind of allow oil etc so
there is uh
you have to have a private standing that
my case has to find a solution um
obviously i don't know if you remember
there was a couple of months ago
a lady that came back to england with a
with a with a child she flew to america
to give her child
cbd
she was arrested as she landed in the
in heathrow
and the child was given to some kind of
social security
uh social services and
immediately it went to the press and
within seven days they changed the law
in england so that's that's another kind
of import export strategy that it's
probably a little bit more risky right
the personal one as opposed to the
corporate one let's move on to the the
next issue which is we were discussing
this back in the green room um one other
thing the impacts of the
uh development of the medical market in
germany what that has done is it's
driven
feeder markets all the way around europe
in fact all over the world right now who
are trying to get medical product into
germany
right and that has driven reform in
places like colombia or south africa
we're sitting at the end here and like
how do you think that
why do you think for example it's
important for the industry i think to be
aware certainly it's not something you
can stretch out of your
realm to do but if you're in the way of
it i mean those are really important
finding you know i would say important
trigger markets
to see reform and will drive reform in
other places and obviously that's
involved in the import export discussion
canada germany or etc what do you think
i'd like to actually take one step back
to the question before about sewing or
not sewing and because just one little
thing that maybe the swiss cheese is
what triggered it there a bit i am from
switzerland what we've done the industry
association has to put has put together
a paper where we analyzed all the
different standards that are out there
and we put them in perspective to
categories and then medical cannabis and
what's coming with recreational and we
made a bottom-up forward motion not a
suing counter-reactive approach by the
bottom-up approach that kind of brings
the industry forward and allows
consensus and based on that then create
standards that we can work with between
the different countries and the import
export regulation in
anything that has to do with eu gmp i
always say it's the easiest
way to do things because it's already
been defined it's already been done it's
been a proven concept the laws are there
the different regulations the exchange
between the countries is there
it's of course the hardest to get it
meets the most different stages of your
compliance and it's the most different
stages reproduction
control over every single aspect of your
operation but in the end of the day at
least it's defined
and i think a big thing that is missing
at the moment is that the definition of
what needs to be done in compliance or
standardization if you want to go
away now medical is clear medical is
clear medical has been done that's the
open trade route at the moment
but what happens with recreational do we
go tobacco laws do we go
narcotic laws do we go full uh
eugmp so i think that's the more
interesting part right now to see other
policy making and then opening different
trade routes is
how do we do how do we define these
different products and how do we build a
harmonized system between the different
countries about that and learn from what
the us has been doing or what have they
i believe they've been doing wrong with
that no choice right it's federally
illegal you cannot move it from one
state to the other it's our choice it's
our chance in europe right now to kind
of
learn from that
but we have to find a regulatory uh not
another regulator
and that's the issue it's like how do
you find that
and how do you define that in a way that
everyone agrees with you i'm sure there
are lots of opinions here about whether
gacp or gmp is going to lead the
recreational discussion across borders
even in germany they're not going to i
mean they're not going to grow
everything that germans are going to
consume right so where's that going to
come from well in a way i agree with
with what luke said i mean definitely
definitely this the lack of regulation
across
europe is is one one object object to to
look at it or a
hurdle that we have to cross
but uh
you know
in a way
if we for example i know like we said
before holland have
tried to come
the cannabis that will end up in the in
the coffee shop in holland will end up
to be gcp compliance so if you comply
with your product and you convince the
authorities or the government itself
showing them convince them that the
product is good
then obviously the demand will
will drive the market i think the
another point of view that we can have
we can
talk about definitely uh is is the
veterinarian product we know that there
is 60 million cats in europe hong kong
as a pets no not as a stray cats
so it's a huge market a veterinary
product for pets so if it's cbd is good
for dogs or cbd is good for whatever the
the code of the of the cats
the demand will
will create some kind of of
allowance in the in the law rather than
through them so this is basically my
approach is
to convince consumers that that product
is
meet some basic standards
that it's safe
but it's
controlled
and therefore it should be legalized
but it's and this is sort of intertwined
right so let's say the german market
wakes up to the beauties of
cbd pet food right and people try to buy
it they try to buy it on amazon and
there's nothing in germany so they buy
it from holland and then that package
crosses the border and someone gets
caught because the germans still have
not decided what cbd is that's the
lawsuit thing right but to your point i
think what you're suggesting is maybe
the development of niche markets
could also drive
i guess consumer demand
but then in that environment
particularly in the in the situation
where we just referenced there is no
standard yet on a european level
welcome to lawsuit city again right
somebody is going to get sued or a firm
is going to get sued that's why this is
coming up again but let's move beyond
that and that's why i wanted to get on
to the idea of
what do you guys think is going to be
the first kind of regulated cannabis to
cross borders
you know in the re in the in the in the
recreational side is it going to be gacp
thc or eu gmp thc what do you guys think
personally like i said if if i look at
my
involvement with with a project in
holland it will be gacp
eu because gazp is is a standard that is
recognized by the ema ema or european
medicinal agency
and it's acceptable all across europe
obviously in germany as well so
again if you've got the narcotic
questions you brought up before right i
mean is it a narcotic is it not a
narcotic certainly on the thc side
you're going to be running into what
exactly is that as long as it's
defined or as long as that is the same
level in the u.n as it has right now it
will be it's a narcotic there's no way
around it so it's it's classified as a
narcotic um in switzerland we have the
pilot project which is like
you know a swiss white or a nationwide
study on how a legalization could go
forward and there's a very clear
regulatory part where this is the actual
narcotics parts that you need to report
and then on the bottom up approach you
have the gacp that you need to actually
comply with then switzerland threw in
there some you have to do it organic so
it has to be grown outside or at least
in the ground so we have added a few
different layers of
making sure that the industry
stays stays uh local in that in the
beginning and it's not being imported
that's the next point that was one of
the things
as long as it's in the in the regulatory
framework it is right now the import and
export is a very difficult thing right
you have to sing that conventionally you
have to make those different agreements
between the countries that means that
both countries need to have the same
agreements on how they declare it the
idea idea so all of that
once we actually agree it's a plant
if you want to transform a plant into a
medicinal product you follow the gacp
guidelines so that is set that has been
that has been done for many many years
you know a lot of smart people came up
with this and you have that as a
standard right and then you go what is
the end product that you want to make
and then you see where it takes you be
it in a consumer product be it in a
medical product and then you follow that
and for me i think the most important
thing is we should stop all trying to do
our own thing
and really see like okay this has been
done in food
this has been done in tobacco this has
been done in medical in the medical
industry
and and not just tried to wiggle our way
through okay now i declare it on this
side as this and i import it as that and
then i distribute it at that and then in
the end i complained that i get sued or
that i go to jail for it like yeah you
just you just wiggled your way around it
but you didn't find a clear straight
line and we have to define that straight
line and then approach the regulator and
the and set standards but you bring up a
very very key point about strategy in
the cannabis market generally a lot of
success is also made by finding that
loophole initially sometimes i i'm not
disagreeing with you at all right but
but for example you know how do you
bring in a plant as a pharmaceutical
product or an api i mean there's lots of
there's lots of i would say loopholes
that exist again because of the lack of
regulatory standard across the eu which
gets to i guess the uber point here
which is certainly within the context of
the eu and switzerland
you know what do you see as the trends
for xm
going forward as
as policies change and vice versa do you
think that for example i mean the
example i gave before germany changed
its medical law and all of a sudden you
have a ring of markets trying to get
their product into germany which is
driven reform
do you see that as a pattern going
forward or not and why
um i guess when whenever a market opens
right there is a lot of people that want
to want to get get access to it one way
or the other and then we see a lot of
different approaches and a lot of
different ways of bringing the product
to germany or bringing the product via x
to z and then bringing it to germany and
there is yeah as you said you can wiggle
your way and there is loopholes at the
end of the day as long as we build an
industry based on wiggling and loopholes
we don't have an economically
sustainable business structure behind it
that will not allow other
large it's not even about corporate
entities right it's just about
supporting uh business structures that
we need to actually grow and bring this
to a further level so as long as we try
to find those ways around it will be
really hard to actually
create a real a real industry right so
so yes those ways are there and as long
as there's opportunities those ways are
being filled but the more we follow
those paths
the more also the out there's always the
other side you'll see told you so
right the cannabis guys again
or the cannabis ladies sorry about the
cannabis industry again right they'll
find their way they found their way for
30 40 years and that's really not what
we wanted going into the future right or
that's that's what i believe is we have
that chance right now to change the tone
to change the actual not just to change
the tonality but also to change the
image of the industry the german
coalition they came out together and
said look we want to do this together in
the u.s it's the only thing that actual
both sides agree on so there's a big
shift in the world and as long as we
wiggle our ways around it and we don't
really try to have a clear path
i think it's quite damaging potentially
damaging
that foreign strategies to drive reform
might be damaging and it would be better
for individual countries like
switzerland like holland to develop a
strong
gacp
policy internally that deals with
cannabis
but it still leaves that question if
you're not growing
like say germany and you've got reform i
mean what what are people supposed to do
import seeds and grow their own i mean
that's my question is like what do you
what is the cannabis that you see
especially thc
in this environment that will be allowed
to cross borders or won't it i mean
maybe it's like the u.s states it's like
holland has its reforms switzerland has
its reform germany has its reform etc
and any cannabis caught going across the
border for recreational use puts you in
jail is that sustainable long-term
either
no i mean i i i think that of course i
agree with you that
people should have a stand in when they
sue however i do tend to agree with with
luke that
the industry as a whole rather rather
than an individual try to set the tones
or set the rules
but if we looking at the other flip side
of it
infomed in israel just announced
recently that they allow cbd but they're
not allowed to use for cosmetic
use so
now what all the cbd are out of the
shampoo
or people will try to find a loophole so
you know
same thing in israel they allow the they
decriminalize decriminalize cannabis
but they excluded
cosmetic products
from
cbd are not allowed to use in cosmetic
products so again the government are
also trying to go kind of
one step forward to step backwards so i
think also the government themselves
don't know what they're doing
well that is frequently obviously right
the case i want to are there any
questions comments from the audience
so far
ah there's one in the back speak stand
up speak up
i'm just wondering uh as far as uh
once we do get to import export
uh
crossing those borders at what point
does it go from
the home like
at what point does the ownership switch
from where that product was um
where the product was going to end up
does that switch in the air
so
so to answer your question first
when you
consume when you strip medicinal product
or
for that our case
medicinal
cannabis it has to comply with gdp good
distribution practice so the same law
that apply for when you send i don't
know aspirin from india to uh
to argentina it has to comply with some
certain of
legislation
of good distribution practice and this
is the the
the law that will govern
the same thing with the um
sorry not recreational medicinal
cannabis when it comes from colombia to
germany or from lasuto to germany
maybe just i think
whenever you have an import in an export
situation you have a buyer and a seller
then you have inco terms the inco terms
is it fob is it free on board is it with
the you know the
freight insurance and taxes it depends
what you actually agree on in the
contract in the buying selling agreement
with whoever you sell it to so when does
the actual responsibility and when does
their payments and all of that go from
one side to the other that is on you to
put it into a contract and that's one of
the things that i meant before when i
said as long as we try to wiggle our
ways around
we do not have access to
institutions that actually protect you
there in any other big commodity
industry you have an lc a letter of
credit then you have somebody that
guarantees that and you do an income
tournament based on that
the risk and so all of those things all
of those things that will allow for a
flourishing industry can only happen if
we it's not just it's not we agreeing on
certain terms right it's been all done
before uh it's all done in other
industries we just have to kind of it's
like the normalization of the industry
and accepting those adapting those
existing laws to it
right so who but i mean i think for
example to answer your question also if
you're importing medical cannabis into
germany there is a very complex
discussion about who you're importing
from the idea of chain of title is very
well um i would say established and
there's not a lot of country hopping
right now in europe but that's another
conversation is there another question i
might just look at it add one thing to
that there's a lot of logistics people
out there that tell you yeah i'll ship
it anywhere i'll ship it anywhere and as
long as you don't see the declaration
form on the import side so you always
have two sides and specifically if you
go with narcotics or if you go in
anything that is on a higher compliance
level you want to make sure that whoever
you sell to either has an agent on the
other side a customs agent or that the
person that wants to sell you that
logistical services provides you with
somebody else on the other side
otherwise they'll take the job they'll
ship the shipment and once it's in the
air or somewhere in between they'll say
like oh well you didn't declare it on
the other side and then they'll have a
nice lawyer that will tell you here look
i'll help you out of it and in the end
you lose a lot of money and your product
is also gone so just
be yeah
look at look at how it's done in many of
the other industries and kind of try to
follow
and
yeah don't get creative don't get
creative importing you know
no no that's not a good idea anybody
else
no okay
well um
where is where is the audience from
mostly is this mostly european or u.s
u.s european
a little bit of a mix
okay so from the us audience perspective
though this whole idea of shipping
across borders is still pretty unique
right so maybe you can maybe elaborate a
little bit more on what the procedures
are oh are we running out of time we
have like 10 minutes you have time oh
okay i'm sure you have a question guys
oh they told me you guys were taking
questions already yes we're taking
questions we're continuing with that
conversation it's an open oh creative
cannabis sort of
you didn't come for a question didn't
come with a question uh yes i have a
question how dare you no i'm kidding
you know duck
you know the answer to that
uh what were we talking about
were you did someone have a question
well we we'd already taken one question
from the audience somebody in the very
very back there was raising the answer
guy you interrupted our conversation
[Music]
so
the whole that whole you know import
export or supply chain or market access
is is a big subject and it's actually
kind of what what i base my my whole
what we're doing on was uh i don't know
i'm not gonna hear
not gonna make a sales pitch but we we
created a compliance software with the
whole focus of how can we solve the
problem of market accessibility how can
we look how can we create something that
allows for standardization along the
supply chain and along the different
players in the supply chain that then
allows them to work with each other in
the back end also have an automated
reporting system that then allows you to
access new markets right and all on a
very standardized but not nothing new
nothing you know too cutting edge over
the top something that's auditable by
the government because they want to do
that if they want to allow you to ship
to certain places and really take a slow
approach slow and steady and get there
and don't try to hoop don't try to jump
the hoop and don't try to go you know
too fast and which sometimes like the
kind of a case it's great if a president
case has been has been formed
but in the end of the day it's really
about slowly building this industry from
the ground up and not taking shortcuts
because that will just bring you
well what's that game with the ladder
you know when you go too fast you can
fall very far so
slow and steady
yeah on that note i definitely agree
again with with
luke and and that's basically what i
said in initially if we convince the the
authorities uh
whether the local government or the
federal government that that product is
is a good kosher up to standard
then obviously there's a way better way
for us to again as an industry to
persuade and change the law and like i
said maybe someone pick up the glove of
a
veterinarian product
um
certainly you know people like
in america
they they a lot of pets so so they they
do that there for cbd product for pair
for dogs etc
but
i i do
think that
again i am coming from the medicinal
background i don't do any of the
recreational
and i
everything that i do is about compliance
and i think i find that the only way to
to change the market and then change to
the attitude is is basically to convince
the regulators that you know we do our
part
but you see this is a domestic
discussion
it that's i think what we're saying this
is a much more
domestic discussion than cross-border
discussion but obviously we get into it
was there another question from the back
no
okay but that's what but i didn't think
from an american perspective it's a
state-by-state conversation still right
if if you're going to produce if you're
going to sell in colorado you have to
grow in colorado you cannot cross
borders with anything except i guess at
this point cbd right the thc discussion
still a state date by state conversation
yes and no because if you look at places
like
[Music]
you know mississippi obviously they not
regulated yet
they regulated for medicinal but you not
regulated for for other jews
but if you look at the uh across this uh
just the town
from the other states just across the
road
you can see that people
from that state actually driving
you know 50 miles just to cross the
border and get it you know
for
crazy americans that's a different story
though
i think it's a big chance for us in
europe to do something different and to
really not follow this follow suit and
not you know we find a harmonized system
that works across borders and that
allows for the trade to flourish and
then i think that's that's what you know
events like this and panels like this
and general uh
compliance efforts and and
standardization efforts are all about
and should be about right finding
something that works for everyone
and then make that actionable and then
based on that you know create something
beautiful but there's still disagreement
about i mean there's a lot of
disagreement right and there's there are
those for example who have for those of
you don't know imported i would say gacp
product into certain companies countries
here in europe and then
transformed that into eu gmp and then
shipped it somewhere else
is that a helpful strategy or is that a
confusing one speaking about industry
coalescence around common practices
well i uh i read a lot
and
there is also these are saying that any
every revolution
has three stages the first stage
they
fight you
sorry the first stage is they ignore you
the second stage they fight you and the
third state
they take you for granted
so i think that
what i feel is that the recreational
market should take a step back
and figure out that we've done quite a
long way since you know i don't know
2010 or 2006 or 2015
to what we are today and it's been only
seven years um if i look at
again
the
after the 1930 with the drought
lost in the in the state
it took the liquor companies 15 years to
pick up with demands
15 years
and now obviously you can buy liquor
store anywhere but 15 years people had
to do
beers and and alcohol in their backyard
because there was not enough product in
the market so
again
we as
driving the market or
helping
forming the market we have to take a
step back and realize that we did quite
a long way
and
we have to be patient that's my personal
opinion
any any other thoughts
wise words from a wise man exactly
exactly well i think maybe we're at the
end of this conversation unless you'd
like to add anything else
no yes no it's been a pleasure likewise
it's been awesome you've been a great
audience thank you so much
and you know speaking about you know
import export strategies to drive
legalization there is a super super you
know event coming up next
with a rather well-known import from the
united states and from germany at this
point so i'll leave it up to you to take
that one let's hear it again for luke
and [ __ ] and marguerite
very informative very passionate
that's very great
i can't wait i can't wait for
international cannabis so i can go to
the local and buy some moroccan hash
while i'm in california
it's coming i mean we used to be able to
buy a rocking hash but it was way
against the law
and now it's legal and you can't you
have to come out here to get it which is
fine because
i love barcelona so i have no problems
oh no i have to go to barcelona and
smoke some hash whatever will i do