on the my left side you see sites from
pharmacy looks no no no in sick which is
a pharmacy which is concentrating very
much on cannabis medicine cannabis
patients a good source of information
for us every time it's about pharmacy
issues then we've got to have it Hin
from Cana medical claiming to be the
biggest importer in Germany for medical
flowers he can tell you more about that
later and we have challeng a cleanse
from Budokan which was for me just a few
years ago mr. cannabis Europe or
something like that if that few time ago
we had only be talk on in our pharmacies
nothing else so this is nice too for me
to have them here let me just give a
very little short introduction what we
are talking about here when it's about
imports because that is not the same as
talking about the German market you hear
more about that later when you have the
German market you have several different
products and a big proportion of this
market is not flowers it's gonna be
Newell pure THC product maybe about
about one third of the market there are
no will clear numbers and statistics
there and there is kind of monopoly a
German company doing that and then we
have big proportion of sativex also kind
of monopolies from Great Britain you
know that and here we are talking about
the rest of the market mainly flowers my
bet is about 40 percent maybe a little
bit more and a growing number but small
but growing extracts that's what we are
talking about here this is kind of quite
a free market with many producers many
importers
and well so that's fun that's the
playground for everybody here more or
less and that's that with that on the
front on the counter of the pharmacies
giving Adam the question what kind of
products do you have there and the
pharmacies and what about the proportion
you sell there in your pharmacy thank
you hi everyone so one I'm just
following up on your on your first at
about dronabinol and the synthetic THC
so you have to differentiate those from
the from the flows and the number you
just mentioned 60% of the market yes
it's a it's a narcotic drug that's has
been described since the nineties and
those numbers are accurate since it's a
simple drug and it's easy to understand
for physicians and this is why they
prefer to prescribe that also the public
insurance cover their costs if only
cover the cost of having a medical
cannabis therapy if there was also a
therapy with journal you know that has
been failed so this is why those number
that high in a final pharmacy we are
specialized in medical cannabis and in
the flows we sell about 55 to seven
strains from the Netherlands and around
25 strains are being imported from
Canada so we can confirm that number we
provided extracts very less than sixty
percent to our patients in the last year
but it's definitely it's definitely
interesting what the extracts are
holding us and horse also mentioned
already in the prescription of this
panel is the
problem of bottlenecks what about that
what is available what's not available
in your pharmacy and everywhere else in
Germany yeah so yeah the bottlenecks are
huge actually
so the pharmacy that's it's quite
challenging actually it's you provide
all sort of medical cannabis that are
available in Germany for the patient
because there is no source there's no
source where we could get the
information which trains are available
right now so as a pharmacy you have to
go and ask what you can what you can
deliver and the bottlenecks also mean
that if you are not well prepared if you
don't have a huge amount of cannabis on
stock that you're most probably not able
to provide the medication to the
patients so you mostly have to say no to
your patients and the patients in need
to find a pharmacy because as you know
the prescription for narcotic drugs it's
only available only you have only 7 days
just to redeem that prescription so the
patients are definitely patients have
definitely a huge problem with that so
what we are trying to solve is to
provide the information what exact
strains are available right now
on the German market in order for the
patient as for and for the doctor to
know where to go with the prescription
what to prescribe other other than that
just one more touch to it from the
pharmacy perspective it's very important
to provide a patient that medical meant
just to follow up on their medication so
you if you can provide the same
medication once it has been used up then
you're not following on exact
and this is quite huge
so once the strain is prescribed and in
two weeks it's out of stock then either
the doctor or the patients but mostly
the doctor has to look for another
another sort of strain that sometimes it
has a different effect mostly not
sometimes all right so this is slowing
down the development we are talking
about three tons of flowers last year
what my bet is fifty to sixty thousand
patients used last year could have been
much more if we had will good supply so
what the hell is going on we Germans are
not able to grow our own obviously at
least we need lots of time to get it on
the road and we are begging the world
give us your baths and we don't get it
especially we see those bottlenecks and
problems from Canada so my next question
- David what's going on you are also
problems importing from Canada right
what is the problem why does it not come
and is this problem going to solve in
the next future hello thanks gr4 for the
introduction just one more thing to add
I said we're the biggest independent
importer Germany maybe this is a little
detail but significant so what is
happening in Canada would we mainly see
two things is we are there's a lot of
facilities there's really really big
facilities that are going to produce
lots of quantities that is your mark and
reserved for Germany for the some fact
that they can generate a higher yield
when they sell to Europe other than in
Canada but let's not forget that Canada
has just opened up in October the
recreational market so and the second
impact is let's not forget most of these
Co of these companies that are supplying
medical cannabis are public companies so
what they did is they entered in lots of
bankable agreements but as provinces to
supply those provinces and
lots of them were over-promising at the
time they were executing this contrast
and they were fully aware of this but
they were literally pouring to have new
facilities up and running online being
fully certified being obtaining in a
cultivation or sales license just some
time that simply did not happen and we
were one of the one of the importers
that actually got hit by this with a
full effect because last year when I was
here was telling lots about a new
supplier that we have helped obtaining
the huge impe status so we did this we
have we we kept our word but what
happened was the next thing is we got
into some political conflict with the
suppliers so we were no longer able to
import from this producer given the
German narcotic regulations and
pharmaceutical regulation obtaining
getting a new supplier Aug P Reddy takes
us or roughly 150 to 180 days so there's
lots of things coming and there's where
we're actually just waiting for an
export permit for from Health Canada to
have new kind of medical varieties on
the market it's let's say three to four
weeks they are fully packaged you are
laying in stock in Canada but at the end
of the day at the end of the day there
is still lots of problems going on in
Canada with the ability to close this
gap for a constant supply but I'm very
hopefully four actually q3 q4 that those
gap will get much much better due to the
fact that a lot of these giga facilities
are coming online I've been in Canada
last week so Monday to to Wednesday and
I've seen a scene a few facilities and
I'm truly confident and hopeful that
those Giga facilities that can actually
use a 50 50 50 to 60 thousand kilograms
a year will have a very positive impact
and then there is a second side this is
also affecting challon's company is we
would love to import more from from the
Netherlands but the way the Netherlands
is selling you to the MC is really
making
a tough life for the simple fact that we
have a fixed amount that is going to
Germany on a monthly basis this amount
is divided by the amount of growing
importers equally mostly equally and
technically kinematical iself has about
200 to 300 kilos on pre-orders a month
that we cannot serve at the moment all
right that leads to the question which
other countries could provide our needs
here and also leads to challeng and that
may be in the first thought unusual idea
of the Netherlands government giving a
limit to the exports there's a funny
story going on maybe you can tell us if
that is right the limit you could
provide to Germany was much lower until
I think summer 2018 and then our Health
Ministry Minister in Japan was phone
calling Pennock Lee the Netherlands
government to give us more lift the
limit is that story right and now is the
story going on thank you
I don't know if the story is wrong that
that in the first place
I won't I wasn't there so I know that
there have been requests on the
political level that's where that's
where the whole thing is is it's
basically playing that's the playing
field in Europe it's on a political and
regulatory level most of the times
dealing with regulatory organizations
dealing with governments dealing with
controlled substances does mean in
Europe especially that it's debts have
fully locked in markets we have been
operating in this market since 2003 the
first 10 years not so much happened from
2008 we started exporting very little
amounts to Germany Italy few other
European countries and that's where it
all started and where the OMC the Dutch
regulatory office that is responsible
for keeping the monopoly on the trading
cannabis I
to emphasize that because the trade in
Europe will not be in the hands of
individual companies if you talk in
cannabis flour it will be in the hands
of the regulatory organizations that are
appointed by their government so in
Germany we have beef farm and all we
have the OMC doing that and at some
point I think it was about eight or nine
years ago the Dutch government was kind
of swamped with requests from all over
the world including Israel they were
asking metric tons of product and
basically we were the only company at
that time and we in that time we were
producing only maybe 200 kilos a year so
those requests could not be fulfilled
but the Dutch government had in in the
my in in in in the back of their mind
obviously they don't want to
disadvantage anybody who was coming to
ask for product is so they start
dividing product in portions say you can
get a little bit of this and you can get
a little bit of that and it was kind of
depending on our ability to expand and
also to the word the change we saw in
the world of the last four or five years
that actually also changed this whole
situation so we were able at some point
and it started back in 2013 I think we
were able to expand we expanded till up
until now three times we came from a
level of 200 kilos annual annually where
we where we were in 2012 we are now at
5,000 kilos annual and we will grow
quickly now this year doubling almost
those number go to 9 metric tons a year
and we have plans beyond that but again
we are we are trying to keep up a demand
and and that's another thing the demand
the demand is not just coming up right
now the demand has there been for
decades already basically however and as
I said in the beginning regulatory and
political hurdles and thresholds kept
patients away from a legal system so we
had this huge illicit system and we
still see it in the Netherlands with the
coffee shops where the product being
sold through the pharmacy is in sick
significant to what is being sold in
coffee shops but that's illegal product
but we also see do see a lot of patients
appear in that coffee shop still that's
a situation you don't have in Germany so
now the market is opening up in Germany
you see patients flooding into the
system
of course the reimbursement thing is
there that's another important thing and
an important feature that the the German
situation now supplies to patients and
that's very good
we had reimbursement in the Netherlands
it it has been taken away again due to
lack of effort of scientific evidence
it's always the same thing
although we know that there is a lot of
scientific evidence but still that's
another discussion that we that we also
need to have on a regulatory level but
that is basically how this situation
evolves and where we are right now to
make a long story short alright maybe
back to that issue you are able to
produce more quite soon will the Dutch
government and their own sea lift up the
limit also will more battle can hit the
German pharmacies next year okay it's a
number of questions in one question so
the question with regard to the do the
OSI and and and politicians lifting that
ban on on sales that is a question for
them to respond to so I'm not a
government I'm just the company
delivering to them but I can tell that
the situation is changing the mindset is
changing also in the Netherlands and the
the fear we that initially was there 10
years ago like Oh Holland will be you
know it will be all over the papers that
Holland is exporting truckloads of
cannabis into Germany that was a
political thing a little bit at that
time and we see that now fading because
cannabis is being taken seriously also
also in how long but we have to we have
to get over the regulatory issues we
also see in Germany if you look at the
German tender how much product is being
asked for
and kilos how much did you sell in the
last whatever you know it's debt is
already too little so the the import
situation is there to stay for a while
I'm pretty sure and it will be difficult
again as David already pointed to the
Canadian issues are real issues too they
are also not able to just export freely
and do whatever they like in that regard
well that's perfect for my next question
what are the countries could provide
there are lots of countries coming up
right now the regulation is that country
must have an cannabis agency it must
meet the European GMP production and it
well it in a case like egg white must
have a divided system of providing in
their country to the medical and the
recreational market that quite Auto
Detail we allowed to import from Canada
with recreational market but not from AG
why because they sell recreational in
the pharmacies but other countries will
meet those regulations quite soon ECL I
am quite sure is coming up on the market
this year then we have attempts from
Jamaica maybe Australia in a lot of
European countries like Denmark Poland
gooeys Macedonia they are all opening up
facilities now so in two years we might
have 10 countries providing and 20
companies or 30 or whatever dabit what
do you think do you think we have 5
countries providing in a year and if you
got plants are you talking to produce us
in those countries what is your bet how
it's going on yes thanks for asking so
there is a few things that we have done
in some of them are public my heart is
gas right now is Australia for the
simple reason that they have a very
similar pharmaceutical system as we used
to have in Germany and also in
in Europe so on top of it they follow
the same strict rules we have an MRA in
place that allows us to you're released
as in Australia this is very comfortable
details that are coming in here they
have great Sun they have stable
political environment so I truly believe
Australia will have a very good role in
supplying Germany and the next time I
don't see Macedonia being that hot for
the simple reason that they let's not
forget they have not even open up their
exports so we're simply talking about
something hypothetical that could happen
I know it's very overhyped right now but
let's stick to details I know that lots
of things are going on in in Denmark and
also in in southern Europe Denmark I'd
be honest I don't really happen to have
an opinion right now for the surgery I
know that lots of these big companies
went to that are also participating in
the German market some of the big names
are actually running setting over
facility mostly rates but it will fit
facilities but up today there is no
facility in Denmark at least I know of
that is fully up and running I would
love to see that we have the ability to
actually grow in Germany also I agree
with you
we made multiple requests with a German
beef farm even to increase volumes
because 10 tonnes that is currently on
the tender well way not be sufficient
kind of medical loan is wholly supply
agreements for over 25 thousand kilos by
now for the next 36 month just to give
you an idea where only one importer on
the German market and we're very very
very confident that we can solve this
very very easy thing if that actually
reaches the standard that is there's
requested all right let's stick a little
bit to this explosion of people
companies taking part in that market
maybe again to David we at the German
cannabis age Association count 21
importing companies right now
more to come probably people seeking for
making fast money what do you think how
is this going to develop will it become
more will it be more in a year will it
be less than a year who will get through
who will get problems what do you think
well I'm also aware of this because we
see that a lot of these companies or are
coming especially in the last six to
nine months and it seems to be a trend
for people to tend to believe that it's
very easy quick money but this is a
complete wrong approach in my opinion
this industry is not a place for
amateurs and due to the fact how
difficult German regulations are or ugp
regulations I know that there will be a
big earthquake in the industry coming in
the next few months from what we have
heard what is happening with the beef
farm they are also look into it quite
carefully but just to give some examples
the way product is imported to Germany
right now is far of the regulation it's
a very you know challenge used to call
this a Wild West and he might be true
some I said it there is a very good
chance that by the time the first player
in this industry and I will make sure
kinematical this player will do it
correctly and what she completely live
the the regulations that we do today
that are in complying with the with the
mg regulatory there will be a very hard
time for a lot of these there are lots
of these newcomer first of all they
don't understand the regulatory second
they are completely under financed and
third is laws of them or technically
only bill to be acquired by chemicals
and then on the other hand you are leaks
by example for the people being startup
you're on your own
yourself just a few years ago and being
very successful and also others becoming
millionaires and a short time so it will
stay a little bit by
and some of them will get through some
won't but all of these more exporting
countries many more producers coming
into the game lots of importers will
also lead to a huge variety in the
pharmacies of several products we
already have a big variety but then
imagine we might have 100 150 200
different kinds and sorts of medical
cannabis in the pharmacies so my
question to Adam what do you think what
outcome will that have would that be
good or not what do you think yeah just
to give a short answer variety in the
pharmacy is always welcome
so it's good to have many sort of
medical cannabis strains in the pharmacy
but there is another way to look at this
from the pharmacy pharmacist perspective
which is how those trains differentiate
themselves from another so how those
strains are different from another and
who's telling whom those informations
and those differences on the German
market so this should be the physician
that as there is aware of all the
differences from those strains and today
on today's market is not the case so
it's still the number number is getting
better that I must admit but there's
still the patients that no more than the
physicians and it shouldn't be shouldn't
be the case so also if you if you have
many strains on stock in the pharmacy
you have a very big logistic problems
you know as narcotic drugs it has it's
it furs under different regulatory
regulatory issues in the pharmacy then
and just simple ot C's and this is quite
a big problem for for pharmacies there
are not specialized in medical cannabis
yes keep in mind that it's not
like in the States or in Canada where
you get your recipe and as a patient go
to dispensary and enjoy to choose out of
200 varieties the doctor has to do it
and decide which one single kind I put
on the recipe and then it doesn't help
if there are lots of grains not
available and it's confusing the doctors
they are most of them are not able to
really say which is the right choice so
we'll see where that leads to I would
like to go on one last issue before we
open up for questions time is running
it's about extracts the first to extract
hit the market last year I think at the
moment it's quite a small proportion but
there's also a second extract coming up
now and probably this is the future my
question to every one of you asking for
short answer starting with challeng what
are your plans I was sticking to flowers
or planning extracts the the flower is
the basis or everything we all know that
so that's that's what we now call API
the active pharmaceutical ingredient or
the raw material you are using to make
extracts are we we have been in fully
into producing flower first we are
getting into next steps where we want to
actually extract in the product get into
standardized extracts from the raw
flower but that will still be an API is
it will still be an active
pharmaceutical ingredients Europe in the
end will require medicines true
medicines registered the medicines
clinically based on clinical research
you have a you have a proper outcome if
you want to use this right you're an
extract from that from this typical
variety currently everything in the
German pharmacy also and correct me if
I'm wrong is happening under the rules
and regulations of compounding pharmacy
so it's actually the product has to be
kind of made in the pharmacy itself
either by labeling by weighing it or by
even extracting it it's something we see
in Holland happening also the difficulty
of making extracts from a regulatory
perspective again is that you're dealing
with a controlled substance and it has
to turn into a medicine in Europe that
is what we see happening in Australia by
the way so in Australia where things are
moving very slowly but that's due to the
fact that they have to develop real
medicines and do their clinical work on
it it's a path we have chosen in Holland
now as well we have done our first
clinical studies on flour that is
helpful because it allows flour also to
be in the market and to stay there but
in the next step will be to come up with
more defined products in the world in
the field of extracts etc but you need
to be very aware that you cannot do that
in the barn behind your house you need
true pharmaceutical lab with under
certain certificates quality
certificates etc need to be in place in
order to be able to do that and that's a
long way all right - wants to continue
with that exact thing yeah so right now
the extracts are really liked from from
clinics this is what I can I can confirm
but it's only hours perspective so
clinics there are clinics in Germany
that only prescribe only prescribe the
extracts and the reason behind is
because the dosage for the foreign
doctors is very simpler to follow up on
so if you provide the strange also if it
comes on to the compounds you know this
the extract is very more efficient than
just vaporizing or smoking the buds
I think to answer the question short yes
it has a great future also in most part
in Germany the greatest since the
doctors and the physicians are the
people that allow you to use this that
sort of medication so yes definitely
it's all right David your thoughts and
plans about extracts yeah thanks for for
asking we are technically it's the same
answer I gave you last year we will have
excerpts from this market very very very
soon on one way or another there is
actually a very good opportunity that
you will be around by it by q4 we're
very interested in bringing extracts to
the market in accordance with an or F
regulations I'm just highlighting this
because I know that at least have the
products that are in the market today
today are not Anacortes we want to give
the the the prescriber the doctor the
full transparency on which strain is
used non-changing strains for this
extract to my very best knowledge there
is no extract today or the market that
is actually being that transparent to
make it actually possible that you can
follow up on therapy results by having
two or three different different strains
might be in indica and sativa in this
industry we're very very interested in
having imported speaking also in
research for for all the extracts and
developing a path to finished medicine
will be definitely the next step then
after that starts all right thank you
and I think that's about on the second
well we have 10 minutes 57 seconds left
for your questions tell us who is ask
tech tech tech tech alright let's hear
it again for York and everybody on the
panel
girl's great excuse me excuse me
speaking I'm Jonathan
you have Jonathan Goldman from sunlight
green import to God my question is
regarding what's your opinion about all
the companies that we see starting to
grow in Columbia and in Africa and the
low production prices are gonna come
from there and what's your opinion
regarding that and regarding the
regulation the GMP and how they're gonna
regulate to that and what you're gonna
do about those companies that bringing
cheaper products yeah
whom do you ask I can I can start yeah
thank you very much it's I totally
understand your question products
whatever whatever is produced wherever
if they have to come to Europe if there
is an export or import license for those
products and it day but that's a matter
of the regulator who will actually then
judge whether the product complies with
the regulations as we have them here or
in the country where these products
being imported so what is likely to
happen is that what you see more in in
agriculture if you have typical products
and and and they want to make a typical
extract from a product grown outdoor or
in a greenhouse or they want to purify
certain compounds from it I think that
will be relatively easy it needs to
happen under under the under the right
regulations obviously and I think that
in in a certain way there will be room
for those products to come to market but
again they will have to be compliant in
full with the regulations as we have
them here would like to add something to
this one I know that there is a lot of
competitive prices out on this industry
let's not forget about one thing
actually before I'm here is about
getting the cheapest market on prices on
supply I'd rather find a supplier that
can actually deliver an up-to-date in
Germany
telling is the biggest supplier on the
German market is constantly delivering
this industry is not about to me at
least not to care Americans values is
not about having the cheapest price on
our suppliers we like to treat everybody
fairly in the supply chain we would like
to have everybody a fair chain in this
industry and this is what makes us
probably so significant so interesting
as a partner also to global suppliers to
the next I'm Atmos fight I am a
pharmaceutical expert and consultant and
I have a question to toot a bit from my
perspectives there are increasing
numbers of local authorities in Germany
refusing import licenses because they
consider cannabis flower as a approvable
medicine because no compounding is done
in the pharmacies what is your
perspective about that there's a lot of
things ongoing in the moment and we also
have the possibility in Germany to ask
be firm to have a categorization of that
and my expectation will be that they
will ask them and what will happen if
they categorize cannabis flower as a
medicine which needs approval this can
happen yes we hear this question quite
often and I don't think it will happen
for one simple reason
cannabis flowers today are still an API
you don't have clinical studies we know
that it works you know that it works we
have we have achieved great results from
patients therapies however I have never
heard that German local authorities
potato Jeon are stopping to give out
licenses the proof that we have 21
importers in this industry today they're
trying themselves out in supplying
betokens material to the to the German
market is underlying my argument here on
top of it import licenses themselves
there might be a bit of confusion so
there is not this one
import license there's several different
licenses that you have to hold an order
to distribute into some
so medical cannabis is German market
this is a wholesale licensed cawt a
clearing clearing from restriction you
need to have an import license you need
to have release license you need to have
a license for a'ready material and so on
and so on so it's not this one singer
license I can tell you for sure that at
least kind of medical up-to-date never
had an issue for obtaining an import
permit we were the third company that
ever received the receipt a license to
import to try to distribute medical
cannabis but again I think the number of
increase in wholesalers that try
themselves out in this industry is
underlying an underlining that we don't
have an issue on the revelatory side we
have an issue on the supply side yeah I
have a question for Adam and and David
so we're we're API producer and we
currently we expect at the end of this
year to have a plant kind of medical
marijuana extracts under GMP with the
drug master file available and I was
wondering if you can buy a plant as an
API would you be able to buy the extract
as an API and then in the pharmacy by
compounding produce and oil out of it
before I answer your question let me ask
you a question who's given you the u GMP
is that a governmental GP or is a
private or dirt G or the governmental
GMP quit this actually makes it makes it
by far easier because the private origin
psi knows that there are a lot of
consultants that are that are offering
services are definitely good to have to
prepare themselves but are worthless
when it comes to import regulatory we
are able to import raw extract if you do
have an import if you do have a huge
impe certification date scheduled I
definitely would like to talk to you
after this panel - my opinion or - my
very best knowledge the only way to
bring product in from from any country
is in a way that you have raw extract
today so what would be the procedure
sorry what would be the procedure then
we just ask our governments yeah well we
should have this discussion a bit more
in deep after this panel and I'm very
very sure that my Qi team can actually
help you in preparing yourself if we get
together
thank you there was somebody who's there
with the questions and also to Adam do
you want to add something but I can just
give you a short answer it comes down to
the pharmacy since I'm not a pharmacist
I can just give you a short answer is
yes yeah we can definitely or you said
extract for you hello this is alfredo
from marijuana business daily I have a
question for David and one for Yelling's
David you say you're the largest
independent importer and if I understood
correctly you're waiting for your first
shipment from Canada in a couple of
weeks and you've also said that cannabis
coming from the Netherlands is being
distributed equally or more or less
equally and among all the importers so
can you explain how you are the leader
then yeah sure
and wait a second and yelling you are
the sole producer in the Netherlands as
of now there was a tender last year that
was cancelled I think it will restart
again this year that's what's being said
can you give us more clarity regarding
if you expect to continue being the sole
producer in the Netherlands or you await
more competition let me just hold on
this question why we are the biggest
independent in water in this industry we
have been in this industry in supplying
2,400 pharmacies up to date in the past
eighteen eighty two twenty month that
definitely gives us a competitive
advantage over all the new startups that
are coming in this industry the chance
that you are walking into a pharmacy and
you would like them to order medical
cannabis and ask them if they know Kara
medical is very very significant we are
providing the best service to pharmacist
we're the most transparent player in
this industry we are currently having
the biggest customer service team that
is providing excellent service to these
pharmacies every single day and we have
just been thank you
so and we have been just voted by
internal requests from consultants
agency that I've seen we have been voted
as the best and most reliable supplier
and they say independent supply in this
industry that tender again but it was it
was it was canceled last year its will
probably come up very soon now this year
as far as we know it will allow for
multiple producers in analysis as it did
from the beginning actually the fun
thing is that the standard process in
Holland is already relatively old but in
in the past 15 years nobody actually has
seen this whole tenor passing by and now
we see a bunch of interested
entrepreneurs who want to get into it
welcome of course I I do like
competition and we expect that the the
outcome of the tender will get into
resolved by January 1st 2021
so we will be in the market for a while
on our own still in the Netherlands and
yeah that's that's as far as it goes for
now I we are all basically waiting for
this tender to come out and actually
show what what the Dutch government the
direction is that government will take
on this one all right I think it's not
enough time for another question on my
watch it's 13 seconds left so thank you
all let's hear it again for your award
thank you
and very efficient
[Applause]