hi I'm Ashley Elsner I'm the chief
operating officer of artery pay we are a
digital payments company that unifies
compliance with transaction so that
banks are very easily able to run their
cannabis programs it's practically a
turnkey compliance program that is
actually run off of technology with with
multiple lines of tracking and and
transaction reporting so Allison cool
I'm Allison cough I'm the founder and
CEO of a company called Artemis we are a
software provider for the cannabis
industry and our core product is the
cultivation management platform helps
automate all the people plants processes
and compliance that you've got going on
specifically built for cultivators so
we're not doing POS we're not doing all
those other things but we built it in an
integrated way so you can tie into
whatever systems you choose to use and
and actually I guess each one to say
where you're based sorry San Jose and we
we actually have operations in
California Massachusetts Nevada and
Washington for your finance thing what
about you with your stuff my stuff yeah
growing stuff we're based in Brooklyn
New York but we also have offices around
the country as well as North America and
we're global so we're in Europe as well
in Australia well I guess if you have
operating clients can use like she said
the states where people are using her
software where are people using your
software almost every state that's legal
yeah and we're also we have a we came
from the non cannabis space first so we
had been selling to Trish more
traditional operations and so we've got
I think every state on the non cannabis
side and every legal state when the
cannabis ID
I'm Michael Pavlik I'm out of Detroit
Michigan and we focus on seem to sell
compliance software and with stash stock
as a company name we really focus on the
RFID aspect in the metric states making
a no touch solution where you don't have
to touch your plants while you're moving
them and having real-time visibility
into all of your cultivation and
processing concerns and
I was a grower for eight years before
this and have 15 years of technology
background so trying to bridge my
experience from cultivation
into technology and providing that to
licensed growers amazing
I'm Joel Sherlock vancouver-based I
think spend a 250 days on the road we
have a manufacturing business one of the
leading manufacturers of the extraction
machines the power a lot of these great
people making oil products so we make
co2 and ethanol ethanol equipment and
much like a lot of people on the stage
with me we are global when four
continents and offices on three great
and I'll give you some context on me my
name is Justin Hall my ticket to this
party is that I registered but calm 26
years ago and I know my way around a web
browser so I'm the CTO but calm we do
e-commerce for cannabis and hemp
pre-rolls and for CBD wellness products
we serve California with our cannabis
THC products and then we ship around the
world people like stuff like weed so I
think what's really interesting is that
if you look at each of you you would
have different visibility into the
cannabis industry you would have
visibility into payment streams you
would have you two would have visibility
into growth growth trends and you would
have visibility into how people are
extracting cannabis and where people
there's demand for your software there's
there's the growth of the industry so I
wonder if one of you wants to wade in
and and and take what I just said as a
prompt to promote the thing that you're
working on because that's what panels
are so bring it on sure so what artery
pay does is actually offers a completely
legal payment solution my background is
actually financial institution law and
operations and that's financial
institution operations so how the
sausage is in fact made the back-office
stuff and one of the things that we were
able to do actually because of my
background is to build the mrb FinCEN
compliance requirements and I'm going to
tell what those acronyms are because we
talked about this right before so Mr B
means marijuana business
and that is a class of a regulatory
classification by the financial crimes
enforcement part of the Treasury
Department with the federal government
everybody is required to follow these
regulations if they want to work with
the cannabis industry but it can be
pretty cumbersome for banks to actually
be able to engage with the space based
on this the added cost and so we built
it into the transaction system to make
sure that that cost was not the reason
why a bank that was interested in
working with the cannabis space could
not work with it it is not a legal issue
in fact it is very much a cost benefit
analysis that they go through and so we
bring that cost down to a very very low
reasonable rate for them and make
training much more efficient much easier
and provide a platform to them that
allows us to actually access the
financial systems openly and with these
partners rather than you know trying to
sneak in or saying that it's a
workaround you don't have workarounds in
finance that is absolutely it you're
basically between cannabis and finance
you have one highly regulated industry
and another highly regulated industry
and you're just piling regulations on
top of each other and the interplay of
those things end up causing a lot of
complications and that's really what's
causing the issues around lack of access
and so we are bringing in new banks we
are onboarding them all the time and we
are able to provide them with the
systems that make it possible for us to
provide you with completely legal
completely transparent payments on a
digital platform so also highly
integrated where we are agnostic as to
as to other softwares that you would be
using so it's a very easy to use your
customers can download the app and
actually go in and pay you in store very
very simple and it works
multichannel so online on the go in
store doesn't matter where you are you
can use this okay so that's so and you
would have visibility into the financial
growth and so can you pluck something
off the top of your head that's
interesting that you've seen about the
financial pattern
the cannabis industry using artery sure
so dispensaries are still primarily
using cash or in some places they are
unfortunately using things that they're
not actually allowed to use they
probably don't know that credit cards is
illegal for this industry period stop
halt like in in the United States now
there's a these are all united states
specific issues because the financial
regulations are United States Pacific so
from our perspective you're seeing a lot
of you're seeing a lot of people who
maybe don't have the background coming
into the space and selling products that
they're not allowed to sell into this
space so really having someone with an
operating background in finance is is
kind of critically important to making
sure that you don't have that sort of
problem and of course when that happens
we see a lot of bank shutdowns we see it
I think almost everybody who's in the
cannabis space has experienced something
where they've ended up through no fault
of their own having their bank accounts
revoked and so we see a lot of that okay
that sounds like accurate data yeah sure
I mean like Michael I was also on the
growing side before this and and worked
as an operator and so the thing that I
think I'm most passionate about in this
space is solving the issues around
technology scale and usability and how
do you get people to actually love using
technology which isn't as easy as it
sounds this is new technology it's got a
lot of issues we've got security issues
we've got scaling issues you've got
offline access issues where you have
remote areas for him specifically in
particular where you've got a lot of
field accessibility issues you've got a
large migrant population working in the
fields when you're talking about outdoor
you're talking about farm workers who
move from one facility to another often
so you've got traceability issues and
lack of transparency when you data
leaves one facility because you have
workers leaving
you've got illiteracy issues amongst
workers you've got language barriers
you've got these the slew of challenges
that make solving technology issues in
this space
really really interesting and really
hard and so the approach that we took as
a technology company was what can we
solve for growers that I knew to be a
major issue because it was something I
would have paid for as an operator but
also starting with the things that are
sticky enough that get you into a system
until you love it and then layer on the
things that you really really need sort
of thereafter right and so instead of
starting from maybe the the regulation
side where a lot of the other companies
started where they said hey here's a
huge business opportunity right we can
build regulated regulatory software we
can link in we can trace we can get
government's to the point where they can
track products so they can tax against
it which is fine great business
opportunity we said well you know what
you're doing there though is you're
creating regulatory software you're not
creating growers software and so we said
you know you got a build software that
people can use on a day to day basis so
start with tracking plants in a way that
is a production value to me so give me
crop scheduling give me estimates on
yield give me how many workers I'm gonna
need today tomorrow next week six months
from now give me the ability to do
purchase orders but not from a
regulatory standpoint give it to me from
a forecasting standpoint so I know if
I'm running low on something I'm not
gonna run out of it and I can actually
send that with a one click to my vendors
or on the sales side instead of saying I
want a POS just so that I can track it
again from a financial or regulatory
standpoint give it to me so that I can
do sales order so I can forecast and see
sell-through rates of my products and
start to adjust my production schedules
based off what's actually selling in the
market those types of insights that to
me make me or cost me a lot of money and
we started there and we started layering
on top of that so that we could be in
all the metric states right have a
seamless metric integration try and
replace the experience with bad things
that people don't like doing with good
things that they really love doing
because it's a tool for me in my
operation okay that sounds like great
tool so any data nuggets that you would
pluck from your tool roll out
observations across the data landscape
yeah I think the the tip I always give
all I'll give this because I've seen it
a lot a lot of times is that when you're
evaluating things think about the things
that you can replace pen and paper first
because there are things that you know
that you have to do because you're doing
them on a day-by-day basis so if you
look at you around your facility and
you're like oh yeah I'm recording pH on
my and I have got a log on my wall can
you put that in a software system or can
you look at those things first because
the more things you can replace that are
very manual one you're just gonna
immediately have an ROI and - it's gonna
be tracing that information so that if
Joe who's tracking pH leaves you
actually have a system and you know what
the pH was three weeks ago
and so those types of things I think the
number one mistake we make all the time
is when we're evaluating technology we
get sucked into what features are cool
what the newest thing is I want to have
AI and everything right like all these
things that are sexy and technology but
the reality is the thing you're gonna
use every day replaces something that
you're already doing yeah I think a lot
of you know what Allison is saying is
same for us but one of the things that
we really look at is scale so as a
company let's say we deal with someone
who can grow 10,000 plants but they want
to get familiar with it first so they're
gonna start with 500 and they're very
successful at 500 now they go up to a
two thousand at two thousand now they're
struggling why does that happen they
don't have a technology in place they
don't have something that's going to
make that economy of scale of compliance
and drive that cost down so right now a
lot of operators actually as you scale
your cost is going up around complaints
because you have more people you have to
train these people the first person
maybe does a really good job the second
person maybe does a decent job third
fourth fifth person your training it's
just more and more effort to make sure
that they're doing that same good job
how can we bring a technology in and say
that one person can do the whole scale
or two people can manage it instead of
five or ten so that's one of the things
we really focus on is a scalability of
cultivators to not have a
burden of manual effort around
compliance utilize the technology to
automatically capture and record things
accurately quickly you don't have to
hire these people and then using
technology you're not interacting with
your plants as much your contamination
risk is going down so you're getting up
a bigger yield at the end because you're
not having to waste as much stuff right
so those are things that we're looking
at in in terms of technology and again
replacing some of these manual process
so that that time just goes away and and
you people are using your software yeah
they're saving time and what what have
you gleaned from watching the way people
use their software one of the things
that that we struggle with is operators
that have been doing it manually and
they look at the technology instantly it
resonates circle oh my god you're gonna
save me all this effort but when we talk
to startups or facilities that are just
getting rolling they believe they're not
going to make any mistakes and they
believe that the process in place is
going to be followed perfectly by every
employee and inevitably it's not and we
see a lot of times people will call us
like oh my god I moved 500 plants and I
had lost three of them or whatever it
took me 20 hours to track those three
down while using the technology we can
find those plants in about five minutes
so you're talking about hours of effort
versus minutes on mistakes and people
don't want to talk about mistakes they
happen all the freaking time and you
have to account for it and how are you
gonna mitigate those risks because one
mistake can cost you tons of man-hours
if you don't have a good process in
place the one that the token hardware
guy
token hardware guy well I think a lot of
people look at data and technology kind
of you know as okay can speed things up
but may be able to save me some time but
a lot of people missed the fact that I
think one of the only guarantees we have
in this industry is change and it
changes quickly
so then investment in data you know that
investment in having those systems so
that as you're changing you have better
to go back on I mean we're focused kind
of after you guys have done your all the
great work and then product is dry right
we're focused on extracting it but you
know there's gonna be change in a lot of
the products that our clients would be
making a year from now or just being a
thought of or dreamt up right now so you
know flexibility in that infrastructure
but ultimately it's led by the data how
do you grow more THC P or you know any
cbgc PN whatever it is like we can only
extract up to a hundred percent of
what's grown no more let me figure that
part out yet but you know it's that side
of you know going back to that data as
the products change to figure out okay
well what did we do and that one grow
run where we saw a spike in this thing
that we're now looking for okay you just
ended your remarks there I will say that
I've chatted with this gentleman before
it was today so the information is fresh
the company he's worked for has made
many of these machines that extract
cannabis oil that can be used then to
make other products so those that the
machines that your companies made are
distributed around the world in two
different countries so man you've got to
have some interesting data on how
extractions going over here versus over
there or something well I think you yeah
I mean we definitely see there's lots to
be learned right and there's a ton of
mistakes that have been made but so many
people are not open to really
understanding I mean in the early days
of the Canadian you know the funded
capacity giant greenhouses and then they
were like oh we can't learn anything
from the guys from California it's like
someone making half a million vape
cartridges a month he's gonna have the
same bottlenecks that you were gonna
have when Canada
maybe one day gets to that point
hopefully you know we're starting to see
a lot of growth in big pharma companies
stepping in in the EU ecosystem it's all
you GMP which is a Pharma level so it's
significantly higher barrier to entry
once you get past like cultivation can
be done in G ACP like farming practices
but EU GMP or good manufacturing
practices is extremely you know lots of
documentation track everything
each piece of equipment that touches the
oil has to be you know you have to know
where the steel came from how do you
clean it like it's it's really really
comprehensive so you know but they don't
have cannabis experience at the level
that we do so you know I think
ultimately you can even learn something
from every single market and you can
learn from other people's mistakes yes
and mistakes that's good that's a segue
to the next question which is if you
make mistakes you poison people if you
guys make with your company so if you
guys make mistakes people lose their
crops or grow the wrong thing or may
poison people too if you screw up people
could be accused of money laundering and
go to jail if I screw up people get the
you know get the wrong get get a hybrid
instead of a sativa vape cart delivered
to their house so so let's talk here but
if you guys are looking at what failure
is how does somebody evaluating your
solution decide that you're trustworthy
when the stakes are high so you have to
look at people's backgrounds if you're
not focused on people's backgrounds and
you can't find out who's running a
company or they say they're in quotation
marks an ISO which stands for
independent sales organization you've
got to know that anybody who is just
sales probably doesn't really know
what's going on in the back and can't
really explain what you're supposed to
be doing and what you're not and you
know the best way to evaluate some
vendors and I hate to say this because
it sounds like I'm you know plugging
lawyers but get your corporate lawyers
involved if anybody is going to be able
to evaluate whether this is going to
actually pass muster they're going to be
able to do so and you know it's a little
bit tricky because from the financial
services space actually the best
financial institution lawyers they're
all in New York City I mean it just
happens that that is like our core the
core location so if you have people who
are coming from that kind of a
background that really have have been
focused on the financial space in New
York City like that's really good
credentials that's really outstanding
for you know somebody who
is coming in and is you know a
relationship manager may or may not know
what they're talking about and so when
it comes down to it you really want to
dig into what they're doing and if after
you've signed a non-disclosure agreement
with people they're still not willing to
tell you who the financial institutions
are that are backing them and that are
working with them that's a huge red flag
another huge red flag in this space
specific to specific to cannabis
regulation financial regulation on that
is when someone is calling an EMR be a
CR B because they're trying to rebrand a
regulatory category and that is not
kosher that is not kosher at all you
have to wonder whether these people are
actually focused on what's best for you
or if they're just you know going ahead
and selling you something that either
you don't need or isn't sustainable
and that's another focus like you really
have to dig into this because you are
heavily regulated and on the financial
side unfortunately mistakes are not
forgiven yeah I mean you're not only
innovating tech you're innovating
finance and if we innovate finance as
much they kind of you might go to jail
oh yeah yeah if you do it wrong you go
to prison and so does everybody in the
supply chain that's involved with you
and so be your customers because
actually the racketeering statutes in
the that our federal federal government
and racketeering statutes get everybody
on quote conspiracy to money launderer
so if you don't know how they work in
the back how they're actually getting
something done you got to get somebody
who can dig in on that and listen your
lawyers can help this is what they do
they do the research that's their job is
to research this stuff for you and give
you counsel and you know if they're
working with you in cannabis they're
gonna have no problem with finance I
mean it's it's not hard it's not hard
lawyers love cannabis they do they love
it they use it they love you you make a
lot of good work for them and it's fine
and good money for them
I think I totally agree I mean like you
will feel when you're vetting companies
like just make sure you've got the
company well but you feel it right and
so like if you're looking at a software
company go to their website look at
their team right if they don't have
software engineers on the team they're
not gonna if it's an outsourced software
engineering team you're gonna have a
hack or a break or a down edge in four
minutes like it just is gonna happen
because if you're not building the team
internally like you have no control over
that product so make sure that the if
it's a software company make sure they
have software engineers on the team if
you want to dig even further go to
LinkedIn right and see the background of
those people if they have three
engineers and they're all recent
bootcamp grads like you're gonna have
what happened with shadow like it's just
gonna happen right like this is this is
what happens if you don't have control
over your internal team and like that's
nothing against those guys I feel bad
that that was their first job but it
happens right like if you're a young
engineer it's those things are gonna
happen so make sure that it's an
experienced team make sure that they
have a CTO that actually has experience
building companies and you can vet that
kind of thing make sure you can see who
backs them financially right do they
have money in the bank are they gonna be
around longer than you are that's very
important uh-huh you want to make sure
that they're going to be around so even
if it's venture back to make sure that
they have the right sort of structure
behind it and that they disclose call
their customers get case studies like
all customers do it when you put an
inbound phone call in I did I tested
this the other day with some of our
competitors and I had fun with it but
like put an inbound request and see how
long it takes for them to respond to you
if it takes two and a half weeks and you
still haven't heard anything yeah like
those are the types of things that make
a good company in any industry whether
it's cannabis or not and so do the like
vet the company a little bit and and
make sure that they're a good partner
for you because at the end of the day in
cannabis specifically it's it's a mulch
ice right the market is changing
drastically regulation changes the
financial markets are changing we have
elections coming up who knows what'll
happen right all of this stuff is really
hard for us in addition to the fact that
you're trying to build a business which
is also really hard and so make sure
that you find a good partner that you
gel with make sure they can speak the
same language you can you know your
business is better than
vendor will ever know it but if they
catch on if they're interested if their
founders is car coming out to your site
to see what's going on because they're
just curious like that's probably going
to be a better partner for you than
somebody who you can't get service
access to at any point I agree with
everything that they're saying but you
know my company actually is a little bit
newer to the industry but one of the
things that we do you know we're always
on site you can contact us directly
we're technology background so the
entire team is all software all the time
and we partner with large scale
technology providers that do some pretty
massive websites and technology
deployments but yeah one of the things
for us is like a lot of our competitors
are going to install software and
hardware in your facility that you're
gonna have to manage and make sure it
has proper security and you know that no
one's able to get into that box versus
you know everything is cloud for us so
we're managing on top of azure we have
all of the built in securities from a
cloud provider we don't have to worry
about you know someone hacking your
local computer that you put password as
the password and stuff like that so you
know how much are we taking off of your
plate from a risk standpoint what
technologies are we using what is our
background those are all great questions
surprisingly people ask us for referrals
all the time and I thought that was
strange at first but I love when people
ask me that because I can give them our
clients that have moved off of other
technologies I can say you know who are
you evaluating right now I might have
someone that actually was a customer and
switched and they can talk to you about
the experience and we'll just connect
you directly like it's not like I'm
speaking on their behalf
column talk to them directly get a few
of them and see what they have to say we
you know that's really the best way I
think a lot of people get sucked into
contracts before they're actually ready
for them that's the other thing I would
say is be flexible don't get into bed
with anyone too soon we have free offers
so you
can use all of our technology for free
for an entire growth cycle so you can
evaluate it locally see if it actually
makes sense for you before you pay
anything so you know we touched on a lot
of the big things people testimonials
you know I think data for sure like
there are a lot of big claims and maybe
some unproven claims in the canvas
market so just get people to back it up
you know I mean oh that's that's a big
claim show me you know there there's a
lot of data available - I mean there's
multi-state operators who have multiple
locations you know if you know if
somebody buys in our world right it the
best thing that someone could do for us
is you know once hey we're on another
platform they come over to a Vitalis
extraction machine and then every
expansion going forward that person's
putting in more equipment right I mean
that's an investment in this partnership
you know but but look at who are they
working with and are those people
continuing to work with them you know
that's that's usually a very strong
endorsement but you know get those
testimonials talk to their customers
figure out where they good has their
service team because things change
problems come up things break and you
want somebody who's gonna be there to to
support you speaking to because you can
just go look at it like that's a nice
thing like go look at the hardware yeah
touch it see it so speaking of someone
there to support you let's find a
question in the audience somebody has a
question someone's got to have one
question could you introduce yourself
and say what you're working on
[Music]
gonna say the same way and I have to say
so far it's been a little bit of a
circle to attract tech candidates here
in the Bay Area it's a problem in
general but then you add on cannabis and
I think that scares some of the tech
candidates away so I'd love to hear how
you've built out that tech team the
question is how do you build out a tech
team when some of the tech candidates
are scared off by cannabis it's like a
caper flick right you gotta go from
scene to scene I would talk about
mission Lariat like one of the things
that we do above all at our company is
we created a set of core values that are
important to us and how we operate as a
business and we leverage that every
single time we're hiring right so we we
push out our core values everywhere and
we talk about them as often as we can
and we interview against them and we
just sort of embraced this you know we
have a mission as a company we care
deeply about it and yes of course we
want to make money for our shareholders
and everything like that that comes with
running a business but like at the heart
of it the why we do it is just as
important and how we operate often Falls
in cannon to the why we do it
and like you're gonna find people I mean
there's a roomful of people here who are
interested in the cannabis industry
right one of the Bay Area's so
presumably some of these people may be
looking for jobs if you're looking for a
job it seems you know she's looking for
attention yeah well if you're an
engineer in the room you're looking for
a job right but like people in South Bay
yeah yeah it's like people are gonna be
passionate about packaging people to
party more at the right at the right
party
but but talk about the the why you're
doing it because the more often that you
talk about the why and not just like hey
we're hiring and it's hard to compete on
salary in the Bay Area because
everybody's paying you know $120,000 for
a new entry engineer like instead of
talking about things that are hard for
engineers to be attracted to if you're
only selling what are you doing and why
are you doing it and how do we operate
as a company and you're selling yourself
frankly as like the founder right and
then I'm gonna be as a candidate really
attracted to wow that's really
interesting
maybe it wasn't super passionate about
packaging but I love cannabis and so we
can find a way to work together or I'm
really passionate about both of those
things and you'll get those people so
are you a solo entrepreneur
yeah so that's one of the things that
critic yeah that's one of the things
that is actually difficult solo
entrepreneurs it's not actually about
cannabis its solo entrepreneurs you have
a difficult time attracting teams so if
you can find a co-founder who is you
know I don't know if you're the
technical person or you're looking for a
technical person to be the co-founder I
think that you will have an easier time
pulling in engineers because a lot of
times which you have a technical founder
they actually have teams that they've
worked with before that just love
working with them and so that's what I
did I actually went out and found my
extremely well seasoned heart and like
old-school IBM er who designed you know
anti-money laundering software for the
FBI and the Department of Defense and
designed transaction systems for for you
know Wells Fargo and Bank of America and
he was you know hanging out at fintechs
of FinTech meetups and things like that
and so in the Bay Area meetups can be a
powerful tool for you actually to find
people who have those those core
interests and you know almost everybody
in the bay has fantastic chops in terms
of like engineering and computer science
so going to those places and having a
co-founder with you so that they see
that it's not just you so it doesn't
feel like they're taking as much of a
you may have to go to that party to meet
the co-founder though yeah yeah that's
exactly what I did just advocate exactly
what I did and you know it's it's again
like you say the passion has to be there
the the underlying story for why you're
doing this has to be there it has to be
really important and you need to be
talking about grander vision but it's
one of those things that's that is much
easier for people to get around when
they start seeing multiple people that
are on your team so they're like oh oh
this is real I need to let you guys off
the loser
over and out of time I'm so sorry one
two three Tekin cannabis