here to talk tech and cannabis
yeah
yeah the cto
of bud.com
justin
hall
thank you
okay
so um we have a great responsibility
we're here to rock your mind for about a
half an hour and take you into 420. so
the we have an additional panelist too
and i'll ask him to kick us off because
it's his first time being on a panel
my name is lee hilpert
my name is lee hilbert i'm with organixx
organics is a manufacturer of oil and
distillates located in hollister
california
our facility is fully automated and we
utilize that automation and new
technologies to try to increase the
quality of the products that we make for
our customers
we're certain that automation and new
technology will be critical to this
industry as it starts to scale up and
meet the future demands of this industry
what background possibly qualified you
to build what you're building
i started out my career in the food
processing industry doing centrifuging
and liquid solid separation
distillations
and pres preservatives
i moved over into the oil field when the
oil field needed some liquid solid
separation and worked over there for
many years in distillation solid
separations
and then when i looked into the cannabis
industry i saw that there was a real
need for this kind of technology and we
thought that there was a great
opportunity to come help if you google
if you google this guy about the only
thing that comes up is 40 patents
hey guys my name is vince ning um i'm
the founder of nabas distribution
um you know we pride ourselves on on
being a tech driven distributor and
trying to make as much as uh you know as
much as possible as a self-service
distributor so you know at the end of
the day we our core competency is we
focus on shipping cannabis products for
brands and helping them get them into
the retail market
what what background led you to that uh
so you know most my professional career
has been in the tech industry and you
know as a technologist we're always
looking for ways to um you know help
bring new software new platforms new
ways to automate industries where uh
there's a high demand for it and so you
know that's how i got into the industry
and frankly i just have a personal
passion for the product so it was pretty
natural for me to put those two together
and get into it
hey my name is hua i have a company
called meadow
ceo and hey
got some fans
uh ceo and head janitor so uh we do a
lot of things there primarily building
software for retailers and delivery
operators i work with over a hundred in
the state
my wife is also an edible maker
so we're pretty entrenched in the
industry and understand what's going on
there
what brought you what were you doing
before meadow that prepared you to build
that smoking weed
yeah that's that's one way to get to the
weed business so um you know we were
sort of rapping beforehand about how
tech impacts us but i think uh hua put
his finger on the way that tech will
interfere with everybody's life in the
marijuana business which is metric and
so just to sort of get that rolling and
get that kicked off how many of you have
not don't know what i mean when i say
metric
you raise your hands okay for those two
dudes in the sweater vests in the back
um
one of you guys want to break it out
probably not mr hardware what about you
guys
yeah i'm more happy to talk about it so
metric or uh california track and trace
is what we're going to be using to track
every gram of cannabis that's harvested
to you know the consumer and it passes
along a lot of different parts of supply
chain from the cultivator to the
manufacturer to the distributor the
athletes get lab tested ultimately to
the retailer
and you know through that tracking is an
rfid tag that's basically low jacked to
the plant
and from that you have package ids are
created from that
from that harvest that can be turned
into manufacturing products or you know
finished goods and when it's brought
into the retailer side you also then you
know bring that those package ids as
well it's it's pretty
intense
but yeah that's what we're dealing with
and uh you guys
because your position in the industry
you have already done some metric
work a little bit you're practically
integrated
yeah i mean that's one of those things
that i think everyone is uh i guess
looking forward to doing is integrating
with metric and
currently
i would say the resources out there
aren't um aren't you know plenty enough
to to have everyone be on the same page
as to how to use this one api
um or and you know a lot of people
frankly right now are using uh are just
emailing in their manifest for track and
trace
i think that's the most common way that
people are abiding by these laws
and in addition
i think you know the the metric
compliance is really enforced once you
get your annual license and currently
most people are still operating under
their temporary provisional licenses and
so um that's something that everyone is
it's top of mind right now i think it's
really important to discuss um just
because uh you know in order to continue
operating compliantly uh moving forward
um once everyone gets their annual
licenses we all need to be on the same
page about how to use this technology to
you know comply with state laws
so so
what we aim to do is to talk very
briefly and then open it up for
questions by the way so if you got a
metric hot pants you get get near nagaio
to get your question in
so i think uh one thing that i was
pitching to you guys is that
for hardware you have to tune you build
hardware to separate solid and fluid for
avocados and shale oil or whatever but
when you when you you had to recalibrate
it for cannabis can you tell us
something about what you had to do there
yeah so just taking our uh our
experience in the other industries the
the base basic science of it is is sound
and goes across the industries but the
specifics about how to handle that the
the individual cannabis plants how to
automate that how to move it from one
place to the other how to integrate with
matrix how to develop software within
our within our platform that will
actually track
all the lot numbers and everything
seamlessly because our our goal is to
have you know a fully automated plant
that really a guy considered a control
panel and can operate and can produce
these products and so there's a lot of
things to think about especially on the
compliance side and things like that and
make sure that the software and hardware
can work together to ultimately meet
that goal i guess i was trying i was
also fishing for like an image of you
going from like
oil dripping off your hands to like
handling soft buds or like the
transformation in your sort of the
materials you were handling you have
stories about that or something no not
really this uh you know working in the
oil field it uh it's a it's a
challenging career for sure moving
around from platform to platform and
looking at those things and
there was just an opportunity we were we
were up in canada doing some blp testing
it was snowing it was colder than you
can believe
and uh things were freezing up and
anyway we were riding along and and it
was just at that moment that we decided
man this is not really what we want to
be doing and we had been looking into
the cannabis industry and and really
wanted to make that that change and so
so we moved out and did it yeah and so
for the guys on the software end of
things we were talking a bit about
whether you know so i'm the chief
technology officer of bud.com i
qualified for this business by smoking
weed and also loving the internet and
registering bud.com 25 years ago i
started coming to this conference four
years ago and networking until i met
somebody who could help me make a real
thing out of the thing and now we
deliver pot so if you like marijuana
we'll bring it to you homes or hotels
bud.com fired up california
but basically um you know we when we
went to build our platform we could not
use commercial software packages that
regular internet startups could use can
use payment methods we couldn't use
e-commerce shops we couldn't use crm
packages we couldn't use billing
packages i mean advertising packages it
was like it was like the the
startup special ops experimental extreme
course i couldn't even believe it
because i've been in software for 20
years but it's like how about if you
just take all the building blocks you
have that you use to make a company and
you remove them all so you have to start
from scratch and do all your own stuff
it really makes an honest sort of uh you
know producer out of you wow uh all that
is to say that i thought maybe in a few
years cannabis will be legal you know
and if president ivanka trump will
legalize it and we'll all be allowed to
use whatever software we want and the
people making specialized cannabis
software will kind of disappear because
we'll all just be inhaled into some
giant erp but you guys were disagreeing
yeah i would say um you know it's it's a
common question that we get asked
actually is you know why can't you just
take an off-the-shelf erp system and
start using it for yourself and i think
one of the main
enterprise resource planning so right
right sorry a lot of three-letter
acronyms in the tech world but um you
know essentially
i think the main reason is because
there's a lot of compliance uh and
regulatory reasons um for instance for
us like we have to bake into
our system automating how to generate
manifests you know testing and all that
sort of stuff tracking um and you know
again abiding by metric compliance
standards
and so those are all things that your
typical off-the-shelf um you know erp
system doesn't come with um and so we
had to build a lot of that in-house and
i think a lot of the other
operators in the industry like who over
here with meadow is is doing himself too
um and i'm sure you know it sounds like
you ran to the same issue and i think
the next step for all the kind of
software operators in this industry is
really to
you know put all the pieces together um
in a way that
we're currently at least we have
software for the industry now um the
next step is really to make those
identifiers for the packages for all the
products unified um to have like a
universal system from seed to sale you
know all the tracking because otherwise
when you pass products from one licensed
entity to another you get a lot of
mismatch of data and the data integrity
becomes poor
so i think that's the next step for us i
think there's a lot of people home
growing their own software and it's
really great for the industry
but that's just v1 i think v2 is really
getting everyone to be on the same page
about
how we interact with each other's
systems
i i think you said everything was great
there dude
yeah um yeah only thing i would add to
that is you know we talked about a lot
of change that's happened in the last
year and last couple decades
you know i don't think traditional
companies can move as quickly to adjust
with what's going on and they don't
really care
you know do they care about the excise
tax probably not i care a lot about the
excise tax you know as much as everyone
here do they care about integrating lab
tests to understand the potency levels
for the consumer because that makes them
a more educated buyer not not yet
it's too still too small for them and
i think if you think about you know will
we be
commoditized into this other realm in 10
years i don't think so i think
there are going to be some best-in-class
companies that come out of this uh that
will be as big as some of the other
operators there because just like
alcohol or tobacco or pharmaceuticals or
food or you know organic food and
subsectors cannabis will have its own
you know thing uh because of the laws
and the nuances of it not just at a
local and a state level we're going to
do state to state you know eventually
we're going to be doing global
if you look at just
shipping across different countries and
the tariffs and all that stuff that has
to be built in i mean do you know what
the regs are going to be in
in colombia when we're going to be
shipping and exporting and importing
from from them
it's going to still have to get worked
out and i think that because of that the
people that are on the ground here that
are with us here today i mean we're all
going to be able to collaborate and work
together and move this thing
way farther than anybody coming in from
the outside that's just trying to gobble
it up
so i was i asked the moderator of the
last panel lauren frazier hey uh what
could tech do for the cannabis industry
and she said ah
there's a problem that you guys could
solve
digitization
people are still using paper
i was like oh my god paper
yeah so anyway well we've got a question
we're ready for questions what's that
yeah we have to use paper
yeah we have to use paper in some places
but i think some people are using paper
when they could be using like
spreadsheets or computers or email or
you know for sure chat or whatever
yeah it's part of the
part of the challenge while everyone's
on a temporary license and then we're
going to move into provisionals and then
provisionals will have the the metric
mandate
you know i think
for
there is going to be a crossing to the
digital side but it's still going to be
a little bit painful too
but hopefully we can lose less trees
yeah we have painkillers to go with it
you ready for questions yeah we're ready
for questions first of all i'd like to
say that you have to use papers or how
else would you roll a joint
with your digits digitally
all right enter introduce yourself and
say what your situation is
my name is mitchell and hold the mic
close to your face my name is mitchell
colbert
my name is mitchell colbert i'm a
lobbyist currently working on the
cannabis e-waste issue
my question is while it is tech related
is not related to that you're talking
about the issues of having to build
everything yourself
as i'm sure everyone in this room knows
mj freeway has been hacked many times mj
freeway is one of the big pos systems
out there do you think there's security
risks present in forcing every business
to reinvent the wheel potentially
leaving back doors and security flaws in
there rather than using tested and true
technology used in other industries
well i mean i'd like to think that the
technology we use is at least as good as
the technology used by the political
parties of our country and the banks and
the you know major consumer brands what
do you think i hope you're not banging
with wells fargo
yeah i mean i think if you look at
modern technology companies today
they're not building you know
co-location servers uh by themselves and
putting resources there they're using
aws or heroku that already have
enterprise grade solutions and
encryption
i think if you don't implement those
solutions then you're also at a risk of
exposing yourself to you know hacks uh
so best in class should be you know
utilizing third party in a way that has
those protections in place
yeah sure um i mean i think as far as
security goes um i think this is just
goes for software in general is that
it's something that
improves over time as you maintain it
more um i can't imagine you know
microsoft started with their old first
computer with the best security
primitives
out there and it's something that as
they reach more and more issues it's
they did a lot of patches and it is
where it is today um but you know it's
something that
for us i think with the v1 level
software that we have currently in the
industry
i'm sure there are a lot of security
issues going on that people can lose
their data over
but i think over time it's something
that you know we'll have more bandwidth
frankly to pay attention to and in
addition
you know more more capital more
resources to apply um so i think i think
it'll fix itself over time you know when
i first attended this conference i was
alone i was a lonely nerd wanderer i was
sort of walking around being like i got
this web domain i like computers you
like weed let's smoke
but then it's like
i just can't realize oh i have an
offering i could i could try and make
the weed world more nerdy because when i
think about security holes in the weed
business it's going into a potential
dispensary partner and seeing the like
the gmail address for the entire
dispensary operation and the password
written on a post-it that's posted up
above the computer i mean that's like
you talk about like you need enterprise
great security and your aws you know
cloud server but you also need the
people on your premises to sort of have
some basic digital literacy maybe even
splurge on like a password manager you
know i mean i think there's a lot of
ways in which the weed industry could
use some consumer grade uh tech tools to
really you know i it's tough you gotta
say that the the culture of security
yeah is pertains to the technical world
too and not just you know when talking
about women and human factors right i
mean if somebody leaves your enterprise
and you've got one password across your
16 accounts like you lost your instagram
somebody just lose 200 million dollars
because the guy who ran off with the
money died yeah and he has the only
password yes that's right yeah there's
great adventure out there but there's
digital literacy that i think will
could could you know there's a lot of
times when i go into business i'm trying
to help them understand how bud.com
could deliver for them and what i really
want to do is give them like a two-hour
it consultation to be like you should
try google docs it'll be amazing what
collaborative spreadsheets could do for
your work
did you have a question yeah stand up
and introduce yourself uh i'm jordan uh
we're
starting out in the utah market um so
that's also
yeah
partially uh where where my question
lies is starting out from
really the ground up
what's the best way to stay cost
effective in our tracking um i mean as
far as compliance goes i mean utah is
not going to be any different than
arkansas and all those other places that
have really heavily regulated
uh religious markets and whatnot
so
thinking rfid tracking to blockchain is
that where we're ending up
gonna are we getting to that point where
thank you thank you it took uh 18
minutes before somebody said blockchain
um i was thinking we were going to be
more supply chain than blockchain but i
think you know blockchain is this idea
you create a ledger that everybody can
see and it including the feds
yes yes because the feds is us man we
are the government isn't that isn't that
the dream so anyway you inscribe the
characteristics of the cannabis in this
ledger that everybody can see and so
it's sort of track and traceable in
perpetuity man you got a lot of work to
do in utah before you try and make
blockchain on the cannabis i mean wow
what do you guys what do you anybody got
something to say on this thing yeah i
mean i think with all startups
it's not necessarily the tools too it's
just how you guys communicate and work
together to keep costs low
um i know when we were bootstrapping
meadow we lived in our apartments we
went to each other's apartments for
office
we cooked just rice and meat and just
that was our dinner together like just
bring costs down
um you know when it topped software you
know we had one user that we all shared
so we didn't have to pay extra user
receipts you know stuff like that where
you just still do that yeah
you know i think there's ways around
where you can cut costs yes but still
invest in in best practices to make
things more efficient
oh for me in those areas i think when
you have
more
things that
more resources oftentimes you're not as
creative so having less resources you
tend to be a little bit more
conscious with every dollar that you
have and then every minute that you have
um i think ultimately though you need to
build something that people want right
you need to go and this is sort of our
yc mantra you go and talk to the
customer what's yc uh y combinator yeah
but
oh sorry y combinator guys you you
landed from planet software this is
planet cannabis right so they don't know
what this is yeah yeah y combinator is
uh
an incubator fund accelerator community
of entrepreneurs who
have started a lot of some of the
biggest companies that you know in tech
dropbox airbnb
weebly coinbase i mean the list goes on
and on
but what's really great about it is
they have a set of
mantras
that you know you should follow and one
of them is make something that people
want and it's so crucial i think a lot
of times everyone's still stuck in their
apartment or at a coffee shop saying i'm
doing work i'm doing the thing but who
they should really be or what they
should really be spending time is going
to the dispensary if that's your your
partner go and talk to them work on
closing out stuff at the end of the day
if you're working with a brand or a
manufacturer and you're doing marketing
go and
to their shop and talk to them um
there's not enough of that you can you
know there's people that have fancy
equipment on the photography side you
guys are amazing but if you don't have a
zoom lens just take your phone and go
all the way up front to the person right
like there's stuff like that where
that type of mantra is important while
you're building your company but it's
exciting utah is great so go for it let
me ask let me ask lee do you have any
advice for people who are trying to who
have a hardware idea and how they can
experiment and innovate and well what i
would say is that if you are starting up
a business that just like they said you
should identify the product that you
ultimately want to produce as a product
obviously that somebody wants to buy and
then you all talk
exactly and then you also ought to do
your homework to make sure that the
equipment that you're that you are
purchasing is the equipment that will
produce that end result for you and that
you don't have to go and rebuy equipment
and start all over when you haven't
gotten it right
see there you go that's it
okay
all right we got one right here here we
go
hey there my name is eric i'm built yeah
right up on there my name is eric i'm
building a
my name is eric
am building a data company for genetics
in cannabis and i'm curious on what the
industry's perception is for data
privacy
so you're basically building like a data
warehouse for all the different types of
23andme but for cannabis
where i upload my dna and it tells me
what i should vape
sort of i could clarify more to you
later if you want
yeah i think the you know data is still
uh an early topic on on how it's you
know being talked about um but i think
for for your business you should talk
with labs you know they're seeing a lot
of the data they're doing all the
testing uh see if you can do a
partnership there that makes a lot of
sense to me i mean steep hill has a big
one a big repository of dna that they've
sequenced apparently um
philos is another group
so you know there are resources there
where instead of like tap you can just
tap into it if they're they're open to
it
i mean are you talking about data
privacy like this is my private strain
well that sounds like the intellectual
property that's an intellectual property
thing and that's definitely a thing
that's going to be in the future right
somebody's going to try to patent train
wreck or claim they were the first
person to invent bubba kush
or acapulco gold it'll be nagayo wreck
and then you can guys that's right i'm
going to slip and fall in the grow room
thank you thank you the three people
thank you call saul did you have a
question
my name is peter here to learn uh what
do you think what do you think the
biggest threats are to your software
businesses is it competitors coming in
from other industries that you know
might have a pre-established erp or you
know crm or pos system uh what do you
see as some of the biggest threats to
your to your software businesses let's
let's make it inclusive okay can we say
hardware okay hardware yep okay um i
would say i think you hit a couple of
those one is you know if someone else
were to go build the same thing with
more money and more resources you know
that's obviously a threat
the other i think that is probably more
top of mind more top of mind is probably
the changing rules and regulations
that happen pretty frequently
it it causes us to i mean the reason why
we in-house our software is because for
just that reason it'd be pretty tough to
rely on like a third party
you know software provider software
contracting firm
to build out what we need just because
our operations have to morph every
single time these new regs come out and
you know the partners that we work with
also are startups and they change the
way that they operate and so we have to
be able to be nimble and adapt and um
you know having our own software really
helps with that um and yeah i mean i
think as far as like other players
coming in and building the same thing
i don't think they'd be able to do it
unless they ran their own infrastructure
um and and understood really like for us
uh distribution um and so yeah those are
the kinds of things that we see as
threats but we're wary of
yeah just a couple points on that uh
you know
another mantra out there is don't worry
about competitors
right
keep your nose to the grindstone and
just run your own race
oftentimes i find that some operators
keep looking left and right and they're
doing something and then they pivot to
go build something that's just like
shittier than what they did anyway
instead of just focusing on what they
they should have done
so oftentimes like self-sabotage is a
threat because of the lack of focus or
just looking at other things that are
going on you know with the with cannabis
regulations is definitely
a threat it could be actually an
opportunity
right if you look at products out there
you're creating a moat and regulations
is a moat
this regulatory mode that you have to
navigate through
and being participatory within that
regulatory process is a unique
opportunity that we have right now the
cement is still wet
right we have the laws it's still wet
but we still have ability to uh advocate
on the legislative side and you know
give our feedback to the regulators to
create better better laws
you know we did a our first push to
metric yesterday with one of our
licensed operators
and you know we were able to help that
by you know i'm on the board the ccia
i'm the board of the cda by talking
about you know getting a hand with them
and commenting and sharing the feedback
that they don't get to see in order to
help move this process along
so i think it's incredibly important to
look at these threats not necessarily
threat as an opportunity to kind of you
know reframe your thinking and how you
move forward to be
uh the best version of yourself and your
company as you kind of evolve
and and i'll tell you briefly if if all
of hua's dreams come true in the
regulations people listen and they
legalize and it all happened and
weeds on sale in walgreens by next week
that would be tough for our business
i mean that'd be a very accelerated
timeline
next week yeah yeah yeah you have the
existential threats your business you
want to share with us yeah i think the
threats to the manufacturing side are
just that the rules and regulations will
get out in front of the technology to be
able to produce those products that can
come comply with those rules and
regulations and so
just uh being able to meet the real
stringent testing requirements and
things like that when you're trying to
run a fully automated process can be
difficult so hopefully they'll kind of
rain those in a little bit and we'll be
able to go
go ahead and process
great thank you we don't have any more
time i'm sorry it is no it is the time
but yeah but don't leave let's hear it
from the panel first of all let's hear
it's fantastic