uh for his personal youth per household three or  per person at the household per person household
I believe that we will have an increase in  prescriptions from Physicians for patients who
want to use our medical Canabis for the treatment  of their disease they have to ask those license
seeds are you making money are you making  money for the cultivation of cannabis at home
you can actually get your seeds from the cabis  associations from the cultivation associations
even if you're not a member you should actually  be able to get get your seeds for home grow
from them so that's the plan from the from the  cultivation association yes that's the [Music]
plan okay ladies and gentlemen welcome to the ICBC  where the world meets cannabis podcast we're very
excited to be here in our studio in lublana with  a extremely special guest uh he is a partner at
Denton's law firm and he is located in Berlin and  he is actually uh heading the European cannabis
group for uh for Dentons and there's probably no  more knowledgeable person in Germany uh or the
rest of Europe then our very esteemed guest uh  Peter Holberg welcome to the podcast Alex thank
you very much for the kind introduction it's great  um we've known each other for years and uh we've
kind of seen um the the whole story of cannabis in  in Germany unfold and I want to get to that in a
second but one thing I'm really curious about is  so Dentons is is it the largest law firm in the
one of the largest law firms in the world um it's  a very esteemed International uh law firm uh and
so how can you tell us a little bit about how you  became the head of the European cannabis group for
Dentons how that unfolded yeah actually you're  right Dentons is one of the largest law firms uh
worldwide with a great number of different offices  in in various jurisdictions in Europe in Northern
America South America as well as in Asia MH uh  not to forget Middle Eastern Africa uh and uh
I think since two weeks also in the Philippines  um with the law fir who has joined our Network
in Mala amazing um um it actually happened uh back  in 2016 uh so uh some time ago uh when Germany was
actually on the edge to legalize cannabis for  medical purposes uh there was and we can come
back to that in in a minute an very interesting  Judgment of of the highest administrative Court
in Germany the so-call Bund M uh who at that point  in time allowed patients who at that point in time
had only a special permit from the be Farm to use  cannabis for their treatment of their disease um
and uh they actually one of the patients actually  wanted to grow at home mhm and um uh he actually
informed the Bay Farm is the German FDA uh that  uh following the uh permit to use cabus for the
treatment of his disease and there were only 600  to 700 patients at that point in time he wants to
grow uh and the Bay Farm he wants to grow at  his house at at home because for for various
reasons because he if he said if if I'm allowed  to to use it for the treatment of my my disease
why can't I grow it at home and uh the Germans  are very good in sending ceas and deist orders
and that's what the Bay Farm did and he went to  court through all the instances and in the last
instance before the highest administrative cour  in Germany he actually won uh with the uh giving
him the allowance that the permission actually to  to grow cannabis for his uh treatment at home so
setting a a precedent basically yes absolutely uh  that was at that point in time for the legislator
for the government a nightmare 600 Growers of  Canabis in Germany Allowed by by the highest
administrative court so what they did they very  quickly reacted to it uh in 2017 in March 2017
uh they legalized cannabis for the treatment of  uh in medical side for the treatment of various
diseases upon prescription from Physicians U  and um of course also then with the goal to
uh uh disallow the uh respective home grow at that  point in time um and uh actually the irony abounds
but go go on that is seven years later that's  seven years later and that's that's actually at
that point in time they they um they're looking  for cultivators in Germany so what happened but
at this point in time was tender you're talking  immediately in March 2017 uh they they there was a
need for various patients who got the prescription  from the Physicians to to get cannabis products
MH uh mainly flowers at that point in time U and  um and all of a sudden there were importers and
of course cultivators and as you know Canada in  the US but in particular canab where we're years
ahead of Germany uh in that respect at that point  retirement back in 2017 and uh we had a cannabis
practice and we still have a Canabis practice in  Canada uh at Denton mhm uh and all of a sudden uh
there was a great interest in the German Market by  in particular the Canadian cultivators I remember
and and back in April 2017 just one month later uh  the first uh uh uh cultivator uh wanted to enter
the German market and I can name them because  its public domain it was canopi growth uh and
we advised them how they could enter the market  they acquired a company which was called mat Ken
at that point in time which was their actually  distributor for the small amounts of uh uh uh THC
rated products of of flowers uh for the small  group of patients uh in the German Market but
all of a sudden ex it exploded so the question  was who can handle that in Germany for them who
has the knowledge uh and I am heading also the  life sciences practice uh in Germany uh and I'm
advising Life Sciences companies which means  companies in the fields of pharmaceuticals uh
Diagnostics medical devices and biotechnology  already for over 20 years I was myself in the
industry uh so it was a n natural fit so it was a  natural fit that uh cannabis for medical purposes
uh is is then handled by my me and my team  from the berin office now did you Vive for
this position I'm curious or did or was it uh a  pointed upon you or did you want did you were you
interested in no I was very interested because  we were following the uh uh Court decision and
the development of that uh Court decision at the  highest administrative Court in Germany closely
because there there was some something on the edge  I would say uh very interestingly and as such uh
we deeply dived into to the new legislation there  was a new law which was Cannabis the Cannabis act
for medical purposes yeah uh in order to advise  our clients accordingly and since then we are
very much looking forward to each and every  regulatory uh changes that is amazing because
I remember I Met You in 217 and I was actually and  I had you know been in the industry for a while
and uh I was I was really impressed with what you  were doing I was impressed how you were doing it
and uh I was just kind of I just thought it was  kind of cool that hey Denton has a cannabis uh
division in in Europe so that's that's phenomenal  and then we take it seven years later and I think
um the big elephant in the room these days and  uh is that uh is Germany is close to legalizing
decriminalizing modernizing something so we hear  a lot about what's what's going to what's what's
happening what's going to happen in Germany and  uh you know we hear about phase one we hear about
phase two and I hear some other interesting things  about like seeds and clones and I hear thing about
about medical cannabis in in Germany would you  give us a quick overview Peter of what the heck
is going on in Germany because I know a lot of  people are really excited about it how much time
do we have for the can can speak about it for  the next two hours I mean how about the cursory
overview yeah now I think was the the Milestone  was of course back in 2017 the legalization
of medical cannabis I think that was really the  Milestone uh and triggering the following events
uh which was then uh the new government uh which  was elected actually introduced the legalization
for recreational Cannabis Coalition the  traffic Coalition which which is uh the
social Democrats the free Democrats and the  green party they introduced that into their
Coalition uh agreement uh with two sentences  only uh they wanted to legalize cannabis for
recreational purposes so that's how they actually  started uh then months really nothing happened um
and uh what they then actually did they triy  to find a way how can we do that uh because
there is a very strict legal framework as we all  know they are the three different un conventions
the most most important one the 1961 un single  convention which uh of which Germany is also a
member but not only Germany it's also the European  Union which is a member uh and as such the uh uh
restrictions for the legalization of recreational  Cannabis not only cannabis but for any kind of
Narcotics and cannabis is of course respectively  uh uh defined as such uh is prohibited so that
is actually what uh uh the German government  took into consideration when they put that into
their Coalition agreement nobody thought about  the legal hurdles MH and all of a sudden there
were more than one legal hurdle not only the UN  conventions and and and we know for example Canada
in back in 199 legalized cannabis recreational  purposes not really uh taking much care about
the UN conventions however uh Germany Germany is a  member of the European Union as you all know U and
um as such they have to adhere to the respective  also European uh regulations uh which means in
uh particular the shenon agreement which is the  basis for the European Union uh and of course
all the protocols following out of this shenen  agreement so back in October 2022 uh the German
government presented a legalization concept very  nicely I would say drafted uh they wanted to uh
cultivate cannabis for recreational purposes in  Germany under the government control they wanted
to distribute to this cannabis for recreation  purposes via uh license dispensaries license
means also under government control in order to  legalize Canabis recreational purposes in Germany
to the full extent as we actually have seen  that in Canada um they knew that there are legal
hurdles so they went to the European commission  and asked can we actually do that why did they
ask because it could have moved forward of course  uh because the European commission as well as all
other European member states could initiate  a respective uh uh legal actions before the
European court of justice for the breach of the  Shen so just so the audience understands what this
what this means basically you're saying that the  EU is basically acting as a centralized Federal
Authority that has Punit or can be punitive uh  take take measures take punitive measures if you
maybe that's not the right legal word but they  can they could sue the respective country they
could withhold funds for other things for example  yeah punative punative actions I would say is the
right the right expression you know Alex uh they  could actually initiate as I said respective legal
proceedings before the European court of justice  right and Germany had just recently lost again I
would say big thing uh before the European court  of justice and they didn't want to risk that again
which is I think understandable what was what did  they lose uh uh the first one was with regard to
the uh toll for private cars uh and their toll  system which they wanted to implement uh which
was not uh in line with to system in the road  yeah yeah or yeah but just for p no we have it
for we have it for trucks uh for all trucks which  are on the on the German Auto oh uh but we didn't
have it we don't have it for private cars other  countries have it for private cars you know like
Austria or France uhhuh exactly Czech Republic  they they all having also so we're digressing
but I'm such a political science nerd why would  that not be constitutionally legal if it's or
why would that be not okay because they wanted to  privilege the German the German drivers the German
uh uh inhabitants the German people uh they they  wanted to reimburse them honest that was was one
of gun early that was that was one of those those  plans cool so so you think so you think that that
that that because they that was shot down or they  they lost that decision you think that was one of
the reasons they didn't no they they actually  were asking uh the the European commission can
we do it the European commission said and well uh  our minister of of Health K laaba said we had very
productive talks with the European commission  was that the euphemism of the day and and all
of a sudden you know this whole plan was in the  bin you know unfortunately because I think that
was would have been the best way to legalize it so  I so I have a question you think that would have
been the best way to legalize it if you were  the health minister of Germany would you have
done it the Canadian way and just have ASU all  um advice from from the higher ups if you will
very difficult question uh you know do you let  me let me rephrase it so I don't put it on you
per se but do you think what what do you think  would have happened if Germany had just gone for
it like that they would have been sued before the  European court of justice and uh which would have
put all the whole program on a hold uh it would  like an injunction yeah yeah you can't proceed
if you already and stopped by the European court  of justice to initiate the respective uh uh law
for the legalization so if you would ask me what  would I have done there are of course ways from my
point of view uh to at least use the uh I wouldn't  say loopholes but the possibilities uh in the UN
conventions and in the Shen agreement uh and I  would probably have decided to do the same way
as Switzerland for example is doing it that we  have scientifically controlled pilot projects in
in various cities in various regions um in order  also to gain some data what kind of impact does
it have the legalization on on the community on  on the on the users um and and then decide how we
can actually move forward maybe Lobby then with  these generated data uh the proper legalization
now this is basically and this is phase would be  phase two we'll talk about phase one but this is
this is more of a phase two thing where you  would um because what the European as far as
I understand legalization is is okay under the  opes of health and research are so some of the
things you're talking about within the convention  yeah that's that's correct for medical purposes
you can of course legalize cannabis which Germany  has done uh which is totally in line with the UN
conventions and the respective sh agreement and  if you then start a scientific project scientific
purposes is also possible under the UN conventions  if you start a scientific pro project trying to
understand what kind of impact the legalization  of Canabis recreational purposes has uh and then
gain data from that and then decide how you  how you going to do it in the future that is
a perfect legal way how you could do it you still  would have the control of course with regard to
the cultivation with regard to the distribution  well not each and every consumer would have got
access to the respective sources in these pilot  projects because they you can't roll that out
Nationwide or German wide you can use it in  uh or can establish it in various cities you
know for example let's talk about Berlin we have  maybe 10 15 different dispensaries where actually
consumers registered consumers could uh buy uh  cannabis for recreational purposes uh and this
is then spread out in other cities maybe in other  areas other regions in Germany uh and and then of
course you can actually gain the respective data  which you correctly said is actually the second
step of the legalization model which Germany  is now using uh but that that is would have
been my favorite solution very much the same as  Switzerland is doing it right that's uh yes I I I
tend to agree with you uh Peter um I'm a decrim  guy for sure but I think you could decrim and
still not have the Social Clubs you could have  just said well we'll have possession you can
grow three plants that's pretty benign but the  Social Clubs so this the Social Clubs phase one
let's talk about everyone's beloved phase one uh  in in Germany which is controversial at least um
there's a I know I've heard a lot of different  opinions on phase one I have a I have my own
take on it um very curious uh to hear your take  on phase one social social clubs Peter what are
you thinking let's let's talk about the the facts  first I would say what what is Phase One what does
it all Encompass so in phase one we have also  two different Steps step one is hom grow each
and every adult uh can actually grow up to three  female plants at home and can use the Canabis
cultivated from by this plants or from this plants  uh for his personal youth per household three or
per person at the household per person household  so if you have three three people in the household
you have nine nine plans U and that that's  that's the first step the second step is the
what you said cannabis clubs which is not really  the Cannabis Club system which we know from Spain
it's totally different uh I would say cultivation  associations where up to 500 members can actually
grow cannabis in a community MH U and can then  use the Cannabis which is cultivated uh at the
uh cultivation Association for their own personal  use okay uh for the recreation so they can hire a
surrogate or they can choose a surrogate to  grow for them do we know we don't know that
yet by heart uh because the kind abis gazettes  the Cannabis law the Cannabis act for legalizing
the recreational use of cannabis is not very  precise on that it's relatively silent how this
structure should function and they leave it to  the states within Germany to really then establish
the legal framework under which conditions uh  the cultivation associations can operate so it
could be yes you're right it could be uh the  assumption is right right that they actually
can source that out that they can combine uh uh  their need or their cultivation possibilities and
source that out to a party who actually the uh the  possibility to grow and has a knowledge to grow I
don't believe that uh this will materialize  Frankly Speaking but we'll see what the what
the various States will come out with and the  onus is put upon the local or the region or the
bundus of each per each bundus stat has can  make up their own time place and manner rules
or locals or municipalities I I would I wouldn't  say that you can foresee chaos uh but you can
see a heterogeneous definitely approach because  this federal law leaves it now for to the various
States within Germany to really uh uh in very  much detail Define the legal framework uh how
these cultivation associations can operate then  we can assume uh that the the regulations will be
more liberal in Berlin and more strict in Bayern  for example yeah the assumption is not uh out of
the world I would say it's we'll see how that  will really work out but first of all you know
the law has to the parliament uh it has done so  already in the first reading the second and third
reading which is the normal uh way in order to  uh establish respective laws in law making uh
will actually is planned for next week uh in in  Germany and we'll see how the outcome will what
the outcome will be as of right now do is that  vote scheduled on the what do they call it the
bundus uh what they call Bund bundes T has an  agenda of course I have looked yesterday it
was not on the agenda yet but that doesn't mean  anything it could be put on the agenda it's put
on the various committees which have to look  at the law as well and from there let's assume
it would pass second and third reading next week  it will be uh retransferred to the bundes which
is the council uh and from there it will be either  passed uh and then only be signed by the president
uh for the implementation or actually refr which  is possible uh to a mediation committee if the
bundesrat decides that there should be additional  amendments and changes in the law right and right
and so right now most people are assuming that  when when it gets to the bundus rat it's going
to go through because it's not politically  expedient for anybody to oppose it because
of how many greens are in the local districts  this is just a little bit that I've heard and
the greens could then stop it if ESP day wanted  to the I'm a little confused because I'm I'm not
a a I'm not an expert on on German politics by  any means but but I thought basically it's not
basically the the the opinion is that it will pass  out of the the bundus rat yeah the bunus R doesn't
have a veto right uh it is not a law which the  bundes part has to actually the possibility to
stop it but they can actually ask for additional  amendments which they have done already because
before it came to the parliament it was already  being discussed within the bundus who actually
said we would like to have a number of amendments  as such then the law was being retransferred to
the various Ministries and everybody was working  on various parts of that law and now uh the new
uh amended uh uh draft of Bill looks a little  different uh in in some respects so they could
they could um I won't say grievance but they  could say well we don't we would we don't
agree with this new little change for example for  example yeah um but we have to look into the some
other uh effects or some other part part s of  that draft law which are interesting for for in
particular the Cannabis industry on the medical  side you know what is happening as well that's
in the draft law is that cannabis and THC related  products will be taken out of the German narcotics
okay so I want to get to that in just a second  because I actually think that that is the most
exciting exciting thing so let's just talk about  let's just finish up phase one here first so the
phase there's two phases of phase one one and the  first phase is what's going to happen let's say
the bundas dog passes it and then it goes through  the bundus r and let's say around April 1st it
it becomes legal what's becoming legal is three  plants you can grow now and you can possess what
25 50 grams 25 grams if you are in the public and  50 grams if you're at home 50 grams if you're at
home and then the second phase of phase one will  go will uh uh uh be like Li they're saying then
they implement the social the social Clause these  asso cultivation associations but at the same time
and that's within this first this first uh this  first step is that the uh narcotics act will be
amended okay so now here I think is I think this  is the elephant in the room what we're about to
talk about now now I don't think this is what  I don't think a lot of people know and this is
a little more esoteric when it comes to the can  G Law and something that I'm very excited about
we know that the market driver in Germany or in  Europe right now is the German medical marijuana
Market that's where the real Market lies yes  there's CBD stuff but that's a little am ambiguous
with the German Medical Market you pretty much  know pretty much right where where things stand
yeah cannabis is coming off the narcotics list  will this if if passes will this be part of a
phase one of phase one will this happen right like  April if it if assuming soeter please tell us what
do cannabis coming off their narcotics which  I'm getting like Goosebumps just talking about
it what does that mean for the medical marijuana  industry in Germany I don't have my crystal ball
with me so but what do you think that might mean  but it definitely oh let's come take a take a look
into the current prescription uh policies today  a physician who wants to prescribe Canabis to a
patient is prescribing a narcotic this is he needs  to have a special permission to do that he needs
to use actually special prescription blocks uh  in a different color uh in order to prescribe
narcotic for patients for the treatment of  his disease that is to a certain extent a
psychological Hurdle from my point of view if you  just change that into an RX product which means
just the product which is uh being prescribed as  as any other RX product for example what would
be an example of another AR for example any kind  of heavy painkillers for example uh who are not
a narcotic but who uh are under prescription  um so that is something which is comparable to
that then okay um and and they of course a great  number of different uh Pharmaceuticals which has
have to be prescribed in order to get get it from  the pharmacy you can't just get it off the shelf
it's not everything which is not OTC over the  counter uhhuh um and as such uh I believe that
uh we will in have an increase in prescriptions  from Physicians for patients uh who are who want
to use medical Canabis for the treatment of their  disease it'll be less cumbersome of a process for
the doctor to prescribe it for example per se  absolutely then there are some side effects
of that the prescriptions will last longer the  the because the prescription for Narcotics has
has to be filed filed with the pharmacy relative  in a relatively short period of time the other
prescriptions are are valid months for for a  longer period of time uh and U of course you
can use this uh uh prescription also in in  European member states oh wow but you know
you can't get Canabis of course in a French  but you could at least have it on you and not
be arrested theoretically yeah theoretically yes  and the courts would throw it out you still could
be arrested you won't get you won't get THC  rated product with a German prescription the
French Pharmacy I think that's clear but the is  possible you know but I think that the the major
effect is and I think that's something which the  industry is also expecting that the description
will increase everybody said Well if you get the  legalization and if you can have home grow and the
Cannabis cultivation associations uh the medical  Market will uh decrease uh we we we don't I don't
believe that and the number of Market players  in the market don't believe that as well uh it
may uh because you know a patient who is currently  using cannabis even if he's a self-pay and is not
reimbursed by his health insurance company yeah he  gets goes to the next pharmacy around the corner
getting a which has a specific quality which is  overseen uh by the regulatory authorities so he
knows what not expensive like it was a few years  ago also right right competition has lowered the
price the price has been significantly decreased  in comparison to 2017 2018 2019 I when it was like
25 a gram yeah um I have another question because  will this make uh I know that now if pharmacies
have to handle narcotics in a certain way in  Germany right you get it you receive it and then
you have to repackage it yourself or what's the  well I guess my question is because when when when
cannabis comes off the narcotics list this will  be a a less cumbersome process than for doctors
to prescribe it will it be a less cumbersome  process for pharmacies to uh procure and uh purvey
it probably not uh first of all in Germany the  Cannabis product is defined as an extemporaneous
mixture uh which why is that so uh in back in  2017 and it's obvious nice to look back into
history uh the German government wanted to get the  products quickly on the market for the patients
who very in need of cannabis mhm so if you have an  extemporaneous mixture which means uh there is a
pharmaceutical which is in the pharmacy but which  needs to be prepared by the pharmacist according
to the prescription you know that is different  from a readymade pharmaceutical which you have to
take can take off the shelf those Pharmaceuticals  need a a marketing authorization which of course
needs clinical trials and B has to go through  the uh price finding process of the German GBA
bundas which is actually for Pharmaceutical it's  fixing the price for the market this was avoided
by putting cannabis products on the market as  extemporaneous mixtures got but there was a butt
always a butt if you have a butt if you have a an  extemporaneous mixture the pharmacist is obliged
because he is doing something to the product in  this case quality control grinding packaging he
uh uh gets a 100% search charge on the purchase  price that's the reason why we had this 25 EUR
at the beginning per gram that's a man is that  mandated or is that compulsive no it was it was
uh in is in the law actually so the the pharmacist  had to do that of course they were happy to do it
but they had to do it yeah that's absolutely  F so basically they already had this provision
that that that didn't mean that they they had  to adhere to such stringent standards like other
narcotics might be with cannabis specifically  so well the the definition of cannabis product
extemporary mixtur extemporary mixtures will not  change uhhuh and I think what is clear uh even
if the Cannabis products will be taken out of the  narcotics Act and the uh put into or transferred
into the new Canabis act uh probably the same  security measurements will apply uh there will
not be less security for example putting it in a  safe having a safe place for the you don't think
no this is will probably not happen uh because  the security measurements for medical cannabis
from my point of view will not be reduced you  will have the same uh handling process of those
products as if they were narcotics fascinating  and so that seems like they had a little bit of
special status beforehand and now they won't have  any spe they'll just they'll actually it'll be the
opposite because it won't because any another  drug that wouldn't be a narcotic would would
not have to be handled as stringently as cannabis  you think is going to be still handled yeah well
no if you well if you have a morphine for example  a morphine rated product this is the same as it's
a narcotic it's handled espe especially at the at  the pharmacies uh you can't just put it on on the
open shelf so uh and that's will remain the same  there will be no changes to that okay so the main
issue of cannabis coming off the narcotics  list is that they the the doctors will be
able to prescribe it uh I don't want to say with  impunity but they just they they have more leeway
yes absolutely that is from my point of view the  the most important effect of uh the of taking
cannabis and T Canabis rated products THC rated  products out of the German well I think this is
the onest I think to me this is this is almost  the biggest thing that's happening with I mean
this is what's going to have the most effect  immediately I think and what I've also heard
is there's no more tender for domestic production  in in Germany when this passes nobody knows about
that could you speak to nobody knows I've heard  that they're not going to they're going to open
up domestic production they won't put quotas on  the limits of how much you can grow can you speak
to that pet there are many Rumors in the market  right now uh so um back in 2018 2018 actually
there was uh a way to find cultivators in Germany  and which was a tender process as we all know the
Bay Farm actually tendered out uh respective lots  for the cultivation of canab of medical Canabis in
Germany and three companies have been assigned  licenses at the very end of that long lasting
process which was actually stopped by the court  in the first in the first place remember right and
then then reestablished uh and afria uh as well as  Demian and Aurora won the respective 13 licenses
for cultivation of cannabis which in fact was  limited in quantity is still limit in a quantity
it's actually 10.4 metric tons over a period  of 4 years which means means 2.6 metric tons if
I'm not mistaken per year plus my plus a certain  certain threshold of probably 10% uh which could
be could be actually cultivated uhhuh so that is  uh what happened so at that point in time so now
of course also these licenses are questioning hey  what is going to happen if the four years are over
uh is there another tender process uh is there  a licensing process for the cultivation of of
Medical cannabies in Germany can others actually  participate then or what is the Bay Farm actually
planning the Bay Farm currently is relatively  silent on that it is of course pending uh uh
thoughts at the Ministry of Health what is going  to happen you know you have hom grow uh with three
female plants per adult you have the cultivation  associations and then you have a limitation on
the cultivation of medical cannabis with a very  strict tender process it really doesn't uh dive
too well right yeah and as such we will see but  at this point in time this is unclear there is no
clear pass forward and do you know what percentage  approximately what percentage of cannabis cons
medical cannabis consumed in Germany is has to  be imported uh well if you look into the import
quantities in the last years and let let's look  into 2023 but I don't have the uh last quarter
figures but it it was uh around 23.4 metric tons  without the last quarter of imported cannabis so
that would be 90% yeah I would say a little less  than that because the 2.6 metric tons per enom can
be increased you know by by a certain percentage  but U 85 85% around that figure well if you ask
the the cultivation the German cultivators they  say well we have a larger they have a larger stake
in the market but but if if you start calculating  it it I would say it's in that region at least
interesting absolutely fascinating um where by  where by German politicians who are looking into
the medical market for cannabis said why don't  we allow more cultivation of medical cannabis
in Germany why do we really need to import it  from various different other other different
countries like Canada and there number of other  countries right now exporting into the German
Market yeah uh why can't we actually strengthen  the German medical cannabis industry which from
my point of view is natural yeah let's do it we  have we we know that we can do it we we know that
we have three cultivation uh companies who who  are really experts in it why don't we try to at
least serve the market for medical uh Canabis at  least to a much higher extent from from German
cultivation so does German do the prices of uh  we won't talk about quality that's a little bit
subjective but we can quantify the prices quite  easily um you know the the argument that well the
German cultivators will never be able to compete  in Germany with other uh foreign outsourcers like
Colombia loto for example I've heard that argument  um I don't know what to think about it because I
actually have no idea what the costs are I mean  you know you can you can grow uh cannabis for
Less in some of these other countries but then  you still have all these other import costs and
Customs cost and travel costs and or shipping cost  and and whatnot yeah what do you think about that
well well at the point in time when the various uh  participants in that tender started to calculate
uh what is a per gr price an appropriate per gram  price and I can say that we were representing one
of those cultivators who did not win uh uh and we  actually we sitting together and see what is the
right price on a program basis which makes it at  least economically feasible uh and now we know and
that's official that's public domain that uh the  per gram price from cultivation in Germany is 220
so they are selling at 220 per gram two they're  selling it at 220 220 euro per gram to the B for
oh is that right no that's interesting I didn't  know that so the they're obviously then their
their their production costs are maybe we could  assume half like a Euro I I maybe we're getting
into a little no that's that's precarious ground  yeah no that indeed because those um parties or
those participants in the tender process they Rich  wanted to win it they they were significantly uh
calculating it and at the very low and as  our client who did not win actually did it
as well but it was still more than the 220 so the  question which you have to ask those licenses are
you making money are you making money yes or no  which I can't answer uh and uh uh of course you
know the uh setting up of a cultivation site uh  for medical cabis in Germany is expensive because
you know the security millions and millions and  millions and millions the security measurements
of course and and all infrastructure which you  need so so very difficult to say how much at
least but this has to be amortized you know  and then of course you you're talking about
a different price structure of course than 220 per  gram right for my point of view right uh but let's
see how this works out uh U I believe that the  German cultivation cultivation sides the German
cultivators definitely can compete with all the  others around the world uh from Canada uh from
Holland from loto or for for whever because we  we don't have the respective transport costs you
know handling is easier uh and and as such but  just what you said you know cost structures in
Germany of course are higher with regard to energy  and and uh Labor uh and what what you also need
is good management and amation can right uh but uh  sense you know if you going to to send uh a ton of
Canabis from Canada to to Germany the respective  transport costs are significant you know uh 100%
um well that's all extremely interesting stuff  Peter I think that uh uh uh I mean basically
we have three major things happening we have the  a bunch of stuff with the can KNG we've got this
social or the um uh cultivation associations uh we  have um uh now what about seeds and clones I think
a lot of people ask about that we hear seeds  and clones are going to become legal in some
way can you speak to that yes they they need to  become legal in some way in which way is a little
uncertain uh with respect to can you just uh order  it by amazone for your private cultivation uh at
home I don't believe that's going to happen darn  it uh but what what what the German government is
thinking is that the for for the home grow for the  growth or for the cultivation of um cannabis at
home you can actually get your your seeds from  the Canabis associations from the cultivation
associations and even if you're not a member  you should actually be able to get your seeds
for hom growth from them so that's the plan from  this from the cultivation association yes that's
the plan so huh in indeed and we will see how  this will work out because the demand you know
if if the LA would come into force on April  1st 2024 and you allow home grow the demand
for seeds for cultivation equipment you know  is enormous enormous enormous enormous and
the question is how can you serve that demand how  can you satisfy that demand and this is something
which uh probably has not been re thought through  so far this is such an interesting conversation
I think we're really teaching uh the folks our  audience so much about what's going on in Germany
uh right now um Peter where would you say the  opportunities are industry opportunities with
this with KNG with phase one with even phase to  uh and with the medical uh with cannabis coming
off the narcotics list I mean I think people can  can come to their own conclusion by uh deduce from
uh everything you said uh thus far of maybe of  of of what some of those opportunities could be
could you enumerate a few industry uh areas and  sectors that you think are going to uh benefit
from this it will be definitely very positive I  wouldn't say a boost but very positive for the
medical market for the medical cannabis Market  which is already the biggest which is Market in
Europe it hasn't it hasn't been growing so fast  as everybody wanted it to grow or as as it has
been predicted to grow but it's steadily growing  and there are some new ways for example now uh in
order uh to bring together pharmacies Physicians  and and patients so there are some interesting uh
platforms who are doing that um so this Market  will definitely have a from my point of view
positive impact from the new cannabis gazettes  home grow um or and the community cultivation as
I would call it MH for for the existing cannabis  industry it's it's probably not that interesting
except for those who are providing equipment  who are providing seeds uh who are providing
uh knowledge uh who can advise uh those clubs how  to set up the respective infrastructure once we
know how the infrastructure will look like from a  state $64,000 from a from from a state byst state
regulation um and uh I think these are the the the  the winners I would say from that uh if the second
stage is coming uh which we still haven't seen  as a draft law which was actually promised to be
uh at least put into the public by by end of by  end of 2023 uh then uh we probably will see more
winners and from the existing cannabis industry  in Germany uh because you know if you have this
uh pilot projects rolled out over Germany you  need to serve these pilot projects with with
cannabis um which is probably which are probably  not the cultivation associations who are going to
provide that so that it will be probably those uh  who are in a position and the three uh licensed
medical cannabis cultivators are in the in the  top position for that for phase two for phase two
yeah in in what regard that they would vertically  consolidate and have their own what well if you or
they would oh I get it I get it that they would  Supply yes they will supply you know they can
definitely uh extend the limited production which  they have right now under the 10 10 .4 metric tons
for 4 years for the medical s they can definitely  uh serve the market increase their production and
serve the market for uh for the pilot projects  so this sounds like when the that the phase to
the pilot projects those are basically going to be  de facto dispensaries that when the EU capitulates
if I will if I may um then those will be the the  establishments and institutions that uh one could
foresee being grandfathered into a license and  and regulate uh yeah and with with those with
those data which you can then generate and as  I said this is my favorite solution for the for
the legalization process with those data which  you can generate from these uh scientifically
controlled pilot projects you can actually Lobby  then uh before the European commission and within
at the other member states for the legalization  on a broader basis um that's that's that makes
sense um what about Brands Peter right now I'm  curious if you go to a pharmac I think people
hear about Germany that cannabis is sold in the  pharmacies under medical um can that cannabis be
branded can you when you go and buy a package  at the pharmacy does it have to be a a banan
sterile package or could it say could it have a  like uh cookies on it or like the cookies brand
with a low with a uh a brand can are there any  brands in the German pharmacies I'm curious well
the question is what what is a brand if you mean  a logo and description description of the of the
product well yes of course we we have of course  uh uh various Brands already in the in the German
Market from various uh companies uh who are  importers who have maybe their own brand or
using different brand bedan has different brands  for example as as Canam medical has different
brand brands for their products now when I say  brand I don't mean just the name of the strain
necessarily could there be like a colorful sticker  with a the answer is no know it's a pharmaceutical
it really remain a pharmaceutical and has to be  pharmaceutically packaged So when you say Brands
that's like the strain name purush or this  is whatever yeah with with a specific of THC
content CBD content Etc interesting Peter you are  down here in Slovenia uh to speak in front of the
National Council which is basically our bundus  rat um you're speaking tomorrow uh in front of
a packed house uh at the National Council we are  extremely glad to have you down here and giving
the uh Slovenian National Council your opinion  on things um do you want to just give us a a a
little hint into what you're going to say or  maybe I could reframe the question and saying
what do you think a country like Slovenia should  do at this stage um um um what should they take
from Germany what should they uh not take uh  what are you going to talk about tomorrow what
do you suggest Slovenia what do you suggest  Slovenia does well first of all I think it's
a big advantage that other countries are looking  into the possibility to use cannabis first of all
for medical purposes but also thinking about the  legalization process like Czech Republic is doing
it as well uh uh I think that's a big step forward  Slovenia has always been very cautious looking at
what's going to happen in other European member  states uh and as such I will definitely report
about what I believe is a real success about the  medical market for cannabis and Germany MH uh and
show the developments show the the numbers which  we have for patients the quantities and of course
also discuss uh a little bit uh whether would it  be better to have uh local production rather than
import uh or is it better to use the already  uh established roots of importation so that's
I think one one piece of my my presentation  tomorrow uh and uh my for my personal point
of view uh cannabis is uh a real good addition to  the possibilities uh for different different uh uh
for the treatment of different diseases you know  if you look into chronic pain and what cannabis
can do for those patients uh who are using other  uh um medications which have probably more side
effects or not well uh but who who are are  looking for a different treatment I think
Canabis is a very good alternative and as such it  has definitely its place from my point of view in
the Pharmaceuticals market so that's number one  number two of course then we're talking about
the recreational Market uh and from my point  of view I will uh definitely point out that uh
the scientific uh controlled pilot project from  my point of view is the best step forward look
into what uh first of all controlled cultivation  controlled distribution and of course then gaining
data uh getting uh really knowledge uh What uh  uh cannabis for recreation purposes can do uh and
then actually decide what how how a legalization  process can go forward that is amazing Peter
Holberg the man the myth the legend we are so  honored to have you in Slovenia and speaking
to the National Council tomorrow thank you for  coming on to the IC C BC where the world's meet
where the world meets cannabis podcast it's been  a great honor thanks so much Peter Alex thank you
so much all right guys we'll see you next week or  the week after that with the next podcast I don't
know how we're going to Top This one this was  really really really amazing a ton of esoteric
knowledge we appreciate youall ICBC Berlin  coming up April 16th and 17th we'll see you there
peace [Music]