the long game well it should be awesome
well yeah I'm Nikki's Liam CEO 3c
consulting just made it back from
America or from South America this is
really important not a lawyer I'm not a
CPA a lot of those past people great
titles use these professionals without
them you're screwed
most of the things we've seen in the
last 10 years were problems from legal
structuring not understanding the laws
or like horrible tax burdens we're gonna
make a [ __ ] ton of money but then you
had horrible accounting in one company
and the investors wouldn't come in
correctly so use these professionals and
just business guidance here originally
from Wisconsin did military after
military went to Colorado right time
right place 2006 right when it was like
medical cannabis cards on the wall - hey
we're doing compliant business so that's
when I came in and have seen this
evolution happen have worked all over
the place in terms of states and
countries a lot of similarities market
to market but some of the things that I
see and least for where this markets
going may be a little different than
most people because I've been inside so
many of the companies it's not just
reading online articles or it's meeting
with prime ministers seeing delegation
work going into a company when they've
got 250 people and they're not let's say
making payroll and super inefficient or
didn't plan their business operations or
for fungal diseases 9 pestis throwing a
huge multi-million dollar company that
when you see those parts of the company
that's where you can see what are the
common trends where is this really going
and it's not small scale a little
warehouses like Colorado back in the day
seeing this now I think international
cannabis business this one has been
amazing from a conference and for years
and years seeing now like what's
happened in this last four to five years
since they started everyone thinks about
Canada or Uruguay for legalizing adult
use like definitely not legal
internationally at this point with laws
and policies but with 19 countries
having some sort of import-export or
production business it's really going to
be amazing but it sucks so much right
now because you have to hold these
positions in these countries that don't
have massive demand don't have doctors
making prescriptions it's not the same
the German cannabis market ask the
American cannabis Mart
thinking legalized medical but you're
thinking prescriptions and doctors and
then Europe having novel foods and how
those regulations are gonna affect a
cannabis business there compared to
we're gonna sell vape cartridges in
Austria probably probably not the same
basis so everything international other
than Canada Uruguay think API active
pharmaceutical ingredient markets bulk
flower and if it's flower it's not
trimmed fancy like in a bag like this is
danca [ __ ] weed it's usually ground up
and unidentifiable so your whole process
is if you're a Canadian for example and
then went to grow in Israel or in
Denmark all of a sudden you're growing
one sort of specification of a product
that's not meant for the whole market
and your whole business plan was wrong
so country by country how they relate
whose pharmaceutical compacts work
together how the UN of the whe OHS
recommendations this March could be like
step two of the step three endgame for
cannabis but it's happening but a lot of
countries talk about this there are
opportunities everywhere but if their
laws are not correct you're going to
completely fail like a Zimbabwe LSU to a
Swaziland if it's not correct modeled on
these laws you really have to be very
careful in navigating which ones are
coming up here because some are just
gonna like waste your time would be
painful most of these businesses
compliance is unique here in Canada or
here in California and Canada but each
place is different so if you're thinking
of a hands-on company and you're
investing in them or operating them like
what rules do you have to follow how do
these rules change how do you have
enough capital to do this and most
people they get this license they see
huge value which that's massive
opportunities with these limited
licenses in states and countries but
they don't realize that that piece of
paper is the whole thing that matters so
how do we not lose this piece of paper
not just how do we make a consumer
package female wellness hemp lifestyle
brand for example it's that aspect so
it's really important to build
everything off of but most people don't
know how to cover their ass in the space
or think what is the value in your
opportunity it's the piece of paper when
we think you know I put ATF on here like
Alcohol Tobacco Firearms they get to
have all the fun stuff maybe it goes
that way but when you
of what we're doing and why certain
companies have come in on an investment
opportunity it's just barely begun but
now is the bleeding like when we're
almost at 20 billion dollars in industry
annually that's just the hands-on
opportunities what what's really gonna
gonna play out here and who's gonna
control it from a US basis as well as an
international basis so some of these
opportunities we're not gonna we don't
grow tobacco in every single state and
have like there's a different tax like
state-by-state or why doesn't our good
beer out of Colorado make it to all
these other markets it's because there's
these different taxes regulations to us
we're going towards federal side it's a
when ya think how are you gonna play
into that with these opportunities not
just I have a cool dispensary in
Berkeley or I have a delivery company in
San Luis Obispo or I have 10,000 Eric
acres of flowering canopy or something
somewhere so to beat the odds here
there's tens of thousands of us now as
companies businesses individuals and
most people don't realize how their
little operation is gonna weather this
next storms you're already sealing it's
not as fun as it used to be but it's way
more fun on different levels this is
what changes things for the hands-on
companies be it any sort if they don't
integrate with their communities
correctly they have the biggest problems
from a tax rate standpoint from you know
being bothered or not choosing the right
opportunities so choose a good place be
involved with that community and don't
be an [ __ ] in that community very
very important like the good neighbor
policies and in California with your
compassionate carrot prop D prop em 2:15
temp state state license process or or
any other jurisdiction if you didn't
have that community piece along the way
those are the ones that fail the people
are crazy huge I've realized it's now
more than ever over a decade that each
company's operation as you're building
these teams or when we look at
investment opportunities where if it's a
team in another country or another state
like that had to bring in expertise how
did they do it how are they doing well I
see way too many good businesses just
fail without good people and it's not
just getting some advisors but you need
your local people and really understand
the operation there's so many outside
industries that are applicable
to this space and the people and their
skillsets but you have a very limited
window where you can take applicable and
make it awesome in this space otherwise
they just crush it because it's not
something else but it's very similar but
yeah the biggest things that I see
important for people it's what they
bring cannabis can be taught trained
learned other than the specific little
pieces but we need some rock stars in
these companies now this is kind of a I
think for all the companies and
countries that I work the most important
thing that happens time and time again
is where how I think about this growing
long term in greenhouses in California
for flowers gonna work for certain
places but the taxes suck here there's
not that much water everyone's excited
about hemp and cannabis here but we
don't grow all of our watermelons here
or peppers or tomatoes or roses we're
pretty lazy when it comes to that
standpoint for cost or you go to
Colombian like the coffee's kind of
shitty and up here you're like lemming
cough it's really good or like the
apples in Chile a couple weeks ago they
were like crappy and little like I
always see big Chilean apples our market
is where products drive - same with
European markets so when I think about
Peru or Columbia or Uruguay or Mexico at
the end of April like what do these
things mean or maybe a huge thing in
Austria could be greater we're gonna
have a giant concrete warehouse growing
amazing can of medical cannabis in
Germany or the Netherlands but how much
does that cost
what are those crazy taxes what are the
operational costs average wages of the
Colombian workers I was just at was like
350 US a month so it's like just pay him
five and they're like they're stoked and
it's amazing for them same thing when we
thought Macedonia if you don't think
about these costs like how much is the
cost of an employee in California the
state sucks and so it's not as bad as
France it sucks when it comes to
employment law and we have to do the
best with these companies but if you
don't think about cost how to do it
consistently with certain quality
assurance quality control systems and
management your visions and dreams just
fail and they pop all over the world and
it's just ooh
22 million dollars here six million
dollars lost there oh this is a great
thing you can't just sell your garbage
to Canadian public companies anymore so
that whole idea of develop everything
and just flip it just doesn't work and I
like this little farm guy I'm from
Wisconsin with milk and it's like you
don't want a CBD
me right now like what's the Krait
what's the price right now of a kilo of
like high-quality CBD distillates or CBG
or any other of the hundreds of
cannabinoids it wasn't that good of an
idea it was a short period of time or
think no offense like a gen canna or a
great business model but like what
happens so everyone's doing something
any CBD side company right now on a
European basis you better be ready to
understand like novel foods it's
happening so there'll be very very few
bonafide CBD companies in Europe and
they won't produce it there it's
expensive as hell where do these inputs
now that you're gonna get for two
thousand two kilo 1500 what about when
the price of distillate goes to 200 200
euros let's say a like a high quality
kilo your business model gonna survive
that like so that the distillates and
the base products for these are
important but don't just jump on certain
bandwagons
or because everyone's going into a
market can be really dangerous I've seen
that get unique with these sorts of
products if you're making products or
have a dispensary or manufacturing
company like know the rules of that
marketplace and be specific from seeing
wanna and Kota and Kiva and bang like
every great kind of start of a company
what is it that they did well how do you
either hitch onto something like that or
define a space or if you're in a new
state like Illinois and you get a
recreational infuse your license or
something how to make like unique
products with that instead of we're
gonna make vape pens and cartridges and
sublinguals and suppositories and like
be specific with your product offerings
it's not just green fields I like this
lavender there's so many opportunities
of them just we're gonna grow dried
flower and we're gonna make oils and
we're going to the things that most
people are looking at are complete
failures now because it's they didn't
understand the commodification of
cannabis and that's where like taxes
agricultural vectors daytime highs
nighttime lows cheap land not ninety
percent clay soil like perfect climates
to do this or to process this under a
high standards and when you think
international that API like with these
brands they're not they're not thinking
correctly about what actually makes a
qualified brand market by market and the
best thing you can do if you're a
California company or others with this
is
how do you have a let's say Delaware
company and intellectual property
company license that intellectual
property market to market easily and
just have different cannabis licenses in
the other countries but how do you do
things consistently across the board
when we can't franchise we can't cross
interstate lines I can't so pull from
some of the best ideas that you can on
that side when you think about medical
markets or recreational markets you know
inside the United States us rec markets
are very different and awesome but
expensive from the tax standpoint if you
don't do it correctly and this is where
what 10 almost 11 states now thinking
finally Maine coming on board
Massachusetts Illinois just indicative
of future markets for at least a while
but that's state you think what 12
current producers 40 more small ones
come online 13 million people twice the
size of Colorado we're doing about 2
plus billion a year and the Midwest
sucks for example more people gonna use
cannabis because it's flat and gray like
these are huge markets just exploding in
our backyard here where other ones have
already happened medical is hard I'm a
medical patient from disabled military
side and that market is so critical to
do right establish it for standards do
it for patients and when you switch to
adult use which is a when I don't like
maintain that same like health standards
there and really protect medical
programs it's so anyone that's in the
industry that's not giving to like the
groups that make new markets for us aka
like more patients more profits more
people that need help like you're an
[ __ ] so if you're in the rat game or
the medical game like fight for more
legalization and help in patients rights
it's what we've hooked on to like pretty
much take over the world and it's the
most important thing to it's almost like
for the first time in our industry in
the history of business if you do the
right thing for like people in the
markets and like planet like you're not
growing 14th floor hydroponic indoor
warehouses in San Francisco high tech
you have 20,000 hectares in Colombia
with massive extraction and shipping
that for brands created here what's the
impact environmentally so you make more
money in this industry doing the right
thing it's the first time ever it just
cost more money to do it in the
beginning but it's worth it when we
think about what were the biggest
problems is peaches I don't know if you
know peaches I
figured out how to make that slide
myself Canada I've had a problem with
four five six years from the LP private
side to how public companies happened so
when I googled Canada sucks for like a
picture I found peaches who didn't like
the club scene but the cannabis scene
there the problem was they were first
and now with like the crash of Canadian
public markets which everyone thought
we're gonna be so cool for so long like
go public be billionaire it's not the
best thing when you're building scalable
companies but they turn the whole world
off to canvas right now in a way no
offense but with their population the
expectations and true values of
companies its hurt investor confidence
on private capital or the right capital
to grow businesses now and they're not
doing that great and if you were in that
it was kind of a bummer where you
thought speculation but just lying about
future valuations and hurting in but
investor expectations we're at this
point now where if you need even like
working capital for a business doing
twenty million dollars in revenue a year
it can be challenging but this is the
best time to invest into private
companies because they're desperate
they're they're proven and they're
scalable and it's kind of that moment of
desperation where you can make some like
epic wins right now but also it means
really good companies are failing and
they're having problems scale and they
didn't plan for these big things and
like I said you couldn't just sell
yourself to one of these big [ __ ]
they get five ten a hundred times your
actual value so now it's like the truth
is really setting in for a lot of
companies and they have to entrench now
for the next couple months like to
really get good positive capital coming
in again but don't be like peaches like
don't be like Canada you know in the
United States for our big opportunities
it's still market by market by market
and within these markets there's market
evolution and time and businesses change
and then new laws will happen there's
like a new product offering but at this
point I found this really fun picture of
cannibalism
it's happening and that's also a very
profitable business model where you have
how many brands in California how many
if you're not paying for shelf space or
you're near borders or if you don't have
really good distribution contracts
you're awesome humble weeds not making
it to the market same thing in these
other states like distribution is key
and it's you're thinking about federal
legalization
alcohol Liquor Distribution licenses
tobacco type taxes when we think about
investments and placements it's what is
it going to look like in that scheme but
there is so much cannibalism happening
now and it's profitable and it's like
never thought that'd be good but in
cannabis as some market establishes only
so many companies are going to be
leaders but for in Canada the same thing
is starting to happen to you which I'll
get into a little bit for the next part
of the year these are the most important
markets that I see other than existing
in current markets or figuring out how
to recapitalize those assets let's just
say aka cannibalism West Virginia's
almost do we're super engaged in busy
and have been in Illinois just to
establish more 275 more dispensaries 40
more cultivation and extractions West
Virginia a nice cute little verticals
not that crazy heart but really good
market to start mass has been a mess but
it's gonna get better
Maine is gonna start but their governor
was an [ __ ] so it's been so long and
not gonna be that great cuz there's tons
of illicit market it's like the
California of the East Coast and Cali
I'm back it's big e reference this is
what we're currently working on in
California if you're here I figured I'd
go through the current markets that are
very important for new business as well
asked these ones are about to open and
any new market like we studied the laws
the policies the procedures of that
place is it worth going or not are these
opportunities valuable or not and it's
not as valuable just to get a license
and think you'll get capitalized easily
and someone will just you still have to
run the business so this is step one for
these new companies internationally I
know we're getting close here watch what
happens in Vienna later with the w8 show
if their recommendations come out for
the UN like I said it's step two of step
three and like federal where every
hundred and eighty six member country of
the UN single treaty if a doctor makes a
prescription they have to provide
medicine if then awesome that means that
are they going to all produce cannabis
in their little markets like Finland
probably not they're gonna like buy
pharmaceutical products from other
places or the bulk oils or the bulk
flour so it's not like the US I get a
get a thing to like produce in each
place it's like where can you do it best
at the highest standards and supply that
future market demand
the lowest cost and highest quality
standards it's gonna be so enormous
the pharmaceutical all of this site is
so expensive preclinical CRO work phase
one two three like these well we're
seeing that was incredible but this is
the world we play in doing us trials
studies anything the us super expensive
kind of a bummer do it other places
first cheaper and then get the same
standards with like pics countries for
example um what I think really what's
big for the future I don't know if you
know this guy Salvador he's like the
longest known shipwreck survivor like
4469 days went fishing with his homie a
year and a half later select be a
survivor also is homie
he said died four months into it and he
put him in the water speaking back to
cannibalism there but Salvador was the
[ __ ] man so if he can do it you can
too if you're having hard times like
this market it's amazing in the new
business but the truth is starting to
come out like I haven't even been in
America for four months and just working
with the companies seeing what's
happening it's this this interesting
moment we all figured would happen we
didn't think it would be this hard this
long and persistent but the market is
only gonna get better so you think about
how to vision airily prospect in the
industry are the laws good are the
climates good like how much capital do
you actually need understand these
business models more than you could
realize like one of those past slides
dopher san luis obispo or go for this
like how many people are there
population demographics like
transportation history like how hard is
it going to be to get building permits
or processes or licenses or permits like
this is a real struggle and if you go
into another country the most important
thing like if Salvador had a map and
like a paddle this is the key how do
their international their country laws
work with the international laws and
policies and then how could other
business models work there and if it's
not good if it's just cannabis and it's
special it's not going to be that
special like in the long run there so I
think that was about all I had
I like pandas a lot so I thought I'd put
that up there do you guys know that
pornography actually saved the panda
bear
I read a study this was like really in
the beginning of the month that they're
using animal panda porn like to like get
males males only like reproduce for two
days a year they're really lazy and I
learned about them when I was in Asia a
little bit so during that two days like
they have to be like amped up and the
population was going way down this one
Chinese doctors like how could I get
this to happen so you know we've got
unique problems pandas aren't
reproducing or you can't raise capital
or your business is failing you know get
creative you know to to keep the species
and keep the plant going alive
thank you all very very much check check
uh one more time for Nicky's Lee also
let's ask him some questions does
anybody have any questions all right
I'll start do you think it's better to
look domestically right now or to look
internationally and should you be
looking for small to invest in smaller
businesses or should you still try to be
in the big multi-million conglomerate
dollar game Capital comes from I think
that's really important where is your
money because that determines where
you're gonna be able to do this
sometimes there's residency requirements
so you know I like us things but I won't
take foreign national capital and invest
into US companies breaking federal law I
don't think that's a good idea and I
don't like to use certain other capital
so like ancillary businesses or medical
cannabis or recreationally that's you
know if I was in California depending on
the amount of capital it's not just
giving another indoor grow but I think
that the internationals are harder to
get into they're more expensive and you
bleed in the beginning but they're gonna
be the huge hundred X plus multiples
that we really want US sides are like
your solid like ten to twenty s but some
markets you get one of these new
licenses in one of these new states like
one of twelve or something if you can
scale that capitalize it and it's the
right state I think there's a super
super valuable but if you're
international you need a little bit more
money and patience and a lot of patience
thanks I got one more over here I just
have to walk
always wear comfortable shoes when you
go to these things it's always my advice
I don't know what sort of advice you
guys have hey Nick your talk a couple
years ago actually made me feel
comfortable to enter this industry so my
question is about your consolidation
slide using those comparable markets as
where we might be headed with national
legalization we've talked to a couple
regulatory attorneys about that to try
to guess where we're headed and we've
heard in general that it's not
necessarily correct to look at tobacco
and alcohol as a guide for how things
will go down because those were less
about state rights and cannabis has
really been pushed from the state
perspective so we're trying to
anticipate is the differentiation and
state regulation going to continue or
are we gonna end up with states all
headed in the similar direction and
we've sort of landed well as long as
it's a states rights thing then it'll
continue to be different state to state
yeah I would imagine it's gonna be a
combination of the two because we're too
lazy to legalize it federally because we
were the first we're the [ __ ] that
like made it illegal everywhere in the
world it's kind of like ooh we're not
gonna claim that one also we're gonna
Trump will protect US businesses when we
do this in it so it won't be one of
those models I think it'll be
comparative eventually though quickly
how alcoholic took forever to get
legalized this is happening very very
fast so the consolidation roll-up
strategy it's more of how it's gonna
happen because even if it is
state-by-state forever which though
there will be federal those still you
know business and Commerce we're going
to try to figure that one out I would I
would say this most important thing is
balance your books get everything ready
like audit ready financials do [ __ ]
correctly so when it comes time for some
sort of roll-up where those big
companies they were just too lazy and
big and risk adverse to come into it at
first they're gonna figure it out like
you already saw a constellation and
Altria and like all these others soon if
jewel has any money after all they're
man it's like
you know these companies coming in to
it'll happen I don't know how but being
prepared for it is what I've seen the
most important thing like how to roll up
that business proper valuations but do
it like an planet like a normal like
once you're done with your controller
actually get a CFO plan those things to
books everything ready and then
depending how you know that acquisition
could happen but you're right it is it's
different than before but it's gonna be
fast and it's the federal legalization
happens and international at the same
time will have to come on to it on a
medical side but the REC side yeah
that's a good question but it'll happen
one way or another
just be ready it's up Nick good
afternoon my name is Daniel with
cannabis Equity working group and my
question for you is are you comfortable
sharing with us your biggest win and
your biggest fail of 2019 2018 or 1919
it is 2020 biggest of 19 I had a
nepotism issue which sometimes like
nepotism is good like family members not
my family very small family and they're
just like a whole Nick's in the weed but
like this is like some partners of mine
were family and they'd been together for
a long time had a bunch of kids it was
like very small cap table epic epic
project they get a [ __ ] divorce where
she wants to leave him cuz he's a
horrible husband I've been working with
him for a year and I'm like oh [ __ ] this
[ __ ] just blew up and that's happened
I've seen in one way or another so to
use that example and not the specific
kind of country business project but you
got to really know like your people and
trust and you're building this like I
said bringing in new people bringing in
new trust is huge so failures and people
is probably like the biggest I'd say
deficit of 19 which I'm fixing but that
one's gonna be beautiful to a
cannibalistic I'm gonna fix that one
take that [ __ ] over now it's [ __ ]
awesome this is painful so it's kind of
like both in the same and best win of
nineteen oh I kind of came up with a
dual model with a few groups on some
international genetics and processes to
where some can produce the bananas and
some make the dried bananas kind of
thing
so those sorts of business models
long-term like genetics impact is really
really critical probably a win that not
realize this biggest I would like it now
but the long terms on that are just huge
and also well
hitting twenty billion last year you
know 20% of our country is legal for
adult use
that's kind of a big deal and now the
medical rights where we have three more
states at least get basic medical assume
biggest win there I think that we're
still still around and and also the
Canada finally like got exposed for the
lying [ __ ] that they were back in
april/may that was probably the biggest
win for the industry to I want to ask
when you say when you talk about
genetics being the next wave or whatnot
is that in terms of patenting them are
people gonna run into problems trying to
have proprietary is it all gonna remain
it's kind of somewhat open source for a
while for the most part there's always a
few proprietary outliers but what do you
think how many types of potatoes are
there in Peru is kind of like my
question of that right how many types of
potatoes will Monsanto let you grow well
not a good example currently and that
like a phosphate thing not that good of
an idea I'm at least on their breeding
side the US is very different than other
countries think about Driscoll's
breeders rights it's not about sometimes
owning the genetic it's like having
certain varieties and having licensing
agreements with offtake agreements for
said strawberry so like here I'm gonna
give you these strawberries for 8% you
can pay me and then I get first right of
refusal back on all your strawberries
I'm putting my little boxes but you're
like dirty and I'm gonna fight pests and
put up yellow sticky traps and like
greenhouses to grill my strawberries or
raspberries that's on an international
side breeders rights in the United
States it's challenging because we think
my og cush are my cookies are my animal
cookies crossed with this blue dream
awesome like Kiev are straight and
variety they're awesome but when you get
deep down into it it's the API back to
pharmaceutical ingredients that are
important and even if it might bridey's
not as good as yours by the time you
extract it and put it into a product
other than certain concentrates it
doesn't matter
it's like certain constant like that's
we're getting to like this thing called
chemistry so it's yeah it's hard as hell
people don't go around being like I'm a
dank corn farmer and I love that side
and like that's I that that that's where
it all came from but the sad thing is a
lot of people are gonna get just screwed
long term when it comes to growing
certain varieties that they had
licensing agreement with but in the u.s.
variety spreads so so quickly it's so
hard
keep a little cutting or tissue culture
so I think for most individuals they
want two problems for using it it's just
for the big things where they're pulling
out specific things that those
protections are really valuable
yeah the [ __ ] is already protected
that already but the plants everywhere
now so it's alright more questions
that's it here's educator did you want
to be on this particular subject it's a
big landscape out there I've seen a lot
but no matter what you're doing in the
space it matters this is
once-in-a-lifetime we can create an
industry that matters that people care
about and it can be impactful and super
profitable but it's not just these
buzzwords anymore that you can follow
behind and think you're gonna have a CBD
company and take over the world like
that was really fun but like the more
unique ones we keep seeing like it's
barely begun and it's gonna be huge it's
just most of the people it's like the
curve of dissolution right now like same
thing with the stock market tech was
cool tech got really cool but no one
actually did [ __ ] all the things crashed
who did survive like we're on that
downward but it's City on a curve though
it's getting larger like the volume
demand so it's just it's this moment
where if you can figure out what's gonna
survive and what's gonna be real it's
not some new IP tracking software for
plants like there's this thing called
agate has that already so or it's not
like some blockchain we're gonna do seed
to sale like it should exist in all
these other markets so they're just
gonna buy the winners scale into that
and use when you have a problem outside
industry solutions and cater them for
this you don't have to buy a thirty
thousand dollar bucking machine you can
cut some you know steel like food grid
and like shut through it depending but
yeah there's a lot of opportunities to
stay diligent and know the rules I think
that's the most important thing I could
leave you with the compliance side
otherwise your businesses will fail and
never happened so really appreciate the
opportunity to share fresh back from
Colombia one more time Miki's Li muchas
gracias por su tiempo stick your order
yeah all right
yo hablo espanol