here to talk about the emergence of
global cannabis Brands because that's
going to be an interesting thing uh we
have a great a great panel from all over
the world and to lead us in this she's
the co-founder of the global cannabis
Network Collective uh they do great work
and they throw great parties put your
hands together and welcome Jill
reddish everybody
else m
hello everyone we go with the mic all
right uh as my panel comes to take their
seats thank you for being here again
after lunch uh we have a really exciting
discussion planned for you all today and
actually to get started I want to do a
little audience interaction first so um
than to yourself if you have a favorite
cannabis brand picture it in your head
picture the logo the color all that um
so okay so raise your hand if you
actually have a favorite brand raise
your hand if you have a favorite brand
few people in the room now keep Your
Hand raised if there is a cannabis leaf
in The
Branding just a few ra hands raised okay
uh now keep your hand or put your hand
up if you live in a new market uh only
about 2 to three years okay interesting
so we have people from sort of all over
the market Evolution here so um as we
get into the panel some of those
questions will make a little bit more
sense uh so to kick it off um ASO said I
am Jill reddish I am the co-founder of
the global cannabis Network Collective
we are a private executive network uh
for international cannabis companies we
create connections all across the supply
chain uh we also do a lot of um thought
leadership for our members uh my
background is in marketing and
communication so it's a really nice
Synergy um that being said I'm excited
to ask my panelist to ruce themselves
because they all have really incredible
backgrounds that I didn't want to
accidentally screw up to be
honest so here to my left Jamie Pearson
please will you give yourself a brief
introduction with your back hi everybody
uh my name is Jamie Pearson I'm the
founder and president of the New Holland
Group which is a global consultancy and
I specialize in helping Brands and
companies that want to cross borders and
I think my claim to fame is that I ran
the global brand and bang which is known
for our
award-winning um 11 Time Cannabis Cup CH
uh in infused chocolate um and uh know a
little bit about cannabis branding and
the challenges of Crossing Borders so
companies hire me to save money and time
by make uh not making avoidable
mistakes thank you wow I'm Lauren um
what can I say um you're you're the
Cannabis God I'm the Godfather of
cannabis um I took the first cannabis
company public in the world in
2004 and I'm probably best known for
three cannabis companies um that I sold
one in
2017 called synopsis one in 20 sorry
2016 synapsis 2017 Kronos and in 2018 it
so Tokyo smoke the combin of the three
were a
unicorn and um uh my passion and mission
in life is to make the world a better
place through cannabis and design
excellent excellence and currently I'm
the chairman of a company called can
Global and we have Partners all over the
world in the Cannabis business um
specifically uh choco my friend Cedric
and Jeremy um and we have Partners
pretty much in everywhere in the world
today and we're building the probably
first Global cannabis
company and just to add in uh I
appreciate how you kept it focus on the
Cannabis experience but of course you
have a very extensive amazing branding
experience outside of cannabis with a
lot of consumer and Retail Brands as
well so amazing I I I'm for just for
interest I grew up in The Branding
business and um uh my father was in the
clothing business so I learned how to
build Brands early on and I'm An
Architect by training and really the
design Excellence is the key to building
a brand um and and uh Tokyo smoke it was
the name it was the community it was
design and it really was telling the
world that we were going to be the
Starbucks of
cannabis love that thank you Lauren and
next up Alex well that's easy to
follow hi my name is Alex pransky um
co-founder and uh operator of the higher
Circle which is a cannabis uh brand
support agency if you will we help
Brands uh figure out optimization of
their supply chain um resources and
branding and developing products um
before that I was uh one of the builders
and operators of a few early brands in
California um and really just a early
participant in the regulated cannabis
Market thank you all right and
naris hi thanks Jill
I'm from I'm naris tesler I'm from
Israel I made it here it wasn't
[Applause]
easy we had to fly through laa and then
we got to Vina and finally got to Berlin
the medican group is a an Israeli
cultivator we have an indoor cultivation
facility that's basically a high-tech
facility uh we started um with our first
brand was named seven seven is a purely
medical brand when we launched seven the
whole industry was just about tons of
products and we realized that if we're
going to make it here we have to really
do a good job of branding that it was
time for the industry to be branded so
we launched our first product looked
totally different from any other product
in the market and that's what made it
survive um we have brand recognition and
the fact that you when you see our
packaging then you see that it's
something different and you got to stand
out because you know guys we can't
advertise we have to find a way to stand
out so that's our first brand it's it's
seven it's an established brand in
Israel it's known for being premium
medical cannabis that doesn't uh
compromise and it's a brand you can
trust having said that two months ago
based on our reputation with seven we
launched our new brand called Solo solo
is a brand for the connoisseurs of
cannabis has sexy genetics that are
brought to the fullest when we put them
in the genetics we buy from We Bought
from overseas and we grew them in our
indoor cultivation facility so it really
brought out the very best of these
really sexy genetics now the power of
branding is that once we had our brand
when we went to the pharmacist B2B and
they knew that we were name that they
could trust then they just without even
trying they bought out all that we had
so that's a power of branding and I'm a
really really big believer and now we're
ready to go go out of Israel
yes thank you naris um we're going to
circle back to you a little bit more to
dive in more in just a minute and of
course we are here to talk about the
evolution of branding and how that can
work um across the global supply chain
so first I just want to level set for
everybody here and kind of Define a
brand a little bit my favorite
definition of what a brand is is is what
people say about you when you're not in
the
room and so Brands include both hard and
soft attributes hard attributes kind of
being that logo the colors what does the
packaging look like what is the actual
product of course and then also those
softer attributes the personality the
emotion that it evokes in you uh so
we're going to hear more about that from
these amazing panelists and to Circle
back naris you you began to touch on the
two brands that you have and began to
delineate them tell us just a little bit
more about that dig in a little bit more
um and if you could give us kind of a
timeline of how long did it take for
these things to to develop because a lot
of folks go to digital marketing
agencies and say design me a logo throw
it up on a website and we're good we
have a brand it's a lot more complicated
than that so much more complicated first
of all you have to make sure that you're
branding what you want to Brand you have
to make sure that one message that makes
gives you the unfair advantage that
that's what's getting across so we
started with the packaging like I said
you know in our in our Market we can't
add advertise we don't have a lot of
room to do anything so we started with
the
packaging we were lucky because the
packaging really stood out and we had
really good genetics even from day one
but we were extra lucky because our our
signature product was perfect for Israel
PTSD now when you have a product that
works for PTSD in the in the the in the
the patients right back to you and say
this is doing well it's it's it's
helping me with with my condition it's
not making me paranoid I can continue
doing my work with using this product so
this one product is what really got us
off the
ground that 3 years later one product is
not enough if we hadn't built it into
our brand when we when we introduced the
other products we have a total of six
products in the uh in the seven brand so
when we launched each product because we
had already branded the the concept then
the other products just rolled right in
and they knew what to expect from the
product and that's the power of the
brand so we took time but cannabis time
um I know in in the in the other world
the rest of the world that we most of us
came from takes a lot longer to build a
brand but for for the Cannabis industry
everything is is on high speed so it
took time but but not that long when we
launched our solo brand it was like that
um because we had the reputation of the
seven brand uh so so one one actually
complemented the other you're creating
an ecosystem exactly and then I just
give the audience a little bit of an
update on the medic the the market there
in Israel um some medical markets
patients don't really get to have a
choice in what they're they're you know
getting from their pharmacists so can
you ex uh just give us a little
explanation there sure well Israel's
Market is going through Rapid change
surprise surprise um on the 1st of April
we have a new reform that went into
effect it's a it's a growing reform it
take about a year before all of it goes
into effect but what happens initially
is that until now you had to get a
medical license once you got a medical
license then you would go and have your
prescription the prescription would say
which category you can use how much THC
how much
CBD and um and you could go in and look
at a menu of of a drugstore look at the
menu and decide what product you want
out of that uh those categories one
difference which is pretty
made a huge difference is that the first
time you go in and the first product you
can get had to be from the category
there was one by oneon-one THC balance
THC CBD and that changed the market that
one
little they they wrote it about this big
in the regulations changed the market
because as someone coming in they had to
have something that wasn't this how much
THC can I can get can I get so that made
a huge difference in the market and and
the way the market uh behaves
and um in this new the new regulations
that are coming
through you don't have to have a license
you start you just go to your
professional the person who treats your
condition and he can write a
prescription that's exciting so we
expect the market will really really
grow really really fast yeah the market
Evolution there is something that I want
to Circle back to um but first I know
that you're looking to expand and I want
to uh hear from the panelists a little
bit about what to look for and expanding
with different brand partners and Alex
if that's something that you could take
cuz I know you have a lot of experience
growing from different markets Southern
Southern California Northern California
and east coast of the us all quite
unique markets right now so uh if you
could share some of your comments sure
sure um I think you know when you look
at expanding a brand you've already
established yourself in whatever your
base Market is and so you have hopefully
some
efficiencies you know in that time in
your supply chain and I think that's one
of the most important things that can be
overlooked when you're expanding into a
new market is you have to understand
that a new market there's probably a lot
of new operators it's hard to know who
is let's say experienced and has
different skill levels so it's very
important to vet all of the different
operators in the market know who your
partners are in your supply chain before
you get to too far along because
obviously small problems can become big
ones along the way very quickly um so
just understanding your business model
and who you're going to be getting into
business with in that market and um
knowing that your retail outlets you
know as you expand are going to you know
be viable and accept your branding and
your products yeah yeah thank you for
outlining those things for us and now
actually Lauren I'd love to hear from
you and if you could share a little bit
of the back ground about Tokyo smoke the
evolution there and I think as you share
that story we'll hear the evolution of
the market and the kinds of things that
Alex just just touched on but Lauren if
you could share the story about Tokyo
smoke it's hard to do that in a few
minutes but um we started out to build a
global brand it wasn't about building a
um it was really about building a Global
brand and um it was very much about my
DNA that I'd spent already 30 years
building my brand which um was part of
the DNA of Tokyo smoke and we sold Tokyo
smoke in 2018 if you go into a Tokyo
smoke store today it looks exactly the
same way it looked because our DNA was
so strong I think our success was
building a community from day one we
were a education retailer and one of our
Great Tricks was you know give us your
email address and we'll send you a pack
of rolling papers I think we sent out
probably 25,000 packs of rolling papers
and that started to build a community
and then I started traveling around the
world and meeting with kings queens
Prime Ministers heads of state and the
CEOs of the largest companies in the
world telling them out how we were going
to change their lives and that stuck
Tokyo smoke stuck everywhere we went and
even today it's still the I think the
most notable brand in the Cannabis
industry except
bang which Speaking of Jamie will you
outline the history of bang for us as
well and and you know illustrate for the
audience the journey that bang has gone
through with with Market Evolution as
well you know was it starting out with
everybody really wanting the highest THC
and then you know where we know um well
the first thing I want to say is um
people often confuse products with
Brands oh yeah that's I I brought
laurena bang chocolate um allegedly
um people confuse brands with products
and a brand is not a product and that
happens a lot and I also think people
confuse companies with Brands and those
two things are not the same either so um
bang was a it started out as a product
it was a chocolate bar and uh when it
started out we're talking about 2010 you
could buy a brownie that would have in
Sharpie on a Ziploc bag one gram of
cannabis was used to make this brownie
and the founder of bang who was a master
choler said this is medicine this is
crazy we have to elevate um so that
people could actually know how much
cannabis they were going to get so fast
forward
um bang was known for its logo it was
known for its tagline it was known for
its packaging all of those things but
what what I did when I came in they
hired me to expand the brands when I got
there we were in California when I left
we were in seven states Canada and I
took our CBD brand prior to novel Foods
into uh Europe uh what I did is made
sure that we were speaking with one
unified voice and the one because a
brand voice is super important um and so
the one thing that I had a mandate from
the CEO who was the CEO before I took
over was we're not going to use the
obvious bang as sex cuz imagine all of
the things bang well bang often
everybody wanted to use bang as sex we
did not want that to be our our brand
voice um he wanted he said this this
plant is female I have a daughter I want
to I want to be proud when people talk
about bang I want them to be talking
about quality I want them to be talking
about different things so we made sure
that our brand voice spoke to a
particular audience so what I did is I
actually head hunted a brand expert um a
brand expert in voice and if you guys
raise your hand if you know the brand 19
crimes
wine okay so short story I went in the
grocery store on a way to a birthday
party I bought a bottle the Checker made
me stop what I was doing made everybody
go to another line and showed me the
augmented reality of how to make that
label come to life uh using the living
wine label app and I thought how did
this person turn the Checker in the
grocery store into a brand ambassador so
I called A girlfriend of mine that does
head hunting in the wine industry found
the woman that did that brand head
hunted her and she became my my head of
brand um and so she smart yeah um the
brand voice of 19 crimes she modeled
after Jax from sounds of Anarchy and she
said women who are 35 buy wine that's
the our biggest buyer and it was cheap
Australian wine and I need to get the
women that are you know between 28 and
36 you got to know your demographic who
are you talking to with your voice I
need those women to buy my brand I'm not
going to talk to them in their voice I'm
going to be aspirational everybody
wanted to have sex with Jack from Sons
of Anarchy so I'm going to talk to them
in the bad boy voice that's how 19
crimes was uh was built and it was that
voice so when you think about it every
bottle as a criminal the whole thing was
about crime and the voice was the voice
of a criminal that's it it doesn't
matter you don't have to speak the voice
of your customer you have to speak to
your customer and she did she and I did
the collab together with Jim balushi um
and and it was a fun project and he came
here and talked about it a couple times
so the evolution went all the way full
circle but our biggest issue I think in
glowing Going Global was making sure
that we didn't use any false friends
it's called so I'll just give you one
example and then I'll turn the mic over
clar
did a product in Germany that was a
curling iron that would give off little
steam and they called it a Mist stick
now in German the word Mist means
[ __ ] and shtick you know what shtick
means right so they named their curling
iron a [ __ ] stick and that's the type of
mistake that Brands make when they don't
understand how to cross cultures so one
of the things that I did having lived in
Europe and America for the last 30 years
is I made absolutely sure we didn't make
any of those missteps there's a lot to
it and Alex talked about supply chain
supply chains after your Brand's been
built but he's right you've got to make
sure your brand Works across supply
chain and those are some of the you know
the voice uh just some of the basics and
so I learned a lot of that the hard way
in the Cannabis
industry I was going to just add that I
think the clearer you are about your
brand and what it is the easier it is
for people to accept and I think a
moment for us was when my son said to me
we're going to be the Starbucks of
cannabis and we were in a conference
like this and there were two slides and
he showed Tokyo smok's logo and he
showed Starbucks logo and that stood in
everybody's
mind that makes a mark and also
everybody in this room knows what it
means to be the Starbucks of something
right so that's almost the epitome of
branding right there I think today um
we're building choco and choco is going
to be the soo Soho House of cannabis so
we want to get it early in somebody's
mind exactly what we're going to be so
they know it and they get it and they
associate it's easier with a frame of
reference yeah exactly now um I want to
turn to talk a little bit about uh where
a market is how to know uh where your
Market is what kind of audiences that
we're going to talk that you're going to
talk to obviously regulations play an
important role of what you can and can't
do there's always workarounds there's
always loopholes so I'd love to hear I'm
going to just throw this out whoever
wants to jump in uh let's you know let's
focus in on Germany of course the
cultivation model right now uh there's a
lot of things you can't do we're going
to find out a lot more about what people
can do as we see people do things and
take risks um I'd love to hear from each
of you what excites you what kind of
opportunities do you see for here in
Germany for
Branding naris you want to go first I'm
going to let one of you guys start
because I don't know enough about the
brands in Germany I'm looking forward to
learning about them you're here doing
market research oh absolutely love it
well I'll jump in on that I think uh on
the rec side of things uh with the
social club model um the regulations are
nebulous so from an American standpoint
uh that's why open and like you know and
the Germans are going to say you can't
do that it says it has to be uh
nondescript well describe non descript
we haven't done that very well so I'm
going to exploit that to the ends of the
Earth and what I anticipate will happen
with the social club model is my Social
Club is better than your social club and
it's going to be like the football team
concept and you're going to have Brands
so that when you send flower out the
door uh the companies want you to know
where want people to know where that
flour came from because when you think
about 25 grams is what you can have on
your on your person when you're out in
public that's 25 one gr joints that's a
lot of weed I mean who needs 25 joints
in their pocket at anyone okay okay fair
enough fair enough but if I got 25 1 G
joints in my pocket and they're they're
packaged in a brand we we know that
they're going to end up in other
people's hands and that's how you're
going to start building a brand and I
think on the consumption side on the
social side we're going to see branding
and I think I think they're going to be
Germans who are going to take those
risks too on the medical side that's
what I'm excited about because I do
think uh the majority of cannabis in the
US is used for medical reasons sleep
pain anxiety cramps whatever it is and I
think it's going to be used medically
also in Germany but people are going to
want the government to reimburse them
they're not going to want to use their
disposable cash cuz why would you why
would you go to a social club and spend
a bunch of money when you can just have
the government pay for it and I think
it'll get there maybe not initially but
eventually and I think that there's an
opportunity for brands in the medical
side of things and that's really where
I'm focused and what you said about the
uh Social Clubs being kind of the first
to jump out and brand I think is pretty
accurate like in the US we have a lot of
retailers moving to branding themselves
and putting their brand into people's
pockets as opposed to selling somebody
else's and um you know I think there's a
lot of creative leeway as you said for
Social Clubs to find ways and especially
as you're bringing a lot of people from
the Cannabis Community together for you
know it's all it's already there but
bringing them in a place where you know
now there's a stamp that says this is
legal people are going to be more open
and willing to conversate and you know
talk about what they like in the market
and what brands stick out to them and so
I think it's a great opportunity for the
Social Clubs to be the first to take
that leap cannabis people are workaround
people that's who we've always had to be
and we'll find a way oh we'll find a way
and cannabis people also really care
about where their weed comes from what
goes in it you know who's growing it um
Alex you've had a lot of experience with
that with humble's finest in the
California Community can you tell us a
little bit about the market there and
the appetite for people to know who's
behind their brand and how it's grown
and things and that sure yeah it um in
California it took a little while to get
people interested in where their weed
came from um and even today you know I
think at least in in the legal Market
where we're the legal Market
conversation with Bud tender and you
know information on the packaging yeah
absolutely and um you know one thing we
learned very quickly when retail became
super abundant is your butt Tender Is
your best point of access to your
consumer you know you get to as a brand
have these very short quick moments with
consumers to try to educate them and you
know you have to have very concise
powerful messages in order to really
make it stick in their mind because
their kids in a candy store you know
there's loud packaging all around them
and you know a lot of like buy this half
off and you know it's very hard to
really get their attention to something
valuable and so when you have a bud
tender that's excited and educated on
your brand as she mentioned with the 19
crimes wine like they sent everyone to
the other line just to talk about it and
so when you can find and it's going to
be different in every market and even to
a degree every store you know what
excites that Canabis Community the bud
Tender Is the Catalyst for all that yeah
we actually at bang had um a two-tiered
marketing strategy we had a a direct to
consumer marketing strategy where we
spoke to our consumers but then we had a
bud tender strategy and it was all about
putting swag in their hands and and
educating the bud tender about bangs so
that when the clientele that bought
chocolate wasn't usually the 24-year-old
male um our clientele were people that
wanted to usually use it for sleep so it
was an older demographic um and getting
Bud tenders excited about chocolate was
really hard um so we had we did a lot of
things we did collabs with flower Brands
and pre-roll Brands where we would give
away other brands pre-rolls and flowers
so we could get the bud tender to sit
still and listen about the chocolate so
when older people came in they would
actually know something and that was
actually really effective so you also
have to understand sometimes you have a
gatekeeper and you got to get around
that gatekeeper so that was why we had
to have two strategies and I'm hearing
with that that I just want to point out
the the market Evolution kind of follows
this typical pattern of people a market
launches first and people really want
flower they want High ATHC and once they
kind of get that okay then there's more
we're more curious about other um other
consumption methods like chocolate so
that creating that direct Bridge is a
really effective strategy and naris I'd
love to hear from you if there's
anything uh different or tactics that
that uh you have implemented for the
Israeli market for the consumer
education the pharmacies Etc well of
course just as Jamie said we have two
audiences we have those who are selling
the product and we have to Market to
them just as if they were the target
audience while at the same time we're
targeting our actual target audience but
um it's hard it's hard because we're not
allowed to advertise we're not allowed
to say that our product does what it
does and we're in a medical cannibus
market so um we've we found that um one
way to educate the customer and this is
important the customer doesn't know what
it is he needs to do to do what to make
the Cannabis work for him we found that
was very important so we put put
together a a podcast um which I gave but
wasn't obviously seven because we're not
allowed to do that so I just gave a
podcast about cannabis sponsored by
seven and uh and we gave work around
yeah you just have to find a way to do
it it took off really well uh we talked
about the regulations what you need to
do to get a
license once we bought in doctors and
say I have a specific medical condition
what do I need to do what cannabis
there's so much out there how do I know
what to start with so we brought on
doctors and I would interview them I
would make sure that they gave as much
information as they could very short
podcasts people don't have a a large
attention
span tip very smart the brand name is
seven so what was the podcast seven
minutes so you got you got to make sure
everything is branded and um you have to
get around you have to get around the
the regulations you have to get around
what's allowed and what's not allowed I
think you said something before that
really matters is that strains
matter and that's what matters and
strange cares abut so strong because if
your strain stands for something then
you don't have to advertise they know
the strain and everybody sorry and
everybody knows the strain they like I
said strains win and every place the
strain wins and whatever that strain is
that when the cop or whatever it is is
that's what everybody wants and I would
say our success is that we have the
largest strain library in the world
whether it's Californian whether it's
land race whether it's Canadian and
that's what will win across all markets
will be your strains in in the flower
segment for sure and I think to nisa's
point um you've got to remember that in
Emerging Markets the people that are
going to walk into the dispensary are
the ones that have the courage to walk
into the dispensary uh with the stigma
being as strong as it's always been it's
sort of like walking into a massage
parlor uh people don't want to have
their car in the parking lot they don't
really want to walk in and when Alex is
talking about all the branding being
loud I imagine my mom walking in and
going oh my gosh like not a kid in a
candy store wanting to run in the other
direction um that my mom's probably
going to be wave four you're going to
have the the young people who are like
yes coming in first the the evolution of
education has to um evolve with the
evolution of the um consumer that's
going to walk into that store and what
happens to Lauren's point is at we're
seeing this in California now weeds like
wine there uh some people like P Noir
some people like svon Blanc people start
developing a taste they know what they
want and you need the strain Library if
you're in the flower department to
really appeal to the developing tape
because people become very sophisticated
in their cannabis palet exact so that's
that's true obviously for for
recreational Cannabis but for medical
cannabis is just is true and that's not
what a lot of people don't understand
because one strain can be wonderful for
me if I have a specific indication and
can do nothing for the person sitting
next to me who needs something different
and the education has to get out there
and it's just um it's difficult they're
not helping us out getting that
information out there so we have to find
a way around it exactly helping
consumers understand what kind of
questions to ask the benefit of being
able to smell the strain yourself so
that your nose knows and you have your
own reaction there now we're we're uh
winding down on time so I do want to
leave it open for questions so start
thinking of those and we have some mics
in the back of the room and uh I think
we have a mic uh for closer up front so
I have one last question for my
panelists it's a fun one while everybody
is thinking of their questions they want
to ask um
branding and marketing there's crazy fun
creative ideas out there I feel like you
have all been pitched some crazy ideas
for marketing and branding I want to
hear from you what's some of the
craziest ideas that have come up in the
in the brainstorming room and have any
of them
worked I'd love to start there so you
guys uh Sasha Sasha can you get that out
sausage in uh in Hebrew is called
cabanos what does that sound like
cannabis so our advertising agency came
out and said you know what we're not
going to advertise medical cannabis
we're going to advertise medical
cabanos medical sausage exactly but when
you say when you say it sounds like
cannabis so we took a local standup uh
very famous standup comedian and he went
on on this really Posh
commercial with a sausage and he's just
talking about
Association that you can imagine what
they are with a sausage and uh having a
good time with it genius I love it play
because I gets everybody talking about
it it get it got viral very very
quickly and it got us out there in a
minute you can't forget that sausage now
that's not really I I was a bit worried
about that I don't want to be associated
with sausage we're talking about a
connoisseur label with phenomenal exotic
genetics and we're talking about sausage
but it worked it work some people say
that we had uh people coming up saying
on on the on the Facebook and all the
all the other the
um the people who came and had something
to say about it said you know whoever
that marketing director is they need to
fire
her but but if they're talking about you
you're not in the room it worked yes
brilliant um all right do we have any
questions from the audience any hands
raised we have let's hear for Michael
can running all up and down
yay Michael
woo I could use this mic oh yeah should
be for the effort I want thank you thank
you um thank you for the super
interesting conversation I really
enjoyed the all the knowledge and
sharing uh my name is ying I'm the COO
for troll master in Europe um we do
automation for all different kind of
grow facilities and we have a a good
problem that I would like your expertise
on we get a lot of positive feedback
from users um who have used the product
and who who share the feedback could you
share a bit more about how you what the
best way would be to utilize that uh
that feedback we get from the community
and put it into our branding um we have
a few brand ambassadors but it's very
traditional is there any expertise you
could share from your side to to kind of
you know have better ideas thank
you sure uh I would say just you know
building Brands throughout the years and
kind of having to change and evolve as
the consumer Market matures it's really
important to make sure that you're
getting a wide range of feedback and
it's not small Pockets I think something
that you know a few of my Brands and I'm
sure others in the market have dealt
with is you get one brand rep coming
back to you like oh somebody didn't like
the product and but they say it as
people don't like the product and then
if you're not really diving in and
actually getting um real data from the
market back and then getting that from a
wide range you're potentially going to
isolate these single cases of hey we
need to make this change or that change
but you know the General market might
feel a different way so I think you know
just making sure that you are thorough
in that analysis and that you're able to
communicate directly up the chain with
like true data from the market is really
important we just had a conversation
last night about the fact that uh Tik
Tok is really it's really what's what's
coming the up the generation that's
coming up uh they're into Tik Tok and
that's that little short burst of
information so if you ran a Tik Tok
campaign where you were able to get some
of those
um testimonials on video and you could
have your brand with the testimonial so
the Tik Tok campaign or the T um
Snapchat campaign or the insta campaign
is just testimonials I did this product
I loved it it was amazing uh word of
mouth is really powerful and you're
basically putting the word of mouth
right out into the market yeah you can
do so much with testimonials you can
make sure that you choose those ones
that you want to highlight that really
highlight The Branding that really get
that message out the most important
thing you want get you want to get out
there make sure that's what you use in
the
testimonial I would also add that when
you are very crystal clear on your
target audience you know what matters
and what doesn't matter as much so as
long as you're very crystal clear on who
you're trying to reach you know the 65
and up crowd is going to have different
feedback care about different things
than the 20 to 30 year old crowd right
as long as you're focused you'll you'll
be okay and time for a very last
question here
please oh hello uh I'm here representing
Isabella Palazo from Italy's Association
for medical cannabis patients and we
would love to know your thoughts on the
Italian cannabis market for medicinal
marijuana we haven't heard so much about
Italy what are your thoughts we're a
branding panel so I'm not really sure
that that's something that we're up here
prepared to talk about it it is an early
Market though so you know be prepared
for what we've talked about here with
the market Evolution um and I think
we're all probably happy to to answer
other questions IND but I would say that
it's huge and nobody's talking about it
we're talking about it we care it's it's
very strict
60 million people something like that
when you can BR lean into what people
love about Italy is probably a good
place to start there's a lot to love
about that country Infuse
gravioli go go find Claudia de Morella
she's working on that very much pesto
infused pesto there we go we're out of
time unfortunately lemons thank you
everyone but thank you so very much
let's here again for the whole panel
[Applause]