all right so our next panel deals with a
very important cannabinoid CBD so the
ABCs of CBD CBD may not be as fun as THC
but it has great medicinal values and
there is a big and growing market for
CBD so I will introduce the moderator
who will then talk introduce the other
speakers he is the CEO of ciske you
sun-grown
vertically integrated cannabis and hip
producer and processor who last year had
a cannabis field and our adult use uh
don't use scanners filled in a hip field
side by side tongue twister there thank
you so give it up for mr. Michael
Johnson thanks everybody so I want to
thank Alex for having us here today and
doing this panel on CBD
I think the CBD opportunity here
nationally internationally but
especially here in Oregon is is a really
special thing we have right now we have
some great experts on the team today
we've got cedar gray CEO of Cisco
sun-grown
Cedars been a pioneer in the Oregon
cannabis industry and in the CBD market
for many years currently sits on the
Oregon cannabis commission and many
other rules advisory committees next
we've got Justin Tom Bay with fight onyx
fight onyx specializes in CBD hemp seed
breeding genetics and their real pioneer
in Southern Oregon who's been working to
sell genetics and cultivate genetics for
companies all around the country last
we've got Aaron Pelle with cultiva law
Aaron's a hemp CBD cannabis specialist
lawyer litigator he's based out of
Seattle but grateful to have him here
for the legal perspective on CBD as many
you know the opportunity with CBD is
massive but there's a lot of confusion
around
compound depends on what lawyer you ask
what expert you ask and often you get a
different answer based on what you can
do what's legal what's not how you can
do it where you can send it where you
can grow it so I'm hoping that we can
give you just you know a rough outline
of how to get into the market how to
approach it and some basic do's and
don'ts so first when I research CBD it's
clear that there's a lot of confusion
around is this even legal on a national
perspective and an international
perspective so Aaron I want to know if
you wanted to jump in and maybe answer
that question is is CBD legal on a
national level that question that's a
it's it's a it's an interesting question
and it's one that no real attorney wants
to put their their name on in its
entirety so it's it's it's about it as
unclear as it could be we have competing
agencies including our Congress who's
essentially attacking the purse strings
to prevent the Department of Justice and
from from doing anything as it relates
to the farm bill Act but the farm bill
act itself was recently this was just a
few months ago and was went to the Ninth
Circuit where they were asking for some
clarity the same kind of clarity that
they asked for several years earlier and
got some clarity and what the Ninth
Circuit came back was a procedural
motion our procedural action that said
that they had lost on on their failure
to present this during the comments
period so they were barred from pretty
much bringing this action and getting
this clarity but they still threw some
clarity in there anyways saying that the
agricultural act did preempt the CSA
which is the controlled substance act so
that was really good news but then the
bad news was that it wasn't it was an
unpublished opinion it doesn't have the
force of law and they literally put in
asterisks next to it saying it was a
memorandum so there's there is there is
an opinion out there that says that it
is but we keep getting a lot of really
negative feedback from the D
and the FDA saying that it's not so it's
about as clear as mud thanks Aaron yeah
it's uh that's a similar answer I've
heard from other attorneys it's uh it's
frustrating that we don't have more
clarity but with what's clear with you
know with cedar and with Justin and many
other companies here in Oregon they are
having a lot of success with CBD grown
in state legal hemp programs one
question I get asked a lot is what's the
difference between hemp and cannabis and
when CBDs involved like what's going on
here where's that line drawn didn't know
cedar do you want to give us just a
little historical background yeah
okay so there's multiple definitions of
hemp
it's very confusing right now for the
consumer in the marketplace I think and
that's because we've got a botanical
definition a historical definition and a
legal definition
botanically speaking well hemp Falls
with all other cannabis in the cannabis
family one of two families and the
excuse me in the cannabis genus one of
two geniuses in the cannabis EA family
hops being the other there's fierce
debate going on right now in the
botanical scientific community about the
exact subdivisions of the cannabis genus
whether indica ruderalis and sativa are
different subspecies are different
species all belong to one species so
that's a current debate but what's clear
is hemp and all other forms of cannabis
fall within the cannabis family and most
of the variation that we see
in cannabis plants throughout the world
is due to thousands of years of human
cultivation local natural selection
pressures combined with humans choosing
the cultivars that they wanted to
propagate and so over the centuries
that's given us a vast array of
diversity within the cannabis family so
that comes to the historical definition
historically hemp most recently has come
to refer to the cultivars of cannabis
that were chosen for fiber for fiber
production and those cultivars had
specific physical characteristics
now however all of that has been muddied
by the legal definition here in the
United States it was started by federal
regulation it's been mirrored by most
states where hemp is a cannabis plant
that's certified to be less than 0.3
percent THC and is grown under the
proper regulatory framework so it has
nothing to do with historical use or
botanical definitions in fact the exact
same plant grown under the ODA oregon
department of agriculture or the olcc
would be hemp or not just because it
grew under a different regulatory
framework so that is the somewhat murky
answer to what is him interesting
interesting
you know we know there's a huge market
for CBD products within the medical
cannabis systems of different states
within the recreational system here in
oregon we at Siskiyou sun-grown sell a
lot of CBD products in the recreational
cannabis system but now we have this
national marketplace and international
marketplace that's starting to explode
with CBD products everything from you
know vape pens and capsules to putting
it in two different food products and I
think the the trends are really
interesting I think Justin I know you've
got some insights you were just at a
show down in Anaheim and I'm just
curious what your thoughts are and like
the evolving trends moving forward with
the CBD marketplace sure this is a
really vibrant market that's it's not
going away it's going to grow rapidly
I think sales this year were estimated
somewhere in the neighborhood of six
hundred million dollars and with the
introduction of the 2018 farm act even
though that's not out of committee yet
it is in fact changing the projections
for market size just a couple of years
ago in 2016 folks who are looking at the
the CBD market and that's only a part of
hemp right and a part of the cannabis
world but the CBD market has been worth
something like two billion dollars two
point one in 2020 well now that's
revised to be twenty two billion dollars
by 2022 so there's the market
forecasters are looking they're seeing
the trends they're seeing that
governments here both state and
federally in the US and internationally
our making room for this and you know
the cannabis industry has as you all
know operated in the gray zone and the
margins for a long time the people here
are entrepreneurs and and risk takers
and so the industry is it's pushing
forward to sort of make the changes that
the regulatory regulatory bodies are
catching up to you in a lot of instances
so I sit on the Oregon industrial hemp
farmers association here in Oregon and
we advise a lot of times the ODA in the
state about what they need to consider
and how to approach regulating the
cultivation of hemp and the aspects of
the byproducts that come out of it so
back to the question sort of is it legal
or not you have a federal authorized
program that lets States set certain
regulatory frameworks here in Oregon you
know we work
under the auspices of this pilot or
research program under the Department of
Agriculture and that's what the the
template is out there for folks so
there's a big distinction right there
suddenly we're able to cultivate a kind
of cannabis that's legally defined as
0.3 percent THC or less and even that
there's multiple interpretations of that
as an agricultural product so here an
organ that means that we can have kids
on the farm we don't have to have
cameras everywhere watching where the
hemp is being grown processed stored etc
right so that already creates sort of a
more streamlined process and a broader
access and you're seeing a ramp up of
production in these high CBD hemp
strains that is is feeding this market
and is going to is literally exploding
in front of our eyes so I do understand
that there's there's a lot of unanswered
questions and a gray area as to the
exact legality and exact mechanisms that
we are supposed to follow in order to be
compliant but it will also say that the
market is is active that the businesses
are operating in at minimum 38 states
right now and that CBD products are
being sold in all 50 states and
internationally we went to Europe last
well earlier this year in the spring and
and hemp cultivation therefore CBD is
just starting to kind of catch up
cannabis cultivation for CBD is just
starting to catch up they've been doing
it for fiber and seed for a long time
same thing in Canada and just went over
to British Columbia for the Pacific Rim
hemp conference there and they have had
something in the neighborhood of 130 140
thousand acres of hemp under cultivation
in the previous year again mostly for
hemp part seeds and some parts for fiber
they're all trying to figure out how to
pivot to CBD production because this is
the lucrative part of the market is
right now and so you know the the market
for even just CBD flower as an
alternative substitute or supplement to
tobacco smoking products in Europe is
huge
so it's a it's a big market there's a
lot of different ways that that you can
participate in the market if you're
involved in in the whole value chain
right and and I think we're just gonna
see a lot of diversification from beauty
and health care products to edibles and
meta bulls and adjustables to to again a
more standard smoking market that is all
happening parallel to the existing
cannabis markets and and infrastructure
that were familiar with
awesome awesome yeah I mean the the
potential is just it's it's amazing it's
really exciting to see all the myriad of
products that are happening all the
markets that are opening up it's it's
clear though that we need support from
our governments both state and federal
to be able to expand this market and
there's a lot of rumblings right now in
the CBD industry about the hemp bill or
the sari the farm bill that's coming up
here in 2018 that's a huge bill I don't
even know how large it is it encompasses
all sorts of agricultural issues in the
United States but I know it's going to
affect the CBD market significantly
Aaron are you able to give us a little
update on the farm bill and where it's
at and how that might affect the CBD
hemp market I made a joke by looking at
my watch earlier because we do it seems
like we do have a kind of a pending
deadline in terms of that coming out
soon by the end of this month mitch
mcconnell's behind it on one side in
legislature so most people believe it's
going to go through whether that's a
good thing or a bad thing kind of
remains to be seen one of the one of the
versions of the bill on one side of the
legislature doesn't allow felons
previous felons to be
involved which really the best growers
of most cannabis if they if they aren't
felons it's a practically a badge of
honor it means you might have been
better at your job than others but
honestly excluding entire groups of
people based on what I consider very
unfair new Jim Crow laws in the first
place are wildly inappropriate when
you're when you're excluding an entire
group of people from being involved in
this market so I I see a lot of problems
with it but the big problem that
everybody should be scared of it also is
is not just consolidation but the
coca-cola announcement like these guys
are telegraphing a whole change in the
market that doesn't include you any of
you unless somebody's from coca-cola
here they're these are gigantic
companies that are coming in that can
deal with the FDA that can deal with
making claims about whether this has
some sort of medical benefit or not and
so every day in some ways I look at this
similar to what I saw in Washington when
we add medical marijuana and that we
have this diversity of people that are
involved in the CBD market that think
that it should be free there's people
that think that it should that are
activists that are involved in it there
are people that are capitalists that are
involved in it but but that that
diversity of opinion means nothing to
the people that would move this forward
because they worship one God and that's
money and so we all have something to
kind of be afraid of because we have
this mom-and-pop sort of effect going on
that it that is questionable whether it
will survive something that's going to
be consolidated under the federal
government one of the versions of the
farm bill act requires that the federal
government does approve any state
program before we're involved before we
can actually implement that state
program so again another fear could be
similar to something that the government
does all the time which is they create a
bill they write something and then they
don't fund it I don't know that that
will happen or not there's a lot of I
consider heavy hitters involved in this
industry that want to see that bill go
through and push forward and see it
funded so but like I say I look at it
with some at least a measure of
skepticism for what happens next
yeah interesting interesting
you know CBD is just it's a compound
right it's it's a cannabinoid so you can
grow it in many systems cedar was one of
the the very first people that I knew
that was growing CBD rich cultivars and
making CBD products in the Oregon
Medical Marijuana Program and then
transitioned and began doing that in the
recreational cannabis program and is now
doing so in the hemp program
I'm curious cedar maybe you want to talk
about what would be the advantages of
going forward with your CBD products in
the Oregon Department of Agriculture
hemp program rather than in those other
state license programs so you have
experience and yeah there are multiple
distinct advantages let's start with
regulatory the regulatory framework of
hemp production under the Oregon
Department of Agriculture is infinitely
less complex than farming under the olcc
requirements that you know reduced
complexity translates to well profits
and happiness and so yeah that's that's
a I mean that that's a huge benefit
right there it ties right into another
great benefit and that's the IRS tax
code 280e horse consult with your CPA
about this but most hemp businesses
considered themselves to be exempt from
280e 280e is a tax code which denies
cannabis businesses most write-offs
resulting in a very hostile business
environment in which its
challenging to turn a profit because
most of the profit is taken by the IRS
comparatively speaking a typical
business run exactly the same way that's
not subject to 280 II might have four or
five times the profit and let's move to
the market place
here in the Oregon cannabis market it's
not news to anybody here that the
markets flooded and prices are at an
all-time low you know that's good news
for consumers consumers and patients so
I don't want to deny that fact I think
cannabis and hemp products should be
cheaper and cheaper forever for
everybody so that is a benefit however
it's a sudden shift the downward price
pressure has been extreme and it's it's
a difficult time in the Oregon cannabis
industry export which has been discussed
on other panels is the Silver Bullet
which will cure those woes but we don't
deal with that at all on the hemp side
hemp is a worldwide market you know hemp
can be well individual jurisdictions are
shifting their regulations regarding
hemp on a daily basis but more or less
hemp can be mail are shipped to every
state and in the United States and
potentially to most countries around the
world so we've got 7 billion people who
can benefit from CBD that we produce
here in Oregon compared to you know 4
million people plus the tourists who
come to Oregon on the cannabis side and
I think the final benefit that I want to
highlight is all of these combined
to create the opportunity to offer
cannabis medicine at a vastly reduced
price to the national and worldwide
market through CBD in some ways I think
CBD is a gateway cannabinoid for humans
because it's not psychoactive people
aren't afraid of it like they are THC so
it's introducing the entire world to the
incredible benefit of cannabis medicine
in a safe and affordable way so that's a
great benefit thank you yeah absolutely
thank you cedar it's it's exciting to
see cannabis medicine like you say
having some barriers pulled down and
allowing entrepreneurs to start to to
tackle these larger markets but Justin I
know you know you've experienced some of
the challenges getting into the CBD hemp
industry firsthand you know it's it
seems so much easier than being a
recreational cannabis entrepreneur or a
medical cannabis entrepreneur but it's
not without its its pitfalls so maybe
you could detail just some of the
challenges that you've experienced or
that people should be ready for if they
plan to enter this market sure I think I
have to you know preface that with this
definitely comes from the perspective
that I'm approaching it from participant
in the the hemp cultivation side of
things CBD is also present in other
forms of cannabis and people are
bringing different strains that can be
one-to-one races or whatnot inside of
medical programs in the state so I'm
coming from the perspective of again
agriculture so now we're dealing with
things that tens of acres or hundreds of
acres or even thousands of acres there
were several thousand acres under
cultivation in Oregon
this year and of hemp almost entirely
for its high CBD content and that is
then targeted for extraction into some
kind of a concentrate that's going to be
used in an end products right so when
you scale up activities like that you
know there's there's all the attendant
capital investments you have to make you
have to
your logistics your cost how you're
gonna get through to the end but there
are certain parts of an infrastructure
you know for this to be a real industry
either statewide or nationally that are
just not there at all yet
and so choices are being made in a
vacuum of clear guidance about the best
way to develop that infrastructure and
and this is in partly the fact that you
know at the federal level our government
is dragging its feet about providing
clarity they're trying to hold on to
this
this bastion of this being a controlled
substance and it needs to be really
firmly regulated for as long as possible
so what does that mean that means if I
want to cure my hemp right or any of our
farmers who gorge a next one cure our
hemp in order to then be able to extract
it they can't go to the the old
tried-and-true methods that cannabis
growers have been using for you know
four decades at this scale it just
doesn't work you can't hang you know
fifty thousand pounds of dry weight hemp
in in a little space and expect that
you're gonna be able to to handle that
on a logistical level so whether it's
from you know the the front side end of
planting irrigating you know cultivating
to the back side end of harvesting
whether to do that you know mechanically
and what kind of equipment is available
out there and then how you're going to
dry cure process to transport all of
that infrastructure is still really in
nascent forms of development so a lot of
people have put hemp in the ground and
then had no clue what to do when it
comes to fall and the rains are starting
to fall and they're trying to figure out
how to get there
their crop off the field and so it does
take a lot of forethought and careful
planning the other thing that you know
we're involved directly if I Thomas with
with breeding and so in order to meet
the federal regulations and grow
something is hemp you have to be
qualified with a variety that is
supposed to mature at less than 0.3 THC
the federal language is Delta 9 THC
which makes our job easier because much
of the THC content at harvest is teal
still THC a but difference which means
that it hasn't been decarboxylated to
become Delta 9 THC but there are some
states Kentucky for example which is
another you know center of a lot of hemp
cultivation right now they apply a
conversion ratio to your THC a and they
say you know 0.87 7 % of that is gonna
be Delta 9 JC so if you harvest too late
in Kentucky
your THC levels will be out of
compliance and by the law you're
supposed to destroy your crop so that
kind of lack of clarity of state to
state to state about Uniform Standards
can leave folks in Tennessee and
Kentucky in North Carolina where we've
been out we've sold our seeds we've
we've been consulting with old tobacco
farmers you know who are trying to make
this transition can leave them really up
in the air and really uncertain as to
how to best proceed lastly I would say
that getting good genetics or good seed
stock to start with can be really
challenging in this and this current
unregulated kind of Wild West state of
the industry I know personally you know
here in Oregon and in multiple states
folks who on good faith bought seeds
that were represented to them as a
feminized hemp strain that would be
compliant and the the aspect of having
feminized seed is important to cannabis
cultivators all around who don't want to
have their fields pollinated by the hemp
field it's two miles down the road
that's 40 acres and just you know went
seed and threw a bunch of pollen into
the wind and and now everybody else's
crop is is seated as a result and in
fact then found out that those seeds
either weren't feminized or weren't
actually compliant hemp or didn't
germinate there are horror stories upon
horror stories upon horror stories out
there so
building relationships doing proper
diligence don't just rely on the word of
a broker just because somebody tells you
something you know you if you're gonna
be involved in this you're gonna have to
dig deeper and you're gonna have to take
the time to do your diligence to make
sure that your fundamental building
blocks that you're working with are good
ones
otherwise you're again gonna have a real
hard time come harvest time yeah
absolutely thanks Justin yeah in any
maturing industry like this there's
there's there's pitfalls left and right
there snake oil salesmen there's
hucksters and I think the due diligence
piece that you pointed out is incredibly
important if you're trying to enter the
market and make you know
business-to-business partners by seeds
all of it is incredibly important so I
think we've we've given a good little
overview but we have these experts up
here and I'm curious if anybody has any
questions out in the in the audience in
Gayo you back there all right man it's
time to work
[Music]
[Applause]
hi I was I was wondering I I assumed
that you guys heard about the DEA
rescheduling 0.1% THC CBD products so
long as they have FDA approval that just
took place yesterday and I was wondering
if you could speak to what effect that
has how hard is it to get FDA approval
what does that look like do mom-and-pop
growers have a chance at making that
happen that's a doozy
who wants to tackle that one well I'd
only say that well I guess it depends on
what kind of mom-and-pop you are so for
example I have a client that's in the
tobacco industry and one of the things
they do is there they get cigars through
and so if you want to do a cigar that
this tall and go through that entire
process with the FDA it's $15,000 and if
you want to do a cigar that's exactly
the same but it's just slightly shorter
it's still $15,000 and up to about 45 so
and then just dealing with the FDA
itself and the attorneys that deal with
it I mean III can't speak to that and
it's uh joyed that it's like asking your
mechanic to take out your appendix
probably not the right guy to do it but
I can't tell you that it's expensive
it's arduous and it does it's going to
take a lot of people out of the market
if that's what they have to do strangely
I mean most people don't really care
what the DEA says and that has a lot to
do with the Appropriations Act which has
been kind of mirrors what's been going
on with marijuana itself which is we've
got the Congress legislature
collectively saying you can't do
anything to any of these people because
we have a hold of your purse strings and
so long as these people are compliant
with the farm bill act and and and the
provisions within and their state laws
you can't touch them and so you have
that at least for a couple more days so
hang in there did you want to maybe just
in the sense that you know this is not
meant to obviously encourage
access or make it easier for the
mom-and-pops operators right in the same
sense that aaron was talking about
consolidation is coming to this industry
the FDA and the DEA are sort of
gatekeepers to try and keep the reins on
as long as possible so this is my
opinion so that the the the Giants and
agribusiness and and Big Pharma
can be positioned to capitalize when the
regulatory framework allows right so the
DEA research licenses are typically with
the universities there they're very
difficult to get so they want you to
partner with an existing University and
then the IP rights that often the that
are part of those deals the university
wants to have a piece of that so that's
one way that they they sort of keep a
clamp on and again yeah this is a very
expensive processes that typically you
have to be a really well capitalized
business to be able to go through to get
these kind of approvals but I would say
that you know on at least an initial
reading of the the versions of the farm
bill 2018 farm act that we see that
there is language that really does
provide some clarification in terms of
you know our ability to access take
things to market derivatives of hemp
beyond just seed and stalk and fiber now
clearly not you know no longer being
part of the controlled substance act I
think this is gonna effectively open the
doors more and I'd say there's a window
of time here there's a there's a few
years whatever that that period of time
is where you know entrepreneurial
startup businesses have you know have a
chance to really make hay and I would
suggest that if you are in that position
leverage the best you can during this
this window of opportunity
yeah hi thanks guys what uh what are the
current barriers to say a CBD edible
being able to sell and transport that
over state lines also internationally
export across state lines regulations
are evolving rapidly but currently it's
pretty much a green light to export
across state lines but that depends on
the jurisdiction that you're exporting
into all of the hemp has to be certified
as approved by the originating states
hemp program and because regulations are
always changing for example California
just banned CBD and food products so you
know it was all of a sudden it's a you
know tremendous hit to all those
companies who were depending upon that
supply chain but so individual
jurisdictions are changing the
regulations rapidly but in general
interstate commerce is open in the
United States for CBD for high CBD
products or CBD only products
yeah and just just to hop in there
speaking is from an Oregon
entrepreneurial standpoint you need to
have a permit from the ODA
if you're if you're just talking about
making that edible you'd want your Oda
hemp handler's permit and then also
you'd want a commercial kitchen license
if you had those two things and if your
end product was below 0.3 percent THC
and and tested by a certified Oregon
laboratory that would be a legal CBD
hemp edible just just to add how goofy
that is in in Washington if you if you
want to put hemp into a product of any
type and you've grown that hemp in
Washington State you have to be licensed
in Washington State but if you brought
some CBDs or hemp from
out of the state and put it into a
product there's no restrictions
whatsoever because we removed it from
Schedule one so under state law so I and
I get that's one to illustrate that
legislators trying to catch up with
their own rules and so there's these
these swinging gates like it like you
were talking about with California where
it's like they were letting everything
in and then there's this knee-jerk
reaction of going the other way and so
we have to be a part of that
conversation and kind of good citizens
if you're in this market you kind of
have a duty to be down there and salem
and at those meetings and at those
discussions about what's going to happen
with these things and be responsible for
for being a part of that there's things
going on with CBD nobody wants to talk
about like when you make a concentrate
what happens with the THC people don't
talk about it cuz there there's other
things going on but the truth is is that
if you sit and continuously concentrate
something there's a concentration of THC
as well and nobody's talking about what
we're doing with that and so if we don't
want this knee-jerk reaction because
some legislature starts up with what
about the children then you need to be
involved to avoid it alright one more
question I think and then we're gonna
break for lunch yeah hi my question
builds on that a bit further a bit
further I extract oil now and have had a
lot of market demand from growing sizes
bulk level people commercial you know
operations wanting to put it in their
micro breweries or what have you and so
I'm curious how you see when they ask me
a say if I'm going to Ohio or something
like that and they asked me that
question they're like okay so we're
gonna put this in our product what are
the legalities of us putting this into
our product and distribute it locally
within our population I know I don't
know if there's an answer for that but I
get asked that all the time so you don't
take that Erin I would only say it's
it's really up to your lawyer and their
lawyer to figure that out and they're
right the memo and they'll charge you
accordingly I mean it's really and it's
the problem what it is is is as I was
saying earlier it's a state to state it
berries we've got 38 states that have
rules on this and a bunch of others that
don't as these guys pointed out it's in
every state no matter where we go
where are they getting it from how are
they doing it but lawyers write memos I
I think that kind of give them and their
clients the kind of coverage that they
need so that they can move forward and
do these things yeah that's the joy
being on the tip of the spear baby yeah
brick-and-mortar establishments are
under higher risk because of their
physical location online commerce you
know check with your lawyer it appears
to be pretty safe but I think in
Nebraska and North Dakota if I recall
correctly a couple of small
brick-and-mortar establishments have
been raided for their CBD products you
know it's a goin 2003 and the cheong
story with the bongs it's like nobody's
kidding I get calls regularly now still
where people are like can I just sell
paraphernalia online it's like well no
it's federally illegal I mean this whole
conference is federally illegal this is
all a big RICO conspiracy to violate
federal law you know so it's it's a
question of where your risk levels are
in doing this and then like you were
saying it's be the change you want to
see so you know I always say only break
one law at a time but really more to the
point it's like if we're going to do
this one thing and this is what we're
doing then show the world how to do it
right and you know that's that's the
figure that's the best I can do with
that okay thank you so much one last
question for real this time because he
was very patient so we're gonna do one
more question and then we're gonna break
for lunch here we go hey guys I think
I've probably met all of you at some
point in time I'm have cascade high
we're a cannabis company here in Oregon
we're obviously looking at CBD market
expansion nationally two major issues
that we've kind of already segue it on
which is are you guys mostly doing CBD
isolate distillate to be able to keep
that THC out or are you just comfortable
when you're doing your processing and in
an extraction if you're moving you know
full-spectrum oil
I assume it's got THC levels in the 3%
area way above the 0.3 and then second
question probably cedar for you more
than anything else do you or actually
Aaron from cultiva do you advise setting
up a secondary company to be moving
those CVE products because of the risk
confusion there with the olcc cannabis
business and any feelings about that
okay so I'll handle the first question
the second one was a legal question so I
won't handle it but okay so for
extraction ciske sun-grown
we base all of our products on ethanol
extracted oil so we're making a crude
oil and there is an in inter that crude
oil will always be above 0.3% THC so
it's not a commercial product for us
there's that's one of the many gray
areas of the law is this intermediate
step where the concentration occurs and
then it's formulated into another
product and diluted below point three
that's a gray area so there's no
concrete answer then it's check with
your lawyer but yeah so so the short
answer is that we you know our crude oil
is not a commercial product except in
the olcc system and all of our
commercial products are reformulated so
that the dilution brings THC below point
three thanks thank you thank you very
very much let's hear it again for the
panel
[Applause]