the
science of cannabis
extraction right it's a science you
don't just wash your hash or get some
tubes in a can of butane and try not to
blow yourself up in the backyard there's
a better way to do it it's way more
Technical and to lead us in this German
YouTube cannabis activist and Pioneer
and legendary I don't even know how you
say legendary cannabis user in German
but I'm sure there's a word for it let's
here for Michael
[Applause]
canot hi hi I hope it was
fun yeah
[Music]
so welcome everybody to our panel of uh
the signs uh about the SS of cannabis
extraction and uh I'm very glad I'm very
proud uh to present you five experts in
Canabis uh extraction uh from yeah
different companies from different
continents and uh let me start to
introduce I will introduce anybody uh by
uh when when he answers his first
question so you don't have to wait so
long for our expertise so my first
question my introduction is uh to Mr uh
to Mr Nick and branos is that right yeah
I I I'm not so good
pronouncing uh so
um you're in the canab business or in
the extraction business quite long in
2009 you founded canab bre which is a
quite uh success successful B2B distrib
distributor and as we all know we're
talking about on the ICBC we're always
talking about two different markets
we're talking about the European market
and we're talking about the US and the
Canadian Market the overseas Market how
we call it um when when it comes to
cannabis extraction what would you say
what are the basic difference because
you are experienced on both sides of the
of the Atlantic so what would you say
which is uh what are the basic
difference between our two markets or
the two
markets uh regulation is more strict in
Europe uh taking care of safety factors
of the extraction methods are much
stricter also documentation and the key
word here is also eug GMP it is there
are factors that they were not they're
not so strong in the US although in the
US and Canada although of course they
are they take good care of safety but at
a different level that we would like to
do it here in the
EU yeah thank you very much and uh this
is uh my next question goes to the next
expert who is also experienced on both
continents
rarez uh you're you're working for your
CEO of a parap uh which is uh located in
Portugal and um what would you say what
are your experiences year mostly because
Portugal is part of the EU and Portugal
only medical cannabis is legal
recreational is still illegal so what
are your experience with especially
European
regulation well the European regulation
actually I think comes for good because
talking about the United States and if
we look say for reports from Bright Labs
I think from 2021 30% of extracts had
high contaminations of pesticides and so
these are the ones that are actually
measured so people that send samples to
be analyz it that is I think a small uh
minery so if we want to to have a safe
Canabis uh usage doesn't matter if it's
medical or if it's recreational in in
Europe so that people can consume
knowing that they are taking a safe
product regulation is absolutely
necessary that's the way to go I'm all
in in terms of uh the regulation it's
only way to
go so when it comes to regulation we
also have to talk about extraction
technique because the better the
technique the P the product is Jorge um
George stf or the doct George stter
sorry stf is that right correct uh uh
he's uh we met this morning and he's in
the German in the in the in the uh us
and also in the European extraction
industry and he introduced me uh a
technique I've never heard of and I'm
really very I'm not too deep but at
least I wrote a book about cannabis
extraction which is available here also
and in German language
and I was really surprised about the way
you do your construction so what's
what's different the way do you uh you
do your extraction from the standard
extraction when we talk extraction we
always have to honor Europe as um where
the extraction is originated so Claudius
galenus in the 100 years ad started
extracting with ethanol and and water
and he documented that for over 50
different herbs and it's uh really uh to
our days um Europe has been operating
based on strict regulations and um
everything that we do into the
extraction space uh we try to make and
improve this extraction they've been
after the like simple methods of
extraction um liquefied gas extraction
was added which is very quick and uh
clean extraction which improves the
purity of the extract regulated by
Pharma so what developed is a next
generation of liquefied gas extraction
that uh Works uh combines the advantages
of all current extractions the ethanol
the butane hydrocarbons the CO2 um and
it's something that delivers a full
power of the plant into ambient
conditions preserving the ph and the
medicinal Valu so that's um um in P five
extraction we've been working that in
the last 10 years uh in the Cannabis
industry and last 20 years into the
fragance and flavor industry improving
that extraction methods thank you very
much George Jonah Jonah Baba we know
quite a long time already he comes from
the consu consumer side of cannabis may
I say so you used to be consumer before
you found before you went into the
business or they say do what you love
and stuff and so I I I did find a lot of
uh early benefits from that side that's
what also drove me to get into the
industry was my passion um just
believing in the therapeutic and uh
benefits of the
plant and so you built up M MX laps in
2013 already which means uh you're in
the lab business and the for in the
extraction business you know ex
extraction you know the products for a
long time
um what would you say the difference
between European extraction which you're
not or what is most advanced what what
what does the consumer search in
in the oversea Market at the moment and
what does the consumer search here on
the European market what what do you
say yeah I I think I think the way I
would look at it is I see I see Europe
where probably like the US was maybe
like 10 years ago is probably pretty
good comparison to where we you when we
started on the analytical lab side which
is really interesting because being at
an analytical lab you're at the
Forefront of products you see everything
that's coming into the lab what's moving
what's popular and I remember back in
2012 when we started the lab all we saw
was flour and then overnight we just
started seeing extracts just flood into
the lab and actually it was very poor
extracts to be honest with you it was I
so badly wanted to like them but I hated
it tasted like burnt popcorn and just
they're adding propylene gly call just
there was Heavy solvent still left in it
it was actually very scary because there
was no solvent uh testing required at
the time and so you were seeing um so
people were doing QC testing but they're
still putting those products out in the
market for medicinal reasons and it was
just very scary so actually what led us
into getting into the extraction side
was based off test results and that's
where we started IMX which is now
decimal which does extraction equipment
But to answer your question so from that
side it was very heavily flower in the
beginning and then it very quickly kind
of evolved into um extraction which was
a combination of Vape pins Edibles
topicals creams and so I think we'll
we'll see that here shortly I think in
Europe I think what people will see is
it'll start slow but then it ramps up
really really quick from that side and
so like just some of the advice I would
give people that are starting out is to
plan for Rapid expansion quickly so
you're not um trying to play catchup or
change a lot of your infrastructure or
things like that as well plan for that
now and also I'd say be versatile from
that side it's going to be very
important to be versatile to the market
especially when it gets to a
recreational side When It ultimately
gets there because the market can be
very finicky and also change very
quickly like what might be popular one
year might be something completely
different than next year and if you're
in a position to essentially be to adapt
quickly you'll be able to grab bigger
market share um a lot faster as well and
so I think you'll just really see the
products as it evolves uh really expand
quite quite
quickly thank you Jonah uh Steve you're
also l experienc in the US cannabis
industry for 12 years uh now you're
working for scii or you founded ccii uh
you're from more from the East Coast yes
correct um as a German um cannabis
activist I always looked on the west
coast um but on the is there
anything different on the east coast is
do you use different techniques over
there or is there a different cannabis
extraction culture because uh yeah I i'
I've all because cannabis New York is
legal now in I've heard and so um yeah
is there any difference in or local
difference in extraction techniques it's
funny to say that I see I'm a CEO of
monzana extracts in New York state and
we're starting an operation there and I
see New York in a very similar phase or
stage to where Europe is right now uh
and and it seems like most countries go
through these stages of early adoption
and then you know ramping up efficiency
and and to Jonah's point I think the
biggest thing uh one of the biggest
things I see here that's very different
both in New York and here versus the
west coast is
scale we see uh people trying to process
one or two pounds at a time in the small
scales which is easy to do with raw and
presses and that type of thing but
eventually when prices drop and they
will uh you're going to need to scale up
so efficiencies of scale take place and
that's where the larger ethanol larger
larger CO2 larger um uh hydrocarbon
machines become more potent uh the other
thing that we're very focused on are
tpes not just the uh extraction of them
but the separation of them and so I
think as this Market evolves there'll be
a big need uh for extra turpine
production and a lot of that will come
from
hemp um the rumor just next question the
rumor in Germany is uh t torped
extracted from hemp are too expensive
what do you agree well I would say that
tpin are too expensive to begin with
because they're ephemeral uh they're
difficult to capture uh in in their
entirety they're difficult to store in
their entirety and keep them unaltered
and most extraction methods and I I hope
I won't offend anybody on the panel by
saying this but um very often uh
techniques like ethanol extraction uh
can destroy those valuable turpins um
CO2 has the capacity to capture them at
a subcritical level uh but but most of
us in the industry who extract would
agree that propanes and butanes uh tend
to be the best at capturing the full
spectrum of tpes uh and the last thing
I'll add to that is that there are new
technologies coming in play right now uh
through membranes that allow you to
separate those tpin from the
cannabinoids and ultimately where this
market ends up if you're really speaking
about medical
cannabis is to get pure constituents
pure THC pure CBD and generally that
involves some form of crystallization so
when we take those tpin out we can then
move towards that crystallization and
then reconstitute or as pharmacists call
it Rec compound to precise Doses and
then we can really start to talk about
medical products okay let
me speak out the
theory um the lower the in point of the
solvent is the better the product is
anybody who once can answer Jorge you
looked at me first absolutely I agree
with that because uh Boiling Point now
the most popular methods are separating
components by boiling points and when
you have let's say I don't know what 80
and your first trip in evaporating at
100 then you don't really have a margin
to separate you're going to end up with
a lot of residual solvent that's why uh
going super subcritical and uh Co 2 or
uh using iosol R134 or using butane
where the boiling point is um close to
zero uh and you have a full 100 degree
of separation you can really preserve
those turpins uh it's very important
also not to destruct and Destroy these
turpins because some of the metals
during heat and uh oxygen it's um
oxidize the turbs and you lose um monot
turs very often because they're the
smallest molecule
and the sience of CHS actually um
if it is uh known by the science that
currently uh the CHS they enhan the
cannaboids uh 50% uh like if they go
into the body they activate the receptor
50% before the cannaboid uh connects to
the receptor um this is recent study
from uh Russo a few months ago and uh
that proves that preserving the full
tpin profile of a plant as it appears in
the strain is going to increase
bioavailability of the same plant not
looking for like water soluble or
anything else the plant by itself
provides you the option for uh better
medical treatment so preserving the T
terpens in a full profile is very
important for um for the medicinal
values of the plant
itself just just to add to that now I'll
start by saying there there's no one
perfect extraction method or one
extraction method that's better than
another it all depends on what someone
wants to make but when we're talking
about turpine preservation and things
like that I think what's really uh
unique and exciting to be able to
introduce to Europe that's been doing in
the US is from a hydrocarbon extraction
standpoint is being able to run fresh
Frozen um and run it and that to get
like the highest tpine content in in
doing that and so um that's some groups
here we're talking about too also which
also changes the cultivation side
because no one's been looking at doing
that over here as well too to how to
properly you know store fresh Frozen get
ready for the extractors because it
really hasn't been an opportunity yet
but in my opinion that's one of the best
ways to get the highest turpine
profile I fully agree but um there are a
new K in Block that is still CO2 but CO2
under pressure and in cogenic
temperatures between 0 and minus 20 here
you can also work with fresh frozen
flowers uh you can even tune if you use
small amounts ofal solvent like ethanol
and other class two solvents that are
allowed for medical and pharmaceutical
applications here you can tune even for
the type of tpin so mon D or
threein and save them with efficiencies
of over
90% with the advantage to other Bane or
so on because when you are using bhan
you always keep
the you always keep these gases sve it
then you have to go to vacuum
applications of vacuum treatment in
vacuum noens to the gas to take the
othery carbon out
but tpin are also volatile so you are
also losing in these process trins if
you are extracting using this CO2 cryo
CO2 method of once you bring to am in
temp temperature is
gone um so at the end the efficiency is
in terms of capturing the pins is higher
and you also can tune this at the same
time this same technique can extract
with efficiencies over 90% cannabinoids
And once again by tuning the the poity
of our solvent that is mixed between the
liquid CO2 and the ethanol or other
class two
solvents you are very selective to what
you are aiming to extract it can be THC
it can be CBD or it can be a
floid uh and the best proof and
fantastic thing about this new
technology is that it doesn't matter if
you are extracting from really bad
starting material like shredded biomass
from flowers and leaves together with 2
3% or if you have hemp with 5 6% or if
you have a 10% flour or a 15 potency
flour 20 or 25 your extracts will be
always over
80% why because you are simply
extracting what you want cannabinoids
leaving most of the other andw
components behind this is really
revolutionary I'm working on instraction
for 35 years uh in CO2 typically
supercal
applications this technique can run in a
super
critical typical system but modified to
have in these conditions and this is
unique uh usually in super critical
extraction you don't get quality and
speed if you want high quality so a very
pure extract you have to go slow low
pressures low
temperatures otherwise you not get
quality High perod with this technique
for the same extractor vessel you are
increasing three to five times the
throughput but keeping an extremely is
not high extremely high quality extract
this is really groundbreaking I think
for me that works on co2 extractions for
over 35 years is the very big step
forward I've seen in over these 45 years
because CO2 on P past in these years
didn't change much so this was a big
Improvement uh that I highly recommend
it so when it comes to CO2 extraction uh
you need a lot of equipment let me say
it uh easily and already the easy way so
in Germany
we'll have cannabis clubs very
soon they're allowed to do
extractions but they are not allowed to
solvent extractions even water hash
though water is not a solvent is
considered a solvent
extractions what would you recommend
them Nick the German cannabis clubs
probably some are sitting here and
listening yeah with regards to water
extraction if it's what would you
recommend if you have a Canabis Club you
produce Canabis for 500 people yeah uh
and uh you want to make extraction but
you're not allowed to do solvent
extraction and you're not allowed to do
water hash what would you recommend a
driving Club you cannot do solvent and
you cannot do water extraction exactly
so I guess you can press it we can press
it uh here we can make make anything
which is mechanical yeah in a water in a
way in a way water extraction is
mechanical extraction in a way exactly
but because we don't have experts who
are in response of the law they consider
water extraction as a solvent extraction
we try some uh some people from the
Cannabis industry try to explain try to
Lobby that water has is not a solvent ex
it's not it's nons solvent but you know
they don't understand it's considered
mechanical separation in a way it's like
yeah but they don't understand for the
not it's also because it's dangerous you
know it's it's not a low oniv level
because it's dangerous for example in
Colorado and they just didn't understand
that you know that's because we only a
lot of lawyers made it but there were
not too many cannabis experts uh when it
came to the law so that's the problem so
I guess there are not many options left
CO2 I guess it's out of the picture as
well yes so what are we left with it's a
GI paper static yeah imagine that could
be so you have to extract for 500 people
every month
and could be a solution I guess it's
it's a way of extracting with no
solvents with using heat and evaporating
the oils out of the plants and then uh
collecting them again I guess that could
be but then again you need very big
systems for the small size of the Social
Clubs it becomes very narrow the options
if you are talking about small amounts
with small systems I guess making ke and
pressing it should be a way that is
mechanical purely and uh it can it can
work for sure but on a
level anybody else can answer please on
a level where you make it for 500
people uh would you agree to say that's
not economical at all if you cannot do
solvent
construction I agree to that because um
when you use sifting you only rely on
the Tricom and there is much more
potency inside of the plant you use
probably 30% of the uh entire cannaboids
into the plant and any mechanical
extraction is not selective so your
quality of the extract it kind of May
Vary a lot and I completely understand
their decision of trying to put the
water into the solvent because once they
say water is legal then uh or uh good
for like solventless immediately two
other metals going to get in that the
steam extraction steam distillation and
and superheated water extraction
superheated water extraction is a
special type of extraction which also we
produce uh that can make water to behave
as ethanol and you really can get a very
good extract out of that too so uh maybe
they have this concern when they uh try
to classify um harush Bubble extraction
but still sifting and pressing or
pressing even without sifting but then
you're going to end up with some
chlorophylls and some uh other things
that you don't really know that don't
really want into will influence the
taste very interesting because water
water steam extraction I wrote my book
four years ago and I announced in the
last chapter that steam extraction is
the future but there was no steam
extraction at that time um Bo what do
you say about steam extraction because
this is very very interesting in in my
eyes because uh it's under hot steam
under pressure and there are no solvents
at all it's just water so did you hear
about it what do you say about
extraction I know applications only for
the pins and if we don't care for out
flower stays after and if thein is the
only uh uh main compound we want to
extract steam distillation is absolutely
the best technique uh the efficiencies
Forin is high I was surprised when I
heard saying that it's expensive to
extract
tpin from hemp because steam
distillation is a quite low cost distill
extraction technique and it's extremely
efficient we tried this with hemp and
the results were fantastic and I was
comparing with some of with all
techniques discussed today here without
any exception and steam
distillation for Pins got the best
results period by far the deficiencies
were huge but there is one new K on
block also there not commercially
available still in velopment but coming
soon that may resolve the German problem
microwave extraction so he already us it
now for the pins but is and is
commercially available uh patented by an
intalian company but with very good
results expensive equipment but is
coming now a solution for cannabiz
extraction also based on microwave can
you maybe explain to me and to the
audience in a few words how microwave
extraction works well microwaves is
microwav is just a wave type of wave in
a certain in a certain uh Spectrum zone
of the right radio frequency
spectrum uh that as you all know we have
microwaves ovens at home that has
capacity to warm to warm any material we
put inside the oven uh the point is that
if you tune for certain frequencies
microwave you are making vibrating for
instance only the tpin this is how the
tpin are extracted and being volatile so
by eating just the tpin in the flour
they vaporize and then they are easily
extracted this is how it's working now
with
cannabinoids having being not so
volatile having higher Bing points uh
that task is not so simple but have been
uh advaned on past years and very soon
there will be here equipments that will
be able to extract cannabinoid using
microwaves uh they are not in market now
because there has been an effort to make
these
equipment GMP compliant for
pharmaceutical applications sincerely I
think it will be difficult to get at
that level but for recreational adult
use technology at it present State it's
there so can be a next big thing very
interesting uh because what I started
growing wheat in 1996 you know you were
always tempted maybe to put the wheat in
the microwave after you hared it but
there was a rule never do that you know
a good grower does not put his wheat in
the
microwave uh but I always learn J those
did you hear about microwave extraction
is that a topic in the US it it's not no
I I know using microwaves for other um
things um when it comes to processing
and things like that and drying but no
not for
extraction it's an American Technology
it's an American company it's there are
some technologies up there microwave but
they also destruct very very badly some
longchain molecules so it's needs to be
perfected for canabo I completely agree
with
you it's it's well I I want to address
want to point up front which is that
water is the quintessential universal
solvent so it is absolutely a solvent in
that way um to address the issue earlier
I I think that uh um a a club could take
dry ice if it was practical and Tumble
it and get much more efficacy and
potency in tumbling and then press that
ke yeah uh but to the point of microwave
I believe uh it's my understanding that
uh in Canada it's being used with some
success in a CGM
environment but for drying I'm sorry for
drying not for extraction yet so there
are a couple companies now that are
offering uh an extraction phase for that
okay and a T and A canabo extraction I
knew about the American I'm sorry I knew
about the Americans not the Canadians
the Canadians good news there's also
another thing called Hollow core
technology extraction but you know
ultimately with all extraction methods
as Jon has pointed out there's a ying
and a Yang to all of them and the needle
you have to thread is the fine line
between capex and Opex and the one point
that no one's brought up yet that's
going to be critical not now but when
the market matures is the cost per
kilogram and that's where certain
methods will start to win over uh over
others you know I would never debate
that CO2 uh doesn't have some fantastic
qualities to it but when those cost
factors start to weigh in sometimes
other methods will uh will prove less L
costly um we did not talk about the most
popular or the most spread uh uh
extraction technique which is
alcohol uh German pH pharmacies mostly
extract with
alcohol
um do the US I mean the advanced
technology companies in us do they still
use alcohol or is that so to
speak something you did years ago we we
do um the problem is alcohol is almost
too effective it it grabs so much and
and uh so your Downstream post
purification needs to be even more
robust and so I'd agree with with Steve
on that where we see a lot of ethanol
use is primarily is primarily built for
like people that want to go to bulk dist
or isolations and is what is usually
when we sell ethanol systems from a
volume standpoint if you're if you're
more focused on very high tpine profile
type if you're typically going to use a
different such as hydrocarbon or
CO2 thank you and does anybody or anyone
of the gentlemen see future in THC uh
steam distillation Under
Pressure do you think that this will be
like the future of extraction or this
will never work steam distillation
probably not going to work for that it's
too of a large molecule for evaporation
it needs different parameters like uh to
push into different temperatures in
order to get it out that's why we
develop a special meod which is super uh
some people call it super critical but
it's really um super heated water so
it's also under pressure with airless
environment and when the water is put in
that environment it behaves like you can
tune it really like 80% alcohol or 90%
alcohol or 20% alcohol so it really
works into the full range of uh Co you
as
well okay thank you George the one
challenge I would say it was brought up
earlier
is there's more than one product that's
being made in a concentrate and the
question is what's the end product are
you going to an edible are you going to
a vape cart are you going to something
that might be dabbable and there are
very few solvents that can span all of
those product categories um that really
is the um the um the Lynch pin of it all
is being able to make all products at a
low
cost thank you very much and I think we
are quite late but I think there one or
two questions are possible if uh there
are any questions from the audience are
there questions from the
audience did you all run out of ideas no
that's one question from the audience
two questions I hope so I hope some
cannabis clubs want to extract soon
we're not so experienced it's good to
have question here we go let's hear it
for the panel by the
[Applause]
way thanks I hope I don't butcher this
you mentioned uh Hol tube extraction Hol
core oh could you say something about
that out of yeah so it came from uh the
bachan oil fields uh it was a way to
separate the oil from the sand and um
it's proved to be expensive but again
you're threading the needle of cost and
it is extremely expensive on the op on
the cap back side buying it up front um
and that's been the biggest barrier to
that particular
technology how does it
work we would need another 15 minutes
and I'd need a board to draw on to
explain it but um it's essentially
almost a microfiltration technology I'll
put it in that way all
right so the my question would be so the
most efficient way for the those
cannabis clubs in Germany would be this
trucken ice Tumbl and pressing this
would be the the best idea everybody
knocking heads like yeah
way it can be an easy and fast way to do
it if especially you have all this
limitation and until these limitations
are gone I guess it can be a good way to
do it they only consider the hash
product as a byproduct of extraction the
every way to make hash either by direct
press or through sifting or through
ultrasound even it's going to be
sufficient now of course efficiency is
not going to be there but at least it's
the first step it's going to be like
this is the first rule that rule going
to evolve it's going to be changed uh
and Depends of uh how that everything
going to start in the first few months
maybe they're going to be like all the
clubs going to write um proper response
to the ruling and that's going to be
voted in September or in the fall with
some changes but for now that's
unfortunately is the only simple way to
do it but I back uh here I must admit uh
German Germany is quite good in
engineering and I think one Club will
invent or uh uh build a mega Rosen press
you know like 5 m by 5 m you know where
they put where they can put half of the
Harvest on you know this this is what I
expect from the jble clubs here please
build a mega Rosen press because that's
in my eyes the only way to do it on
Commercial level you know so I built a
Ros and press in Washington state the
press two
kilos at a time with Boeing Engineers
whether that's good or bad I'm not sure
but as long as the doors don't fall off
of the press you'll be but the one the
one point I would like to make about all
hashes and rosins is that if you were a
gold miner and there was a a quarter of
an ounce of gold in your rock you're
only getting half about half of it out
and the only way to get that other half
out is to use some type of solvent and
when we pressed those rosins we would
take the bags we pressed it all the
biomass we' even scrape the plates and
we'd rerun that in a BHO or an ethanol
process to get the other half of the
gold
out fantastic are closing statements or
arguments you'd like to
make no any more questions from the
audience I was just there
microphone um one question especially
now for the German Social Clubs what do
you think about um especially if you use
tce for pressing to do a um separation
um electric separation
before sounds like an interesting
experiment let me know how it works out
for
you I mean really I I have to say you
know this entire industry is one big R&amp;D
project and uh none of us have all the
answers here so s seriously let us know
how that works out so um the electrical
like what they call in the moment the
static sifting
I'm sorry can you repeat um the
technique they call in the moment the
static
sifting static sifting so like
hydrostatic extraction you know that
that has benefits but much like with
steam distillation which again is very
very effective um we find you lose what
we call your high notes and your low
notes and your Tarpin so you get more of
a blended tpine um you're going to lose
those sensations of a particular strain
and you may also uh do what we call
isomerized chemicals
um we actually in Washington state
invented a chemical uh called um um THC
THC EXC me
cbdt I believe was the chemical and it
was caused by too much heat you you're
changing the chemicals whenever you're
using heat and that's the
challenge okay thank you uh for your
expertise and especially for the German
clubs will listen uh listen very well
because when it comes to extraction we
have to learn a lot from uh the yeah
from all the guys over from overseas and
from Portugal of course thank you very
much let's here again Michael canote and
uh the rest of the panelists