all right here to discuss the European
cannabis industry the head of the
European cannabis group for Dentons
let's hear it for Peter
[Applause]
humberg ladies and
gentlemen good
morning one year ago I have been
standing here and presented what was a
plan for
legalization which was significantly
different from the original proposal of
the German government back in October
2022 it was and I have to say that and
sorry for disturbing the party a partial
legalization we are far away from Full
legalization which the government
actually wanted to
establish and the Germans wouldn't be
Germans if there are not funny stories
about all this and you know Germans have
a very special sense of
humor and let me just uh Enlighten you
with two very funny
stories the first one uh our Chancellor
Olaf Schultz as you may know is
currently in China having diplomatic
talks in
China regarding various
issues yesterday in a official statement
about the
talks in a side remark he said this
shiny Nation should not get the
impression that all Germans are now
smoking
[Music]
weat what kind of statement is that you
know even the Chinese president could
have say well you should not get the
impression that 1.4 4 billion Chinese
people are getting drunk every evening
so uh as I said it's a kind of a sad
rather sad story and by the way uh where
is no uh if if you actually if you
actually have weed with you and you're
smoking you're not uh a patient and
that's the next funny story and you're
traveling to B wenberg which is one of
our states here it could be that the
police is questioning you where you have
the wheat
from because for home grow it's too
early it's 15 days you couldn't grow
that at home uh the social clubs or the
cultivation associations are not yet in
place so the question is where did you
get your read
from and your questions of course as a
witness because after the legalization
you will not be punished if you are
carrying less than 25 G in
public and if you don't answer correctly
well you can be imprisoned for
contempt that's what the police and
Barton wenberg actually said so don't
travel to stutgart and smoke openly I
would say at least for the time
being so welcome to the the club last
one
laughing so what we're going to do this
morning after these uh funny stories we
get a little bit more serious let me see
whe I can do that yeah so we are talking
about a little bit of
business that's what we all are
interested in besides the various
legalization issues I would like to take
you on
a on a journey through various uh
European countries where do we stay
stand there of course I will Enlighten
you a little bit about Germany and what
is going to happen there just really
saying these what are the real points in
this uh legalization process and then we
going to Czech Republic Malta Portugal
Spain Switzerland the Netherlands and
the UK and then we'll see what can we
expect in the
future and if we look into
the uh industry estimates here and I
don't want to bother you too much with
facts and figures I have only two slides
of that um is that the expectations uh
are
significantly high if you look into the
Cannabis Market in Europe uh forecasted
for
2024 it looks like $6.2 billion
US well if you look into the medical
Market uh which was I would say nicely
developing in Germany but of course has
not reached uh its a full extent for
various reasons uh this is a figure
which is not too far away from my point
of view from
reality uh as we have heard uh this
morning uh prescriptions within the
first 14 days of since April 1st have
really doubled in to some expect it is
an increasing Market we didn't we we saw
that the legalization of cannabis taking
cannabis and THC related products out of
the narcotics act would have also a
positive effect on the prescriptions in
the medical Market but nobody expected
that these figures in the first two
weeks really would appear uh we have
clients who have platforms bringing
patients pharmacies and Physicians
together and they have need tripled the
prescriptions uh for since before in
comparison to the time before April 1st
so the medical Market is really going
forward the effect of that legalization
and we will see that in a minute is
significant so these are the forecasts
of the uh sales here uh and the turnover
uh of CBD products Medical Products
pharmaceutical cannabis products like
sax for example uh and the recreational
cannabis
so it's a significant growth which we'll
see so this legalization even it's only
partial has a significant effect Market
in Europe and we will see other
countries and I come back to that in a
minute we will see other countries
following the approach of Germany uh and
we all know and I will show you that
once again why the uh
legalization actually is not what we
call a full legalization uh but it has
has its positive effect of course these
facts and figures here may be a little
bit too optimistic and we have seen even
after the legalization of medical
Canabis back in 2017 in Germany some
figures which have never been reached uh
but uh it the legalization has a real
impact on the industry and I will come
back to that in a
minute so this is the pathway of Germany
and I don't want to elaborate too much
on that how we actually legalized uh
cannabis here in Germany I think the
most in important key points are October
2022 where the full legalization like in
Canada was proposed by the government
followed
by constructive talks with the European
commission as Mr labach our minister of
heals actually said well I have of
course a little bit of different
definition of constructive because the
outcome is that we have now a partial
legalization with hom grow cultivation
in clubs and of course the uh
decriminalization which is a step
forward but it's far away from the full
extent of legalization as we have seen
that in the program of the government
back in
2022 the German government was afraid of
being sued by the European Commission
because they clearly made a statement
you not should not go forward with that
plan even as a pilot country here in
within the in the European Union um and
we will sue you before the European
court of justice for the breach of the
Shen agreement and that was a convincing
argument for the government not to do
the full
legalization so if we look like now into
the uh consumption and cultivation rules
here in Germany and we have heard that
this morning I've just put that together
as a brief summary so the most important
one is cannabis has been removed of the
list of prohibited prohibited substances
in the German narcotics
act uh it is now put into the new
Canabis act and of course all offenses
and the punishments have been
significantly reduced uh it is still
forbidden actually and that is what you
should know to even hand over uh the
wheat which you have cultivated at home
to your friend absolutely no goal you
cannot even uh uh give it to one of your
family members actually if they are not
growing that uh like your uncle who's
visiting you from stard for example so
uh these are some I would say uh very
difficult to understand regulations out
of this new cannabis act but it has all
to do with the consequences that to be
compliant as much as possible under the
UN 961 convention the Shen agreement and
its protols so there should be no sales
uh there should be no profit making uh
cultivation so these are and we will see
that in a minute with regard to the
Cannabis cultivation associations these
are not cannabis Social Clubs we are far
away from that it's a cultivation
Association where up to 500 members can
come together and grow their eat even
third parties are not allowed to touch
the plant only members can do that this
is all what we have seen the Cannabis
which is
a in part in Parts very detailed in
other parts it's has a lots of
loopholes uh and again of course here uh
the in private space you can store up to
50 g dried flowers this was the last
amendment in the law why 50 GRS well if
you cultivate three uh flowers or if you
have two family members who are growing
six flowers and you're harvesting it
well I I'm not a cultivator but this can
definitely be reached quickly if the 50
g dried flowers really
quickly sorry PL yes right so they have
increased that uh and the 25 gram of uh
you can carry not only four you can
actually uh carry 25 G uh I have no idea
why 25 G should be here the threshold uh
you may ask those who have actually
implemented in the law 25 it's a lot 25
G is a lot I would say well there are
calculations 70 70 uh joints something
like that 25 gr uh it doesn't sound uh
wrong so uh that is what you can carry
in
public and again we have some some rules
and regulations which which are somehow
strange uh for example uh uh where you
can actually smoke of course away from
kindergartens sport Arenas Etc where you
have to keep a distance of 100
m uh there's also something in provision
in the law if you can't see it the
school the kindergarten you can actually
smoke there yeah it could be less than
100 m you are not allowed to smoke in
pedestrian areas in the time between I
think 8 a.m. till 8:00
p.m. but but don't count me on that on
that time for whatever reason so uh as I
said it is to a certain extent uh an
interesting approach uh and uh we'll see
how this actually will work out in the
next weeks when everybody can Harvest at
home and then the social clubs or
cannabis cultivation associations will
become active
with uh July
1st maybe just a word with regard to
these Social
Clubs the the law now is totally silent
on where how and under which
circumstances a cultivation Association
can apply for a license to grow they
need a license that is clear so it is
left now to the states
and of course to the communities to set
up rules and regulations under which
circumstances the cultivation
associations can actually
operate and Frankly Speaking they are
helpless they are helpless they are
looking for guidance because you know
they have neither the infrastructure nor
the Personnel nor the financial
financials in order to really implement
this infrastructure to control the CL
clubs to license the clubs to check the
applications uh and as such I'm not that
confident that we will very quickly see
those cultivation associations being
operative well 1 of July is the due date
so until then the respective uh
authorities have to have implemented the
respective rules and regulations for
these clubs there are already so-called
f as we say in Germany who have a Lish
themselves and who are ready to get into
operation but they don't even know to
whom they should file any kind of
application there's not even a form uh
in which they could actually send the
application and of course no
Authority let's have a look into the
medical cannabis and I mentioned that
already uh it is for the medical
cannabis a big step forward that
cannabis and THC rated products are
taken out of the German narcotics
act uh there is a new prescription
requirement Which is less strict as the
prescription of a narcotic so Physicians
do not have even to register with the
bay form they have they should not use
the I would say red prescription blocks
uh where which is kind of a
psychological barrier anyway uh to
prescribe kind of so that relaxation has
actually caused the increase of
prescriptions uh in the last a couple of
weeks
um and what is of course also important
the uh certain relaxations with regard
to where you can actually uh purchase
your readed with the respective
prescriptions in the pharmacies
having said that for Germany uh we jump
into the next or travel to the next
country which is the Czech Republic the
Czech Republic has always been
supportive of the German approach uh
very open uh with respect to the uh
legalization process uh and medical
cannabis was already legalized back in
2013 um and in the use of recreation
uh cannabis is is still illegal uh there
are also some uh rules with regard to
new
substances uh which uh came up on that
market which of course also are causing
some uh issues here like hhco and
thcp uh and you will see in a minute
that the Czech government is taking care
of these as
well um
what the what is expected here is that
there will be a certain legalization uh
in due course uh in in in Czech Republic
as well and in 2025 actually at
beginning of 2025 these restrictions of
these new seven uh substances will be
reviewed again uh and there is still
kind of a stand still the they were very
when we started our legalization process
in Germany they were very Force coming
and now it slowed down a little uh and
we actually the Czech Republic wanted to
go for full legalization uh in order to
challenge the European commission and
see what's going to happen uh risking to
be sued before the European court of
justice for the violation of the shenen
agreement this is off the table uh at Le
until now unfortunately because they
would have of course uh one of those
countries which have uh actually then uh
probably before the European court of
justice at least make their stand Point
very clear unfortunately it's a little
bit of a change right
now we travel to Malta well not the
largest member in within the European
Union but one of those as we heard this
morning who started their legalization
process and uh yes indeed it looks like
that the German legislature has copied a
little bit of what the males government
has done with regard to the Cannabis
Social
Clubs uh which are the
CH cannabis harm reduction
associations um in January 2024 so just
recently the first club actually became
active started its operation and the
maltes have actually
established an authority for the
responsible use of cannabis who actually
are testing um the quality of the weed
which is cultivated in these clubs
jumping back to Germany yes this will
happen here as well what is going to be
tested is not clear uh what is clear is
that the members who are between 18 to
21 only get flowers with a THC content
of 10% or less uh with only 30 grams all
other adults above 21 uh there's no
limit except that they will get only 50
g a month uh what kind of quality well
again I we don't know whether it's gacp
or whether it's anybody's asking for GMP
or just a regular control with regard to
any kind of uh substances is also not
yet clear here we have an authority in
Malta who is taking care of that
all right from Malta from the little
island in the Mediterranean to
Portugal 2018 we had already the
legalization of medical cannabis uh
recreational is not legal but it has
been decriminalized to a certain extent
uh so if you look into consumption and
possession of small amounts uh there
will be no real
punishment uh which is a step forward
there it is of course away from what we
have done here in Germany with regard to
the legalization and the very very
strict uh decriminalization of
possession uh currently there are two
drafts uh in Portugal that allow the
consumption cultivation and possession
of cannabis for recreational use and uh
well we'll see what the government will
do there's a certain instability in in
Portugal uh and we'll see whether they
will move forward following Germany
maybe with that model which is in line
what the European commission actually in
the constructive talks with the Germans
have actually asked to
do from Portugal to the larger neighbor
Spain um medical cannabis is not yet
regulated in Spain the cultivation of
cannabis for research and medical and
scientific purposes is prohibited and
less authorized of course by the uh
Spanish Agency for medicinal products
and medical
devices um the Ministry of Health
actually announced in February 2024 that
had started the progress to develop a
Royal Decree with which it plans to
approve the regulations of medical
cannabis so a little bit behind Germany
uh all nearly seven years uh but we'll
see what actually will Spain be doing uh
despite that of course as you know in
Spain we have these cannabis
clubs great number of Canabis Bloods
where actually you can go and
consume again back to Germany in these
cannabis clubs or cultivation
associations consumptions are allowed
yeah you just what you just can do as a
member you can go there and collect your
weed that's all and have to leave
there's no even no space No Room allowed
where you can actually consume your
cannabis so you have to take it home uh
different of course from the model which
we see in Spain and so it's not
comparable at all the cannabis clubs in
Spain are not comparable to the Cannabis
cultivation associations in Germany and
there are lots of rules and regulations
with regard where you can actually grow
as one of these cannabis clubs here in
Germany uh and uh that will be
interesting to see what the state
government and the communities are
bringing up
all right to
Switzerland Switzerland not being a
member of the European Union actually uh
uh has implemented these scientifically
controlled pilot projects and you may
have heard about that uh the UN
conventions the various un conventions
in particular the UN convention 1961
exempts the use and transfer of cannabis
or uh cannabis for medical purposes and
of course for scientific purposes and
that is actually what the Germans
anticipated here and have implemented
into the second pillar because as we
heard this morning already uh the
legalization process has two pillars
first is hom growth cultivation in clubs
and then of course the second one is the
implementation of scientifically
scientifically controlled pilot projects
very much the same as Switzerland has
done that um of course we were expecting
the first draft law on that before
Christmas uh even the Easter Bunny
didn't bring it so we'll see when we
actually will get the first draft on the
table we know that the Ministries are
working on that uh for the
implementation of uh these uh pilot
projects uh we don't know yet whether
this dispensaries will be licensed uh
how to register as a participant in this
pilot project what are the numbers of
pilot projects in which regions do we
have them how many actually can
participate so that is all unknown we
will see that and you course hopefully
uh in order to have the implementation
of the second pillar of that
legalization process which is of course
a step
forward however I think what is uh
important
to know is uh that U the uh third pillar
uh which nobody actually has recognized
is that the German government is going
to seek uh other countries in Europe to
influence the decision-making process at
the European commission level for that
they would like to gain data see what is
the impact of the legalization and once
these data has been gained they will
definitely go to the European Commission
in order to convince them to change the
prohibition policy very important step
nobody's really talking about that uh
but is an important part of that
legalization process uh for that as I
said we need that scientifically
controlled pilot projects in order to
get to gain data and if you look into
Switzerland they have actually these
seven different uh pilot trials as we
call it uh some of them have already
been active some of them are set being
set up uh they uh script for example
weed care and Turan these are these
projects actually PPP uh public private
Partnerships uh together with the
universities who is are going to collect
the respective data of the use of
cannabis and what kind of impact it may
have uh this is the model which Germany
is going to implement to which extent I
can't tell you not I can't tell you at
this point in
time so just a couple of words to uh the
Netherlands oo the
Netherlands uh actually uh you know
since 20 since
2003 uh medical cannabis was permitted
uh and already back you know in 1976 the
use of recreational Cannabis was
permitted uh if you have reached the
legal age so it's a long history of the
use of of Canabis for recreational
purposes we all know this coffee shop uh
system where you could actually could
get in and and consume buy and consume
cannabis uh which was uh not legalized
but it was
accepted uh which is
uh speciality of the uh Dutch criminal
law you they can do it in Germany we
couldn't do it we have a different
principle we have to implement and rule
the the respective laws in in the
Netherlands they are following a system
where they can but not have to do that
and that's what they did uh actually
ignoring the use of cannabis in these
coffee shops which were actually illegal
um however now they are starting up as
well uh to implement this uh kind of
projects scientifically controlled as
well U so there startup phase uh with
respect to that um so the are going to a
certain extent legalize now their copy
shop system uh smart move of course also
in the borderlines of the European uh
commission guidelines and of course the
Shen agreement uh and they have as you
know licensed out uh to 10 cultivators
in Netherlands to to serve the market uh
with uh cultivated cannabis for
recreational
purposes so now we are leaving the
European Union and jumping
into uh the United Kingdom uh and uh uh
that's kind of very interesting if you
look into the UK CBD market for example
you will find a great number of products
and those who are either living there or
who have visited the UK they she have
seen all the shops with regard to CBD
products uh and uh which are if you look
into the European legislation are not
permitted in particular with regard to
food supplements uh and of course as you
know you know foood supplements
containing CBD CBD which according to
the decision of the European court of
justice is not a narcotic needs a
registration under the novel foot
director of the European Union and of
course we have companies who have
applied for that uh and they
applications have been put on hold by
the respective directorate of the
European Commission because the
respective safety data they provided
were not sufficient so they have asked
for more data and more data and again
for more data and now all the applicants
who are left over I think of 50 are
around 35 which have uh formed groups in
order to get the uh
costs actually divided between them for
gaining those data uh are would say
frustrated by that
approach uh in the United Kingdom uh
there this if you look into the medical
Market it's a very limited market uh
very limited market with regard to the
indications and very limited market with
regard to who actually can prescribe uh
the respect Ive uh uh Medical
Products um if you look over into what's
going to happen here uh there's a leaked
report for a pilot project for
decriminalization of cannabis well we'll
see what it will bring actually um and
of course the mayor the office of the
mayor of London is up to reelection in
May this year so just shortly and in
we'll see what actually this has as an
impact on the new cannabis uh
legislation they are looking forward
though it's all connected of course to
politics our Chancellor in China the
mayor in London having elections you
know it is the the law is made by
politicians and that's where we have
actually to Lobby
that so if you look into uh in Scotland
uh it is interesting course uh uh in
Scotland the ruling uh is that of the of
the Scottish Lal party uh they advocated
uh a kind of a decolonization of drugs
including cannabis Scotland has one of
the highest drug death rates in Europe I
didn't know that before I went into uh
the investigation of that and uh we
hopefully will see a change in the
policy approach and a kind of a deiz
probably to the back door as outlined
here so coming to the end of my
presentation let's have a look where do
we stand here and today in Germany and
in
Europe the legalization for medical
cannabis and recreational purposes gains
momentum in Europe I think that is clear
everybody is getting into the discussion
of legalization of medical cannabis I
had the pleasure to be invited to
Slovenia to speak before the National
Council about the legal legalization
process in Germany uh of course starting
with medical and uh there are other
countries not only Slovenia but also uh
in the uh in Czech Republic for example
in other parts of the European Union who
are looking at what is Germany doing and
as such it may have a pulling effect
they are looking into more and more uh
uh legalization at least for medical uh
it's not legalized in each and every
country of the European Union and of
course we should actually try to get at
least the harmonization within the
European Union at least for medical and
earlier or later also for
recreational the obstacle as we know uh
is uh the the shenen convention and the
EU Council framework decision of
2004 uh and of course the various single
conventions to which the European Union
actually uh uh is also a party and a
such very reluctant to allow member
states to go forward with a full
legalization so if we look into the
political challenges and we heard that
this morning as well from from gor uh
there are of course uh in all
countries part ities groups which are
strictly against the legalization of
cannabis U not only for recreational but
also for cl for medical
purposes um also in Germany and we have
to say that very clearly the opposition
are very very clearly said that they
were against the legalization Pro and
they are still of that opinion today so
the more we go forward the more uh we
step into a
legalization uh and the
more experience we will have the more
data we will have with the
legalization uh the better the arguments
are to me to do the next
step and
nevertheless uh I'm convinced that more
countries in Europe will go that path
and as such our legalization in Germany
wasn't all that bad I think it's a good
step forward even if it's not the full
legalization which we
expected thank you very
much Peter humberg Peter Humber I think
we have time for a question or two maybe
if there's a question does anyone have a
question all right Derek has a question
thank thank you my question is about the
talks that the German government said
they had with the European commission
what's unclear to me is there's no name
of who they talk to there's no date
there is no official release has there
really been this discussion can you tell
a bit more about that is there a
discussion yes there was a discussion I
I I believe our minister of Health that
he's telling the truth on that uh it is
and was not not a formal process there
was no there is no process in order to
get the opinion or to get the uh the
confirmation of the European commission
that we can go forward it was an
informal Talk of the ministry and uh the
group who wanted to do the legalization
to a full extent uh and I don't know to
whom they talk uh of course probably to
the directorate of which is responsible
for the pharmaceutical developments but
uh it is indeed not even published it
just said they were constructive talks
with the European commission and I said
as I said before I have a little bit of
a different understanding what
constructive really means uh but that
is between us they have been feared
away they could have of course gone
forward with a legalization process uh
they could have not been stopped but of
course they could have been actually uh
sued before the European court of
justice and Germany just lost two large
cases before the European court of
justice so they were afraid of another
one from my point of view and that's the
reason why we have this twostep
legalization process Which is far away
from the total
legalization all right uh oh you have to
jump we have we have time for one more
I'm glad I wore comfortable shoes uh
I'll remind you also that there's
microphones back there
[Music]
hi Peter um I guess my question is
regarding pillar two in Germany what are
in your opinion what are the chances
that it gets passed and implemented
prior to the October 2025
election that's a let me see crystal
ball uh there is a if the opposition uh
the conservative parties would
succeed um they have
made statements uh since the
legalization even before that they would
like to reverse it whether they really
will do that is another question you
know we're not in Thailand uh this is a
democracy and of course there are
different opinions about uh the
legalization process um from my point of
view it would be difficult to totally
reverse that legalization
without uh getting at least a
significant
uh uh significant strong opinion against
it to say it in more diplomatic way more
diplomatic than all of schs yesterday in
China so difficult to say uh I don't
believe Frankly Speaking that they will
totally reverse that that legalization
uh which is which is from my point of
view uh already uh as you would say
written in stone at least sorry my
question was pillar two oh pillar two oh
sorry yeah yeah there you go yes all
right we're out of time let's hear it
again Peter
homberg
fantastic uh thank you thank you very
much I think he makes a good point