but we would also we're going to be
about doing about 20 minutes of
back-and-forth thing and then we're
going to ask you and currently encourage
you to ask questions from audience but
we're not going to do this right away so
as they were saying on the last panel
right the lobbying discussion in
particular is difficult and there's some
issues in this industry that are
persistent and have not been solved yet
and I think it's fair to say that
everybody on this panel believes that in
some way some of the larger industry
issues in part can be solved by
technology or at least greatly aided so
I'm going to throw this question out
immediately what and where do you think
technology of whatever kind can help to
continue revolutionizing this business
and if those of you guys don't do like
Storz and Bickel is that's sitting next
to me so I'm gonna throw it to you
quickly because everybody knows you're
made from your international innocence
yeah thank you very much money time yes
my name is Rebecca from source and
because we are producing vaporizers or
first revolutionising technology was in
the year 2020 product will gain a
vaporizer on the market before the time
you had to smoke it more or less or to
eat it there was no other viable way so
this was a one revolution but what today
is very normal
everybody knows there are tons of
products out there so it become a very
mainstream I believe the application
form will be in the future more
revolutionising we see all this
concentrate vaporizers and it will go
forward in this direction we see
alternatives like capsules but you can
in chess so I believe there the
technology will go forward can I just
add a little plug here I mean vaping is
seen as like the future not just of the
cannabis business but a lot of other
medications a lot of other kinds of
things right I mean yeah and
irresponsible yeah whatever can
but cannabis is a little bit special of
because of this decoupling oxidation
process THCA transformed into THC there
must be also substances still found what
can be viable for it so what about the
rest of you so please you know introduce
your firm quickly where do you see
technology helping to revolutionize the
business is it sales it's tracking is it
you know just knowing what you're doing
where are the things that you guys see
technology revolutionising the business
thank you that works hi my name is Jeff
Keene I'm the CEO of a company called or
product called 365 cannabis but it's
actually based on a Microsoft dynamics
platform an ERP platform so the way we
feel we're going to help revolutionize
the space is actually taking something
that works at outside the industry and
bring it in so we're looking at the
cannabis industry like every other
industry that's out there I think the
cannabis industry in markets like Canada
and the u.s. started out thinking it was
unique in every sense but from a
business process since it's like a lot
of other business it's Agri its food
process manufacturing its distribution
warehousing and in the US and now
starting to be in Canada is also its
retail so rather than look at it and say
how do I solve my problems in cannabis
for those things we're bringing a
platform from outside that does all
those things and applying it to the
cannabis space and then this term seed
to sale that comes out there in the US
and Canada where you're compliant if you
do all the right business processes and
you set the system up properly then
you're automatically going to be
compliant and you achieve your seed to
sale that you hear so often in US the US
and Canada anybody else have somebody
back here yeah absolutely say hey hello
everyone my name is Anna Sethi on the
CEO founder groomers consulting the way
that technology has actually
revolutionized the industry in my eyes
is that it's helped us scale this helps
us automate this helps accelerate
personally for me you know I I'm
launching a software called Odyssey it's
focused on licensing of Department for
cannabis businesses in the US and it's
it's really accelerated and scaled the
process of being able to do that even
though we can't fully automate it and I
think that you can acquit to you can
equate it to something like you know the
turbo tax or legal assume when the
cannabis industry and it's focused on a
lot of the pre-license aspects of giving
these entrepreneurs license getting him
up and running but I've seen everything
in my 25 years of doing this I've seen
everything from you know just these DC
to sell tracking him
our control systems all the way to like
robots AI drones inside cultivation
facilities that are spotting things like
disease pests and controlling these and
automating it and so we're gonna see the
same thing when it comes down to drop
shipping medic medication eventually so
it's really interesting to see how
technology is really taking this to the
next level and I can't wait we're really
excited to see that so I'm gonna talk to
you for a second so you see and I agree
with you technology is helping to
normalize as well as ultimate routine
processes that have also impart slow
down this industry is that it's absurd
absolutely and we have yet to see some
of the best out there I mean as we go
through this innovation period it's
almost like a renaissance period of
Technology we're seeing more and more
and more come out every single day and
everybody's just really taking it to the
next level so it's really exciting
so hello my name is many I'm the chief
product officer and interim CEO now it's
the technologies we're a Canadian
company were fully vertically integrated
ecommerce platform in Canada
specifically we have sales only license
which essentially forces us to be a pure
play a technology pure play company we
leverage technology to enable
optimization of the user experience and
we deliver solutions such as education
telemedicine applications the ability to
purchase cannabis online same-day
delivery
journal and etc and we can talk about
each one of these technologies are
siloed assets separately but my bias is
and it's going to be very hype this
around the artificial intelligence and
one of the things that we're focused on
is to try and understand how we can
leverage AI to help people find the
right product for them and actually
brought one of our lead machine learning
engineers with me so that everybody can
harass him and see him not just me
ha but that those just like the FinTech
industry was really changed where you
had people were very very passionate
about what they're doing an
understanding regulation and using
technology to change that industry and
we still see that impact since 2009 till
today v ik is still changing literally
we're in the infancy days of Technology
and cannabis combined so so anyway we
met pay for those of you who don't know
what it is it's not many feet of
advertisement but we are using watching
and we're actually going to no matter
what the technology is I think here
whether it's hardware or software there
are ways to use existing technology to
automate processes there are ways to use
new technology to push the envelope
there's a whole bunch of innovation
that's coming out but one of the things
also that struck me about this panel was
how the international it is ok so you
have people here with the international
experience and technology certainly
across oceans is different and a lot of
us are looking at the compliance space
one way or another how about it just
shout out where are where do you think
the International cannabis industry in
some ways has started to reform or put
pressure on or change the cannabis
industry in other places and how does
this chemistry now being international
play into the revolution revolutionising
idea of tech in this application yeah I
am we have the last 12 months we
distributed into 19 countries around the
world so it's very to national and it's
everywhere available and of course with
this technology you have done the way
how you can consume cannabis in a
medical way you have 10 inept ways it
you can try all that and so it's the
technology is really a nowadays
distributed worldwide in a very fast way
but it's compliance different from
country to country right yeah exactly
and I've called my European
Andre we are here a medical device
manufacturer a medical device
manufacturer means that he needs to be
have a quality management system it's
called traceability what is called C to
say on the other hand on a device and
destroys ability if you get back
defective device with a serial number
you must be able to track back but you
purchased every single part you built in
and where you have it so to so the other
requirements are relatively high and
they are different from country to
country for example you don't have
medical device in the USA because the
FDA is not ready to approve a medical
device then if you go to Israel you F of
course also other requirements labeling
in Hebrew in Arabic can also be a bit
challenging stuff like that and the
latest compliance in regard is the GDP
are the channel directly from the SP 400
confirmed no privacy yeah yeah privacy
law so this gives you also another
compliance I think what I think from
people from North America they are not
ready for the GDP are as far as I can
and I can see of course the law is less
than a year old politically it's a
strict law and it's a bully I leap
unshed law and it will be followed it so
I think it will also affect a lot of
people who touch Europe in any in any
babies their products there's some
compliance coming up I'll take the next
one concern interesting question on
compliance because so we do business in
Canada us and there's a number of
international companies in Colombia
Jamaica Australia Denmark that we're
dealing with right now in the cannabis
industry but the platform is already
international so if you look at the
platform work we're using for ERP is
already almost in every country in the
world including Germany just not in the
cannabis space so the Canadians when
they came into the space with their out
bees and we came in a few years
afterwards we saw the legacy of this was
they compliance to them was just in my
complaint to Health Canada and I'm
meeting the regulations so I can keep my
license and they didn't think about
compliance in any other way
so now all of a sudden the Canadians are
coming to us and asking us for GMP first
of all I think they probably had to look
up the the acronym is most of us do good
manufacturing process which in order to
export your product from Canada to
countries like Germany you have to prove
that you are a GMP processing facility
and the Canadians weren't thinking of
that at all so it's I think in some ways
the international space has a way to
benefit from what was already learned in
the US and Canada not do the same things
look at it as a business that has to be
compliant as it vs. a compliant industry
specific to candidates that has to run a
business and his compliance everywhere
GD P R GMP FDA requirements are not in
the US yet but they're coming so all
these things have to be in place their
public companies now trading so now Sox
compliance and how your financial
reporting goes so we actually had to
employ which I didn't think I'd ever
have to do running a software company as
higher compliance chief officer just for
us to handle not only what's going on in
cannabis but also the compliance ins
coming at us from everywhere else I'm
gonna push this one to you right so
that's a discussion about what can
technology do to revelers revolutionize
the industry I think sales and
advertising is certainly there right
however controversial and I wanted to
throw it in that direction because you
know the question is about how
technology can be applied to overcome
some of the bigger issues whether its
compliance or laws or etc certainly
sales online the discussion of the
industry press online 2014 helped push
forward a whole bunch of things how do
you see this working how do you see this
technology discussion changing
regulatory frameworks that are still
holding the industry back like
advertising or etcetera so so that's a
very important point to remember that
everybody's very afraid of compliance
gdpr and they're very worried about what
are we gonna do with it
essentially if you look at it it could
be a huge opportunity because the
existence of gdpr raises the bar and
allows you if you build systems in place
to comply with that allows you to create
moats around your business so for
example part of GPR and I'll get to the
advertising sales promotion part of GDP
RS is security by design or segregating
data not collecting data that you
shouldn't if you don't need it for a
true process so for example one of the
things with automatic processing of data
is that it's not exposed to humans so
you can segregate it within the system
and then you're protected from a
compliance perspective you can automate
a lot of the requirements that gdpr has
and then you create those modes about
the business and and you use that
there's an opportunity specifically
around sales and marketing that's really
interesting because I spent the morning
talking with a lot of CBD producers and
suppliers here and the one thing that
everybody spoke about is like we cannot
advertise we cannot sell our our
products online or so we're not ever
test a product I even though the panel
previously that spoke about the exact
same point and CBD let's take it as an
example in many countries many countries
is completely Mingo however the big
advertising networks like Google and
Facebook Adsense double-quick etc those
are the ones that don't allow you to
advertise and guess what happened a
Google on GDP or in France there's a
disruption so I just want to come back
to you that cuz I think your system
actually helps people comply by
automating it literally by using the
legal form so you're kind of combining
those two do you want to talk a little
bit about that yeah sure I mean you know
just as you were stating about you know
the different countries to have
different laws or that are just coming
online or becoming aware and educated
just in state California alone it's like
that it's like the whole world are all
worlds policies in one state so as we go
from city to County to the state level
it's all different just like you go
throughout the United States it's all
different so we've had to find a way to
kind of shut that based on best
practices we know that the FDA is going
to step in eventually just like you have
you should always be focused on good
manufacturing process in practices or
good business practices that's a fair
oran factor when you're coming in and
exporting to the EU as well because if
you're not compliant then you're not
going to be able to serve that market I
think that uh when it comes down to it
when it comes to have the technology let
me ask for a quick how many people in
this room right now are in a start-up
mode for a tech company Laura or in a
tech company right now how many people
anybody great awesome so we are not
limited as what I'm saying with
technology you can license that
technology you can take that technology
to other countries you're not limited
like cannabis is limited and for the
fact that we are you know a technology
firm or able to actually serve more
markets than our counterparts you are in
the cannabis industry trying to get
licenses of cannabis and that's the
thing that we always need to compare
that to in my opinion you said license
technology to others is AWS right AWS
started as an internal solution for
Amazon because they couldn't find
something that met their needs and now
it moved to a ten billion dollar your
business because they every who here
doesn't you or uses AWS in their
business right so I think so I think we
can all agree right that in some ways
technology is revolutionizing the
industry because it's normalizing it
it's saying this is just a commodity or
it cetera so but as a way of a lead-in
and I saw a lot of hands go up there are
a lot of people in startups and we would
like to now open the you know the field
for opera for questions so if you have
questions please go ahead and bounce
them back to us because one of the
things we were talking about before we
came on here is I think I'm one of the
few people actually who's gone through
the German incubation system there are
opportunities if you are starting to
look at applying technology and want to
apply technology in this revolutionary
business where you can start to enter
the market in new and different ways in
part by normalizing that in part by
saying I'm not just dealing with
cannabis as this crazy plant I'm dealing
with a narcotic that has to be that's an
awful evil drug it has to be approved or
etc or I have to try to plant fortitude
ah so I think how would you say that and
you're going to pick on you again how
would you say that technology has
changed the equation
normalization if that makes them mean to
me for example you have to get you have
to go through insurance approvals as a
medical equipment provider you're the
only person on stage has to go through
that so technology is also adding a
different level of compliance to you as
well is that revolutionary to you for
example as a medical device manufacturer
of course there are there are a lot of
medical devices so it's not so important
if it is for cannabis or for something
else you need to follow the medical
device rules and they are there and if
you comply lie and there's of no reason
to decline any allowance to it on the
insurance idea we have tried to get here
in Germany generally recovers to get on
there's a list it's metal this thing
ever you can get on then you get a
tender doctor can prescribe it and the
place you get it green bars but
unfortunately we have not reached to get
on this list yet they are still too many
holes and they are still unsure and a
fear that they are get a lot of
prescription fights but we are working
for and hopefully they will have to yeah
at least we can work a deal on that
question so anyways I mean I think for
example you for example are actually in
a licensing and processing approval
discussion correct yes correct I mean
you know essentially again it comes back
to their regulations at the state level
in the u.s. in this case and in Germany
or other heirs if they were to do
licensing it would be anything that they
obviously the government level so we
what we do is we sort of analyze when
when regulations come out you know
regulations are shifting and changing
this is it's dynamic compliance I like
to call it really because this whole
space is very dynamic so when it comes
down to it we have to really navigate
these processes but if we can accelerate
it and lower the barrier of entry and
put you know promote more diversity and
bring more players into this game you
know to really get it to the point where
folks can really innovate we are gonna
see a hyper jump in that space in terms
of Technology in terms of how you know
folks actually operate and so we want to
ensure that first that you guys get
permanent and regular it regulated and
licensed and then there's ongoing
compliance
that handle and everything else because
everybody's focused on that section as
opposed to the pre-license section so
that's where our focus is
but again coming back to technology and
how it's changing the face of the
landscape there's things like the
Internet of Things for instance IOT
we're seeing IOT manage like how the
plants growing you know checking you
know it's like full automation on this
right and so as a business owner that's
trying to scale and serve a high demand
in this marketplace things like that are
pretty important I mean it lowers the
the costs associated with it we're able
to really magnify the ability to grow
these plan exactly the same way over and
over again which is consistency so we
have a fracture supply chain now on the
global level but you know just to
basically us or just based in the state
of California it's still a fractured
supply chain so we're not able to get
the same consistency on products because
businesses are scaling and this is a
plant that changes it's it's you know
it's consistency over the course of time
I should scale it or have you for
nutrients or a different lighting
all right different management
techniques on my plan so it's really
interesting to see how technology
shaping that but most importantly is
that it just innovations doing that this
isn't never stopped it's gonna happen
over and over and over again
just like with the internet when it
first came out so I like to come in here
to that because that's how fast this
thing is moving right and so I would
HIGHLY highly recommend take advantage
of that absolutely so so I'm going
through the Sally is there anybody with
questions right now he wants to ask the
panel anything we're gonna keep going
okay sorry didn't know I think you had a
specific issue that you wanted to bring
up in terms of I think you were sort of
talking about the fact that to try to
take it to the next level that of all of
us in some ways from a technology panel
or a technology solution well just I
just generally lessons learned right I
mean exactly
coming coming coming with it from a
platform that already works in other
industries and coming into the canvas
space into North America first of all
the international space has at once a
life time opportunity to set their
business up from the ground up
not only because cannabis is new but the
businesses are new in setting it up the
right way with technology and making
some of the right
decisions most most US companies that
are in the space have probably gone
through two three four different
iterations of solutions whatever they
tried in the beginning didn't work
they're now on to you know multiple
others and from our standpoint this is
where we're now coming in from the
outside saying you're in agriculture you
grow in greenhouses people have been
growing in greenhouses for decades
hundreds of years and there's already
software out there that does that for
you so why are you trying to apply for a
new software does something that's
already established out there so we're
kind of coming at it from a different
way saying you're in supply chain
management that does agriculture that
does food process manufacturing
distribution and potentially retail so
for us we're not looking at it having to
introduce something brand new because
the space requires it we're trying to
normalize it by saying it already exists
out there don't go make the same
mistakes that the others did where
you're buying software from the ground
up that isn't proven anywhere yet but
it's trying to find itself in the
cannabis space because it's gonna get
out of scale as you normalize the
business out there all those other
things start to hit you the normal
business processes that every other
business runs in and the Ender you're
here to make money
on these businesses it's not just about
you're in the cannabis industry and what
software will work for that we'll see
and this is where I'm hoping to
introduce you no controversy here so you
know obviously your bed pays you see a
new technology called blockchain right
and how do you integrate that into a new
industry while minimizing risks and
attacking the issues that you're
attacking well one of the ways that we
have decided to go forward on this is
actually blending this so we're holding
workshops where we're bringing
stakeholders together who aren't
necessarily tech geeks but there are
business people with problems and
they're coming together and they're
discussing them and that is how we're
starting to I think also start to pin
new technology processes and
re-engineering into a new business which
it very much is here as much as we are
I guess re-engineering processes so I
think that this for us the cannabis of
vertical has given us a way to address a
larger problem that is faced for example
by the chronically ill people who need
to get expensive medical equipment
pharmacies people who are touching this
system but didn't necessarily have
another way to touch it but but I'm
gonna throw something also out here
because everyone's talking about this
the whole enabling ash aspect or not
enabling aspect especially with you
throwing privacy and all the other
issues about online sales right because
online discussion about this industry I
think has very much led to greater
legalization as much as governments have
not maybe gotten the regulation right so
far but clearly I think the online
discussion in technology does lead to
online sales would anybody like to take
a and dive into that as and also from
the the enabling and also the privacy
perspective so you want to yeah I can I
talk about online aspect of it I mean at
the at the end of the day that's where
the industry all businesses are going to
right because as humans we are lazy we
wanted a path of least resistance so if
I'm able to sit at home and if we look
at the full stack of the cannabis
industry if I'm able to get a
prescription without leaving my house
and then buy a volcano
without leaving my house and have it
delivered I will likely prefer it over
having to leave get in my car drive
there's no see a doctor and go to a
pharmacy pick up the product etc so from
in regards to ecommerce right obviously
I'm quite biased so I can continue
talking about that aspect for for a
while but it is something that is
driving this industry forward well let
me let me be up to analyze gets it easy
the e-commerce or is it telemedicine I
mean I think that there are two aspects
this is the telemedicine there's the
e-commerce there's the do people feel
comfortable not seeing a doctor our
regulatory agencies were taken when you
get into the narcotics side of this is
gonna say yeah the years of schedule -
you don't have to come see a doctor
anymore is that realistic Germany you're
gonna today I read that you can get then
you can get online - it up dying
you can claim to be ill for your
business and yeah this is a new system
who is available here but it's very
controversial and the doctor doesn't get
paid yet by the way there's some issues
maybe an so general remark about
compliance because it was here about
fearing compliance or I I think it's
very important to be compliant until I
think every managing director CEO must
take care to be compliance and
especially in this field because on the
one hand you don't want to get extra
holes because you are treating something
with cannabis but on the other on the
other hand you also do not want to get
to be very favorite because it's gonna
have a sensing you can you don't need to
be compliant because it's cannabis all
the sites you don't want to see you want
to see you don't want to get extra
levels but you also want not to get in
any easy way on well let's move up your
bit being on the compliance because I
think technology can also used for
research right and and sort of the big
data data gathering aspects I think of
basically all of what we've decided I
mean I think what's interesting about
you guys is you're moving me more and
more into a world where you can gather
information online for example through
the bait I was soon right
I don't want to say but regardless I
mean there is there's definitely this
whole discussion male about digital
health in the cloud and privacy issues
how would you I don't have touch of my
one yeah we we actually built in that's
not were the problem right the problem
is that a lot of people use cannabis but
there is no way for them to actually
measure if it's helping them or not so
there are not a lot but quite a few
companies that build solutions to
address that we are one of them there's
a great company that these are here
today strain print that does the same
thing and essentially allows people to
track usage and the impact of products
on their symptoms and initially at least
that's what we released this were like
no one's ever gonna give us any data and
we were very surprised to see that
actually people were very forthcoming
but they weren't Germans that were they
right no there might be droids right but
the people who are very very forthcoming
with
because there was a lot of value that
was created in exchange for that day too
so that's something that is is actually
moving forward in the idea of being able
to collect real data from real people
and analyze it and generate insights has
value across the entire list you want
for patients for example were able to
recommend what strains are right or
wrong for them for the industry we're
able to help growers understand what's
popular what they need to grow because
of growth cycles for device
manufacturers they can understand what
temperature's people are using is it
conduction convection based what are the
most popular models etc there is so many
different elements that can be used that
are valuable for both parts of the
industry so it's something so silly
because we're turning ability so hands
up how many people involved here in the
startup side are using technology in
education that's up I mean how many are
using it in compliance how many are
using it for medical processing okay
anybody else who wants to speak up I
mean we really are trying to encourage
technology companies to come forward and
talk about their experiences because we
can all learn from each other I mean I
will say that my experience here has
been actually to sort of use some of the
stigma around this plant to actually get
people to agree to start to use new
technology for example I mean if people
agree we on this narcotic and yes we
need to track it and no we can't really
do this because gdpr says we can't
follow this etc I think that that does
also create a new opportunity to apply
new technology in a new way to fix
problems that are affecting this
industry as it normalizes and
potentially other pieces of a larger
vertical have any of you had experiences
without that you would like to
I said I'd like to come back to you you
know what you stated about how there's
nothing new here guys I mean like at the
end of the day the tech there's
technology out there it's not about
reinventing the wheel it's about making
that little way much better way better
than what it is because here's the thing
like the technology we developed it was
really kind of out of multiple different
pieces we took the best of several
different pieces of technology that
worked in our field and infused it
together into something that's brand
spanking new right and the same thing
goes for a lot of these different
practices like you don't need to create
anything new even unless it's something
that has to be created you so encourage
guys to look out there and see and do a
lot of research because before you spend
all this money or your investor's money
for that matter on a lot of different
things that you that is already existing
just do a lot of research first because
there's a lot of things out there that
parties serve that purpose we were
seeing a merge of all these different
industries merged into the cannabis
industry from all different fields that
includes you know medicine that includes
technology that includes agriculture
that includes retail they include supply
chain tracking that includes all the
different logistics and transportation I
mean there's so many different things
happen globally that you're just going
to take from all those different
industries and then apply your own kind
of sort of style to it right and I also
want to um you know real quickly you
know talk talk about this hotel medicine
aspect of this or just working with
patients and gathering that data you
know I have a friend of mine his name's
dr. Len a he's based on Los Angeles if
you present a company called endo canna
health now what endo Kenneth Health does
is they take your 23andme data and
translated the information into what you
need for you what would work best for
you in terms of cannabis products right
what would work worse for you in terms
of causing stress or anxiety or
different things like that really really
cool technology but this way you're able
to get highly targeted patient data
that's that's that's really amazing and
so you know exactly what works for you
because what will work for one person
may not work for the other person right
so so we're not important to see that
it's pretty incredible and I'm gonna
jump into here right so the difference
in
privacy the approach to privacy from a
technology perspective is a very very
different depending on where you are I
mean if you're in California on with
Google and we don't care about privacy
and I'm gonna say that because they just
got the suit here and you're in France
they don't and I you know I think that
there is a wide opportunity here but I
think that that is one of the issues
that we see is that privacy and the
understanding of what privacy is aware
that data can go and who can have access
to that and why is a discussion that I
think the cannabis industry in general
and patients and doctors should step up
on I mean weird we're in that space we
don't believe that private companies
should have as much information about
people as they do and we see gdpr to
your point I think as it wayno setting a
much higher standard where patients
actually have control what they don't
and that in itself is something that we
can enable with the use of technology
while giving industry more information
that they ever possibly could have hoped
for but it is completely anonymized
because of the way that we approach it
so maybe that is one of the ways to talk
maybe we can talk about a bit about
privacy because I think this is a huge
huge discussion that it's not often
talked about because do you were like
gdpr doesn't matter it doesn't affect my
business in Germany or in Europe right
now and GDP are violation one to PR
violation they can ding you for percent
of global sales so if you think about
just a cannabis perspective of this
beyond the tactic a privacy as a medical
discussion should be baked into all of
us this particularly can hurt a company
has small medical sales here in Germany
but a global footprint for example so
how do you think that and I'm going to
maybe the end of this a little bit early
because I want to speed things up and
make sure this conference goes on but
how do you see technology influencing
the privacy conversation and I would say
if you want to add in the cannabis
industry fine but I think that
technology can be used to highlight that
so for example you're in you know are
you making plans to
people their own personal cloud access
for example or you know in your industry
or you think about the fact that yeah
I've got a you know ease are there
privacy aspects on the on the on the b2b
side that maybe we have a thought about
I mean I think that is from my
perspective that is where I spend a lot
of my time thinking and planning and
working but I don't know I just jump in
there because I mean what you just said
is so complex depending on where you are
so we conduct business in the u.s.
there's over 30 states that we're having
to deal with if you know we deal with
Canada we the data that we take from our
customers is not our data it's that we
put it into Azure it's your environment
in our model so the data is yours we
just have to help you manage it and in
Canada the data has to stay inside of
Canada
so as a technology company we have to
put platforms up everywhere that comply
to that requirement that really has
nothing to do with cannabis has more to
do with with the data side of it so
privacy relates to the consumer but it
also relates to your data everybody's
coming to us looking for aggregated data
on your business not just from what
you're selling to patients but you know
what products are selling it every other
industry has aggregated data that
they're looking at if you ended with if
you come from the hotel industry every
Hotel knows how busy this hotel was last
night what the occupancy was here as
compares to everybody else and what the
average room rate was and this industry
needs to know the same thing what
products should I be selling how much
how much does it cost me to produce that
product how can it be more efficient and
you have to share the aggregated data as
a community so that we we can all get
better on it so there's the privacy of
that information so we we don't give
that data it has to be you guys
providing that data amongst ourselves
and then a community setting itself up
where that aggregated data gets used
okay so I think we're being signaled
from the side here that we're running
out of time
last call for any questions you can
catch us later there is some there
Kerber botanics conversation is very
interesting because we launched our
online shop in the UK but the plan was
to produce two apps one for under who is
one
iOS and connect the chakra fly into the
app so when you sell a product we want
to capture the information from the
customer how they use it and how it can
help for us to choose the next next
product but the GDP or spin you talked
about is very interesting because you're
already starting to sell not just New
York air or Germany France how do we
sort of manage that later but yeah I
think I hope that the rule is privacy by
default or privacy by design and so you
have the tracking unit needs to be
disabled but you are able to ask your
client that shows the information it's
you it's still possible you just need to
say why you might want to the data be
collected
what kind of Tidy I want to collect it
and you need to ask for permission and
you can do the same thing educational
scales for it back to that's the other
thing so it is compound yeah it's it's
GPR sounds scary but it's quite simple
as long as you give consent and there is
a reason for you to have that consent
which sounds like you want to provide
better service your customers just build
your privacy policy in a way that gets
that consent and then you can do pretty
much whatever you want as long as you
define yourself as the data controller
in that matter short answer is
complicated any other questions and see
you later - I have a quick question when
you talk about AI and all these things
how do you deal with implicit biases or
the challenges you have of gathering
quality information because you can make
the smart machine but if you tell it
dumb [__] it's gonna be a dumb [__] good
question
like you know target in garbage out I
think that's right that's a basic right
the expert evidence in the Vancouver
dispensary case was that patients want
to see the product smell the product
like going to the grocery store buying
your groceries so how do you deal with
that you have a license to sell online
Canada only allows that I think you in
Shoppers Drug Mart yeah
the ones who have it medical patients
only get it in the mail and they
complain that it's in the container they
have to open it up sometimes there's
some problem with if they send it back
so delays than getting their medicine so
that the evidence from the patients and
an expert doctors emerges from the
states was that this was a very
important part of delivering medical for
medical patients so not sure if the
drone can come and drop down and give an
option and go back up and you can think
or how are you gonna deal with that
well actually I'm sorry you know it but
in Germany actually that's illegal so
you have to go to the pharmacy and the
medical I guess culture here I mean the
our potatoes are trained to actually I
mean that's why they want patients to go
to the pharmacy to literally have the
pharmacist who is trained in this hand
over that drug but to your point there
may be regulatory issues that say you
can't do it as you're doing in Canada
which affects another thing that seas to
sail for example but then you're gonna
also in terms of access issues if you're
too sick to get to the pharmacy but
those are places where technology can in
fact begin to start to connect them but
as we find privacy issues all are all
the way along this because it's not just
a product that you can buy like a
regular commodity product this is still
stigmatized so privacy is in the room
and every single light I think it's
gonna be based on preference how many
people refer to have a dropship to your
front door then okay but that'll never
replace the retail experience are you
going in there it's smelling different
things the only thing it will do is
enhance it right so we're seeing
enhancement of that retail experience so
and big Hoover's a lot different than
Germany and that's the evolution for
medical to retina we're seeing as well
if you're coming from a North American
perspective you're already going well
isn't it just like alcohol and why can't
you buy it and consume it like you do
alcohol and the international students
still talking about it medically and
what is it and is it a medicine is it
you pick it up in a pharmacy you can get
it online so I think if you look forward
a few years you're going to see that
same change happen that's happening in
North America as it tries to embrace it
in a recreational analyst way and have a
retail experience
yep you don't sit to be web Canada I'm
sorry to drive you but in Canada it
seems like the privacy aspect was not
really brought up until it went into the
recreational market which is an
interesting twist I thought but but that
question in regards to brick-and-mortar
versus the e-commerce is we shouldn't
even talk about it right it's the same
question that was thirty years ago in
regards to of 20 years ago University
e-commerce in general and now you see II
Congress growing endlessly and malls in
the u.s. nothing to do with privacy was
talking about the consumer experience of
choosing a product without being able to
touch smell and understand it and that's
a classic question of you know we've is
different and we're gonna go a little
long because I'm getting passionate now
lead is different than lumber or a
blender right you don't have to smell of
liquor you don't need to look at the
crystals on a blender right you want to
smell your weed you want to look at it
you maybe want to talk to the person
about the genetics if you want to know
something about the grower and how it
was growing it's all thoughts without
any different always get that experience
without so mature that's a maturity of
the industry right because right now I
think that's because inconsistent
product might be coming through and you
can't get the same experience listen you
could give five different growers the
same cut and come up with five different
styles and five different smells of five
different effects all from the same weed
so it's really hard to you can get them
out of why big a or a double block or
whatever it's very hard to get different
to make sure people are consistent the
blue dream from one person is different
than blue dream from another person and
it's America and here's the other thing
right so I mean I know that this
discussion is saying if there's no prep
work fewer privacy discussions in
e-commerce but there are actually a lot
it is there a question there was another
poster I think what time is it though
because we're running super late