can you hear us representative Gabbard I
can hear you business technology it's
possible thank you so much for calling
in to the International cannabis
business conference here in San
Francisco
we're very excited to hear from you
representative Gabbard you're Criss
crossing the country you're hearing from
Americans what are they telling you
about medical marijuana reform and adult
use cannabis legalization what's the
sense of where America is at America is
more United around this issue than those
in Washington would have you believe
it's an amazing thing and really hope
inspiring actually to see how you know
at my town halls I'm here in New
Hampshire right now we're holding town
hall meetings every single day we've
held over about a hundred and twenty
town halls here for the last year and at
every single one we have Democrats
Republicans independents and
libertarians coming together talking
about the issues of the day in this
upcoming election and this issue around
legalizing cannabis is one that has such
incredible cross partisan support and
that people in some of the most rural
conservative towns here in New Hampshire
also support the frustration here in New
Hampshire is that even as it is the Live
Free or Die State it has still the most
restrictive laws relating to cannabis
even medical cannabis in a neighborhood
of you know Massachusetts Vermont and
other states that have have done so much
more to legalize and ease people's
access to cannabis we held a panel here
recently a presidential forum that we
hosted and brought in different leaders
here legislative leaders there's a woman
who's a nurse who is advocating for the
legalization of cannabis with the nurses
Network there's a woman who is on a
medical board here who herself needed
medical cannabis and whose add the
citizens advocate for this so they
brought an incredible treasure trove of
real life experiences and the real
challenges that folks in New England are
facing which I think are reflective of a
lot of the challenges
that we're facing across the country but
the hopeful thing is that this is not a
right versus left issue this is for most
Americans it's a question of freedom and
fairness and choice and for people to be
able to access this plant as medicine to
regain their lives to achieve wellness
and in many cases even as we're dealing
with the opioid crisis to save people's
lives medical medical marijuana is
polling at 91% in America right now I
don't even think clean water polls at
91% you've been in Congress do you
you've helped push legislation forward
what do you tell people when they ask
what's the disconnect here do you have
any hopes for congressional reform in
2020 or 20 21 with regard to medical
marijuana it's really it's really gonna
require the kind of grassroots driven
pressure on members of Congress to make
this happen I continue to be surprised
even as you're talking about the
approval ratings the popularity or the
favorability ratings across the country
most states have have legalized some
form or another of cannabis but still in
Congress there's a lot of unwillingness
to even look at the facts to examine the
data and therefore just rely on the
stigma and myths or the things that they
heard growing up saying hey marijuana's
bad or they say I don't want my kids to
smoke marijuana so I can't support any
kind of legalization others use the
excuse of kind of the cart before the
horse thing saying well you know I serve
on the Financial Services Committee for
example and I co-sponsored and supported
pushing through the safe banking act to
make sure that banks who are working
with local dispensaries or others within
this industry are not living under the
federal shadow of potential prosecution
and some of my my colleagues and on the
committee I was surprised they were just
saying well look you know even as they
advocate for states rights and
respecting states rights they say well
this is something that is still
federally illegal so we can't pass
this bill because it's federally illegal
even though the states have done there
there's not a whole lot of logic the
arguments that are being made so once
again I really believe in order for us
to bring about the kind of change we
need to pass legislation like the the
one I've introduced the only bipartisan
bill in Congress to end the federal
cannabis prohibition it's gonna require
constituents resident citizens of this
country you know Colin Colin endlessly
tweeting emailing dropping by mounting
this pressure that will force leaders in
Congress to catch up with the rest of
the countries at given that ninety-one
percent support and we still have
trouble moving forward is there anything
that's incremental and bipartisan and
realistic that we can do in this
Congress or next year's Congress given
everything else that's going on in the
country or is it just going to happen at
the state state level I think what we're
seeing is it's already happening at the
state level I think that the financial
industry is now paying more attention to
the opportunities that exist within the
cannabis industry and I think that's
another pressure point that can help
influence members of Congress to
recognize if nothing else there's a
strong economic argument to be made here
as far as an incremental approach you
know we have a number of bills in place
that try to chip away at this for
example you would think as much as our
country supports veterans that that
would be kind of an easy win right a
low-hanging fruit to be able to say our
veterans are coming home dealing with
chronic pain many of them or traumatic
brain injury post-traumatic stress and
they don't want to just numb that pain
away by taking these highly addictive
opioids and they want to be able to have
access to medicinal cannabis so let's
let our VA Doc's prescribe that or even
refer them to someone locally even that
is not something that this Congress the
the this highly partisan environment in
Congress has been willing to get done
and to put on the President's desk I
think potentially the strongest
that could be made where there could be
an incremental approach is is around
medicine it is it is undeniable and
there are so many examples of how
medical cannabis has saved people's
lives we saw a little bit of progress
made around the story of Charlotte and
how her parents and those like them
found the only relief for their children
in their epileptic seizures through the
use of cannabis and I think there's a
lot more that we can do on that to say
if nothing else let's begin with a
national decriminalization legalization
of medical cannabis when we talk about
states leading the charge
I see Hawaii is implementing medical
marijuana there's continued drive to
bring adult use cannabis to Hawaii what
do you foresee happening in your home
state I think Hawaii and Ford we've been
on the cutting edge of a lot of things
that I'm really proud of but in this
area it's it's disheartening I really
there's there's a bit of a generational
difference I think in some ways even
though we're a strong Democratic state
the representatives and Senators are
pretty diverse
I was really disheartened when even as
both our State House and state Senate
passed legislation I think it was last
year the year before that said if opioid
addiction qualifies under our medical
cannabis access laws it was it had
bipartisan support but our governor
vetoed it citing two issues number one
he says there's just not enough evidence
and data to show that medical cannabis
will help people who are struggling with
opioid addiction which is just crazy
it's crazy because we've seen how in
states where people have that option to
use medical cannabis the numbers of
opioid addiction and opioid related
deaths have decreased dramatically
the second reason he cited well you know
if they want to if they want to include
this then they can go through the
bureaucracy of the medical review board
and so on and so on
who we already know is opposed to this
and will have a predetermined outcome
just shows the work that still needs to
be done even in my home state and I I
counting my voice among many to be able
to push this forward because it has to
do directly with adult use with opening
up medical cannabis for all the
different needs that people have but it
also is impacting the hemp industry that
I think has so much potential especially
in my home state of Hawaii where you can
farm 365 days a year they had to
completely destroy a whole crop of hemp
I think it was grown at the University
of Hawaii to begin this pilot project
because it had some minut fraction of
too much THC in that hemp and they had
to completely destroy it it just it
doesn't make any sense to me citizens
often feel bewildered and powerless when
it comes to affecting this national
change but I'm sure you've seen how
citizens everyday can affect their
environment in their local cities and
counties whether it was in the city of
Honolulu all the way through their
regions and their state legislators
office in 2020 what is the the checklist
as a citizen for engagement and and
pushing on these issues it sounds like
it starts with being registered to vote
registering others to vote what do you
tell people to make them feel empowered
absolutely
registering to vote and making sure that
your vote your voice is heard through
your vote at every level of government
is essential try to do at least a little
bit of research before you go in and
cast your vote
ask your your elected leaders questions
and share information I think I think
the biggest hurdle here is overcoming
this gap in lack of understanding and
demystifying the myths and stigmas that
still surround cannabis and really talk
about the real life examples of how this
has has created a lot of opportunity or
personally impacted someone's health or
really it comes down to the question of
liberty and freedom that every one of us
should have the freedom to be able to
choose what we put in our body and so
making sure that your voice
is heard not only through the ballot box
but actively engaging with your elected
leaders and others in your community is
what I think will have the most the most
powerful impact and I think we've got to
do it at every level of government you
you do get those emails from your
readers you are your constituents do you
get those physical printed letters do
you do you get those meetings have they
moved the needle for you do you have
personal stories that have changed your
votes I have not not related to cannabis
you know we have had other situations
where there was a bill that was coming
to the House floor for example that had
to do with privacy online it was
something that as we were heading
quickly to the vote I think the day
before it had large bipartisan support
there were things though in that bill
that would have had unintended negative
consequences on our own civil liberties
and privacy and I saw in real time how
in my office phones are ringing off the
hook
emails were coming in like crazy twitter
was blowing up with people saying don't
support this bill because X Y &amp; Z it
will have a negative impact on our own
civil liberties as it pertains to our
online engagement and within a span of
hours on that day that the vote was
being had on the House floor
it went from a bill that had
overwhelming bipartisan support to
having overwhelming bipartisan
opposition and the bill died so this
doesn't happen every single day but I
think it illustrates the power of of the
people in this country that that that
really too often isn't recognized and
then people rightly so they feel
frustrated because they feel like their
voices aren't being heard in a lot of
cases but this is one of I think a few
examples that shows hey when we all
stand up and use every platform possible
to make sure that our voices are heard
they will be heard and depending on how
your elected leader responds is how we
as voters
can hold them accountable we still have
the power to hire and fire people if
they're not doing their job
lastly Leafly the app that I work at our
news organization is releasing a jobs
count this morning that finds that in
2020 about two hundred and forty
thousand Americans or a ployed in the
cannabis industry
you know comprising billions and
billions of dollars of economic activity
it seems like the level of institutional
advocacy for cannabis might be higher
than it's ever been in Washington DC but
there's a lot of industry leaders in the
audience who been battered by high taxes
and regulations and ongoing prohibition
and some of them must be wondering if
the message is getting through to
Capitol Hill so my last question is are
you seeing that lobbying blitz are you
seeing that advocacy show up like never
before on Capitol Hill are these K
Street dollars being well-spent in terms
of the cannabis industry trying to you
know participate in get its voice heard
I think it's too early to tell to be
honest I think that I'd have to go back
and look at the results but when we
passed the safe banking act as one
example on the House floor I didn't see
anywhere near the kind of bipartisan
support that I felt it should have I
think there's there's still a lot more
that needs to be done I don't know how
much is being put into this from an
industry perspective but bluntly bluntly
there are still some high hurdles to
cross I think it's so important that we
don't allow this issue to become caught
up in the hyper partisan environment in
Washington where yeah sure now in the
House Democrats have the majority where
we can pass legislation like the safe
Banking Act almost with with full
Democrat support with no or very few
Republicans on board but now it's going
to the Senate where it's sitting there
like many other bills just waiting for a
vote that may or may not come about I
think on a bright note an area where we
can look to how this has worked has been
around the successful inclusion of hemp
in the last farm bill
that was past something that saw a lot
of opposition even for Mitch McConnell
for a long time but we know how powerful
the hemp industry that's growing in his
home state had a direct impact on him in
being the one to make sure that the
provision that we work to include in the
house stayed in that Senate version that
was finally signed into law
representative Gabbard thank you so much
for standing up and leading Americans
and enduring that criticism of doing so
and participating in this a wonderful
experiment in self-government thank you
so much for your time thank you great to
speak to you all have a wonderful
conference Aloha
[Applause]