to discuss unlocking the medical
benefits of cannabis we have a Allstar
panel and to lead us and moderating that
panel uh biochemist researcher at the
National Institute of biology in Luana
please welcome Professor Dr tomra
[Applause]
lern use the microphone
oh
sorry a panel yes on a medical use of
cannabis we have heard now how it's
produced and for this reason I would
like to invite my dear colleagues uh
which is one uh David noow Professor
nebauer who is a pediatrician and
neurologist child neurologist and has
been leading the uh pediatric department
of uh neurology department of the
Pediatric in in the past or have been
was okay so
please and uh the second one is the
famous pharmacist this is Professor
borit strule who is internationally
recognized uh and very busy in different
businesses and Pharma industry and
consultant so he is a professor at
faculty of Pharmacy of University of
lublana leading the department of um
pharmaceutical biotechnology so please
let me
[Applause]
down
and for the introduction I would like to
say just a few words about medicine
cannabis in medicine and we know that it
has been used in medicine for thousands
of years thousands of years in many old
but civilized cultur cultures and uh
actually started all in China about 500
years ago but then the really
Renaissance of modern cannabis medical
Sciences was done in Israel and the
leading scientist was Rafael mulam which
you maybe know and he initiated uh and
of course then motivated several
scientists all around the world uh to
researching to um researching the
properties of cannabis he discovered
endocannabinoid system and the use of
medical cannabis by using really
state-of-the-art biomedical biochemical
physical methods to prove that and um of
course also bioinformatic and based on
such a solid foundation there is still a
problem how to translate this knowledge
to clinics and um here um we have
problem here we have problems as we
already heard a little bit around and
these are the problems that are related
to the medical agencies and uh
administrative obstacles in many
countries also in Slovenia especially in
Slovenia I say and unfortunately and
also there is a problem with Medical
Society medical staff medical doctors to
accepting to even understand try to
understand the benefits of cannabis
although the science is really showing
that it has infect and we will hear
about that uh today so uh about talking
about the history I would like to ask
first uh of course the was used for
various diseases and I would try ask you
first David which diseases have been
discovered first to benefit from the uh
consumption of cannabis products in the
history and now it
is thank you very much Tamala well in
the history it is well known that um
already the um especially Arabic um
mohamedan doctors were using cannabis
for different purposes but especially
for the seizures because at that time
for epilepsy there was no other
medication um in the in the end of 19th
century or in the beginning of the 20th
century first first medications were
bromides and soon after that
phenobarbitone and this was actually a
kind of help for these patients with the
severe um epilepsy problems
however um already um at the end of um
20th century there were some just few
reports about possibility to use
cannabis for the severe um epilepsy um
patients for those with um very
resistant epilepsies and at that time
maybe we already had pharmaceutical 30
or even 35 drugs which were quite
effective but still one third of the
patients will remain um resistant to all
these uh
treatment so um I think pediatric
epilepsy was the first one to merge from
this medical cannabis um uh treatment
and it was in um 19 no in 20 2014
actually that the mother of young
Charlotte who had severe um early um
epileptic syndrome which is called D
syndrome um and she had for 200 or 300
seizures per day and she went to Stanley
Brothers in Colorado and she ask them um
if they can produce a kind of oil from
the cannabis for her daughter and it was
actually a miracle because um within 10
days of this treatment uh the girl um
has become nearly seizure free instead
of 200 seizures per day she had only
four or five per week um and thereafter
it came to the public um in some
newspapers and so on and from that that
time on um the research on um
cannabinoid a treatment for severe
resistant epilepsy started
um okay we have we have used um kind of
um canab canab Bol um from 2015 on so
this is for 10 for the last 10 years and
um already at this early years three
years after that we have um published um
a paper with a retrospective study and
we were astonished when we um uh analyze
the data uh 1 of our children was um
completely seizure free So 20% was
seizure were seizure free and um one
half of the patients they had only
occasional seizures so um it was a
remarkable result and and soon after
that also the other studies um confirmed
that yeah that's that's really amazing
especially for the families on Mothers
and especially then for the children to
that can grow learn and get into a
society now I want to ask you also if
this is um first disease that was FDA
approved also or were they others um yes
um the majority of the studies maybe I
can just uh show some
comparisons um here is uh one systematic
review um um and you can see that the
majority of these studies that is
um this is our study and there are also
many others um you can see that um the
results are um rather similar in all
these studies um and epilepsy is the one
which is the most studies however um in
Brazil and um in Israel and also in some
states in um America they were using
also for the other conditions especially
for the spasticity
for behavior problems in autism for um
severe sleepiness problems and for um um
pain of course pain is also one of the
um topics which is studies this is still
used now all over the world but not only
for children no no no no no it's for but
then um for Els the epilepsy is not um
treated with Canabis why is that um
unfortun well I'm talking about our
country in Slovenia unfortunately the
neurologist for adult persons they are
very rarely um using canabidol um even
if it if it has been proven um in also
in the uh double blind studies that it
is very effective and also this um uh
nice um uh guidelines are um giving the
this
recommendations that it should be used
as an addon drug not not as a primary
antipeptic but um add on Dr but um they
are not using it okay thank you oh you
want to no there is only one thing more
I would this this this is the summary of
these studies but um what I would like
to say also is that um there was one
study in done um which showed the
comparison between um purified canabidol
which we are using and um the extract of
cannabis which is um they're they're
calling it canabidol enriched cannabis
but however there is THC also inside and
as you can see this is our study and
these are the other study but um when
you use cannabis enriched preparations
the results are even better which is
which is to some extent it is normal
because then you have this ENT Rush
effect and all yeah we are coming to
that later on in the discussion with a
pharmacist but now I would uh move to
borut and uh first I would like to say
that uh uh first after China then also
this knowledge was transferred to a to
to the to the east practically to India
to the Syria to Persia to Greece to
Egypt and then it came also to Europe
actually first it came from India by the
uh medical doctor and chemist William
oon and he was um also working in India
for a long time transferred this
knowledge to England and there uh soon
after that it was already in English uh
pharmacopia and also in American
pharmacopia and uh even in
phopa as I learned today for several
several years until of course we all
know that a Prohibition came 100 years
ago about and uh since then of course
and now recently it's again in European
pharmacopia so what does it mean because
Slovenia will also accept European
pharmacopia how would this change the
attitude to prescribe Canabis to use
Canabis and especially among the doctors
well thank you very much first of all I
would like to thank to organizers for
giving me the opportunity to be here
andar excellent moderator as usual uh
well uh the same faces the same audience
second or third year but what is new
actually unfortunately not that many uh
I'm going to emphasize that I'm going to
talk as a pharmacist so I have to
Advocate uh some kind of pharmaceutical
legislation but on the other hand I
would like to put a very big black spot
on this regulation particularly in
Slovenia in order to move forward with
what we're talking about so you have to
know that scientific uh evidence are
something but uh clinical studies a
proof clinical studies recognized by FDA
or IM uh European Union it is something
different nevertheless we'll come to
this later on now uh finally we are
faced with the European pharmacopia
monograph on the flowers of medical
Canabis it was uh issued on July 1st
2024 so very very new document and yes
we have this document what does this
mean that all medical Canabis that is
going to be produced in Slovenia or
imported from any other country uh how
to fulfill completely fulfill with the
criteria which is in this monograph this
is good but let me tell you very recent
example one of from iCal uh company
wholesaler distributor ask so um this
company apply for the permission for
import a Canabis which Canabis medical
Canabis from bedran you all know that
this is the golden standard European
union and the monograph was prepared
according to the uh characteristics of
this plant which is very well
standardized with the content of 22% of
uh uh THC and other components
and what uh what was the answer from uh
agency it was a negative one why because
do not uh I mean the certificate of
analysis from the company that produced
this bedran uh there is a slightly
modification in the uh Ash residual Ash
and or zening but I mean we're talking
about 00005 instead of something like
that so extremely rigid and this is the
take-home message I
many times I emphasize this if there is
a will there is a solution is there a
will from the regulatory point of view
we're going to get the solution okay so
coming back yes this is fine we have now
monographs so all importers all
producers by the way about the
production it was excellently um uh
presented uh by um my colleagues from
Andrea from uh hope Institute uh yes we
are very close to the standardized uh uh
um plant uh however uh all producers in
terms of medical Canabis had to fully
fulfill good agriculture and collection
practice which is this the case so it's
impossible to raise the plant somewhere
in not controlled conditions this is
something that it is important you know
that we just passed with the referendum
uh it was very clumsy one but never mine
I mean the outcome is good so something
is important to know we have to
distinguish sorry this is not real
question but just to mention a little we
have to disting between uh medical use
and recreation use I'm am for both
however we have to to to to separate
this because of the conditions if we'd
like to have a raw material for the
final product in terms of medical
Canabis we have to raise the plants
according strictly according to good
agriculture and uh and collection
practice which is not the case of the
recreation one so coming back okay we
have this one and on top of this U
medical agency uh for I mean sorry
Agency for medical products and medical
devices ask uh importers yeah or any
kind of I mean any individual to uh
provide a special for which is called
the um written request for the needs and
it was uh uh explained to us that there
are no need to produce or to export
which was also mentioned by
um Andrea uh that actually that the
needs are here I mean that the the
plants are already uh available at
oncological Institute let me go further
more because I'm quite upset on this
what is the document that agency is used
for one single document it is called
recommendation for paliative care for
oncological patients could you imagine a
recommendation this is the bottom level
in hierarchy of the documentation uh
they do not care about any kind of
international guidelines we have quite a
lot of guidelines and in this
recommendation there are only two
indications one it is a pain but the
Canabis is supposed to be the second
line medication not the first one in
this document at the second it is
prevent vomiting prevent no NAIA which
again means only two single indication
for the oncologic patient that are on
the pallative care so this it is a a
dust let's say if there is no wheel
there will be no no uh kind of of of uh
uh um um let's say some kind of
improvement so what about other diseases
neur neurological disease etc etc uh
okay I will stop it here and let me yes
because I have many questions one is uh
also for you about the role of
pharmacist in not only uh suggesting
call helping patients that are coming to
to the you know to the pharmacy and ask
for help but uh even more so what is the
role of Pharma industry are they um
somehow of course it's a competition are
they opposed against or can they perhaps
involve cannabis uh production of can
cannabis Pharma in their lines or is
that what what is the situation in the
market yeah well you know from excellent
question thank you tomor from Sil
industry it is not a carus or Red Cross
there is always uh profit behind and
from from Sil it is not oppose uh
preparations coming from Canabis but the
regulation it is extremely strict which
means that the pharmaceutical industry
has to uh perform clinical studies that
are extremely expensive then the whole
indications
are technology it is protected I'm
talking about cannabis it is protected
by patents so these are patents uh and
we we have these products for example
epidox which is composition of CBD uh
THC predominantly CBD um 10 to1 or 15
to1 something like that then we have
sativa it is finished product composed
of T THC CBD one: one 25 5 Mig so there
are products but due to the very strict
loation and patent uh protection it is
very difficult to penetrate this as a
product pharmaceutical industry it is
for a business let me uh uh implement
this to OIC you all know that this is
gp1 Agonist which is actually the only
indication it is treatment for diabetes
uh patient but due to the fact that very
pleasant side effect was found out that
this is the reduction of the weight uh
all of us we are seeking for this oamp
this is of label use actually and
Pharmaceutical industry under the table
produce a lot a lot of this kind of
compound because of the business of
course officially they could say no the
only indication in this one so this is
not not against but you know again it's
very and the other hand is this a real
profit uh if uh um several uh factories
are going to produce uh medication with
only two
indications uh which yeah exactly which
are actually the second line products
for Tre these indications this is really
amazing but what does this mean for the
patients and of course this is unethical
to the patients because they are um at a
declined of any treatment and then they
go to Black Market and you have good
experiences and maybe this case please
explain us what happened when suddenly
the import of uh uh of uh epidox was
blocked
yeah um we have studied a group of
children where parents came to us and
they were asking us um if we can analyze
these products which they bought um at
the black market for children and we did
the analysis and um this is what we have
found
oops so this is this is it now if I
finished before um with the slide where
I showed that um cannabis enriched
canabidol is much more potent than
canabidol alone like pure canabidol or
isolated canabidol somebody would say
this is the slide showing um how
different um were um THC and CBD
contents in this
specimens you can see that um even um
the ratio sometimes was 1 to 100 that
means that um the children were giving
pure THC on one hand and on the other
hand there were products with um very
high content of CBD and there was no THC
so these were the products that the
parents were buying Black Market
in yes the parents were buying this at
Black Market Market we never ask them
where did they get it no however this
analysis yeah our Institute Yosef Stefan
did this analysis and this is what came
out and together with this um very
different concentrations of THC and CBD
and some of them they're quite dangerous
very dangerous and because you know that
when you have CBD together with THC the
CBD is counter of THC so there will be
not so much s effects and the other
thing was that there were a lot of heavy
metals and even steroids in these uh
samples so um these data unfortunately
were not published because the paper was
not accepted but I think this is I think
this is a very important message I hope
it will be so they can see how unethical
is to expose children or patients to the
black market def but uh I will now clear
something because we were talking and
maybe the audience is not really uh
knowledging this that we talk about
medical cannabis which is the full
spectrum as you said the broad spectrum
or full spectrum this differences and
the pure cannabinoids isolated and mixed
together and uh what is the difference
the as I understand this mixture medical
medicinal cannabis is hard to make uh
this this kind of therapy Therapeutics a
uh randomized clinical trials as is as
by The Doctors medical doctors for a
drug and ex for the drugs to be sold so
can you explain what is the difference
and how this we call this Entourage
effects of different cannabinoids
different terpenoids flavonoids in the
in this mixture extract of the flower
medical flow so what is the difference
and how to yeah thank you for this
question actually yes you are completely
right you know that uh well the
composition full spectrum composition of
the kabit extract it is composed not
only on canab there terpenoids or any
other kind of plant secondary
metabolites allow me to compare this
with the very well known remedy which is
uh it is sell like uh medicine now but
it was know for the centuries and this
is extract of valeriana of falis
valerian actually uh faculty of Pharmacy
University of Liana we perform some
studies but not only we all around the
globe scientists try to isolate um um
particular I mean uh um substances like
uh um ingredients you know that for
pharmaceutical industry it is much
easier to deal with one component one
compound one molecule uh due to the I
mean analysis control of analysis
standardization and so on okay so uh it
was point out that um okay what we
analyze so there were uh valerenic acid
um essential oil votr flavonoids if we
test not only we but uh this was the
Consortium yeah exactly uh All Around
The Blob uh the effect what what is the
effect what what is the supposed to be
effect um sedative effect
um let's say some kind yes as a sedative
as an um uh um anti I mean antic and so
on we you know how valeriana is work
okay so we found out that not more than
up to 5% of this effect were exposed by
a single component separated separated
from the mixture exactly which means
that the mixture really works
pharmacologically
synergistic particularly the same it is
with the canavas extract of course we
have to be very precise on which kind of
indic we're going to to monitor or to
going but yes I mean in generally uh I
am I'm in favor to have a full spectrum
but you know what does this mean full
spectrum this depends on the mode of uh
extraction uh mode of application for
example uh then the growing condition of
the plant etc etc but it's possible I
mean what's the difference between full
and broad
spectrum um well we call full spectrum
if there is um th H C inside and um
broad spectrum if there are only non
psychoactive canab canabo so the TFC
quty is a difference between full and
Broad okay when I stay with you now and
go to the Future from the past to the
Future what is the future of using
cannabinoids or uh medicinal cannabis in
Neuroscience in neuro neurological
diseases what your vision as we have
been astonished by um canabidol use and
Effectiveness um using it in the
resistant very resistant um childhood
epilepsies we have been even more
astonished um using it um it also as as
as in in the case of epilepsy um also it
came from the parents they actually came
to us and they asked them um why
wouldn't not what why would not try a
cannabis product that means full
spectrum that means canabidol plus
THC um in severe Behavior conditions um
of autistic children these were children
who were having a lot of different
antipsychotic drugs the the regular well
they're also um off label actually no
they are not meant risal for example and
Quin and so on so on but the parents
were coming and they said um each drug
of this anti psycotic we used it was
worse so why we will not try this
product and so we said okay we have um
um product um which is a CBD THC 10 to1
so that means 10 times content of CBD is
higher than THC and um let us try this
and it was remarkable really because
these behavioral problems of autistic
children which can be very very serious
I have here a video I hope it will
go um you will not hear the voice
because the voice is awful but this
boy um he had this um temper
tantrum after seeing um through the
window that their neighbor park the car
not on the usual place but uh a place uh
beside and he got this temper Tantra
yeah this is typical upset yes yes he
was completely upset and this is
actually typical for this severe
autistic children and sometimes they are
also um Hing hurting themselves or even
the the family members and so on so this
is really and uh the results were
remarkable but not um only in our small
study that there were only 17 children
but there are um this year studies which
proved actually the same this is Maza
the the
Brazilian authors and Miller Val um the
doctor from Germany um she did a lot of
study on um toured syndrome and tick and
um cannabis and this is our own study
and and this is the first randomized
double blind PLO control clinical trial
on 60 children with this severe autistic
um problems and it also show they all
showed including ours that these
behavior problems these severe behavior
problems can be um really overcome um by
um cannabis and um at the end I would
just say um that um one of our families
uh the boy is now 17 years old and they
said after so many many years um um of
trying different antipsychotic drugs uh
we have now um time um when we can sit
outside together and have a coffee um um
in peace um and we are really very happy
because sometimes you need just a little
bit you know but for this parents that
means a lot this is the quality of
completely changed quality of life they
can go outside and they can they can sit
together and you predict that this will
be taken the CH the child's or yes yes
yes I I think his life in
yes thank you this is really an
experiment and I think uh it's
astonishing that also you found this out
as many others and it will be probably
also going to be approved by FDA or uh
our agency our agency what do you think
about that our agency based on this data
approve such a
treatment so tell us something about the
suggestions how to deal with that well
um I do believe really I do believe that
we're in front of uh something which is
is called a final goal final goal of all
of us and this is that the patient will
be able to get the prescription to go to
the pharmacy and to get this or that
product based on the flowers of medical
Canabis uh I do believe that at the
agency that now they have all
documentation which is needed for
production or for not for let's say for
uh importation and it is stupid to ask
uh about the number of patient that need
this one you know uh there is estimation
from examp from National Institute of
Public Health it is estimation that
12,000 only concer patient are regularly
use uh medical Canabis uh and uh well
and the answer from agency was there is
no need what it is needed it is on the
oncological Institute again this is the
combination and this is the comparison
that only uh cancer patient are eligible
again to to get yeah to to to get this
so the final goal will be to come to the
pharmacy now this is impossible uh on
the other hand well not why Pharmacy not
because I'm pharmacist but everything
should be regulated in the whole
production chain from the beginning to
the end let me uh Implement something
that I many times I try to uh to give
this example and please try to
understand me correctly for example if
you get a bacterial lung infection what
will be your first uh step to go to
doctor and then to get a prescription
with what antibiotic right and the de is
going to be then delivered to you in the
pharmacy why not look at this why not as
soon as you think or you know that there
it is a bacterial infection why not to
moisture one piece of the bread put on
the uh uh in front of the of of the
window and went for 24 hours there would
be enough aspergilus and penicilium
molds that spread the surface of this
bread believe me there's plenty of
antibiotics inside why because you do
not know the dosage you do not know the
safety and it is very inconvenient and
very ugly to eat this kind of molded
bread so you trust that the final
product with antibiotics which are
produced on the same way they not put
okay bread somewhere but mean I'm
talking about G&amp;P but at the end of the
day this is the same so trust the final
product but allow patient to get it
that's the the goal of the regulation
and I hope as we met karagi this morning
that the new legislation will be uh
adopted soon of course there will be a
lot of discussion but we uh are coming
to this and based on the oncologic
patients uh also the uh Society
Association of oncologic patients in
Slovenia is strongly supporting this
movement and I see in the audience Anna
liter who is the president of that and
congratulate for all the efforts that
you are doing to this patients get a uh
meaningful uh meaningful advice at least
from the doctors thank you and so I
think we are uh rounding up this session
and so I um emphasize here that to catch
up with the global advancement in
Slovenia we really must do Foster first
collaboration between science Academia
and clinics on one hand and Industry on
the other hand and this is clearly what
for what we show for what we show so
foster the uh collaboration between
Academia and uh clinics industry on one
hand and also this should be supported
financially but public private
partnership and this would be more
profitable than anything and of course
we have to be open also to International
uh Financial networks to to get support
for this kind of research because so far
most of the research was done based on
the support of the Pharma companies and
uh the public money in Slovenia nowadays
is spent for prohibition first and then
how to prove the drugs are toxic so the
department of Toxicology in our clinical
Center University clinical Center is
working intensely on that and making
seminars and webinars on these topics
not mentioning the Cannabis can also uh
help cure some disease or at least help
the symptoms to disappear so also this
regulatory um experts and agencies
should work independently of the
politics or
ideological obstacles whatever they are
and uh so I think that we will soon get
to that hopefully but we will try to get
that uh with all our efforts and try to
get more people involved in in our uh
cannabis uh research development and so
thank you very much for your attention
for this all right let's hear it for our
panelists now I want to some questions
we definitely have time for questions
questions questions I'm coming I'm
coming I'm coming over I don't need I
don't no we need we need to
hear yeah I hear you I
can thank you um so we was talking now
about anzing
of the quality and the the percentage of
cabs in uh cannabis plant so my question
is uh how big is the problem with
cannabis plants
diseases and using of pesticides
herbicides and other use of chemicals in
uh farming so uh when you analiz uh
those uh
samples um is there
uh did you find uh something there can
harm uh the uh the health uh of using uh
because obviously uh Farmers uh have uh
to use some chemicals they do so uh I
need I would like to have this answer
and please one another more can I answer
answer this first okay so you are
meaning diseases of the plants and I
think that Andrea would be the best uh
expert on this because she's dealing
with plants and Andrea do you have any
data on the plants uh viruses infection
plants uh cannabis blant viruses
infection or bacteria or whatever or the
pesticides the
harm okay uh thank you yes there are
some uh infections of course with
viruses varat in hemp plant as well uh
they can be treated let's say with heat
treatment or cold treatment it's more
complicated like so we cannot spray
against it uh but there are not allowed
let's say plant protection products in
ham production which are let's say uh
registered but there are some which can
be used for
ecological um growing so there are some
um let's say ecological products which
can be used against uh fungi against
some let's say predator mites which can
be used to uh to uh to strict or to
control the other mites and so on so
there are strict regulations what can
you what can you use but there are not a
lot of them uh which is a general green
deal in EU not to use PL protection
products as much as we can on Market on
on the market products I don't have the
I just know what are what can be used in
plant in hemp growing purp for medical
purposes yeah but I don't know what what
is if the question is what is going on
on the market I don't have those data we
have some regulations we can be sure
that we can what we buy on the market
for
regulation
is regulated is good use there's some
institut or will be
some I don't know if there's a lot of
regulations on the European side on
pesticides and and and whatnot uh right
now maybe maybe we can ask our
pharmacist are there well uh just just a
lot lots and lots all right well I'm
wrong no no no let's all break into
small groups no no we just need to
answer this question first well just
allow me allow me to add this very very
shortly well actually you know now uh
due to the fact that we have this
monograph uh there it is also one
section about the pesticides so as soon
as you are going to fulfill this you are
free I mean you are on the safe side so
don't worry about this now before it was
the responsibility of the producer but
again there is a general legislation in
Europe as was said uh which pesticides
are permitted currents and so on so on
but yes now we have this so what is your
second question please uh may I just add
this before we are going forward so if
if you buy let's say uh the the hemp so
cannabis with ecological biological
certificate before you get it you have
the control there are a few uh let's say
organizations in Slovenia which are
doing a sample so U blind sampling of
the samples they are doing the analysis
and you cannot get the certificate if
you're not following the regulation so
there are few uh few institution which
are covering this so you cannot get
their certificate very easy thank you
and the second before we get to your
second question let's uh we'll get this
one are you're good okay thank you so
much okay thank you and
um hi hi good day I have one question
for Professor David uh we are producer
of CBD oils for many years now and um
one parent with uh with a child who have
who is your patient come to us and ask
for
advice uh and we created one oil which
is 30% of CBD 10% of
CBG and uh in beginning we had some
positive results but then
we try to create something better then
we add U terpenoids 1% in that oil so
after that we get uh way better results
so my question is do you have some data
some knowledge about uh terpenoids that
can help to calm the child because we we
know that let's say the the meren and
Alpha and beta pinets are doing good job
for now but I think that there is more
room to enhance those um those U
medications but still we are still doing
that under like
Cosmetics uh we are doing that regulated
it is really pure it's by GMP hccp and
ISO controlled uh it's it's pure about
uh you know I understand those questions
that that people are asking and also
Blake Market is um can't create that
kind of Purity we can provide but my
question is what can we do in boundary
of the
regulations now we can do only like
cosmetics and of course you you you
suggest to the parents how they can use
it better way uh what can we do more to
help the the the patients thank you yeah
thank you very much for the question it
is actually difficult question um we do
know that um FL flavinoids and
terpenoids and so on they they have a
very good effect um either I it can be a
calming effect or um just the opposite
no and um Professor rouso the famous
neurologist who he did a lot of studies
with these different
Kars um and with the different um uh um
extracts of um um different terpenoids
concentration inside and um it really um
um sometimes um it adds um the effect to
the canabidol and to THC um and
sometimes it can completely change um
the the the effect however um we are for
the time being we are not um able to
analyze it and um even it it will be
very difficult because we are always
calculating the dose according to the
patients's um age and the patients
weight um however but calculating only
canabidol and THC um if um if we would
go further and include the terpenoids
maybe it will be in in the future it
will be definitely um um something much
more effective clinical studies or so I
think we are late uh and we have some
time we have some time we have like two
minutes hi I'm Andrea petre I'm the CE
of alos BPR and hammed Pharma together
with Daniel hanganu with the president
of Hamed Fara I want to ask you a
question uh Professor borut we have done
in Poland and in Romania CBD as elimary
supplement do the government of Slovenia
accept on mutal recognition to notify
this product at
supplement uh well no uh the answer is
no why because simply CBD is still uh
you are talking about CBD right uh yeah
we speaking about the full extract full
CBD you know that efca uh this is still
pending situation with uh efca regarding
the CBD it is CBD is supposed to be a
dietary supplement or a Noel food at the
time being it is not clear answer due to
the fact that uh the agency not I'm not
talking now about the agency for
medicine product but about the uh some
kind of unit dealing with dietary
supplements uh they are very strict in
terms of all regulation in terms of
European Food Safety Authority uh it's
not still uh any kind of decision
whether CBD it could be a diory
supplement uh so now which means that's
why it was said that it was like a
cosmetic this is the the mimics right we
all know but this is the only way at in
Slovenia according strictly according to
the legislation of European s Food
Safety Authority uh CBD is supposed to
be a novel foood because it was consumed
after 1970 uh 97 so uh I would say no
but try
try okay fantastic that's all the time
we have let's hear it once again for all
our panelists Dr turn
[Music]
[Applause]
Dr very informative