more exhibits upstairs too support our
sponsors we'd like to thank ispire for
being the title sponsor for this year's
conference here in Barcelona and we're
going to bring up the next uh Senator
panelists this is we're going to discuss
using innovation technology and research
to improve cannabis and here to lead
this panel is the manager of cannabis
Hub let's hear it for Natalia
thank you
[Applause]
[Music]
all right
nice to meet you
good morning everybody
hope you're having a wonderful time
today
thank you ICBC for having us
and let's welcome Valenzuela
CEO from Valen veras and founder of the
Cannabis Hub within the UPC the
university the Polytechnic University of
Catalonia
basilar
ready sick he's the project manager and
founder from research nature Institute
then we have Carlos ferreiro Vera he's
the CEO of fito plant research
and then we have juancho Rivas he's the
business developer from aptus plantec
please welcome
[Applause]
so we will be talking about
how we use innovation technology and
research to improve cannabis
harnessing science and Ingenuity to move
the Cannabis industry forward
so the first question is what are the
main current challenges of the sector in
Spain and what are the challenges that
your companies and institutions like
Aptos Baden beta's research nature
Institute and fito blend
house as a company according to their
particular activities
Ruben would you like to start or yeah I
can do it okay thanks a lot like that
we're going to be here and it's a pass
for now to have a chance to show what we
are having here in Spain and basically
what we
we really have a problem with MEPS so
it's the urgency that it's complicated
to do the research up to an agency that
let us be really restrictive with all
the documentation it's really slow and
it's not as easy on any other country
especially like for example Portugal so
I would say like what if
the problem that we have is that we
would like to improve that and see how
we could unit forces to to research
together without that limitation
yes I agree as well I don't know I
cannot speak for Spain but International
it's very hard to exchange let's say
samples between the Laboratories or
other things because
even if there is small amount or even
standards for uh you know laboratory
they consider it as a illegal drug so
this should be changed and it was also
initiative from Israel from
because we should be able to cooperate
worldwide
okay from fito plan we have two
different kind of activities one of them
is a research where we generate general
knowledge and another one is
commercialize the knowledge that we
created before
um unfortunately uh the charging the
challenges are the same we have the same
problems uh and unfortunately is is the
amps so I mentioned when before
from our point of view to the balance
correctly or activities both of them is
necessarily a speed up and improve the
channel communication with the amps
and of course is essential Harmony size
the rules into the different countries
in Europe because obviously we are
losing many business opportunities
yes definitely I agree with you guys it
looks like we've been here all morning
and we're all talking about the same
we're all having the same problems AMS
they are not regulating I'm I'm juancho
from Aptos we are a nutrient company and
talking from my side as I mean last year
we had a like 10 projects working here
in Spain this year is known we are
forced to go outside to work outside we
have to go to Portugal we have to go to
Uruguay Czech Republic I mean we should
unify this why why shall I go to
Portugal If it's my neighbor is just
here why I mean is this should have the
same rules and where Europe are we
Europe or what we should be we should be
ruled by the same
laws I believe but that would help us a
lot to work as a company to develop the
company we could create work and
possibilities and pay taxes in the
country I don't know why they don't see
the and they don't help us a little bit
more really
great so regulation is kind of an issue
right now also a little bit of this also
a little lack of the education also they
need also to help us to do a little bit
more of research you know to the
companies that want to to get ready for
this
right
um only one detail maybe I um I am
completely agree with you because uh
unfortunately we haven't uh the the law
that we need with uh the reality that we
have in Spain but I that I tried to
mention before is that uh we need that
the agency has a very fast answer when
we try to
um asking for something and essentially
uh speed up the bureaucracy procedures
when we try to
maintain the license that we have
because the rules is very restrictive
but a seats
was one of the first companies
researching in Europe and it's something
special we've got lucky time ago to be
able to research on cannabis but right
now compared with Portugal Adventure
we're saying information just can give
you an answer in one two weeks Mbps
could take four to six months so how
you're gonna research in our industry
having that long time of reply so yeah
thank you
thank you well seeing this
um the next question is then how are you
making use of Ingenuity to push these
limits currently
so
um yeah
actually from the Cannabis Hub we saw
that we have a lack of Regulation into
the hemp inside Spain
France is really increasing the
production they already have uh more
than 18
000 hectares of crop and we don't have
we don't have any decorticator in Spain
and then we were looking why we have
that problem in Spain and what is going
on what happened we cannotch track so we
cannot extract once we grow even seeds
of fiber the biomass cannot be used so
for extraction usually Farmers they send
it to Germany or France or any other
place that they could extract
and furthermore we have all that issues
with some varieties than in our climate
are not really producing as we expect
and that we have the limitation on zero
three percent
we came with the idea inside the
Cannabis Hub to present the p l Bernardo
proposed it before and we were showing
them a bit how we could press the
government that they don't need to
change the law they just need to have a
different view about the hemp and how we
could be competent and related with
other countries so um what we are doing
we are just presenting a p l is a
proposal no law to change that rules
inside the hemp and being able to be
really productive here and have a chance
to to revolutionize the hemp industry
this is what we are doing
uh yes we are also now
somehow organizing uh cannabis Hub in
Slovenia or actually we want to connect
all the players in Slovenia for uh you
know quicker and better growth of
cannabis
[Music]
business but this field is also
important education and the quick
response or transfer the knowledge from
the research facilities to the industry
so all the uh you know stakeholders can
benefit from from this we have a lot of
knowledge
we have a lot of investors on this field
but all these things are I think too
much dispersed and we have have to
somehow bring them together for you know
benefit of it
yeah
from my point of view try to find
solutions to these issues is a little
bit complicated especially if we try to
to do something alone so for me the key
uh for solve these problems is the
collaboration because you know the
threats lies in the numbers
so
um for this reason for the plan uh
collaborate with different associations
satms in USA economics Hub here in
Catalonia we have created aikame the
first Association of companies with
authorization by the MPS for production
or for scientific purposes
um but I I think that the key is the
collaboration and the change the culture
um from my personal point of view
um to change something is by the
education for that reason here in
Catalonia in the University of uh of
Catalonia we have created the first
master's degree noise is a postgraduate
course where we try to educate the the
new generation about the benefits of the
plants and how is using the law that the
very strictly loud that we have here is
possible work correctly with the plan in
all the possibilities that this amazing
plant has
necessarily with you basically it's
definitely one person alone is not
strong enough in this case and when
we're together we're gonna be stronger
and these days for instance this to last
two days that we've been at the Cannabis
Cup working you come up with a lot of
ideas
and ways to work to try to convince the
politicians that are at the end the ones
that has to do something about this so
this is why I think that the Cannabis
Hub is really really important in these
cases for us to be stronger and and get
to know to to get to reach one point
together
thank you all apart from this
um some people might think how are you
able to collaborate when some of you are
even competitors so the next question is
what's the benefit of collaborating when
you are sometimes competitors and how
does this improve or boost the
development of more competitive and
Innovative products
uh uh for example in my case I think
that the problem that feed plan has are
common of the rest of the company
so I repeat again the same answer the
threat lies in the numbers so if I try
to do something alone is maybe maybe I
haven't the capacity to change something
but if we if we collaborate with
somebody a special expert in this sector
maybe we can found a new solution a new
idea a new channel of communication with
the agency
etc etc so again the collaboration I
think that is the key if I found
something interesting for us is
interesting for my competitor but
everybody win at the end this is
thank you
yeah well I think that collaborating
with a competitor can provide access to
data analytics and trends and new
resources that are mutually beneficial
that's for sure working together can
help identify sales opportunities and
promote gross selling and even you know
even though sometimes we are competitors
in the same sector
as I said before I think in some cases
we have to be together we have to be
together because we have in this case we
have the same interest as some of the
companies that are in the hub or or
similar interested you know so
basically is to convince the politics to
let us work and this is what we have to
do
I agree if we will you know stand
together then as mentioned we will have
uh
or we can make big bigger pressure to
the you know decision makers to change
the the rules and the sharing this
experience and the knowledge between the
you know companies and the research
facilities will definitely lead to
faster growing industry because if we
will hide from each other then nobody on
the end nobody will benefit
and as I mentioned before connect in
this industry and Science and transfer
the knowledge to the industry uh as soon
as possible we have big challenges now
you know cannabis can replace so many
things from the insulation to it's not
just you know so-called recreational or
medical it's so so much other things we
can get from cannabis
yeah
collaborate with a competitor when we
are in a really young industry it's the
forest there isn't any tree there and
there are growing few trees but still is
all to do so if you think about your
competitor I think it could be your
friend in many of the parts and for sure
we're going to have our own private
things but there is an example not
within the Cannabis have
we saw an opportunity to develop a
technology that could evaluate the many
different characters from from from hemp
from fiber from seeds from flowers and
then instead of being fighting between
us we just collaborate and together we
develop that technology that at the end
is one of the benefits to other
companies so
think it's so young the industry that we
still have a lot of collaborations to do
and actually there are other big
companies that have more power that if
we don't play together they are going to
play the game so I think there's a good
chance right now to have other
collaborations and being together in
that Hub I think is a really good
opportunity to grow
that's right
thank you guys
well let's move for move forward with
what are the latest innovations that
you're developing in your
businesses in in institutions
foreign
all the time we are generating new
genetics of course because we are
genetics
um and as well as different kind of
method to extract or purify compounds to
uh in order to license this knowledge to
our customer but if you're asking about
the the last or the most important one
um the latest things you've been doing
that you would like to share for example
okay that are relevant to you okay uh
because there are a lot of information
I'm doing 11 years into the company what
you're more passionate about yeah we
have many things maybe the most
important one of the the last one was
the five papers scientific paper that we
published at the last year uh we talk in
this studies about the new technology
not new technology new possibility to
the micro preparation systems
um
using in vitro cultures
we have evaluated different molecules of
asking us what happened about the
manager of the plan and we have
discovered that the uh this uh some of
these molecules
um
accelerate the metabolism and increase
the concentration of some cannabinoids
after that we have polish review where
we evaluate all data on the pool league
data patterns about destruction and
purification Mission methods in order to
offer
um something from an industrial point of
view to the society
after that we
um have a greater collaboration with the
hospital Veterinarian Hospital of the
University of Cordoba where we evaluate
the pharmacogenetic
of CBD in two different two different
um
how to say that Pathways and
[Music]
administration
bias
and finally we have polish something
about the equality control where we
evaluate the effect of the temperature
and this is something very relevant
because
in the last table we the participant
mentioned that some in some cases the
analysis are a little bit different
between
the labs
and sometimes in this publication we
show how the temperature affect to the
results and maybe modify the quantity of
DHC levels and the cultivars could be a
very high problem
I think that this is a good summary
thank you a lot of work
so it's a lot
mainly from Bad Emperors we are so proud
that we are going to launch during this
week our new nir system that could
analyze
a bit about the technology we saw the
companies that have been playing with
that but we are really lucky we've got a
really good collaboration with SeaWorld
a company from United States uh that
provide together with us on the Hub we
can have many other companies breeders
and feedbacks that help us develop that
system after four years we are going to
launch it so I welcome everyone to come
to overstand and see that technology
that I'm so proud that without it
uh yes our Innovations we're not really
Innovations but uh in the last few years
we were helping with the several uh you
know doctorates or Master degrees for
our students and the faculty of Health
Sciences uh then we together with
biotechnological faculty
we are we have a project of family
growing under different conditions on
different places in Slovenia where we
follow and actually our
chief of flight is following the
cannabinet interpret profiles or from
different areas for the different
strains
then we are now working on the
development of biodegradable polymers
from hemp which I hope will sometimes in
the future you know replace the petrol
based polymers
our work we also presented on the last
kind of World Conference in in Colombia
uh also as a scientific word work where
we also presented the
[Music]
uh samples analysis of samples which was
used by
uh
patients from the black market so we're
also following this part I know it's uh
semi-legal but it's very important that
we obtain data what the people are using
you know to improve their health so this
is in short
yeah well yes
we are a beer stimulants and special
fertilizers producers
um at the moment I'm going to tell you
the three projects that we are working
and at the same time collaborating with
the Hub with the universities here in
Barcelona okay at the moment we are
doing some evaluation of patented the
Emulsion of plant oils on monosilic acid
as a tank mix
additive for a better performance of PPP
it's also trying to reduce the use of
pesticides okay in the other side we
have developed a growth system that is
GMP certified
is acquired with a Vortex spray device
for able root system basically we're
working with two group systems and we
are implementing some sensors together
with the students at the University at
the UPC to improve the the the system
basically
um mixing the both projects together we
are also working with at the faculty of
biology here at the University of
Barcelona optimizing the expression of
genotype in in specific strengths of
CBD hemp okay this is basically where we
are right now
okay thank you guys
so maybe let's move to the last question
then we open a space for questions
so how to Envision the Cannabis industry
looking like in the future from a
research and Technology ecosystem
perspective I mean what does it depend
on to fulfill this vision
well we see it we look we see working
with clean wealth sources and under
quality control formulated produce
products I mean we want to go to for a
cleaner Planet this is the idea to work
with less residual products we work with
non-heavy Metals at all in the products
we have also developed developed the the
growth system as I said
to economize the the the growth system
we are going to work with the less plans
but at the same time we want to have the
same production but with this we are
going to reduce cost of production time
nutrient soil
about that apart that the materials used
are all
how would you say it in English like
clean materials not not residue
materials okay
and I think data is going to be the
future so that's why we are also working
in implementing all kind of sensors in
our crop to get the maximum data
possible from our crop
like this we also reduce cost because we
can improve all the all the treatments
okay this this has for the future and
this is what we are working
yeah
um the connection with is my idea is the
data for me to to um to create a future
a company with future is essential to
Innovation and for that reason fetal
plan is focus complete is completely
focused in the science uh in great
Innovation and explore the data uh later
the explore the knowledge and uh this is
the problem the science The Innovation
we have two different problems we need
that the company have uh feel free to to
to create something new and the another
problem is always the same the money so
what we need we need a stable rules from
the government without the varieties or
during the time or maybe
interpretation of that because uh if
something changes maybe a product of
three or four years could be disappear
in only one moment and something
important in the morning so we
appreciate if the government the
government create special grants
to to help us to develop something
interesting for the community at the end
because this is the future of the
society The Innovation the data at the
end
thank you Carlos yes definitely you know
simple legislation is the key for
developing this Market because
everything what is over regulated you
can almost not come forward you know
but the other things I hope that or
maybe we see that everybody is realizing
that cannabis will be the next
Industrial Revolution from the point of
sustainability you know from I don't
know many of things we are using today
from plastic from whatever can be
replaced with sustainability use
sustainable plant
uh and uh and the plant or processing
the hemp has much lower
environmental and CO2 impact you know if
you produce whatever from hemp it we use
much less energy energy than if we use
you know the traditional waste so I hope
that we all will you know bring this
together and our lawmakers with finally
get it that there's must be changes soon
I agree thank you good uh just to finish
my view of the future of that industry
is to exactly replace the petrol
to see the new Evolution of all what
this plant can give us to not destroy
the plan to change the humanity to see
that we have a powerful plan that
together with data with universities and
with Innovation we can actually change
all what we use our homes our clothes
all our furniture our cars everything
could be made out of hemp so I think
this is the filter that we want to see
when we create the Hub and actually
within Venice we always have been trying
to look for new technologies
collaborating with companies to look for
that future the companies that are going
to develop that technologies that are
going to replace the products that
everyone is using are going to be the
ones that are going to have the key
point to develop that industry and it's
not going to be for smokers for patients
it's going to be for everyone so that's
my future and my view please let's work
together to develop that industry that
technologies have done Innovations and
let's do it together I think there is a
lot there and we are missing the point
so view unit forces we have a big chance
and I just want to add you know I hope
that industry or investor will realize
that there will be no moves without real
investors
you know
because to develop some new product you
need a lot of money and it's hard to get
money from the bank these days so we are
really depend on the this sector
I agree I agree for sure Carlos was
saying France we say investors we need
money but for sure I think we need to be
consumers will start that Revolution
once we start buying chemicals people
will start doing people will invest
companies will invest in him to develop
that industry so I think we all of us
the ones that we are here in the world
need to start consuming hemp products to
let that Revolution go
yeah quite an holistic uh change what we
need well thank you very much
and is there any question for the
speakers
[Applause]
hello my name is Christian Gaya
I'm listening to
um
More Than This panel and everybody
agrees on that the law must change and
the laws makers must be convinced and
there must be pressure on lawmakers and
so on
so we all know that politic is heavily
influenced by Lobby
Lobby work so what do you think about
how this process is maybe interfered by
pharmaceutical Lobby
behind that totally it's totally related
MEPS is control exactly by the
government they don't allow us to do
research and develop our Industries here
because they are the ones that have it
who is the one that is exporting
cannabis in Spain is the company is
related with the King and like with all
but we know Franco and all
the bad situation that we had in our
country so for sure it's obvious this is
why I was saying that if we change that
concern for sure it's going to be
difficult to change the economy's law we
already do it all the black market do it
so everyone is consuming cannabis in
Spain we are waiting a lot but everyone
is already using cannabis so what I
think is that we have the power as a
consumers to strive to look into other
Industries and yeah they love it control
everything it's only us as a consumers
that could press and see how it's gonna
this change
this is my viewer
um
um of course
the minister of Agriculture mentioned
before that the agency and don't create
Laos so only regulate the situation
so it's a politician
the answer is in the politicians so the
MPS is only a regulator
if we don't have the capacity Life
Society to uh
demand a new situation the MPS haven't
the tools to do nothing is the minister
so
yeah I certainly agree because the
biggest problems are not the politicians
the biggest problems of bureaucrats
because politicians they change they
have to go to elections at least every
four years you know then they promise US
whatever but when it comes all to the
bureaucratic Mills it stops I am in this
process in Slovenia for 20 years I was
on I don't know how many committees for
Health and Social Justice and whatever
politicians in Slovenia you will not
find even one politician who is against
the regulation of cannabis not even
police for example but bureaucratson
Ministry of Health and so on
they stop the things you know because
they had they they are not elected they
are there forever and that's the point
and I hope this new government and the
the new some
officials and the Ministries uh that we
will be able to change this perspective
very soon and that's that's the only way
among education of course
yeah I I agree with you he
um I mentioned before that of course in
Spain the bureaucratic system is chaotic
and a disaster for the companies if we
try to do something new especially so
yeah I I just want to mention that I
don't know is Romania is exporting
cannabis but the the funny priorities
that we don't have a medicinal law but
we export and actually the ones are
exporting related with the government
and all these bureaucracies so what I
was saying is just look to the numbers
look to the money and who is the one
that is exporting and then you will have
your answer
you know it's everything you shady area
regarding the single convention any
extractor of cannabis is illegal even
hemp extract CBD extract is against the
single convention so there must be
changes maybe not we will never move a
single convention because it's here like
for 60 years and it will be another but
at least
you know inside the European Union or
whatever because this is really a
nonsense after 60 years
hey thank you for your words my question
would be
a common sense Logic for the future of
cannabis for example in Europe uh
wouldn't be it much more better if we
would have communities in the model like
we have tomatoes you know like
more home Growers are the most cannabis
is grown by home Growers even more than
the industry in the whole world will
grow in the future and the Tomato model
exemplifies exactly this kind of like
you have old strains you have the
industry which is growing you have uh
you know everybody grows Tomatoes if you
have a garden why not cannabis and why
not regulate it in the same way yeah
can answer that because somebody's gonna
go but what about the children
save the children from weed you can't
just grow weed at your house kids will
get the wrong idea
that's the problem and then also when
you tell a bunch of Corporations
oh go ahead uh you you don't have to
convince convinced people like us you
know you have to address this to
somebody else
we know we are fighting for this but
it's hard to explain this to the
bureaucrat which is always in the same
mode bureaucratic mode
engineer was studying here at the
University of Barcelona and I was like
yeah I really want to learn how to do
the best cannabis in the world and then
I was talking with my teachers which is
the most powerful uh crop related with
the economy and he was his tomato it's
really what really it's tomato it is
it's tomato but I would say as uh he was
mentioning you know what about the kids
and he's actually a psychoactive
substance which we should have been
regulated but I would say why we don't
have it as a wine
and we have been talking a lot about
that and it's really related we always
want to have the cheapest wine that
we're gonna have in the supermarket
which is one even liter and you are
going to be able to have your 200
000 or whatever a really good wine so I
would say I like the idea of a tomato
but I could probably prefer to compare
with wine
actually we have a good wine law in
Slovenia which says that everybody can
have wine at home as much as you want up
to I don't know tons of liters your own
wine homegrown but as soon as you enter
the market you have to fill fulfill
certain uh you know regulations and I
think it should be regulated completely
the same way
one more question from here please
hello and my name is Sergio I'm a
production director in linear health
well we have all the problems that you
already mentioned about the AMS about
regulatory about laws everything you
mentioned we have the same problem we
don't have the only ones who are let's
say producing for exporting Spain many
many other peoples has a license
I don't see any benefit we are getting
to be linear I mean
there is nothing different from each
other so I'm agree about what Carlos
said
that we should be together in order to
push new regulations and and of course
we will be close in order to understand
what you are doing because we are doing
something similar so
I'm here in order to to know you and and
push together
I could be a super pleasure I think Hub
would really need to be together with
Lineo sorry if I said something that
could
um
um yeah yeah it's exactly but uh I was
just looking to the numbers no I would
not say that you are the the first
exporter no you jump from 6 to 24.5 tons
which is actually wow man you really
good and uh I don't know I would say
like yeah please let's work together I
think there are a lot of companies and a
lot of projects that jump from Spain to
Portugal because Mbps is really
difficult to work and uh who knows why
this was my point of view but I'm sure
we could work together and I would love
that sorry one comment uh because I
agree that is very uh is not fast
is not easy because you need a
pharmacological knowledge but the rule
assist and you can work with the MPS
because I am working with two different
kind of licenses during 11 years so
only like a comment
foreign
I'd like to make a comment about this um
maybe we're approaching government in
the wrong way if you look at Canada and
the United States the amount of money
that has been collected in taxes is wild
and you know it it right now countries
need money for infrastructure for
everything so why not approach
government in a way that we can actually
save you with the amount of Revenue it
is over taxed in Canada absolutely but
you know the different U.S states it's
it's incredible how much money is being
collected by governments
you know I know this we therefore we are
making Now new approach it's it's not
just this it's also human rights and you
know uh uh for example in Slovenia we
spent yearly 20 million euro to
prosecute people or to you know imprison
people which are on the end release by
Supreme Court
because you know to help yourself it
cannot be a criminal offense so why we
are spending 20 million euro yearly on
nothing that's where 2 million people in
Slovenia we are not big nation you know
but but you know now it's coming slowly
and uh if we all together we'll pull
this Wagon in the same direction then it
will be much easier yeah I would like
that I totally agree with you actually
we have been uh during that working
teams inside the canaries Hub we have
been trying to evaluate how we could
um proceed with our report show it to
the government how taxes compare with
already countries like yours know that
we already have a sample uh in the panel
before they were talking about how the
pharmaceutical Lobby
has the power into that country and
that's the key only Spain spend the
devil than friends and Germany you know
so I think
that's something that good related to me
with that so what what can we do no this
was one of the points let's do that
report let's show it and yesterday we
were talking about what can we do we
need a revelation and listen to the
medicinal cannabis we have been waiting
December would say the way that we were
expecting in December and we still are
March and we don't have any answer and
we are suffering that is going to change
the government and we're still not gonna
fall low so this is something telling
you you know there's a huge Lobby
here pressing that and what can we do go
go to the streets work together or at
least try to find a solution but I love
that point thank you
any more questions
any more questions we have two more
minutes
all right all right then thank you very
much for the panel