okay
coming up right now one of our sponsors
this man is the founder
and the ceo of grow glide and he's going
to talk about vertical integration into
your cannabis farming
he's back there let's hear it for travis
schwartz
trevor schwartz
charlie hodge
you got it just grab one of those
microphones
how's it going today everybody
uh my name is travis schwartz i'm here
with uh growglide uh i think we're gonna
need a minute while they uh sort out
some slide situation
um all right so here we go thank you
all right let's catch up so here you can
see the what's a single tube what we
would consider a single tier versus a
multi-tier it's two or more
today we're going to talk about a few
different subjects we're going to talk
about california
and how
vertical is taken off there of the
cannabis capital of the world
reasons why to go vertical
lessons learned from our time in the us
doing vertical and the european
advantage
um in california was a pioneer for
cannabis in the united states and this
market continues to be one of the
strongest to date
in this picture you are sorry
and this picture is kind of uh how in
the early days there were a few
large there were very few large scale
black marker grows
here you're seeing
what we would call a typical
single tiered
primarily hps dominated
image
most of these were as i said small scale
really simple to set up
also called trap grows
and most people were just kind of doing
what worked mentally
in late 2018 the industry started to
evolve you started to see multi-tier
coming out
many of the first
solution providers were storage
innovators
who made slight changes to their product
and labeled them for indoor growing
picture here is a kind of generation one
of a grow glide rack
with integrated
drainage and
sloped drainage system
and obviously they're on wheels to
optimize the floor's base
there's a very robust market going
forward in the last 18 months we've seen
vertical cannabis explode
most investors no longer tolerate single
tier build builds
and growers have adapted to complexity
vertical cultivation in the united
states
it's almost impossible to gauge the
market potential of the future for new
builds but we've determined that the
old single-tiered market that can be
converted is roughly 2 billion
this is one of my favorite pictures this
is actually some of the guys from jungle
boys and the cure company they're
visiting one of our customers in long
beach california this picture is taken
on the third tier which
which about five meters up
many people would believe that you can't
grow quality product in a multi-tier
environment
hopefully you can see from this picture
that that is in fact not true
the key to the success is proper
planning
and products
but we're going to touch on the vertical
advantage so by going vertical
you obviously can increase your roi by
up to 300 or more
many times cultivation licensing is tied
to an actual single address
so by utilizing your existing height and
floor space you can increase the roi
without additional licenses
last but not least environmentally with
proper planning and vertical
[Music]
growers can minimize land waste
power waste and water waste
as an entrepreneur i know firsthand how
exciting it is to build a new business
and how quickly it can fall apart if you
skip over the details so the lessons
that we've learned is planning planning
and planning
poor planning leads to poor performance
obviously we love multi-tier and are
huge advocates however it's not a magic
cure-all
proper preparation is critical
sorry proper
proper preparation is critical to the
success of your vertical grow and the
benefits that you all want to achieve
these three key issues that we're going
to cover next are the difference between
a vertical grow that's successful and a
never-ending headache
those three key things are going to be
workflow microclimates and safety
workflow is obviously from the beginning
designing to your building to thinking
about your team's best efficiencies
workflow is going to be crucial
microclimates is by far the number one
biggest issue that people don't think
about when they go to a multi-tier grow
you have the issues with
humidity and temperature
across the different levels throughout
the room
and growing excel is great growing at
quality is better
proper air flow is going to be the
number one biggest thing which i just
mentioned
and you've got to get that air to move
around both within the layer and up and
down so
there's a few solutions on the market
happy to talk about those more later
and then last but not least is safety so
your cultivation team is going to be
working at you know heights up to 15 20
feet off the ground how are they
protected what are the safety processes
you have in place
the european advantage
is
obvious in that the
you guys have had the
the advantage of
being first to market and really
innovative in the agriculture space
um
also you can watch and learn from some
of the mistakes that we've made from the
early pioneers of vertical cannabis in
the united states
so europe's big ag industry
uh has some major innovators from the
inn farms to the nordic harvest these
companies are really making headlines
today and for the last decade
cannabis cultivators can lean on this
open attitude and really skip the single
tier growing phase
the u.s is currently transitioning out
of
some of you may have had the chance to
meet our new team member uh but ludwig
uh simone is joining us who is the head
of operations at one of the largest uh
vertical farming ag operations here in
europe and he's joined groveglide's team
as a gm of europe so if you haven't had
a chance to catch him uh come see him in
our booth number one
uh so now i'm going to kind of cover
some of the predictions that i
anticipate to happen in europe as it
relates to vertical cultivation
uh based on the experience in the u.s
so obviously the demand for european
cannabis will be cannabis will be robust
as jamie pearson mentioned this morning
it's likely to be very underestimated
germany on its own has the potential to
be a four billion dollar market
secondly the u.s multi-tier is rapidly
going to continue to shift uh to
a higher count of tiers and they're
going to focus on utilizing sas software
solutions to ensure consistency and
quality throughout their products
there will be continued to be
consolidation among multi-tier vendors
and as i believe that flour will always
remain king from a product standpoint
extraction which requires high volume of
flour
to make various products from resins to
rosins to edibles etc
those are going to continue to skyrocket
as the mature the market in europe
continues to mature
cannabis is going to be a true cash crop
driving further innovation through over
the in the overall ag tech market
the overlap between ag and cannabis
cultivation will continue to increase
and at this point i believe that
vertical ag is actually starting to
learn from vertical cannabis versus the
other way around it's been going for the
last decade
more technology tools will continue to
be created to help
cultivators plan
a successful operation from that
workflow climate and safety standpoint
i'm stealing this idea from jamie
pearson but we're going to have lots of
time for questions here so this is a
quick qr code in case somebody wants to
download this presentation to learn more
but i'd love to open it up to any types
of questions that people have as it
relates to vertical ag airflow workflow
anything along those fronts
and um
yeah i know i speak really fast so i'm
sorry for that
young lady in the red
[Applause]
how much time do i have to give you in
order to
have you prepare what i need how much
advanced time do wait let's do it into
the microphone hold on a minute i'm
sorry i was
if i'm building out a grow
how much time do i have to give you when
at what point in the process do i need
to come
talk to you about
what i need
thank you for that that's a great
question um
so to go back to the planning phase um
as early as possible you know we have
cultivators who come to us who
uh
haven't had they don't have a building
yet um ideally you're in the planning
phase before really anything has been
done a lot of times our team is uh very
knowledgeable from we have a lot of
cultivators on the team and they can
actually help you kind of design your
project around workflow um
generally we're seeing people talking to
us anywhere from
i would say eight to 12 months before
their facility is actually they're ready
to install the the racking system um
but it also comes we have people who
show up a month before they need it so
the more planning the better success
you're gonna have in the long run for
sure
any other questions plan ahead everyone
i always tell people especially in this
industry start early you're high
you guys all waiting for the translation
to go through
have you learned everything you can
today no more no one has any questions
at all
no
does it triple your yields
at least at least
all right that's all the questions i had
then do you have another question jimmy
is there anything that you've been asked
here that's been surprising when you
were out on the expo hall that
has given you pause about what's
happening in europe
that's a great question i think that um
the most notable thing that i've learned
is that
some areas are far they're much farther
ahead
than i would have anticipated as far as
places that are operational
um
and
i've also heard from a handful of people
who seem to have more knowledge in the
space than i that
germany likely will take longer to
to get uh recreational open than they
anticipate just due to the kind of the
things going on in the world right now
so i think that both the positive and
negative the negative being germany is
going to be behind but everywhere else
seems to be
much more
ahead or prepared
can you retrofit
existing grows
that's a great question i mean you
definitely can
you definitely can retrofit obviously
you're you're going to have
limitations to deal with whether that's
um what your ceiling height is that's
generally your biggest limit um secondly
do you have enough power to convert to a
multi-tier
from both the lighting perspective and
the hvac perspective
jump in if anyone else has questions
but i have a question another one can
you do this with sodium halogen lights
or does it have to be led
uh yeah that's a good one uh you
definitely can
my co-founder darren actually started
with hps uh for multi-tier you just need
probably an extra 12 to 18 inches per
tier in order to be able to have the
spacing to do so
but it's 100 possible
how many tiers can you go up
uh you're unlimited based on your
ceiling height um we've done up to six
tiers before i probably need about 28
feet which is
about nine i think uh meters
but most people don't most people are in
that fifty you need about 15 feet to do
two tiers 12 to 15 and ideally 18 to 20
feet uh so five and a half meters uh to
do three tiered system for flower
systems are nowadays like roguelites is
very
adjustable so you can fit it into
two-inch increments to come up with
whatever size you you need so our motto
is to help growers grow how they want to
not tell them how they need to
do you guys give
virtual help so you don't necessarily
have to go right to the physical grow
you can do this
like somebody in europe if you're back
in america they can
you can work with them uh over zoom
uh yeah that's actually how we work with
most of our customers we have a full
team of about 10 on our solutions team
who's able to walk you through the
process get you
the specifications for me that you would
need
over zoom we have some really cool room
generation tools where you can kind of
see your product uh in real time and we
we
also send out um
we have some virtual reality type
applications to where you can see a 360
view of your uh of the product
all right are there any more questions
oh fine i'll put the one in the back
i was texting my friend in arizona i was
about to do a 25 000. we can't hear you
just wait i'm on my way i wore the
comfortable shoes
simple question just texting my friend
in arizona who's doing 25 000 square
foot four-tier grow
and he's like this sounds fascinating
where can i come
see this guy and what he can do
yeah so we're based out of riverside
southern california
so we have a full showroom there we have
about 70 cultivations that we've
installed in the last 12 months totaling
about a half a million square feet
those are spread about across about 12
states
and we do have a handful of those
customers who will allow like scheduled
visits
so i'd say southern california and we
could probably swing one in arizona
potentially
thank you
i just want to make a comment i think
you brought in the future
to
to this conference because vertical
farming will be
the future in terms of protection of the
the lands
and
in terms of
sustainability of the planet health
quality of life of course we need more
and more production and this is the
answer congratulations thank you so much
appreciate that thank you guys
travis schwartz ceo and co-founder of
globalize globelight.com
grow glide for all your growing and
gliding needs