[Music]
yo what's up ICBC family we are in for a
real treat today I know I'm in for a
treat because I'm at my first German
cannabis Pharmacy that specializes in
cannabis I'm with Manu and Lao here and
they have created something amazing
right in the heart of Munich at Helios
uh Pharmacy and uh just if you both
could just really introduce yourselves
really quick and Manu uh what do you do
here um hi I'm Manuel I'm uh the CEO and
co-founder of Helios cannabis and I'm
the brain behind the Cannabis section
and uh the Cannabis concept for the
store here and how long has the store
been open right in the heart of mic so
the store open uh we opened the store at
the 19th of February I guess this year
so um just of months so thanks so much
for giving us the tour it was so cool
one thing that was really interesting to
me is that it reminded me of Harbor Side
uh dispensary back in Oakland like about
15 years ago because You' separated you
have you have a separate area for for
cannabis and as far as I know uh that
you're one of the first people if not
the first to actually do that and if not
the only ones to do it now and of course
that reminds me of a a dope uh harbor
side was the dopest California
dispensary back in the day so what how
did you come up with that uh uh concept
MH yo uh this concept um has their
rootings uh when I joined oam University
back in 2016 you went to oam I was an
Alum at sterdam U big up oer Dam shout
out Dale yes and Jeff yeah um so if
you're willing to get some knowledge in
cannabis so because you went to
oaksterdam and you took their classes on
dispensary you were dispensaries you
were able to then incorporate that into
the pharmacy model for Germany and make
it more efficient than than it would be
if you were just normally you go to the
counter and you can the same people go
to the counter who want cannabis or not
Canabis so that has to be a little bit
cumbersome or confusing at times I'm
sure do the Cannabis patients need a
little more time for example exactly
like that yeah so we started um when
with cannabis with a normal Pharmacy um
a little bit um outside of Munich and we
had exactly um this type of situations
uh that we always had problem when it
comes uh those type of patients come
together and we decided that we need a
secondary Pharmacy where we just
focusing on the on the uh distribution
of cannabis and since I joined uh oam a
few years ago um that is something I
always wanted to bring up with and um
I'm I'm really glad that my uh business
partners um are following my vision with
that and um put their heart also into it
like I do and bring cannabis
to the people and uh spread the love for
cannabis and the the special needs you
can get out of can you giving me [ __ ]
Goosebumps right now I'm serious man
this is the revolution in in Germany it
really feels like something special is
happening what you guys are doing is
Cutting Edge Leo uh what do you do here
with us I'm Leo I'm one of the pharmacy
owners and the second one is missing
today it's Stefan our senior partner who
founded the first Farm where we started
all the things in back in 1996 so um
yeah and so what do you do do you do you
do formulations also yeah not only but
we are specialized in doing formulations
so it's not only the the flower itself
but we can do a lot of different type of
formulations um we can do extractions we
can do mechanical separations um with
the with rosin that we get from there
for example we can do other stuff like
nalin we can do Olio gels all kind of
topicals but in all based on medical Bas
that is dope homie so so so two weeks so
unfortunately 2 weeks ago you guys got
raided by the Bish uh police and they
came in and they took your your H your
your hash extraction and the equipment
and all the equipment freeze dryer and
all all kind of stuff that all because
the Wasing system was too
heavy it out but um yeah but they took
it all because they said that uh doing
all that kind of formulation is against
the current law cannabis law which was
released or implemented in April 1 of
April this year um but we are a pharmacy
so actually we have the right to do all
kind of formulations not only with
cannabis but with all kind of medical
stuff we can do cocaine eye drops we can
do
ketamine much harder drugs you can do
these formulations but for some reason
they said you couldn't do it with that
with thatman law that was implemented in
April is split into two sections one for
the consuming part for normal P normal
um uh people that are private consumers
that are
ERS home C this is the consuming part of
the law and then you have the medical
part of the law where you get the
wholesalers Distributors producers and
pharmacies loc so they said you were
going against some
consumer really yes that's that's what
theyy consumer if I'm at home and I do
any kind of extraction it's
forbidden that's clear but as we do it
here we have the prescription from a
German physician so here we are which we
had which we had exactly so here we are
in the pharmacy that's not the private
space right so all we do here is a
something that we do in the pharmacy and
all kind of formulations that we do are
medical formulation so um that's what we
don't understand why they why they yeah
it doesn't so it sounds like you don't
have to be the world's greatest German
lawyer to understand that that sounds
like they're doing a little making a
statement maybe a little bit showing you
know how they feel about it or whatever
however um as we know in the states when
this stuff happened before then this is
a good time to obviously take it to
court uh when the law looks at it
objectively it sounds like you will win
your case even though it's a lot of
money and a big hassle to do it but you
boys could set uh a clear precedent for
Germany and is that what you guys plan
to do yes definitely definitely have to
they don't uh give us another option
because uh they try to charge us with
complete wrong law we can't say okay you
did a you did a mistake let's do it like
that because when we don't say no
against those type of uh it is a fraud
they try to do um when we don't do
anything against this who will it and so
we got a big up the Helios boys right
here because a lot of people are in this
game just to make some money you know
and that's fine if people want to get
into the game to make some money I'm not
one to judge but when you find real cats
at Helios right here you know like Manu
and Lao these guys are in the middle of
the fight right now when everything's
opened up these are the guys setting new
precedents you know we we have a saying
once you legalize that's when the fight
really begins and you guys are right in
the middle of it so I appreciate your
time thank you big
up much you guys right on thanks boom
[Music]
now