we are very blessed to have this keynote
speaker here um all the way from Seattle
I don't know if yall are hip to
leafly.com but they are an amazing
website uh they have all sorts of
educational and
informational uh videos and articles and
I write for them so you know I'm very
excited um and I'm on a couple I think
I'm on some cannabis 101 videos too and
some things and they have a really
really solid president presence in the
United States and uh all over the world
really it's the internet so you can do
anything you want but she's here to talk
to us and we're very excited let's hear
for the CEO of leafly.com Yoko
[Applause]
miasa good morning Berlin and thank you
perfect pronunciation there of my last
name um I'm so excited to be here with
you
today what a momentous occasion and you
know what what's sticking with me is
that
approval rates I've read were 45% in
this country 45% approval ratings for
legalization you did this in the US we
have 90% of the people who support
legalization and I can tell you at the
federal level it's going
nowhere the other thing I'm excited
about uh I'm Japanese by background born
in Japan raised in the US our system our
legal system in Japan very much rooted
in what Germany has done so my personal
hope here is that my home country can
take what you've done and replicate that
better versions yes but this is the
first seed this is how it
grows so I'm I'm really excited about
the advocacy and the partnership that's
come to fruition to achieve reform it
takes so much time and dedication and
many of you are in this room gorg Alex
so many others who've made it happen and
I wish you a heartfelt congratulations
and massive gratitude for that
achievement that personal advocacy the
years of dedication you've pushed this
industry that we care so much about
forward but soak it in today cuz our
work is nowhere near done that work
includes transitioning consumers to
Legal
channels creating sensible
regulation solving the complexities of
injustices that have long served and
really undoing years of negative deeply
rooted
stigma and that work that work has to be
grounded in education education about
cannabis that's derived from science
research and
data so of course at the center of this
learning is a plant a plant that that's
been in use for over 10,000 years
traveling the world following our
patterns of human migration being put to
countless historic and current
uses thousands of years later since
2010 Leaf Le has focused on connecting
people with the long history of this
plant how it's been used and how it can
be used to enhance lives and leveraging
what we've learned about this plan and
continue to learn to share knowledge and
build community through our online
website and mobile
apps in our second decade now we now
welcome over 70 million visitors a year
who come to Leaf Le to research and
learn about cannabis and in North
America to purchase and order products
from thousands of licensed Brands and
retailers so that role we play as a
convenor an indirect Market participant
across three dozen US states in
Canada has given us a front row seat to
watch legalization and regulation unfold
to observe how people search buy and
consume cannabis and to witness how
thousands of businesses of all sizes
seek to sell it and from that front row
seat we have some observations we've
seen Market launches go well and some
not so
well and sharing leafly's direct
experience working in this unique
industry it's our hope that you all in
this room can take the lessons we've
learned to win legalization in Germany
and
Beyond so what does winning look like
each country and Market will have to
Define that for themselves but that
Journey wherever its destination it
starts with breaking down barriers like
stigma and negative stereotypes that
impair our Collective ability to allow
cannabis to be a meaningful active Force
for good good for individuals and good
for local communities around the
globe so the journey to normalize and
destigmatize starts with solving what I
call cannabis
illiteracy and tackling and solving that
illiteracy starts with opening
Minds we are all in the business of
Chang changing minds and changing Minds
begins with stories stories about humans
history with this plant reconnecting
people with the knowledge that our
ancestors for Millennia have used every
part of its plant its seeds its fibers
its extracts for utilitarian medical and
spiritual
practices and that's only within the
last 100 years that humans have spread
the seeds of prohibition driven by a
group of powerful American men
who waged a campaign against the plant
their actions weren't rooted in science
or data but in racial discrimination and
misinformation so couple that history
with stories of broadly inclusive
stories of communities and cultures that
have leveraged the gifts of the plant
whether it was the member Physicians of
the American Medical Association who
came out in opposition of
prohibition or old Japanese family
recipes that call for use of hemp seeds
in a traditional pepper mix or the local
communities in the US who are
experiencing job growth because of the
Cannabis industry or how those same
communities are reinvesting cannabis tax
revenues in local schools and nature
conservation we find that surfacing
these kinds of stories of cannabis's
everyday uses and benefits helps to
wedge that door open it enables greater
learning and further
understanding of this plant and its many
magical
properties this is the path to
destigmatization the opening of eyes and
Minds to the possibility that our
ancestors just may be knew what was up
with Canabis and that the relief and
efficacy that they experienced thousands
of years ago can now be backed up with
science and
data so keep telling your stories that
normaliz ize use and combat cannabis
illiteracy keep talking about the relief
that so many find for cancer treatment
pain management epilepsy and PTSD keep
sharing new stories that change the
narrative like Alex said how cannabis is
a multi-functional plant that can be
foundational to creating a green
economy because when a society is
broadly educated people are able to make
informed decisions and become better
participants in cannabis
society and we should be looking to our
governments and Regulators to join the
education journey and to incorporate
that knowledge into their
decisionmaking to help their citizens
overcome cannabis literacy and invest in
and share in science-led research that
expands Beyond campaigns that perpetuate
stigma and harm
hypotheses research about harm reduction
it's important but it's equally
important to fund research and studies
that can explain why so many people
consuming cannabis experience positive
outcomes we can't unlock the magic of
cannabis without varied
perspectives so think about this we're
raising the Next Generation in a post
prohibition Society they are way more
open and disposed to the plant to
parents know enough to guide their kids
through the decision of whether and when
to
consume what about the middle-aged like
myself people who are looking for
alternatives to alcohol or prescription
drugs to treat pain or for help with
sleep and then the Boomers who are
surprisingly way more open and welcoming
of this plan than my generation seems to
be all of these discussions require
Baseline know knowledge in the plant how
to consume it its different form factors
and different strains and equally
important when not to consume
it people need to know that everyone
experiences the effects of cannabis in
unique and different
ways and many of you in this room know
all of this but there are hundreds of
millions of people outside of this room
who
don't so that's our collect Mission
solving cannabis illiteracy with data
and information changing hearts and
minds and that's what paves a path to
Global
legalization that's a long that's a lot
of ground to cover an education is a
long game but trust that cannabis
literacy will come if we stay committed
and refuse to let negative stereotypes
stigma and misinformation impede its
progress what won't come nearly what
won't come nearly as slowly I hope is
building sufficiently robust developed
channels for procuring legal licensed
cannabis what we've consistently seen at
Leafly is that the more legal regulated
access points for cannabis the less
elicit sales in fact through re research
that we did last year we found that
local Municipal banss on legal stores
effectively creates an economic
protection zone for elicit sellers it's
really hard to keep consumers safe in
that
environment no one wins neither the
consumers the citizens The Regulators or
the nor the licensed
operators just as I said when I started
I'm really excited by German Germany's
move here the right to grow this plant
at home because gardening is not a crime
and to procure it through the Social
Clubs but we need to ask are these
channels broad enough to allow those who
are seeking access to the plant the
ability to get
it a Canadian Provincial leader once
said to
me it makes no sense to legalize
cannabis only to regulate it back into
prohibition
prices and taxes are also a key part of
that access priced are taxed too high
consumers flee back to the illicit
market and there's more research to be
done but in the US we found that at
north of 33% in a price disparity
consumers shift back to Legacy spending
patterns and governments and
municipalities must resist the
temptation to tax or regulate operators
out of existence
we have seen over the last 24 months in
the US markets an an unimaginable number
of lenses lose their license due to
taxes and or the high high cost of
compliance and
Regulation and operators remember this
this is a crop prices will remain high
while Supply remains constrained but
when the wholesale prices of the CR drop
fall so will your revenues so build your
businesses understanding the eventual
economics of supply and
demand so my final lesson to share and
really this is really a wish list if I
could turn back the clock and redo what
we've done in North America so
far the the these would be the
prescriptions deal proactively with the
criminal justice implications of
Prohibition in the US many states have
committed to the automatic expungement
that's the um eradication the deletion
of criminal conviction records but some
in my like my home state of Washington
we were one of the first states to
legalize cannabis for recreational use
we have an expungement bill but it's not
automatic and what that means is each
individual must go and seek that
expungement on their own we have a
highly burdensome court and
administrative system so that is
practically impossible for people to
navigate
expungements shouldn't be the criminal
justice pieces should not be an
afterthought cuz if you've been arrested
or convicted for something that's no
longer a crime you shouldn't be treated
like a
criminal I understand that you there are
advocates in this room who support the
removal of cannabis offenses and my hope
is that you learn from our shortcomings
on this front address these convictions
proactively invite these individuals
back into society and back into this
industry where they can contribute in
valuable knowledge on how to cultivate
and distribute this
plant so the era of wielding cannabis as
a weapon or tool to destroy individual
lives that time has passed now is the
time to allow for healing and Justice
and let cannabis do what it has done for
thousands of years and that is to help
humans heal and build community
[Applause]
[Music]
it's a profound privilege and a
responsibility to be a part of the
legalization
story but to serve the magic the full
magic of this plan halfway done is not
an
option legalization is but a stop on the
long
journey as you travel this road know
that the journey has resulted in
transforming years of negative thinking
into Market opportunities that heal
individuals and build
community I'd like to thank Alex Rogers
and the team at ICBC for inviting me
here to join you
today I'm struck by the sheer wealth of
knowledge and experience that each of
you bring to this
table and I really look forward to the
learnings that you will share this week
and to hear your stories that's
invaluable to me that's invaluable to
Leafly cuz that allows us to
continuously expand our audience's
knowledge of this plant and how it's
making its way once again around the
world through
legalization thank
you Yoko
Mi uh that was wonderful um she makes a
lot of good points about the