hey everybody welcome to the 130 soil
science panel called creating a thriving
rhizosphere
so this is this is for all US other
welcome
I am Shea colos moderator of the panel
and host of the shaping fire podcast if
you enjoy learning from the top minds of
the cannabis business industry I
encourage you to visit shaping feiyr.com
to enjoy in-depth interviews on campus
business health and technique that will
provide you with actionable information
and not waste your time also our youtube
channel serves over a half a million
minutes of exclusive campus content a
month that I've gathered from
conferences just like this one and from
traveling the country to visit industry
experts as a matter of fact if you dig
the panel today it will be on the Xingu
fire youtube channel next week
other recent guests have included
cultivator Kevin Joe dream The Godfather
Canada's terpenes neurologist dr. Andrew
so geneticist dr. Reggie got Ino on
cannabis plant patents and colabello
market today Natacha breeds on using the
canvas root ball as medicine and many
many other folks so it's a lot of good
stuff so if you've got your mobile phone
with you and you know you do please take
a moment and put it on vibrate so so
they don't have to hear it immediately
to my right is Colin Bell Colin Bell is
the co-founder of mammoth microbes and
co-inventor of their flagship product
mammoth pee he received his PhD in
biological sciences specializing in soil
microbial ecology and plant microbe
interactions to his right is dr. Jade
Stefano J Stefano is co-founder and CEO
of puffin farms she earned her bio
degree at Reed College and a doctorate
in naturopathic medicine from Bastyr
University in 2016 and to her right is
tad Hussey Tennessee is owner of the K
is on organics he earned a master's from
Macquarie University Australia in 2005
but received the bulk of his soil
education in the family business over in
Redmond Washington tad manages the
research and microscope microscope
testing for kis organics and teaches
soil and body courses at the k IX farm
he is the co-founder of logical garden
awkward a3 science-based horticultural
forum that has formulated soils and
nutrients and other products over the
past
decade 10 is also host of the cannabis
cultivation in soil science podcast so
if you're so nerd and haven't checked
out taps podcast I highly recommend it
it goes they go deep into vocabulary
that loses people which is usually a
good sign
alright so so today we're gonna be
talking about creating a threads inside
writing rhizosphere and for people who
may be new to soil science that's the
area that lives all around the root
structure so it's the neighborhood of
the roots so we're gonna be talking
about a life that happens below the soil
near the root so we're gonna start with
a question for Colin first and then Jade
and tad will take a turn with the
question as well so here we go so Tom
for a generation most cannabis growers
have simply followed directions on the
back of the bottle nutrients and hoped
everything was okay in the soil now
though we understand that having a
thriving rhizosphere is essential to
great tasting terpene profiles and
sustainable results for business what
does it mean to you to have a thriving
rhizosphere
and what are some of the outcomes you
would expect to see in the soil from
your campaign from your cannabis ground
when you actually do create a thriving
Rises here yeah thanks very much Django
and for me this has been a really fun
journey because I approach
motivation for my academic our
fundamental science background where our
school microbial ecologists and for
years and years I a my studies and my
publications focused on understanding
how microbes interacting to the plant
system work plan health plant
development in natural systems and in
agriculture systems and so in thinking
about how to apply microbes or what I
think about rhizosphere
health in more precision agriculture and
or practices it all relates to the
biology the rhizosphere
is the root zone and microbes thrive in
the root zone and there's a really
significant interaction that occurs
where a plant can feed the microbes from
the carbon they assimilate through the
air and squirt it in as simple sugars to
stimulate the microbial community or
rises here microbial community they do
that because they can in exchange when
you get a density and it with the right
diversity of microbes when plants do in
the rhizosphere
they get exchanges with nutrient uptake
with protecting the rhizosphere from
other potential pathogens and what I
think would see data-driven when we add
more biology and to what might be
relatively sterile salt environment we
see the plants respond by increasing
their yield and increasing their quality
and I attribute that mostly to the
the increased absorption potential that
plants can take nutrients that might not
be available through those microbial
interactions and assert them or allocate
them towards more yield important for
quality metrics but some nutrients and
micronutrients become a limiting very
quick because absorption capacity within
the writing sphere or substrate times
and microbes as they do in nature will
liberate those micronutrients and allow
pets to take them up those
micronutrients in particular act as
catalysts or as cofactors to allow
plants of maximizer physiology which
allows plants to increase yield
significantly and quality what we see in
our studies and I'll end it there it's
when we engaged with commercial farmers
and on our trial farm we have cannabis
and high CBD cannabis farms in Colorado
strictly from our any purposes not only
did we see increases in yield but we see
significant increases in different
terpene profiles and different
cannabinoid profile which which strongly
relates to the plant microbe interaction
different microbes will will help plants
in different ways take up those
resources to allocate towards those
qualities right on based on so do what
do you look for to know in your soil or
in your crop that the rhizosphere is
hell yeah
when we first started growing indoors in
early 90s we tried all different methods
we grew into positively minor
chronically these soil chemical
fertilizers organic fertilizers this is
older than that one it was all tied to
things a week and by the end of his
journey and immediately started rolling
to my keys and we were doing it in food
in the early 2000 we at some point
realized that kind of is grown in soil
the Coles teeth better at that point we
didn't really have the science to tell
us why but it was some just you know
visible through experimentation and so
we started growing exclusively in soil
at that point and and now that all the
scientists coming out we know that there
is this microbial community that it's
making you treats available and letting
the plants get optimal health so they do
Express profile which is really
interesting I think people have known
for years the soil in cannabis tasted
better and they just didn't know why and
so now we have the evidence which is
pretty cool and so when we started
growing in the 502 we grew decide to
grow outdoors you know living in a
living farm in the soil as needed to the
earth and until the edge loop ends
they did not miss fertilizers or
pesticides it was just hey a year after
year
sucking the life out of the sandy loam
soil that were blessed with and so by
the time we got it it was a really good
piece of sandy loam but it had been
stripped of a lot of organic matter and
I just put the microbial community
that's not so great and so we have been
working over the last five years to
rebuild that and so that's been every
year we see an improvement in the soil
and it's been a really interesting
journey but um but definitely soil is
always it provides the medium for
microbes and then adding things to the
soil so we have had a lot of biochar
which is really important that is
put in a soil and it will be there for a
thousand years or more and I'll be there
forever it's inorganic carbon so it
doesn't break down organic carbon does
and provides habitat for all these
microbial communities that we're talking
up to as far as an actionable item in
building Farm soil biochar is our
absolutely favorite one of our favorites
because touched a lot of things going
back to the condom hit on the living
around nutrient cycling from the
layman's perspective this idea would
work when we're adding organic nutrients
this slow I'm really doing is repeating
all these microbial communities to the
rise of Spirit events cycling the
nutrients are making the plant available
so when we had fish meal we're not
directly to feeding the plant that's I
think really important but what we're
finding even from working with like
giant pumpkin growers for instance they
sort of peaked out from a seed to fruit
around 1,000 pounds 1,200 pounds which
is pretty amazing but since they started
reincorporating back in biological
things like Michael
fungus and various organic amendments
and taking more care with the compost
and looking at the biology they were
able to up the hills you know after
group genetics now there have been I
think twenty three twenty four hundred
pounds so it's sort of there's
definitely a synergy going on in the
rhizosphere that is really important and
then Jay touched on one biochar and as
someone who has worked with some
different biochar producers I just want
to comment that not a lot of charts the
same and it's really important to know
what you're purchasing and what you're
applying because the biochar sort of
this catch-all term but if you get high
quality biochar I would I would say
we're seeing about eight to nine percent
better growth in yield just with the
addition about traffic so it is a
wonderful thing
Thank You Ted so first we're gonna start
with with Jay and then go to Ted and so
so got respond on a commercial scale
producers are working with large volumes
of soil and they often need more
scalable solution than we use at home
growers they may be using local soils or
importing soils to
our facts either way these soils may not
be in the best condition for growing by
the plants what can you suggest for
commercial scale growers to invigorate
and revitalize the soil there and
getting you put to work yeah so and
that's kind of what our situation was so
cover rocks are a really great thing and
that is something that you there's all
different types of cover crops micro
mixing ones are especially beneficial to
reinvigorate the soil and they they put
out roots that help the texture of the
soil and break up compact soil they also
fix nitrogen from the atmosphere and
release that into the soil and when they
die they are turned into a additional
organic material and nitrogen of the
plants feed off of so a Laurel person
that was using cover crops in your Isles
and then in between the plantings so
offseason led to cover crop and that
will keep growing into the spring and
then it may or may not move
and whether you're doing a no-till or
until scenario other things that we
really like that are economical at scale
are alfalfa meal that's pretty cheap
input material it's got a compounds in
it but no microbe is absolutely loved
and that's so Mike again it's not very
strong but it adds a lot of organic
matter provides great substrate for
microbes to feed on world caffeine's
that's another thing that it's a little
bit more difficult it scallops they can
be quite expensive but there are some
sources for affordable worm castings
involved and you don't need as much as
you would think so even at relatively
low concentrations worm castings provide
really great but when the activity
organic matter phosphorous all kinds of
nutrients and so that's another one we
love what else
rock dust and that's another chief of
method a lot so they're lacking
micronutrient micronutrients so Brock
powders and different sources to provide
a wide spectrum of base micronutrients
and those need to handle very carefully
they are an inhalation hazard and so
when those are being used as a proper
precautions need to be taken and mulch
is a really great thing to do and that
can be done with like the cover crops
grow I'm going to use though those down
right under the plants so we do not eat
our farm anymore
we pretty much mostly leaves and cut
them down we put a lot of cover crops
that's like choose your leaves so we
choose alfalfa and vention not
affectionate clovers and beneficial
insect attractive plants like Calandra
and there's a little bunch of them
radishes daikons and so these are grown
around the bounces and they start
getting too big and encroaching on the
plant will mow them down then they
create a mulch way there are plants but
that brings down other things
and so thinking you have to keep a bare
soil under your plants or use black
plastic just put that weeds it's kind of
a little bit counterproductive in a lot
of ways I'm not a fan of that so yeah
they catch a good time that's pretty
answer no but they have a lot to add
other than I always suggest that people
if we're talking about their farm which
seems to be the focus of this particular
question then I always suggest get to
know your neighbors find out what cover
crops they're using on their on their
fields because a lot of times they've
done that research for you and they have
that knowledge bringing in an outside
consultant like myself to come in and
tell you what cover crop surrenders not
always the best idea you know they'll
know about a type of water and how your
water might change over the course of
the season - which is really important
and then also find out what you can
source locally there's so many great
amendments probably in their area I know
like Ellen's burgers coming out of a lot
of cow manure available but finding
things that are locally sourced is
really really great option obviously
evaluating the quality of that so we're
casting Spain from Canada are going to
be a very different quality than we're
casting stay front of course when you
are
waste or other sources so it's important
to do a little more research on all this
stuff I really know what you're putting
on your soil but there are a lot of good
local resources and then the last thing
I'll mention is on our farm which is the
vegetable part we use a lot of barbara's
chips to get the free they need place to
dump the chips and when we get to sit to
his chips we take those as we save those
for composting and then all that hard
wood chips that we get in we use for
pathways going to Florida that doesn't
great job where these pressure you know
we really don't want again
everything's been covered pretty well so
I'm just going to kind of overview my my
perspective of this and we're gonna
start with the carbon carbon is the
currency of all life on earth and it's
the currency what he provides the
substrate and the fertility for plants
to exist soil is a habitat and it's the
pool of nutrients that plants need to
grow the only element that plants get
outside the soil is carbon and they fix
that from the air from co2 every other
nutrient they get from the soil so if
you think about soil as a habitat and a
pool of nutrients that are available for
your plants to grow that's the focus and
if you think about carbon as a currency
of all life that is the Pope
since the carbon creates the habitat and
the binding capacity and the motility
capacity for your soil to hold nutrients
it also creates the habitat for the
microbes in that soil to cycle the
nutrients reflecting on what was shared
in these past conversations to deliver
those nutrients to your plant and so
scaling carbon as we get to bigger farms
is probably the challenge we talked
about mulch we talked about biochar I
want to talk about cover crops and
there's there's costs and trade-offs
associated with all those practices I
think as farms get larger the cover crop
become much more scalable and what is
the plan at the end of the day we used
to say this in academia from a
microbiology lab plants are charismatic
carbon pumps they plant themselves in
the ground they take carbon from the air
and they suck it right down under the
soil
so cover crops if you can have seed and
use cover crops effectively you add
carbon and habitat into your soils which
improves soil fertility in the capacity
of nutritional value to be delivered
back up to your place
you know one thing I'm gonna - as far as
comic Roscoe is you know if you think
about it what makes one of the things
that makes the Amazon so so alive is
that the canopy is holding the moisture
in and that's what we find from cover
crops - is because you've got this small
area below the cover crop where you've
got an Amazonian type canopy and at the
top of your soil is kept moist all of
the microbes and worms and all the other
light can do their thing closer to the
top of the soil where more of the
cannabis roots are located and so
another advantage and if we remember the
third question when I come back to you
tab because when I heard you answer this
question before we usually get your plug
for soil testing and so I would like you
to hit on the importance of soil testing
and then GP if you want to add
testing that emigrate but but give that
one sure so when we talk about any soil
or any nutrient program or any even my
criminal additional we have to look at
this really we have to know what's
arguable soil because what we're trying
to figure out is what the limiting
factor encourages and if that's a
nutrient that's something we need to add
but randomly and adding you know a
nutrient really doesn't solve the
problem and it can actually compound or
create even more problems down the road
so it's really enough balance and that's
that's sort of my pitch for soil testing
is without and it's just another tool
that you can use as gardener just like a
rake or shovel or anything else to
really know what's going on and it's
it's really the I think the foundation
that we want to build off of and when we
talk about microbial additions what
we're doing there is we're essentially
unlocking or making those nutrients more
available to plants and you serve about
two aspects you have it the test itself
which is gonna tell you what you need to
add in terms nutrients and then you have
the microbes which are going to give you
the ability to siphon those nutrients
into a horrible man I think either
together
yeah so again I think growing or
cultivating or farming with David dating
different decisions is critical
variability happens Farms cultivation
cannabis barns is alive
dynamic systems they're always changing
and we have been doing that change with
some form of data and it's critical to
start with the baseline of understanding
what we're working with as I mentioned
our substrate in a pot or a substrate as
soil in the ground as a as an inherent
soil nutrient holding capacity which is
going to change as your plants are
taking up nutrients in natural systems
those nutrients are recycled back down
to the ground as to try this one sub
plants and the leaves fall and so
there's a natural cycle and managed
farms and annual managed farms often
there's more nutrients leaving the soil
then returning and if you know what a
nutrient baseline you have at the
beginning of every season you can be
very efficient and informed with what
you put back in and I think that's a
really critical step that general how
the culture ought to say is is missing
significantly
there are soil tests it's a common
practice but
I know from years of research and
agriculture scientists that more
nutrients are put in than our ever taken
up by plants and in turn build up happen
and we have pretty good a technological
pollution in waterways and buildup of
phosphorus and nitrogen pollution and
those excessive chemicals fertilizers
that are added in the soil deeply or
decreased microbial biodiversity which
decrease soil functionality and so
balancing out your nutrient inputs
actually nurtures the potential of the
like the biology in your soil to persist
and by balance out the nutrient cycling
potential so your plants can can grow as
naturally as possible and soils without
having to amend a lot we should be
responsible and knowing your microbial
presence the biodiversity and the sea
views or the concentrations along with
those nutrient tests allow you to have a
baseline that you can follow over time
farming broad scale farming is about
predictable variability so you can be as
consistent as possible if you put a crop
in you want to have a predictable
outcome year after year because you can
manage predictability and so that's what
we're trying to do and he goes all the
way down to understanding the substrates
slow changing anything man yeah
that's all good stuff and I can't
overemphasize how important soil testing
is we test every year and we've actually
seen organic matter where it go up it
was one percent when we started we're
now at five or six percent and so even
as we use a low till says defeated with
tilling we see an increased and you know
we're putting back a lot of organic
matter that's really important and then
when we add nutrients we we buy only
what would need the order we do the soil
test and and so for a micro and macro
nutrients and especially micronutrients
alliances and whatnot we some years this
might need to add dole might other years
we may not and actually we don't don't
our soil is we don't make we have a lot
of natural light medium in the soil but
different types of lines and and just
the the basic amounts of the essential
nutrients you can calculate that and add
fixed amounts and do that consistently
every year and then under not too much
you're not a ninja little and you're
just right and it's you know adding
stuff with
other than science and really important
to test your soil retaining isn't fast
so this is a little bit aside but I feel
like soil gets a bad rap in a lot of
ways because people whenever they see a
deficiency in a plant they just assume
it's a nutrient deficiency caused by the
soil and especially for indoor growers
you really have to look at reviving the
quality of the lighting intensity
lighting your co2 levels your
temperature committee fluctuations your
hydrologist later water has a massive
impact on nutrient availability so don't
just assume that your YouTube deficiency
means you need to have cow man
or something else like there's a lot
more to it than that and I don't I would
encourage people to look at the picture
holistically I get phone calls from
people Tommy you know they send me a
photo and say fix this and I go hey
there's no way I could no one could you
really have to know the whole picture to
really understand what's going on so
well don't worry my foot down
that's next question and so this is
gonna be our third and final question
before we go to your questions
so if you if you think you're gonna have
a question that would be the time to
determine what it's going to be so so
this one we're going to start with you
tab and then we'll go to
Jassa so Ted the cannabis plant
rhizosphere is an ever-changing place
that has an abundance ha's and
efficiencies over time other than soil
testing which we've already covered for
commercial farmers who need reliable and
consistent results how do suggest the
soil being managed over the scope of
years to remain potent and abundant and
not get depleted season after season you
know I really like always answer this
realizing that in these commercial
systems every time you harvest a plan
we're pulling out nutrients and we're
pulling out organic matter and those
things need to be replaced and recycle
and so by getting data points on that
through soil testing we were able to
better manage over time our soil
fertility by improving ourself agility
like Jade's been able to do raising that
organic matter four percent doesn't
sound like a lot but that's a huge
improvement
I think every year I'm guessing their
inputs are going down because of that so
creating not only a better soil
fertility through mineral nutrient
management but also through biological
management that's where that organic
matter and that harvick creating that
habitat is really important yeah that's
really well said I think about it same
exact way sustainable agriculture is
about giving more than you take away and
moderating your practices that
accommodate that is what I would
encourage and that's about repeatability
and if you're after year if you have
pretty measurable or pretty consistent
routines as far as how you're amending
soil and you collect the data on the
responses or results of those practices
you can slightly alter and tweak the
practices to match consistency
consistency is key consistent practices
equal
system results for manageable results
that you can alter slightly to keep that
trajectory 1% a one-person EcoBoost
organic matter of soils is it's
incredible a 5% doesn't happen very
often that means that there's a real
drive in this form to maximize carbon
content which is a direct correlation
with soil health so that's a nice job
well gee both of them are saying that
your numbers are awesome so what
encloses out of this question with some
with some actionable things that folks
to do over the life of their farm to
start the bachelors and so we touched on
somebody's already uncover problematic
is
and that's probably one of the fastest
ways to put carbon back into the soil
years every year you might get one or
two cycles of tilling in plant matter
that then act to that organic material
level in the soil and so you know I
really I really like cover crops pick it
up but of any lots of miles and you
can't really add too much compost I mean
it's possible but it would be very
expensive to do so and so just putting
in as much compost as possible alfalfa
Hays and mulch with those and those are
pretty cheap and add lots of carbon to
the soil and if you on when his dirty
your soil well stuff can turn around
really quickly like I said our apartment
was hey they were tilling it just
putting planting hey see the money agro
and just cutting hay cutting hay three
years here is just sucking nutrients and
carbon out of the soil and once we start
putting stuff back and adding compost
and biochar
it just it turned around really quickly
in reversing light I've had one percent
a year increase and it doesn't sound
like a lot but if it is significant and
so we're getting up into those ideal by
a percent organic matter levels right
now it and hopefully it'll keep growing
but we're pretty happy with a rap so
we're going to question it let's do one
quick experiment question because one
thing that I often hear
after of awareness are people are I just
can't afford all these amendments or the
soil right and then you know
is so hot right now and a lot of the
ideas come from using natural materials
found in global area hopefully even
under our farms I'm going to pay for
hell
so like you know in 90 seconds or so you
each hit that idea of using local inputs
or three inputs so that you don't have
to work at all started with you ten but
you know Canada is really popular
together the Korean natural farming I
have not an expert on it but I have
taken quite a few people that have
experimented with it I love the idea of
sourcing things on your farm as much as
possible I think we do have to look at
the fact that not all nutrients are
found when all harms and where we may
need to bring it in puts but there are
things that are there that we can use
and for me Kenneth is very similar to
permaculture which is something a lot
more
this idea of just creating sustainable
systems or healthy ecosystems and so I I
personally like on our farm for example
we we try to recycle so we we look at
the best use for every by-product that
we have so for example with our with our
leftover vegetables and things that
don't get stole if they when they start
to rot those go to the pigs and that pig
manure them to be used to nutrients or
especially our plants down the road so
we're looking at completing the cycle as
much as possible with what we have
available on the farm yeah I mean look
like amendments year after year that's
quite expensive and it's it's difficult
for people and then you've spent lots of
money buying amendments and so be able
to use little
very appealing and so in our case you
know art they accept that we've done
that we've grown cover crops and you
know turn those into compost to fill
those in and that has gotten us a lot of
a lot of bang for our buck we have you
know memorable that are very much I
regret it's just another thing to manage
on a cannabis farm in Washington and
there's so much hassle and regulations
than just adding animals to that future
would be unmanageable for us but for
people that can have animals under
firmly against the hey exciting friend
to have chickens on their farms and they
go around and they let the chicken into
the pot kiln they eat the they make
who've been made but fertilizer in the
name of the needs and and so there's
there's a lot that you can do with
animals they're cheap with chickens so I
would love to do that someday we're not
there yet
I think about this is economies of scale
and adding carbon back into the systems
revisit this topic and I really think
you can use cover crops with precision
and confidence if you can understand
and you can see very market results if
you had a clover which is a nitrogen
fixer we're not only you adding the
carbon in the soil but your attitude in
fixing nitrogen in the atmosphere and
bringing that to the soil also in you're
gonna see very different results we have
too many grass or alfalfa or a clover
and if you understand these cover crops
more you can engineer the soil fertility
based on your farm there's a lot of
physical properties a soil type there's
water holding capacity the climate that
you're in and so you're gonna have to
tailor those practices to your park I
would use biochar in my home garden I
can't use it on my 65 acre farm it's not
scalable but I can go global on there
and so understanding how your video and
how your the barn responds what your
farm needs you can really clearly
identify the stoichiometry or nutrient
ratios nutrient expectations that
different cover crops can bring in to
supplement the soil health to meet the
maximum productivity that you would like
for your Candida
outdoors at the tubulars what we're
talking about Thanks cool thing silent
alright so weird open up the question
this has got a question to get a starter
right so on that cover problem we're an
indoor garden we are soil myths and now
if I was to use cover crops because we
have to bend their soil after our soil
test at the time is it going to be
harder to amend that soil with the cover
crop on there to get it in the soil
correctly yes I am going to have a
caveat and this is based on some
experience not all practices work for
every environment I'm a big fan of cover
crops even on an indoor I think that's
interesting but there's trade-offs with
every decision that we made and I'm
going to add that we need to make sure
we can measure that difference on a
broad scale if I add clover and grow it
over 65 acres I can really measure the
difference over a couple of years and
not only the carbon in the soil but
potentially the nitrogen levels as well
it's a cycling dynamic process
a couple years that's naturally I'm not
sure an indoor pot system if it's
measurable in one cycle and you want to
have measurable results and I also want
to urge caution when you're in play
implementing something like this into
your system I think it's a great idea
and I've had growers who tried to
implement clover as an example in their
indoor grow and it turned out to be a
vector for pests that made it harder for
pest mitigation and so there are
trade-offs with every decision we make
and your environment might not be as
suitable for a cover crop as an outdoor
environment and there's other solutions
where we want to nurture the micro they
wanna nurture the carpet building
capacity but maybe in your case and you
know you guys use mammoths adding that
life you see good results maybe adding
some more carbon you're gonna see some
good results if you add in clover maybe
you're going to see good results but the
clover is an active vector to bring in
more pests maybe that's not the right
solution as that example so you really
have to work through every scenario to
find out what works best for you and
experiment with it thank you
so cabra really good point one thing we
have to remember with an indoor
environment is we don't have that same
diversity of beneficial insects
naturally occurring like you would on an
outdoor farm and so I do think cover
crops are about more challenging endorse
that's one more crop you do have to
manage fairly stringent that being said
I know people that are doing it
successfully either on a commercial
level if you want to check out Joshua
Steve's Lenoir freshwater farms that
would be the example I'm closest to but
a lot of the guys I work with they're
choosing not to use cover crops for that
reason because it is a it is a pest
concern than you know just such a
concentrated environment as a matter of
fact I just interviewed Joshua steeple
and steveland on indoor polyculture on
my last episode at chicken Flair , he
goes in-depth on using cover crops and
variety of plant species all through but
only in the indoor environment this his
specialty
so we've got time for probably one more
question when we have great I've got
three Cowboys they mentioned those but
not all biochar is created equal
what would be a preferred type of
biochar we've seen a lot more people
cold calling us at the farms
representing different types biochar and
and obviously I'm concerned anyone
I have an opinion and then Tabitha's
born expert but in academia we looked at
a whole bunch of different biochars and
actual the surface area the consistency
the variability over time and just like
what we're talking about agriculture
consistent inputs equal consist outputs
a consistent process you get a
consistent process and that yields a
good product and it's consistent you can
go on it I think that what we've mined a
lot of the biochar manufacturing
facilities are taking and inconsistent
inputs and they're getting inconsistent
outputs and it's all over the place and
I'm Steeve my research that we conducted
several years ago and I know that there
are facilities manufacturing facilities
that that focus on predictable
predictable variability there's always
gonna be a little variability and I
would I would ask those questions
rigorously and look for the data to make
sure that
produce consistent product over a long
period of time but if within 30
different students a hardwoods as you
mentioned earlier versus vegetable crops
again is it just consistency or is there
one medium that's better than other to
have your biochar created from so many
different kind I doubt that is there's a
so many different kinds I don't
I'm not going to discount the value of
biochar it's additional substrate and in
kind of an inert carbon meaning it just
has a lot of surface area and a habitat
which will allow the nutrients to bind
and microbes to create habitat so you
can conceptually get great value from a
lot of different bio power sources but
if it's not consistent for your farm
you're gonna have a consistent result
inconsistent results and that's the big
challenge in my opinion thank you
this could be a whole talk
and their relationship so I got biochar
we're talking about pyrolyze materials
so very very high very very low oxygen
levels and if you don't do that what you
end up with is charcoal and one of the
quick tests that Ranil over a blackout
volatility we've worked with for years I
have a good relationship with her they
she said the key to take your biochar up
close but it's not it's not high-quality
contractors is now
absorption rates it's just a quick test
but you need to get all these test
results and I've heard of companies
anecdotally using all types of materials
because wood sourcing is tough with
black owl and uh they're using virgin
forest / that sounds horrible I realized
but it's actually a really good source
because it needs to be need to be dealt
with or it's a forest fire hazard and by
taking it and making it into biochar
they're able to sequester the carbon and
so there are good sources out there but
you really have to do do due diligence
on it and I have seen research that
showed a good biochar be throw meat
eating from chicken manure to woods and
all these different sources it's really
enough that I consistency of material in
the quality of your necklace yeah and
just to add to that one that I have seen
it is concerning if see people making by
up to her out of the lake on waste wood
from what I would and stuff that bad if
he says stuff in that that's something
you would definitely like stay with you
hear anything about using an e-waste
from Germany process would I'm stupid I
offer that that does happen and then the
other thing with biochar if you can't
make it yourself and there are all kinds
of instructions on the internet how to
build a reactor and it's quite simple it
involves a 50 gallon metal drum and and
you can produce a lot of oil turn away
and the people selling by yourself with
like a thousand dollars are like a tote
for a 510 pounds of thousands incredibly
expensive this is a buck a pound or
something and so any any biochar even if
it's not like it'd be making yourself
and it's not like ideal condition
biochar that's particle size it doesn't
matter everybody when you're putting
yeah exactly you're putting carbon into
your soil of my three and that's a good
thing
so I'm if you can figure out how to make
it yourself like that is a really great
way to go the last time I had a
conversation with somebody about
we don't find anywhere - I see the place
that people are selling for it's pretty
alarming so it's definitely something
you should try to make yourself if you
feel at all crap here people definitely
highly recommend that everyone if you
want to charge it as well
with thinking like a chance - you need
to and typically just a small amount of
nitrogen is all you need so in Amara
schools we have it in the rate of 5 to
8% so again not a very high rate that's
a very aggressive rate for an
agricultural so you get a lot less
outdoor but a small amount of nitrogen
is what you would want to get on there
we so far as efficient either all the
same I can get a rate of like house and
else pretend gallons so not very much
people can even use compost teas and
things like that but if you were to have
it just straight biochar on your soil on
your plant that's actually be more
efficient than you're planning on basis
of taking up nitrogen so you can see
your plant yellow and efficiency just be
careful that were in charge
yeah it'll suck them to create also
and for a decision right now fantastic
well thank you all for being here for
the
[Applause]
you