so hey Colin thanks again for getting
together with me here for a second so so
first of all thank you for sponsoring
the shaping fire podcast we love your
support yes and we love telling people
about mammoths pee and you know since
your commercials run on the shaping
fighter podcast a lot of people come up
to me and ask me about the product you
know I can say you know I use the
product and I like the product and what
it does for me but there are like like
four questions and people are always
asking me that I know I'm giving them
sub optimum answers because it's not my
product right so I'd love to go through
those questions with you and just have
you answer them the proper way and then
and then when people ask me I can just
send them for this video right perfect
all right so before we get into those
four questions for anybody who's not
familiar with the mammoth P product from
mammoth microbes we just explain what it
does yeah absolutely so my name is Colin
bellum the co-founder of mammoth
microbes and the inventor of the
technology mammoth P is a liquid organic
microbial additive that acts as a
catalyst to maximize plant phosphorus
uptake that allows plants to take up as
much phosphorus naturally as a plant
possibly can which allows the plants to
maximize its health development quality
and yield and that's what we see when
growers apply mammoth pee as an additive
in their fertigation or nutrient regime
that the plants will maximize their
phenotypic potential maximizing their
quality and increase the yield as much
as that plant can do we typically see an
average of around 60 percent increase
yield with Mimas P additions so is the
idea but what's actually in the bottle
is a collection of microbes living
microbes and and they are helping change
the form of the phosphorus so it's more
readily obtainable by the plant that's
the idea that's exactly right
transforming foster some unavailable
forms of bioavailable
that's a microbial function and that's
why we selected the microbes an active
consortium of microbes it's in mammoth
pH just a concentrated bottle of
microbes but these microbes function to
facilitate phosphorus liberation to
maximize availability for a plain empty
phosphorus liberation I like that right
on all right so here are the four
questions that I get all the time so the
first one since it is a living product
and you know you know probiotic growers
are always trying to you know ferment
things or make compost teas people ask
me can they can they just buy one bottle
of mammoth pee and then just take little
bits of it and and incubate it to make
it more right - by adding a little bit
of molasses or something - admit to make
it grow and then never have to buy the
product again is it is it possible to do
that so conceptually yes these are
active microbes that they are viable and
they will grow in different substrates
the challenge is maintaining the
integrity of the community structure I
think what happens as weari propagate
communities of microbes over time that
there's going to be drift in the
relative abundances of the different
microbes and that relative abundances is
really important we did a lot of studies
to show that the microbes in mammoth pee
in those relative abundances do
facilitate much higher phosphorous
cycling then the isolates the
individuals or different combinations of
the species they're in so you I would I
think that you're gonna compromise the
quality of the product over time by
doing that I do recommend plugging it in
it's that's what's one of the reasons we
made it so concentrated so it is
scalable it's 0.6 mils per gallon and so
the product does last I'll go a long way
and you can play with it and I'm all
about experimenting but just know that
we have experimented internally and over
time we do see drift and that's why we
recommend going back to the main source
you might even carry it out one
generation but then it'd be nice to
start from the from the original source
of the bottle that you purchased had to
continue you know just maximizing
confidence so when you say drift if I'm
interpretating you're interpreting
alright what you're saying is that okay
so when you got the bottle you've got a
particular rate
she loved microbes but when you go to
try to incubate it yourself those
microbes are opportunists so if it's
warmer colder or there's more air or
less air it's going to choose different
microbes to favor and then it's going to
get out of balance of what it's supposed
to be and all of your testing of why
mammoths pee works is because of the of
the microbe mix that's in the bottle and
so when you go and you try to redo it
yourself you might get drifting
percentages so it's not really the
actual product anymore yeah yes there's
confidence and knowing that you have
something very consistent in the mammoth
pee bottle if we start to work on trying
to scale the microbes up just inherently
if you don't have a completely sterile
room which we have pretty much in our in
our facilities when we're scaling the
bottles up when we wash the balls and do
everything you're gonna get a lot of
issues environmental fluctuations
seasonal environmental fluctuation you
have contaminants coming in Cecily and
so it's really hard to think with
confidence that you can continue to reap
rocket mammoths and keep it pristine
right I would be hard to do right on
that makes sense so um you know so I'm
gonna bring up this question but I
understand that it's pretty farcical but
but people will often mention on threads
that there are there are microbes in the
product that are dangerous to humans
right and so some people say I won't buy
it because it's gotten you know this or
you know another microbe and odd thing
is is like people will choose different
microbes yeah so so you know is the
product in any way you know dangerous to
humans even if used incorrectly no I
mean you don't want to ingest any
fertilizer you don't want to ingest any
life microbial product it's not good for
you I've actually had some growers write
me and said hey long story short don't
ask I mean just as a manaphy and nothing
about happen don't try that at home is
not a good idea no matter what but you
know that's part of the rigor of the
regulation we have to register our
product every state with every country
we have a really sophisticated team of
actually world leaders of soil microbial
ecologists early on that we brought on
board to make sure that we were doing
everything the right way were scientists
and we want to bring value to growers
using microbes
Solutions every one of the microbes and
the strains that we have in mammoth pee
our BIOS bio level safety one which
means that you know there is the very
lowest chance of anything bad happening
and we haven't had any cases ever of
anything like that occurring you know we
do recommend using safety precautions
just like any fertilizer would on the
label it's just kind of a generic we've
have guys producing the product since
day one
you know it's just no different than
brewing a tea honestly the way you're
handling mammoth be the difference in
mammoth pee is are so functionally
targeted that the you're gonna use that
it's a specific clone or bloom stimulant
to maximize the availability of
phosphorous for plant uptake alright so
this last one this is the most common
question that I get from people and I
guess is kind of a two-part question
number one doesn't matter when it
changes colors and number two how do you
figure out what the expiration date is
both great questions so the expiration
date on the bottle we suggest using with
within one year after opening the
expiration date is on every single
bottle on the on the but back so you can
see that our shelf-life data now is
real-time data and it's out over 27
months and so the product is actually
viably good data supported over 27
months saying that we do still recommend
using it with one year after opening
because that that continues to once you
add that oxygen it's a different thing
well the microbial activity actually
increases when you open the bottle and
so it's amazing how long these microbes
lasts in this solution so I'm not
worried about that at all I do think
that you should follow recommended
applications if you can use it within
two years you're gonna be perfectly fine
and again just so there's no
misunderstanding we just gave guidelines
on the back of the bottle because
honestly every time we get more data we
can change all the labels or we just
wait till it goes out the first the
first shelf life or recomm
a use on the label was six months
because we had six months worth of data
so we put that on there then when we had
two years we actually changed it out a
little further so shelf life is not an
issue it lasts as long and longer than
any product I've seen on the market is
actually fascinating what does the
change in the color part change in the
color is oxidation that occurs sometimes
not always and it's very confusing we've
dialed in why it's a little harder to
control this is life in a bottle this is
nature in a bottle and there's some
variability what we do know is that the
guarantee analysis is at least is at
least the same between the lighter
bottles and the darker bottles what we
do know also is they're slightly higher
microbial activity and higher microbial
concentrations see a few counts in the
darker bottles which means that actually
the darker bottles are a little more
effective probably than the lighter
bottles when we have a lot of growers
that use mammoths and what they do is
they like to grab the darker bottles
because they know it's a little more
concentrated both of them are very
effective and work very well that
happens because as microbial activity
slightly increases sometimes it can
create a slight oxidation event which
actually colors some of the carbon
constituents in the bottle slight change
in color as a effect of slightly higher
activity I still our team still can't
figure out how to normalize that to keep
it consistent it's a little bit of a
mystery again it's really hard to
control every aspect of nature and we're
dealing with nature soil microbes that
we're trying to package for farmers and
for growers and so it's a little bit of
a challenge we're still working on it I
hope to have a better answer soon but
what what I do say and I stand by is
that mammoth microbes work and maybe
even a little better with the darker
color cool well thanks for answering
those questions for me now I can just
like move everybody alone in this video
yeah and if you want to learn more about
the mammoth P product you can go ahead
and click on the link down in the first
comment and it'll take you right to the
mammoth P product thanks a lot for your
time Colin right on appreciate it