so I feel yeah I've heard about this one
talk that you give sometimes that's
called Mean Girls about clicks female
clicks in the Canada scene and I haven't
seen this talk and I haven't seen a
video of it but I'd love to hear about
it what what is the what's your idea of
Mean Girls in the cannabis scene well if
you flush back to high school or even
grade school there was always a bunch of
girls there's the girls like for the
cheerleaders they were pretty they had
everything and then there was only
everyone else the out beers and so I was
always in the group layout layer and
what I discovered as I was going through
high school okay I want to be one of
them wouldn't want to be one of them but
then once I graduated high school I
thought great you know I hate high
school now I'll go to college it's
amazing but I what I realized
women
it was gonna go downhill from there so
one of my first lessons as an adult was
don't don't bloom in high school
so now let's fast-forward to cannabis
and what we have here is everyone's
coming into the industry really being
everyone's rushing in but there's a
great opportunity for women we are on a
level playing ground we can go in and we
can create something for us there's
nothing that there was nothing there to
begin with so there's a lot of
opportunity and a lot of ways of playing
outside the rules because women are
really great about how to think outside
of the box we have to think about how to
feed the kids make the house work a job
do this pickup that so we're really
great about multitasking and coming up
with ways of making things more
efficient so the campus industry is a
great thing to go into because if you
were an accountant we just have cannabis
you can be great if you're a chef you
become a few chef tour make edibles
business if you ran a great business you
can run cannabis so but with that many
women in there we're all looking at each
other okay you know how can they help me
how can I help her and we build these
great communities I have some some
friends that I know our life log in
cannabis and I will know them until I
get to the grave amazing wonderful with
men and women but sometimes you get that
high school mentality brought back in
where it's this is this is my patch no
no you're not no you're not touching
this this is what I gonna do
and I'm not gonna share but I want
everything that you have because I'm so
amazing so you run into a lot of women
with a very large entitlement and ego
and if you don't give them what you want
they want they become thin the mean girl
they say oh been affiliate she's a [ __ ]
because she just did it that's not gonna
do this and so you're building up
already these gangs and cliques
you're either pro affiliate or you're
anti affiliate and that becomes this
playground mentality of groups in the
corners which should not happen because
now not only a weak fighting to get a
place a foothold with men we're also
fighting amongst ourselves over petty
things how and it is a culture that has
been brought in because women need to
this is how we bring each other down we
talk about their looks we talk about how
they're not a nice person we we dragged
them down so that we can go higher
there's a Chinese expression called
crabs in a box where crabs will never
will are not a community based group of
shellfish because every time one tries
to get out of the bucket another will
grab that crab and pull it down so in
cannabis there are groups like this
where they're women that try to get
ahead but other ones pull them down oh
she doesn't deserve it
I deserve as she shouldn't get this
rather than all of us think we all
deserve it and we need to work together
and in my case I think I pissed off a
couple of women because I didn't agree
with their ethos or the way that they
were
how they were in the industry ken that's
me you know that's the one I personal
view it's and so what they did was they
took it personally and maybe I made it
personal so there's a there was that but
ever since then I am now called out as
the mean girl pretty much bunch of
people that's for better or for worse
yeah that's okay but that's it's all
it's all high school hijinks and
eventually we'll get past them
we just need to grow up a little bit to
what degree do you think that it is I
mean since since you referred to it as
Mean Girls so what degree do you think
that it's a gender relationship or more
that you've got a whole bunch of a type
leader type strong-willed independent
women who are all in the same field and
so they fall into power blocks just
because of the personality type
regardless of gender yeah and that's the
same for high school you had a whole
group of a type girls too who strive to
be at the top of the feeding frenzy and
so that whole culture again is brought
into cannabis it is I see a lot of it
now in cannabis because there are so
many groups who want to take over from
the place of women girl right there's
quite a few smaller groups popping up
and they're not working together rather
they're cannibalizing each other
for members I have a group kind of mind
group you don't want to go in that group
cuz I have the better speakers listen s
rather than just coming together as a
group or abandoning women group and
going into more mentoring groups for
women who are coming up rather than
bring a speaker in put people together
that I would rather see than going it's
to a panel see three people here I see
about 45 times already that's not going
to give me much value maybe to a new
person but to a new person I much rather
have that new
to be paired with someone just a little
senior to help them through that's how
we combat Mean Girls because a new
person will not know where to go Ravens
I haven't seen very many mentorship
programs for either gender outside of
incubators right clearly that there but
that's mentoring specifically based on
you know VC capital or making money um I
think that a lot of people they don't
want to they don't want to mentor folks
because they're already feels like
there's too many people in the field and
it's so ultra competitive right that a
lot of people consider their their
business experience in cannabis to be
almost like intellectual property and
they don't want to mentor people do you
see any more of that happening with
women for women cuz I wouldn't see that
stuff cuz I'm a guy I think actually
then you make a really great point
because why there are not a lot mentors
it's time everyone some of the bests
that we know cultivators improves they
don't they have don't have time to
mentor anyone and if they do is more of
to be on a paid consultant side
I think women can mentor other women
because we there's some up here who can
this is not the time but there are a lot
of us who are in middle and lower in the
industry that we can mentor someone just
coming in we do have that time that's
where I can see it I don't I'm you're
not asking say a Kevin Joe dree alright
to mentor you because you know he has no
time but you can ask maybe another
cultivator who is lower who's just
beginning to who might have time and in
exchange never this is a good this is
what I learned growing up Asian you
never go to a house empty-handed if you
go to someone and someone invites you
into your home and you bring something
so someone offers you help and wants to
mentor you open it up and give them
something because it is in appreciation
because the last thing you want is to
have your mentor feel that they're being
taken to grant
so you have to be then again open your
heart as they open theirs to you it's a
two-way thing well thanks for sharing
that idea y'all got room thank you I
know um I have no idea it's gonna be
here ball with the holes planes this I
know means were super loud