hey there thank you to for being here
this morning I know there are other
things that you could be doing so I'm
glad that you are here uh thanks to Dave
for the kind introduction and thanks
also to Eric Norton and his team from
imperious Expo um not only for creating
this opportunity for us all to get
together and strengthen our scene um but
also for this opportunity to speak to
you this
morning so there's no doubt that
cannabis is an exceptionally high risk
uh business for entrepreneurs and and
yet we've all been attracted to this
industry like a moth to light right I
mean we're all here and we're feeling
passionate about it and we pride
ourselves on participating in this
industry that is one part patient care
one part booming green rush and let's
face it one part taboo and sticking it
to the man right so our industry is a
tornado and and yet here we are it's
it's filled with risk it gets Messier
every day and here we are feeling
passionate about it and taking those
risks so during my short keynote today
we're going to consider this dichotomy
of the mess and the risk and also why we
feel so driven to be
here for newcomers to the industry it'll
be consideration of the risks and
benefits of participating in this new
cannabis industry and perhaps a warning
of some new surprises that may come
along when Arizona legalizes adult use
in 2018
and for others who have been in the
industry a bit longer it will provide
some laughs about our shared struggle up
to this point so first let's start with
the risks let's look at what we're
really talking about here well first and
foremost what we hear from people all
through the uh the Expo this weekend is
people are afraid of running out of
money one of the questions that we hear
out on in the panels is that people are
like I know I've got raised this much
money I need to do everything I need to
do for that amount of money and yet the
numbers often don't uh pencil out that
is a very significant risk you're an
entrepreneur you've put it all on the
line and your money is quickly draining
away another risk though is that you can
have an otherwise solid business model
you can be an entrepreneur who's
practiced in business and coming from
another industry and do everything right
and yet your state and local taxes can
eat up the profit that you have and what
you're used to excluding with your taxes
because of the 28 issues eats into your
profits so you can do everything right
and still lose because you're not
generating the appropriate
profit not only that but cannabis
business partners make strange bed
fellows it is incredibly common across
the country for people to get together
decide over smok in a bowl that they're
going to start a business together and
then everything goes aide just because
you're good toking Partners just because
your neighbors just because you like to
serve together just because you like to
hike together does not make for good
business partners especially when it's
very likely that one or neither of the
business partners has any business
experience they just think they know
weed these are very real risks and these
are not risks that we generally run into
in other Industries because in other
Industries there's usually some sort of
Journeymen capacity right where you
you've started uh as a newbie or an
intern and you become an admin assistant
and then you work your way up and then
and then you you know get some middle
management experience and then you break
off and you start your own company well
everybody who's doing that was
Prohibition era and most of the people
in prohibition era may or may not have
much experience with the sales cycle
with HR with handling the finances and
so what we've got is a whole bunch of
people who are starting businesses on
passion personal faith and quite
possibly
the money of their
neighbor let's also be aware of the high
risk there is that a landlord changed
their mind we see this all over the
place we all experience the pressure
right from our friends and family um to
some degree about going into cannabis I
can't tell you how many times I've heard
the story from Cannabis entrepreneurs
who were talking to me and they said you
know I knew that cannabis was going to
be a real [ __ ] you know I knew that I
had to give it my all I knew I was
signing up for 7day work weeks I
understand this is startup but I did not
expect the the parents of my children's
friends to no longer let their kids come
over to my house I did not expect that
the pastor at my church was going to
take me aside and saying what are you
doing to the children of our
Parish I did not expect that you know
the local shopkeeper that that I
normally work with every day would just
like start making these uncool comments
about the business that we're in and yet
we as cannabis entrepreneurs we
experience this regularly and the more
you come out which essentially means the
more success you have the more likely
that this is going to happen and so that
delineates the the the last risk in this
section SE section which is
divorce it is incredibly common for any
new startup to put an insane amount of
pressure on a marriage and even if both
people in the marriage are part of the
Cannabis company and maybe sometimes
even more if they are it puts pressure
on all of our relationships our time
with our kids go down our time with our
spouse can sometimes go down and if you
work with your spouse your off time
you're often talking about how to have
the canvas company not
crash it is astonishing as I travel the
country to talk to in the different rep
states to hear people say yeah well I
have a lot more time now to invest in my
company because I'm separated from my
significant other these are all very
significant risks and yet all of the
risks that I've given you so far um are
things that can happen to any startup
it's just um turned up to 11 when it
comes to
cannabis so then let's talk about the
Cannabis specific
risks one of the most common is that you
have put together this fantastic IC plan
for a marijuana grow and you have got
your strains all figured out and you
know you're getting your genetics and
you are ready to go but then there's a
hitch right and it changes from state to
state but it kind of smells like you
didn't win the lottery to get a license
or perhaps you didn't get approved for
some crazy reason that they may not even
tell you because most of these decisions
are made in a black box of
bureaucracy and then you know also maybe
they have um maybe you're misreading a
felony that you used to have maybe it's
for producing cannabis and now you're
trying to go legit you're going to leave
your black market days behind you and
bring your excellent skills to the legal
market and they're like eh you know we
know that the laws say that that we're
not supposed to look at those but but
you know we're still going to put
somebody else in line in front of you
these are all risks and these are risks
that affect us every day and are become
a part of our Lives because we're
choosing in to this high-risk industry
another specific risk that comes a lot
with cannabis is the guy or the gal who
had all this money and was going to fund
your program suddenly does not have all
the money that was going to fund your
program and we all know right we're
certainly not getting Bank uh bank loans
to start our businesses so that means
okay where's your money going to come
from either somehow you were magically
independently wealthy and you are going
to make a big beted on cannabis or
perhaps you got some some friends that
you you know play sports with or your
neighbors or they're at your church or
wherever and you talk to them and
they're all like they see dollar signs
of the magical green rush and they're
like I don't want to be left behind I
remember when I missed Google right and
they're like trying they wanted like
they wanted they want to prove the world
right this time they want to they want
to uh they want to show that they they
they smelled the money when it was
happening and so they tell you I've got
this money I'm selling my this other
business I'm selling this painting I'm
selling whatever I'm I'm getting I'm
getting inheritance there's a good one
too and they tell you you can have all
of it for your business so you start
work so you go ahead and you start
banking all of this work and you and you
start putting in seven days a week and
you st start to make promises to your
allies you start reaching out and making
new networking friends all on the idea
that you're creating this inertia and
then when that check is received and
transferred to you you're ready to go
go then the day comes you've got
everything all set
up you're calling them you're ready you
know you know the the the the the we're
ready to build it we're ready to put the
order in for the parts from China we're
ready to sign a lease and you know they
don't get back to you for 3 days a week
and you realize that the person that you
were depending on for the Lynch pin of
your business plan has evaporated and
they're embarrassed so they don't want
to talk to you and it really doesn't
matter at this point what their excuse
is or what their reason is because it's
already done and all the work that you
put in your seven days a week is flushed
out this is depressing stuff and we all
know that we see it all around us in
this scene there are more companies that
are vaporware than there are actual
companies in our industry at this point
and we all really hope that we're not
going to be the one but we also happen
to know that it can happen to anybody
cuz we've seen iten to good folks so
even outside of maybe things in your
business plan you know all over the
country as as cannabis legalization is
getting more real and more tangible a
lot of counties are just freaking out
and establishing
moratoriums so suddenly out of nowhere
where you live is no longer allowing
cannabis growing cannabis companies
cannabis retail and they just they you
know nine people on your local County
Board suddenly makes the change like
that I'm still not perfectly clear how
in the world a state can legalize
marijuana and a county can then say
except here it just seems wrong to me
but it happens all the time Oregon
Washington California and I'm assuming
it's happening here in
Arizona but if it's not as you move
towards recreational and people start to
see the difference between medical and
recreational they just start to smell a
different vibe I'd say that you can
expect
it you can also be expected that
neighbors of grows will start doing
whatever they can to kind of push your
buttons and push you out you
know in the city it's challenging and
important to uh make sure that your
exhaust doesn't smell like Candace right
Alpha and beta pining has got a smell to
it that not a lot of people are familiar
with or if they are they're Amar with it
and they either well probably like most
of us like who's smoking the day right
and for us it smells good but for a lot
of people they smell that and it smells
like the bad guys it smells like the
criminals and they don't want that smell
anywhere near their house and so if you
live in the city and you're growing
indoors in a warehouse you need to darn
sure that your scrubbers are intact so
that you're not smelling up the
neighborhood but similarly where I live
on Vashon Island you know we only have
agriculturally zoned property The
Growers on our Island figured we're good
to go you know people have got cows
people are growing all sorts of crops it
should be safe here as far as smells go
because we've got 5 10 15 acres and that
shouldn't be a problem and yet you have
neighbors who just don't care for
cannabis maybe morally or maybe they
think it has something to do with their
kids and so they just start filing
little grievances with the County Board
they turn you in they say oh I smell
this aw stink when maybe they smelled it
once on a sunny day during your Bloom
cycle and it wafted their way sometimes
they it's not even about the the reality
of it it's about their reaction to it
this is another risk that we have to
deal
with and finally the last one in this
section is especially appropriate
Arizona there's a risk that some giant
pharmaceutical firm puts its thumbs on
the scale of democracy and plunges a
half million to influence a state
election so they can pedal more opiates
and try and Corner the market on
cannabis before it gets legalized with
the
people we all know that cannabis is
going to get legalized properly in 2018
but it's a shame that corporations can
put that kind of money into what is
essentially a local election and tip the
scales of Justice towards corporate
greed instead of thinking about
individual rights and patient
needs finally
raids now if your first thought was
raids we don't have them they're not in
my neighborhood and they're unlikely I
got to tell you you need to be prepared
for it it does not take a lot for rates
to begin in your local area because when
you think about it what we are doing is
diametrically opposed to the income of
traditional law enforcement now it's
certainly true that there is a great
deal of law enforcement that supports
legalization for a variety of reasons
but we also know especially in small
towns there are local sheriffs and
others with a chip on their shoulder who
see this as some sort of loss and they
are looking for a way to retaliate and
they want to buy their new gear and they
love coming into your business and
capturing all of your gear
so all you had to do all you have to do
in a lot of places in the country is
simply piss somebody off whether it's a
local sheriff a councilman who has some
influence some midlevel bureaucratic
jerk who demands some ridiculous permit
that you just say you know this is a tax
that you're putting on me locally which
is not justified based on the state law
and yet locally they make this permit
and so they're essentially extorting you
any of these people that I'm describing
can give the green light for a raid to
happen on your property and you know I'm
not saying it's necessarily a violent
raid but I'm saying that anytime someone
comes to your property in swat gear and
yelling that sounds like emotional
violence to
me you could just be laate on your taxes
you know a lot of folks are laate on
their taxes a lot of people are really
late on their business taxes but when it
comes to cannabis ta taxes we have to
meet a different standard I know of
jurisdictions in California where if
you're laid down your taxes just like
you know three four business days they
know that since you can't use Banks
you're sitting on cash at your place of
business and they know now they've got a
reason that'll stand up in court to why
they can come to your
property force their way into your safe
capture your money and then make you
fight them to receive it back and God
help you if you've got some nice CO2
extraction equipment well they'll take
that as well and then you're down
another six figures for that plus if
you're an extractor that way well put
you out of business because you may not
have another 100K to pick it up get it
installed and and um and get all the
necessarily finishing technology as
well there's also the possibility of X
employee trash talk so maybe you have an
employee that worked out for a little
while but you know canvas companies kind
of go through employees pretty fast and
you know they leave with a chip on their
shoulder and they kind of want to throw
you under to the bus so they go to that
sheriff that councilman that person who
gives the permit and they said you know
what they're violating this rule this
Rule and this
rule that is often enough to cause a
raate on your property when they should
totally just send somebody a permitting
officer to check it out but when it
comes to cannabis people jump the gun
they go right from questioning to we're
bringing in with the guns in the flag
jacket and I had thought about that for
a while why is this why do they go from
Zer to 100 so fast and it's because the
bureaucracy still considers us scrims
they are assuming that we've got weapons
they are assuming that we are going to
resist they are res assuming that they
have to be protecting their lives and
with time this will go away because I
don't see a whole lot of violent people
in this room we're just normal folks
we're normal folks who are excited about
something and we want to
participate but that's not how everybody
sees
us it's okay to be cautious about going
into cannabis and you know it's probably
really smart before you go in a cannabis
you should have a real heart-to-heart
talk with your family spend some time
thinking about what your risk tolerance
is you know you cannot be brave or
courageous though with some amount of
fear and everybody in this room who is
has chosen to start a cannabis company
is exhibiting courage because we are
moving in the direction that history
supports even though a lot of those in
power don't yet recognize
it entrepreneurs and other Industries
they try to equate themselves with us
but Canabis entrepreneurs are their own
breed and like no one else you how we
cannot even use the bank
what is an entrepreneur without a bank
and checks and the ability move cash
around and develop cash flow we have
none of that and yet entrepreneurs in
other Industries say to us oh you know I
could do that if I wanted to no you love
your security too much you are not risk
tolerant in this way and you don't care
about the plan we are
different we are odd we're Fringe we're
dreamers even even if you're a suit wear
and finance person with an MBA if you
are in cannabis you're still an oddball
Fringe dreamer to show up in cannabis
and dive into all of this risk and find
joy in it doesn't matter where you come
from the fact that you are here means
you're part of this new
community all right so now that we've
covered all the depressing stuff that
makes a second guess why we're even here
today let's talk about why we're here
here
today the title of this talk today is
risky business why we choose
cannabis we're here because we choose to
participate we choose to be courageous
in the face of messy
laws unsteady
enforcement and the Judgment that we get
from our community sometimes so for all
of this risk and potential headache what
are these rewards that keep us deeply
involved and working 7 days a week and
potentially risking all of our
savings you know this answer is
different for everybody but there are
certainly some common
things number
one and most important to me we are
healing humans it's as simple as that we
are self-empowering and choosing to do
the good thing we have chosen to be on
the right side of history and make
cannabis happen where we live we choose
to work our asses off in order to
relieve the suffering of our fellow
human now in states that are still P
purely medical that is the primary
conversation that happs how are we going
to help patients but I got to tell you
by living in and visiting other wck
states that gets lost awfully fast as
soon as the W Market comes and it splits
our scene there are schisms in our scene
between people who are in it because
they cared about the plant and they want
to heal humans and people who smelled
money and moved into the new industry
they were in Tech and then they were in
real estate and now they're in
weed I'm not really faulting these
people but they're different than us
they're different than the people who
are into it because we can help heal
each other number two it's just fun
the Cannabis industry is the best
industry I have ever been in and I'm one
of those people who
did Tech the doom boom and real
estate I was a cannabis Enthusiast the
entire time and I was educating those
around me about how to heal themselves
with cannabis but I also wasn't really
all that interested in going to
prison the community we have created is
funloving our events are way better than
any other industry and how great is it
to be able to get together at events
like this get together compare business
strategies share best practices teach
each other about extraction technology
talk about our favorite strains trade
genetics and then go up to the roof of
the hotel and totally get
bait we are funloving people and even
though you know I'm in a suit today
because it's kind of the role I'm
playing as panel moderator and
delivering the keynote to you today
we're probably the only industry where
we can dress like this and still be
considered professionals it's a damn
good time to be in the Cannabis industry
and that holds a lot of weight
especially if you've ever done time in a
blue chip company or in a cubicle or
working for some
jerk another reason is that for many of
us this is a dream come true right I
mean think back to when the first times
you were smoking with your friends it's
a summer afternoon and you're all high
and laying on the grass and looking at
the sky and joking about when you be
great someday to move somewhere warm and
you we'll just grow weed and we'll have
a really good life right sometimes
you're fantasizing about you know living
in Humble County maybe it's Hawaii
that's a real popular one but you know
since we're here in Arizona this pretty
boss too I can see people fantasizing
about moving here and growing as well
the point is is that that growing
cannabis is filled with ideals that
encourage
Community positive relationships within
people and many people's ideals and
dreams of fantasies about what life can
look like fit right in line with growing
cannabis so not only is growing cannabis
and being in the industry fun and it's
been a dream come true for many of us
it's also
cool and cool to a certain extent is the
Judgment of other people because we can
know we're cool but it's different
because I love when I tell people that I
work in cannabis so often their response
contains a little bit of awe and I know
you've had that experience right because
when people find out you work in
cannabis you can decide you see this
thing in their eyes where they're like a
they never really thought that somebody
who looks like like you might be in
cannabis or that they thought you did
this other thing but more than anything
you can almost feel a little bit of
jealousy because you are following your
passion and you're choosing to like we
said earlier kind of Stick it to the Man
a little
bit which leads me to my last one
another reason why it's great to work in
cannabis is simply because it's taboo
you know everybody in this room feels
and identifies a little bit with being a
rebel with a cause a bad boy or a bad
girl right we are giving the finger to
the man and maybe her parents and
certainly the whole structure of our
society who has told us for years that
good people don't smoke
marijuana yes yes we do and we're going
into
business and finally number
six even though there's all the risks
that I already delineated and that's a
lot of risk and you really have to have
an insane amount of risk awareness and
comfort with risk to even go down this
path but if you do in addition to it
being fun and enjoying yourself and
helping patients and being cooler than
your friends there's a chance there's a
chance that you can make some
money the challenge with that though is
that we all know from states that are
already into this that the mark are
tight and a lot of it's eaten up by
taxes and yet there's that promise of
being first and we've seen how being a
first mover in Industry can equate into
large sums of money down the line and
you know sometimes it doesn't even have
to be large sums of money sometimes it
can just be making enough to get by but
doing it in a way that you can feel
proud of maybe tons of money will come
down the line but but maybe that's a
long-term goal maybe you're just glad to
be taking part in righteous living and
righteous income and feel that you're
living your life with honor and wanting
to help patience and move the ball down
the
field so in
summary
cannabis is sketchy and risky and mean
people play
dirty the risks that I've delineated are
not new to any of you and there's as
much luck involved as there is skill to
having success in cannabis and you may
need to try several several times to
find the right situation or company or
business partners before hitting the
right
opportunity but I'll tell you
this it's the best game in town and for
many it's the only game in town we get
to help patients and we get to be cocky
love Breakers at the same time and we
just might make money so dream big help
your neighbor make smart moves and enjoy
this building process every damn day
because today is the only day we know we
have and building a cannabis business is
an honorable Pursuit thank you