we go beyond start up it's a pleasure to
be here this is my first time at the
summit
and it's been a fantastic day my name is
Elizabeth Bennet I'm a professor at the
Clark College in Portland Oregon I'm an
international political economist typer
to the intersection of politics and
economics
thank you about most is globalized
supply chains and what I care about most
is workers rights and exploitation all
over the world so until a few years ago
most of my trying to attend organic
textiles and coffee and following those
around the world seeing how people were
treated when they're working in those
industries and also paying a lot of
attention to what consumers are doing so
if you want to see you know who made my
shirt where was my coffee grown what do
I want to support with my collar I study
consumer activism in global supply
chains last six years head on between
Colorado and Oregon and thinking a lot
about Panama it was story unfold and so
over the last two and a half years I've
been doing a lot of research on these
issues as they apply to cannabis in the
States
so what I'm interested
is who is growing who is trimming and
what is their flight's length is it one
of dignity and possibility of agency and
opportunity or it's a one of hardship
and limitations so I want to talk about
some changes I see happening in the
canvas labor force what you sort of like
where I think it's going well some of
the problems I think are associated with
the very current and very nature of farm
labor return labor in cannabis special
challenges that this industry faces
compared to others in the campus market
in the last say 30 years in terms of its
growing and trimming 75 percent of
cannabis will be us as you probably know
is coming from the west coast most of
the people growing working for other
people at arm's trimming have been white
they send us form and they've been minor
labor working in town and agriculture
products in the offseason so that means
they're people with relatively great
amount of privilege compared to workers
who are in other agricultural industries
that's not to say that there haven't
been immigrants and migrant laborers
working in which for the last 30 years
definitely the
but it's not been what Stockton this is
really different than the rest of
agriculture so for the last 30 years
people who have been working in cannabis
the demographic today I just described
have been accepting a great deal of risk
in exchange for a refill a reward on the
payment very high compared to working
other agricultural sectors the risk has
also been extremely high so we know that
for cannabis grower occurs in Turners
tweets that is pervasive being
chronically do not paint that correct
amount we're being asked to wait
additional weeks or months and a
different amount sexual assault and
harassment is common unsafe living and
working conditions also common between
2012 and 2016 the Humboldt domestic
violence service center said that they
receive about 2,000 calls per year from
Humboldt County alone about two people a
year ago miss maybe wasn't working in
cannabis in Humboldt County those
statistics are much higher than in other
places so as I've been working with with
triggers and whips workers I have yet to
encounter one former has been working
for over five years in the industry who
has not had a personal experience of
some sort of Lieber exploitation or has
not personally known someone who has had
that experience
we don't happen
the demographics of the labor force and
the amount of exploitation we know it's
at least on par with common with other
agricultural products the United States
everyone has the story
so that's what we've been looking at
we'll take the last 30 years
things are changing I see if it changes
and labor force going in different
directions for the illegal and illegal
markets or for growing and trimming on
the illegal market prices are appalling
be giving a huge amount of value for
products are are largely over I think
someone said this leads to innovation
and communication which is fantastic it
also leads to different types of labor
exploitation so what I started to see
happening in the info market is
attractive people who are willing to
work for less money these are often
migrant workers new immigrants people
with legal status foods that are less
straightforward extremely vulnerable
populations are beginning to work
so this is starting to look a lot like
big agriculture big agriculture in the
u.s. a place where the most vulnerable
people in our population work people who
are mean least except susceptible to
exploitation so if you give a sense of
what that would look like or cannabis to
move to the beef big act model each year
in the United States 300,000
agricultural workers report of pesticide
poisoning 20,000 agricultural workers
report a cute pesticide poisoning those
are reported accounts not estimates
based on reported data so that's a very
very low end of what's possible that's a
lot of people with too much pesticide
exposure that's all helps us understand
why life expectancy is shorter in the
United States rabbit cultural workers
and helps us understand why first weight
is lower for children or agricultural
workers and why does children are more
likely to have chronic health conditions
that they're not an agriculture so we're
listening age wouldn't have we know that
in the United States a big agriculture
women we're working in the field 80
percent report sexual harassment and
wanted to be whether they
they happen or know someone who has been
sexually assaulted while working in
their fields so if I segment campus and
labor might be moving toward what Big
Apple is like and I started this in the
chorus that I've heard here drop today
which is to say we don't want to go that
route it's not a good place to be and
that way I think it's likely that things
be worse for people working in
agriculture services so what about the
legal sector something I care about
making this research opening the
conferences is this is a room full of
people who largely work in the legal
sector or what we care about is
regulating the Neal sector we are
positives problem and I thank you I see
the legal sector moving in the direction
of the meat industry in the food states
so if you know anything about the top of
the big meat industry
it's always rely on relation waver the
work is extremely challenging and
extremely dangerous
Human Rights Watch reports that all
manufacturing and
State to work in slaughtering process
meat is by far the most dangerous
this explains why 2006 the people who
worked in these slaughtering abilities
were the most vulnerable of our
population the people in our communities
are at PDS to exploit people who had
migration services where they weren't
allowed to work who are undocumented and
in 2000 rivers or beef across human
conceits are neat facilities and the
industry decided we can no longer hire
people who might not Eve we go to work
in the United States you should be hired
we should hire a resettle refugees
because they are the next easy Institute
in our community and we know that their
legal support who are not susceptible to
raising more so what big need looks like
in the United States today is 35%
immigrants 10% coming from East Africa
pervasive reach that's pervy for sexual
harassment
human rights watch reports a high number
of injuries on the job and a hostile
working environment especially for
workers of color especially for Muslim
workers so they excuse me Colorado
hundreds of Muslim workers were fired
when they were
we have prayer times that that suited
their cultural needs and we're asking
for this facility and help arrange some
production practices around narratives
they require there's union-busting or
event missing after organizing meat
factory workers to really vulnerable
population so it's very big time the Old
Market would it look like in two ways I
see the new market going in terms of
Labor and labor abuse you know the lines
between what canvas labor used to look
like and who look like a future isn't
isn't so clear and the difference
between illegal and legal sectors it's
not so clear so to illustrate I hear
stories every time I talk to trimmers
about what's going on right now so I
talked to a woman in Oregon a whole
bunch they both described last year
looking for work on a legal firm and
believing that the farm was growing with
license and was going to sell it illegal
market she wanted to beat me in a legal
market that was her intention she was
locked in the basement without a
cellphone and that allows emergence or
trimming was done our typical stories
that I hear all the time
evenings where the legal sector in organ
this past year so some of our
conceptions about what happens now the
canvas is legal don't believe that much
the reality of workers lives so if we
don't want to have a problem of big meat
and then you know under the route the
agriculture and we don't want to go the
route of underground exploitation then
something needs to change
there's some defects in campus compared
to making sweaters or shoes are growing
coffee the industry's reticent to
highlight its problems right it's been a
long fight and they go but follow the
careers of many people in this room and
you follow in heart to have canvas
recognized as something that deserves
the seat of its people and it throw it
under the bus by showing ways widget
displays people can be challenging and
I've seen a lot of shoving leader
problems under the bus as to not reveal
a blemish
energies know that now private
organizations won't touch candidates and
football and constantly were right I
talked to every fair trade domestic
territory workers rights organization
was a judgmental como students no one
wants to work especially the industry
that has to do something consumers are
not your marketing candidates as places
radical shopping they don't go into
dispensaries and ask for organic and
fair trade every single time even if
they would in other markets or virtual
and shopping for other products and
people misunderstand the labor practices
and need to be educated about what their
leader looks like so well thinking that
something's burnin Washington or Oregon
it must be fairly for the fair trade us
MA
so ways forward to close baggage things
about policy and enforcement employer
education workers rights education
collective action supporting the growers
- who are already duties making sure
there are people in the room I spent a
lot of time to achieve growers in an
Oregon people are paying health
insurance or providing incredible work
if I was fighting them and urge them to
do to share their practices and supports
us and because it's that vote with your
wallet
that's over you wallet support voluntary
initiatives there been lots of organic
blank labels that have come up from
campus you may be familiar with clean
green or Crime certified since the USDA
Organic people for cannabis there are a
lot of substitutes that are kind some of
those Libre provisions some of them film
and a ones that do include labor
provisions can do a better job so if you
see something labeled as ethical as
is that the last thing it's not consumer
education and I am happy to share over
networking some statistics from two
years ago at Portland I had a number of
college students go to all the random
samples have the dispensary for language
with not and we're asking for socially
responsible and environmentally friendly
cannabis and we documented what people
willing to sell us and things were being
about those products we gave a 75% of
dispensaries of BC not an A
I think I said protectors
I mean it's not inclusionary system at
all look at barriers to entry was one of
the hardest reasons and say Washington
to get a license it's a major factors
from what happened a felony which is a
result of the war on drugs prior my wife
that we need to set up all the nails in
the plans we need to kill Isis
secondly well capital to give the dogs a
license to be able to Canada to
understand economics and let's
understand that there are racial
disparities in society pretty faint this
is fact this is the housing bubble prank
pondered like Spanish communities make
between they are all types of different
policies from the GI Bill to the
homestead how the discrimination all
play into the legal counter said were
students on the ground today and why
there is no positive inspection of thank
you mission the war on drugs
or at least our housing discrimination
how discrimination is that these
determination of the well
in capital gains in America money
without without one ownership you have
no access to welcome you know staying in
a perpetual state of poverty that then
to is also types of the education system
the education system is funded about the
titles of your homes and your value
you're on the red line neighborhoods
never England gain equity or net value
in your home there was never a chance
for your schools to gain full funding
and become an educated community from
those if you have an uneducated
community if you have a local level T
prime neighborhood if you come up top of
the housing discrimination on top of all
these other breath money everything else
that or the although now it was targeted
at hippies and black men that's not a
pretty famous expand we have a large
population of people in prison in the
world have that population being black
me that right there excludes millions of
guys really involved in the campus
industry a two-parent a two of black G
parent home making a hundred thousand
dollars still has less of a chance of
buying a home today in America in today
2017 that a one parent quite there
well the wealth gap between whites and
blacks is like 12 to 1 the numbers are
just there my life all that leads into a
person into those properties was leads
into war on drugs which leads to the
targeting the black men which now we
have these characters which it's hard
it's for me it's a rest of the legal
cannabis is really just a slap in the
face of black America yeah it's not it
hasn't it's a fail social experiment
it's been exclusionary from day one you
know it hasn't addressed any of the
issues I mean we just saw the man after
speak about what it was like to come to
the floor in PTSD but the war on throws
on like men we can't get recognized the
pts it's nobody whatever say anybody in
my community who asked me to give me
it's the inclusion either not wanting to
be involved in a system that was so long
victimized and criminalized the exact
same thing and everybody in his world
was attempting to build a personal
economic we're not looking at the
economics of the entire to any countries
it's about personal life gay cannabis
industry
every every every idea that comes with a
sign English why did Naaman Trenor good
at me if you look at what the trauma
that black Americans have suffered
because of the war on drugs people are
also looking around from expensing while
I'm one of the very few I can see the
camera now this room is even thinner
graphically representative of the state
of Washington which is dangerous if my
dreams are a curse and black beans we
have less than 1% black people in this
room so what are we going to conclude
what we collectively to address this
issue is not being addressed by anybody
not quite anywhere I was just actually
lovely today to the multi- programmers
might be the most regressive equity
programs in the country but you can't
get licensed unless you know somebody
that is disenfranchised before they want
trouble get a license so there's there's
ways of attempting I've been involved
with canvas in the stasis 2005 and that
would take off and it's the same
conversation but what we're going into
what
and Washington is looking at likely to
in the bracelet discrimination problems
with racism is not my property the
property that the problem the problem of
inclusion in the system is it's going to
take everybody in this room to rethink
what opportunity you can't inclusion
cannot be you can mean the security
guard at the front door inclusion has to
be executives it has to be it has to be
administrators world versus service
worlds it has to be that the same person
was sitting in prison for bagging of
lead in its selling lead now has
hireable skills towards a little bit of
a kinky because he had a felony was his
final you know sigh family my father my
conclusion conclusion is just really
think twice ago article it is you're
doing them in cannabis makes are they
actively doing something or are you
using guys like keeper tokenism versus
you know participation slaves
participated they're doing a great level
of disc America
so I didn't never come into the family
protection that could be different but
is expect some kind of inclusion
somewhere along the line for what the
war on drugs did to an entire community
and in the movie Florida the end of not
addressing of that he's in my
competition and we got into a lot
because world but because that part is a
part of America where the drug was still
happy two distinct we've talked about my
friend conversations in here today about
the opioid continued as a matter but
they're still in South Seattle president
young blankets for crack how do we
determine that opioids that are less
more addictive or less harmful to
society crack so the disparities in the
trouble are still happening does not
talk about the Disick normal and
ignorance is bliss ignorance is safe
this is same as place behind each other
difference so really think twice and
horrible which is doing before the end
here inclusion of minorities involved in
this in this cannabis community because
this thing isn't going to growth as you
started doing everybody just it's just
not to grow without diversity here
classes diversity diversity
[Applause]
maybe three set that timer please
Thank You Aaron and thank you for coming
today in many ways first of all I'll
introduce myself I can just
automatically zoom in from a lot of
people here already flagrantly I am dr.
Tom Foreman founder and executive
director of senators from dependence and
central policy I working for the
Alliance
besides the predecessor to the
Alliance's last four years you know to
develop our education aspect canvas
legalization ways that go beyond
industry formation figuring out problems
with that we you guys know how to handle
that in many ways but there's also the
broader social issues basically and I
came to this start this organization
slightly optimistically I think thinking
that's because the soul of the cannabis
industry comes from oppressed people to
be honest people in pain oppressed
people say hippies were real talk about
the anti-war activists socialists 1960s
a man that I gave you a nice prelude to
this general concept the idea is that
those values could at least be carried
into a system that had a lot of problems
an economic system that already has long
then I talk about you know can this
Agriculture don't want to become a lot
of regular agriculture actually and I'm
thinking like any aspect of the cannabis
industry become like the way industry is
in the right states which in particular
it sets up you know barriers to not
prosperity the survival for increasingly
large amount of people then increase
inequality in this country in the last
30 years is absolutely astonishing we
have seen public policy shift from at
least pretending to care about the
public and more towards let's enable you
know the private sector to take care of
our city policy and determine a
free-market level but that's what's
happened is the concentration what will
probably hang with you and then it's
absolutely infected where you can this
legalization and a very very very
significant degree
so my broader purpose is to talk about
racial political economy but in a way
that doesn't try to represent black
people in white because if you see
that's greater you need to do that
you've got air and thankfully this
especially you know here speaking from
that community what I want to do is talk
about that at the big picture and this
past year has been very interesting for
me as I've been asked to go speak I
thinking in context where the things
that I swirl with here in Washington
state you know get put into a different
perspective this past june was invited
to go speak and theorize the network
at the University of Essex in the UK and
it was fascinating because of all the
perspectives there and folks who are
dealing with you know real significant
issues related to you know the truth of
migrants mules weapon violence in
swimming and I go in there and I'm like
oh yeah like you're from a place where
without arrest for a policy I'm going to
complain about it and and so it really
forced me to kind of like think it's a
lot harder about what community what are
those connections between but like what
I see without fear that I want to be
finally and the broader picture which is
well something changed that I think the
way things are are not good in every
sense of through the words international
political economy of which the u.s. is
an ad driver so I wonder -
personalizations to end the drug war
that was the point of the primary point
and I want to say that that's how I find
though to soul it was primarily of a
soul was that as a racial justice
initiative is he cool things that you
know maybe there could be some markets
that that happened many initiatives that
we've had so far really they're selling
race all right but but what ends up
happening is is the distance for God I
think by now is plenty of evidence it
like this is a baby switch in many ways
into the pump he's always concerned
about you know racial justice economic
justice and then you turn around and you
are darkness - just completely forget
about it and make it about state revenue
will make it about say like you know who
gets to be represented to the
decision-makers
people with a long money so one of the
the other the other conference I'm going
to bring into the sort of dialogue by
Quincy was DBA caucus my plan which was
kind of like a breath of fresh air for
me because I could go there and start at
a higher level of conversation that I
could go there like saying this and
explain this was not you know
conversation at all right what's ition
about the TPA is here that even they
want to step down and there's new
leadership the DPH prior to now this
focused on you know doing campus
legalization initiatives because you
know themselves they would help right
and I think that the EPA is dramatically
shifted mission because one of the great
things that come saw at the reform
conference which is foot race front
Center in this country when it comes to
you know what DK is working on to some
extent there are few policy initiatives
that do directly manages the grace in
particular they intersect a little bit
with some DK people right cat Packer
down in LA we're gonna learn about that
like yeah they they're taking a extra
couple of weeks to get it figured out
but it's precisely because they're
they're dealing with natural social
equity and so that I'm just going to
open it up and see what happens
they were make sure that about
there the process now and that cat
Packers did big part of that and I think
one thing you look forward to going for
it is in fact that DK functions as funny
mechanism for such a change no question
you're going to be seeing I think a lot
more effort to its academic engagement
and policy you know faces and then you
seen before in different areas so you
know we can be incredible you know where
is the actually existing policy effort
addressing Aboriginal economy you know
municipal rags over little such a sort
of wants to pop it open
la is doing it with style there's not
much here in Washington and positioning
Nova Scotia's have a school where the
racial justice things that you guys are
doing anyway it's come up with the pret
side is there a point it out you know
but the points and you know until it's
getting the license aren't you feel
spots or someone from a pack leader all
right well you're asking the private
sector to do something that to me is
it's it's good better than nothing for
sure it's basically like there's a
public interest and we're gonna leave in
the prep sector to do it and I think
that this urn is where that's
appropriate areas perfect actually this
is so big that actually we need to get
this head-on various access is really
the fundamental issue is that we rated
it so tough to get parts industry no
small part to meet regulatory issues and
until the yesterday apparently
to comply the Cole memo which is trends
outside was much ado about nothing
whether we have solar the Colo has been
used as an s actually a way to reproduce
racial injustice has been used to keep
air inside
it's been used to you know prevent home
bro from from the impossibility if you
wanna shout for granted sentence because
what he says numbers a small step right
if you have home bro we are gonna get
research real research to tell us okay
at home
I say the place that their industry your
team is that you want counties to stop
banning you want you know to be able to
be allowed to sell advertising stuff
it's got to be okay with general public
to the degree that they comfortable at
that point like you guys may know a
little free to operate and do all the
dresses are particular markets it's that
removing stigma only helps you and folks
who are opposing on the world for
economic reasons to me I think
think back really really carefully
because you're reproducing prohibition
as a cultural institution that they like
that this is a licenses to two people
what we can't reconstruct communities
that actually destruction effects of
prohibition they're not that I'm just
throwing you know one person in jail the
knock-on effects are the invisible
punishments that have happened to
families breaks up families in comes
upon the dreamers Excel just absolutely
gutted and I think that Richard Nixon's
wet dreams this pretty much the politics
of mercifully woodcomb really like is
it's clearly represented who's the Pope
whose public safety matters right and
every time we talk about protecting the
public and what you know that like
generally speaking when politicians talk
about they're talking about the
particular individuals or stakeholders
who are paying lobbyists to tell them to
say that and I think we should then
exchange hostile governments should not
be a marketplace policy should up
something they bought and sold there
should be public representation that
were a representation in transparency
becomes tense
position and that's you know that's not
just going to help no black people cause
it's going it's going to help you know
the folks the broad spectrum population
that is not represented right like I
said the problems bigger than cannabis
can see the promise of democracy and
have them do it and it's really
important that you know the racial
argument is is lifted up and amplified
as part of the broader social problems
right they're not just affecting black
people the person electical xb2 right
want a better society so you know as a
result like questions are total para see
to bring up in public
can you discussed in arenas where like
this understanding is there like in
Atlanta so where you have actually what
about what about us record right right
loses income
how do people participate what about
patients without HIV patients what about
people who have actually ready to come
together before quite as you want and so
forth and get therapy benefit out of it
it wasn't just a marketplace it was also
being together not nice sanitized which
is kind of the story the hiv/aids crisis
in the social clubs in San Cisco so it's
not just probably more options at work
that can come but removing politics of
suspicion and fears all right it's
really important each small step we can
take is important I think in this state
like right now like homegrown is one of
those small steps that's actually
removing the stigma that you remove that
like big people okay that remove the
power of people
China pulse so that's my message really
is that I need to let Social Policy
govern markets nothing that were around
and that's gonna lead to healthier
markets you guys are squeezed to death
by complying with regulations that are
there to protect the public
but that protection is a political
theater
for the most part and the thing is is we
can't go around you know
and continue to stigmatize you know
folks who participate in the Kansas
market in the informal market either
updates its anytime you have to get more
punishment prop up something here at
your on the rough side and look what
you're doing
so today
[Applause]
I'm so Patterson aye I'm gonna research
Connelly office Financial Management
three economist that support the
governor's policy staff and other that's
a piece like the legislature interview I
work for the USDA National Agricultural
Statistics services before I came back
to Washington I for others those in the
other Washington sweating it's I mean at
a statistician genes so my job research
economist with my family is pretty fun
but it leads me on in all sorts of
different ways but I also wanted to
thank Walker and inviting me here and I
also want to know the people here are
like really amazing so
I went to the LCD to provide economic
guidance on how to Institute in working
market
I didn't kidded that the market should
define us and I said the number of
consumers was unknown that the quantity
demanded was someone I'm not a member as
well and further the number of producers
in the auditorium now I recommended the
notion that the number of producers and
retailers would equilibria as the market
matures and thus the number of licenses
should not have a maximum I said several
of the LCB constituents that the table
vehemently disagreed I said hey I'm a
capitalist so they'll see be higher than
anti cannabis drug policy persons that
guide their economic system so in my
mind I was saying what a working market
for canvas and a reasonable expectation
Republic is where consumers can buy a
high-quality cannabis product that is
uniform the canvas is pesticide free and
press fit so in essence an orderly
stable market that safe free of
antitrust and protection
so it's a promise we have not covered
recovered from the 1936 games only
farmers and fighters is instead a
convoluted password of entrepreneurs
equal to eat eager to create a
capitalist market and crotchety men
regulating based on archaic mythology
and overreaching a lot so I looked at
this and I one of the things that always
intrigues me about market failure is
asymmetric information you might
remember like the cigarette in the
street used to say that cigarettes are
actually imported so I thought ok I'm
gonna look at this from purely like what
do we have here what is what is provided
to the public to know about this
industry so I just looked around I said
ok well that old Seabee is is tasked
with providing some sort of education
material on marijuana cannabis reefer
whatever can so I said okay whoa
I picked one subject fairly random I
said said said can't getting high
cosmetic problems and I said okay
whoopsies
so I pressed on the link and it said
science based information from above I
said okay well that's interesting it's
produced or presented by the University
of Washington
no offense it was the alcohol and drug
abuse Institute and it says scientists
think that cannabis causes problems
remembering problems with creates and
negative effects learner hi
I know it's tough there's no citations
whatsoever and it says science based
right at the top so I get a little okay
you claim science based so where are the
citations and then so they look like
that well is this one professor that
used to be here and he just because I'm
one of the nice right out of those
seasons of the public didn't read and
digest we just he just summarized it
right there I said okay well that it
well the person pointed me to be a
National Science Foundation or the
National Academy of Science current
release maybe somebody seen that's like
170 pages order but I already has a okay
well that contradicts everything that
your website says so what what is the
point is this education what is it
what are you trying to get what I never
the way
but so what's the purpose of the a some
asymmetric information in this game
who's winning what why are the wider the
allegiance is still there to this
prohibition mindset what is the purpose
and that's something that I wondered of
you know but I believe all sorts of
markets been so the LCB adopted the same
provision strategy as they use for
alcohol the same number of retail stores
exactly that's the probably got the 233
stores right Costco scold okay we need
something it's enforcement of
enforcement so the woman history of
prohibition has wide cultural
implications you may have heard
marijuana is a very dangerous drug yet
this hypothesis is profoundly unproven
and reality is not an impressive support
of the assertion the canvas is at all
dangerous though the only thing I will
say that canvas is dangerous is
enforcement right how many people have
you ever seen dying for camels not but
how many people have been arrested
anyways so what happens next up we can
just see but I will know that in
Washington the latest estimates are
they're about 11,000 direct employment
jobs in the cannabis industry though the
wage rate is somewhere in the mid $13 an
hour range so let's see Mele I I was
shocked it was that low but you know as
the black market still there so that's
kind of that sort of ambiguous question
so but beyond that you know what's
really the economic cost of prohibition
I mean that's what I that's sort of in
my mind's eyes like why why are we in
this sort of lockstep of it's not it's
not a free market at all this is the
small microcosm of a few licenses which
are getting the maximum number for what
reason I don't
right thank you for the wonderful
introduction
Lara thank you for the invitation to be
here and I'm honored to sit on a panel
list of people of such depth of
knowledge about the state of the
industry it's possible future I'm gonna
shift gears a little bit
my name is Bart Ober and I'm the mayor
from the city of Arlington about 18,000
people or one I like to call us on the
urban edge we used to be ruled we need
to be sophisticated and we are in quiet
ways and we but right up against the big
cities and the urban as that happens in
Snohomish County so what I want to talk
to you about today with your indulgence
is I just want to tell you the story of
Arlington economists and how it came
about and I hope through the story that
you can gain some insight into have
elected officials might be viewing that
I Bible too initiative what it means to
their community and hopefully what you
mean to their business initiatives so
first I am always excited
thank you as a bold step and I offer
anybody who wants to step into business
in 2012 in November state of Washington
voted positivity for I 502 the
initiative final - to allow campus
operations in our in in the state of
Washington I've been a mayor for nine
months I never sat in elected office
before we had a huge problem cement city
coming out of the recession we were not
recovered we were really in the depths
of it still even though nationally the
economy is starting to recover and this
was like home okay when we're going to
add to the place I kept all of the
literature that I have received from
August through November because there
was a lot of any elected any kind of
omission that there's a lot of
propaganda throw at God but I knew this
was the message that our community was
getting and this is what we would have
to talk about well oh man so the first
thing is we sat down and we look at the
numbers for our jurisdictions our
antenna conservative community in
Northern Sonoma County had voted
positively in the direction of i-502
so that's where we started our citizens
wanted it so we better figure out what
we're going to do about it I called a
meeting of our senior managers that week
together because I wanted to gauge where
we were at as a city with this being a
relatively new mayor and many of them
had
positions for a long period of time and
I wanted to hear honestly where they
were at witness and it was very
interesting and some of it almost fell
over really mirrored the literature that
had been going around the community for
two months those in the public safety
you have been being funded by the war on
drugs for multiple decades were very
nervous about the public safety concerns
to the community however they couldn't
really articulate those public safety
concerns internally now have questions
but you know the kids the school oh my
god
crying all of those things that are
going to happen to our community if we
allow this to happen our Community
Economic Development Department those of
you were here last year have the
privilege of hearing Christiana see the
inspectors perspective on the industry
I found curiosity going on there what
does it mean they notice of each your
business initiatives what's the
employment look like what's going to be
the ratio of employees per square
footage how does this fit into our
culture and our desire to be a
manufacturing community so that wasn't
really that was happening there and then
there was just a lot of ambivalence like
I really do you want to do this and
that's like you know it doesn't matter
what we want to do our citizens have
spoken to us that's our job to figure
out how to make word what they want so
we went to work and we use our Planning
Commission how many of you okay
intravenous
these are counties that businesses in
that you all have within those who are
planning under the growth Management Act
aside from elected officials it's
usually a pepper along with tears called
Planning Commission and the Planning
Commission sets about helping
jurisdictions figure out a lot of the
regulations under land-use that are
going to happen so they deal with a lot
of positive additional things better
ones who are doing the comprehensive
plans to figure out what Sony goes where
and who could go where so even though
this would affect them to Chairman our
money Commission's and they won't take
us on as research older gentleman or we
thought you know he's pretty fair and
open so let me go do some research
he began watching people around the
state of Washington will understood what
the cannabis industry might be what does
that look like and what does it mean to
a jurisdiction and he brought us back a
report that was devoid of any judgment
but really a lot of factual information
and a lot of it was this a lot of
unknowns this is the beginning of
legalization of an industry who we
couldn't classify as an industry before
because it was done on the black market
and it was Revo so we haven't figure out
what all of this with me well some of
the directors started to be a little
intellectually curious of this and how
many - you're intellectually curious
come talk to us by the job because
that's what we want we'll train you what
you need to know how to do the
qualifications but we want people were
intellectually curious
get a little intellectual curious how do
we make this work how does it fit into
our initiative so that way there was a
lot that went on in that period of time
but we also then we had to educate the
elected officials myself and the City
Council members who would be responsible
for this so those of you who don't know
in the last 10 years cities of all sizes
have been driven by data through the
recession and what happened afterwards
we're using data base data data
dashboards trying to make more effective
decisions for the resources that we have
at least I can beautify some data
techniques the understanding this
industry so we made charts of all of the
information all the propaganda and all
the fields of what was going to happen
and that became the metrics of the
dashboard that we were going to measure
as we started to regulate I 502 in our
community we also knew that the
legislature and the liquor board at that
time another liquor Canada sport had a
really big job in front of them to
figure out how they were going to
regulate this industry and what it would
look like so we are smart enough to know
that this was going to be an
ever-changing playing field and I tell
you this because it's important in your
jurisdictions your elected officials who
are watching this whether they allow it
or not have seen dramatic changes in the
regulation of this in
verse five years in the first 12 months
there was complete overhaul of some of
the regulations that affect us at the
local level through zoning and planning
Backstairs cities and municipalities off
for this because I got how do I do
something then I've got the attention
that I've got a reformat I've got to go
somewhere with it and we face those
problems as well too so I think it's
important for you to know that that
stabilization of regulation and when
this industry gets that point is
critical to its success and the ability
for it to operate everywhere in the
state of Washington so we started with
we looked at the state line we looked up
the state you know when he started
applying for licenses and we saw like I
think it was 49 business and then like
our license in the city of our may 10 so
we kind of freaked out at at that point
you know give you kind of beta test this
we've got a gas form you know our necks
right so think we know where it's gonna
go but we might be overwhelmed hey you
know we we set our first set of
regulations under the guideline at the
first tier 1 tier 2 tier 3 canopy spice
you know all that structure that came
into place and so because we were trying
to build a man in that
let me explain that initiative which on
cannabis industry clearly understands
now we want to provide parents housing
and job growth in the community and when
I say job growth I mean family wage jobs
our fullest $18 an hour or more and we
want people to live and work in the
community because that's what makes a
healthier community when families aren't
spending 6 to 7 hours community and
their home and they can take the kids to
baseball games or they can participate
in school activities the family
structure is better the neighborhoods
then grow for that the school system
most of math and that's a real
fundamental issue to healthy communities
so when we look at what the job
structure was my story we have to cut it
short anyway important answer minutes
left so I'm going to speed it up here a
little bit so after figuring out that we
have to figure out all these 49 license
and 2 licenses out there where we would
start and how they feel enough time to
pay attention to our data dashboard and
know where we were going with it we did
put some limitations on the first year
we said it early will allow I believe
was twelve or fourteen looser processors
to come in we have
where they will go and what kind of
study down we go forward a couple of
years after you know I think ten of them
had been in operation for at least 12
months we sent our third a the dashboard
and all the propaganda literature it
wasn't true
it wasn't our experience we had zero
public safety calls on cannabis
operation I mean zero not one not even
somebody you know with the NS fault the
heart attack Department nothing we had
absolutely nothing so someone that was
pretty profound the only issues that we
didn't have and they were really
relatively small was others of similar
issues you know it was smell our
community wasn't used to that we decided
okay you know you something area to do
you think a whole nother tacked on that
but maybe we could short some of our
local regulations about carbon scrubbers
and things where we knew that producer
processors would be closer to
neighborhood level
it's really now selected officials only
want us to distant want problems we want
to dispel the propaganda we want to try
to find a way for this to work in the
community one of the most effective
things that we did in Arlington was some
of the research that we have done and
event meeting with people who were
Deducer processes some of the first ones
in our community so they had a
relationship with our Planning
Commission which became a relationship
where their senior management and then
he came relationship eventually with our
elected people once we have it doesn't
produce the processes in our community
we really wanted to tell them this is so
exciting this is a brand new emerging
industry rarely we get to watch brand
emerging industry develop from birth to
maturation we don't get that opportunity
here adopted and we see shared economy
like uber and lyft but their take off
some other industries this is all brand
new and it's
citing but there's an opportunity and a
need for the industry to self-regulate
in this because if you don't
self-regulate government officials who
know nothing will regulate it and that
happens everywhere so we asked our
producer processors to form a coalition
is called the ACCC that I'll need to
cannabis coalition share of our
coalition mr. today Sean thank you
because we don't know what we disapprove
some of the propaganda the rest were
still mentioning data on but we need to
understand the city and we need you to
understand how to integrate into the
city we need you to understand what our
priorities are and you need to help us
understand as a business when we think
those priorities so they want the
coalition maybe every month through this
we've brought in people to speak on the
legislature to state legislators local
law enforcement has completely change
their mind on the cannabis industry
probably not going to tell you or their
kids they're a fan of it
but there are no longer against it there
are no longer the arch enemy to the
legal cannabis so they look at it so
those global relationships if you are AC
problems in your jurisdictions if you
get things that keep coming at you you
don't know where it's coming from really
only one you here today
take a step to talk to the people who
run your jurisdictions and listen to
them I know what the priorities are and
help them figure out a way to show that
you're helping meet those priorities of
the community
[Applause]
all right normally I don't ask questions
you do but I'm gonna in this case of an
ask Aaron asked a favor of you or D and
for the son I facilitate a lot of things
and people talk about stuff they don't
talk about three steps they take
something better they have interesting
conversations can you give this audience
a couple concrete steps that they can
take in their life officer I wouldn't
think would be like be having targeted
astronaut training system of programs
showing people how to do it like what
the step said she had to go to the heart
was that she have an entrepreneurial
training classes showing me to the
especially people who want to gain but a
traumatized in-depth look this legal
system is not coming to eat you you're
not going to go jail
you're not going to be criminalized
here's what the steps you gotta give it
being intentional about have an
entrepreneur training class
another thing is policy
examinations like really their academic
policy for library located that we
really look at the policies and see what
it is that's keeping certain people out
and figure out ways to maneuver those
policies or influence those policies to
try to help get more and more inclusion
for people from capitalist family cannot
be involved I believe that the normal
model is probably the best model out
right now but as Dominic said that's
stealing the private the private sector
to come up with butter this was drinking
privacy the government involved so
having us try to solve that what do you
find me yes you don't know what they
might do the next day essentially to
prove that I'm not against this session
said a lot of people are I think that we
didn't create because not what's going
to make people addressed with this thing
is for the first time I think some other
things are already being an absolutely
to set don't take an inert stance for it
a definitive stance world in the state a
licensed event we've given a lot of my
progressive racism in this thing and
nobody wants to customize this is one of
the most precious things
w12 is scared of all the people around
you accountable for their words and
their actions check them on there's
things like the best races that's wrong
we have to be inclusive in situations
don't be no second timid attendance
stand sign with a Spanish nominee single
at the moment we can't continue this
education program and man please please
your local education program because of
the clear ahead of me because of how the
LCB set up where this tax cut both our
education systems are not being funded
so those impoverished Netherlands are we
meeting Hammer hammer Hammer hammer and
everybody has some kind of sport
recreation whatever the 3t whatever it
is one of the three licenses in an
improper typically be intentional cars
an educational program we're either
scores your throws wherever you're
manufacturing is located to be very
vigilant about being involved with
educational programs okay
don't see a mr. Clark yeah so I'm gonna
let me ask me
this is for you I remember correctly he
told me a quick story about how one of
the stores in town was then invited into
the Business Association yeah for
blessed community have in Ireland
because I think sometimes we're really
are open-minded but one of the things
we're looking at has new industry coming
in is you know in every every other
business in the towns and counties where
you operate at some sort of Association
and Chamber of Commerce a Business
Association these are really valuable
and fundamental pieces in the business
culture is they allow access to
expertise and problem-solving and
sharing of ideas that I didn't see
happening with the cannabis culture
everything it was very closed model it
was a very uncertain model it didn't
know what it was facing in the
marketplace as the cognoscenti and no
idea what a customer base would be what
supply and demand would look like there
were a lot of pressures so when our
committee we sent out to invite a couple
of the newer
into the largest service groups into the
chamber to give presentations I also say
something that really impacted and
changed other people's minds was the
manufacturers are willing to do towards
so they were willing to that
visualization from reefer madness to a
manufacturing sophisticated industry was
priceless in that and now the chemist
coalition is viewed as one of the end
kind of industries in army - they
participate rotary they work with me on
fundraising for the appropriate causes I
mean everybody out there thinks that
you're making a million dollars a month
[Music]
we don't understand your business model
they don't understand the regulations of
the taxations on your businesses you're
not making a million dollars of your
expenses - your income is incredibly
onboard but there's a lot of stories not
told but integrating sorry integrating
into the normal business culture in the
community can go a long way to what I
think every every panel up here to talk
about today which is educating people
about the truth in the industry
first question Todd you mentioned you
would share your work to the LCB
happiness but did you share your report
on store path or your your thoughts or
which share the best ones sort out and
then a follow-up to that if you don't
mind if you can provide your thoughts on
how to expand access without that moving
the market share of pre-existing rescale
licenses there I talked to the LCB a few
different times and in the first
instance that was like at the end and
then another instance it was at the 502
occurrence you know I think that they I
think they daughter made at my head so
whether I said
which I again I'm a freak I know I'm for
the free market for save I was I was
pressing them to let the market expand
as it should better tuck away commerce
to the market can come and Weaver's lead
us they caught business to to guide the
retail system I hire I place the idea of
online with entering into a medical
perspective though if you look at like
how many how many lists can you buy
aspirin not say that the retail
establishments should be commuted that
much but there's obviously a demand for
medical products that my hands I should
be more accessible than one of the three
stores and I recently did a book at how
how far anyone to stay hadn't tried to
get to a you know how many do you want
campus exceptions I'm gonna publish that
data yet but I will put that outside
working with the temporary steam but I
think that the market in my mind's eye
should be a lot different I think it is
a lot bigger than we're seeing and
there's a lot of smoke in theirs
I apologize
where are the cattle stores and you you
specifically said that cab is in other
words yes you know how do we adjust from
here we already have licensees go me you
know we have the other issues but we
need access what you know in my in my
mind it should be based it should just
be population based and it seems to me
that was quite simple that you look at
you just have that some proxy of what
the demand looks like do you do it like
how many bars there are what I mean you
know that
really but medical then it's like you
know how many stores you have becomes a
whole other thing so I you know we had a
bunch of the Bible to bow texts that he
came out there were four hundred seventy
something medical establishments paying
taxes to the department how they study
got out and said 333 I don't know
[Laughter]
right now therefore disperses sort of
violent
that's like Kennedy's face or something
I would say so number of years ago
Business Association we're trying to
figure out how much a business title
could exist in a population base what
they came up with is a very broad
unscientific her but basically they
would take the population base and say
okay six to make eight percent of that
number is how many shoppers did not find
anybody but that's what they were using
to say we have a membership in this area
we can support about the people
fire thank you so much for sharing I
really admire you and I love your
intellectual curiosity job-seeking
Steven I have print in which length to
this question which is which is true so
city management has been a very kind of
audible approach to embrace this
industry who has proven itself to you
how you treated me employees youth drug
test mix with marijuana or or you still
look here me too
excluding anyone the puffs for marijuana
from employment identity that's great
question thank you we we do still have a
no tolerance
and it probably will be there for a
while until the industry is more
accepted and normalized into the state
of Washington okay next question
thank you I just have a question for
anyone wants to answer truths and
reconciliation commissions was we're
done in our South Africa and I saw Aaron
went to South Africa under the title so
that was a solution the government had
to deal with long-standing structural
violence was lost between blacks and
whites in Africa okay and so I'm
wondering if maybe States government's
local places to do such things get
Longworth when people affect community
members to have listening sessions of
Truth and Reconciliation to kind of call
this process of a long-standing Soviet
trauma that we've lived under that
doesn't get voiced as much and the
employment drug-testing has a lot to do
with insurance the insurance of directly
workplace acting and workplace insurance
and so those a lot of you can change so
that you don't have to have drug testing
policy to get where they sit exactly
thank you reconciliation mr. Clark legal
representation to happen under this is
not there but I think we're going to
conversation Aaron just expungement
criminal records state of California
actually has a process for that
why does they actually have a bill to do
it but enthusiasm that guy
fifteen apparently the lobbyists without
terribly you know motivated to pursue
that okay apparently threat that's one
one thing you could do industry is
attach criminal records bump into your
next legislative burning list say today
were expunged eternal records right here
and now have a bigger effect than just
your blue American industry physical
wreck but you can employ other places
right through the reconciliation
condition it sounds that on papers were
all that was was a way for white into
Galloway that get used for killing five
minutes it right exactly and bits of
black families yes I killed this person
this is why I did it doesn't work on the
body and they would never have a counter
okay this looks like your last question
primarily a tote and with respect to the
notion of access to the product
I've been forecasting and estimating
size and services started and I kinda
had the verge of midway through last
year that was independent of the SSP
would be a physical invasion and it
struck me that it appeared as a
significant number of consumers that
have been using the regulated system
were beginning to go else
I don't know stop using or whatever but
when you look at the trends actually
across time and standardized it against
the population characteristics of the
local parents it's very clear that
something happened about midway through
the last year before that just started
in bad great now I think this market is
underperforming by about 20% of the new
basis transactional basis largely driven
by the lack of retail access even though
there's by the business licenses
allocated there were fewer than 400
stores that sold more than a thousand
dollars hospital every year and just
blows my mind and fewer than half of
those have a medical certification in
market laws so from the government's
perspective the governors of the
spectrum if revenue is important to this
state particularly as our reduction
strategy if you're shipping a
recreational and we're either used to
this product why is it acceptable that
an agency of the government can use crap
science which is demonstrably just
ridiculous also controller to slap won
something that basically is this is
something that historically used to
regulate so that's how many cannabis
norms we found out that they were
staffed without to increase the revenue
and at the same time while forcing
medical patients and medical providers
to either go into the regulated system
or decriminalize themselves and then to
basically shop spin through regulation
and
computer legislation of instances so
that fewer than 5% of the producers have
produced better products less than 1% of
the product sold was meant for the last
year that's a sales tax and and a fewer
than maybe 1/5 of the access points we
have the degree in cross area are earned
they will serve patients as patients
that is a broken system in my opinion we
make our money serve these do you think
the governor might be interested I think
I think Jay is interested in the
marketplace whether he's down at this
fundamental level or the micro level of
this John's right I don't know because
as I've said before actually not here
but the the entire amount of revenue to
the state is dust and this industry is
very small so do they care that they
care only as much as the money
right aerospace really care tech they
care no the reality is that when they
started releasing the licenses I joking
was dimmable cambogia said well in 11
years I'll actually get to the 233
licenses well they still aren't there
but now we have he get to 530 whatever
any yeah it's a really weird you know I
don't understand what they're doing with
that but I will say that it was when
Portland well Tory you know made it
illegal to grow at home I got on the
phone with some producers I don't know
if anybody I just call it random sort of
the guys that were a thank you I said
hey what's going on and a couple of my
wives lost 50% of my business back like
week and so recently I was having
Portland one of the guys let slip a
Matthews and I just kind of ate for 17
bucks and it's some of the best I've
ever had and I said okay cool he goes
that would have been 56 bucks in Seattle
where is John
so what nobody's bringing it back and
forth
I think I mean my own personal gain take
away whatever my affiliation I think
what happened to the medical industry is
totally unethical and immoral