hey there so last weekend I was in
Denver for Indo Expo and I was
moderating a panel of soil science PhDs
and and will drink Q&amp;A I asked them so
hey what are your thoughts on 24 hour
light cycle during veg of cannabis
because you know there's a lot of people
who argue a lot of different ways online
about whether or not you have to give
cannabis plans some dark times so that
they can have a natural sleep cycle or
whether or not you can run your plants
at 24 hours of light and get finished
with your veg cycle 20% faster right
over the course of the year you can
actually put in another cycle in your
garden so there's a big advantage to
that if it is possible so anyway I was
curious what they would have to say so I
asked the question and dr. Karuna Chow
ray who's in R&amp;D at mammoth microbes
said something that was surprising to me
you know normally everybody talks about
the health of the plant itself about
whether or not it can do 24 hours a day
of photosynthesis and be healthy but she
approached it totally different she's
like yeah the plant grows up faster and
bulkier but what you're doing is you are
starving the rhizosphere you're starving
all the microbes in the soil which makes
the plants super susceptible for all
these different kinds of diseases that's
a whole different approach so after the
panel I asked her to step aside with me
and get on camera and and the answer the
question so that I could bring it home
to you so that you could check it out so
this is dr. Chow Ray's answer if you are
into 24 hour lights or if you just like
thinking about photosynthesis I hope you
totally dig this
everybody so I am here at Indo Expo
Denver today and I just heard a
fantastic presentation on microbes and
rhizosphere and and my guest today
caught me off guard by saying something
that kind of blew my mind about the 24
hour light cycle as you may know there's
a lot of fervent debate online about
whether or not you can grow cannabis
plants in the vegetative state for 24
hours a day lit the entire time so
having no dark period and there's a lot
of debate back and forth but but often
there is not a lot of evidence and then
I mean Karuna today and she has got some
very interesting things today about
metabolites so Karuna thank you so much
for joining me for a moment
hearing you speak today caught me
totally off guard and I was excited to
hear essentially for me
new information in this debate people
are having about the 24 hour light cycle
so please if you would teach us all your
thoughts on whether or not using light
on for 24 hours is helping or inhibiting
growing cannabis plants asking this very
important question
well plants are like humans or any other
living beings we have they face a night
phase
they also behave differently in day and
night in the daytime they have the
sunlight where they are going to use
everything do you know synthesize sugars
food so to say and the plant is growing
at the same time the plant is also
putting down sugars through its roots to
the microbes in the soil right so then
it's also communicating with the
microbes at nighttime all these
activities will shut down and that kind
of metabolites so when I say sugars
there are different sugars there are
different metabolites that are released
by the plant roots and they actually
feed the microbes that they love so the
friendly microbes are the microbes that
will help the plant grow they are the
ones that are dependent on this plant
food now if you keep the plant in only
one cycle then you are depriving the
microbial population of one category of
food so while the plants are growing
tall they're growing in biomass it's not
exactly healthy for the entire plant and
it's rhizosphere that is one reason that
you give it a break so let the plant
flip the cycle and make the different
set of metabolites or not constantly
keep feeling the same metabolite - it's
rhizosphere microbes where the microbes
might be like
really overwhelmed with all these
metabolites being thrown at it in 24
hours so even though microbes in the
rhizosphere follow this kind of diagonal
cycle they are not used to seeing this
metabolize constantly constantly and
that is one reason I think that you
definitely have to give the plants a
break so so to make sure that I
understand you correctly when the lights
are on the plant is producing its sugars
and photosynthesis and everything that
it normally does for itself but when the
light goes off it pushes all the sugars
out to the rhizosphere and your
beneficial microbes and so if we're
running our lights for 24 hours we are
potentially starving our beneficial
microbes that are in the substrate and
and so in addition to so so so the first
thing that wouldn't be bad for the
cannabis plant would be we're starving
the beneficial microbes which then makes
the plant itself less robust because
it's got less microbes in the
rhizosphere what else is there anything
else that might happen to the plant
itself by not getting a break like like
like when we don't get a rest we get a
little delirious right right so the
plant is always in the mode that it has
to grow grow grow right might and gives
it a time to kind of rest relax a little
bit but now when you are just keeping it
on a 24 cycle the only thing it here
says keep growing 3
keep doing photosynthesis keep growing
pig and so in a way this is not natural
so I think the plants are going to be
stressed in that format so give your
plants a break don't keep them on a 24
hour cycle so that so technically that
that stress could express itself in a
lot of ways maybe decrease cannabinoids
or less resistance to lolled or pass or
however it chooses to express its life
cycle might be doing it very much indoor
grows but they have almost like sterile
environment they can keep it closed and
that's when they think that giving it 24
hour life cycle is giving them plants
which they think are better plants but
that plant is just kind of safe propped
up a little bit so they're susceptible
to a wide range of things so so if the
24 like our light cycle is is setting up
the plant for potential failure right
the reason people do it is because you
can reach the end of the bloom cycle
about 20% faster right so for people who
are trying to do a certain number of
cycles a year for profit right yeah
they're saying we're just going to push
the plant to its extreme so that we can
save that 20% of time exactly how would
you weigh that yourself and the
advantages to saving 20% versus the the
susceptibility of the plant to pathogens
so let me put it this way
can save on the time and you can get
more butts or more flowering cycles but
what is the quality of your buds are you
sacrificing your terpene profile are you
sacrificing your cannabinoid profile
just to gain that 20% extra time is it
worth it so you have to keep that in
mind also to maintain this 24 hour life
cycle like I said you have to have
practically a staggering room everything
has to be so dialed in that you cannot
change little bit otherwise your plant
is going to just die or not perform as
good so you are creating so many
restrictive scenarios for growth whereas
under a normal cycle you are not your
plant is healthy enough that it can
withstand little bit of fluctuation that
is what you want and you can keep your
cannabinoid profile steady I have heard
very little about how the but quality is
if you are bringing it down to this very
short cycle I have not yet seen that
date database like I said data is the
first thing I will look for oh this is
how it works show me right show me the
evidence and so far
so as far as the data because in your
presentation you were very clear that
data is everything would you share with
us some of the research that has been
done on this and we can put it in the
links below so that people can check it
out at home sure sure if I find
something on cannabis definitely if not
definitely on other plants I just find
out all those links on what effect is 24
hour photo period thank you so much
corona check it out thank you