hi welcome my name is Tyler marquart and
I am here today via Shango lots and
shaping fire and we're going to show you
how to make bubble hash using a washing
machine uh kind of more on a way of
entry level or in a position in which
maybe you don't have access to every
single tool that these multi-million
dollar facilities have that you may see
on Instagram we think this is an
important way to help people kind of get
into the industry get into the
hashmaking and just making hash for
yourself as a medical patient or just a
home grower there's a lot of different
tools out there and ways to make hash
you can make it by hand you can make it
by using the machine and this way is
going to try to show you an efficient
way to bring that home and and we'll be
able to have really high quality hash at
your disposal
So today we're going to be talking about
the different types of tools we use
we're going to be talking about the
different types of material all the
steps that go into the production of
this hash using this machine this is a
20 gallon washing machine this is an
older model that I gifted Shango years
ago we've been using it every year for
probably the last five years to make
hash and you've seen other videos with
the material that's come out and so this
is a great machine they're they're
already in the last they handle up to
about 900 grams you could probably put
about thousand grams of material in
there and they would still put out a
high quality product
but nonetheless you can get these for
used for a couple hundred dollars off of
Craigslist you can get them new offline
for a few hundred dollars as well uh
probably up to 500 bucks with shipping
and whatnot
um you know as of the these days here
the prices change pretty quickly but
um 20 gallon machines are great to go
with if you if you're running uh some
bigger outdoor plants uh if you have uh
you know more than a couple thousand
grams of material and you want to get
through it in a couple days this is a
great way to do it if you don't produce
that much material all at once and
you're getting it over time there are
also five gallon machines that are
available too they're smaller they work
just as well they're efficient and they
get you a good material uh to start with
to get your medicine you also can do
hand washing too uh by using a power
drill or just a spatula and pushing the
material around with your hand a lot of
people actually will get into this later
prefer that method because it gives you
all uh what you would consider a much
higher quality product because there's
less agitation and you're getting the
the most ripe trichomes off the head of
the uh the plant material but if you're
trying to get the most quality highest
quality and the most material at once
the the machine is the best option to uh
to go to
another tool that's super important that
you need is going to be a garbage can
um
some people will say Okay garbage cans
are not the ideal you need to use food
grade yes ideally using food grade
everything would be the optimal thing to
do but again not everybody has access to
food grade quality materials and they
still want to try to make hash and is
this going to give you a tainted product
uh probably not you know over time it
may degrade and leech but if you're
running the first few times and whatnot
it's not going to we've been doing it
for years and we're still running
marathons so again
you always want to try to lean towards
the best practices and and refine your
Technique as you go along using better
tools but if you're in a position in a
limited budget uh you're on uh you know
you're if you're a medical patient like
myself you may not have a ton of money
to invest all at once and thousands of
dollars of equipment this is this is a
great option and way to go to get where
you need to start
um so the the garbage can is an option
you can work your way up to food grade
tubs and um and stainless steel is also
another great option as well too again
stainless steel is expensive but you can
go to
restaurant stores use restaurant stores
and and find equipment there as well too
for sale
um we're gonna need a Dull Knife uh or a
straight blade anything that has uh you
know a couple inches that you can use to
scrape a material off with this is a
ceramic blade not very sharp which is
great you don't want to cut the thing I
often like to use two so that when I do
scrape I can scrape off using that and
then also sometimes a large spoon is a
great option to help scoop out and or
shave off any of the stuff that you got
on your your knives
a pizza box is also going to be helpful
if you can access that or cardboard
pizza boxes are really easy to use
because they're convenient they have a
lid it keeps material out from getting
in
and the cardboard itself will help
absorb some of the water that is left
over in the bubble hash as it's drying
also I like to slip a little piece of
parchment paper in there you can label
it with the different screen sizes and
separate your your poles or your runs
according to the size of the
uh Micron of the screen and that helps
you kind of organize it to find out
which section maybe is the best for you
works the best for your application of
what you're looking to do these are
obviously readily available found at
your local pizza place uh you might have
to pay a couple bucks to grab them but
you can use them and they're easy to get
a hold of but like I said parchment
paper I like to use the unbleached brown
stuff
seems to work really well haven't had
any issues one of the other things that
we use is a frisbee you're probably
gonna look into a frisbee or a garbage
Clan lid depending on the size of the
material you're using so this is
something like this 20 gallon garbage
lid will help as well too if you're
using larger bags
um a pancake spatula so if you've ever
seen a pancake spatula before we don't
have one right now but basically it is a
spatula that has some holes in it and
that will help push material around or
flatten down material when you're
pushing it first putting it into the
machine
and then of course there's the Buckner
funnel and the freeze dryer so the
Buckner funnel you can go on a shaping
fire we have another video that uh the
we have two other videos that talk about
and walk through that use of that
technology and uh if you could afford
one freeze dryers are also a wonderful
option but again that's a multi-thousand
dollar investment and they also have a
tendency to malfunction
so and there's no real Insurance
programs on those so again this is kind
of approach to what hashmaking in a way
of basic uh utility and tools that you
may be able to find readily available in
any grocery store or any uh hardware
store near you
um
but maybe not the most like advanced
technology there are probably a ton of
other videos out there that can talk to
you about that but this is just going to
help you get started and get going and
get your get you processing your
material at home so that you can have
really high quality hash that you know
goes from Farm to Table
um or in our case Farm to bowl uh so uh
first of all we need to procure a set of
bags these bags were donated to us by
our friends over at the Press Club
um they do a wonderful job with all
different types of accessories or bags
and rosin so if you if you need anything
please go ahead and check out their
website which is the Press Club Press
Club dot Co again that's
thepressclub.com and you can find these
bags they are called The Press Club wash
bags they come in a variety of different
sizes and they come in a variety of
different
um amounts so you can buy one bag you
can buy a eight bags set and you can buy
I believe a three bag set as well too
um and so each bag has its own Micron
size starts at 220 and it goes down to
45.
um there's def other increments in the
in the middle too and those basically
separate the size of the trichome head
that the plant produces so when the
plant grows it produces trichomes they
don't all develop at the same time they
develop at different rates and so you
may have different size trichome heads
and they also are multiple different
types of trichomes so other trichomes
have smaller heads that will be removed
you have glandular trichomes Cecile
trichomes and sisal with tricon so we
want to avoid collecting cystolith
trichomes but we want the glandular
trichomes they're mostly what we're
trying to procure
so those bags are the essential part of
the component to what you're looking for
to make bubble hash the as of today are
shooting the video the eight bag set on
the Press Club site is uh 299 dollars so
uh a washing machine right let's say
roughly cost three or five hundred
dollars they're looking at 299 dollars
for that you're a few hundred dollars
investment already into this you want to
make sure that um
you you know you can utilize these tools
to the best uh
um best technology that you can
[Music]
um
so preferred material you use
we're going to start you could either do
fresh frozen or you could do dry
material fresh frozen is when you chop
the plant down at Harvest and you
immediately put it into a freezer and
you let that material freeze and then
you take it and you put it into the
machine and you start washing it it's a
really great way to capture mono
terpenes and other volatile organic
compounds that would evaporate or at
room temperature and you may not have in
a long term
Some people prefer this method uh
because of the quality of the end
product the end quality of them product
also has a different color it usually is
a little lighter in color and
um has a slightly different consistency
as well too
with dried material that's cured that
material will have a different flavor
profile it will also have a different
color to the end material it'll be
slightly darker as well too because the
trichomes develop over time and they
convert as well as the terpenes will
change over time Frenchy canole talks a
lot about this and I urge you to go out
there and look into the videos that he
has as well too because he's spoken a
lot about this uh recipes for entry we
uh we very much appreciate your
contributions to the uh the hash
community
um
so when you have dry material you're
going to be looking at somewhere maybe
between 10 to 15 percent return on your
um
your Harvest from the hash this is
dependent on the quality of the material
you use so the higher the quality of
material the better the hash that's
going to come out it's also important to
know that not every single plant washes
or runs through the machine and provides
an end quality product really well some
do much better than others I wrote an
article called breeding deceive on the
pressco website on their blog and it
really kind of gets more in depth into
what makes a good hash plan we've found
that some plants just really wash better
over and over and again they hold their
quality over longer than other plants
and you know it just has to be something
that you you do over time the more you
practice the better you're going to find
the nuances of this plant washes really
well because of this characteristic or
this plant doesn't wash so well because
it gets too sticky and the resin sticks
to the bag and you can't get it off so
there a lot of practices involved it's
like anything you want to get good at
anything you got to practice it and do
it over and over again so the same thing
goes with making hash the more practice
you have the more errors you'll make the
more you'll learn from those errors and
the more successes you'll have the more
you learn from those successes you'll
combine those two informations and
you'll be able to move on and really
make the best quality product you can
for yourself
so there also is this other way to
really kind of know before because you
don't want to maybe take your whole crop
and say let's wash it and you really get
a poor return you can do What's called
the jar Tech this is a simple method
where you take a mason jar fill it with
ice and water take about 10 grams of
flour at Harvest put it in there cap it
give it a good shake and wait a couple
seconds like shake it for 30 seconds
shake it for a minute and then let the
trichome heads fall to the bottom you'll
see the collection at the bottom and
again this is something that you'll have
to do over and over and over again to to
gauge what is good and what is average
and what is below average
having the jar Tech really helps you
analyze what the plant is able to do and
give you when you have uh when you're
looking to procure a hash plant so the
jar Tech is a great option to really
kind of field test what you're doing
before you invest your whole crop into
washing and dumping it into a situation
where it just didn't return because it
just wasn't that type of plant or it was
it didn't come out the way you wanted to
do that time
um so definitely check into that
trichome development is super important
when you're looking to process material
you're really going to want to look into
the get what's called a loop or a
magnifying glass or something that can
let you look at the trichome head up
close and really see it over time if you
track during the last few weeks of your
plants growth and you watch those
tri-cat trichome heads expand they'll
get to a point where they'll stop
expanding and that's pretty much when
they're ready to that that's when the
the plant is pretty much ready to
harvest is when that bulbous head is at
its fullest potential you don't want to
go too far you want it that it's like
the top of the bell curve and a couple
people talk about this Frenchie can only
talked about this Swami talks about this
and this is when you shake a plant you
can smell it or when you walk past it
it's very vibrant in its smell and
that's because the trichome heads are
ripe and they're falling off and they're
opening and releasing the terpenes that
you can smell and the other volatile
organic compounds
so learning these techniques when you're
harvesting learning these techniques
when you're processing learning these
techniques when you go to wash all
really help to add up to an end quality
product that really just gives you
better material at the end again
practice practice practice
research practice and then you'll make
your applications and you'll refine them
and you'll end up really really really
enthused with what's what's happening at
the at the back end of the process
um
a lot of the a lot of the Harvest timing
and a lot of the processing is also very
individual to the person what I prefer
and what Shango likes and uh what other
people like is completely different I
might like something very lethargic and
so I like to let my plants go a little
bit longer Shango might like something
that's very uplifting and energetic so
he might like to harvest his plants a
little bit early or right in the middle
at the the high peak of moderation so
learning your plant is really important
and learning when you like to harvest
your plants is really important now
there are obviously conditions when you
have to chop and drop because of
environmental conditions law enforcement
whatever the reason being you may have
to adjust what you like to do to the
conditions around you but in general if
you're repeating the process every year
and you're you're only growing a few
plants at Home under your medical
license or under the legal state law us
then you can refine your process and
learn or you can acquire material from
other people and process that material
so learning your Harvest times learning
your plants learning what plants wash
really well all really help you advance
faster through the whole process
um
storing that material is also important
so the more you touch the more you
process the more it moves around the
more it bangs around it's going to bang
up the the plant material and it may
knock off the trichome head it may break
it open and open those volatile organic
compounds in the and the cannabinoids
into
um
uh into the onto the leaf surface so
they won't be able to be acquired
because when we wash and we sieve we're
trying to collect the trichome head as
an individual head and then collect a
lot of them and make sure that there
isn't any plant material or any any
other material that is left
so once we have all those things dialed
in and of course you know it takes time
to to practice this you're going to have
to go through some harvests and you're
going to have to figure out what you're
going to you know what works for you but
once you get all that down it's really
going to become more of like tying your
shoes and a walk-through process of
getting getting that end product so
starting out now with using the machine
we've already pre-loaded this machine
um because it's just easier so what you
would normally do is you would come in
you put a layer of ice at the bottom
cover it up
this machine can handle up to a thousand
grams of material you can use less
material just add less water and so if
you only have let's say 300 grams of
material you're going to use a little
bit less than half the machine so here
we don't have as much material today we
don't have a thousand grams that we're
gonna be putting into this machine so
we're using less water you can see the
the water
condensating on the outside here and not
up here so our water level stops here
with the ice and the water and
um
but we start here with the ice at the
bottom so you start with the ice layer
at the bottom that goes in and then you
layer your cannabis on the top of that
and then you layer another ice layer on
top of that as well too
now you don't have to do it this way you
can just put the ice in there you can
put the material in there and you can
just add water and and you can do it
that way but this kind of helps keep the
the ice on the top will help keep the
material down and help rehydrate it
while you're adding your water so that
it kind of moves through the machine a
lot easier and flows and the trichome
heads break off with the water
application as opposed to breaking off
of a mechanical operation from the ice
so there are different types of ice
cubes that you can use of course you
need to find what's readily available
for you if you have the space at home to
make your own ice you and you have
filter filters to filter your water to
do that it's really that's you know
great you can save a lot of money by
making your own ice and setting up and
you can quality control that aspect of
the the input one of the really
important things to remember when you
start using the ice in the water is you
want to make sure it's filtered you
don't want to use any water that is out
of the tap that you haven't tested
because there's heavy metals there can
be sulfur for instance on the island
here there's a lot of sulfur in the
water so we're unable to use that tap
water because it leaves a sulfur taste
in the end product and we want to try to
avoid that so ideally I'm using
distilled water or Ro filtered water or
even just regular filtered water I mean
if you wanted to you could use a British
there but you're gonna have to
do a lot of Brita filtering into other
containers to get the amount of water
that you need to do the wash but water
quality is super important ice water
quality is really important so when you
start making your ice the quality of the
water
going into that is super important you
always want to use distilled or RO water
if you can if you have access to it if
you don't get your well water tested and
see where it's at you know if it's not
high in Mineral content it's not high in
Sulfur or anything that has a distinct
smell or taste to it when you drink it
then go ahead and use it try and do a
couple runs and see what the hash comes
out like if it comes out okay then then
you know it's good if it doesn't then
you got to stick with procuring
distilled water or RO water
um so now that you have the ice in your
water your ice is layered your cannabis
is layered your ice is layered on top
you can add your water that water is
going to fill all the way up to the top
of the ice there and you're going to let
that material sit
um in this for probably anywhere between
15 to 30 minutes again that's dependent
on the the material how dry it is going
in if it's fresh frozen obviously it
doesn't need to sit in the water for 30
minutes because it's already full of
water and it's frozen and cold
so you can avoid that but for the most
times you're going to want to let the
plant sit and and
soak in the machine for roughly about 30
minutes
some people like to freeze the material
ahead of time that's awesome if you have
freezer space to do that it's not uh
imperative it does help the trichome
heads break off and it slow makes the
process of rehydrating and keeping it
cold faster
um
but it doesn't have to be done you can
just use room temperature flour it's
totally fine
um now the run time is also something
that is dependent on what you want to do
the plant material itself and how much
time you have
um you can run the plant the machine for
up to 10 minutes and just thrash
everything around and try and get
everything in one bout but we found that
if you run it in lesser increments you
can pull higher quality material out of
it
at a better rate so the most ripe
trichomes are going to fall off around
the first few times that you're doing
your first wash and the second wash so
the first wash you may may only want to
run for one minute or 30 seconds or
three minutes that's up to you it's
something that you need to to decide
what you want to do if you want the
super most ripe trichromes run it for a
minute see what comes out
running your second wash for three
minutes see what comes out and then
adapt from there and go on and try to
make your uh your Corrections that way
if you're looking for just getting more
food grade quality where you're you're
not smoking it and it's not super
important that it's very clean and uh
unadulterated with plant material then
go ahead and just run a longer wash on
your first few runs and try to get as
much material out of it as you can
again practice right find what works for
you in the situation that you're doing
for the thing that you want to do so
once you've acquired your bags uh to
wash with you're going to have your
garbage can here and you're gonna need
to layer them into the can
you're going to start with the lowest
bag the number 45 then you're going to
go up to your 73 then your 90
then you're going to go to your 120 160
uh
190 220 again however many bags you buy
is depending on how much you can afford
and what you want to run and then you
also find out which bags you want to use
over time
different bags will pull different
trichome heads and different plants
produce different size trichome heads so
again it's a practice kind of thing and
you'll have to go through a bunch of
different material to find out but once
you get your bags you're going to take
them like I said put the lowest number
at the bottom put that bag in first put
it around you'll have these little tie
things to come in here and cinch it in
and that will help keep it taut to the
the can when you run the water so it
doesn't pull the bag into the
um the whole can that would not be an
ideal situation
so here we take this put it in
also before you put your bags in here
you're going to want to pre-wash them go
ahead and just take a hose you can use
regular water for this it's not a huge
deal but just go ahead wash them out you
may want to kind of fold them up a
little bit put them in some water wash
them sometimes for manufacturing they
come with a couple loose threads so you
may get some fibers that come off you
know it's not a big deal get in there
wash them give them a little pre-wash go
ahead let them dry out and then go ahead
and put them in uh stacked with 45 at
the bottom some folks will use the 25
bag I'm not a big fan of the 25 bag
personally it's some it just it's not
worth it the material is not there it
doesn't it's not
my personal opinion is not worth it but
if you want to go ahead and use that low
of a bag that's cool
um use it see what it how it works for
you but yeah 25 45
73 so they all cut and different
companies make different size bag
numbers
um one of the things that you also want
to remember too when you buy your bags
is to match the diameter of the bag to
the opening of the container that you're
using so this container is a 20 gallon
container because these are specific 20
gallon bags that the presco makes
Fresco also makes them in five gallons
10 gallons you got the 20s here and they
go up the 30s as well too 33s
um other companies like the Bubble Bags
they're gonna have uh uh their biggest
bag I think is a 20 33 bag which works
in a 33 gallon container and for both 20
and 33 gallons size but the the Press
Club has made more specific bags for uh
different applications so again check
your bag size with the the website that
you order it from and check the size of
the container that you're using to make
sure they match not super inconvenient
to have to go out and buy another one
but you know it's an extra 25 bucks that
you don't have to spend so once you get
your bags here you're going to layer
them in I don't usually bring them under
the handle here because it stretches
them out you really don't want to
stretch or pull on the bags really hard
because it'll kind of move the they're
all in like a mesh form right so you
have squares tiny little squares
throughout the bag which is what is used
in the C evening process so if you
tighten and loosen it changes the
diameter of the the hole in the bag and
so you want to kind of keep it loose and
but you also don't want it to fall in
when the water comes out of the machine
and and fills the bag so again there's a
practice curve there that you need to
learn and once you get that curved down
it becomes substantially easier
so that's kind of the end here that we
have for the uh putting the bags in and
we'll get back to making a run on the
machine here all right we're back and uh
we're just going to run over a few
things here before we uh come to the end
I didn't mention sprayers before and
sprayers are important part of kind of
collecting the hash after you've pulled
the bag you definitely want to get a
good sprayer you can use a hand sprayer
that you would you know like a hand pump
sprayer that would um you would maybe
use to use it for cleaning agents or
something like that that does work it
it's it's you know if if you have
arthritis it's not the option you want
to use
if you struggle with a repetitive motion
it's not the option you want to use but
again if you if it's the only thing you
can find in your area for the time you
can totally do that even if you can't
find a sprayer you can use a one gallon
jug put your couple fingers over the
hole and kind of just pour and let it
run around and push all the material
down that's going to be the most basic
way to do it you can step up to like a
pesticide sprayer so you could go to
Home Depot or you could go to Lowe's or
any hardware store and look for like a
10 gallon pestic Sprite spread excuse me
a 10 gallon pesticide sprayer
um again you're not going to want to
contaminate it with pesticide you're not
going to want to use it for Korean
natural farming inputs or jadam or
anything else label it with the words
hashmaking only put a label maker
sticker on it draw a star on it whatever
it is you got to do but basically only
use that for hashmaking so that it's not
contaminated with any other inputs or
anything like that
um that hand pump sprayer that you can
get from Home Depot it's like a 10
gallon hand pump sprayer it comes with a
wand that's a good option to use for
home it's cheap it's probably about 25
30 bucks at most and it's going to do a
decent job at getting the trichomes that
are stuck to the side of the walls of
the bag down to the bottom a lot of
people in the who are doing commercial
production like to use sump pumps in a
an exterior 30 gallon garbage can
that is then run through a hose
and uh you just end up using one of
these and then you spray down into the
the container and that really pushes
down we unfortunately are unable to use
this at the location we're at today
because the water is higher and sulfur
coming out of the tap so it would
contaminate our hash and kind of give it
that sulfurated flavor so we try to
avoid that and we just don't have the
setup to run the pump here at this time
so again this is a video designed
specifically for entry-level uh people
or those people who are in areas where
you just don't have resources to the
things that would make the perfect setup
sometimes you just got to do what you
got to do to get through to figure it
out and that's how it is so make sure
you have a really good sprayer that's
super important to help collect all the
trichomes it really will just get you
the maximum yield and return from
everything and you'll be able to to be
more satisfied with your end results on
that for just a very low input cost
a purchase
so yeah so once you pull the bags out
you're going to scrape them you're going
to collect everything put it on the
parchment paper put it on a drying
screen or put it in a pizza box or on a
piece of cardboard anything that's going
to kind of let the water move out of it
and and go
away from the hash so that it could dry
quickly
so you don't particularly want to heat
the hash that's going to really cause
some degradation you're going to lose
some terpenes that may convert some of
the cannabinoids if you're heating it
over time but yeah so basically look
into
um
when you pull out everything uh get it
onto the parchment paper get it on the
drying screen get it in front of a fan
or put it into the Bookner funnel and
use that to help remove the water out of
it or you can go ahead if you do have
the funds to to get a hold of a vacuum
up or a freeze dryer the freeze dryer
will be the best option to help you
remove the water as fast as possible and
get you the highest quality product at
the end
um
so now that you've got the uh process
set up and you're either going to choose
your air dry your Buckner funnel air dry
which is another air drying technique or
the freeze dryer you're going to go into
storage once your hash is dry and you've
determined that it's ready to store
you're going to want to either put it
into a jar of some sort a glass jar with
a lid that can seal
and or put it into some cellophane tie
it up into a little ball and tighten it
basically you want to keep air and
moisture out and some folks will even
put in some of those
uh moisture transfer packs those will go
in there they work sometimes if you want
to use those as well I think they impart
a personally I think they impart a
flavor onto the the material when you
use them I avoid them but that doesn't
mean that other people don't like to use
them and they're not successful with
them they are in their eyes and that's
totally cool
all right so some final thoughts here on
the end of our day making hash
I just want to make sure that everybody
knows that this process is kind of a
golden gold out process and that means
using really high quality material will
yield you really high quality hash as
long as you do a good job receiving it
so so if you start with lower quality
material you're going to definitely end
up with a lower quality end product but
that's the whole goal is get better at
growing or get better at sourcing better
material and then you will also probably
get better at receiving hash over time
because it'll be easier your results
will be better and you'll feel better
about what you're actually doing so
that's really important and be patient
about what you're doing it is a long
monotonous process that you have to be
repetitive over and over again if you're
only growing once a year then maybe it
is only once a year outdoor material
that you're using you're only going to
be maybe making hash once or twice a
year then so if not if you're going
indoors you're going to have more
practice or if you have the ability to
grow Auto flowers Outdoors you can use
those to practice with too that will
just help refine your Technique to get
better for the full terms or the indoor
or whatever it is you're deciding to do
with your your production method also if
you're looking for more information
about how to do this because this is a
very casual visual video and
kind of just getting you the basics of
what's going on go on to social media
sites like Instagram or Facebook take a
look at people out there there's a bunch
of people obviously Frenchie cannoli
rest in peace Frenchie he was one of the
best housemakers in the world and he you
know has a ton of information on his
Instagram page his wife Madame cannoli
and his Apprentice cherry blossom Bell
are also putting on classes all over the
United States they were just did a class
in California and
um and so they're a great resource as
well too to pass on the tradition of
hashish making and Temple ball
production there's also other people
like jendo she's an amazing hashmaker
she's up in the Northeast and she is
will answer your questions and help you
get on the right Pathway to being better
hash resin Ranch in California is
another great person to take a look at
there's a variety of people out there
but also be respectful because gendo and
resin Ranch will just likely quickly
tell you to [__] off if you are being
very impolite or pushy remember these
people have thousands of people
following them and they can't get to
every single question every day but if
you're patient and you wait or if you go
through their Scrolls and watch go
through their posts and you go through
their timelines you can find the bits
and pieces of information that they they
give out for free and and you'll be able
to be more successful faster in your
production in your hashmaking so be
respectful be patient and have a good
time and as far as making all the hash
because that's the real end goal is to
enjoy what you're doing make a great
hash product and and then enjoy that
when you're when you're finished with it
so if you have any other questions throw
them down in the uh the comment section
there I'll do my best to jump on and
answer them when I can I appreciate you
hanging out with us here today with this
in a video get to help you get off the
ground and get started my name is Tyler
Marquardt and hope to see you smoke some
hash with you sometime soon cheers