thank you so much using technology and
tools to go into new levels of
expression this ancient relationship
ultimately in each one of these people
is this monstrous force of innovation
and it's an honor to get business
moderate this panel my name's Jeremy
mama I'm from Portland Oregon and the
director of production science at Perth
coal tomorrow
it's a high-tech controlled environment
facility and the working cannabis metal
like found in the dispensary called
Pharma co-founded Logan cannabis
projects and founded
with handles over a year so they feel
like a way I know how to quite say this
year things are really going to a new
level and and really I want to make sure
they've allocate any of time to hearing
where those levels are so I'd like to
start with a basic question analytical
reading implies that there is technology
facilitating outcomes in the genomic
space and then ultimately that results
in a key matific outcome what I would
like to talk about the first of these to
have them and introduce themselves and
then you into what is your experience
with using analytics and reading to
actually get into this space of creating
plants that are more useful my name is
Josh Porter I'm the president of SC labs
and based in Santa Cruz
I've been testing cannabis now for
almost 10 years I started on actually
working and ready shops Depot weren't
there for a year and I don't have
experience with reading I have
experience with analytical siphoning and
supporting breeders and it's just been
exciting to see people kind of take
reading to the next level and kind of
the you know garage reading that we had
early on where we're just crossing
hybrids and hoping for something
interesting to you know kind of what
we're seeing today which is a really
interesting key motivic expression that
was kind of finally tapping into tension
of what cannabis can do I mean you have
this plant that is always very unique
interesting bioactive cannabinoids and
really we're only playing with a couple
of them and a plant that can also
produce all this unique chirpy profile
that can potentiate those effects
potentially and give unique flavors and
aroma to cannabis and we're really only
working with you know you know maybe
seven eight nine ten of those
cannabinoids so that's that's been
exciting to see these people really kind
of starting to to challenge that in a
challenge that what the plant can do and
it produce interesting to me you mean
got trains I'm rigid you know I'm the
president of Steven I'm also the
director of R&amp;D for me this has been a
really exciting night because I come out
of plant biotech and and so this has
been interesting to see an industry that
should have as much information about
their plan as any other cash crop
because we are as a big akattak prop as
any other crop united states
but you know it was interesting for me
to be able to come into this industry
and say oh wow we know nothing and then
to start to compile the data from the
tens of thousands of tests that we've
done and to start to see trends and
those trends are what Josh is talking
about right where we can start the co
these plants obviously CBD THC were the
first ones right but we have a plant
that makes over 500 active compounds
right by active compounds I mean by they
have biological activity that we know of
because we know of their corresponding
or exactly the same compounds and other
plants right so we know that they have
functionality and so you know what we
what we can do at the analytical
chemistry level is
use some of those tests as markers for
greeting without even going into
genetics right so as long as you've an
outcome you can follow it right so
that's the beauty of analytical
chemistry in the in the early days of
the industry because there were markers
you could see the results of a breeding
program and now we've taken to the next
level where we now have marker-assisted
breeding we start to do the same things
that the Monsanto so the Dow eggs can do
and and those things will help improve
the proper products that we make on our
site as well before waiting for Big Mac
to get into its own Seth preferred
co-founder of Oregon's CBD where
industrial hemp seed research an
development company based in my
background is actually PhD in sociology
and my my analytical training was in
analyzing large multi causal datasets
looking at world energy problems I also
had a killer breeding facility in my
garage but about 10 years ago so I was
teaching at a carriage policy class at
Oregon State where it's up for 13 years
and it
to coincide with legalization in Oregon
and that was a recreational adult use
THC legalization and industrial hemp and
industrial hemp was legalized in Oregon
one month before the 2014 farm bill pass
read the farm bill read the Oregon law
and said oh man we've got plans to fit
that bill I think we can make this work
and the main driver of this for me and
was moving from plant counts and canopy
size limits to unlimited numbers of
plants because you know as soon as you
have access to very large populations
and you have those analytical
capabilities you can start to tease
apart some of the most incredible things
for this planet they manifest themselves
consistently as long as you are looking
today we are going into our fifth year
of productions we had over 4,000 acres
of industrial hemp grown in the United
States using our high CBD high terpene
content feminized industrial hemp seed
and we're looking at about a hundred
million seed capacity for this upcoming
year with the expansion of the farm bill
in addition to a number of different
novel compounds as successfully isolated
this also develop a very impressive
American high CDG cultivars which is
quite a feat that than we ever seen I
think the marketplace the big props to
you for that my name is Riley I'm a
plant breeder founder of chimeric
genetics which is a seed company around
the Europe and also same company called
Kiel American salt
and we do like I said Connecticut ports
for Caden lp's plant-breeding also
worked with NATO research mark Louis for
a few years down here between 2013 and
2016 and being so pretty interesting
keema Baris on which you saw on the
screen in the previous presentation so
on you know on athletics you know how do
we have how do we talk about how it
impacts us as cultivators and selectors
of breeders and you know I think the
truth is that we following we've all
been doing this all along you know
anybody that's selecting plants you're
going plants and selecting using our
nose or our long as nerve you know our
brain by saying these things analytics
really gives us a sixth or seventh sense
right a way to look at these plants that
we can you know we can't you can't pick
up a flower and smell it and say oh
there's seven milligrams and limonene a
minute right so we rely on technology to
do that since we started relying on
technology we've seen some pretty
interesting things you know I mean for
example
molecular farms last year one of our
clients turn a pro they won first place
in a couple of different categories one
of them was the THC category with their
lemon crush and I was you know one of
the first varieties that was really
created through directed analysis you
know chasee compounds using a laboratory
and there is some people in the
community that didn't like that they
said that they cheated right well to me
it's not cheating to use analytical
method it's like we're we're in this
developing industry we want to use all
the technology
to further our goal because our goal is
to further the plant right to making
better plants for consumers better
plants for hours and the laboratory is
just a tool to help us do that using the
analytical technology which clearly in
cold culminates in a chemo tipic an
alice will validate that the
phytochemical inventory will plan
accurately as these compounds ultimately
there's other analytical tools they're
being used to optimize I'm wondering
every set maybe you could describe it a
little bit about other tools you have
used prior to the chemo type to optimize
the plants and to get to these
outrageous outcomes like by the way not
just what we're calling a tight floor
plan which is CPU knockouts that have
high CBG so like the the most I've heard
actually from available lab results over
anywhere but also I'm hearing a typed by
plant cannabinoid Knoll so rich and
besides lots and lots of testing we
spend literally years in using every
single testing the analytical tool that
we can there's a orange photonics it's a
good example they're a vendor here it
says it's sort of a rough HPLC system we
use for screening but it allows us to it
doesn't work right actually for
we're looking for but it messes up in a
way that's predictable if you run if
you've run five thousand tests with the
machine if you've got all the data to
back it up you look at it go okay if
you've said it offer third-party
analysis with a competent lab you can
start to see the pattern emerge right
and this is this is really what we're
what we're looking at the main thing
that we do outside the analytical
testing is actually field trials for our
cultivars that we released to farmers
which is something that is it's a mice
number in the THC industry for the most
part because of the small sample size
that most farmers are working with as
Mark said earlier that previous
presentation you know 10 phenotypes of
10 seeds that's a good thing right
when you're doing something that is
literally thousands of acres at a time
you cannot have that type of phenotypic
variation we say that our plants are
homozygous for very particular traits we
know that because we've done large-scale
field trials a year before where we
evaluated 20 different mothers that were
separated out from thousands of
different planets to get to that point
to see which one actually recombines and
creates a good field plant that farmers
could succeed with it's almost like when
you're seeing thousands and acres of
your seeds out there the plants are
naked if there was any error in your
breeding it's going to show up and
people are not going to be happy which
was evidences here in Oregon with
memory sale essence Avery industrial
hemp seeds providers Thank You Ryan I'm
wondering with your experience not just
with me prove it especially with maple
in the survey of the chemo scape it took
place in California actually I'm not
sure if anybody is aware of it if you
miss this last talk that dr. mark Lewis
Ned they provide an effort it was a very
sophisticated effort to look at what is
out there let's be on th CDC media and
what's the inventory that this market
and most mentally was the most mature
work I've seen I know how deeply
involved with that can you talk about
some of the analytical work outside of
the chemo type data or the analytical
tools rather that were used to be
productive in creating a really mature
body of work well we really looked at
chemistry so you know Mark said marks
chemist and obviously that kind of
drives the mission but you know
marketing says it's very true the the
metabolomic Emmis tree that is produced
by the plant is really a reflection of
the genome and so like like Reggie was
saying earlier we don't necessarily have
to go and use all these tools to start
poking around the genome when just by
using the chemistry assay we can
actually get a whole bunch of
information about what the plant
produces so that was really our focus
was you know HPLC for cannabinoids and
the GCF ID for for for terpenoids
and you know we had the like like I see
an SD bell we did intake for
dispensaries you know in the process of
these many tens of thousands of samples
that came to the laboratory for the
flower destined to end up on the shelves
of a dispensary we will take this
analytical data
and you plot what we saw in the market
and I think SC labs and steeple apps
probably have very similar data as well
right you get as you're running
thousands and thousands tests to start
to group things and see that there's
different types and you see what exists
in the market they also see the holes
and what doesn't exist in the market
right like what we know if theoretically
exists in the space and and then how do
we fill those those needs it's like Mark
said earlier it's like that's innovation
you see you see where what's what's a
missing SKU and that they can use that
information to go and develop them one
of the qualities I know that I hear
advanced readers speaking to as an
outcome of analytically assisted reading
is really hitting stabilization I think
there's been some potentially like abuse
of that idea in that we don't know what
we're talking about when we talk about
stability and a broad and general sense
I think it's important to think about
what sort of traits we're trying to
stabilize and see consistent and almost
like its expression and curious if you
could describe some of the traits that
you would prioritize in terms of
stabilizing for consumer relevance and
other elements it totally depends on
what your goal is and any good reading
project starts with thing that
originated us what is your goal are you
trying to make are you trying to have a
fuel flavoured dense tall short
flowering plant or are you looking for
something that has other characteristics
so it's it's that is everything and then
you don't build out from there and you
make it personal what is your goal where
are you going my goal is to make sure
that we have access to all of these
different compounds for people and
animals rice there's there's been
fantastic fantastic research has been
done by GW Pharmaceuticals they had a
15-year monopoly a huge head start in
this industry and they have these
wonderful plants that just sit in a
building like they're not doing any good
right now and while there's great
information that can be derived from
pharmaceutical trials like encourage
companies to continue doing that type of
work just getting the compounds out into
the public sphere for people to use and
try and say well this works for this or
this works for that I had no idea that
CBD V is just like nicotine and coffee
that's great let's find out if that's
true for the entire population or if
it's just a subset of the population
with a very specific very specific
genetic makeup right it's we need to
look at what our goals are before we
head down those paths
yeah yeah I mean having a goal thing is
really important I think the way the
canvas community currently works is you
know people will finally do these
phenotypes elections and save 100,000
plants you find a tricky special plant
and then they want to breed that on the
cross doji right and and that kind of oh
gee if eyes everything in the market and
it brings back this uniformity and its
kind of its like I said these breeding
programs don't have a goal other than
I've got something special that I need
to do something with it right but when
you have something special again you
have to think about what your goal is am
I trying to replicate this thing that I
found into a seed line but it's like I
said you have to start with the goal
right and every breeding program really
has to have a goal it's not just about
throwing a ball around and trying to
find something paying your mortgage is
not an acceptable I want to ask others
either
and I can add just a different spin on
stability right so stability what you
when you're talking about the way Seth
talks about it either
the goal is established and you're going
after the specific trait or traits and
then the breeding program accentuates
that right but there's a whole other
level of stability and AG that we kind
of ignore right and that's why we are
stuck with clones right so the future of
this industry cannot be cloned based I
just want everybody but the only way to
make it not on base is to understand
basic breeding techniques into then to
breed for what is true stability so that
you can have a unique donor the donor
unique you know flower donor and then
every time you breed them you get the
same genetics out right and so that
requires a lot of inbreeding back
crossing traditional you know
agricultural breeding that we do not do
yet in this industry so other than which
you're saying absolutely and as well as
stability you know I think when you're
reading for for you know traits outside
of the chemo typic traits you know that
that's a whole thing that achieving
stability with your chemo Tiffa Canales
is important too and I think early on
the laboratories didn't necessarily even
have a state you know the the right cut
tools to give these guys all the
information
I don't think it's necessarily on the
greeting community's fault it's I think
they didn't necessarily have the tools
until really recently um to to take to
go in and in action rework or some of
these key much other traits that that
now we start to see kind of exploded as
as the laboratory anybody nap analytical
standards for a lot of the compounds you
guys are are actually expressing in the
plant now when we know that chemical
analytical testing services have really
raised a trail by which producers could
derive insight and really understand
sort of what the inventory of your
plants were I felt very fortunate and
Oregon to have met a man named Pat
Marshall who was actually doing testing
from the mid 90s and really was an
activist chemical analyst who was
looking at 64 compounds I know that
there was a grower ecosystem that
started a circle around that chemist who
were the people who actually understood
what the inventory and the state was and
that it was game-changing in Oregon to
have just a single lab it was available
in offering the service and now we of
course have really many at scale mature
labs as sea levels people to you to
really prominent industry leaders I'm
wondering if you can talk about a bit of
like this trend where you started and it
was a steep hill over it was you know
as initial effort that was very
challenging so even when you deal with
like producers coming into a very low
margin scenario and expecting to get
basically unlimited services for nearly
nothing and you have capital intensive
equipment and high paid scientists in
this I mean this is unbelievable
complexity just a little bit about your
messy Birds well yeah early on actually
there early on it was absolutely boring
job
I mean we're analyzing for three
cannabinoids that we could get
referenced and it's four on the GC so we
weren't even looking at acidic in
evidence we're looking at THC CBD and
CBN and all day long you kind of look at
the same time a de Graaff over and over
and over sometimes it can be a little
higher sometimes a little bit lower but
you know we're just analyzing see the
same report and and I remember the very
first CBD strain that came to do as I go
along
something different blueberry from from
it was the first first CBD strain that I
know that was being so kind of in
California is kind of a verified city
street not anyone who'd just want to
talk to a trader obviously but but on
the drug market it was the first one was
commercially available in a you should
changed everything and an anomaly
shipping yep 14:15 cannabinoids that
most of the labs are testing for dozens
of terpenes and so um you know it's it's
come a long way and it's become a much
more interesting job but still for so
long we're seeing kind of a scene
commander grammars a lot and now this
has been really excited to watch the
work these guys have done because it
makes I've got more interesting it in
and we're actually all these types of
compounds were testing for not make
sense I mean again like I said really
you know up until the last few years
we've had you know high THC I
CBD maybe a little bit of CVG one or two
or percent between crack or something
like that and you know six or seven
turkey that's really expressed in
hitting and it's been just excited to
see kind of this company sometimes it's
by accident sometimes you see someone
does even know what they have and you
can only go so far in that in Indian and
so it's really been really really
changed you know even just in the last
few years so the so many messy births so
I mean I think he when he started he
would so well and so the messy birther
was just describing I think describes
exactly what I would say anyway but I
would like to add to that that the other
part of your statement where people come
in and expect all this free testing for
the margins I cannot tell you I have
heard me hey you should let us test for
free because will make your lab better
okay no problem
so let me Amy first and then if it's
different I'll give you your money back
because exactly what Josh said they all
kind of look the same right and it's
only more recently that the job really
has expanded you know and one of the
things that we are noticing from this
expansion is that we've really done a
lot of damage to this plan right so a
recent paper came out where there are
some compounds that you can only find in
CBD lineages because we've broken the
THC pathway so badly right so so one of
the things that has to come out of I
think all of this is our understanding
of what we left behind
I try to get it back so the the people
who are out on the forefront of the
analytical chemistry side what worse is
great because there's analytical
chemistry available to growers now but I
can tell you that one lab is not the
same as another if anybody has submitted
flour samples to a lab for testing you
know this we could take one flour submit
it to a lab and I say a CPG flour will
get a 20% result back we send it to lab
that we trust and we get a 16% back
that's four percent but four percent in
that situation is 25% of the total
cannabinoids it's a big deal it's a huge
margin dare you send it to another lab
and they tell you it's CBN right I mean
there's if this is an Oregon with
accredited Labs labs that are accredited
by national organization so they have to
go through potency standards they have
they've been screened they've been
tested over and over but there's still a
huge disparity between good labs and not
so collapses way to preempt and the same
way this our internal have variability
conversation I think
because here we have the ability for the
first time in history to really
understand the inventory of this class
simultaneously we have consumers who do
not trust the output of the analytical
testing facilities due to this inter lab
barriers and realities as a producer I
can affirm that I can find such an
unbelievably gross range testing between
different analytical testing services
that as the dispensary comes are one of
the things I had to do would simply
require everybody to test her in one lab
because I wanted to have a patient
resource that actually started to
provision accurately curated cultivars
of kima Morrison in reality is I think
even in 2018 and now into 2019 we expect
to continue to continue to see inter lab
variability can you speak to any of the
efforts that were put to ultimately
resolve some of this challenge to
provide consumers and patients with
reliable information so in early a
variability starts at the grower I just
want to say that makes oh yes labs
actually have their own issues I'd be
lying if I said different we make
mistakes machines go out of calibration
they break etc etc right but at the same
time we're dealing with a very
heterogeneous plant where you can have
from one bud to another on the same
planet 10% variance in THC right so the
question then becomes is how is the
sample coming into the lab first you
know how consistently are the samples
that are being bashed together to make
it a regulatory batch how consistent is
it in the grow and then what is the lab
then doing to make sure that they
minimize that homogeneity
virginity by the proper lab technique in
the lab right so I would like to say
that labs like SC and us and you know if
you see a 10% difference between SC nos
a 10% 10% of science is actually an
acceptable number it may not may not
make you happy as a client but it's an
acceptable number in science if your
plus or minus never said you're pretty
good you want to be plus or minus five
percent but realistically in a very
heterogeneous matrix that's a good
number but at the same time I will also
say that because of this stuff that's
going on and labs now have to be an ISO
certified and and as ISO certification
comes along you actually have to do a
lot more jumping through hoops it was
okay to get your CRM Azure certified
reference materials from one one
provider before well now that your ISO
credit if your ISO accredited you can't
do that you have to have multiple
sources for your CRN's so that you can
cross-check them before you even use
them in your analytical batch right so
so because of that what we're seeing is
we I was just in another like cross lab
comparison for an Rd sample thing for
somebody out of state and they test it
with three labs and all three labs came
in within one or two percent most of the
time right so a lot of the interlab
variability is going away and I want to
add to that that was with Turkey will
tell you getting terpenes right because
they're so volatile is really hard so we
had three labs in this cross comparison
that ball came in within like interprets
of no higher than the five or six
percent difference right so the labs
were getting better right but we all had
the same exact single batch oil when
your work
right so the oil that we started with
was very homogeneous so you have to add
those things together and understand the
whole process I think so I'll start with
California because I think I think the
two states and we have a lot of outside
Portland as well and I think the two
states have very different regulatory
regimes and I think they I think I think
different challenges so now that
California's regulated labs are forced
to do a lot more quality control have
run ELQ uses quality control samples
with every batch that check that
calibration so your machine can't drift
out of calibration so you you know you
can catch it and carry over you can
catch all these issues that pop up and a
lot of labs aren't doing that before
there's a lot of reasons price pressure
you know when you're in a voluntary
market and you can only get you know 50
60 bucks for a test that should be 150
you know quality is going to suffer and
in people corners now in California you
have a lot of new labs in the market
because you know they saw billions of
dollars in the testing market which is
silly but if you jumped in and bought a
bunch of equipment and didn't
necessarily have the wherewithal or have
had the time to get up to speed since
we're all you know developing our own
methods and so you're gonna see a little
bit of that in California as well but at
least in California what we've seen as
the regulators are gonna come down on
you and shut you down if you're not
doing a good job and that's been proven
up so so that's that's the key thing is
he's good oversight from the people who
are regulating the laps if you're not
gonna have a good oversight on people
regulating the labs and why we do it any
of this now you know mandatory testing
because otherwise we do have what
happens in Oregon where you have several
labs that are just openly you know kind
of I don't know how they're doing it but
getting getting their customers an extra
five six percentage points not relative
absolute on their THC test and you know
we have customers that come to us and
you even say well sure we'll do some
pesticide Testament you vote sorry we
can't do can happen our testing with you
it's a it's a comfortable competition
thing and we've had so much downward
pressure in Oregon and Oregon market
that they need those extra few points to
sell the product and they know that
everyone knows what's going on and the
state's not doing a damn thing about it
and so you know I would you know or let
you know it's not a good oversight
system and so it's long as to happen
what it does is it drives the labs that
are not cheating how to visit us and so
that's the thing that's gonna happen in
California if the regulator's ever kind
of get lacks on the labs I mean it's
it's it's a pain in the ass and you know
just scared every time I get a call from
the BCC but really that's what's gonna
keep the labs that are doing it right in
business it's a strong oversight of the
testers - they put us in the kind of
hall monitor position someone has to
keep it a really good eye on the fact
that that we're doing what we need to do
because we serve a very critical
functioning than this you know there's
there's a lot of um I guess incentive or
you know bad actors or lateness and both
of them can be equally as damaging as an
example Josh just said that drives the
good actors out of business I just shot
my new mix of a lap down roads after
that reason so yeah and I think part of
that you get remembers we as an industry
and as a consumer base are actually
responsible for this - right like you
don't go into a
wine store liquor store and ask you know
what's the highest alcohol content beer
what's the highest alcohol alcohol
content list or wine right it's just
it's not the way because humans products
on and when we put such a pressure on
these on labs really because even want
to get these high dollars for high THC
content it's just nonsense it's that's
that's not a good metric of quality and
I think that we you know we really need
to do a better job of teaching consumers
that it's not you know that's not the
way to find a good product for your fear
ailment you don't go into a dispensary
and say hey it was the highest or people
do but they shouldn't right so so the
Greeks have this word called a shot dose
which is like the final thing that
really it's also the beginning of a new
thing but rather than metaphoric for
this you throw the stone into the pond
and the ripples are happening at the
tiny is actually the ripples that have
already occurred after the event and
then the central events there's this
notion of chemical analytical testing
came in the cannabis it funnily
disrupted the long term consumer
relationship that fomented in the
underground and the Prohibition era
especially and my sense is that what
we're living through is actually a lot
of ripples we've already now have the
ability to actually get out of sort of
inter loud variability and have really
reliable testing data but that means now
we have to update everything else and I
think a lot of the frustration and I've
heard some of it expressed here and I
certainly feel
of it is that we have a consumer trend
pursuing high THC over any other quality
we have growers who are just talking to
brilliant like some of the best horrors
we have having been so much worse our
they're testing really high or testing
out labs that are unscrupulous we have
indica and sativa frameworks which are
certain cultural and attributes that we
can't actually define by science good we
just have so much catching up to do and
I guess I'm just wondering if there's
any sort of like here we've got and the
little reading at scale we have a future
to look forward to of moderately dosed
products are incredibly chemo diverse
and very sophisticated and evil it means
these people's needs but we really have
anyway is education and sort of popular
education platform issue with how do we
get the consumers and the patients and
the market to actually serve acknowledge
this event which is a curve which is
that we must reframe how we view
cannabis I do a small start I'd say that
those ripple it's a great metaphor the
ripples are definitely out there but
most of them are not from THC I think
most of the ripples in the pond around
us right now are non-psychoactive
cannabinoid so that's your grandmother
who is responsible for a lot of the
shift in public perception THC is an
itchy drug I love it
but only about 20% of the population
consumes it and even then only a small
portion is about 20% of that 20% drives
the actual consumption patterns those
are the people that you need to target
in terms of Education and making sure
that they're on board with new knowledge
about turfing diversity or flavor
profiles and the different effects
effect that those will have on you but
it's those other markets with different
compounds that is the other 80% of the
population
animals and that sort of stuff I think
we're the popular consciousness actually
gets ahold of this planet where you can
see that it's not just for recreational
use or for certain aspects of pain that
come along with psychoactive
implications there's there's a whole lot
more out there including the replacement
pods
we don't need hops anymore pops I love
them they're their cousin right but they
take a huge amount of agricultural
infrastructure that take five years to
get to maturity and every five years 20%
of the hoplites
Oregon and Washington get ripped out
because of disease with cannabis you can
have a single you can have a crop that
grows once every year it gets replaced
by seed and produces exactly the same
compounds and hops do so this is popular
consciousness is already changing and I
think it's being carried out by a lot of
different people it's not just Arbor in
a place like this it's society they've
got this variety will have a tram that
you know like I said one I guess was a
CBD last year but if you haven't tried
it and you're interested in these plants
with different compounds I suggest you
let me get yourself a pretty rose and
stuff and trying it out it's a CBD CBD B
plant with like one milligram of THC per
gram it's AK extremely low THC content
but when you smoke this and you know
about five ten minutes later I don't
know if I would describe it as nicotine
caffeine but you definitely feel it
effect right and when you can you smoke
this stuff and you realize and I'm high
and then you think in the context of
weight there was no THC in that plant
right and I think it kind of
recalibrates our expectations because
really it's about experience it's not
about it's pretty user experience it's
not about again this
like TFC number so check it out if you
haven't tried those things okay well
yeah I've got a few things I think I
mean one of the big reasons I think THC
is kind of such a has become what it is
as far as is is kind of selection of
purchasing decisions is it's the cost of
cannabis and we cost $50 for innately
cannabis and get a couple joints out of
it I mean I would want the biggest bang
for my buck - it's expensive you know
and so as we see kind of canvas kind of
come down to kind of earth in any price
maybe maybe people just kind of start to
drift away from that and start looking
back at I want canvas that tastes good I
want get on a quality cannabis and so I
mean if you if you if you really have
the need to measure something the lab
should be TV ETV cheating on a total
turkey contract because I would say that
that's here here
quantitative quality indicator much more
so than THC of these in it so I just
think I think naturally over time this
is chemistry becomes more available it's
more reasonably priced and consumers
will start looking looking to other
things just your honor how can I get
offered you know a couple hits and so on
hopefully it'll sort itself out a little
bit to an Indian I agree the other
cannabinoids in our part of the future
in a much wider wider market than than
just use you so the the idea that THC
drives everything the reality is that
you know if we were to use the proper
terminology we get high well the CBD
gets you higher than a different
I mean so the term is psycho
psychotropic versus you know psycho
active but it's still psycho right so so
okay they came out wrong however but
still meaning that no matter how you
look at it you're still having an effect
on the brain right so so one of the
effects gets you high but I would like
everybody to who has not yet about CBD
by itself to go smoke CBD and tell me if
you don't feel more relaxed afterwards
right and if you were feeling more
relaxed I'm sorry but you got high you
know I mean so you know so that's one
aspect as well and I think the other
aspect is you know if we if we start to
think back to old school be like
Acapulco gold man I read right so those
things only make it four six eight
percent but they made a tremendous
amount of terpenes if you look at the
end raises in general right you see a
much broader turfing content where you
have a much higher expression on more
turbulence well back in the day we got
really high off of that stuff because of
the terminal entourage in fact right
what we see now is that as you go and
drive up the THC content the turkey
profile gets narrower and the number of
things that express at a high level go
down so the chase for TAC may not be
getting us where we really want though
about five minutes I want to make sure
you get access to these geniuses does
anybody have questions and by the way if
you have not heard Shango says interview
with Seth proffer and talking about some
of the analytical reading methodology
hit on the shaping fire podcast Berg
some of the best content I've heard in
the last couple of lectures highly
recommend checking so so similarly the
brain trust on the stage has got me so
jacked and excited this is it I wish I
could enjoy this all the time so my
questions for you as all
technology-assisted
breeder of folk who I respect you know
there is this continuum we've got we've
got you know males and females to make
new progeny we've been doing that for
ages now we've got analytical abilities
to you know really look at what we're
doing and helps speed up processes right
and then we've got the part that you
know people are talking about things
like invasive breeding right when you're
starting to like get involved with
crisper and you know editing the genome
right so as people who I everybody here
I respect where did you personally put
that fresh old on where long the line is
reasonable and worthwhile to press to
reach these goals that we have before
you're all like okay that's where I'm
gonna draw my line for whatever reason
you don't have much but I would say
there's so much left to do before we hit
that line that you know let's let's
exhaust those options first and then we
can start talking about CRISPR and
things like that but I think I mean
things that's doing market in Brian I
mean there's there's they're doing
amazing things and they're not you know
not that I mean anything so you know I
think I think it is this guy can do a
lot once we start pushing it so for
thousands of years we didn't have
or anything right so and we did a good
job in all our plans so you know
traditional traditional genetic breeding
is a very powerful tool the most
powerful tool set in that tool is the
breeder himself you have to be able to
observe you have to be able to take
notes you have to be able to record and
follow over trends if you can do that
you you you've got the game beat pretty
much right so yes you can do better if
you have analytical tools and ultimately
the the ultimate expression of that is
to take those analytical tools find out
what the chemical compounds are because
that they are your metrics by what you
measure and then dive into the genome so
that now you can you can do it faster
and and increase generational cycles
right so if you can look at the sea this
is it's cracked you have your seedlings
and you can do a genetic test and you
find you have all the alleles you want
then you're off to the races you get rid
of the rest you force over those guys
into your next round right so you can
really do generational cycling as many
as 4 to 68 a year if you have the right
tools right so so that's ultimately
where we need to go
but CRISPR is one of those things where
when you maxed out everything you could
possibly do you do anything right so we
are nowhere near you nowhere near that
right not to mention the fact that what
we're finding out is that CRISPR make
some other mistakes other places that we
don't know about so CRISPR for cannabis
is like someone who can't quiet the
attention long enough to get through a
sentence honest honest honest to god
it's at this point I feel the same way
as these two gentlemen there's so much
that hasn't been discovered at this
point why why go down a path that could
potentially introduce all kinds of
problems for at least with our trading
program there's so many everytime we
submit samples we get something
back that says you know there's this
there's a spike under chromatogram and
we don't know what it is
I don't either so you know here goes
another two or three years yeah
there is when you look at the history of
planned reading the traditional plant
breeding with other crops it's gone
through phases and the the first major
phase in the Green Revolution was the
advent of creation the bath ones which
require light breeding of two separate
lines and then recombination once you
fix the specific traits that you want
followed by with field trials to
establish which of the spread lines are
the best
that's an awesome it's an awesome
program the next stage after that was
mutagenesis and so this is involving
either plenty increases or decreases so
we're talking in cannabis now about
creating haploid lines which basically
have half the chromosomes of the plant
but those chromosomes when you double it
again lead to true breeding stock with
one generation it's a it's a huge
generational beeping tool for cannabis
breeders it doesn't require this is
something that happens naturally in
nature I wouldn't say it on a regular
basis but it does happen all we're doing
is inducing that quicker in the lab
CRISPR is different Chris Berry is is a
very different animal and I think we're
not there yet in my opinion yeah I think
kind of a different approach I mean I'm
not opposed to CRISPR CRISPR is just a
tool to to edit the genome right and
there's all these other tools like talen
or you know zinc finger nucleases it's
not these things that we can use to do
that the canvas is a special plant and
that it breeds very similar to the way
that humans breed I mean if you think
about the tomato for example it's made
its you know grown in the greenhouse and
the becomes long and pollinates itself
pollinates and it produces a seed in the
tomato where that if that tomato didn't
come from a high perceived it came from
an heirloom tomato see you
take that sienna the tomato and plant it
and grow it into a new plant and the
fruit on that plant would be identical
to the planet that it came from and so
on and so forth for twenty generations
well we all know that when we grow
cannabis and you cross two plants
together that the plants that come out
at the end they don't look like that
that's because we're what we call
obligated prosper so you need to have
another individual of the same species
to procreate and that brings in a
separate genome into the mix which
creates this huge level of diversity so
what's seconds talking about in
mutagenesis it's like you said when you
have your goal the second thing that you
want to look for in a breeding program
is finding the variability upon which
you should select a cannabis is a really
remarkable clap being an Emma krauser
because it has all this inherent
variability so we can go through the
genome and look for special things and
and you know every trait essentially
exists on the continuum we have low can
have like proofs and plants but if I can
a plant producing class today with tall
plants and shorter plants high yielding
plants and low yielding plants and
essentially any trait that you can
characterize has this variability right
so I'm the CRISPR now though CRISPR
allows us to do these special things I
mean a couple of days ago they just
published a method in in a rice variety
for producing a polemic to see so now
anyone knows what makes this is but it's
essentially an ability of a plant to
produce a seed without sexual
combinations sexual recombination so you
might imagine that if we had a a
convicted cannabis line it would produce
seeds without pollination from an
external plant and all of the seeds
would be identical with a parent plant
that's really valuable for for mass
planting on field
so there there definitely is a use for
these technologies I think that we will
see them shortly so lots of its talked
about how he made specific strains with
a single cannabinoid more for the
pharmacological aspect how relevant is
that reading program these days with
fractional distillation as a viable
option as a plant actually have to be a
single cannabinoid for the FDA music
when we use distillation techniques -
you can't as long as they're present in
the plant and a lot of these compounds
are not present in certain plant lines
and you can't make him express enough to
get economically viable
total total oil content it's it's a it's
an excellent point part of this as well
is making your plants more economically
efficient if you have a pure CPG line it
gives you the opportunity to to magnify
that total compound based on how much
people need but you're completely right
I think the chemistry and the
technological side of our industry is
starting to catch up with with that
stuff I think the combination of those
two things plant breeding and technology
continues to make us more efficient in
yeast I want to point out to you know
again we can do all those things through
chemistry and you know specific
extraction this was accede to it or
whatever but it's it's always more
efficient if you have a plant that
already almost approve approaches your
goal so if you have a plant that
produces 99% CBG a for example of the
cannabinoid fracture
and the other 1% THC or CBD there's less
work to go to do by chemists Raymond
saves labeling saves costs so in terms
of delivering your product to market
efficiently and a cost-efficient basis
it's better to have a plant that does
most of the work in that rather than
have to go in through technology and
change it after the fact
do you happen to know the timeframe
there yeah well Dave she good friend of
mine so you know I know all about that
pretty program it was done through they
were I was actually the really the first
program first sitter's of breeding
programs that was conducted through
selfing technology and ideas guide which
is free things and it really only took a
couple of months it once you identify
your targets you'd be surprised with god
you're just meetings but you can do it a
couple of generations so i would like to
caution the the whole distillation that
is process only because from the
analytical lab site what we see is
people are when you combine regulatory
testing with distillation you end up
with a situation where a lot of what you
expect to see delta-9 is gone right so
it turns into Delta and Delta ten or
whatever else and suddenly now you're
not dealing with the same compound so
distillation does not necessarily also
get you what you want
thankfully we're on the panel and not
the synthetic cannabinoids panel and
ultimately there really is a scaling of
producing cannabinoids it was wild
as here and meet the teams from India
and who can produce and he's very
efficiently and cost-effectively and to
see the Cronus partnership with ginkgo
by our works and to start to watch them
the Bowman you know these big swirling
energies around since that it
commemorates and I promise
there are really you know it's very easy
to produce that scale very pristine
individual compounds and the reality is
I think all of us Sharon and this
movement really is sharing a passion for
the plans a passion for the way the
plants through using technology and all
the tools that they're available to us
to ultimately facilitate your the best
possible use and relationship of it and
I just really want to appreciate and
celebrate that there's so many new tools
that have arrived there are so many
brilliant people in this conversation
and now there's a lot of clinical
research and other things that need to
substantiate what these new plants and
narrations and compounds can produce and
quality of life and I believe we're
really going to change the world I have
a faith in this every morning when I
wake up and it's mainly because they get
to hear all of you
you