hey there so we are here today to talk
about the regenerative cannabis growing
conference that that first toured the
last two years but now is back for a
third year I'm here with the designers
and creators of it Joshua Rutherford and
Layton Morrison and and guys I wanted to
have you on the channel so that we could
talk about why people should go to the
conference because I'm a big fan I
missed the first year but but last year
I was able to check it out and and it's
like a gathering of the tribe for
regenerative cannabis people's so so
Joshua why don't you go first and and
kind of describe the conference and why
it matters yeah I mean the the goal with
the conference really was is to get
people into the you know the science of
organic regenerative cannabis
cultivation and to dig into the details
because I found that through online and
different teachings different people
were missing different parts and that
bringing together the different speakers
and the different thought minds and
these different angles that they would
bring a more clear whole picture that
was kind of the real main driver and
still is the main driver but we've kind
of had this secondary mission that's
popped up and you've nailed it right on
the head of gathering of the tribe and
for whatever reason the timing was right
when everyone was transitioning you know
into legalization that that we needed a
place where we could come together and
like figure out how are we gonna do that
and so that is kind of crept into part
of the conferences is a coming together
and you know Josh and Kelly the DEM
collective has been a big part of that
and were we're really excited to see
where that goes in the future and so
it's really kind of been a supporting
you know supporting the community and
and holy hell like being in Humboldt
last year I mean all the places but to
meet people that have been growing weed
for 10 years 20 years 30 years and and
doing the struggle all on their own it's
just like your instant brothers and
sisters there's like hugs and like man
we're instagramming about the rain this
year and it's just a camaraderie it's
been really cool so last year I was at
Michigan and I've had the same
experience where people I met in
Michigan you know they've got their
unique
community of people and now you know I'm
texting back and forth to them and some
of those folks went out the humble now
they've got new allies and humble and so
so you already mentioned josh and kelly
from dragonfly earth medicine who are
you know we're all fans of but the the
list of educators for the event is as
incredible as it's been the last two
years so will you just name drop a bunch
of people who are on the flyer dr.
Elaine Ingham of course she's the the
Guru leighton-morris and obviously mine
for my partner and he brings a whole
interesting level Chris Trump we're
gonna have Suzanne Wainwright Evans
the bug lady the bug lady chip Osbourne
which he didn't join us last year but he
brings a whole part of soil chemistry
that's like super handy heady and
supercritical it's we're talking about
the minerals in there that's a real part
that's missing in the conversation I
think we're gonna have dr. Efrain out
there and talk about my Oh cries I fungi
and then of course uncle keV Kevin Joe
jury you know stoked to have him back
and and and we're really turning Sunday
into a genetic day into a Kevin Joe
today to talk about genetics and to do a
seed swap which has become a huge part
of this
it was amazing last year to see breeders
who were selling $300 $500 packs you
know giving and trading seeds openly
amongst people you know and it didn't
have to be cannabis seeds there were
there was vegetable seeds being traded
it was so beautiful and it's it's how
we're gonna survive and it's how we're
gonna a few Philo's yeah so so so so so
so far you're picking up that it's a
it's a real community event it's really
down to earth
we've got like dream team of speakers
gonna be there but you know when I first
started posting that tickets were
already on sale people are like oh I
went last year I don't need to go this
year and I'm like nanana
not not only do most of the speakers
will will speak for an hour sometimes
more especially in two hours right on
even if they're speaking for two hours
most of these speakers could do whole
days on their own and these speakers
know that they need to provide new and
different content than last year and so
so so Layton I know that you know like
you were very clear that these speakers
are the top of the industry so why would
we swap them out why don't you tell us a
little bit about about why people who
were there last year shouldn't make sure
that they're here again this year well
there's just so much new information out
there you know the the deeper
understanding of these what I'm gonna
call communities now of organisms not
just three four bacteria there's there's
a whole community of these guys that are
working together and there's some new
information on f2b ratios which is
fungus the bacteria that's coming out of
Brazil that Elaine learned over the
summer so each one of these speakers
every year ups their game and brings new
information at the tables so yeah we're
gonna be touching on the basics and
making sure that the newbies have some
point to start but we're gonna be diving
deeper into the present information that
we've learned over the last year and
these relationships between the speakers
I mean that that was like an amazing
thing to put Chris Trump and Elaine on
the same stage together and then like
Friday nights we all the speakers
present get up there and Duke it out
because we all don't believe in
everything but then again you start to
open your mind saying well I understand
what you're saying did you ever look at
it this way and so there's there's a
whole symbiosis that it's occurring
right in front of you as real time well
and just to add on it I mean it really
wasn't to our last conference in Maine
that the team of speakers really started
to feel like a team
and break down some of those social nor
and get some social norms and break down
some except for people where some
barriers and you really get into some
stuff and like it's just been very
powerful to be a part of that that's
organic yeah it is organic so so so what
we're saying here is that it may have
taken all of last year for everybody to
get to know each other and my favorite
parts are when one speaker from the back
of the room
like Wendy Kornberg who's like
constantly interrupting people are like
but what about this right and then they
go huh and so you've got these active
conversations between the different
educators happening in real time in
front of you and you know what if you
have something to add you can raise your
hand and add it to like where the hell
else we're gonna get this I don't know
of anywhere else and that's why you guys
pretty much did it right absolutely we
wanted to prevent the misinformation
that's been going around and clean up
some of these details so that people
really do have a solid base foundation
to work for which is why the name
science is in the name yeah and stay
away from sponsorships has been a big
part you know we don't have sponsors
we're paying the speakers the ticket
sales pay the speakers to be there and
we've asked them to be there for two
days one to two days you know they speak
for two hours some speak for a little
bit more but they're there to interact
with everybody and that was really the
goal it was to push us all as the
community and it's happened you know
build the community so that people know
that other people are struggling just
like them and they can rely on each
other to work together to get through
this because it is it's trying times
really is and when we first talked about
bringing folks back we I was really
reticent to be honest I was thinking we
needed to bring us some some different
topics but as we as late in our dialogue
that it was really you that just became
very apparent that that was it was 2.0
and we needed to try to make that clear
to everybody that there you know Suzanne
has been busting her ass she's going to
school she's going to courses she's
working a ton with cannabis you know
it's it's really impressive to see what
the learning that's going on and even if
there's going to be different topics
this year than there were last year it
doesn't mean that you don't go to the
same speaker on a different topic right
these are all people who have got like a
wide range of knowledge it's not like
they only know two hours worth of stuff
right
I mean Jojo dree alone right Jojo can
speak all two days whatever and and and
and and keep the time full of
interesting anecdotes so all right so so
Joshua for for people who don't know the
reputation already like we all do about
the regenerative cannabis traveling I
don't know circuits of Roadshow Roadshow
that's much nicer um like who is this
for who like like if you're if you're
watching this and you're like like okay
you know we want to go to something like
this but I don't know if this is for me
who are the people who need to make sure
that they're here I mean it's really for
cultivators and a hundred percent you
know others beginners are welcome but
it's really for advanced cultivators who
are deep down the organic whole and I've
been doing it for a minute to up their
game you know and one of the biggest
feedbacks and most impactful feedbacks
that I think that both of us got was
with so many hugs and so many thank yous
and I'm thinking you know thank you
thank you
you know like thank you for coming and
making this happen and people were just
so thankful to be a part of just what
we're talking about the community aspect
and the the sharpening of steel what's
what it was the same honing of steel or
whatever but yeah I mean again the
they're missing little pieces and they
don't know what those pieces are but
then they start to understand oh god now
I get it
that's why this year I kicked it out of
the park and then the year after I
failed was because I missed this piece
so it's it's really sharpening everybody
on a many levels and then they also can
get together with the speakers and talk
about their specific needs which i think
is really real
valuable for these cultivators and it's
cool too because there's not like vendor
booths and sponsorships here and so on
the brakes you know you can step outside
and share a toke with like these these
educators and and talk to them and ask
them your questions and it's not like oh
they spoke and then they got to run to
the airport and they're gone
they're actually there for a day or two
because there aren't sponsors paying for
it your ticket price is paying for it
and so they're there for you which I
thought was really cool you know I don't
want to say who I smoked joints with but
it's nice that you can go out with these
brakes on the brakes and share share a
joint with like one of your heroes like
how bad this is that right yeah so so so
let's talk about tickets so tickets are
already on sale so if you want to go do
not waste your time in getting a ticket
but also it's different this year
because the tickets were available at
the door last year none of that this
year it was made for a total pain in the
ass right like in though it's it's early
in the morning everybody's half asleep
everybody was up all night like
exchanging information about
regenerative cannabis none of that so so
this year it's going to be a limited
number of tickets they're all available
in advance which means we're almost
certainly going to sell out and so so
Joshua if people want to get hooked up
with a ticket in their City how do they
do that
the website is easiest regenerative
organic cannabis calm click on the city
then scroll down on the bottom purchase
tickets will take you to a vet right
right on so pretty straightforward so so
it's easy to buy tickets you go to the
website and the link is in the in the
description below order online if you're
like I don't have the money today we
take credit cards and and also you know
don't be in the position where you put
it off and put it off and put it off
until all the tickets are sold out that
happened you know to lots of people well
not at the event but I'm thinking like
concerts that I got skunked out at right
I put off the stuff forever and ever
until I can't get like a ticket and then
I'm like oh I guess I'm not going don't
be that person
right there the value of coming together
as a community and sharing this
information and the fact that we're not
alone growing right the idea that that
there are other organic cultivators out
there who really care about microbe life
I think is a pretty big deal so so $350
will change your life yeah it will
change your life I've been told that a
lot it's it's been really cool and I
don't take the credit to us I just take
the credit to the community and coming
together
one thing I did want to add that I think
is pretty pretty vital is we are adding
breeder booths this year so we're gonna
probably four or five and we haven't
released the names except where we got
hyep Pacific Northwest roots he's gonna
be with us and we're gonna have some
more guys they'll be there all weekend
to talk with you and also sell their
gear so yeah and there I don't think
we've mentioned the seed swap either and
so one you tell us about Friday night
yes well we do the seed will stop on
Sunday at lunch and it's an open seat
swap bring what you got bring what you
made and it's actually been a really
cool literal cross-pollination where you
know some guys from yeah I don't want to
start calling out who and what you know
because people are moving these these
genetics in and out of the legal market
yeah but it's it's because you know have
looking for something you know with
osmium you were talking about that
earlier and who has the oldest guy over
here how's that go link down him and and
then now it's being grown in Maine over
here or up in Canada and it's it's
really cool and we're helping each other
grow better by helping each other get
better genetics right um it's really
awesome and so since I thought that the
seed swap was on Friday but it's
actually on Sunday Friday night is
special to tell us about Friday night
Friday night we have all the speakers
throw down
so we bring all the speakers in and we
put them up on the stage and I kind of
foe host it but really it's a live Q&amp;A
and we let the audience ask questions
and it it creates awkward moments
sometimes when when Ocwen different
members of the you know speakers on a
disagree good we give a beer and stuff
and get them loosened up a little bit
and it's been really awesome and
powerful and and and just fun for
everybody
yes so so if you are into regenerative
cannabis this is not something you want
to miss
and the guys have set their schedule
from the west coast all the way across
to the East Coast and also hitting in in
Canada once in Vancouver and so you know
last year people in those cities were
certainly there but people flew in and
road-tripped and put together their
posse and all came like like this is um
you know this is the kind of thing
that's worth traveling to so you know
don't be don't be left outside hearing
about how great it was so again the link
to get tickets is in the description
don't miss it if you care about
regenerative cannabis like come meet up
with more family and no two shows are
the same oh yeah they're all different
there's different speakers at each one
right and also there's feedback is
different than the whole vibe is
different of these things so yeah I mean
you can go all four and you guys still
learn something new each one thank you
so much to everyone that's come it's
like seriously you guys all again to
come back to all these places it's been
a true blessing
you