good afternoon
well we know that the rooms got a little
more people realize that they're late
the panel that we are going to start now
so welcome to the what about panel we
are going to discussing best practices
for commercial candidates horticulture I
am your host through the panel
shadowless and I'm also both of the
shaping fire podcast if you enjoyed
listening to interviews with the top
minds and Candice I encourage you to
grab what like flyers for the podcast at
the door every week I speak to a
different Channel imminent and they
teach you all about their expertise
let us first a welcome our guest
starting on the far end
Brian ken from bird in the middle we've
got Casey Rivera from yerba buena and
right here next to me is Katie Hobbs
tomorrow the two worlds so these are
merely highlights of each speakers bio I
encourage you to google them or approach
them after the panel for more
information let's start on a next to me
here with Casey hubs Casey is the
laboratory director head of research and
development as well as the Dro team lead
for or grow LLC a large Tier three
tennis producer processor in Moxie
Washington she has a degree in
neuroscience and they certified
herbalist with knowledge in sustainable
farming product development formulation
qa/qc standard operating procedures and
plant extraction next to Casey is Casey
Casey burberry is co-owner and lead
cultivator and yerba point
Corrigan Casey has over 20 years of
indoor/outdoor a greenhouse cultivation
experience with a heavy emphasis on
sustainable and green practice its
practices
he also designs commercial drone
facilities or other Kansas companies and
on the far end is Brian camping
graduated from I want to ask you what is
the name of this university because in
gold well law from the University of
Guelph with an honors science degree in
environmental horticulture he majored in
went to the ologies a minor in plant
production plant pathology and twist and
homology brian has been a grower advisor
and birds for over 10 years
we're doing clients to establish
successful protocols and engage in
trials set up to the highest of
standards so we've got a fantastic
while my panel today and we're going to
going to chat about 40 minutes and then
take about 10-15 minutes of questions
and then we'll be complete so we're
going to start at the far end with a
question for Ryan and then and then
everyone else will have an opportunity
to weigh in their their opinions as well
so the right you know what is a common
error that can be avoided when scaling
up from a prohibition-era sized
Bravo of let's say about 100 blooming
plants to a very large licensed
commercial cannabis grow forecast
here but your illegitimate decorum and
understanding that basically you're not
dealing with say several hundred square
feet but now I do work with disabilities
and you multiply work in Canada as
consulting that like I do work with
facilities that are in the tens of
people arranged and so the information
of the taxes that you do life before
especially once we get into what I call
a high tech or high intensity range it
just amplifies itself done you can do
some of the similar classes that you
usually a small production but now you
have to understand that especially with
the companies I'm working for they're
looking for very high yield in the
shortest period of time and in Canada
the federal government regulates all
medical marijuana production so we also
have to answer to the federal government
and my my job basically is is again to
then we hold the ideas of cultural
practices include very expensive
environmental practices practices that
are going to create the highest yield
with the best quality in a shorter
period of time but a gtu this so the
dude the question is when scaling up
from a probationary over on a hundred
plan to a large license grow what are
the common errors that you can see being
avoided with little forethought so one
of the big issues that I come across
and be quite frequently is a proper
planning in planning starts the
beginning with your business development
understanding what I can achieve this
motivation so you're trying to damage
are you establishing a facility that is
going to produce as much as possible
are you selling facility that's going
for the highest quality are you having a
research facility so understanding what
your motive is and what your business
practices extremely important first step
it's not what you begin to plan your
neck a bit that planning you know many
different ways to make know what your
business model so depending on whether
you're going indoors outdoors greenhouse
so understanding your in developing your
business model with really high strength
at the beginning is really important
yeah all this does not refer to slam
medals it also having proper procedures
and processes in order or even going
really important because if you have
issues and problems sorry about that
okay if you have if you're trying to
deal with problems of small
their deployments intensify and get
larger when you try and upscale
so if you have your processes in order
and like you said next we have a role in
this in this factors and knowing which
direction your companies to develop for
is a really good idea because some how
many focus mostly on edibles on focused
on low Sun will do concentrating for the
plethora and so if you know a stretch of
your going and you have those processes
yes actually idea that that you have a
column that is small and your small grow
when you scale it up your problems are
likely going to scale up as well yeah so
Kate Rivera um so commercial monitor
crops of all kind at past issues because
of its lack of biodiversity and and
other predators
what is the suggestion you have for
commercial growers to avoid losing whole
props attack yeah that's a difficult one
for everybody
so the Canada plan is one of the first
plants mobile deployment varietals grow
have a environment the lineages of
webbing plan come from are in numerous
different areas with with numerous
different environments so knowing your
screen knowing what's going into those
rain
important the number one most important
thing is is pest management being
proactive as opposed to reactive is
always the best approach to it having
the pest management programs where you
act like you have at Nvidia you don't
take care of your client health is going
to say you look for success longer group
missions a monoculture crops that's a
tough one there's a lot of people that
they I bet this variety and I can
produce X amount of counter for life I'm
gonna go for it what happens is that
wonder writing kind of digress is
genetically a little bit like you have
nothing to back yourself up with so the
first to find your genetic diversifying
them in a way where you're understanding
those genetics before you put them into
a population before your timing on them
for production is really key
I think a lot of people go for it the 50
trades for the hundred strains and they
lose focus on what nice rains are doing
become extremely hard a tough one to
figure out what are my strains
benefiting from or what it what am i
hitting my trainings but so in my
opinion pest management starts to the
mini and it's always something like a
need to be reevaluate and you know what
strains map we we have about 30
different strains that are our facility
in each one of those trainings we have
two humans
program we primarily use predatorial
insects our main motive defense as well
as other natural my go insecticide
bacterias and whatnot so learning how
the responses of the plant are each of
these methods is really important more
data you collect the better your
programs going to become how about a
thorough my question before we move on
JD so you said that one of the good
ideas into issue of work as if you have
a hesitancy in infestation now to
prevent it and then when you describe
your palate of preventives
you had both you know pesticide grades
but also that Vincent I'm assuming that
when you're talking about planning ahead
you don't mean spraying when there are
tests you're talking about more leaning
on beneficial insects because you really
probably don't want to add chemicals
that children necessary that do you have
correct interpretation that's true well
when I mentioned sensitize a lot of
people get this idea of chemicals that
identifies just anything that combats
that they can be a micro insecticides of
using fungi using bacteria using calcium
enriching your plants to be healthy so
that way the bugs don't want to attack
you that's the most important right it's
okay and at the same original question
what suggestions you have for commercial
growers of scaling and tactician
preventive maintenance
you're number one
Nellie kind of having a protocol set up
prior student having plans you
personally probably that idea I heard
were enormous into Judaism outdoors and
we have scrubs we have your net here
your medicine so try to implement those
things in the beginning and making it a
habit just really easy to get going and
then as a lot part and humanistic
practices on the back end and also one
thing that was hard for us in the
beginning we were expanding on the
ground of that we were submerged right
in the middle of top view and so getting
to know like what agricultural problems
are already close to your facility or in
your area is really important because
don't know about you'll know what's kind
of expected what exposures yet also like
Katie said preventive influences
preventative sisters also like a
companion plan so if you have outdoor
grow you know look into what you can
plant see some of our antibiotic
relationships with the plants
of them grill healthier from giant while
different kinds of by our management and
I think that if you start off that way
you'll have a better chance
I think that idea of knowing your
neighborhood is really insightful
because a lot of this thing that the
neighborhood of our grow ends either at
the walls the greenhouse or the
warehouse or at the fence line but it's
just not the case where I'm from in in
Washington on Vashon Island one of the
time that we run into a lot is a terior
mold called botrytis which here in
Arizona that you can see a lot less of
that so wonderfully dry and great
growing environment but one of the
Pacific Northwest we get retraced a lot
and you know answers speaking to some
experts on this in the area about why we
have such bad woods right another like
well yeah sure it's cold and you got a
wet knife and Misty foggy morning now
really it's the one field down in Oregon
and will look like and they explained
that to make late bottle vintage
Riesling in Oregon they actually spray
boat rightist
on the grapes and so that degrades
shrivel faster well that makes its way
blowing up to Washington and so being
aware of what what is in your
environment that could be adding X
variables to your bro is very important
well so so Casey on this end we will
start with you on the next question so
and and teach Rivera already
touched on this a little bit we're going
to go farther down we have so many new
Rovers start with a wide variety of
cultivars because they want to grow
something for every taste in the market
and while others focus on just a few
cultivars and focus on growing those
effectively how do you balance that for
yourself and commercial level between
having enough varieties for the market
but also not having there be so much
variety that you can't tend to each
specific cultivar needs specifically
right so we have followed the 30 to 40
strains our facility right now which
which is kind of heavy
we're trying to narrow it down what I
think is probably a better approach for
like our our market is having you know
five six seven flagship something that
you can own in the market something that
you're really really really successful
at growing if you were going to want to
come back for a good idea and then also
having enough straighten your back
pocket that if you do lose genetic
diversity are taking your genetics
starts to degrade over time and you can
have something that you're working with
to pull out and replace it or have time
to
that it but you know cloning and making
them stronger in kasya
the nail on the head with that the more
you diversify your strain database the
more you have to pay attention to a tree
and that starts to begin knowing what
your lineage of restraining are can do a
better indication on how they're going
to grow the problems that you're going
to see with them one thing that we do in
here but one is we really are close to
what the market obviously we don't just
grow blue dreams and og we really kind
of as well as we want to shake the
market with what we find is a good
genetic able we're breeding ourselves
but also coming out with good variety is
a really solid variety that the market
actually want as well too so we work
really closely with all our partners
expenses our extraction company to find
out what's working and at that point we
figure out how best to grow a crop
specifically or what that market so
there's a lot of ways we can shape the
market and there's a lot of ways that we
need to be listening to the market
responding not understanding that the
song is a six month for a year out you
have you have to continue paying
attention to what your genetics are
doing where they're going
one thing that we've done is we
separated our genetics into three
categories we have age decency the a is
our our string that we can really sell a
lot so those are going to be naturally
Remus the bees are the ones that sort of
self but maybe are through that harder
to grow and so we'll place those on an
every other cruising type recycle and if
these are kind of more of our research
strength strain that we're really trying
to work on to develop for the market but
it's not quite there yet so you
obviously don't want to put your seeds
in pretty 100 pounds of those one of
those in a smaller area really through
miliion and experts and then bring us
arguably acceptable i do canada
completion basically of different
strains but we do concentrate on a
hybrid that is going to give us more
veining a medicinal classification
because the government does regulate
that so we are looking at being the
total percent THC content the CBDs maybe
we're looking there and were looking for
strain so in the greenhouse which you'll
see is you'll see meaning for forty two
or three major strains and that's
basically because it's dictated by the
pharmaceutical industry in Canada we
don't even have to spend except for DC
which can get away with a lot of things
we we don't have to spend again because
it's just of being legalized so so most
of our strains are stupid
most of our strains are based on one
being are the medicinal industry is
going to be requested you know I can
imagine how the business
in Canada the variety would be something
that will be mimicked because you know
in the end you can only cleave so many
people but but from the horticultural
side I would think that'd be a real
pleasant a pleasant thing if your
responsibility to keep these friends
live and you really only have two
varieties you can get into such intimate
relationship with them instead of 40
plants that I can't imagine that there
be a lot pleasure in that my work like I
am of time physiologist so my work has
always been this to basically look at
for instance requirements that the
different strains how we unfold so many
leaves in a short period of time to get
us into that state 6870 date flowering
period even looking for now strains that
are going to go below the sixty eight
sixty day work on that so there's still
if for me it's always great to read the
periodicals on on the different strings
on the blendings to see where where we
get into whether it kneeling an 8020
indica sativa vice versa that type of
thing that that's what makes the world
go round for me yes I'm just being
infallible and then again going to be
paying attention to
as extremely important you're talking
about genetic drift more you
mass-produced and clone up clone on
clone we're evolving these plants so
gravity more rapidly than most other
fine programs out there so paying
attention to these variables that can
cause a tricks here sometimes towards
the positive commence towards a negative
so pay attention to those and what might
be causing this expression to come out
really important so keep kicking your
very servic you and this ability that
you remember talking about yesterday so
indoor growers and any municipality did
find or worse because they're unable to
control the smell all the blooming
plants what suggestions you have for
trying to keep those smells indoors we
convinced our neighbors that artists own
cars that's a really tough way to do is
only under operation depending on if
you're doing it changes I'll sealed your
environments are there's numerous
technologies that you can use we quickly
yesterday about h2o2 plasma generators
that basically change the structure of
things in the air and gave odors
charcoal filtration another thing that
we do within our rooms is we watch our
negative deposited pressures so there's
nothing leaving the room our rooms are
pressurized to the point to where things
are staying in
we can move really really close
monitoring of where that air goes we're
constantly moving around our facilities
checking our HVAC unit and checking any
kind of exhaust and personnel our arm is
in a rural zone so the complaining isn't
too much but you know it's possible that
one person does not like the song as
well for some reason and you really have
to do everything it cost again it goes
beyond the programs as well do your
trimming your production your tire rooms
all those parts of the facility are
really things that you need to think
about in your other mitigation right yep
we haven't known the option of just
setting up facilities into urban areas
of the world they basically have to be
set up as far as away from any type of
residential area and we do use rubbers
and we do use heads of overt emitters
but it's not really a problem because
gel don't have out we're so proud it's
like in Uganda if a a farmer 175 he's
not allowed to be within 100 miles of
any any area because of the big order
so I guess perhaps it's best to find a
farm and then some a new facility
because then you can't differentiate
between the south sooner or later
don't want either so you don't have a
lot of visitors coming here you're
injured you're way out Manila's no
litter I would just add you know know
your know your community don't be afraid
to go out there and make friends and
tell them ahead of time
Mavis what's going on if I come over to
see your facility talk to you top tier
community officials and see you what
they feel is how you know how about a
new beginning isn't you're better
prepared and you can budget it in in
there the other stuff walks you with
your charcoal filtration their deposits
pressures there you can set up you know
the HEPA filters which are really
expensive and don't all day clock with a
flip odor control and then there's
there's bio filter skew that they're
doing some work on which are not yet you
know to go to but somebody's definitely
keep a nice I think that the idea of
community outreach and involvement
cannot be understated as well I mean
every one of us who owns it works at a
cannabis company is a is a
representative of our industry as a
whole and we have to remember that for
you know past sixty years or so we've
all been demonized because of the
unfortunate political and popularity of
plant that we all love so much and so
you know they expect us to be you know
and she unclean folks who are mean and
now we're talking to right but but
that's how you intend to get so much of
this community pushback when when you
show up at your neighbors did you
freaking welcome somebody in the
neighborhood yeah
you don't need to bring one chain but
you know you show up there you know and
you're smiling and you're you're saying
that you're here and you're nice and
you're glad to be them and invited over
for you know tour so they can check it
out that kind of openness and when they
see you know these are three very
friendly looking humans here right this
is going to tend to decrease their
barriers to society that your vendor
nice folks and that they don't want to
go call the local councilman and talk
trash about you yeah really good we even
take the time to have not on silica
content but we will have a community
night and we talk about why we're
actually growing medicinal and really
try to educate we try to educate the
community or just people and chart and
see less a Braverman abrasiveness coming
back to us and with the pull up you're
standing that this just isn't a
community we're affecting a medicinal
industry of all ages of young children
of people everyone that means no and I
think we're starting to break a lot into
good media thanks for a lot of magazines
that are really putting a lot of effort
into that now to show that we're not
here we are there for a purpose familiar
Yeah right right minute exactly the
issue has been education we've all been
educated one way for so long in evolving
that lack of education in my opinion is
a set you know and I promise not that
all of us do it everyone involved in and
I hold in the industry as well as I call
in a community up to all the communities
reach out to our local legislators our
laundry facilities as well as our
neighbors to really help educate and one
what this client is doing the world and
what we can do so I think that you know
if you want to get a whole bunch of
growers to kind of like engage in really
ruthless debate like at a house party or
something
you could have someone a few questions
the first one is which is better indoor
or outdoor this is what everybody feel
itchy out of it but the other blood and
is also fun for pushing buttons is this
next question start with you Casey
so you'll grow over shoes there favorite
substrate to grow in for a variety of
reasons but but it all gets very
specific when you have to scale up to
large-scale industrial commercial
growing so so Casey when's your
preferred substrate for commercial use
and why right so this is something that
we've been tackling recently we were
basically it really
and at that time we're spending about
$120,000 a year on substrates and so we
were using a lot of chelated nutrients
and whatnot so what we found is that by
switching to a recycle organic-looking
select oil we're able cut off reuse our
oils there's no film ended where you
need to leave the feature class a lot of
organic living material when you create
this this perfect environment to grow
beneficial bacteria and fungi and
basically just remove the plant you put
a do one in and you know you're cutting
down on th you know testing pH in your
soil making sure that it's has a
sufficient level for nutrient uptake and
you know you're not messing with dirty
reservoirs they have to clean all the
time so to support pop propositional so
that that's one of the things that you
really need to consider in my opinion it
is a little bit of a touchy subject but
anyway what I critical particles are
majority but I think that there is
really good information
one item down great alcohol - a
phenomenal six so high
article one called Denton haven't highly
effective platforms and I had a lot of
really good information about beneficial
in the soil and then also another
article on growing for maximum flavor
and then a book talking with micro yeah
team with my little brother
so sobriety takes me that yeah I have to
go to it the large industry they look at
just a feed like mix and I'm supposed to
be selling beef early mint but the other
Nappanee it's like you say is coming up
with a good organic next I would usually
then every year I would add a third new
that mix only to get the biomass worth
we figured biomass can get quickly after
a while and insults note sometimes the
matter so if you've done a flush and you
reject it because it's totally organic
you have to understand that all your
organic feeds me the biomass microbes to
break them down into an elemental source
of nutrient but I always find still life
look at what I would do I removed that
way but then I have to work with large
announce whether you use a peat perlite
they would use Michael rising in it but
they don't use a lot of arguments they
use like inorganic salts and they go
happen to the older to be investors who
are saying we want this year we want to
dispatch for short periods at nine
would you do so we have both I work with
both sides full-time chemistry before
you go I just want to point out there
hop in grind answer with a new awesome
grower just you know man you got baby
bio mass that's Nextel around you go to
your dolphin go straight go straight in
basically tool depending on your
business calls pending on what your
outcome is you can use any variety of
strength personally we go with your
denim exploit wearing Indo farm as well
we do have to do have this made you
throw a little bit outdoors but worry
indoors as well and we use a
regenerative oil approach we worked with
a local company that builds our soils
based off of the recommendation that I
give in the blend that I have they
regenerated for us three complicated
bring it back we've developed a really
good program yeah we could do this
in-house but right now we don't have the
time or space Olivia
so we outsource that to a local company
that work directly with on each of our
one we don't just have one room we don't
just have one vegetative plant and that
goes into learning your plant each
specific variety life a little bit
different things and I needed to up
lament that with a nutrient
the whole year of getting your plants
that beneficial right off the bat in
that resistance is a great approach one
of the terms that I hear a lot is a
drain away and a lot of people feel like
the soil is okay we're running off well
honestly you're optimizing your facility
and you're not going to be any water
what kind of redevelop that term into it
is it BTUs and one thing that we do is
we pay close attention to how that place
is reacting how many water feeding how
much nutrients were applying to it and
that we were able to adjust our
scheduling as well as our partner client
being feed everything
optimally so we don't having trained
away there is ZERO wire that comes out
of our facility that is not used by the
plan there are benefits to using other
types of growing methods we use
aeroponics and all our cloning just
because that's what our schedule allows
best work takes a lot of space save a
lot of time and if you're doing it right
increase of really healthy brew system
very fast starting the vegetative mode
which California research in our blooms
we use the regenerative soil and paying
attention to your soil is key one thing
that we do is we get our feet surface
are we tested so we can see our biology
going on roadies our element our
interval going on the lake surface we
also test our soil as well too because
the soil when it comes in so we need get
a big fine on the welcome what are sort
of looking like not just mineral oil but
imperialize we also set the performance
of plant and if our plants are unhealthy
as well too we'll do soil tests because
that's really going to tell you what's
going on
like do I have a weak magnesium
deficiency or am i giving it too much
health you blocking out my magnesium so
paying attention to your soil pay
attention to your coal yours pay
attention to your plans really ties back
to that they dig but it really goes from
start to finish in this new your
operation you can do is sustainable you
soil the daily hydroponic sustainably
they comes back to what kind of business
are you creating for yourself just one
thing I that is I always look at the
percent duration in the minutes
basically we always sell oxygen short
events but say if I have a mix that's
too tight and I can't get rid of the
that order the system can get rid of the
excess for free water that's filling all
the large pores which should only be
filled with after watering oxygen people
understand how important oxygen is
oxygen is at replenishing villages we
call them Bolger receptors I can get
oxygen my next can get rid of all of its
excess water in less than three hours
can get oxygen back in there a lot of
your minerals or elements are basically
looking for Oh to to group the group
into to move into the plant places fast
so there is a speed for that also too I
have to promote myself and that's a lot
of Boston I get a lot of mediators we
have a lot of these so-called space Neri
that hold on
but you want to look for all those roots
that keep on subdividing small group
through years
95% of water and nutrient taken up by
plants picking up through those little
goo FairTax
so it's by getting a lot of repairs we
didn't reach the root surface area by 20
to 30 percent meaning that so anytime
you put something through there whether
it's just eh offered water or nutrients
in that you've created a root surface
area so that your nutrients you have
much more diffuse not going through as
leaching but going optical time in with
that is paying attention to that thing
in the light to your soil that's
actually feeding your plant is really
important
are we creating an environment for our
bacteria is our rhizosphere healthy is
it active is it producing for our planet
is it giving our plants the beneficials
that it needs 16
that oxygen is what's keeping the
bacteria alive and healthy creating an
anaerobic soil systems a really tough
thing and people get psyllium wilt a lot
of pathogens to come out of that
knocking atmosphere so it's okay to keep
repair while you're on life restart this
next question with you
so some growers build their entire grow
or on the style of watering that they
intend to do well many of the solutions
used in smaller grows simply do not stay
tail up to commercial use so what is a
watering solution that you believe is a
good one for consideration by new
tenants producers that's a good one I'd
hear of a boy oh we started out with we
have a lot of new partners on the team
and and I'm an educator I really like
teaching people I don't just like
telling people how to do it I like them
inquiries on their own and if they don't
of the wheel to the barn
we started out and watering everything
in and our facility we have over 7,000
plants so if you can imagine the time it
takes to hand water 7,000 plant or what
that is to educated all of our partners
on what's the soil saturation rate what
is the plant doing paying attention to
the plant while you're watering and how
much is going in there it kind of
connects you a little bit the plants are
connected to us and the more we connect
ourselves with those plants the more we
pay attention
they need recently we shifted into a hog
native drift system which right now
we're on about version 3.5 business
that's how it goes there's no perfect
plug-and-play system everything kind of
need to get designed by your own but
we've developed a brutha drip system
after learning these metrics after
learning exactly what our plans need by
hand watering them we've developed we've
been able to move that into our drip
system and been very successful at not
only minimizing our time that it takes
demands of human hours at a pace of
water your experience your system but
also excessively getting the plant
exactly what it means
every time I can't count to 30 seconds
of a thirty second that brine maker make
a TV cam so telling someone getting a
twenty seconds I may count twenty like a
bartender or I made count twenty as a
one thousand two one thousand so having
a system to where it's exactly the same
every time and then understanding what
your points are doing are they opinion
are they not of taking it
do I need water every other day so
knowing that really helped dial and
optimize your your water yeah I agree I
would propose on that actually we we
have several thousand plants at our
facility also started up and watering
everything is that half of our apartment
water you have implemented some
variations to do rooms built recently
and attach the background on hand
watering and getting to know your plants
at that point very much less idle
anarchic urination sobriety you are can
through your pure evasion but a given
one a facilities can hear speakers
that's a lot of plans we go very
high-tech time I've done that as
archaeologists I do do that well
transpiration protocols and data and I
for providing strain because we all know
that the lean mass is different the
problem but then through computers we
put it through a pall system and I know
plan that's only three weeks old in 60
days oh how many liters of water it's
actually losing based on the foot-candle
reading or the light reading of that
name and we just feed that back into a
pulse pistol and it pulses the water
through leaders post water linearly
what we're trying to do is basically
reduces much stress
unfortunately pinterest does not show up
or they tell you that well the plant is
wilting so it's under stress basically
the plant stress usually with any
clinton substrate shows up three to four
days prior to that and so you might miss
three or four days before watering where
so when we're basically doing this is
trying to meet the dealer requirements
but still got to be even grower you got
to do you still have to go up there and
once a while check the roots you have to
lift that pot i have i've time not do
anatomy when i would just ignore when
you're up there 6:00 in the morning
living every prophecy do i water if
you'll find water because of those
things as all and water now a lot of
that young roars watch walkway you look
at the plant yet and all the computers
do not turn the computer off go out
there and learn how to your plants our
remaining time with its when cannabis or
not you can be a roots min instead of
Laxman because we're top artists and
kumkum like to say you maintain that
ideal for good rises here so we got this
time for a couple questions so I have
any answer
yes but my question is intended and
whatever identity - trading would that
limit the entire global health world
patient and we're not reducing this
range but we're always working on still
developing the trainings - what what
what you still medicinally and tossed by
and produced what he's looking for
so it's not that one all story we're
never one of eliminated strains we're
just working with them to see what what
gives it best what we can do at that
time and I think it right Kate correct
me if I'm wrong I think the way of the
Canadian system work is your customer is
not actually the public your customer is
of our circuit company the financier is
knowing you what they want
yeah and so it says like the
pharmaceutical company that choosing the
searching Pro how they're going for it
it's not any growers and pharmaceutical
asked me and I'm always at at wit's end
with pharmaceutical company because
you're not working at at the plant at
its potential and work should be growing
more just like they're just looking at
one entity of it which not gonna work
not going to work if we just I say it
was very we start getting in television
we're going to be a dream for any big
problems
yeah just show me how to an annoyed
no no but that's what see that's what
sells to the pharmaceuticals okay it's
like half the pharmaceutical oral
medicines we take give you breakers
there's Morgan that do the same thing
but they produced 200 side-effects
that's your our people Brian yes you and
your leaves are you know we send them to
an analytic lab does agriculture testing
and depending on the state there's
certain labs that can do it they're glad
set if they're USB 8-month it won't
touch it so just reach out to the local
lab and he's doing what some last night
has a tissue testing some last might as
well tell my to vote so just reach out
so in community people that run the labs
are for lack of a better term like
myself a treat so they love talking
about this stuff and they may be able to
help you with another lab or under labs
so in-house testing the IG not right
okay what's the turnaround well in order
to make it kind of depends on the season
we there's a lot of agriculture in organ
you know it is very seasoned oh you want
for at least a month you know and so it
just depends on what happening with
arrests agriculture until we develop
cannabis specific labs that can come in
all the enticement pets we got to rely
on agriculture lab I'm interested when
you are taking these samples make sure
you're taking the lately samples
basically revolves refer to the will be
call the most recently matured leaf I
mean someone likes they won't want to
test that that yellow at the bottom
that's not going to work
I'm not want to test the one in the
middle you have to test the one that's
actively taking up all the nutrients
appoint on and in soil samples if you're
using soil then they do one type of test
now if you switch over to Blake dating
Pete like mints with his no soil in it
it's always good to let the lab know
that because then that isn't totally
different test if it does one learn it's
a precious minute talk about the
intensity of caravanning I definitely
did most version what do you think about
biochar compost tea that the word for
anything else to you
pentagram men were increasing that that
like I give when we get to like all lazy
soil it needs to be things like biochar
and other amendments that are going to
actually be symbiotic with the root
system they're always they're always a
good a good addition and again it is
based on you should know your soil you
should your plants will tell you in that
no lifetime I'm getting a little
sluggish I'm getting a little grayish
teal blue instead of a vibrant green so
yeah there is the benefits those but
again all I can really say is that
totally when you want to try these new
products there's enough information on
the internet to learn about these
products you should totally understand
that product before you use it that
you're using it for the right purpose
because sometimes they cost a lot yeah
one thing that we've been working with
recently is our cast
and the worm castings are a really good
amendment because they have so much
biological activity in them and you're
not going to per your plants by applying
you can't really apply too much so it's
a good place to start
and Sarah's here what we use oh they're
good people to talk to
without your question yeah there's
actually a lot of different companies
right now emerging in the bacterial type
of the market a lot of people think we'd
be feed when really we should kind of
arrest ourselves away from the beam
mentality and think about our
biodiversity of our soil Bokashi certain
bacteria that promote phosphorous uptake
instead of adding a behavior in the
middle of a community this different
bacterias that are responsible for doing
different things so like I said
understanding what that product does
when you should apply it how you should
apply is really important to maximize
that you're not going to want to offer
as boosting bacteria on at the beginning
maybe you will depending on how our stem
growth just depends on the strain that
you want to produce well to so learning
was brought up learning what that
bacteria does and again jet lowenfeld
that he's produced at three different
flows now
they're amazing books even microbes with
our giant union with bacteria incredibly
knowledgeable books on how to use those
and why just the fact that getting back
to the make sure that your media is a
meeting that's going to be well
oxygenated after cream image because all
of these additives they can get very
lethargic and lazy if you're Michael
sphere it is not a healthy rhizosphere
so you're pouring a lot of money into
something in my mind isn't working it
will work but you still have to before
you get to the get-go all these
amendments and you have to be very
confident healthy with the rhizosphere
that you're throwing what a fantastic
collection and experiencing share today
thank you very much - kinky hug Katie
Rivero and right hand