he's not yeah well we're gonna move on
without comment and we will will go
ahead and read his bio anyway just so
it's on the video but but we'll see
so everyone welcome to the 130 panel on
microbe life
I am Shango Lowe's host of the shaping
fire podcast if you love hearing
excellent information from cannabis
experts I encourage you to check out
shaping fire calm that's where my
podcast lives
Jeff Lowenthal's has been on the show so
there's that fantastic show to hear also
we've got a blossoming youtube channel
now that's serving over a half a million
minutes of exclusive cannabis content
that I recorded at conventions so you
might want to check that out
so our micro panel today is Jeff lone
fellas he is a reformed lawyer and
author of the award-winning and
best-selling books teeming with microbes
the organic gardeners guide to the soil
food web teeming with nutrients the
organic gardeners guide to optimizing
plant nutrition and his third book in
the soil trilogy teaming with fungi the
organic growers guide to Mike horizon
Jeff also writes the longest-running
gardening column in North America having
never missed a week in 40 years 44 44
that's right this isn't as well and
while you're clapping in 2005 he was
inducted into the garden writers Hall of
Fame the highest honor a garden writer
can attain sestri correct also with him
is John Pizzarelli he is founder of
cutting edge solutions as an early
adopter of the soil food web system his
business is rooted in sustainable
agriculture John helped developed the
cutting edge product line to support
natural soil ecology including their
flagship product humty and co-founded a
Mike brought microbiology lab in 2004 to
support their research efforts one of
John's current side projects I love is
growing milkweed and a variety of pollen
producing flowers for migrating monarch
butterflies so let's say let's assume
that Colin's going to join us and we'll
plug into Colin Bell is the co-founder
co-inventor and chief growth officer at
brossentia the parent company of mammoth
microbes
just by
where you've heard of him before Colin
completed his PhD in soil my crop
microbial ecology in 2009 as a
researcher and scientist at Colorado
State University
Colin polished dozens of peer-reviewed
publications that were focused on
microbial mediated processes that
enhance plant growth Khan left his
academic producer position in March of
2015 to launch gross Sencha their first
product mammoth pee is a beneficial
bacterial bloom stimulant that targets
phosphorus so the way that we're going
to do the panel today is we're gonna
present the panel a question and then
each panelist will have a chance to take
a swing at it
unfortunately the panel is only 45
minutes so we're gonna we're gonna be
moving around along pretty swiftly and
we may or may not have time for
questions at the end so Jeff lets us go
ahead and start with you since your
since you're closest so so Jeff in a
commercial growing operation
conservation of resources including time
and money is vital and changing from
traditional cannabis growing techniques
consistently consisting of bottled salt
nutrients too instead using holistic
growing techniques that bring the soil
alive can seem differently expensive and
time training and changes management
often resists making the switch to
living soil because they're afraid of
the risk involved with doing something
that they say differently that it's
different can focusing on building
thriving microbe communities in
commercial operations be financially
beneficial in addition to just being
natural yes because I think the biggest
change are in a long time and grow stuff
and we know that they're going to grow
stuff the way they make cigarettes and
the way they make beer and the way they
may do everything else they do it will
not be a natural system and the way that
you're going to be able to distinguish
yourself from them I believe is because
you're going to be organic and that
we clean those early articles in
California that one out of five plants
didn't make it the testing etc etc you
know you're gonna you're going to be the
positive side of that story and so I
think definitely it is gonna be worth it
from an economic perspective regardless
of whether you believe in it or not are
not are your thoughts Jonathan well you
know that's a good point in that you
know sustainability means you can save
soil and so by reusing so I mean it's
one of the key factors in labor in you
know wasting time wasting money as far
as salt based fertilizers go I mean
that's that means pretty much everything
in a bottle is if you think about it
seaweed is a salt based fertilizer salt
based means that it's on the si or salt
index and the so Lennox is made out of
sodium nitrate and sodium nitrate
actually is an organic fertilizer so it
gets kind of confusing when you say salt
based but there's a lot of people that
are going back to amendments and going
back to compost teas and that's a good
thing and I think that a Jeff's point
that that by differentiating yourself as
somebody who's growing with living soil
probiotic Li I mean it's a huge
marketing win for you it's a product
differentiator that you're not gonna
find just anywhere and also I know what
Colin would have said to this question
as well Colin would have also said that
it is a misnomer that using living soils
and building healthy microbe communities
is less yielding rain historically
people think that oh you have to use
bottled nutrients in order to to get
these monster yields but what we're
finding is that we as we learn how to
take care of our soil yields are
increasing and are being as competitive
as with these traditional products so
John this isn't this next questions for
you so much of the market for flour is
based on bag appeal and many consider
frosty flowers and intense coloration to
be the result of intense
Thatta canoe treants what can
commercial-scale growers do to create
frosty flowers with great bag appeal
while also respecting the health of
substrate micro-communities
I caught like half of the issues it was
one space but you know I think if you
just work off what I think that question
is and you know when you say bag appeal
of course everyone is looking for you
know frosty flowers and the terpene
levels being boosted and you know as a
as a fertilizer manufacturer I mean
probably the most important thing is
manganese you know manganese is a key
micronutrient that all plants need and
they'll you know take it you turn into
an enzyme that acts as a catalyst and
moves nitrogen through the plant but and
the canopy see a family we're hot
there's hops in Canada and and pot
basically cannabis the you know the
manganese make is even more an important
role as the basis for the the terpenes
being made with the early blocks
building blocks so how do you get more
manganese in there when manganese is
only available in soil it like a pH of
four and you know the way to do that is
is microbial breakdown and you know I we
actually have a product that we use
microbes to break that down so microbes
play a key role in you know being able
to build a terpene profile and you know
mammoth pee has some good bacteria in it
that also make phosphorus more available
and you know you don't want to overload
your your soil with too much phosphorus
too much bone meal or you know even too
much you know using products that have
phosphoric acid in them because they'll
shut down mycorrhizal you know fungi
relationships and you know that's
another benefit of using microbes that
make like bacillus mega tyria our
Pseudomonas pooted
that may we'll make more of the
phosphorus available on phosphorus of
course you know adds to the flower
structure but you know there's a whole
different school of thought out there
now something I was already questioning
well let's hold questions the end of
things the you know as far as getting
the flower is more frosty you know
there's a there's a lot of different
fungi and bacteria that produce amino
acids and you know we have an amino acid
product that kind of mimics that and
it's organic in that and that boosts the
actual structure of the glands and
swells them up and they get more
crystals on them so you know as far as
building a good flower structure you're
dealing with a lot of microbes as far as
building good overall look and terpenes
you know once again you're looking at my
microbes processing a little bit such as
manganese but then Foley or spraying
follow people do that with humty or
compost teas and they find that that
actually influences the plant and gives
it more flavor and more and more crystal
structure and you know I built a lab and
I've worked for over 20 years and trying
to figure that out but that's not like a
one-minute question so so the question
that we asked when you're running in is
can using microbe communities and living
soil create flowers that have got the
bag appeal and are sexy and will compete
with the kind of stuff we see from
synthetics and petroleum products yeah I
think you know there's interactions with
all that and so it's not just one thing
there's no one solution and there's a
lot of solutions that we have to bring
together to achieve our final goal and
the final goal is quality and we think
these quality metrics is back appeal is
one is not really my personal metric for
success it's the quality of the terpene
and maybe they came up with situates and
then that smell of that flavor that
translates from the smell I want that
terpene flavor or the terpene smell to
translate to that flavor and then
there's even a more sophisticated
interaction or sure there's THC and CBD
and other Kim annoyed but then we know
that there's these interactions with all
these terpenes which helps enhance the
effect how this flower makes us feel
I've you know tested and looked at a lot
of different strains for the CBD and THC
is the same but they have completely
different effects and there's all this
chemical interactions which contribute
to that and so how do we make that full
package it's by what John said
maximizing the plant's ability to take
up the resources it needs to maximize
its full phenotypic potential I think to
a large degree that's we have to make
sure the nutrients are there and then we
have to make sure the nutrients are
bioavailable and then they can be taken
up and so that's an interaction with
maximizing our plant genetics and our
environment and then what we're talking
about is the input and the availability
of these inputs in availability to a
large degree is a microbial function
maximize the plant's ability to open up
and I got out of breath writing strict
pass it to Jeff and uh and so just to
maximize your plant's ability to develop
through the nutrient uptake in there and
that's the microbes just like John
saying yeah I mean the microbes are what
would take the organic materials and
convert them into an available substrate
that the plant can take up and I think
it's important for everyone to
understand the plant uses 17 nutrients
you can't put a terpene down in the soil
and expect that terpene to go into the
plant and come up out and do you crystal
that's not how it works
each plant cell produces what it needs
those trichomes are producing the turkey
and then making the crystal and putting
it outside so it's happening inside the
plant what you have to do is give the
plant as both these gentlemen have said
everything they possibly need in order
to make that little factory operate
properly
you can't have a boycott with China over
the tariff for phosphorus because you're
not going to end up with you know the
right kind of beans you know it's you've
got to make sure that you've got
everything in the soil that you need
it's just that simple and the other
thing after two other things I think
have to worry about you have to worry
about genetics I guess you'd say three
things genetics you have to worry
because if you don't have great genetics
you're not going to get you know great
turkeys the genetics of the plant which
I think you said when you said phenotype
you've got to have great sunlight you
gotta have great light if you don't have
the very best possible light than the
factory is not operating at its optimum
you know a thing and and then I guess
the other thing you have to have is
gentleness this that's too many people
who are doing hydroponic come in and all
shake the plants and do this is that you
got to be careful and gentle and then
the last thing I'll say is I think we've
got to go to a lot more research not on
a microbial level but on a cellular
level Menomonee insect UV light level
because it's pretty clear that UV light
is one of the things that causes these
trichomes to grow so you know let's
let's figure out what spectrum where it
is can we alter it can we change it is
there a special time to have one kind of
UV light over another you know all that
kind of stuff I think this isn't as
important as the microscopes anyway so
Colin this next one is for you go first
so establishing a commercial operation
can seem like a long-term project and it
is but at some point cultivators who
want to make the switch to probe
probiotic growing techniques have to
make the jump and get up to high yields
and repeatable results fast what advice
would you give to a professional
cultivator ready to make the switch to
living soils so they quickly achieve a
baseline of production that they can
refine over time
hmm so we're gonna refer this to write
to living soils instead of just
solutions what I think I'm just gonna
kind of talk to about how I'd respond to
that question I jump from a hydroponic
grow or let's just have the full extreme
a hydroponic full hydra or to our living
soil grower that's a heck of a job and I
don't think that's a quick path I think
they're stair stepping so understanding
the steps of moving that direction
having this angle this is what we want
to look like and these are the kind of
things that we need to start adopting
and practicing in our grow and getting
those results and stair stepping over to
that full organic living soil
cultivation is is what we're gonna do
you know I think that I've been this has
been a really fun week and kind of
reflecting on the last two weeks I was a
bunch of huge grows in California and
like the Salinas area really really high
throughput acre size greenhouses full
bore and then the last week I spent with
a bunch of growers and farms have been
humbled or is a lot smaller scale living
soil the hubell growing in all this type
of stuff so it's very fascinating to
take all that information and kind of
synthesize it and understand how does
you know the humble you go living soil
type of the grove get scaled into a
high-throughput manufacturing or
cultivation facility and I think that
isn't I don't think speed or is
realistic I think consistency and having
clear benchmarks and a clear goal of how
to get there is is the answer I think
part of that is understanding the
different components that get us there
you know there's this substrate
component there's this input based
nutrient component and then there's my
living soil components and we might not
get all the way there but I think I
would encourage facilities that are huge
in our commercial scale and are looking
at really high throughput I've talked to
him as we're getting from point A of
where they are right now cocoa and
synthetics to organics and microbials
and you know their inputs and living
soils they're gonna find the solutions
that work best for their current
practices and they can plug in and then
take the next step I think one of the
big steps I'll leave it up to the other
guys is this substrate one of the
facilities had that I visited big
facility had the synthetic cocoa the
normal stuff and then their biggest
challenge was organic substrate to grow
in and you wouldn't think this they're
adding the microbes are doing the things
right but what they're getting
challenged with is you know it's it's
it's really to do if you just kind of
acknowledge it is the drainage you know
if you serve to get this organic living
soil in a pod or in a container compacts
and does something in the hydrology is
very different then then a cocoa and
that was one of their biggest challenges
so understanding how to scale every
aspect of those inputs to get to the
single whatever kind of skill things so
they can achieve within what their
infrastructure is the goal and I don't
think that green house is gonna grow
like the growers and humble but I think
that they can achieve to the best of
their ability natural inputs to get
organic higher quality in product using
natural solutions and a lot of those are
probably commercial you know at the farm
in Humble the the girls are trying to
get all their inputs from their land you
know that's not gonna happen at these
commercial facilities so finding the
other sources for those inputs is key
well next so you said Hubel so that
means the they're cutting down trees
putting them into work yeah I've seen
this I built these things before yeah
it's kind of interesting you know
because the it depends on the tree you
select I mean you can select cedar bad
choice and it does not break down black
locust forget black locust hey no that
does not break down either but fir
breaks down pretty well and some people
actually grow and red wood sawdust and
like this substrate sir you're talking
about there's a lot of different
companies that use redwood sawdust as as
their base and they kind of do that for
a number of reasons but one of them is
because if coco coir all comes from one
or two sources and it's all treated with
calcium nitrate so you can never get an
organic certification on coco coir
unless you know you deal with a specific
company like well gold I think has an
organic cocoa core but I mean they're
they're a large company but in the
scheme of things that are very small and
they're also in Humboldt but that Huebel
stuff is kind of interesting I don't
know if anyone here has seen this kind
of you've seen this before it has seen
this raise your hand if you know that oh
wow that's way more people that caught
if you candy buddy wants to see these
drawn out I actually visited the same
farm that Colin went to at Moonlight
semi moon time medicinals and it's got
pictures of their 6500 square feet of
Google culture in Garberville and you
can see on the on the shaving fire
YouTube channel it's incredible yeah but
but back to you John so we're the
question we were working on was making
the switch from synthetics to probiotics
and what would you recommend for
somebody wanting to move in that
direction they're trying to take their
company in that direction oh because
there's they're straight well you know
you have to look at it as being indoor
greenhouse or outdoor you know you're
not going to do a huge ill structure
indoors you know some people might try
it I mean
you know I've seen investors buy
anything you know just say cannabis
enough times and you know they're
throwing money down Huebel even that
sounds great you know an organic oh I
gotta have this but you know in a
greenhouse it's it's more challenging
because you know you have to have the
height of course and then you have to
have the airflow too and they tend to
trap a lot these mounds to trap a lot of
humidity but outdoors you know you are
actually seeing it being used outdoors
more the to take the steps you know it's
kind of interesting this whole industry
is changing so fast I mean I was talking
to this chemical engineer and a PhD
chemist that we used to work for a
Novartis and they're there in Willets
and they clean oil for two to three
dollars a gram and you know these are
the first people that have actually seen
you know I I'm not going to talk about
their process because like I said I
would but they can do it and they can
end up with a clean product and now you
know that's a big issue because in
Salinas they're worried about all the
drift I don't know about you but when I
go down there I get a headache after two
days because you know they spray so much
it's a real challenge with the
surrounding agriculture in particular
yeah it really is so you know you don't
almost have to have as you know wet
walls to trap a lot of vapors coming
through and then of course that builds
humidity and you know your your question
though was how do you step from some
pure Rockville hydroponic setup to
ultimately having living soil and like
Collins and
you know if you wrote have you read
Jeff's books we realized that you know
that's that's not easy that's like
either a complete commitment and you
pretty much have to own the property at
that point because the overhead will
kill you but it's certainly worth it to
make that make think those different
steps and microbiology is with you every
one of those steps you know it's in
liquid form you you have mammoth pee you
have you know Jeff talks a lot about
compost teas I mean these are the things
that are going to help your plant along
and sustain your plant as you test out
these different substrates and
ultimately you know try to work with an
amended soil and you're gonna end up
foliar spraying quite a bit to to keep
the plant going so you know I I guess I
could probably lay out the answer by
describing a couple of different places
but I don't know how much time we have
this I mean I go on and on we're still
doing pretty well on time so okay you're
interesting dude so just you know let
arrive well you know so you weren't
humble and and humbled you know it's
always been a place of a lot of
experimentation
I haven't ranch there and Willow Creek
and you know I'm right in there with all
the experimenters and so I started
experimenting in 1978 when I was a kid
and my first cannabis crop so I've been
doing this for a minute you know it's
like it's makes 40 years and so I seen a
lot of growers succeed fail or just go
on and do other things and the
microbiology was always there and in
Humboldt in Mendocino you know they had
the advantage of being in there early
and then of course attracting all the
helicopters which pushed their
cultivation back into the edges of the
woods where all the microbiology was I
mean things coming like and you know
things coming off like in and you know
other plants interacting and
that's kind of where I got my education
was you know as a kid digging holes you
know using a flour sifter to add the
amendments and because I didn't want to
get you know hit over the head with the
shovel for doing the wrong thing and you
know gradually I got really good at it
and so I got to work in a lot of
different places and I realized I had to
go back to school to study microbiology
because there was more going on than
just fertilizers and and you know that
led me to actually looking at other
plants and other other plant compounds
and you know there's there are products
out there now that are you know almost
like homeopathic products so just small
amounts of certain other plants I mean
you know we have a whole biostimulant
line available commercially
that's plants from Southeast Asia and
North America and if coal plants from
Africa and they're harvested at
different times and they have different
you know compounds in them that
influence the plant in making brutes
growing blooming and then of course
boosting terpenes and that comes from
john jebin's and the whole skin Chadwick
who you know brought double digging to
this country from France and you're
giving the thumbs down on Chadwick
double D Grayman
oh let's go to Jeff now about double dig
I haven't heard this myself what do you
think yeah when you know the
microbiology is Ryan d double D right no
I actually learned that from my
girlfriend forced me to farm with draft
horses for several years
anything right right right I was with
it's an intimate trust me
you know working with draught horses but
but that's where I learned about the
degradation of the ozone layer and the
fact that fungi was being destroyed by
flipping the soil too deep because you
know in like nineteen idea was growing
quinoa and I thought you know ripping
the soil with a d7 cat was a great I
well you know I'm learning from old
farmers right so I thought you know that
this is how you do it out here and uh
you know Lassen County but then I
started look at more soil samples than I
realized under my scope I'm like wow
there's less fungi than if I just go to
the outside of the field where it's
undisturbed and you know then I realized
I had to do more fertilizer inputs and I
was like wow this is gonna cost me money
deeply ripping and then I looked around
I realized why they were all going out
of business and why I could have an
organic farm there because they couldn't
afford their own fertilizer inputs so he
just proved that in fact you can't go
commercial from right around about where
we are today I'm just you know so I
would start with something like key to
life or I used by our natural I get a
system that's in place that's got four
or five or six different inputs right
you've got a TV app five you how many do
you have I have and both of these can be
used and I don't mean to pick on these
companies there are other people out
here organic as well as inorganic so you
can use them in a hydro system and a
soil system so you're you're you're
starting to make that conversion you can
understand what's going on what's
working what's not working
and then you work on the substrate which
is what you mentioned and you convert it
into a soil substrate it can be done and
it's not that difficult if you've got
enough money you are a consultant they
do this all the time but you start with
a base somebody's system that you know
works and that's got some scientific
background as you can read on it and be
able to tweet and think about it and
then you say okay now I've got this
system and it's working now let's fool
around a little bit with mammoth pea
let's see if it makes a difference you
add that into the system and in every
one up frankly and I think you guys will
all agree they don't really even need to
add the stuff in anymore once you once
you get your system working and it's
alive that you've made the conversion so
yeah it does work it can be done and
it's easy to do for individual small
people less easy for bigger people but
if you use a system is based on you know
no worse either hydro which I consider
to be synthetic obviously and we're soil
grain then you can start anyway as far
as the inputs are concerned while you're
making that conversion you start looking
around for where there are good
endpoints of work who's not using what
ways perfect you can use that they don't
know that they're not using where's the
where's or grow or somebody's
inadvertently or stupidly throwing away
their soil after every grow there's ways
to do all this stuff and so that sets us
up for the graph for this next question
great so this time we'll go about
college on and then we'll finish up with
you Jeff so so this applies for both
home growers and patients and also for
commercial folks because we as we all
know you know you need to be choosy
about which products you you purchase
because some of these probiotic products
can be expensive what would you
recommend as being a few inputs that can
be grown either simply at home or you
know larger and
commercial-scale that can be grown and
had high quality inputs to a probiotic
soil in order to help keep costs down
that's it I wish we wouldn't have
started with me I probably need to
reflect on when it comes down to me as
chemistry and biochemistry you know at
the end of the day I think about
everything as a chemical profile a lot
of the papers I did in science I have a
background of a research scientist from
Colorado State University of PhD in
microbiology and that's what I was doing
for a long time it was really
fascinating not along with plant microbe
interactions with neutrons to a common
tree then as we all have a seed and the
PDK ratio in our bodies so do plants and
microbes and these are the things that
we're trying to fulfill we eat food
because we're trying to fulfill our
internal stoichiometry our nutrient
demands our nutrient needs that's what
we're trying to do with a fertility
program we're trying to deliver the
nutrients at the plant seems of the
congroo uninhibited and so thinking
about these inputs what you want to
think about them is that a biochemical
level a nutrient profile level and you
grow those things up you know for
example office is a really good example
as I like you where it actually
incorporates more nitrogen into its
biomass because of the way it fixes that
nitrogen and so forage alfalfa is a
really good example of a relatively
higher nitrogen input you want to think
about these aspects and you can actually
test for it or test other you know any
kind of input for its nutrient profile
and that's why you're selecting these
and so I think thinking about that
thinking about the scale that you're
growing and all these things going to
affect but generally what I would say is
if you don't know what's in it you can't
use it with precision any microbe the
function any of these inputs you have to
identify that once we
understand what it is we can use it with
confidence and precision and consistency
that's good I'd like you know you're
going back to the Humboldt example I
mean experiment right experiment in your
own gardens on your own farm and but
keep it control you know it's a lot of
times he will just broadcast completely
and then of course you know then they
they say oh well it didn't work that
well on this control but the control was
just the weakest plants don't select the
weakest plans for your control you know
you mentioned a number of things like
for instance if you're in a forested
area here's something you can do get
organic milk in small containers bury it
open it up
bury it up to the level of the milk so
it stays cool in the soil and see if
that turns to yogurt often that is good
lactobacillus that you're getting right
out of the soil and you can take that
and you can actually put that into a tea
if you want to test different milks
that's always a great one you know you
can get commercial milks and when you
actually get it close to your nose you
know why that's not really a food what's
your favorite milk um well since I'm in
Sonoma County its Straus Straus organic
milk it comes in glass bottles and the
neck is just perfect the perfect size
for pretty in microdopes it's like it's
like an old school and it's like an old
school of microbiology flasks yeah so
that's a good one and you know it just
shows people if there's something
already in the soil so we people want to
just wipe everything out you know and
this is the this is the sort of thing
that Jeff was saying before about double
digging you know double dating now is
the fall so you're you're breaking up
the lower soil but you're not taking it
so completely flipping it when it
started out they were flipping the soil
completely and they were wiping out all
the fungi
and you know what up the example I gave
was you know ripping the soil and of
course you're flipping it up and once
you go deeper than 10 inches and expose
it to full Sun is wiped out the fungi
and you've got to do something to
replace that and you know just going
back to the idea of T's I don't know if
anybody who uses you know how many
people here make T compost teas wow
that's a lot of people let's go how many
people here have heard of Elaine England
that's even better you know because I
was at that much it's already standing
but it's good it's good that you've
heard of Leaning minute because you know
she was one of the pioneers and sort of
bringing the whole tea culture thing
back and you know a lot of people took
it pretty far you know they started it
up to use wheatgrass and you know we
dress as zo tin in it and corn seed corn
and you know you get different enzymes
when you make a fermentation out of that
and then put that on the tea too so
there's a lot of things to experiment
and try oh now I'm drifting really far
from the question but we can bring it
right back so Jeff since you haven't hit
this one yet and maybe you could
actually name a couple of species of
plants that people who row so we're
talking about inputs that people can
grow either at home that they can put
into their plants that will be helpful
and save them some money or be done in a
commercial level below that maybe
they'll do you know a handful a rose so
so what are those planets well you can
get any number of carbon copy ously
lentils there's all sorts of red clover
white
and they're cold catalogs just full of
cover crops and all of them were fine
one of the things I think that really
you need to do though is as you say you
need to know whether the stuff you're
using works you know and that's that's
always that means testing so you you've
got to test people don't test got a test
for a decade you got a test for the
microbiology using in Lane England's
test I think you got a test using this
new bike micro bio meter so you know
what kind of biomass and you've got to
use these tests intelligently you got a
some of our expensive some of our cheap
you got to be able to meld them together
so that it works for you and you've got
to be able to to retest to see where
you're trending and to many of us don't
you get a fine-looking crop you know hey
I must be doing everything right you
don't know unless you test informations
power we've always been told that we
believe that and yet you know as growers
we don't test enough kind of test and I
think once you test then you start
putting in inputs because you want to
test to see whether it's working when
you buy a product you test to see what's
working if it doesn't work you don't buy
it again etc etc at night and you get
this but but it does start with growing
your own inputs if you can't grow your
own mycorrhizae fungi collect your own
mycorrhizal fungi from natural areas
around your property or rounder existing
grow your existing plants contain all
sorts of things that you want to use
again I always talk about you don't
throw away male plants you use the old
root system for both males and females
because that's put one unbelievable
extra days into the soil you want to
collect that kind of stuff if you see
somebody that's thrown away their male
plants
of course we all are that's why we're
here at this thing what else is out you
know in the sunshine getting cancer so I
think you know overall we think about
this Millis approach of having a living
soil because we want to reduce our input
I might keep what we have and continue
to use it but we have to understand in
that particular substrate plants are
always taking a wave long on the
substrate it's allocating resources said
it's gained mostly of all new terms from
the soil into its biomass when you're
harvesting that so it's going away so
there's never a complete regenerative in
agriculture that there's not some type
of replenishment and so there's you know
certain resources don't know how many
crows are out there using things like
soil testing you know nutrient analysis
where you know from one crop to the next
where your nutrients are substrates
maybe deplete so you can just add those
specific elements in with precision and
not add everything you know you're so I
might not need everything might need
some very few items or you know and
there's an example where even
phosphorous there's total phosphorous
that might be in your substrate but not
available so a de calais to maximize the
availability of that phosphorous you
don't need to add any phosphorous in in
cases a lot of micronutrients are clear
examples nitrogen is always a world
problem and maybe you need a source
every well if you use mammoth P you
don't have to use Mac's person in fact
you can't even buy phosphorus in long
food anymore that's one of the that's
one of the challenges with some
nutrients because it's been so abused in
agriculture in other places they banning
banning phosphorus in general
fertilizers unless you can prove that
your souls needed significantly so you
can actually justify the purchases so
you know it is a movement of using
biologicals it's not just us that are
out there preaching this all agriculture
segments are trying to understand
by all of you because it's a necessity
for our environment for the ecology and
for maximizing crop quality Neel quite
frankly they're sexy and yeah lots of
lots of applications that's right hey
you know what one thing that keeps - you
mentioned though is fully or spring and
there was an article that came out in
science magazine last week I think about
foliar spray compost tea I think it was
and what it did to the fertilizer
situation and the plant
it also been fully or sprayed and what
it did to be to the exudate mix in the
soil so we got a fall in the spring is
apparent to me something we need to
study we study the roots we're not
studying the foliage like the see I
think we're going to get timid gonna be
careful with your folio spray why
because this article says can you do
that above ground you are impacting what
happens below ground and just google
foliar spray fertilizer below ground
under news for this week or last week
you'll get the article organic garden
check out
not so so in finishing up I know this is
crazy because we got all this experience
but they only gave us 45 minutes so so
we we are complete here so the three
fellows will be here for questions
afterwards but for the moment we need to
start shifting for the next speaker so
thank you very much
[Music]