so Alan thank you very much for taking
some of your valuable time to talking
with me today here at 7 acres so the
reason I wanted to talk to you is
because yesterday during the tour a lot
of the gross staff were telling me about
how limited you were with the genetics
that you were able to choose to grow
from here in Canada for now right and
your role here at 7 acres is is is
moving the company towards this new
Jeanette in house genetics concerned
called Cambrian and and you're gonna be
having to help develop the palette of
colors that your growers get to grow
with so let's start by talking a little
bit about the the state of play right
now in Canada and when what your
artificial bureaucratic limitations are
to what you can actually grow right in
Canada we are limited by what's legally
available we have a set of conditions
where we have to be able to buy our
genetics from an already licensed
producer so when Daisy Rose started
there wasn't a reservoir of
blackmarket interior became weightless
and we had to go looking for white
material so to speak and they were a
very small number of producers typically
overseas that we could get these scenes
from so everybody in Canada is basically
tapped into the same reservoir of
genetics and we've been trying to
optimize that ever since so just to give
folks an idea of how much you have
access to that's white that you know
meaning like legally accessible how many
different chemo bars do you think ever
choose from tens of hundreds of so again
it's a very limited whereas the other
markets have again hundreds of strains
that they can choose from we are we are
down to tens it's very very limited and
and that really commoditized is the
product right if all of the LPS in
Canada are picking from this very small
candy bowl there's a lot of similarity
in products right yeah so you have you
have to really differentiate yourself on
the quality of the material because
everybody like you're saying is
generating roughly the same sort of
cultivars right on so so that of course
creates a situation where you want to
start breeding more in-house so that in
your role you can help the LPS that are
involved with seven acres and some
Freeman is the family be able to widen
their their their their choices for
plants to grow and so would you tell me
a little bit about Cambrian and how that
is swarming sure yeah like a medium is
looking at just that it's that we're
looking at optimizing the genetics that
are available for use for licensed
producers well at the same time
optimizing the
environmental conditions we're trying to
optimize both the genetics and the
growing conditions for each of the
different situations what we're going to
be doing is we've gotten access to a
fairly large pool of genetics that we've
been working on curating and we're going
to be going through and final mining it
initially and selecting out strains and
then getting into more typical breeding
programs
phyto mining that's a new word for me I
like that that's great so this this this
this larger pool so is there going to be
a window where you can bring in new
genetics and so you'll be able to work
with those not just the small key there
is a window that's opening up in the
legislation that we can bring in
material and we so you're probably at
the point right now where you are you're
scanning the globe for the stuff you're
most excited and breed with and putting
it all on deck to bring it in during the
wind yes we are going to have a very
full shop so so what what what kind of
actions are you taking to identify those
genetics around the world I'm assuming
that you're talking to lots of breeders
and lots of people who've been doing
this in the heritage years yes yes and
what again that we're going through and
again taking advantage of what's
available and again we're not just
looking at what's happening and what's
going to fit today we're looking at it
as a very long term play is that
when we're looking at the cold furs were
bringing in that
be using the lottery
seven acres were regulating full-scale
large production but also looking at the
the next phase of the cannabis markets -
like optimizing for what's going to be
happening two years three years five
years down the line you know in the in
the states we've had a lot of challenges
with with people taking chemo bars that
they love outdoors and bringing them
indoors or as similarly people taking
chemo bars they love indoors and
bringing them outdoors and and you know
I live on Vashon Island in the Pacific
Northwest
and we constantly have challenges
because we love like a lot of the sexy
genetics here in California but a lot of
that outdoor stuff doesn't work when you
bring it and you do it on the Pacific
Northwest island where it starts to rain
the first week of October so for you you
are choosing genetics for a very
particular indoor environment that that
that also has glass up top so you are
also getting Sun so almost light
assisted greenhouse really feel entirely
greenhouse what are you looking for
what's your what's your what's your hit
list of what you're looking for in
genetics that you want to bring in that
you can that you can work you know at
seven acres we have a very specific
clone to dog we have a when we pump
through a lot of harvest in one
greenhouse and to do that sort of
scheduling on this sort of scale we have
to have plants that come to mature
maturation in a very set period of time
there are some very exciting things out
there that take 14 weeks to mature we
have a very set period of time in that
14 weeks just doesn't work for us so the
first thing when we're looking at
specifically here
is the timeframe for maturation within
that though one thing that I'm really
excited by is looking at how we can
adjust the environment the neat thing
with greenhouses is everything's up for
grabs
if you want more light you put more
light in if you want more water you put
water with whereas Northwest if it rains
today you get wet yeah there's nothing
you can do about it in the greenhouse
you can make it rain whenever you want
and to say you know if that one thing
I'm really excited by it's looking at
that like 14 week strain what can we do
with the environment to get it down to
fit our our timeline how can we change
the temperature regime how can we change
the light to make these ones that
otherwise wouldn't be fitting in our
system fit so it's a really
hybridization of the genetics and the
production that makes them work here
that's interesting you I when I was
listening your answer I thought I knew
where you were going that you were
you're going to take these 14 weekers
and then cross them too much shorter
finishers and then you end up you know
somewhere in the middle and then you
find a phyno in there that's especially
short and there you go and there's
probably going to be some of that but
the idea that you want to coax the bloom
cycle to shorten by the environment that
would that was a surprise so that must
involve a lot of data collection yeah do
you explain that a little bit data is
your friend that's again one of the
things I was very excited when I started
it was just the how rigorous they keep
track of numbers here both going ahead
like looking at well what happened if we
did this but looking at the records how
you can adjust and see what's happening
with the various crops you know when
you're saying about you know looking at
adjusting the genetics to fit that is a
long term but because cannabis is really
a new crop there's so much that we can
learn with what we already have before
we have to get in there and start
adjusting the genetics I always use the
example of the Agricultural Revolution
with time money and genetics and
production they've been able to almost
double production every 10 15 years for
corn for the last 30 40 years with
cannabis because it was illicit for so
long it hasn't been able to take
advantage of that now in the opportunity
we have we can that we can do catch-up
we can apply all we know about genetics
all we know about production to get
cannabis up to the level of like other
agricultural crops in a very short
period of time you know it's it's
interesting because you say that that
cannabis is a new crop right and I know
that like there's a whole bunch of
heritage growers that a cringe when you
hear this because you know people are
going back to you know Revolutionary era
hemp and then and then the the cannabis
landraces coming in during the 70s and
80s from you know Thailand Mexico and
all that and then and then you know
modern-day the u.s. is producing some of
the the best genetics that have ever
been in cannabis and we've all been
doing this from the start and yet we
have not had access to the materials
that you've had you know with
ornamentals and other types of plants
for generations right suddenly we've got
we've got analytics and we don't have to
hide so we can spread out our space and
we can have multiple grow rooms and and
then all of this fantastic technology to
take data about the plants at its grows
so you know we all get that it's like a
great brave new world right are you
finding that the the pace of development
and I'm not talking about GMO here we're
talking about traditional hybridization
how much more quickly do you think that
that that development of cycle increases
now that you've got
access to these types of materials yeah
there's all the sudden we can take
advantage of everything and everybody
know for years it was an evil just to
step back what you're saying about the
heritage side of it is one of the
standards we always use is can we scale
produce what that guy and without one or
two plants can do alone so we're still
using the her acute desire as our
threshold and to do it at scale of that
quality and quantity is really the thing
so so recognizing the great work that
everybody's done so far but being able
to institutionalize it to make it a
production component so the second one
is is that we were saying about you know
using the what making it jump ahead
there's all the sudden we can go to
university and say you've got a genetics
department can we buy some of your
professors time to work on this project
can we work with you on these sort of
things we can go to a major financial
institute in this aching can we work out
a relationship where you can help us
fund this sort of work it's it's really
the it's been a slow burn like a nice
warm coal fire yeah we're throwing
gasoline on it I find it interesting
because I like that you gave the nod to
the quality of bosch small batch craft
artisan flours and that your benchmark
is to try to meet that fidelity but then
also instead of having it in you know 25
plants that are all you know hand taken
care of in somebody's basement you're
doing these huge grow rooms of it at
that point the analytics and the
automation that you can fine-tune you
know become necessary because it was
interesting when I did the tour
yesterday I kept on seeing all these
really thoughtful automated solutions
and we had a little conversation with
the staff about the the classic phrase
the best fertilizer is the shadow of the
farmer
and my question was with all this
automation it's less time that the
individual growers need to spend with
each plant and and then and then the
Madi one of your one of your lis growers
he's all like he says but we're always
looking for ways to add additional touch
yes and and I didn't really understand
that and he explained to me that it's
about we want to automate so all the
plants are getting the same love which
frees up his time to spend more time
with the individuated place and see what
else they need yeah
and I thought that was pretty elegant
because I'm pretty staunch that that we
don't hand watering his fan is is a
great thing because you spend a little
bit of time with each plant and but then
when I see it rolled out at scale we're
okay they're automatically all gonna get
watered the same and treated the same
and he did the same in the same airflow
and these fantastic air Sox that are
underneath the tables making the the
room very uniform and that frees up the
staff to give other sorts of care and I
was surprisingly convinced right I'm not
that's not you you know scaling is not
usually where I come down but the proof
was in the pudding the plants looked
fantastic they were thriving there was
zero pest pressure and and they smelled
good and then you know afterwards I got
to try it and they tasted fantastic as
well so bringing this all the way back
to your idea of breeding for does these
environments is that the target
environment that you're breeding for and
what does that what kind of freedoms
that does that allow you when you're
breeding for than that yeah cozy
environment is the take it yes that's
that's one of the environments like we
are looking at this big picture like we
are looking at this production
greenhouse at scale and we're also
looking at the next phase which will be
might be growing in fields here no so we
are looking at the whole spectrum we're
starting with the greenhouse because
that's where we're from and that's what
we know what we're also looking at the
big picture but the the freedom it's
just like you're saying is that we can
get to the point where every bud is
exactly like the other one and we know
everybody knows that you know we up and
down the same plant the quality changes
from one plant to the next quality
changes and if you're really talking
about that premium quality product the
guy who buys it wants that the person
who buys it wants to know that they are
getting the exact same thing every time
if this time it's a dud and next thing
that's a head sort of thing you know
you're going to be cautious but if you
know exactly what you're getting each
time and that's where we can actually
start looking at saying well what do we
want the quality the consumer what does
the consumer want rather than saying
what we're going to give them what do
they want from us we can start looking
at environments that changed the Turcan
weight profiles is that if you give the
water at this time of day what does it
do to the lemon levels if you give this
quality of life what does it do the
Piney and all those sort of fine-tuning
you versus commented on the the
automation and that automation sounds
like you're dehumanizing it I look at it
as a palette of like painting is that if
you have to mix every paint color and
set them up yourself you're going to be
spending all your time doing that you're
doing any of the artwork if the computer
supplies all the different colors that
you can add and change you can actually
do some pretty fantastic painting with
that palette the changing of light
quality quantity can all do that so to
maximize the potential of all the
genetics we develop we can optimize the
the environment to fit that particular
plant
I like that example that's great so so I
know that you are busy building a
cambium so I'll let you go but thank you
very much for your time I appreciate it
all right thanks a lot
Thanks