um it is common for folks though to
socialize and medicate outside
afterwards so if you want to hang out
you know you know Jeff's going to give
the demo and then we're going to you
know we'll give away the raffle stuff
and then you know people kind of hang
out and mingle and then puff outside and
then I hear that there's quite a party
down on the dock and on the boat
afterwards
so the um the the fairy workers actually
tell me that they they actually know
about us and about
our and it's cool anyway so we've got a
reputation all right it's a good
reputation yeah it's a really good
reputation nobody's bummed out with us
so so so tonight's demo is from Jeff
Church also known globally as cannabis
Reverend Jeff has mastered every modern
extraction technique and most of the
ancient ones he has traveled the world
to learn uh both exotic techniques as
well as spread modern techniques from
the United States last year he went to
spannabis in Spain and turned on all
sorts of the world famous canvas Legends
onto rosin oil and gave rosin Dabs at
the Cannabis Museum there in Spain he is
a patient advocate from way back uh he
has been on the front he has been in
front of the laws helping people helping
humans get relief since the very early
days here here in Washington Jeff is
presently an extractor at 502 processor
puff and farms and he continues to
consult everywhere as well um he and his
wife have also just welcomed their
second child into the world too so
that's a
win so so Jeff is absolutely one of my
mentors but even more so I'm grateful to
be able to call him a friend it is very
much my honor to present to you Jeff
Church
thank you for that warm introduction
Shango that was wonderful so uh I'm glad
that everybody came out here tonight
it's a wonderful wonderful crowd for a
really great method of Hashi extraction
so tonight we're talking about toble
hash and it's pretty simple it's ice
water and agitation that's pretty much
it beyond that you have screens that
filter out different sizes of particles
so you'll have uh your plant material in
one uh and then you'll have all of your
valuable resins on on other sizes so it
takes a little while uh for the Cannabis
to rehydrate uh and so I'm going to dump
that into the water right now I've got a
bucket over here 5 gallon bucket uh
filled up you know a little over halfway
uh and I've got some ice in there
there's been cooling the water um this
is a 133 G of what was the strange
change go uh California Girls California
Girls seeds from seeds are from Humble
yeah some Vashon outdoor uh cannabis
right here so it's this is just little
uh tiny popcorn buds uh so we'll toss it
on in the
water and then uh so I've iced this
water previously but I'm also going to
throw some more ice on the top of it so
it kind of makes a sandwich of ice
cannabis and more ice on the
then I'll add a little bit more water
here to the top just to make sure that
all of the Cannabis is uh exposed to
this cold cold
water all right so ideally I like to let
this soak for up to 30 minutes uh to to
rehydrate the material especially if
it's uh dry material um you can also run
fresh material that's frozen uh they
call it fresh Frozen um and uh it it
makes a really nice bubble hash but it's
not something that you really need to
rehydrate so you kind of toss it in
there everything's cold out of the
freezer you put it into the bucket uh
and start going um but so tonight I'm
going to just do this dry uh dry
material method so what what you do is
uh you've got several different uh sizes
of bags um the smallest one that that we
have which is going to go in first is a
25 micron bag and so it's a it's pretty
simple it's a 25 micron mesh on some
kind of a uh you know jacket type
material yeah canvas type material and
uh so just set these bags in here and
so I like to do all of my mixing in one
bucket uh rather than inside of the bags
uh you know kind of the first methods
that people were doing they were mixing
inside of the bags um but I found that
it actually puts some wear and tear on
the bags uh so that's not really
something that you want to do if you
want to save your your uh your bags give
them as long of life as possible these
bags in particular are quite old they
they've been being used for about 10
years now so yeah so so they will last
quite well um I just got these back from
a friend of mine that I had loaned them
to um you wash them in the machine
washable or do you yeah so you you can
definitely wash them in the machine I
would say that uh you know you want to
save that uh for doing that every once
in a while not with every run what I
like to do with the bags is is I'll take
them uh after they're done
and rinse all of the uh the material out
of them if there's any resin stuck to
the screens I'll take some alcohol and
and use some alcohol to free the resins
off the screens and give it another uh
another soak um as well with some
alcohol and then I put it into a bucket
of water and just kind of uh massage
them around and get get the handh yeah
give it a little hand wash so it's
really gentle um but you can also um you
can also put them into the washing
machine and i' I put you know a cup of
vinegar in there with them and that kind
of gets any kind of musty smell that
they might have it kind of cuts that
down a bit um and then do make sure you
do an extra rinse on them because you
don't want to have that vinegar flavor
into you know if they still smell like
vinegar that's not a good thing um so
yeah so the first the first bag was a 25
micron bag the second bag is a 45 Micron
bag and so these sizes uh as they get
larger um that's also a larger ho size
of the screen so um so then we'll move
on to a 73 Micron
bag do you worry at all about like that
contamination or kind of Ms or funguses
from reing
bags
wash yeah definitely definitely and you
know we've actually run into some some
issues uh in the medical Market uh
making products um you know we we had uh
and we really don't know where the
contamination came from uh but we had
some samples that tested positive for
ecoli so yeah so they never made it out
to uh to patients to to smoke we just
destroyed the material um but yeah it's
definitely a concern there's bacteria
and and molds and and such they will
grow row on the material on on the bag
material so um you
know yeah so so
like at your I2 yes we do run we do run
these bags at i502 and you know we're
just very careful to keep them very
clean you know as soon as you're done uh
doing doing the wash you want to make
sure that you wash your bags as
well water or just regular tap water
just regular tap actually well water
where I'm at but but it has really low
parts per
million in it and it's it's very clean
water um a lot of people do use RO water
though that's definitely reverse osmosis
water is is a popular thing people will
will make their ice cubes out of reverse
osmosis water and um you know I haven't
really gone to to that length um I I I
have um used in the medical side we had
an ice machine that we were using uh and
so we we hooked up carbon filters to
that uh and that was good enough for us
to to have uh you know have some some
good clean clean water but tonight we're
just using bag
dice so and and you know i' I've never
really been too terribly worried about
it for my own consumption uh bacteria
and things like that but it's definitely
a concern for the 502 Market because
your products are going to fail uh
microbial testing and you're going to
have lots that you have to destroy you
know um or I guess you can technically
extract those with other methods but you
know then you're extracting whatever the
molds and bacterias are along with it um
so these first three bags that I put in
here the 25 micron bag the 45 Micron bag
and the 73 Micron bag or where you
generally get uh your hashes um this
next bag that I just slipped in here is
160 Micron bag um and this one is is
your very largest uh and heads and plant
material so you'll you'll get sometimes
you you'll get like a greenish uh
material that comes out of this um the
190 Micron bag I have seen only a couple
times anything that you really want to
smoke come out of this and that's from a
plant that has extremely large resin
heads um but usually it's just kind of
the green Duff it's it's like an extra
catch bag uh for the plant
material flip those in
there and then finally this blue bag is
What's called the work bag uh you know
that's that's what you know the original
name for it was the work bag I don't do
any of the work in there anymore like I
said because it'll break up the bag um
but this is a 220 Micron bag uh right
here um they used to sell a 250 Micron
bag which I have one of and I rarely use
uh that that they kind of said was for
commercial production so that you can
make sure that you're getting the most
resin out uh of the pl material fastest
um the 220 Micron bag might hold back a
little bit of resin it might get clogged
um a little bit so doing successive
washes will really help you get it out
but um you know I the 250 Micron I kind
of just moved away from that so so
that's the B right there uh plant
material will go in this in this bucket
here
um then we have this right here question
yes are the colors in the number
standard yes they are yeah so the purple
is going to be the 25 micron always the
45 Micron is white uh the 73 Micron is
yellow um there is a 120 Micron I'm just
going to grab this as a prop bubble man
was kind enough to send down a whole set
so this is the coveted door priz right
here whoy person is that gets them um
but so there's an orange color and this
is 120 Micron I'm not using it tonight
but it's definitely something that uh
I've used in the past and uh it will be
an extra filter above your 73 Micron
that can lead to slightly uh more pure
product on your 73 Micron um but you
know for for the purposes of the
demonstration tonight it's not really
necessary to splice it out too terribly
much um there's also one that I forgot
there's a 90 Micron bag which goes right
above your 73 and it does the same sort
of a thing uh kind of splitting the
Micron size up uh so that you can have a
tighter fraction of the resin heads uh
in in size um and then let's see is
there any other one that I'm forgetting
no uh and then you know the 160 Micron
red green for 190 uh and blue is the uh
work bag um the 220 so they're they're
always the same at least in the bubble
bag brand uh there's lots of other
brands out there U but bubble man was
the first one in North America to
provide bubble bags and so I've been
using these bags for years and years
yeah since uh 2001 I think was the first
time I got to set of bubble B
so yeah and they actually they offer um
two different kinds of bags they have
this standard set here that I'm using
and then they also have the bubble bag
light set which is a slightly cheaper
material um I guess you know not as
heavy duty um and they don't carry a
warranty like these ones do these ones
are lifetime warranty if you ever have
anything that goes wrong with them any
one of the bags they'll send you a new
bag no problem so and they've been
really good about about honoring that
even with the much larger sets you know
it's it's been no problem to get
reimburse or get a new a new bag sent
down so cool um so yeah the the one
other screen that you have uh is this
and this is a 25 micron uh pressing
screen they call it a blotting screen
it's a pressing screen and uh basically
you the idea is you put your hashish on
here and then you're able to
squeeze out a little bit of the excess
water and so that's that's kind of what
this is for what we've kind of move
towards uh in canas extraction is doing
rosin right and so this right here was
the very first screen at least that I
know of uh that was used for U making
rosin and so you put your hashish in
here and and you fold it over then you
you uh with heat and pressure squeeze it
and the hashes extrudes out of it so you
know I was actually down in Oakland uh
with a friend of mine uh uh space and he
and I were sitting around saying hey you
know how are we going to make this rosin
no nobody had really put out there in
social media world how to filter your
rosin um and so we were saying oh jeez
you know really what we need is a filter
because all this material is just kind
of running here and there a to get a
little bit of high quality oil out of it
but most of it's contaminated with the
rest of the hash so um I said you know
hey we we need a filter and my friend
Spacey said hey I've got a filter I've
got a 25 micron filter let's do this and
so that it was uh the method was born
rosin right there so um so yeah some of
the other tools that that we use um I
like to dry on parchment paper um
parchment paper seems to
be kind of the best method for you know
home uh home use at least um and then on
cardboard uh and so then the cardboard
acts as as a desk and it draws out the
the moisture from from the hashish uh
that that basically your paper will get
wet it'll draw the moisture out as well
and then that draws it away again so
it's kind of a way to mitigate U having
too moist a pases CU you know as we were
discussing earlier there's big issues
with M microbes uh as as far as I know
yeah go
ahead would there be any point in
setting that on on a low heat Source you
would not want to apply heat to it
actually cold is is better um heat will
heat the resin and it'll melt and any uh
there's a possibility that there's going
to be water in there if it hasn't dried
all the way and that water will kind of
get clogged in inside of the resin it'll
it'll lead to more mold so it's it's
actually better to not have it in a hot
hot area you don't want in direct
sunlight or anything like that so you
know just you know uh yeah
um but yeah so so the microbial issue is
definitely definitely a big thing as as
far as I know it's it's about 8 hours
that uh it takes for microbes uh to
start growing after water has been
introduced to them uh so in the drying
process there's going to be some amount
of microbes and of bacteria um that is
going to bloom uh and so you want to
really use material that doesn't have
microbes in large amounts you want to
kind of keep that as uh you know it's
just not advisable to to run material um
molding
material material like powdering Milo or
mices and such things of that that
nature you know I mean it's it's always
best to use the highest quality input
that you can it's going to give you the
highest quality output um so but uh but
for you know the 502 World um what what
we kind of come up with now is a freeze
dryer and so if you take your material
and it goes right into the freezer uh
and it's frozen then you pop it into the
freeze dryer um you're able to keep the
material
um both you're you're able to get less
oxidation with the material so it's it's
going to stay a much lighter color which
is more uh appealing to the consumer um
and you're also going to have this
microbial issue is basically beaten
right because you don't give it the
chance to bloom the the microbes aren't
going to bloom in the freezer the freeze
dryer is going to sublimate the water
away from the material uh and so you're
going to end up with a dry Sandy product
that hasn't had the chance to kind of
Clump together and and and get you know
globed together because it stays all dry
the resin heads are rock hard when
they're cold uh so it's able to kind of
dry everything um and also put freezing
it will expand in water that's in there
so it actually kind of moves the resin
heads away from each other just a slight
bit um so that it's able to uh dry
inside of the Patty that you put into
the freeze dryer so I really recommend
that I think that the freeze dryer is
the the best method for drying bubble
hash that we've we've come up with yet
so um but yeah it progressed I mean when
I first started making bubble hash there
wasn't even a recommendation to use
cardboard um and so it was like you know
use like a paper plate or use a plate
itself you know I mean it was really
really you know there wasn't much out
there for information and then uh then
we we came up with the cardboard uh
cardboards seem to work great except for
with the kind of the stickier resins
they would get stuck to the cardboard
you get pieces of paper that came out of
it so that's kind of not the best way
parchment when that that idea came
around really kind of won me over for
sure because uh you're able to get the
material off of the parchment without
having uh much of the parchment come off
hopefully none of the parchment coming
off um Jeff yes did it not work to
decarb it before it
started well if you decarbed it um most
likely the resin heads would
melt so they would be unaccessible by
the water extraction method yeah so they
would
definitely I would say unless you're
doing a really long wa it's big a m i um
so um so yeah so the rest of the tools
here that I have um got pressing screen
the parchment uh this you know this was
just kind of a banker's box lid uh and
it's just nice for transportation so if
you're going to make it somewhere and
move it somewhere else it's nice to have
that um I usually just cut up a a
cardboard box at home and then tape a
piece of parchment to it but this seems
to be a nice method um I like to use a
Civ uh to break up the the bubble hash
so that it can dry properly so uh you'll
put all of your your bubble hash in here
and then take a silicone spatula and
kind of move it around and and it'll uh
it'll come through the Sie uh and you
can spread it out kind of evenly on this
this cardboard and then I use just a
dish brush uh to kind of clean up uh any
excess uh bubble that gets stuck to this
tool so that you don't lose a whole
bunch there um you're able to get back
and then uh you know just a plastic card
is something that's nice to to move out
the bubble hash if if it's in too thick
of a pile if if when you're working with
your Sie too much of it fell in one area
you can kind of move it around and uh
spread that out um and then a spoon to
get it out of the bags and so I've used
all kinds of different tools um there's
a lot of other great tools but some
since we're just doing this for home use
figured this be a great thing CU
everybody has one of
these yeah
so all
right got a few more minutes here any
other questions that people have at the
moment tell us about the different types
of hash and why you would use one versus
another so the different extraction
methods that that are out there okay
well um you know we've got uh this
bubble hash uh it's definitely a great
method it's a nonsolvent method although
water is technically a solvent there are
Turin that are water soluble that are
being extracted but uh it's it's kind of
the it it's the least of a solvent uh of
all of the methods out there um then
there's dry sift so that would be using
screens uh and kind of doing a similar
thing uh but without water right so
that's that's another method dry sift is
is really nice kind of gives you the um
unadulterated or
un uh it's it has the least refinement I
guess of all the processes out there um
I've done a lot of uh CO2 extraction as
well but that takes really expensive
Machinery uh and so that's not really a
home method um and that's that's a great
solvent it's you know something that's a
fairly green solvent a lot of the CO2 is
just waste uh from industry that's
recaptured and so that's definitely a a
nice way to to use that um butane
extraction propane you know all of those
things are are interesting what lemine
yeah uh and and you know those those
hydrocarbon solvents uh are great for
getting the canabo content out of the
material economically right so it's not
very expensive for a setup as compared
to a CO2 extractor um that the time that
it takes to do the extraction is much
reduced uh compared to a CO2 extractor
um but you know each of these solvents
has a specific uh capacity for
extracting the constituents so certain
things are going to be
extracted uh with your different
solvents that wouldn't necessarily be
extracted in the same way uh from other
solvents would it be good to assume that
if you're using ethanol extraction
you're taking all the trines in their
natural form with you yeah so that that
was actually the very next one that I
was going to get to so uh ethanol is a
great uh extraction medium um it has the
disadvantage that when you're going to
uh remove the ethanol uh from from the
extract you're also going to remove a
lot of the Turin uh especially the the
most volatile Turin those are going to
just hop on over with the alcohol and
you're going to end up with a turpine
INF infused alcohol well I wor about
that because alcohol is a is a hydropic
rather than hydrob so it's it's going to
when they're together it's going to hold
a certain amount of water with it mhm
yeah it's uh you know that's that's
definitely true and and also uh it it
will extract the the water content of
the plant material as well so uh but
it's definitely a great uh great
extraction method um that's that's
really good for RSO and such yes sir um
does ambient room temperature have any
play on um like the manipulation of the
the half she after being extracted or
even during extraction yeah so you know
with bubble hash uh or dry sift um you
really want to have uh the coldest
environment possible that's that's the
best way to go about it you're you're
doing this extraction in cold because
the resin heads hardened up uh they will
also free themselves from the plant
material a lot easier when they are hard
uh so they just Shear off really easy
they just crack like ice would crack
right um so you know I I would
definitely recommend that if you're
going to do bubble hash on any kind of
commercial scale you want to have a cold
room so you know either a walk-in
freezer uh that you're working in or
having um a room that you've outfitted
with a u uh an air conditioner that
you've overclocked there's a really cool
Gadget it's called a a
coolbot uh and so you you hook this in
there and and and basically it takes any
air conditioner and tricks it um it it
it
will have a little heater uh that heats
up by the temperature sensor so that the
air conditioner thinks that it's not as
cold as it actually is and then it has
another sensor that that reads the
outtake of the condenser so that it
knows when the condenser is going to ice
over so it'll basically make sure that
you're not going to destroy your
equipment but at the same time it
overclocks it makes it so you can get it
down to I think it's uh in the high 30s
is is what you can get with one of those
but but you know I I see a lot of people
set their rooms at 55 that's a common um
extraction temperature so um and doing
doing everything you know the moment
that I that I pull the hashish out of
the bags it's warming up and so by the
time I get it into this uh to this C if
I don't work fast enough and it's a
really gooey strain it's just going to
gum up all over this the SI and and
become a problem so um you want to work
fast when when you're doing that that's
kind of what what we've always done and
then you know now the new method is cold
rooms you know and then you don't have
to be as stressed about how fast you're
doing everything so yeah so you only
make cash in a month with
are that's definitely a a good way to do
it um and it happens to be when uh the
Harvest is in usually so traditionally I
I've made the bulk of the hashes in the
last month of the year and you know
January and February as well so those
are kind of you know December January
February are really really great months
for making
hashes yes sir so I'm sorry I don't want
to like
tear off like too advance of
topic but I'll foret if I don't and ask
you so um a lot of the people that uh
that I see that make hash I'm pretty
good on Instagram and stuff these guys
have a tendency to uh allow the bubble
to dry in patties for up to let's call
it 8 to 12 hours or or even longer in
cold rooms or refrigerators or something
to keep my crow grow down and then they
will either Sid or uh micr plane right
and um so my question to you is it
sounds like you're at least in this
particular uh lesson you're an advocate
of taking that bubble quickly going
through the process very quickly getting
it out there spread out so that it can
dry very quickly uh not or waiting that
time and such and I'm just wondering
from your point of view um do any of the
methods that I'm talking about
previously that did they hold any kind
of water uh creating a more palatable
product or something that maybe more
melty or whatever you know consumer Happ
right so so I would say that that
there's definitely advantages to doing
the cold cure right putting putting your
hashish
into a cold refrigerator or a you know
freezer um as well uh before you would
microplane it um if you're going to be
using the Civ I don't really see as much
advantage of that because you're going
to have
uh it's going to be so cold that it's
going to harden it if you put it into
the freezer um that that it's kind of
going to be hard to get through the SI
but the microplane is definitely a nice
way to go for um really sticky material
so if it's going to come out of your
bags and it's going to be really really
sticky um you're going to want to use a
microplane and that'll actually rupture
a lot of the heads uh when you're doing
the the microplaning but uh and it could
lead to a little bit of tpine loss but
if you've got a really really sticky
product anyways you're going to have a
high tpine content in there as well so
that lead to a more greased Out product
even after it's drive right right yeah
yeah definitely definitely but you know
the resin heads are are all created
differently there's you know there's
different amounts of uh of kind of
liquefiable contents I guess is what we
could say so the canono and the tpin are
are really liquefiable contents of of it
there's there's also wax uh there's
there's a membrane there's a cuticle and
so some of those uh constituents that
are in in the Rosen head don't really
melt so on some strains you're going to
have you know pure pure resin where you
don't really see any other contamination
when you look under a microscope but
it's not as melty when you smoke it uh
just because of the nature of the
genetics right um and then other strains
um are going to be super super melty uh
and and hard to deal with when you're
when you're processing so that's those
types of strains really want to do in
the cold room uh doing a cold cure is
definitely a good way to go but I think
that nowadays if if you're going to go
through the trouble of making that cold
room get a freeze dryer you know if
you're going to be working with that
type of material uh because it's you're
not going to have to do all this cold
curing uh you're not going to to do the
microplaning so you can actually take
this this material that previously with
other methods you would have to
microplane and instead you do the freeze
dryer and it comes out dry uh like a ke
um now when you're pulling that material
out of the freeze dryer it's frozen
right so if you're not in a cold
environment you're going to have
condensation right so it's going to
bring water from the atmosphere and put
it right back onto your hashish so you
definitely want want to have uh an
environment that you're doing it in
that's cold if you're going to be
pulling it out of the freeze dryer so
yeah go would you share why it's called
bubble hash bubble hash well U it's
bubble hash because of the bubbles that
form when you smoke it so um yeah so so
the the the more pure that it is uh the
more boiling effect that you're going to
have when it smokes so just like a dab
boil s when you when you drop it on the
dad BR it's the same sort of a thing uh
they're really you know when bubble
hatch first came around they really
wasn't um as much oil and there wasn't
you know as much of that going on this
is really a pure pure method uh of
extraction so that that really explained
what the product was itself that's being
produced so can you go ahead and tell us
about the star chart yeah definitely
definitely um so so there's a my good
friend space down in Oakland um who I
worked with on on developing the you
know Rosen screen method um him and his
Partners down there at the bizaar which
was a um measure Z Club in Oakland so
measure Z Club is actually a place where
you're allowed to consume and sell
cannabis in the city of Oakland will
kind of turn their head the other way
and and and not worry about you because
they have a law that was passed in
Oakland measure Z which made it the
lowest enforceable priority for adult
consumption and sales in a private
setting so as long as you're not doing
it out in public then it's you
know yeah yeah yeah so um so they they
decided that they really needed to have
a hashish rating system uh because you
know back then it was really
you know all hash was kind of like 20 or
$25 a grand retail there wasn't really
too much difference in price even though
the quality could be drastically
different right so they came up with
this star rating system it's a one
through six star rating system uh and so
it starts off with one star being the
lowest uh and that's basically Kei
that's something that you really
couldn't uh press very easily with with
just you know the the and pressure from
your hand uh you couldn't really press
it into a Patty it just kind of crumbles
so that's that's one star two star is
something that you press together um and
then when and it'll hold and when you
smoke it on a screen it has a slight
milk to it it'll kind of have the sheen
where you can kind of tell that the oils
have done something but it's not really
boiling it's not really bubbling right
um then three star uh it'll go from
whatever shape you you put it in uh and
it'll melt into kind of a pile right so
like a it'll make like a Hast stack kind
of a pile out of whatever you put onto
the screen and it'll boil up into that
pile um a fourstar will melt uh down
into a puddle so it'll be kind of a
boiling puddle with contaminant so uh
nonm uh
constituents all over in that in that
puddle um and it'll kind of have like a
there'll be like a a flat a flat chunk
of contaminant after it stops melting um
five star uh it'll melt down into the
puddle and it'll actually boil the
contaminant out to the edges of the
screen if you these are all um being
rated on a screen because it's kind of
the easiest way to view uh what's what's
actually happening with the milk um so
the contaminant will get pushed out and
it'll boil a big clear Dome uh so it's
it's a a big bubble uh that that has no
contaminant in it except for on the very
edges of it and it actually shows uh the
screen so you'll have like bare spot in
the middle of the screen and contamine
it uh in a ring around the edge um and
then six star uh which is you know the
height of uh of what you can produce um
will boil and it it doesn't really
collect contaminant in any one place in
particular uh there's going to be very
very little contaminant on the screen
and most likely it'll melt right through
the screen and you won't have anything
left over there uh so that's kind of the
star rating system and I brought that up
here to Washington and uh uh a lot of
the community in the medical community
adopted that uh star rating system as as
well as uh the company that I was
working for at the time or owned at the
time conscious extracts so we kind of
push that forward here yes sir so sorry
this going to happen to you all oh no
that's great I love questions I love
questions um so in watching you put
together the bags at least for this
demonstration uh Pro you skipped a
couple yes and uh which you know totally
I I get how all that puts together so in
looking for a a hash at the end as far
as your product is concerned if you're
trying to achieve that six-star rating
do you feel it is absolutely always
necessary just use all the bags and
split it up
or is it is there a way to tell or is
there a way to at least guide you
towards knowing okay I can use the 73
and the 90 and maybe the 120 together
leave the 45 out or you know I mean like
how how how do you go about deciding
what bags you use to try to find product
right so so really you know I mean for
for to today's market the 502 Market um
I really like to have two grades
possible right um and so having a lot of
different bags that's kind of tough
right um but but you can also have a
third grade that would be all of the
other uh all of the other grades that
aren't the super melty varieties that
you compress into BR so so yes it's
definitely
uh it's defin something that that you
would want to have more screens in there
if you're going to try and make that
six-star um but really that six-star is
dependent not on the screens that you
use but on the material that you that
you have so if you have good starting
material you're going to have an amazing
product and if it's a five star where
you're using less of the bags you throw
another one in there you might pick that
six star um because you know because you
had a little bit more filtration and you
were able to get out a little bit more
of the contaminant um but yeah it's all
about the material the material is is
key for sure um in the
process all right well I'm going to
start this up I think it's uh probably
been
uh yeah it's been long enough
here so I like to
um I like to I like to uh do a 5 minute
spin got my my drill here and it's got a
variable speed on it so it's able to go
slow it's able to go fast and this is a
submit mixer and I really like this uh I
really like this head here it's a it's
rounded right so you don't have any
sharp edges sharp edges are going to
lead to breaking your material out so if
you've got the rounded edges it's going
to just thresh your material it's going
to bump into it your resin heads are
going to fall off and your plant
material is not going to break up as
much
so we'll give her a whirl here five
minutes if you guys want look you're
welcome to come up here and
have so uh 5 minutes of ucation and then
I'll take this and just
in
here I usually dump almost all of it and
then give a little squish to get any
resin that might be down at the
bottom and then I also like to keep my
bucket clean so I'll
usually put put some water in there and
wash out any last little
bits and then we wait again
so yeah yeah five more minutes um and
then I like to give it a little s um so
usually in practice uh it's it's either
five or it's it's either 10 or 15
minutes um I wait from the time it stops
mixing until I start pulling the bags
out um so tonight we'll just do the 10
minutes just to what are we waiting for
so what we're waiting for now is the res
to sink right so right now there there's
kind of this Matrix of plant material
and and ice and water and all these
things and the resin is denser than
water and so it will actually sink down
to the bottom and so we're waiting for
it to to do a little bit of sinking and
then uh then we can also give a little
more agitation 5 minutes later to kind
of mix any bits that are still stuck on
the plant material that have settled on
plant material and uh allow that to
drain down so
yeah any Merit to putting on a little
low vibration table I mean totally could
I've never done it before um but uh but
I you know seems like it might it might
help move things down right yeah yeah so
um people definitely do that with keep
right when they're making ke they put a
little vibrator on their ke screens and
and bounce the the resin off so you
don't have to break the plant material
up and you can kind of just you know if
it's cold enough room it should Shear
off really well so um I had a question
about uh washing machines right so
there's uh there's kind of two two ways
to go about it uh this this method you
know at first it was like a cake mixer
right that's that's what I used for
years um then we moved to the drill uh
with a paint mixer and the paint mixer
it you know it was it was good but when
I found the cement mixer it was just
that that that perfect
tool so yeah so it's kind of the
progression over the years but but the
uh the washing machines are are really
an interesting method so what you what
you do with a washing machine is you um
you fill the the little it's like a
desktop type washing machine they
actually make bigger ones as well um but
uh you fill it with some ice and water
and then you put your plant material
into a bag uh that is all the mesh
that's at the bottom of this 220 Micron
so it's all 220 Micron it has a zipper
on it and uh you put that into uh your
washing machine and just turn it on and
so you can set it for however many many
minutes you want to do your your wash
and then it's got a little hose and you
drain it right into your bags right so
that's definitely an easy way to do it
um I've seen similar qualities uh come
come from it I would say that if you're
doing the fresh Frozen um I've seen a
lot a lot of people have better success
with fresh frozen using the washing
machine than they have with the drill
right but with the dry trim it seems
that the drill is better for me at least
so that's kind of my personal personal
preference there um but yeah yes sir so
I'm going to assume that you at work you
probably use the like 20 gallon washers
St
um at work we do dry material there um
and so we actually use this same setup
but in 32 gallon bins um so they're
they're just a a rubber made uh brute
trash bins U but we actually buy the the
white ones that are food grade right so
they're actually it's a little higher
quality plastic you can actually put
food into um and uh yeah but then we use
the freeze dryer for the finish so so if
I'm sorry I guess are you using the
bigger washer machines or we we don't
use a wash machine yeah the same exact
same exact thing yeah I use a little bit
beefier of a drill uh it work this is
just like my personal home drill you
know um but the same mixing head um I I
use on the 20 gon set and then are you
draining oh you're draining into a 20
gon instead of bags yeah so I've got a
32G uh trash bin that actually holds the
20 gallon uh set of Bubble Bags just
kind of that's you know the trash bin
that works the best for for those bags
and I I've seen bags that are uh that
are side walls are all mesh or at least
extended mesh would you do have you ever
reuse those do you like those um yeah
you know the the all mesh bags are
definitely uh definitely great uh but I
would say
um yeah I just I just use the Bubble
Bags because it's what I have and it's
what I've used for years and and uh I
really like to uh support bu man and his
Endeavors although he doesn't really
need too much of my support
nowadays so training in the 20 gon bags
is not like a big deal like I couldn't
imagine trying to drain a 20 gallon
trash can into a 5 gon uh set of bags
that would take a while right
so bigger bags bags does that just drain
quicker yeah you know uh you're just
able to hold all that water in there
yeah so if you're if you're doing it
into you know if you're draining your
big 20 gallon washer uh you probably
want a 20 gallon set of bags to hold all
that water so that you can drain it all
at once um there's also a lot of people
will use another method um where they'll
cut the buckets right and then they'll
stack stack they they'll put one one bag
in each bucket right and then stack the
these buckets inside of each other and
the the very bottom one they've just got
a whole bunch of holes drilled in the
bottom of it and they do it in a sink or
they do it outside where it's okay for
the water to just drain um or do it in
into a big tub you know where they've
got it kind of raised up um and then you
could use a 20 gallon washer with a 5
gallon bucket right so and and if you're
using the All mesh screens there's much
more surface area of of mesh for for
your water to move through because
that's you're moving your your hashes
through it but it's also really how fast
is your water going to drain through
right so so yeah the all mesh bags are
great for kind of doing that sort of a
method where you're using the smaller
bags but a larger washer yeah yes so if
you were trying to make something for
someone with cancer so you know usually
I've been making the alcohol extraction
M do you think because this has got more
of the tpes in it it would be a better
medicine well it just really depends I I
would say that uh you're going to have
um more of a strain specific effect from
Bubble hatch right because it has all of
those Turing in there um I don't really
and he just he just left he'd probably
be the the one to talk to about about
that uh you know whether having
something with that's full of Turpin
would be better for somebody with cancer
I'm not 100% sure I have not done enough
studying for that but I will say that
you really see um the modulating effects
of the different strains uh the tpin
that that are in there from Bubble has
versus having an alcohol extract where a
lot of those tpin are gone or changed
because in the heat process
They do change uh you know and break
down mular so
yeah yeah yeah that's the other thing so
this would not be decard right so you
know if you were going to eat just
bubble has straight it would be a THC
acid that you're consuming rather than a
THC that's been converted and unless you
smoked unless you smoked it and then
during the the act of smoking it's doing
that deep
yeah
yeah all right any other
questions Jeff are we doing really well
we got about a 15 minute window left is
that yeah I'm going pull this and we'll
we'll have it on the tray within 10
minutes of awesome
yeah and so I would say that uh that
when I'm doing this uh at home uh I'm
going to be doing four washes or at work
uh I do four washes um I've done up to
12 washes on certain strings and come up
with melting material what I like to do
at home is do the for washes and then
take it and throw all of the plant
material into a crock pot take some of
this bubble water um that's left over
and fill the crock pot up and throw a
whole bunch of coconut oil into the
crock pot and uh and cook that to get
the remaining canono out of the plant
material um so I think that's that's
really a great method to get the best of
both worlds you get something really
next to smoke and you get something
that's going to be very effective to eat
as well
so right cool well let's get going here
on this uh
so I like to give a little jiggle well
it's in the water just kind of uh
get pull up pull some hashes out of my
hand yeah I I like to to give it a
little shake to get any of the resin
that has gone down to the bottom uh to
drain and when I'm doing my first SEC
first and second uh pulls I really try
to just pull it out and kind of move it
around like this so that the water is
draining over over the different parts
of the screen and washing any of the
resin heads out of there but not squeeze
if you squeeze it you're going to have a
lot of the plane material that has
broken down go through there right now
the pl material has floated up to the
top and the resin heads have have come
down to the bottom and so you want to
try and keep that separation as much as
you possibly can um in the third and
fourth run however I I start giving it a
little bit more of a squeeze to make
sure that I'm getting the most out of it
but those are lower grade um end results
so um so you take your bucket come back
over to it
um I like to kind of stretch the bag
back over
it and then you just dump it back in
there so that's that's ready to go again
for another
wash it's always handy to have a a nice
place to
set your bags as you're pulling know so
another bucket uh you know set off to
the side Jeff if you're going to do that
a second time will you pick the second
bucket up so everybody can see it second
bucket the one on the floor this one
here yeah I don't I don't know if you're
going to do that for every wave yeah
yeah yeah yeah well so I mean we're just
going to do the one tonight because for
for time but right on yeah yeah yeah
yeah so that's that's what we've got
there um
so if you were doing this for
real really going to do four washes
would you have that one back on ice at
this point in time well it's still on
ice and so I would pull all these bags
still got ice yeah oh yeah there's
plenty of ice in
there yeah you guys I don't know can
see just put on the table we'll
yeah so it's just plain material that's
been threshed a little
bit so then as you pull your screens I
like to to take the screen and fold it
over like this uh it it gives you kind
of this shape where it draws everything
down into a cone down here so instead of
it being a flat circular screen uh and
then just give it a little dunk to make
sure that you've gotten all the red
that can fall through the screen uh to
fall
through is there an advantage to doing
four washes as opposed to like one long
wash well so so there's in the bag or
when it's in the bag after you've done
your mixing there's resin that's stuck
on the plant material and so it kind of
helps wash it more um so if you if you
were to do 20 minutes say of of mixing
um you're going to have the disadvantage
of it's going to be broken up so you're
going to lose that ability to have the
higher quality resin that you pull from
the very beginning of it um and you're
going to get a little bit less so so
every po kind of generates in quality a
little yes yeah yeah yeah uh and andg
grades and yield as well so there's
going to be less and less of a
yield but so with that being said let's
just say the the 90 Micron that you pull
on pole one is that not the same as the
90 on pole three yeah definitely and you
know I would say depending on what you
how your material is um if there's a lot
of dirt in it or you have power Milo or
you have issues like that that first
wash might be lower quality than the
second right so uh when I'm working with
outdoor material a lot of times I'll
throw the material into the water
and then without beating it up just kind
of getting it all wet uh throw it in
bags and and pull that out so that you
wash off any of that
dirt exactly exactly but you don't want
to be you don't want to do it too much
cuz the resin is going to fall off so
but then that resin can be saved what
you do get the dirt Pan the resin uh can
be saved to make proc you still do that
in like a cold
water um yeah I actually don't put ice
in there but it's like cold out of the T
yeah right so Jeff can I ask you though
pu with all the rains we had this year
did you have much dirt on those flowers
out there um you know there's definitely
some dirt on the bottom pieces for sure
uh that came up like Splash up yeah yeah
so you know the cleanest microbial
counts ever yeah outdoor cultivation
definitely you're going to have some
some dirt growing in dirt and the mar it
splashes back up onto the plant so a lot
of or Growers had to learn a lot of
their crops they're not passing
microbes yeah I saw the huge pile of
cannabis the one grower just mountain of
cannabis that he burned CU he's like all
it just went to mold you know they grew
so much cannabis this year they couldn't
take care of it all you know and that's
that's the problem with a lot of the 502
Farms they they don't plan for
um you know when their first startup you
know they they don't really plan for for
having issues like that so um so yeah
this is
a so the the resin will collect itself
on the screen I like to give a little
wash to uh it does it does a couple
things it gets it all down into into the
center of the screen but it
also washes away some of the smaller
particles that you haven't gotten out of
there and it also washes this water that
is basically a canvas tea it washes that
out of the product so it gives you a
little bit cleaner of a product um but
in practice it you know I would use a
pump sprayer like a agricultural sprayer
with ice so it's going to be cold cold
water that you're spraying in here just
toight are you just spraying around the
inside of the bag or are you actually
like trying to
material yeah you're you're really
spraying the the resin itself yeah yeah
so
um come around you guys can peer in here
and
see
yeah up first
he's not
a little
more
yeah well the secondary wash is going to
be not quite the same amount right so so
you
know I would I'd say it's it's more than
half the amount you would get you know
half again you know um but um but yeah
it's diminishing your yield will
diminish as you go but you will recover
substantial M more by washing it again
oh yeah definitely okay so what I like
to do is uh you know at least at home is
kind of put it over a bucket like this
and create suction so I'm I'm just
drawing the water through the screen by
pulling down on it um you can also use
these pressing screens um but for this
small amount I'm just going to use this
uh this method here and
so um so you take your
good describe what you're doing yeah so
so so I'm just scraping the uh
there did you get
some that's
free yeah so so so what I'm doing is
just scraping it off of the screen of
the
spoon and uh and then putting it into
the S and then I'll just work it here uh
work it through the
S that's just to to help it dry this is
to break it up yeah exactly so that it
doesn't dry in a
clump when you do an alcohol instruction
and you put it through the coffee filter
you up a whole bunch of the stocks of
the tripon yeah is there any value to
those you think well you know I'm not
going to say no because I believe that
all parts of the canab plant are
valuable but for consumption uh to get
you high I would say probably not very
it's going to be I I couldn't really say
for sure because I haven't done the
research to be able to to to
tell yeah but but I would say you know
what what you have there is the stocks
you also have the the rosette of gland
cells which is like kind of the
manufacturing plant for all the Turin
and cannaboids inside the Rosen head so
that's going to be there you know that
that's kind of what what you have there
yeah
you find using a smaller is easier than
using a larger one this little Sie I
would not use in practice I would
actually use a little bit larger of one
cuz it's it's much easier to deal with
but this is what I could
grab you know uh I actually use this uh
my favorite s is one from uh is one from
Ikea it's called the idealist and so
it's like about this big you can a kilo
of res into the thing and S so yeah when
you're when you're scaling up and doing
a lot larger it's yeah it's it's kind of
the way to
go yeah so then I just take the bag off
and there's there's a little bit of
resin left on there but not too terribly
much I just come over here and give it a
little wash this water's really cold so
it's going to help aid getting it uh out
of there
and there we go
so over here this looks fairly good I'm
just going to kind of it up just a
little bit really quick and uh all of
the uh tools I use this brush on uh so
you can just brush the any of the resin
that's going to stick to it and if you
brush it off right away it doesn't stick
so much to the card that you can't get
it all off otherwise it's going to cake
up it's just gets nasty but you can keep
your tools pretty clean uh by using that
um yeah so
then the 45 Micron so 73 is generally
going to be your um highest rate right
most cannabis plants produce a a trome
head that that falls in that 73 Micron
and above uh State um there are a lot of
sativas that have smaller resin heads
and there's a lot of you know different
different varieties that have larger
resin heads but kind of you know as as a
cross-section of of the size of resin
heads out there uh the 73 seems to be a
really good screen to capture the when
you say the 73 is generally the the
better of them what is it about the that
that's better it like the more Turin or
more more res and higher THC or
um well okay so when you're washing it
uh you're adding contaminant as well as
freeing the you're freeing contaminant
and freeing resin heads and so if you if
you're taking the the fraction that has
the most resin heads present in the
plant material you're going to have the
least amount of contaminant right so you
you're you're able to have a higher
quality product just because you've got
more resin that was in the plant yeah so
you mentioned cuticles before and their
thickness uh how big of a role does that
have in like helping to get off uh the
the the the head of the um the stock
without damaging it or opening it yeah I
mean it's it's definitely huge uh you
know um some resin even when it's really
really cold uh is going to be cemented
to the stock you know and so it's going
to be really hard thresh it away um and
you know it's it's just you just kind of
you've got to work with your material
find out if it's a if it's worthwhile to
to process that type of material with
that method and if it's not send it over
into a solvent category do you find like
more ease in with certain types like
like a sativa do you find more a thinner
cell wall so it's easier to manipulate
over an Inda or yeah I mean I would say
like AF guy is is one of my very
favorite strains um and it it it just
the resin Flies free from the plant
material and it's also really cake thin
resin um but that's also one of those
streams that I've run up to 12 times and
uh on the 12th run it was still a three
star so it was very much worth it for me
to do that but I was just tired at the
end
of yeah hash
muscles he je yes if you did run up to
that situation could you just let the
marijuana sit overnight in cold water in
the fridge or something and start
over you know I I wouldn't I I would not
recommend soaking it for too long um I
think that there's going to be
some I I I don't have any definitive
proof but but I believe that there's
going to be some amount of water that's
going to come into the resin head itself
and kind of moisturize that resin and so
I think the 30 minutes of soaking is is
kind of where you want to be yeah kind
of on the side of that cuz I have done
that basically people been like oh I got
to go to bed I can't do it you know
right uh when you come back the next
morning even if you got tons of ice in
there your plant material is just going
to be mush and then if you run it again
you're going to have so much like excess
uh contaminant like what we talking
about right the pl material is going to
break
up this one I pulled just a little bit W
than the first one so you can kind of
see what not to
do you want to have an amount of
moisture in there um but you don't want
to have too much moisture in there or
else it just kind of cakes together you
can see that the pieces that did go
through the SI um on the second part are
more clumped together that's not ideal
right so you want to be more free free
pieces
there
so
yeah yeah
um yeah it can bit but it more just
smears ground
it's and again just rinse the
bags you know after after you're done
it's I can't say it enough it's very
important to to wash your bags when
you're totally done with the process to
keep them in the best condition you can
with ISO or water um if there's resin
stuck on the screen uh use on the screen
itself uh isopropyl alcohol is great um
but uh usually just water is is what I
like to work with so get
strong if use warm water melt on and
it's going to melt on there then you're
going to need
some water exactly thank you yeah if you
uh yeah and so when you're draining the
last bag it's a little slow you can kind
of give it a little up and down jerk
like that uh but gentle don't go too
much if you're doing it on the big 20
gallons I don't suggest that there's a
whole another method that you would use
but uh because it can rip the screen
doing this um but this this will free
the resin heads that are clogging the
screen get them back into the water
allow for more of the water to drain
more
l so that's the 25 yeah this is the 25
micron here would you consider that to
be the Lesser qualties some of the
other um well just it just depends I
would say on this
stream possibly um what I what I ran
yesterday was a bunch of stas and the 25
mic was actually really nice so um the
73 was still my highest grade um but uh
but it was it definitely still melted um
I think the 25 is great
rosin rosin's my answer for anything
that doesn't
know what is r roson is a a method of
heat pressure
extraction and uh and and what what you
do is you basically take
a heat Source a lot of people like at
home can use like a a flat iron like
straight a hair straightener um and you
use parchment and you take the hashish
you put it into a screen you fold that
over uh and then you've got it in
between a piece of parchment and you
take the hair straightener and squish it
and the liquefiable contents is the
canono the tpin some of the waxes some
other constituents that are inside of
the Rosen will move outside screen and
you can collect them and all the
contaminant the the non mty uh parts of
of of the hashish will stay in the
screen okay so yeah so it's a way to
make a hash oil okay without sof
and I also like to kind of give this
little tug well draining or while while
I'm scraping so keep it from being wet
there's moisture on the other side of
the screen and moment you stop pulling
on that and creating the suction the
moisture breaks right back
in National Geographic over
here Farm
interesting National can
graphic to an end
that yeah so this one just all really
stuck to the screen so if you didn't
have this little brush technique you'd
be like oh jeez what do I do with all
that but the brush it'll get it right
off so [__]
so when you're drying your hat are you
just drying the water that you basically
added to that dry PL or is there somehow
now like water somak into the membrane
of the resin or like how does that work
you're you're really drying the water
that you put in there on the outside of
the yeah well the reason why
I just because
stuff I'm not going to get there some
people advocate for like a 3 Monon
drying time yeah well you know that
that's definitely going to going to dry
your resin more you're going to have
more tarpine Lots cu the Tarpin will
migrate out of the resin head um so yeah
but but I'd say that you know the
fresher you can smoke it the more tpine
content you're going to have in there
just as long as you're sure you got that
yeah as long as it's going to be Shelf
yeah so there you have it bubble
hatch all right cool now if you were
doing
this maybe three questions would you
repeat this then three more times yes
and and how much more would you get uh
based on what you get there would you
get 50% more
yeah at least at least um so you know
you stared with 133 gr what are you
going to end up with there so generally
you're going to have it between five and
you know the highest I've ever had was
177% on that after E Street um so from
from your original plant materials
weight you'll have 5% um on kind of the
low end I've had a little bit less than
5% as well um but it just kind depends
on the starting
material yeah are you going to reuse the
water that's in that bucket now I would
reuse this water exactly
that with that water yeah you know I
mean you could totally drink this I've
actually fermented it with h I've added
sugar and yeast and fermented it into a
wine right one more question any more
one more yes so how long did you say you
were going to dry that for uh so one
week one week yeah that's that's kind of
the the perfect you can smoke it
tomorrow without without it sizzling and
popping uh but but if you want to put it
into a storage container uh you'll want
to wait a week at a at a temperature of
it's just like room T yeah yeah and and
you know definitely having a colder
environment is better it's going it's
not going to melt the resin heads and
and trap water in there as readily if
you have it in the
en on
that yeah
definitely drer and then it's done the
next day it's completely dry and ready
ready to
pack cool thank you