So, I'm really excited about the guest
tonight. Our guest tonight is Tad Hussy
of Keep It Simple Organics. Keep It
Simple is an edible nursery, production,
greenhouse, outdoor preschool, organic
hydroponic shop, and feed store in
Redmond. Uh Tad is an educator and
sought-after speaker on probiotic
growing for all kinds of crops,
cannabis, food, and anything else that
there might be. Um so tonight he's going
to talk about a wide range of probiotic
growing techniques so your gardens
thrive. And I saw this presentation at
Canacon in Seattle um over the winter
and it was standing room only. There
were a couple hundred people there.
Everybody's all packed in because Tad's
u experience is so valuable. So, I hope
you find it valuable as well tonight.
Please give Tad a warm
welcome. First off, I just want to say
thank you to Shango and Vivian for
having me out here tonight. I really
appreciate the opportunity. Um, when I
talked to Shango and he told me I had a
little more time to talk, I actually
changed my talk around. So um I made it
more about kind of my journey through
growing and learning and we'll cover all
the topics that we discussed but just in
slightly different order. So I I titled
this talk biological horiculture. Um
I'll explain more here in a little bit.
So uh let's see if we can get this thing
working. All right. So this is uh keep
it simple farm. This is my place out in
Redmond. My parents own a 7acre property
here. About 5 years ago now, we realized
that the nursery industry was crumbling
and uh I was just getting into edible
landscaping and chickens and all of this
stuff. We had an online business and the
nursery that was on the property uh
moved to a new location. So, we decided
to take it in a totally different
direction focused on urban farming. Uh
we opened a feed store. Um we're doing
like like uh Shango said, we have an
outdoor free school that meets there
every day. And um that was a giant
pumpkin we grew one year was 725 lbs for
over 1,000 this year. Uh and then this
is just kind of a shot of the property
here to give you a little bit of idea.
But we also have a trail in the back
along Bear Creek which is a salmon
spawning stream uh just for education
where we have over a thousand people
every every fall coming through to learn
about salmon and about native habitat.
So we're really uh excited to just be
part of the community there. Um it's a
wonderful piece of piece of property. If
you ever get a chance to come out to
Redmond, love to give you guys a tour.
So, this is our greenhouse in the back.
We're doing veggie starts all from seed
at the beginning of the year starting in
the spring and then we eventually um
that's actually my dad right there. We
uh we planted out. So, this is a photo
towards the end of the season where we
had a beneficial bug mix growing in the
middle row here, our tomatoes over here,
and then right here we have our uh
cucumbers that are just kind of on their
last legs for the season. Um, so
everything's just kind of starting up
this year. We haven't gotten tomatoes
yet, but we're getting really
close. This is I had some farm shots. I
thought we had a photographer come out.
Uh, we just had baby pigs recently.
These are mini pigs, so full grown is
still not all that big. We got turkeys
running around. Uh, these goats arrived
two weeks ago, including this little
baby. They're mini, so we will hopefully
eventually have have milking goats. But
the thing I love about the property is
the kids actually get to come in and
interact with the animals. We have an
area with the chickens and the turkeys
and some beehives where the kids get to
go right in there um and interact with
the living parents because that was
something I never really got uh got to
do as a child. But let's back up a
little bit.
So, oh, I don't know about 10 years ago,
I was working uh my dad had this online
business selling compost tea brewers and
I came into the business after finishing
my master's degree down in Australia and
I kept getting all these phone calls and
people are like, "Hey, I'm growing 30
tomatoes in my basement and all
right." I was like, "What is everyone
using our product for?" So, I started
doing a little research and I walked
into my first hydroshock and this is
kind of what you see when you walk in
there. It smells funny. It's like
walking down that that aisle at Home
Depot and I was like, "What does this
have to do with growing plants?" It was
totally foreign because I come from
having my parents owning a landscaping
business and nursery my entire life. I
hadn't even seen any bottle nutrients
before then. So, uh, I I started looking
into it at that point and trying to
learn more about um about what exactly
was going on in the whole thing. So, uh,
one of the things I like to talk about
is the environmental impact of some of
these phenri. So, I did a consult at one
of the larger 502s uh this year and I
walked in at a facility and they were
literally emptying one of these totes of
chemical nutrients down the drain and I
asked them where where's that going? Oh,
we have a septic out back. They're
literally across the street from the
fisheries and wildlife. Like I'm just
waiting for the EPA to show up on the
door. And I think that's the next big
issue we're going to have for a lot of
these larger growths. So, it's really
important that you consider where this
stuff is going. And on top of that, the
the traditional thing is you you get
your soil, it's fairly inert. You pour
your bottle nutrients on it, you
directly feed the plant, and then you
have to oh, let me back up. So, all of
these phosphates that we're dumping are
creating algo blooms, which pull all the
dissolved oxygen out of the water as the
algae grows. And then we have all these
areas where fish and other wildlife are
no longer able to survive. And one of
the largest besides Texas is actually in
Oregon. So, uh, homeowners in general,
especially with our our our perfect
looking lawns and then also, um, our
cannabis plants, we need to be
especially careful not to be putting
excess nutrients out. Um, this is what I
was getting at. In addition to that,
when we're done growing, a lot of
growers, we just they dispose of their
soil. So, this is now no good and you
have to throw it out and it ends up
looking like this in your landscape
because it has all the perlite in the
first time it rains. And this is the
traditional way that people were growing
for the last I don't know 20 or 30 years
you know ever since uh based nutrients
were
invented. Uh so during this process I
started reading more and learning more
about what is actually going into these
products and what are we what are we
paying for? Um one example is potassium
silicate. So silica helps with thicker
stocks keep the plant from tipping over
uh in the wind. It also helps with
overall just plant health and growth or
if there's too much um of any
micronutrient in the soil like a little
too much magnes or a little too much
iron. Uh the the silica will help
mitigate that by spreading it more
evenly through the leaf tissue so you
have less damage. So silica is a
wonderful addition to your garden.
There's a bunch of different ways you
can get it. But if you were to go down
the store the hydro shop and buy it, uh
the most common brand I think most
people know is Dagrow Protek. That's the
one I heard of before before I got into
growing. You know, $44 a gallon. Well,
all they're doing is taking this powder
here, this egg 16, which we sell online
for $12 a pound. This makes up 3/4 of a
gallon to the exact same strength as Dro
Protect. Uh silicon blast has a little
bit of sodium silicate, but we don't
really need more sodium for the most
part with a lot of our a lot of growing.
And then Rhino Skin, which is the
advanced nutrients one, is really the
worst in terms of price. And I won't
pick on these other mild nutrient
companies with the exception of Advanced
Nutrients because I think they've done a
lot to hurt the industry in terms of the
way they promoted themselves and
cannabis in general and they're just
well known and ripping people off. So
when we start looking at what's in
organic bottle nutrients because we're
we're completely organic on our
property. Uh we don't sell chemical
nutrients. I don't really know a lot
about chemical nutrients. I understand
how they function, but it's not
something I'm really passionate about.
So I'm going to stick to organic all
nutrients. So, what's in most of these
products that we see here, you're going
to find molasses, hemic acids, seaweed,
fish emulsion, fish hydraulicate, and um
added labeling nutrients down here.
Because one of the things I didn't know
prior to all this is when you see a
number on this bottle that says, let's
say 555, that means it's 5% nitrogen, 5%
phosphorus, 5% potassium, or at least
that's what they're guaranteeing. So,
what some of these places will do is
they'll say, "I have a proprietary
nitrogen source that's exponentially
better than everything else on the
market." It's not. They're just putting
10% nitrogen in there, guaranteeing 5%.
So, you So, their product is going to
get you're going to get that putting on
more nitrogen than you realize. Your
plant's going to grow a little faster,
and then you think that you have to
spend an extra $100 on this product.
It's It's a crazy racket, and uh it's
something I was never even aware of
until I had to register my first product
as a fertilizer.
So, also when I'm looking at soil tests,
I can't necessarily assume that that MDK
that I think I'm putting out to match my
soil test is actually going to match it.
So, keep those things in mind um just in
the back of your head when you're
evaluating products. So, molasses,
that's what you're going to find in
products called Strapped or Sweet or Bud
Candy. Again, enhanced nutrients. Um we
sell a three and a half gallon bucket
for around $20 at our store. Um,
unsulered blackstrap molasses is really
unsulered blackstrap molasses. You don't
you don't need to spend all this money
on it. And uh, one other thing about it
too, it's not going to make your butts
taste any sweeter. Plants don't work
that way. That whole pour Kool-Aid on
your plants to get bread. I think we
disagree. It just doesn't it just
doesn't work. So, the sugars in there
though are a wonderful microbial food
for all the different microorganisms
that we'll talk about in a second. Um,
it also has a little bit of potassium in
it. But, um, again, you don't need to
spend your money on, um, a brand like
that. Uh, seaweed is one of my favorite
amendments. It they contains over 70
different elements, uh, plant growth
hormones and plant growth regulators.
Um, it helps with drought resistance,
uh, heat and cold stress. Um, it's just
it's one of the best things. Like if I
had to choose just a couple things that
I can use in my garden, uh kelp meal or
seaweed would be probably top of the
list. Um but when we look at what's
actually in them, they're they're all
going to be seaweed derived from asylum.
It's just it's North Atlantic sea kelp.
It's the most widely studied. If you
want to read more about kelp, there's a
little book you can get for probably 20
bucks on Amazon by TL Sen called seaweed
and plant growth. Did you have a
question? Yes. See, you just use that as
a cup as a bulge. I so I use it two
ways. I uh I buy I I use kel which I mix
into the soil
um for my potty mixes and then we also
carry a product that I buy from Aadian
makes it and then same with this
Nature's Essence and it's just uh think
of it like a extract. So it's like a
fine concentrate orange juice. So you
can add this to water and get over 100
gallons. Now, if you're harvesting
seaweed, which I think that might have
been what you're getting at, you do need
to rinse and wash it to remove all the
all the salt and sodium from it prior to
uh composting it or putting it in in
your garden, but you could pick up a lot
of these same nutrients. It's a little
different kelp that we have out here,
but can still be beneficial.
Yeah. So, as you can see, a pound uh I
think we sell for around $18. Um or you
can there's a lot of places you can find
it. um make up over 100 gallons of
liquid liquid kelp to the same, you
know, the same rates as what they're
selling you in these bottles. So again,
it's just another way to save your
money. Uh humic acids, uh humic acids
are excellent chelators, which means
they bond with the minerals in your soil
and help make the plant available.
Um variety of different products. Again,
when it comes to that, uh the ones that
we use are uh it's called from
Terravita, the SP85. It's 85% humic acid
by content. You're using just an eighth
of a teaspoon per gallon of water. And
that comes out of the agricultural
industry. Um the the gentleman that buy
the seaweed and the humic acid from is
over in Lancaster, Pennsylvania, and he
works with all the um all the farmers,
large scale farmers over there. Um
because realistically, like no farmer is
buying Rinse organics or general general
hydroponics. it's just not practical and
they can't afford it. And yes, I I
firmly believe cannabis is a special
plant and it's medicine, but it is
called weed for a reason. It's not hard
to grow once you learn stuff. And from a
nutrient perspective, it's actually
quite easy to grow a big healthy robust
plant. Uh fish hydraulicate, that's
probably the one liquid nutrient that I
really like to use. Um we use it on our
veggie starts when they start to get a
little rebound in our in our farm. U
fish hydraicate is very different than
fish emulsion. So fish emulsion is going
to be very high in nitrogen. Fish
hydraulic is be much higher in
phosphorus. Uh fish fish emulsion is
typically the Alaska fish fertilizer
that you may see in the store. So keep
in mind that they're very different. And
when you give both of them to soil based
microbes, the fish hydrolate is going to
perform exponentially better. So it's a
much better microbial food than fish
emulsion.
Natural form of that a natural form. So
depending on the brand like Organic Gem
I believe um they use an enzyatic
process to break down the fish. They're
all certified organic. Um but they do
have to put in a small amount of fat
phosphoric acid as a stabilizer. But u
as far as I know, every organic
certified agency allows for that. Um
otherwise it would break down way too
rapidly because it is such a good micro
food. Um, we use it to charge our
biochar that we put into our soils. Um,
we soak it for a week in the fish
hydraulic as a way to fill the cation
sites
up. Uh, so one of the other things I
like to point out, uh, right now, this
has been a big issue with pesticides.
It's something that a lot of a lot of
consumers and medical patients weren't
even aware of. They think when they're
buying a plant, it's a plant, you know,
it's grown naturally. Well, it really
isn't. And unfortunately, there are a
lot of uh unscrupulous people growing
plants cuz it's a lot easier to spray a
plant with Eagle 20 and not have to
worry about powder rebuilding for the
life of the plant. But these things are
systemic for a reason. They live inside
the leaf tissue. It's not something that
you want to be putting in your bodies.
So, if you can know your grower, I think
that's the really the best thing. Or
grow your own medicine. It's really uh
really what we promote. Um just half a
step back. Oh, yeah. Great. Thanks.
Okay. So, the other thing I like to
point out, uh, this just came out
recently. So, the Oregon Department of
Agriculture tests, uh, a lot of these
microbial plot products. So, something
like the MFP, for example, they would
test to see, are they meeting the claims
that they say they're putting on these
products because no one else is doing
that. You could put whatever you want on
the label, and no one's regulating it
when it comes to microbial products. Uh,
some of their findings were were kind of
surprising like this advanced nutrient
product, Piranha. uh they didn't detect
any of the product that they claimed was
in
it. Dr. Earth came back higher, you
know. So, uh these tests are all freely
available online. Um if you shoot me an
email, I can send you a link to it. Um
OG Bowar is another one most people know
and microisal applications. Um Santium
Organics. So, they are looking at these
things to actually test to see if you're
getting what you you pay for. So, just
because it's on a label and just because
it's made as a claim doesn't mean it's
necessarily true.
So, you really have to do your due
diligence.
Um, all right. So, after all of that, we
decide I decided I learn figured there
was got to be a better way to grow
plants. Uh, and this first half of my of
my talk is really focused on um what I
learned from my father and from Dr. Leum
and Jeff Loenfeld when it comes to uh
organic gardening. And this was my
philosophy for the the first 10 years
that I I was growing. So, uh, what is
biological horiculture? Well, this is a
photo from the Olympic rainforest. My
friend Moan came to visit from Australia
and she had never seen trees like this.
She was just blown away. Um, she's a big
hippie. She absolutely loved it. So, uh,
one of the reasons I like to show this
is because, uh, Jeff is always famous
for saying, "Well, there's no one out
there dumping Miracle Grill out in the
rainforest." And it's so true. These
these ecosystems are diverse. They're
phenomenally healthy. And it's all
because of the biological activity
that's going on uh beneath the soil and
on the and on the surface of the floor.
So when we look at this look at this
tree, you can see all these roots down
here. Well, the plant is
photosynthesizing light. It's taking in
light from the sun and it's putting
anywhere from 30 to 70% of that energy
back out through its roots to feed the
microorganisms in the soil. So when you
think about it just shows you how
important these microbes are to this
entire gardening process. So when we put
out Miracle Grow uh highly which is a
highly concentrated salt, we're actually
killing off a lot of these
microorganisms through the process of
osmosis. Um and then we become in charge
as the gardener of directly feeding this
plant and playing God. Well, in an
organic system really all we're doing is
trying to create the optimal environment
for these microbes and then putting the
plant in charge. And that's really the
most important thing I can I can
emphasize when it comes to uh microbes
and your garden. So the main thing here
is the nutrient cycling. So it starts
off you have your plants here. Um it's
going to drop leaves down. It's it's
photosynthesizing energy. It's also
dropping detritus onto the floor
creating a mulch. It's getting eaten by
uh different microorganisms that are
then cycling the nutrients back into uh
nitrogen or whatever nutrient form the
plant wants. And then uh that nitrogen
feed the plants feeds the plant and it
continues. Now in the indoor garden
we're pulling organic matter and we're
pulling nutrients out of the soil and
that we're not always replacing with
that plant because we're harvesting our
crop. Same with our vegetable garden. So
it's a little bit different but we can
incorporate this concept into our
growing practices for the healthiest
plants possible. So this is another
thing I stole from Jeff because I
thought it was just such a great
illustration. So the plant is really in
control of this process. It's putting
out exidates. These are things like
sugars, carbons, carbohydrates right
into the soil to select for the type of
microorganisms to create the food that
it wants. So if it wants more uh I'll
say it wanted more Japanese food one
night, well they would put out food and
the Japanese person would appear and
they they get to eat that or the next
night maybe they want uh Indian food or
Mexican food whatever whatever
particular type of uh exidate it creates
it can control this process. Um and it
can actually change it on an hourly
basis. So if it wants its nitrogen in
the form of nitrate, it will select for
the microorganisms that will create that
create that nutrient that nitrogen in
that form. Same for ammonium or whatever
whatever particular uh nutrient that
plant wants. It's an amazing process. I
heard a soil scientist speak and he was
saying we know more we know more about
the moon or about the solar system than
we do about what's going on directly
under our feet in terms of uh soil
science. There's just so much more for
us to learn. So, I'm going to go over
really quickly just kind of what makes
up the biology in our soils. Uh,
bacteria and archa are clumped together
because they have similar functions, but
archa is something that we didn't even
know existed outside of deep water vents
up until I think 15 20 years ago. Um,
they're their own kingdom classification
altogether. Uh, but they function for
all intents and purposes very similar to
bacteria.
uh fungi or fungal hype uh prozzoa those
are all the things you studied in you
know 8th grade biology class uh
nematodes microarththopods worms and
larger
creatures so bacteria um one interesting
fact is that they can produce in the
vicinity of 5 billion offspring in the
span of 12 hours if they have enough
food unchecked they would double the
mass of the planet in in just a couple
months they're amazing amazing growers
and uh I'll show you a photos of some
here in a little This is under an
electron microscope here. Uh they're
great decomposers. So they are the ones
that break down all of those uh greens.
So anything that's high in nitrogen,
it's easy to break down. Simple sugars.
Bacteria is going to take it up really
quickly. Uh and they decompose all that
plant matter and material to um cycle
these nutrients, but they also
immobilize the nutrients. So when that
bacteria eats that leaf, it takes that
nitrogen, holds it inside of it until it
gets eaten by uh prozzoa or you know
silate or something and then what it
then excretes is that plants available
nitrogen. So that's it's it's a very
important part of that whole
process and it enhances soil quality
because it's food for these other
microorganisms in the soil. uh
decomposes organic matter for us and
retains nutrients in the ryosphere which
is that's just a fancy word for area
around the roots
uh enhances soil
structure competes with diseasecausing
organisms. So, if you have beneficial
microorganisms around your roots or on
your leaf surface, they're going to help
protect the plant from uh airborne and
and soil based
pathogens. And certain uh certain
bacteria actually can fix atmospheric
nitrogen. They're in the riseobia
family. So, it's pretty amazing um all
the things that bacteria can do. Uh
fungi, they're the decomposer of all the
brown. So, when you're told to get your
uh greens and browns right when you're
thermally composting, that's so that the
bacteria and fungus can grow to really
uh decompose everything correctly for
you and and heat up by their uh by their
reproduction. So, they create pathways
in the soil, all these little pockets.
When that when that hay dies, then
bacteria and other things can move
through it to different areas in the
soil. And you can see how how it can
create soil structure uh just based on
how it combines soil into aggregates. So
by just by having better structure in
your soil, you'll reduce um you can
reduce erosion and other problems. Uh
fungi release acid which will lower the
soil pH. uh it retains nutrients in its
biomass and they uh there's actually a
whole field now created by Paul Stam
it's called micological remediation
where they've used different species of
fungi to uh deal with everything from
radiation to oil spills. It's it's
really fascinating um and a really
exciting field. It's still
growing. So most people have seen
something like this before on wood
chips. This is myelium. thousands of
strands and a fungal hy wrapped around
each other. Uh this is it under various
types of different microscopes. This is
a bright field microscope here. This is
a phase contrast microscope which is
what I use. This is a microscope filter
that my uh my friend Tim Wilson came up
with. So how many people have heard of
microisal
fungi? Oh wow, that's pretty good. Yeah.
So it's something that we didn't even
know about I think also 20 20 years ago
and now it's you know fairly popular.
Um 90% of plants have a symbiotic
relationship with this fungus with the
exception of uh brassacas. So things
like kale, broccoli, cauliflower can
actually um have decreased healthy
growth if you if they do form that that
relationship. Um but most most plants
do, but it's specific to the type of
plant that you're growing. And for
cannabis, for tomatoes, for peppers, uh
for fruit trees, it's all
endomicizing. What you see here is
ectoicroising. So the endomic actually
infects inside the root. Um and it is
one of the primary ways the plant gets
phosphorus. So when we start looking at
different brands, if we want to spend
money to buy microisal products, um
here's an example of some. So this so
again what we're looking for is
endomicroisa and specifically glomis
intrarates and glomis mossi are the two
ones most widely studied and known to uh
infect cannabis and fruit trees
vegetables all the things we were
talking about before. Now uh aelas
blueberries those are all a totally
different type and so are conifers. So
we're really just talking about most of
our our basic vegetable crops and then
cannabis. Um here you're getting 83
propagules per gram of bonus interatis
lus mossia 8 8 ounces for $71. You're
also picking up
313,000 propagules of triricoderma. Now
if you were a mushroom grower, you're
probably familiar with triricodera. It's
a very very aggressive micro and um
they've done studies that show that it
inhibits microisal infection. So having
in your microisal product in rates that
are exponentially higher than the the
microisal you're buying really doesn't
make a lot of sense. At least I haven't
seen any studies to support it. The ones
where they have shown good good results
using tricoderma the trachoderma levels
are much closer to what you would find
in soil not these highly elevated
levels. Um, but when we look at these
other products here, you have, you know,
27 spores, 23 scores per gram. You're
getting 3% hemic acid, a little bit of
sugar, but you're paying $52 a pound.
Um, this product down here, you know,
2.46
propag, you know, for $14 a pound. Uh,
the two that I carry in my in my hydro
shop for people are uh the micos by RTI.
And then this one just came out this
year. It's uh by a gentleman named Ron
Wallace. He's over in um Rhode Island
and he's a giant pumpkin world record
holder and his product is guaranteed at
300 scores per gram. It's actually um
but he has testing on his website for 5
to 600 sports per gram and it runs $12 a
pound 5 lb increments. Um so these are
the two products I use. Now most of
these companies I think are sourcing it
all from the same place and just cutting
it at different levels. There's very few
people that are actually uh actively
cultivating uh and no mic horizon. Most
of it's coming out of Canada. But again,
we're still taking their word for a
certain for to a certain level that
actually what they say is in here is in
here. I did hear back from the Oregon
Department of A that the numbers on the
micros product were pretty accurate. Um
but they haven't released that yet to
the public. They just that was all they
could tell me was that they came back
looking pretty good. So again, you know,
you can spend $14 for two scores per
gram um thinking you're buying a
microisal product. It really isn't going
to do anything. And if if you buy a
fertilizer bag that says it contains
microisa, you're probably not getting
microisal because um they put just
enough to get on the label. It'll be
like 01 or 05 spores per gram. There's
really nothing in there. Um one other
thing I want to mention about it is it
needs to come in direct contact with the
roots. If it's more than I think it was
like 5 millimeters from a root tip,
it'll never infect your grow. That plant
will just stay as a spore. So, it
actually requires those root exodates in
order to in order to grow. So, really
important that you put it down into the
root. Sprinkling it on top of your soil
and watering is just not an effective
way to get that infection. So for me, if
I'm planting a bed of strawberries or
I'm transplanting a rooted clone, I'm
putting it directly into the root zone,
right into my transplant hole or I'm
sprinkling it right on the roots in the
plant and then I'm forgetting. I'm not
going to worry about worry about it
here. Uh the only other thing about
micro I like to mention is in addition
to tricoderma, high phosphorus has been
found to inhibit this relationship,
which makes a lot of sense. The plant is
getting all the phosphorus it needs.
It's not going to try and cultivate this
relationship. Uh Jeff Blanchfell is
writing an entire book that's going to
be out this winter just on microisal
fungus which should be uh should be
really really good. There's a lot about
this um this particular relationship
that we're still
learning. Uh so this photo here is of
neatus fungi. I like it because
uh it's it's a wonderful illustration of
all the things that we don't know that's
going on in the soil. So this is a fruit
eating neatode. Neatodes are blind. It's
crawling through looking for fury and it
stumbles into these rings right here.
And these rings um are when they fill
this this is an actual fungus that when
the neode goes through it, it actually
can close and it's it's like
instantaneous. It's like one of a second
and it fills with water and then it will
consume that neatode and then use that
nutrients to feed itself and in turn
feed the plant. So it's these natural
systems that we weren't even aware of
that were going on in the soil this
whole time that uh are really
fascinating and these are the sort of
things that we want to promote. That's
why these microorganisms are so so
important to the biological aspect of
growing. Uh so prozzoa one thing I want
just want to say about them is they they
consume a ton of bacteria. They're what
keep bacteria in check for us them and
neatodes. And so they they retain the
nutrients and then when they die um
after eating all this bacteria, what
they poop out is also uh soil available
nutrients. These are nematodes. That's
actually a good neatode there. And those
are little wants and it eats bacteria.
This is a root feeding neode here. This
is this is this neatode under a
microscope. So you can see the see the
difference. And there's a root feeding
one actually inside of the root there.
Um, so nematodes are good and bad. You
can buy them
um actually online for different a
variety of different uh diseases as a
biological control. I personally haven't
used them, but I you will if you look at
a slide of good soil or compost, you
will naturally see a bunch of
nematodeses. However, nematodes don't
like a liquid medium. So, you won't find
them um in compost tea. They don't grow
in compost tea. They don't like being in
water.
So nematodes are kind of like the I
guess the lions and tigers that are the
apex predator of the soil. Um they
mineralize these nutrients in plant
available forms and then they find a
food source for other other
microorganisms as
well. So worms uh are actually not
native to North America. That's
something I didn't know. They were
brought over by Europeans I believe or
maybe the Vikings. I don't know. But
they weren't the Germans. Okay, the
Germans, they weren't here originally.
Um, they're amazing shredders. So,
compost that would or organic matter
that would normally take one two years
to decompose uh without worms can be
decomposed in 3 months. So, they shred
everything down really really well and
they increase your microbial activity in
the soil. um and what they excrete is
not only going to be higher in uh
beneficial
microorganisms, but it's they haven't
figured it out yet, but when it come
when by processing through the worm's
body, it comes out with five times the
levels of nitrogen, uh seven times
levels of phosphates, and 11 times the
levels of potach, which is potassium.
So, uh worms are worms are amazing
creatures. Now, I'm not I'm not saying
go out and buy worms for your garden or
take worms and throw them in your in
your container plants. Um, if the
conditions are right, the worms will
appear. Um, otherwise, you're just
wasting your money and you're feeding
your neighbor's garden or killing off a
bunch of worms. And if you do want to
buy worms for a worm in, uh, you can buy
the cocoons online and they're uh much
much more affordable. Um, yes. But is
there any um like program? I'm I'm a
student that will permit me to get a
loan to have started compost pile and
that other people could use that compost
pile and that we can use natural soil
and have no need of any any chemicals at
all. I have no idea on that. I know well
I I I know I may I'm getting in contact
with them. Okay.
Yeah, there are um there are programs
for composting through different cities,
I know, and counties, but I'm not sure
about for worms, but um well, it's not
specifically the worms at all. Just have
Oh, just for composting. Yeah, just have
natural soil and no need of bringing any
soil on, taking any nutrients out at
all. Yeah. Yeah, there probably there
probably are things like that available.
I'm just not familiar with them. All
right. Yeah. Thank you. So
uh the reason I show this slide is just
so people realize that it's not a linear
progression. All these things are
interacting together. Uh that bird for
example is going to have mites and and
other microorganisms on its feet every
time it lands. It's going to fly
somewhere else and drop down these
things. Um it's going to the bathroom
which is being eaten by you know
bacteria, nematodes, all these different
organisms. So they work together um
symbiotically. It's it's a web not a not
a linear
relationship. Uh this is a chart I like
to show people because
um it really starting over on this end.
We have the plants that prefer highly
bacterial soils. As soils progress, they
become more fungally dominant all the
way down to an end like here. Um
cannabis, veggies, things, they end up
right around here. They want a balance
of bacteria and fungus. That being said,
when we make compost te's when we're
looking at microbial products, uh, we're
just trying to put out, it's a shotgun
approach. We're putting out what we can
and let the plant really be in control.
A lot of people get caught up on this
chart and say, "Well, I'm growing
tomatoes and tomatoes like bacterial
soil. So, I'm only going to do things to
feed the bacteria or I'm going to add
bacteria." Which gets us away from that
whole thing that I was showing you
earlier where the plant really controls
that environment.
In fact, uh, one of the things
interesting things about plants is they
can adjust the pH in the ryosphere. So
even if the pH of the soil or the water
you're using or the nutrients is not
what the ideal for the plant, it can
actually change the pH right in the soil
itself. Um, for whatever it needs, and I
found with our soils over time, the pH
just settles into that, you know, 66 to
68 range. Even if we started with a soil
that was 7 72 um higher than you would
traditionally think to use for a plant.
Yes. Do you know how uh it's through the
X again the stuffing out into the soil?
They they release certain organic acids
that will adjust adjust the soil pH.
Yes. Do they release those same organic
acids in soilless mediums? Um I believe
so. But I don't think that if you don't
if you don't have enough microbial
activity going on around there then you
won't have that same effect.
Um but that's a good question. I it it
depends I think on the media too. Like
cocoa can support cocoa core can support
a fair amount of microbial life but it's
it's inert when you first you first get
it. If you were mixing worm castings
with some other uh biological source
into there then I think it would have
much better chance. whereas Pete Moss
already has a lot of good microbial
activity in it. So um it just depends if
you're talking a rock wall or you know
truly hydroponic situation then um I
wouldn't really
know. So having good u microorganism
activity increases your disease
protection your nutrient immobilization
against lockup within the cellular walls
of the plants. uh you get the right
nutrients at the right
time and uh it helps decompose toxins,
get rid of residues. Uh that on the lawn
is a classic example of uh not having
enough microbial activity in your in
your soil. Um it builds your soil
structure, reduces your water use,
increases water capacity and on and
on. So how do we increase beneficial
biology? Well, bunch of ways. um compost
being one of the one most people are
most familiar with. Uh mulching compost
TE's uh nutrient TE's that are going to
feed microorganisms in the soil and then
organic fertilizers.
Um I'm not going to spend a lot of time
on these uh because I think you guys are
probably pretty familiar with them, but
I can always cut back if we have time.
Uh a few different types of of compost,
thermal, static, and worm composting.
Um, if you're buying compost, I tend to
recommend the worm castings just
because, uh, most likely the worms did a
better job of it than than we did. Um,
thermal composting, you actually have to
heat the material up to 131 for 3 days
where you turn it, keep it below 160.
Um, it's quite a process. Static
composting, you literally just leave it
a pile, let it sit there for a year or
two or 6 months or whatever until it
breaks down.
Um, compost, not all compost is created
equal. Um, every time I walk through the
grocery store, for example, when I walk
by these bags of compost, I just have to
shake my head cuz they're not anything I
would ever let anywhere near my garden.
Um, a lot of it a lot of the municipal
composts are really, in my opinion,
poorly made. Um, and when you look at
them under under a microscope, you can
see that they're not they're typically
not finished. Um, that's where you get
all the ammonia and some of the off
casting and the odors. Yes. Also an
issue with marine compost now with
bioplastics is that there's there's
actually PLA in the in the compost that
has broken down all the way. So do you
know what the life is on them? Uh well
it depends on the actual product and it
depends on the facility and how well
they're like you said in a in a in a
high heat compost compost facility. Uh
if they're really doing their job and
they're screening well um you can end up
with very little residue. But uh I used
to work in in commercial composting and
you know you uh believe the stuff that
gets through those bags. I would never
put it in my garden either. Yeah.
Uh so there's a bunch of different types
of teas that you can make and I like I
like to differentiate the difference so
people can understand what we're talking
about. uh plant teas that would be an
example of uh well something like this
here or uh using like and I'll talk I'll
give some examples here like nettles
comfrey where you take it steep it in
liquid and then water it um you're not
using compost as a source the main
benefit is is for nutrients not for
beneficial
microorganisms the other thing I hear
people talk about when they say te's uh
they're actually talking about leeing so
the stuff that comes out the bottom of
their compost pile or out the bottom of
their worm bin Uh that's not really a
compost tea either. Um it's going to be
high in nutrients, but it's not going to
have a lot of beneficial microorganisms.
You may get some bacteria that slide
through there. Um but that's something
that you would need to uh be careful
with and make sure to dilute down quite
a lot before watering your plants. Uh
the last thing I like to mention on that
is if your worm bin, you're getting a
lot of liquid out the bottom of your
worm bin, you're putting in either way
too much veggies or you're overwatering
it because it really you shouldn't get
anything on the bottom. uh manure teas.
That's something maybe your grandparents
did where they throw a bunch of manure
in a bucket and it stinks up in place in
the barrel and then you water your
plants with it. Um you're going to get
nitrogen and other nutrients, but you
are also potentially getting some
pathogens there. So you have to be
really careful. Um that's something that
I think would work great for roses, but
I wouldn't use in my vegetable garden
because I don't want to risk ecoli,
salmonella, all these things that are
known and a
rose. Uh put to sleep teas. These are
those things that you're buying um in
the store, the hydra shop where you you
know they have a label and you put it
you put it in a bucket and then they
tell you you can water it in. Um I
looked at a lot of these under
microscope and there's just not a lot
going on a lot of times which makes
sense when you think about it because
you're making these organisms go
dormant. They're left on the shelf for
who knows how long. Um I try to avoid
these products whenever possible unless
I don't have any other alternatives.
Uh compost extract is where uh the
farmer has a ton of a ton of compost and
doesn't have time to brew it all and
just needs a lot of liquid. So they're
just stripping the microorganisms off of
the com the soil aggregates out into a
liquid media and then applying it to the
plant. Um and then lastly, the one that
I'm most familiar with is airated
compost tees. It's also called ACT uh or
ACT. And that was really what our
company specialized in for 10 years. And
the whole idea behind it is really
simple. Uh we want uh aerobically
brewed. So we're selecting for aerobic
microorganisms. These are ones that want
high uh high levels of oxygen. When you
walk down to the edge of a pond or a
swamp and it's all that stinky smell,
that's from uh anorobes, things that
like low uh low to no oxygen levels. Um
whereas if you pick up really healthy
soil it has very little odor to it if
any that's all those beneficial
microorganisms that are are
growing. So uh next to that the water
source is really important. Having uh
having clean water without chlorine or
chloromines in it. Um and then lastly
compost is is the last is the last two
one of the last two ingredients. So
having compost that has good biology in
it because your brewer is only going to
replicate the micro you put into it. Um,
and then what food source you add to
that is going to determine what
microorganisms grow. So, it can be as
simple as literally throwing some
compost in a bucket, stirring it for 24
hours, you know, as you walk by
periodically and watering down with
that. Or you can get really scientific
with it in my brewer where you know
you're maintain your dissolved oxygen
levels above 6 milligrams per liter for
the entire brew cycle. And you know,
that's what our company is. We tested
all this and we came up with recipes and
I can tell you at this elevation at this
temperature you should brew for this
length and you'll get this this final
product. But don't get daunted by that.
Like to feel like you have to go out and
buy a brewer. You can make these things
at home. I can send you links. Um
there's plenty of ways to do it
affordably on your own too. Yes. The
same thing of like putting the the
compost is like putting worm castings in
and you can do the same thing with
Exactly. And is this the same thing
where like you put a a little pond pump
in the bucket
is that is that is also in your
experience for irration. If it is a pump
that has an impeller motor where the the
micro the compost the microorg
times that will kill off a lot of the
the microbes. Now, if you were to have
an air pump where you're pushing oxygen
into a tank where you use an airdood,
then um it's it's much better for for
the for the organisms. Um that being
said, when this industry first started,
you know, 15 20 years ago, they were
using little aquarium pumps and a little
tiny uh airstone, and then we found that
those really weren't maintaining enough
oxygen um to the levels that we wanted.
So, they ended up we had now bigger
pumps. And then we found that airston
really hard to clean. You have to use
like muratic acid and they get clogged
with bofilm. That's the because the
bacteria forms glues to try and stick
around there. And uh if you don't get it
clean, it will build up kind of like uh
Jeff's example of our bofilm being the
plaque on your teeth in the morning. You
wake up that slimy surface that's all
created by bacteria. So you actually
have to remove that. It's really hard to
do that on an air stone.
Uh, this is like this is our my little
lab at home. My little home office now.
It's pretty fun. That's my microscope
set up. Um, and this is what the tea
looks like under a microscope. I don't
know if you can really see, but there's
a lot of bacteria cruising around. This
is the the fungal hay. It's eating. This
is probably like a piece of alalfa or a
small bit of
organic. But this is what we're looking
for under the microscope because
otherwise you just have a bucket of
brown water. you really have no idea
what the heck is in it.
Um, and while this is the microscope is
fun, it's not necessarily a tool that
everyone needs to needs to use, but it
is it is a great one to have around. Um,
what power is that? This is this is
probably at uh 200 times magnification.
You're probably getting a little bit
more from
the from the camera itself.
Uh so the last thing in the little in
the biology aspect of this is uh
biological controls. This is something
that's becoming really popular in
cannabis. Um I know I had the issue with
grips and I was just going in the
flower. I didn't want to spray anything
because I was already scared to get some
pistol formation out here. So um I
bought some of the the cucaris which is
a insect right here that will eat the
juvenile ths. and uh roof feedles was
another one that will consume grips as
well as fungusn larv. So these are these
are alternatives and ways to control
uh different disease problems in your
garden without having to spray or
anything anything dangerous. Um there's
a bunch of different companies that sell
these online fire for shame back there
with natural defense. Uh I've used
Evergreen Brewers in the past. Um
there's there's a whole bunch of
different places you can get these these
bugs.
I wouldn't buy these in a store. I would
order them online and have them shipped
to you. Um, just so that you know it is
is going to be um fresh and and more
viable. So that was the first 10 years
of my gardening experience right there
and that was the extent of my knowledge.
So I thought okay if I have a problem I
put on more compost it solves everything
and I get healthy plants. I didn't
really get into the whole idea of these
different minerals and their and their
point the nutrients in the soil until I
read uh Steve Solomon's book the
intelligent gardener. Has anyone in here
read this book? Few people. Okay, great.
I always promote it in my talks. Uh I I
talk to Steve all the time online now.
Um and basically what what he did in his
introduction in his book I think is
really what made it sold me on it. So
he's found a territorial seed down in
Oregon. uh back in the 70s he was
homesteading feeding I think 80% off of
just his land triing all these different
seed crops um really committing to this
homestead lifestyle and over time as he
was doing this you know he was just
bringing in more compost like you teach
um and his teeth started his gums
started to get loose and his wife's
fingernails were softening and they
moved to Fiji and while they were living
in Fiji they uh their health improved
dramatically micro. So he wanted to look
they were in the exact same diet. They
weren't growing themselves, but he he
looked at where their vegetables are
growing and they found that they had a
field where or valley where where all
these veggies were being grown that was
flooded every year by ignous rock
deposits. So essentially the field was
being remmineralized with all these rock
dust every year by this
river. And uh so then he moved back to
Oregon and continued with the same diet
and started having the exact same health
problems. So he started looking into
this idea of mineralization and it
actually dates all the way back to the I
think the 1910s or the 1920s with
William Alrech um and since then there's
been people like Michael Stera Carrie
Reeves with the whole idea that if you
balance the minerals in the soil um
everything else all the beneficial
microorganisms and everything else will
take care of themselves whereas the
first half of my talk there when you
hear from um Dr. like Ingum and Jeff
Loenfells is like if you just if you get
all the beneficial microorganisms there
they'll make everything available in the
soil and you don't have to worry about
minerals. So Steve what Steve had to say
made a lot of sense to me. I mean if you
plant a tomato in soil that doesn't have
the right levels of you know zinc and
maganesees and all these other things
then they're not going to be in that
tomato and then what I'm eating is not
going to be as healthy as it could have
been and neither neither is the crop
itself. So this is where he started
getting the idea of soil testing. So, a
lot of his a lot of his book is is
pretty dry, but it's it's on the whole
concept of balancing the minerals to
grow nutrient-dense vegetables. So, the
healthiest vegetables possible. And he
claims that since doing this, uh, he he
actually started fat. He had to stop
eating so many vegetables because they
were so much healthier for him. Um, and
he also looked at different cultures
around the world and what sort of
mineral and nutrient deficiencies those
populations had based on the soils that
they were growing agriculturally on. So
really, really interesting idea. Um,
this is a test from a friend of mine.
This is actually on our soils that we
make. This is this soil that is uh I
believe three years old that we've been
amending, you know, every cycle for
cannabis. And uh this is the test result
that we got back. Now, these test
results, one test here is just $25. So,
if you have a garden, you want to test
your soil, it's 25 bucks. You're
probably going to spend that on
fertilizer anyway and not even know if
you're getting the right fertilizer for
your garden. Um so, it's a great great
option for people. The lab that we
really like to use is Logan Labs. Um,
was that your question? Is that correct?
Yes. So, Logan Labs standard soil test.
It's 25 bucks. It explains on their
website how to take a sample.
Um, the thing about So, King County will
give you a free soil test with ANL Labs,
but they don't look at anything beyond
uh your macronutrients. So, that that
free test doesn't tell us levels of
boron or iron or zinc um or any of these
other these other micro nutrients or
trace minerals that we may want.
So this is this is our greenhouse. I say
it doesn't work. I I don't know whe our
plants love it. I mean this was our
first year growing in this fashion. Um
this is actually from this year at the
beginning of the season. This was from a
couple years ago um in our inside of our
greenhouse that one of our own employees
built.
Um we have exceptionally healthy plants.
you really like to the reason I call it
biological horiculture is because I like
the idea of doing both that that
biological aspect but also incorporating
the science and horiculture of mineral
balancing and some of these other
things. All right.
So what I told Shango I would talk about
this whole idea of wildcraft and you're
growing your own nutrients. This is
comfrey. Um from this angle you can't
really see but uh all along here we have
um our fence line around our employee
garden. So we planted comfrey all the
way along that edge because comfry is a
dynamic accumulator. It pulls up
nutrients out of the soil into its
biomass and it produces a ton of biomass
which you get to harvest three or four
times a year and you can use it to feed
your worms to feed your animals to um
compost or just um a lot of times in
orchards they'll plant a gill around the
trees and literally just cut it down and
lay it back down right there in the
spot. So it's it's an amazing plant. I
actually have a couple here. This
particular cultivar that we have is the
R is a Russian cultivar called Bocking
14. It's sterile. So that means it's not
going to take over. Most people hear the
word comfort and they they freak out and
I get it. So where you do plant it,
you're committing to having it there for
the rest of your life. My employees
screwed up in a few places and now I
can't get rid of it. It's in the garden
itself. Um if you dig around that area,
just a quarter of a root will form a new
plant. So, it's super easy to propagate
too once you have it in place. Yes. Is
Russian is the Russian cultivar the one
though that you want to be really
careful about ingesting? I know there is
there sort of two basic types of comfry
and there's one that you really want to
be careful about ingesting. I read a lot
of stuff on comry and depending on which
website you go to, some will say it is
it has a you know a low melonated
toxicity and then other ones say it's
this amazing medicine. Um, I personally
don't ingest it. We do feed it in small
amounts to our animals and we haven't
had any issues, but I couldn't comment
on that. It's one of those things I
don't depends leaf or root and the root
while it has great use topically does
have the stuff that you don't want to
ingest. That said, I've been growing it
and eating it for 30 years and I'm
obviously
[Music]
okay. So, here's a nutritional profile
on comry. Um, you can find these for any
any plant. Um, this is a beautiful
flower. Bees love it as well. Uh, borage
is another one. I brought a few plants
out of that. Another dynamic
accumulator. It self slows, so wherever
you plant it, if you let it go to seed,
you'll have a ton of them. It's easy to
pull out, though, so it's not a big deal
if it does. And the flowers are actually
wonderful. They're edible. You can have
it in the salad. They don't taste like
anything, but they look nice and Uh
here's uh my dad grew a few plants a
while back in this tiny greenhouse and
we had some borage growing right there
and there cannabis. It was really
pretty. Uh horse tail or equism is
another one that's high in silica.
Again, all these things claim to have
these nutrient profiles, but I like to I
like to think back to what uh Steve and
these other guys are saying regarding
minerals. So if that soil is low in
silica, well that that equinim is
probably not going to be really really
high in it either. Yes. So, I've been
reading some articles that have been
talking about silica possibly becoming a
new macronutrient. Yes. Okay. Yes. And
like before people thought it was just
MK and that was it. And like now silica
is becoming starting to be thought of as
being almost as needed as MDK. Yeah. If
you if you Google uh silicon s l i l i o
n the strange medium element, there's a
wonderful article that's talking exactly
what we're talking about. Yeah. I think
it's a really really important
underappreciated nutrient. Is there any
issue with like overdosing plants with
it or besides potassium blocking out? Uh
I believe well with potassium silicon
there is because you're also applying
potassium but uh one thing I notic with
cannabis especially is it really likes
potassium and it seems to really like
silica and I haven't seen what those
upper limits necessarily are but uh yeah
that's one of the things about this is
it is a balance. So, you're looking at
your they're looking at their calcium to
magnesium ratios and I think there's
another one between like iron and magn I
don't remember. I have to go back and
read the book for some of those. Yes.
So, do you have to process the horse
tail, compost it, whatever. You can't
just put it in your soil around your
plant. So, most of these are either you
can you can use them a variety of ways.
So, you can just dry it and throw it
right on top as a mulch. You can uh boil
it and put it into a pot or you can um
leave it in a container with water for
an extended period of time and then
water your plant. So it's just you're
just extracting it over time for any of
these leaves. So for me it's as simple
as just taking a machete and cutting
down the the comfry and then laying it
right back down where where it came from
around my around my crops a lot of
times. Uh willow is another one. It's
where aspirin comes from and salicylic
acid. Um, it's a wonderful uh rooting
hormone, natural rooting hormone. You
can take the twigs. Um, I actually talk
about when I show those podcasts and uh
create your own your own rooting hormone
using this is a chart I got offline.
Just all I want you to get out of this
is that there are a ton of different
plants out there. I'm happy to share
this with people. I know it's possible
to read it here. Um, but for all these
different types of plants, they all have
different nutrient levels, provided that
those nutrients are in the soil. Um, I
do see tobacco on here or nitrogen. I
brought a couple tobacco plants here off
for you
guys. Uh, really quickly, this is
something that a friend of mine um down
in Oregon discovered. You may more
people talk about like the idea sprouted
seed teas or barley teas. Essentially,
barley is really really high enzyatic
activity. That's why we use it for um
for uh brewing beer for example. And
when you malt it, you're you're
arresting that end at its highest
enzyatic level. So they've done the work
for you. I actually brought some barley
to raffle off today, but literally all
you want to do is take it, throw it in
ideally a flower mill, but if you have a
blender or coffee grinder, throw it in
there and then uh take it and sprinkle
it over the top of your plants because
if you think about it, that seed has
everything that plant needs to live. It
has all the enzymes um and everything
else. Especially uh kiteese is one
that's really important to us as
gardeners. Um kiteise is one of the main
ways that the plant protects itself. Um
that's why we add crustation meal and
different different other aspects to our
to our soils. Yes. I'm sorry. Is that
special barley? Is it already molted or
you can use any barley? Molted barley.
Okay. You can buy it at your brewing
store. Okay. So molting is like a
commercial process that they do to the
barley and you want to make sure to buy
molted. You can you can buy regular
barley. You can sprout it until the I
think it's the merist stem is is half
the length of the seed hawk and then you
can grind it and then immediately apply
it. But you can also just go out and
buy,
you know, where they're like
scientifically doing it exactly right
for you that whole process. But you
don't want to put it in the water and
let it sit. That was the mistake I made.
Um these enzymes break down quite
rapidly. You literally want to just put
it right onto the soil and water it as a
really cheap, affordable
uh thing. And my uh my friend Jan, who
was the one who taught me about this,
I'm doing trials on it right now, but he
claims um
15% sooner flower times for cannabis.
And um he hasn't had any issues, he
says, with powdery milk.
These are pretty big claims, but
um it's it's it's a very affordable way
to do I know guys spending as much as
two cups a week on a 30 gallon pot. So
that's a top dress of the soil, not
application on the plant. Yes. Yes.
You're literally just sprinkling on top
of the soil after you after you grind it
and then watering
it. Uh biochar
um there's going to be a talk out here
on that. Uh essentially it's it's based
on terapreta this idea of uh Amazonian
soils that were enhanced over time
through the breakdown of uh carbon and
manurs and organic matter.
Um I wasn't a big fan of biochar at
first and uh started learning more and
more about it. The main thing it does is
erase the CDC for essentially the cat
exchange capacity or the ability of the
soil to hold on to nutrients. Um does it
work? Well, this is this is our soil.
Both of these photos, this is our soil
with 10% added biochar. So, we make a
biochar soil and my my buddy at Goldie
Garden set this
daily. That really shocked me on the
first cycle. I thought the main benefit
of biochar would be over time as it
breaks down it helps retain nutrients in
the soil, but it really it really does
seem to be a pretty amazing thing. Um,
and it's not just charcoal, it's
pyrolyze, which means they're really
really high heat at very very low oxygen
durations. This is uh my dad. This is my
dad made kil um for making biochar. This
is not a good example of a burn in it. I
was burning up a bunch of juniper. You
shouldn't see that much ash or white
stuff on top. But um this is the design
that he used. They sometimes even just
put holes in the ground. But he's trying
to take this concept over to China as a
way of increasing soil fertility over
there in addition to compost tees in
some of these villages. Yes. Is that
like a gi this giant walk? Pretty much.
Yeah. um what's in the outside there
that you're it's got like a a barrier on
the outside but then um the way it's the
way the air goes through it. If you if
you Google cont kilm you can read all
about them. I don't know I didn't know a
lot about the physical properties of
this was totally my dad's project. I we
buy our biochar from a company called
black biochar. We don't make our own for
our
soils. So the last thing and I'll go
really fast. Biological horiculture for
cannabis cultivation. Here is this is I
got this photo from uh Gold Leaf
Gardens. They're a 502
um here that does all organic growing.
Um they're using our biochar soil. Here
they have a micro clover as a um as a
living cover crop for their cannabis. Um
this is what we're putting into our
soil. I was going to talk about what all
these things are, but I think I'm out of
time. Um I have a lot of them up here.
Hey Tad, why don't you go ahead and go
through it? You've been taking questions
that we we've been going. We'll just go
into the question time. So go ahead.
It's interesting stuff. Okay. All right.
I go really fast there. So uh Alaska
Pete Moss. Uh, I like Pete Moss over
cocoa because it has um a little bit
higher cat exchange capacity. Um, the
biggest reason I like it is because it
contains existing microbial life. Uh, I
I've tested it my buddy Tim Wilson under
the microscope. Cocoa cord is not. They
both have sustainability issues. Um, but
I personally prefer Pete Moss. That's
why we use it in our soil and we use
this 50% of our total. Uh, old fish
compost. It's a 2 to three year age fish
compost. They do use some postconumer
waste which is why or sorry uh they use
some yard clippings not postconumer
waste so they're not using food scraps
but that's why I was curious about the
plastics. I was just talking to the guy
today. Um so hard to find high quality
compost. This was the best I've been
able to find. Um and for the most part I
really like it. I have an example of it
here. I used it in my garden. Uh earth
castings which I discussed essentially
warm poop. Uh volcanic pummus. It's an
irration source similar to perlite um
without being heated and it's uh it's
what adds porocity or arration because
the plants need that in the soil. Um I
prefer it over perlite because it
doesn't rise in the soil like I prefer
over perlite because it doesn't rise in
the soil like perlite
does micro catalyst is a product that we
have um it's what we use when we make
compost tea. We're putting it in our uh
in our soil as well. Um when we look at
the place for rock dust and basalt those
are mineral things adding trace minerals
to our soil. Um all the things that we
were talking about there with mineral
balancing. Uh calfos is soft rock
phosphate. So that's a calcium and
phosphorous source that's also mined. Uh
oyster shell flour is a mind calcium
source calcium carbonate. You could also
use agricultural line which we have down
below too. Exact same thing. Whichever
one is cheaper if you're looking to get
calcium in your garden. Um, organic
alphaalfpha meal. Alpha alpha meal is
probably my second favorite amendment.
It's it's very low in nutrients. Um,
it's put on 1% nitrogen, but you're
picking up something called
triricontinol, which is a plant growth
hormone, which plants really like.
That's why you always hear about people
using roses and it's a wonderful
microbial food like molasses. Um, you
can get wonderful compost teas and it
just increases your beneficial microbial
activity in the soil and it's really
cheap. Um fishbone meal is a phosphorous
source. Uh crustation meal is a
wonderful source of
um of uh slowreleas nitrogen and also
kiten we talked about that kitenise
enzyme that breaks down that's really
important for disease
protection. Uh kelp meal we already
talked about a little bit. uh nink cake.
Nink cakes is a is a holy tree out of
India that
uh is slowreleas nitrogen and then it
also is a wonderful bacterial food. I
found I was just testing that with the
microscope recently. But you can take a
couple cups of neck uh put it in water
solubilize it over a day or two water
the soil it'll kill all uh fungus net
larvae for you. It's a it's a
wonderfully affordable uh fungus net
remedy. Uh karani cake is also out of
India. It's uh it's another nitrogen
source as well. Fish meal is a fast
release nitrogen source. Feather meal is
a slowreleas nitrogen source. Uh bone
meal's got a little phosphorus in it. Um
calite and egg are just calcium sources.
Um I have microisal on here, but again I
would consider this a microisal
application. That's why it has some
asterics test in it. And then
beneficial. So that's what we're putting
specifically into our soil mix. There's
so many different ways to make your own
soil mixes as well. Um, but this will
just give you idea of some of the
variety out there. One thing that I do
like to caution people on is azamite.
It's actually it's a it's quite high in
aluminum. So, whenever I see a soil test
where someone use azimite, I can usually
tell right away just by looking at the
aluminum levels. I think there's better
options, especially locally. We talk
about mining things. Well, the the guy
green uh glacial rock test is coming out
of Canada and the basalt's coming out of
Oregon. So they're they're locally quite
uh geographically close to us, too,
which cuts which makes it a little bit
more
sustainable. Uh so does it work? Well,
this is uh this this is a crop that's
over four years old here that was grown
by a friend of mine um for under $50 in
nutrients per uh per light. So or per
yard of soil. So and he was averaging
about 1.2 to 1.6 pounds per light um
growing in this style. And literally all
you do is you harvest the plant. So you
yank it out, shake off whatever soil is
on the roots and uh take it away and
then you bring it back in a little bit
of organic matter and uh some we have
our nutrient impact. But essentially
it's a combination of those nutrient
ingredients that you would remend the
soil with and then 24 hours later you're
replanting uh back into that soil into
your flower room. So it becomes a much
more uh ecological and sustainable way
of growing indoors. Yes. Are you tilling
that stuff back into the soil or are you
actually just top dressing it and kind
of That's a good question. So, we're not
uh we're not literally tilling it. We're
we're disturbing the first few inches of
the soil which are naturally designed to
be disturbed anyway. Um I've had
multiple discussions with a friend of
mine of whether or not that's no till or
not. We are likely disturbing the soil.
So, it's kind of but we're not we're not
like digging it yet.
Uh here's what a room like that would
look like under uh say AutoCAD or
something. So we have the beds, we're
filling with soil, we're adding levels
to scrog those beds. Um and this is what
I think the most efficient way of
growing is. And this is what we really
promote for people because once that
soil is in place, we're not having to
move it in and out of the facility. We
can lightly amend it and uh everything
stays put. Now this is a this is a shop
moldy gardens. They're one of our
they're one of our favorite growers.
um they are doing 4x4 beds on pallets
that they literally can move those
pallets around the facility um as
needed. They're actually getting up to
three lbs per light um using the Vita
double-ended hoods and
uh they're using CO2 as well. But uh
really amazing people say that this
style of growing can't produce the same
levels as hydroponics and I I would
disagree. I mean they're they're doing
really really well.
[Music]
I'm a soil guy. Yeah. But uh yeah, so
this is Gia checking the light levels
with his meter on that. Oh, thanks.
And then uh the last thing I want to
talk about here is blue mats. Anyone
heard of blue mats? Yes. They are auto
waterers. They're awesome. So this
little carrot here, there's no
electronics whatsoever. It measures the
moisture tension in the soil. And then
you can control through these drippers
how much water comes out by turning the
little knob on top right here. And so I
have this hooked up to a reservoir in
this photo. I just filled. It's gravity
fed. And once I dialed it in where I
wanted to, you're done. You don't have
to water your plant. It takes care of it
for you. I had a guy leave to Alaska. I
came back. His plants were touching the
lights. Um, which was a problem, but
they were healthy. I mean, after being
gone for a month and having his wife
fill the reservoir. So, you can hook it
up to a mainline. Um, the most important
thing with these soils is water, keeping
the soil evenly moist. So, we found if
if you get a moisture meter from this
company and you keep it between 80 and
120 MR, um, you really keep that dialed
in, uh, you end up with a much much
better crop than if you have wet dry
cycles or you're not consistent with
your watering. So, we don't want to
stress the plant out um, dramatically
with our watering. We don't want to
stress these micro either.
Uh here's just some examples of some
hybrid programs. These guys are spraying
chemicals or not spraying chemicals, but
they're applying ionic salts. They're
throwing the soil after every run, but
they're still using a high quality soil.
This is in our biochar soil. Um and
these guys had a bumper crop with it,
but uh you still have the same issues
then of sustainability, and you're
having to throw away the soil every
cycle.
Um this is another one. These guys are
uh this is
uh Green Rush. They're tier three.
Um they they do a phenomenal job, too.
But they're also uh they're throwing out
the soil every run as well.
And they have a better photographer than
we
do. So, here's some resources.
Um Kiss Organics is our online store. If
you want to read more about these
amendments or anything like that, we
have a description under every
amendment. Uh Kiss Farms store and then
logo garden is a free forum that um I
have with Tim Wilson that you can sign
up or look at free information on there.
I have the Oregon Department of A list
on that website right now. Um these are
the two books I talked about and this is
my contact info if you have any
questions. Thank you for your time.
So, so yeah. So, so for the folks that
are the kind of people who don't like to
interrupt the speaker, I want to give
you a chance to ask a question. So,
we'll get three questions. So, who's got
a question or maybe you already asked?
Oh, there you go. What is your masters
in special education?
Yeah. Soil is just something I'm really
passionate about my whole life.
So that's special
education more
than topical questions. You talk about
developing a symbiotic relationship with
the microbes. Is there a best time to do
that? it's something that you plants
that you choose to do or like if you're
going to do it, is there a better time
to try and cultivate those or add those
or I think of it more like a mentality
or sort of a paradigm in terms of how
we're always treating the soil. When I'm
looking at soil and treating soil, what
I'm thinking about is that microbial
interaction and that activity. So,
that's what I'm always cultivating. I'm
less concerned with um what's going on
above ground as I am below ground. And I
just think it's just a it's kind of just
a a mental switch though is really what
I'm what I'm suggesting for people
regarding regarding these plants and
gardening. So it's something you're
always trying to do with you know micro
fungus with quality inputs with
composting compost piece plants all that
stuff.
You touched on bacteria and fungi but
you didn't really touch on protozoa a
lot. Um can you talk about like their
nitrogen fixing abilities and and how
that works? Yeah. So the main function
um as I understand it is that these the
prozzoa you know flagagulates amoeba
they're it's very very good at consuming
consuming bacteria. So then what they
excrete or when they die is that plant
available nitrogen or nutrient.
That's the
main and so like if you were to brew a
tea earlier in the production of the
plant like in veg would that prozzoa
dominant tea be beneficial for
increasing nitrogen for the plant
naturally or would that be detrimental
to like kind of increasing the burn or
anything like that to your plant? I've
never seen a properly made compost tea
burn a plant. You really you really
can't over apply it if it's made
correctly. But over time, so when you
first start brewing compost tea, you
know, let's say
70, good good brewer, good oxygen,
you're looking at around 24 to 36 hours
is sort of that optimal window where you
have all the diversity and that that
thing can maintain. As you start moving
further out towards 48 hours, you'll
start to see um one species of protozoa,
one one type of flagagulate uh with its
specific morphology and you'll see one
bacteria and it'll just kind of take
turns going back and forth in terms of
um all those yeah all those flags eat
all bacteria and then it'll die off
because there's no more food source. So
I always aim for that 24 to 36 hour
window uh for the most part um depending
on what I'm brewing. I don't try to make
a bacterial tea or a fungal tea. I just
try to make a I guess a nutrient
universal tea and that's fine throughout
the whole period of cuz I find like I'm
trying to make these dominant teas where
I'm using different ingredients of like
either kelp or molasses normal acid
sometimes to get more bacteria or
whatever is it worth it to try to put
all the effort in or just make one tea
the whole time. I would make my tea the
same for compost te's when I'm talking
about beneficial microorganisms and then
you could cater your nutrient tees or
plant te's more specifically towards
that that stage in yeah Johnny why don't
you be the last question then we'll move
on oh um I was curious if you know
anything about
uh well you mean in terms of these sorts
of microorganisms or like with humans or
there's a way to grow this propion and
I'm curious. Oh, well there. So, there's
a forum on Facebook, the Shango I'm part
of that's a probiotic farmers
association. They're they're primarily
focused on a lot of anorobic
microorganisms um in Bukashi and EM,
which I'm not as familiar with. They're
they're anorobic microorganisms. Um but
I I would say I don't really know if
that term has been defined yet for for
gardening or farming, but a lot of these
things I would say are friendly towards
that. Yeah. And for those for those of
us who do who are not ultra nerds on it
like people like me we you know I booked
him as a probiotic growing speaker. So
for most of us we would call this entire
presentation probiotic. Okay. Because
the idea is about creating the plant to
be as healthy as possible so you don't
have to add all these non-natural
inputs. Right? So it's probiotic. You're
making the plant healthier by by feeding
the soil and the soil takes care of the
plant. Right? So pretty much the whole
presentation loosely would be
considered. Yeah. So cool. So there you
have it.