welcome everybody to the 11:30
presentation with Jodi Lucas I am your
host Shingo lows from the shaping fire
podcast if you enjoy learning from the
top minds in the cannabis business
industry I encourage you to visit
shaping fire calm to enjoy in-depth
interviews on cannabis business health
and technique we've got over 100 videos
- that are all unique to us including
this presentation today so make sure you
check that out at shaping fire calm this
presentation from Jodi Lucas is he is
from smart robots and it's a title
designing the future Jodi has been on
the forefront of highly efficient state
of the art cannabis grow facilities for
the last eight years he has designed
built and retrofitted well over a
million square feet for some of the
biggest licensed producers in the world
today he'll be talking about designing
the future of cannabis workshop
horticulture let's give it up for
joining this never had someone doing
welcome to Portland in to Expo my name
is Jerry Lucas
smart girl pros it's a company that I
put together a few years back and doing
design builds this was about 2009-2010
we specialize in everything from
greenfield projects which basically
means moving earth building new
structures or retrofits which is about
80% or 90% of the market efficiency is
our main focus and when we're designing
and building Green Grove facilities
designing the future is pretty much
basically kind of encompasses all that
the key to success in this industry is
designed built everything revolves
around a grow facility dispensaries
extraction facilities all these things
rely on a grow facility and if you don't
keep in mind and take notes and build a
highly efficient grow facility and a
market that's extremely volatile these
days you're gonna be out of business and
is happening in states that have been
online for five six years and even newer
states that are coming online the price
volatility is is real and it's affecting
businesses and people are shutting down
so there's a lot of opportunities when
it comes to doing these facilities you
know high capex is very costly to build
these things especially you're gonna
build it right there's always an idea
that hey we'll build it right now try to
be as cheap as possible cheap is not a
word that you can use in this industry
mentality is we'll build it get in start
earning revenue we'll take some of that
money and then we'll go ahead and we'll
modify or retrofit it doesn't happen it
just doesn't you know a lot of investors
that come into the space or guys that
are trying to start off with little
capital you know if you have one major
failure you're out of business number
one number two if your cost of goods are
too high you're gonna be out of business
so with that kind of mentality I've seen
it since 2008 2009 do it as cheap as
possible we'll take that and we'll make
that money we'll put it back in it
doesn't happen it just doesn't cost of
goods it goes in line with your capex
you know you've got to be able to
manufacture a low cost of good and if
you're not if you're growing an eight
hundred nine hundred thousand dollar
pounds you know you're filing bankruptcy
it's just the way it is you know prime
example in the state right now
sixty-five percent is a hard number of
licensees that have not applied for a
renewal next year 65 percent of
recreational licenses why because the
market dropped down to high-end eleven
or twelve hundred dollars for high-end
greenhouses are saying maybe 600 or 700
and there are some exceptions but we're
talking 80 percent of the market that's
growing all the same products and
growing mediocre stuff because they
don't have the facility set up right but
it's costing them a lot of money out of
business we're seeing the same thing in
Colorado same exact scenario you know
value engineering ve great word to use
because you have to be aware of what
we're spending money so well we'll get a
little more into the value engineering
aspect but there is you know a component
there that you need to pay attention to
just because something costs more than
anything else doesn't mean you should
buy it yeah one of my favorite sayings
is just because it's on sale doesn't
mean you should buy it it's the same
kind of deal you can spend money smart
and buy high-end equipment without
spending top dollar for it as well this
is the big one too successful
methodology for commercial space you
know there's a lot of different ways to
grow this at these plants some work
better than others but when you're in
the commercial space you have to be very
aware of cost and how you can do it
effectively and cost-effective and we'll
push a little bit more into that as we
move forward the market volatility
I touched briefly on that but I think
you know we're gonna see a lot of
movement from a federal aspect sooner
than later there's a lot of initiatives
that are happening especially now that
our administration is on board with
pushing things you know more into a
regulatory environment and
decriminalizing rescheduling if you're
gonna see that the word swing even more
vastly as states are allowed to
transport product back and forth and
we've seen what California can do
specifically from a black market
perspective I mean in one one year they
could drive the price down hundreds of
dollars from black market product we're
going across the state imagine when that
goes
it's gonna be it's gonna be a massive
blow for a lot of businesses so the
first the first step of all of this to
build efficiency which is my favorite
word in this industry floor plans floor
plans are the baseline of everything you
know workflow needs to be kept in mind
and it needs to be very tight you know
labor is gonna be your most expensive
cost in these facilities and minimizing
you know links of walks and pass keeping
employees in a tight circle you know
believe it or not 15 cents here a dollar
here all these things are going to
affect your bottom line it's going to
affect your cost you know bench of
London lighting layouts you know educate
yourself you know there are vendors
there are companies that can help you
lay this stuff out don't try to build
benches on your own you know what ends
up happening you seen time and time
again what adventures were being bill
because they try to save some money then
they're failing all their tests because
there's mold and mildew that's growing
on the wood that's being absorbed from
water on the floor and those spores are
flying up the plane and on the plants
and a failing test and that's a problem
you know what it's a good investment
spend the money fertigation management
very important as well there's a lot of
opportunities there to control your
recipes control nutrient cause water
cost eliminate human error human errors
in this industry can be detrimental to
crops I've seen whole props or multiple
rooms get burned up because people would
make same nutrients by hand and a
hundred thousand square foot facility
and hand watering and then suddenly
you're out millions of dollars
mechanical systems this is this is a big
one calm and we're going to drill down
into this mechanical systems everything
next to lighting and your building and
if you're not spending some time and
make it
that you're going through some proper
designs or even entertaining some of the
stuff that's out there it's behind the
efficient your electrical costs are just
gonna crush you and last but not least
part of the efficiency equation
environmental controls
you can't put a thermostat on a wall in
a grow room and expect your maintain
temperatures and humidity controls that
can be it'll never happen just so floor
plans you know some of the big factors
regulatory and compliance is as a big
challenge you know you have to think
about stuff with security cameras
decontamination protocols which that's
one of the big ones that actually gets
left out you know you got to have dirty
come into the building and clean go into
the gross space this way here you can
actually can handle control pressures
depending on where your building is at
or if you're in a greenhouse you know
greenhouses is very challenging
depending on the demographic location I
mean here in this state alone I've
worked on some stuff down south and with
all the you know the non-organic
wineries and and veiners going on you
know there's overspray there's bugs
there's powdery mildew there's botrytis
you know so decontamination is a big one
and if you handled on the front end
you'll get through your compliance and
you will pass your tests and you won't
be battling bugs and have to have some
crazy IPM in place maximizing your gross
base that's gonna kind of go back to
your benches you know if you have a
hundred thousand square foot facility
you should be able to maximize that
space and utilize about eighty percent
of that or seventy percent of that for
canopy space for growing specifically
and there's a lot of ways to achieve
that you know I talked briefly about
workflow I can't emphasize workflow
enough I've seen a lot of facilities
where people are walking down hallways
that are 80 foot long when the floor
plan could cut that
have and you can get into a flower room
you know by cutting your distance in
half again two minutes here three
minutes there four minutes here spin two
people just kind of wandering around it
affects your labor and a few if you
can't grow a four or five hundred dollar
pound endure your and for all the pain
you know because what we've already seen
like I've expressed high in the market
for wholesale versity and nine hundred
dollars for large bowling you know and
when I'm talking two hundred pounds or
300-pound sales here and there that
doesn't leave you a lot of room if
you're growing an eight hundred dollar
pound out the door equipment locations
this really pertains to mechanical
systems and with electrical these are
things that be kept in mind when you're
designing the facility you want to know
where all your infrastructure is coming
in the building
and you want to have short runs as
possible because copper is very
expensive even aluminum wiring is
expensive and this is a lot of
labor-intensive kind of stuff expecially
from the high voltage aspect shorter
runs is going to cut down your
installation costs as well as mechanical
water drilling systems which we'll get
into a little bit more minimizing the
distance of travel is gonna be key
because you can save tens of thousand
dollars and maybe even more if you're
setting up your facility properly and
putting mechanical systems electrical
rooms in the right location all these
things equate to running a low cost of
good years back when I started doing
this I I saw what was going on I was
helping some friends set up their
facilities I built a hundred hundred
like grow back in 2009 which back in
2009 that was that was a very large
growth I laid the whole thing out
I drew it out late at I'll hand it off
to engineering and architects and they
were like learning like we've never seen
anything like this usually they're
having a coach
long as I started building more
facilities and getting some different
situations I was always trying to figure
out how can I make things more efficient
and how can we make more money if I have
a $700 pound cost of good in this
facility well the next one how can I get
it to 550 or 600 how can I get it below
500 because I think that they I saw the
writing on the wall I mean you know a
lot of people coming from the black
market and if you go back 10 years and
you look at what the prices are now in
comparison
they are 60 to 70% less in the black
market I mean all the way from New York
California the numbers are just dropped
tremendously so cost of goods are very
important which is all based on the
efficiency of your facility so so
benching you know it's a little costly
on the front end that there's a lot of
options in the market but it is a
long-term investment I mean this is a
long play this is this is a marathon
this is not a sprint you're into it just
try to make a quick buck you might as
well stop now because there is no such
thing the amount of money you're going
to spend on the front ends and the
amount of money you're going to try to
get your ROI by the time that two years
or three years rolls around price is
gonna fluctuate and you could be out of
business so you have to think from an
investment opportunity and that mindset
you know not just coming from a growers
mind come from a business mindset as
well that's a smart investment these
things will last decades so spend a few
extra bucks I mean we're talking $11 a
square foot on average ten dollars a
square foot it will last you a lifetime
there's a lot of controversy around the
single level versus a vertical growing
we've worked on a couple vertical grows
and they're very challenging
flowering aspect you know from a
mechanical and environmental perception
you have two levels of temperature and
humidity to deal with and he rises
naturally and most of the girls that
I've gone into that are vertical already
the top layer who is this very well
because the temperature is right and the
humidity is right and then the lower
level suffers because the humidity falls
it's gonna be cool so then you have two
different grades of product and you know
everyone thinks so if I go vertical I
increase my space as well it's not a
hundred percent true you're gonna get a
little bit more space but then you're
gonna run static benches and you have to
we'll have Iowa is in between that so
how are you really gaining that much
more gross space really not I mean you
have to have a minimum of three foot or
three and a half foot base on fire code
so how are you gaining at your space
then you've run into all the
environmental challenges I'm not saying
it can't be done but it has to be well
planned and well thought out and there's
a lot of new options in the market too
with actual to tear rolling benches that
that can help increase that canopy space
but from a mechanical perspective it's
it's challenging canopy management it's
very important and air movement these
things kind of play hand-in-hand it all
comes back to environment controls and
mechanical systems being set up properly
and making sure that you can move air
you can D humidify and you can cool as
much as you need it and be able to move
that air through the canopy
you know canopy management's you know
there's a lot of guys go and really tall
plants and they're shaving off or
skirting three or four foot of the plant
doesn't really make a lot of sense you
know for me as a Gore I would rather
grow shorter plants and control my
canopy and have a three-foot plan and
that way their light penetration you get
down but we can also get air through
there instead of trying to pull air up
through this deep dense Camden canopy of
plants that are six or seven feet tall
you have the same performance out of the
for a plan and you have shorter cycles
as well because you've altered edges
long it's a whole different subject but
you know canopy management air movements
very important lighting design there's a
lot of options there's a lot of
companies in the market you know educate
yourselves talk to them you know there's
reps that will give you information and
you know don't take everything as gospel
but listen take some notes and then do
some comparisons yourself and then make
your own decision or talk to some guys
that are using these fixtures but
there's a lot of options in marketing
some of them work better than others and
this is kind of falls into play with
don't you know buy just because it costs
more because it necessarily it's not
gonna get you more performance out of
your out of your lights you know the
technology hasn't really changed a lot
you know there's high pressure sodium
still dominates the markets EMHS made
some you know as made some advances and
could be used with certain applications
but you know HBS's still seems to be the
dominant source LEDs have made some
progress but as far as performance and
you know cost associated with you know
the capital expense it's very costly for
LEDs and I might still like to stick
with something that I know this working
day in and day out versus running with
an LED that you know they had their
challenges there's one thing that a lot
of people don't understand they they do
a doping effect because there's certain
color spectrums that they can't achieve
so they take a phosphorous they coat the
the actual the diodes when they heat up
then it manipulates the color special
well you know phosphorous has a shelf
life of 45 days a half-life so at some
point of time it's gonna integrate and
when it does degrade you don't know you
have no idea you know from a veggie
perspective we don't see it being
affecting the plants nearly as much so
from a vertical rack and veg LEDs things
work great but from a flowering
perspective you know a year year and a
half two years you're gonna have to have
a spectrometer and you're
we take measurements at certain periods
of time to ensure that your color
spectrum has not fallen off because if
you don't you lose 3% across your canopy
that's a lot of money especially if you
have twenty thousand even ten thousand
squared of canopy it's a lot of money
that's going to be lost ppfd in
methodologies you know know what numbers
you need and what those numbers mean you
know 900 ppm ppfd or a thousand eleven
hundred you know these matters the
numbers matter know what you're working
with and if you're gonna run higher P
PFDs
which is something I like to do it comes
with challenges you know more nutrient
more feeding you know you have to have a
more robust mechanical system but in the
offset you don't have to run your
electrical as much I mean we're running
nine and a half to ten hours and flower
you know and over the course of the day
that's big cost savings because you can
scatter your timing in between peak
hours and the whole peak hours you know
you're saving yourself money because
there is an actual thing of photo actual
photon saturation plants will get to a
point where it's they've had enough and
they're going to shut down there was a
paper that was issued by a Purdue where
they talked about the over saturation
and what they discovered that there was
effect and it affected a plan so
negatively that it would detrimental a
shutdown the photosynthetic engine of a
plant so if you're crushing your plans
for twelve hours at a high ppfd
more than likely you're gonna get stress
which is gonna call us lack of yields
lack quality norm Aphrodite I mean all
kinds of problems can happen mechanical
systems have I mean very very very very
important you can never have too much
coin you know your mechanical system is
going to cover coin humidification you
got to have redundancy in your systems
if you set up a system properly you
should never have to turn off a light if
an HVAC unit goes down or if a water
chiller goes down if you're turning off
lengths because you don't have enough
cooling or your systems are failing and
you don't have backup I mean you kind of
lost the race to
you know the systems that we design and
build we use a lot of options with
natural gas we do heat recapture on a
heat exchanger that we pump back into
the hydraulic system which is part of
dehumidification so they're highly
efficient they cost about 25 percent
more on the front end 30 percent but
your ROI is gonna happen a whole lot
faster because we've seen savings and
you were running ten fifteen thousand
dollars a month up to 30 or 40 thousand
dollars month in life and at the end of
the day that's a lot of money in twelve
months and that will affect your bottom
line also it helps you know going with
these natural gas options you know we've
see on the exchange rate anywhere from
Denver for example is 12 or 13 cents a
kilowatt hour overall once you throw on
demand charges here's another thing
people to understand you throw on a
bunch of lights there's a demand charter
so that electric company's gonna hit you
for and it's gonna tax you for 15
minutes and increments you know so you
don't see that your initial billing I
mean you actually have to take a class
to understand an electrical bill but
they find ways to hit you and next thing
you know you're paying an extra four
thousand five thousand dollars a month
because you're turning all your lights
on at one every single time we try to
find ways to offset that and find ways
to slowly ramp up lights you know use
natural gas so if you're paying 13 cents
a kilowatt hour even for an ear cold
water chiller on a gas exchange is about
2 cents 3 cents for a natural gas water
shoulder so these things can add up
quick we also developed a system to
where not only will recapturing heat and
use that for power
we're also capturing the exhaust and
cleaning and treating it and the
byproduct of exhaust is co2 makes up
about 60% of it and exhaust 50% so
suddenly you pay the same amount for the
setup if you're gonna use liquid co2 but
then you're you have no additional cost
because it's a byproduct for the water
shows themselves so from day one you pay
a set-up cost after that for the next
five seven ten years you got free co2
you're coming off your water chilling
system fertigation management the
seminar before me Sarah was talking
about RO systems and I think a lot of
things get lost in water people don't
realize that how important water is with
nutrient delivery using just the carbon
filter is not going to cut it you know
there's a lot of minerals that are in
your city water especially will even
well water they could be very damaging
but a plant can't uptake those minerals
that are in your city water and what
does that end up doing it ends up
causing problems with plant performance
because then it's gonna actually slow
down your uptake because the plant
doesn't know what to do with the
minerals that are put in front of it
with RO water day in day out you know
exactly what you have it's clean water
and your new two programs will also be
highly effective on the recapture side
we also use another RO system where we
can capture the condensation as well of
a leach a you know Alisha are generally
gonna see ten to fifty percent runoff on
average but condensation you're gonna
see forty percent of forty five percent
of water coming back to transpiration so
if you're pumping 10,000 gallons a day
through your nutrient and through your
irrigation you're gonna see at least
four thousand gallons coming back a lot
of people are just dumping that straight
out of into the sewer why not grab that
water you can get about an 80% rejection
rate on that which means you'll get a
person of four thousand gallons you can
get thirty-two hundred gallons of
reusable 100% clean water
and why would you do that it makes a lot
of sense you know there are going to be
regulations on stuff that's being dumped
down the drains we do a lot of work with
canopy growth in Canada and Aurora and
they're already on you know super
vigilant about what's going down the
sewer and they're already happy to put
protocols in place to eliminate what
they're putting down or minimizing the
amount of PPM's that are going down the
drain
it's going to happen here too I mean
don't be fooled you know as well as we
had a conversation outside about
slighting and and FCC regulations that's
coming you know of a fixture cannot pass
FCC regulations you're gonna see a
problem with that eventually because
there's a lot of frequencies that are
being shot out into the atmosphere
coming from these lights and if you
don't run with some fixtures that are
regulated or that are listed on the FCC
eventually we're gonna see some
challenges with that the automation of
thing I love about fertigation
management is removing the human error
is the big one the second thing is it
allows you to tweak recipes to a
specific cultivar some OGIS are very
particular some sativa is a very
particular i mean golden code is one of
them you can't feed that plant very high
ec values she just she won't take it
so with these systems they're all
computer-controlled
you can capture your nutrient programs
plug them in they'll never be they'll
never change unless you change them and
then you could take test results take
that data and then cross-reference it
and make adjustments where you can
figure out where in dial in plants for
specific camp anoints profiles terpene
profiles you know there's a lot more
than just feeding nutrient to to your
plants into your benches and the other
great thing is that also that minimizes
cost of nutrient and water you know we
do water delivery into rock wall we're
only doing about a liter a day for
feedings a liter a day versus if you've
run a three gallon plant with Coco
perlite mix or peat moss you know you're
looking at a gallon so multiply that
across 14,000
or twenty or a hundred thousand plants
it adds up I mean everyone knows
nutrients in a liquid form its tonics
it's not super expensive but on that on
that level that's very costly and unless
you know what you're doing with you know
with powders you know that's a whole
different ballgame it's a whole
different ballgame if you're gonna try
to mix powders on your own environmental
controls last but not least the great
thing about environmental controls is
once you set it it's gonna run every day
you want to set you want 42 percent RH
that's what its gonna give you and it's
gonna give you a one percent swing plus
or minus all dependent on your
mechanical systems if you want your
temperature 82 percent that's what
you're gonna get if you want seventy
eight percent in your mother room that's
what you're gonna get you know they are
a little costly on the front end but
again you're able to dial everything in
and every single day you're able to
control the environment which is one of
the most important things next to the
plan itself these systems will also such
as pre verbal capture data for you as
well tell you how much power you're
using that day what the peak load is if
you ever have an issue down the road
with a crop you know what and you're
down 20% you can go back and access all
your data you can go back into your
irrigation system you can go into
environmental controls and you can
determine what happened what happened
here and if something goes sideways
which is also great you get text
messages you get emails there's alarms
so there's never a moment that something
goes sideways on you that you don't know
because the system is there monitoring
all for you and the best part is you
keep everyone's hands out of it so no
one's going to playing with things you
know you can control your controls and
you're good to go and all these things
matter and to the portion of Labor
you know 30,000 40,000 square-foot
facility you know we set one up in
Florida 40,000 and they're running in
staff of 1718 people that include
it's the harvesting team because there's
all these systems in place that minimize
having to have 40 bodies to hand
transplant cocoa or take a container and
go into a deconstruction room and rinse
it and clean it
I mean labor again it's gonna be your
biggest thing and all these things are
gonna give you the efficiencies that you
need and that's gonna do it any
questions yeah he's I think the
microphone check check Hey
so I've heard a lot of debate over just
kind of a general questionnaire by a lot
of debate over having multiple smaller
rooms or having one large room can you
talk about like what would be more
efficient or what what's your opinion on
it so and and I didn't touch base on
that I usually do so there is this long
go in controversy and primarily is
really more about containment you know
but you have smaller rooms we can
control bugs we control pests if tom is
going into room one then he's going into
room two and there's Anna fest station
of room one where's the containment
there isn't there isn't its delusions
unless one person is going in and out of
each room that's never gonna happen and
also controls become much more intricate
it much more difficult to control a
bunch of small rooms versus larger rooms
so in a larger room we design larger
rooms primarily two reasons one control
becomes a lot easier the larger the room
is the more volume of air you have the
less modulations you have in your
environmental controls so 12-foot
ceilings is a little low 14 or 15 foot
ceilings makes a lot more sense because
even though you have this air above the
lights the lights are your vessel of
cool inventiveness everything is based
on your lighting load so you have the
space up here but that's conditioned so
if temperatures start to rise you have
this volume of beer to help buffer
so your modulations are a lot slower
which is what you want right so I mean
this is what we've been doing for about
five or six years larger rooms versus
small I used to do the smaller rooms and
then realize yeah this this is the way
to go well the problem with the vertical
is not necessarily about the the size of
the room does matter but it's about you
have two different levels then of plants
that are transpiring and you have you
know from top to bottom you've got two
levels of temperature load as well so
whether you're LED or you're growing
with a high-pressure sodium or something
that has more heat and and and let's
just say real quick a watts of watts of
WA the law of physics it's very clear to
generate that one want there's going to
be he and just because an LED doesn't
have radiant heat it has dispersed heat
coming through a ballast or a driver as
heat nonetheless there is there is no
LED is the magic answer to heat there
will be heat so on the first level
there's a second level see heat rises
transpiration will rise and then drop
back down so then you have this lower
level of humidity that you have to deal
with the higher level is going to have
less because the light and load and heat
load is higher up there it's going to
burn off a bit more that that humidity
and the more problem really comes in the
off hours when the lights turn off
because when the cooling shuts down and
hits its target number so you go from 82
agrees to come down to 62 when the HVAC
shuts off the dehumidification the HVAC
was supporting and the lights were
helping with is gone then what are you
going to do how are you going to
dehumanize that space because it's going
to spike it will spike and you will have
problems all through the dark hours and
you know when you get too much humidity
in the room the plant that's on a
cellular level the cells themselves will
stretch and when they stretch and absorb
more humidity well then it opens up too
if there's anything in that room that
plants gotta get it
what are you saying for costume is for
outdoor grows a straight outdoor yeah
what's that canopy you know fifty
dollars a pound
I mean most of the cost there is gonna
be I mean there is some nutrient cost I
mean but a lot of its watering watering
a nutrient you don't have a lot of labor
associated with it it's about what we've
seen greenhouse has been averaging about
150 it's about normal and again that
depends on demographics depending on
demographics so you know if we built in
desert ponds for example the cost is
more because we have to put in you know
infrastructure for cooling so we have to
still condition the air so we're
building full mechanical systems to
offset that heat so it can swing but
yeah you know about $150 $200 you know
on the indoor side we're seeing 350 to
I am setting up a nursery in Southern
Oregon okay and I wanted to go back to
your comments on natural gas was that
just for water chilling or was that also
related to age fact I've got natural gas
coming into my place it's not hooked up
yet but we're playing using it for the
propagation room I was reading some
articles on dark heart nursery in
California and they had mentioned that
they were analyzing their costs and they
were figuring out that they're spending
more money on dehumidification than they
were on on cooling and I'm sure they
were using an electric do you
modification I'm not sure most opposed
most likely electrode Rima Fakih Asian
is like it's just like AC so I mean it
consumes a truckload of power yeah so
they had moved to DX minutes yeah and I
haven't bought my HVAC systems yet
working with Energy Trust Oregon and
evaluating everything but if you had any
thoughts on that for propagation
hardening off room I mean they
appreciate it yeah I mean you still need
some dehumidification there I mean
you're naturally running them you know
higher humidity is 65% you know 70% so
you really only need to stop it from you
know peaking past that but you know the
dehumidification that we like to run I
mean everything is water-based you know
so we use a hydraulic system where we
have a boiler as a backup and we're
capturing heat off the chill inside but
I mean there are a couple options in the
D hue side that you could probably take
a look at it'll be a little bit more
efficient than just running standard
electrical
but yes supplementing the gas is is
gonna be helpful it just depends on the
space and the budget I mean you know all
those things are gonna matter
but yeah electrical duplication about
you I've got one for you Jody so I know
that you're continually driving
efficiency to be able to get your price
per pound down as the primary driver and
also when I'm down covering and talking
to folks in NorCal right they're very
much into artisan and you know one acre
cap and you know the the flour is better
with the with the shadow of the farmer
and you know off you know small-batch
artisanal up right so so setting aside
the price per pound for a moment right
because obviously that's a really
important driver if you want to play at
all absolutely what kind of quality of
product and the final flour are you
seeing at these level of efficiencies
and mechanization versus you know
smaller traditional gardens that we saw
during during the Prohibition era where
there was a lot more labor involved and
in California build its name on the
quality about that product because of
that and it's good question I mean but
the reality is as we you know
essentially we're building those
facilities so that it gives us the
ability to grow nothing but high-end
product and that's all gonna be you know
based on certain factors and the
genetics themselves are gonna play a big
role in that but we do all these things
so that we can grow the best product
that we can it's not about just a cash
crop in less turn as much volume as we
can
let's turn as much volume of high-end
product and because the market is very
small when it comes to that high-end
product but all of the stuff is so that
you can't grow a high-end product and
alleviate all those stress points as
stress as what's going to affect your
harvest in your crops and from
generation to generation the more stress
that it cooks over the years the less
quality that you're going to have
to the smaller eels you're gonna start
seeing but that's I mean that's what all
these things are for this is the B in
that 8 percent of the market then the
high end of the market because if you're
going to spend the money and you're
trying to grow a cash crop why grower
level stuff because it's gonna cost you
the same amount of money you always want
to grow the high-end stuff so that's
that's the target here is to grow grow
better quality product than other guys
down the street Thank You Jody thank you
anybody
[Applause]