right on we are going to get going
welcome everyone to the first expert
panel team period Expo
I'm your host Shango love hooked on the
shaping fire podcast if you white
listening to the top experts in the
industry talk about the passion that we
all share in cannabis I encourage you to
tune into the project you can pick up
flyers near the door I also want to let
you know that joke magazine is
sponsoring a partay tonight on the roof
of the Clarion Hotel that starts at 6
o'clock see box
sunshine you favorite canvas
professional friends and she comes
through yet so that's not the route all
dependent hotel that such a box this
can't open the next 50min is
establishing your brand identity I'm
very pleased to welcome to Las Miranda
and you died you and does she have
daunted so these are merely highlight
the East feeders biome I encourage you
to google them or talk to them after the
panel to find out more first
some stage left
Amy Donahue is co-founder of hybrid
social and Kansas brand the agency
specializing in organic local media
customer relationships in co branded
she's based here in Phoenix to her right
is Celeste
Randa founder and CEO of canvas
marketing lab the whole search service
agencies custom suit pocket watches web
design so she
promotion and she is made in California
enter her rapist unit often comes in
emerging market with an expertise in
building ran that week she has an MBA
from Reuters business school and
undergraduate in molecular biology for
instance which I had a mission she's off
to jump in and of the Southwest chapter
of minorities for medical marijuana
Thank You three for joining us today
so the format is pretty casual today the
goal is we're going to present the
panelists with a question I'm going to
start with a different 11 each time and
and get all three of an opportunity to
comment on the topic and then we'll just
go through and see how many we get
through in the next 50 minute we will
also have and mincer questions at the
end so with that just are beginning for
the first one so any facility can
accompany simply come up with a name
that sounds good to them and then go for
it only to find out later that it has
some problem what advice would you give
us a new canvas company so that they can
increase the likelihood that they choose
an effective brand name wagon start as
we can't brand ourselves being on our
personal passions are these that are too
close hoping differently our logos to
somebody then they're missing
your audience so always hire
professionals especially in an industry
we know what the trends are like if you
do it super self again nobody's gonna
get another a beautiful promise
great you know I would add them there to
remember even statues lesser are kind of
terminating this joke and you make it
memorable when you make and catchy so
kind of attacking me a lot of times it's
two words the first word text words are
never a letter I worked real well for
have been right back also in addition to
that remember to make it trademark if
you know you remember to make it
something that you cannot trademark
gypsy two cohorts and my plural for the
devil seven even bleach keeping book so
keep that in mind a leader I think this
goes back to trip recipes that they have
to start with geosearch only little
marketer first and foremost so I always
look and I find is doubly so because you
can't find any probably first over event
I look for the social media angle
complete or not in addition trademarking
you going to the property to be able to
build your brand actually if you can
secure the platforms that meet you of
that sex became unconscious where you to
agree v8 to do surgery and I would say
even experts compatibility crisis I was
opening my company merging marketing I
gave you 15 Mary Jane all the time and
has applied for digital voice we share
ways on say how you compute severity
marketing I'm still I'm actually looking
to change my own that's the point is
it's a learning thing and the Pieta
finishing people you can before Kansas
has to remember like houses social trade
and you can be very messy them still hit
back of the messenger by the way if I
can't drive or social I did not react I
hired an proprietors be lasting living
thank you this is a great segue so so I
also agree and the best way to go to
hire a professional because if you are
trying to name your cannons company it
may be the first company that you've
ever made and and you have your owns and
experience however if you're using a
brand strategist they have hopefully
have beautiful doesn't making prophecies
on River belt and so let me connects to
where you know let's say that for
whatever reason the opportunity is not
going to hire someone and they decided
that their executive team is going to do
themselves now all four of us as brand
strategist we've got our favorite
exercises that we like to run our
clients through to help them come to to
generate Heike
so so we share one of your preferred
exercises
to the client insulting generating you
know I would say first and foremost to
try to combine what you do with a word
begin and his trademark a you know and
if you can find those two things I
secretly visited you know hip again if
you can find an identifier along with
something that is unique I think that's
right in the alley that you want to be
and you know I didn't mean to create
this brainstorm and you know I think
it's just talking a client will be the
topic client through and pretty soon
you'll figure they answer their own
questions and it's just hitting them
leading them to do and so you know talk
about you making a few conversations
with friends and family remain you know
can talk through who you are who is your
consumers what are you doing and the
morganelli
through your own discussion you'll have
up with your ranked communal event I say
what she said but we basically take that
thing and if you have charging being a
force that allows us to kind of continue
our customer or client would at least
that be
Asian and Indian students returning a
selvage a lot of the exercise we were
not in develop literally digitally
stalking my clients and the potential
customer base that they're tied to to
reach in that way I would say I think
it's culturally hacking we're trying to
figure out LaHood we want is about the
particular target market ax will lead us
this rightward several types of hurt
resultant one of the things that I
always recommend it to clients when I
was in the Brandon game with don't go
which necessarily your first choice
they'll come on the quarter five-day
lightweight I like number one to number
two or number three or number get by
that you could totally desire and then
choose from those going from the first
one that you get you that you might it
might be great that day but for it to
create a a company name that's not
staying power you're going to do much
better to choose one from and rule five
that your Orion moment online them so
let's start out the other the schita so
a comfortable Sarang silver he's kind of
established out of potentially go code
them the names let's talk a little bit
on logos so the company grand mark says
a lot about coming right and it is a
thing of being open how to respond to
them would you name a common mistake
that you see in logos and other software
problems on the keeper real high in
somebody else's style if you will is up
the state are taking that isn't
especially in Canada that shape because
the underground for nearly 11 years of
birth yet um listen usually might not
with a granite or even I can even pay me
what I want the to apply but I would say
that ultimately patches are your way to
get a seasoned business we know we
already saw Girl Scouts kind of doing
that is the name of strength so I looked
at the region I think I see I need to
get someone company with a brand logo
that looks exactly like something out as
a play of it and it's so cute it is so
clever for not real-life business you
know it's one of those things is been
sailing for last look of sharp
interesting because my firm did ran
study a couple of years ago that ran for
the big topic of conversation about to
leave or not to be a logo and you know
there was so much discussion on do not
leave to give me dreams values this by
mainstream this map and so we didn't
study that we did it for a company we
did a tribal to about having me
we did a child oh that did not we put
the prize into the dispenser
that all see the packaging design on it
right now can't believe you're not the
package with the elite although it
wasn't mapped directly so almost three
times more the subs when it comes to a
local you know I understand these a few
months ago main James and I'm all for
that
but also keep in mind that your logo
cannot be totally off from who you are
or what you do and I'm just as much as
you can to say who you are the amatis
when you create your local you know
another problem is even that in common
color a lot of people will use colors of
the color you know that are right next
to each other which is technically very
definitely the lowest empty consumer
vision will be grabbing the top of
shelving remember to try to use the
color colors that are opposite on the
color wheel in color spectrum and we do
that work much better as well wine first
don't use fiber when you pay five
dollars for nothing your brands like for
five dollars and I understand that not
everybody has a budget right a lot to
random self but I really can guess when
you pay more in this industry I should
go a little bit more towards the
mainstream when I work with brands I
like stuff that's more coming cheap
an example is impossible we argued well
but Howard sterling he was on that bet
he had to edit in public was more fun to
me that your engines go all out I'm
serious
so we can hold stuff back and be more
clever than the hey we're a cannabis
company I kinda like that better I kind
of like the creativity of that and no
offense to anybody like it kind of think
the leaf is easy and I would reiterate
that you know during the last question
we mentioned going with a professional
and it's almost always a good idea to go
with a professional even if you just
want them to rubber stamp anemia or
anything that you're a mullet then I'm
going to come to a graphic designer
for goodness sakes go with something too
professional because once your brand
large in the market you can't take that
back
and yet you're if you're starting a
company that means you got short on
funds that leaveth a conservative on how
you're spending your capital so that is
a good place to spend your money because
you know if you want to come out as a
quality product if you want to deal out
in health even if you want to go very
like edgy and talk a lot about it you
still want to be a clean design that
really stands itself alone by itself in
the market you're going to get that
accomplished graphic designer and and
also since we've mentioned having an
expert to help you both with name your
company and with choosing and then
building your logo I would say there's a
good case to have it lead to different
people very often the person who's how
can you name may also have some
the design shops but the reverse really
isn't as strong to have a graphic
designer
help you with the aiming aspect because
people play vocabulary and design at
this well they're different books to do
great can also add that when you are
first starting off and you have nothing
keep it simple right because ultimately
grand and local school few iteration
through the years just look at embassies
of adult absences that you showing you
the unit have transformed the department
without reviewing that therefore target
in his transformative actually doesn't
matter in general but is transformed as
well this is you won't be able to have
iterations and then you have
professional errors up couple on top of
things that you may be started up with
and we can reduce it into something has
been validated plus rebranding gives you
more attention you have a party or some
kind of rebranding launch which is
getting into orbit
when you can pick you up the attention
to you mean you remember when SP
regretted their logo I actually whatever
Bernal run trade journals for a lot of
just they're simply changing their logo
so so now we're going to start with us
left in the middle there so it's less
you'll there are so many players in each
candidate needs you know whether it's
extraction or retail that competition is
really severe what's the strategy that
you like three staying a company apart
from the rest of the pack as far as the
brand experience goes
you know I think that that also has to
do with demographics you know and where
you're located a lot of these products
can't cross the economy so keep that in
mind you know if you've got a product in
California and we're launching first in
the product is you know in New York you
know those to me that's benefiting our
brand now if you're thinking about
licensing mass sales growth you also
have to definitely because you can
cocktail in them but you know in the
initial branding you know I would
definitely say that look at your
demographics and ask to do your consumer
because they'll also have to do with
your branding and your branding method
no leave my current over 40 clients and
four different countries and that alone
is branding huge nightmare because you
your branding so many different ways not
only for a safe territory inhabited
country and you know everyone can just
very very very different so look at what
you're you asked as well when you're
branding and you know please that
consume you know if you have your
consumer in New York is very very
serious tactics not sourcing or isn't a
casual laid-back
keep that in mind especially because
remember when most of these products
your combined with in your safe so keep
that in mind
[Music]
we are crazy endlessly online so what I
do is it to show the personality of the
company in your online presence so your
Facebook page or your Instagram account
if you're at one company like mine a lot
of that voice comes through so it is
about like celesta and knowing your
target audience are you telling someone
like me who the jack woman or are you
going to a gentleman through morning
that would be if you're really really
new to initiating like audible the hell
is my target audience what I thought of
my client is really identified the white
space opportunities I did that in
corporate America that's worth a lot of
companies that will say okay I set up
the company for success is to actually
look where there is the best opportunity
where there is a competition and is
actually easy and I think once you
fulfill the single detail about
everything and you show me a one-way
that's relatable to the particular
demographic differences have Wilson you
know like this one interesting thing
about Canada so what we've seen so far
the Kansas sale cycle it's not so much
about gaining new customers to come to
Canada because people come to Canada on
their own the chance of sale cycle is do
have wheezy [ __ ] so really when I was
competing against the other
on the shelf next to you and they'll be
really aware about who's already in the
market and what they look like and
differentiate yourself from them and
think about who you are who you want to
be in comparison to them because in the
end you know there might only be four or
five different company mouths shelf next
to you and they are going to be in the
computer and even one more thing on that
to is done I find that a lot of my
clients become me or even call me about
people are thinking about launching
brands being haven't even taken the time
to go into a dispensary hang out to see
what people are pulling off the shelves
see what they're saying you know when
they pull it off the shelf just hang out
purpose in some mystery and see for
yourself
you know why are they going out for
product talk to the people that are a
little bit faster you know people tell
you more than you think if you just ask
and ask what is the roughest product
that your body you know what me to
purchase it and you'll see that they
tell you yeah definitely then take that
in mind you need um proposition and just
twist years a little corner choosing
reasons what you do you know I wanna
double down on that you know blood
enters are our own unique lot you know
there's something that you want to take
their advice on living that you don't
well one thing I they are experts on are
what people buy and I think think of no
other thing for all of us as Canada's
entrepreneurs the after byte header then
you know which were these product rise
to people pick up which one guilty
synced and visually acquaintance and
then one
- visually excitement event in read you
know ingredients or strength or house
use or letters their lesson your
students
this is incredibly valuable information
the bartenders can be a focus group for
you they can't get anywhere else and
honestly a lot of people don't give
blood vendors the respect that they can
deserve on this topic and so if you ask
them for their opinion you'll get a lot
of opinion and it's all three and to
your vendor
let's see chatter so so Celeste hit on
this a little bit and let's let's start
with the in here so on so do a lot of
damage viewers at the state level you
know are looking to eventually go
national either they want to take their
company national or they're looking to
get bought out and put together the
larger brand
what kind of advice to each of you give
to your client who need to be
competitive now at the state level in
order to get their revenues up so they
are on a capital but they also want to
the bigger national market doesn't
normally playing it yet but they want to
make sure that their disposition with
their brand that they can get bought out
and then in putting local with much
other cons right first hire a trademark
attorney right into decision even if
you're going to be local turn on or two
or five years you need to be trademarks
and a time but second would be if you're
creating a great intial blood once you
go and ask them before are we clear
I can tell you how many people like that
I saw you wagon because it is a small
industry still but if you are active
online in a great website things like
these create that lets you handle it
every networking group where in Canada
your name out there willfully it gives
me those what new mention I know I say
to again try to keep yourself as unique
as possible you know one grandma did
that really well was role and they made
their branding their look unique their
colors recognizable things like that and
was not be purchased to do as how many
or or merchants or whatever was what you
built their purchasing and grandpa and
you create the recognition which is
worth looking hard on creating that
uniqueness that recognition and then
also don't forget the element of quality
and customer service because we know
what is going to purchase or work with
you if you have a bad customer service
or your quality in our so keep one nine
to twelve about the marketing of effect
and branding branding brand don't get
out the bass coaches and I would ask
that reduce paper the first is that an
educated consumer is going to be of
that's the person s bring more people
back to the table so in addition to
really crafting what your product launch
strategy is verbally you want to
leverage the visual space getting blown
away and you're really looking to
provide education which is global and
means for advocacy which is also verbal
the second thing is I feel like when you
think about a national strategy versus
the local one you're looking at are you
packing into Main Street so yes please
more cannabis consumers absolutely is
again two episodes up but if you are not
competing you have not use it in 20
years and you're the person than just
your element still using it or pictures
of abuses in the Darian brush and in
realizing that it works for my own where
I work for my son and I want to be how
are Celine you're not necessarily just
going to be sold on cannabis and so you
want to make sure at the very least
you're reaching that population of
housing people type accident educating
them they want to be educated to hunter
and evangelist for you if you do have an
income saying if you do what you did
earlier and tell my friends to and
ultimately that's why would we want us
elaborating that powering in that reach
on a national level now what you think
that that's right hand or a vacuum so so
what we're talking about expanding from
state levels in the national level you'd
only locally legging didn't be
participating in all of your your
locally then your media events like this
for the you know that Arizona market and
you'll go with these things talk to
people and establish yourself in your
reputation for both you and your product
at state level but we're all looking for
hopefully you know getting your bought
out or when nationally
that's where the real serious dollars
are and so that brings us back to
digital which all three of you are
experts in and so I want to top us out
there that what was the thing that I
find that the top level jazz companies
are doing that others are not they're
creating their own original content and
you know so many options off the doors
they don't have time just looking at you
they're busy and so they just take
whatever new story is going around that
day and they just repost that and that's
all that happens people end up hiding
you because they're seeing those same
articles everywhere else and so you know
what I don't tell people is you know
take pictures of things that are
happening in your company's world that
that gives you a sense of authenticity
and create the feeling that their review
actual humans behind your coming so for
this question along the same line is
what are some suggestions or even just a
suggestion that you give your clients on
the Digital side o how they can seem
Nilla tangible real human company but to
their Facebook I think it starts with
including yourself with a story so I
started off as a
knocked over a Campari to see these are
not typical have children girl but I was
a former stoner and Hobbit I started on
watching videos of Celeste actually
talked about marketing and then I wanted
to lead a question like that when I
talked about Ohio at the end of this
executive I don't know where as four
months ago I had $13,000 and their
language would be I think it starts to
telling the story itself there are not
enough boys and you know I was thinking
stage one of my different people but
back tell that story that ultimately so
I think that the more dreams with your
own story out there the better and the
more effective and filled but maybe
wanna bid column select businesses as
well and then that was followed with
education about I restarted so some of
the advocacy pieces were all in the
community together and and our hope and
purpose emerge eventually that means I
think that that power you need to be a
digital phase really works and you can
start being no cotton just attorney on
yourself
other classes I didn't work is like I
have data event I forced people in our
profession to make a multi happen figure
out your hashtag hashtag is very sexual
do please leave normally
so that becomes worse you know I would
say that we are along the same lines
between the humanize yourself and a lot
of my clients with my social media team
it'll give seven coordinators and it's
so funny it can get boring it can get
glance there's only so much community
propose so much education you can give
so much about this so yes
give those things that's important but
at the same time humanize yourself for
constantly Ellen your height send us
photos of you guys working in the office
send us photos if you guys thought it
would be doing you know have to have
your product there's a photos of all
these types of things that humanize
yourself you know and I think it's very
important to to passion pain to write
your own carcasses you know that
authorship is invaluable that SEO
centigrade is the analogy those links in
announce when people rerun your original
articles are invaluable so it takes time
no more delay I don't like to write but
I do because there's too much value do
not and so was to a going in you lose
too much vitamin value in new media and
so take the time right
optimize those articles from SEO athlete
horses welcome get Patrick
you crazy we have humanize yourself and
you're claiming to be a big difference
cultivation fix every time I post a
cultivation picture from a dispensary
clients I get more engagement than
anything since you and I have any
complications but everybody out there is
not an amazing people - seems like that
it's the innovative Roman and and it's
bit syriza trying being behind it things
like that it's also branding yourself
and make sure you have a professional
photographer because I'll do a driver
and on the other one what am I going to
can't remember there was just a
cultivation so anything was evil but
tender picture show pictures of your
waking you can begin what if someone's
on the fence about it there are diesels
are afraid of what it's going to look
like inside it's transparent as you can
be it's going to help you right now
that's well said and you know should so
many of us are any industry a lot of the
things that we all get used to the end
consumer is definitely not you - I mean
it will happen out in kind of readings I
remember the first time I saw a male
plant getting off Holland and on the
early days windii never see that because
the
Morini be called early on consumer never
got speed one and a prism I saw it you
know fingers addendum polymer will
commence nature in India you do that
because you can't think about what's
happening in your shop you know but
better not get the retail job or an
extraction shop whatever we're going
your place of business
think about what you're seeing that
other folks are you don't know how
popular and how much share those big
bags of nodes are you know that
extractors both you to see where these
other eyes get big and they get all the
dreaming about a right and so think
about what your company is doing that's
cool in college the same thing that you
keep out on with your own employees at
work take pictures of that stuff even
corn pictures and you'll have somebody
there like you know like this major Cody
continue to seem fun buying zine let's
see here so so what so you know many
companies find great success in
co-branding with another company to
benefit both what should a company look
for in a co-branding partner I
definitely think that you need to be
able to cross-promote with partners you
are in a relevant situation hedging
reversible and that's one of the things
that we love doing that are because the
amount of clients we have we have
promote them all and it's great because
we will drive traffic to both of them
even more traffic and get more haulers
and more engagement because we're
prospero me so we can go to prosper look
to get happening to are relevant to what
you do look to engage with influencers
who have more followers than you or
people or a captive sometimes use their
hashtags and cross promote that way
another thing if you have a product to
shout out dispensary you'll see this out
pays off in the long run that sort of
thing look for for that relevance in
children I don't even think I haven't
even asked that that was a really good
explanation as always make sure you
information as well not all the time
silences are really cool with it because
if they have a good for instance I'm it
means keeping track that and the limited
but I I will pad and across from uh
between grant design
I think there's also an interim opponent
don't forget to ETL fundamentals that
you see every day in consumable Target
or Walmart Walmart store well you can
trust to look into that way and well if
you have a heart that goes in the
dispensary you can you know make a lot
more headway with a number of uses you
got going out the door get in order to
dispensary itself awesome potion
satisfactory and you use those win by
following up with the support individual
space like hey we've got something going
on to this particular place 20% off 25%
off so there now to the time
I also recommend eating a little bit so
that people are able to track how much
having additional incremental x87 to the
floor a little type of hospital so
they're so kind of order yourself eating
program you're not sure what that is you
know right learn did I actually learned
it from uh from Puff Daddy right I mean
this hop is is it is the original go
grinders you put on an album and then
you have all your friends yes on your
song so now I can find one album but now
you're getting paste of you know five or
seven other artists on that same
mountain and so now you go by you know
JB's album and now up now you can turn
on in like six or seven people and it
goes on and on from that we do the same
thing again if you are a Grover jeweler
do coke party a co-branded party with
one of your retailers in it Imperius
Expo is is go prank all over the place
I mean hiring already catch the dope
magazine party tonight right so so we're
talking about Japan
tonight I'm from the chafing fire
podcast there's an Phil Gramm so there's
all these different ways as soon as you
think about people in the scene who you
can consider allies and who you would
like to have your grand mean little bit
just go ahead and reach out Wednesday
Able's lets you soak them together and
cross pollinate our markets and I think
we'd all agree that it really works
wonders to Train audiences let's see so
um so this is this is an interesting one
so so it worked out use yes so don't
enter state level um when are your
favorite places to spend advertising
dollars to get brand awareness one
digital world but I do think that the
matrix for marketing at the balance of
hosta is very important
I will say that the biggest bet are
going for me is going to be first proper
action especially if your saga after
action is