oh right
looks like there were people shuffling
about and she said it my name is Mark
Lewis hello everyone why does it feel
like David o'clock in the morning snow
so I'm here to talk to you today about
cannabis breeding biotechnology terpene
these flavors we taste but to do so I
can have to tell some stories because I
don't know of the many plant breeders no
one higher how many people use cannabis
okay so this isn't going to be like deep
into plant breeding and informatics if
we want to do that I'll bring it Briony
up afterwards if we can we could explore
some of those topics but this is more
just kind of an overview of where the
industry is going and how innovation is
one good be a key segment and growth you
know previous too busy meant used to go
to him pecans and in CIA and all this
replaces work the biggest innovation
from the standpoint of the conference
goer was a new trimmer or you know some
extraction system that they hijacked a
process that was already fine-tuned and
Barban applied it to cannabis so I guess
my point is it was a whole lot of
innovation one would fancy LED nights
grouse changers all stuff that
agriculture and the $1 a pound or
conventional basil could support right
you can't can't spend the 20 million
capex and a range of greenhouses if you
don't plan to make it 20 million dollars
in the first few years and that's worth
standing in the cell looking down at the
marketplace you know we have to think
you know what's what is the largest
segment and in the market for
what's kind of a story and then in the
biggest area that were actually
innovation in this thing's was it isn't
any technologies per se it's a different
order and for us to understand that area
think about the cultural perspective on
the market and how its permeated through
almost every sector and that that's a
cultural perspective you know I used to
play Monopoly in college on Fridays
before that I played at home with my
brothers my family but when I went to
Rose Hulman for the first time where I
got my undergraduate cynical engineering
the first Friday of I cannot
all the deities landed in and I did not
hit it and they're like oh that's going
in the auction house the next person's
turn and then item element you read the
directions you're here to be an engineer
you don't read the directions so those
fools are talked to me by my family or
by my culture and it's an example of
where somebody had taken something it
was more complex and kind of
oversimplified it and made it less fun
and that's where that's what the
cannabis industry has done in a lot of
ways I'm not cooking at anyone but the
notion of piratey AC is better the
notion of holding your head longer
you'll get higher all of these things
those are all cultural impacts and I'd
like to think that that's not the best
way to look at things especially if
they're not done daily users the biggest
market segment because those people
aren't going to want to feel weird so
nothing to paranoia any they're not
and that's just not the culture you
definitely don't like a mother of two in
a soccer being worrying about other
mothers judging her for being high that
moment if you would you innovate a
little bit you can remove those feelings
you need to make this a lifestyle drug
which is essentially where it's going
I'm not sure that cannabis is a plant
and cure anything but it definitely can
be applied as a lifestyle drive which is
a huge segmented farmer
whether it's anxiety its adult use or
benefit it doesn't matter
they're both therapeutic so we have we
have to think about this in the grander
scheme and step back and a lot of you
might realize that alcohol was like one
of the best Feeny killers on the planet
we've used it for years to treat the
pain and it's just a bottle that you buy
at the store oh another cultural impact
is the indica sativa notion took it
based on that perspective the biggest
innovation cannabis in 20 years to the
THC concentration right there's been
this linear growth every year it gets
stronger and whether it's correlated or
not correlated I like to look at the
literature and in 1996 the group did a
study looking at cannabis use and we'll
get to the definition can
and at Hearst events in 1996 about 20%
of cannabis users experienced adverse
events same study was done eight years
later than six years later with in 10m
study study
40% of users experience adverse events
so if you fast forward to the future and
today you know a lot of people are gonna
a banana this event you know doing a dad
and getting the panic attack it's an
adverse event had the car provocations
of some adverse event you're essentially
overdosing of a compound and the word
more studies are coming out supporting
the notion that high THC and high CBD a
lovely isn't as beneficial as the two
together right it's a lot like there's
only see commercials where the cop
crashing offices and you know they're
better together or saying my wife are
going to say the chocolates by itself
the point is there isn't a lot of
diversity of market placing how do we
bridge that gap technological innovation
in the space didn't exist really
we need to change that I feel like this
could be this could be the conference
where it becomes more technology focused
it's not just a new trailer or extractor
as I mentioned before that's was an
innovations event of the industries
brought here it could be new things it
could be novel plant types could be
resistance to pests and disease and all
of those things that we all are happy to
working on so cannabis what is it right
you go to the doctor they write your
description for poppy poppy maybe Cody
first off the morphine depending it is a
clean for anti-cancer therapy many
compounds one flavor tree and cannabis
today's medical program is there's a
recommendation for cannabis what's it
what are you using it you know what
chemicals are acting on your element or
your system and a lot of times we don't
know more as this generic indica versus
even
two dragons I dated but this is Miss
nomer that cannabis is just that thing
and there's a huge disconnect between
anecdotal reports of whether it's so it
helped taking my painting or you know
the music oh man there isn't
corroboration on the research side and
we want to know why that is right and it
could be because the markets homogenous
you know but only high THC there's only
teaching night only offers THC in a lot
of levels right now so so the research
is impacted by the marketplace and the
cultures because the culture says hi
titi ta titi ta titi and that has been
eccentric focus whereas all of us in our
day is CBD seems it is this booming
market of everybody wanting to buy it
off Amazon something you know find that
cure but happens at data the way that
regulators look at this is very Tec
sensor we kind of see some of the
universal sorry these are symbols for
cannabis and five out of seven half of
THC right on the moto and you know
Oregon with their oversupply of 1.3
they were very smart they trademark
their pox on both of these that can make
the money back licensing that simple out
to other jurisdictions but they they
have the commands like we're selecting
law that's pretty cool but it's the one
without THC in the top level very
forward-looking and if you have a
product that doesn't have THC in it but
is a cannabis product and it has to have
the THC logo on it I mean that doesn't
even match FDA would like that very much
anyway this whole definition of cannabis
and we need to be careful with that
because indica and sativa is a cultural
concept it's not really a constant
rooted in anything other than our own
culture and before I get into the meat I
was like remind everyone that in the
past it was closets
backdoor deals zero regulation today or
somewhere in the middle in the future
it's going to be regulated
whether it's FDA whether it's us the BCC
whoever someone gets regulated and
that's all about public safety
it isn't to kill the culture it is it to
stop the movement
but it's to make sure that people are
putting adult when it's Nathan's which
happened recently versus some season
attendance ever being spiked with
synthetic cannabinoids
it's the guaranteed public safety
because at the end of the day someone is
gonna have to pick up the Medicare bill
for kids 18 to 25 doing dad it's their
whole life and causing some sort of
brain harm by overdose and the THC
console internet not saying that that's
going to happen that's certainly a
possibility right and if all you have to
do is clue administer a little CBD to
mitigate those harms why wouldn't you do
it
and you still get all of the benefits
and all of the happiness and all up to
high you just have a safety net there to
protect your brain which is probably the
most that I think will work and you have
a much routine
so and I just like to tell a little
story about a person who came to us back
in 2011 in 2010 and she was looking for
something to get off effexor and like
zoloft and paxil she bounced around
between his anxiety medicines and
essentially she was super stoked on
cannabis became legal and she was like
oh my god she's an alternative to a
pharmaceutical so she goes into position
in the position right to her
recommendation and the recommendation is
for cannabis and she says well just
don't smoking because smoking isn't that
bad so she doesn't a dispensary she said
[ __ ] candies chocolates just you know
no Stevie dependance back there is the
recipe right and she was painting on the
walls with mustard calling me and saying
this is crazy and just chill out and
take it out so she goes back to the
dispensary because you know with you
know we're all like chalk flowers you
know
the animals would label all out all
their still not leave all that weight
percent definitely telling you need to
have a okay that's cool so she tries it
indica it's the same thing just
basically anxiety anxiousness
Bakula and the dominant turkey in the
marketplace and them going kind of fast
here to get to the part where it's cool
innovative but back then in 2011
three-quarters of marketers piercing
dominant on the type one side of
California a lot of innovations happen
between now and in an hour a lot more
chemical diversity SC labs tested as the
best and state see the most improved
tests but it was pretty hard to miss
then and
the nature article from January about
98% of the products grown in Washington
State were high TDC at 98% TVC were
power there's so many different people
likes right I mean there's there's a
hundred and seventy different salad
dressings
there's only THC right like how do you
have you hit all of those different
people types right in in flavor and
fragrance different panels are decided
by how they taste
not biases blind study we look at
everyone
some people have mutations and the taste
buds that don't allow them to taste
certain flavors and that's a huge
segment of the population so when you're
making products for the masses you have
to look at all these different market
segments and create flavors and effects
and things that are targeted and not
just oh we're gonna bang this out I take
see make money because that's gonna
raise his bottom it's going to come to
an end at some point but if you look at
the toolbox for NIDA and again this
marketplace is pretty limited
you know the TVC was different dominant
beings and for CPD there's only pretty
much one
chirping that's embarrassing there are
some exceptions on the marketplace for
the most part it's a homogeneous product
offering so Smith is just she didn't
like it she gave up on cannabis she said
through coos that was all good until was
pretty guy on TV you know even my dad
called psychology to sell eternal life
it's cool now Sunday said so got calls
from their parents and school state
support everybody it was only partly yes
and like buzz killer not buzz given when
unit to nursing that CVD is just like
the deadly combination for kill your
medicine make you depressed I think but
that was her experience - she didn't
like the end of the cloud all day she
actually preferred the pharmaceutical
solution for a problem which is sad
because you know anytime they can't help
someone you always feel like you got
something on the table and you need to
need to go back through time orders but
during this time some clients of ours
were working towards something but for
me to explain that something I have to
actually explain the way to visualize
that something you know I saw a hat
today they said chemicals kill cannabis
heels and I was like a machine gun blast
in my own studio but to be able to see
all these chemicals whether it's the 17
tear beings or you know 13 Kennedy minds
that this final tax report outlines
would we had to do something because
when you got a test report from a
laboratory that was essentially a bunch
of lines in black and white with the
numbers and letters like loq and you
know whatever to spend three people they
didn't really get anything glean
anything from it and the market then
would say hey it's the strongest was the
highest THC let me buy that and really
the same thing
I'm a speciality yes specifically for a
way to visualize the test results that
could be easy and intuitive and we
worked on this for her
we color could omit the terpenes
intuitively so that you know by my name
is yellow
my name is green and basically the warm
tones on the terpene profile they
instigated a a sativa bike terpene kind
right so if you just make your eyes
terpenes one of those lively
whatever you can totally feel the effect
of them if you have a consultation high
enough typically in high THC cannabis
the THC pharmacology overwhelms the
terpene pulmonology so you get kind of
this justify but as you start adding CBD
to the mix the terpene entourage gets
shuffled out and rises to the top
this particular example is classic first
like I said I think the laser reflects
off with the thing there's this
pointless but the way of platelet aroma
there that's activated the terpene
profile over the purple bar just weird
nursing and blues that carefully and
then the green is piney
this is indicative of any Kurt so
purpose is a category that we defined my
chemistry there into the name game so if
you have kins GDP or per protocol or
classic verbs or even blue dream they
follow this kind of cassette of terpenes
that you know people are
now having said that we can continue our
journey with Samantha where you looking
at this is OG legend it's a pretty
pretty indicative no cheese hybrid OG
classic European classic publication my
mini dominant really great though Geno's
a pops in their face explodes this is a
type 1 &amp; 2 look at the black circle
looks like a doughnut black is THC great
as the CPG this is mostly THC then it
gets her frankenstein and sag thanks
right well if you're in a greenhouse one
you're gonna get that adverse obscenity
so yeah I was working for me just as
much as I was working for Samantha here
Ronnie Lee is probably sick
because that room yeah volcano man
and they showed that you know the
delivery of th season one of those is
tired of smoking was recently so it
explains a lot but then you add all of
the CBD in which this is a breathing
technique right
most of the cannabis that breeds type 2
and the industry has a ratio of THC CBD
of one to two there are reasons for this
is hard to find a couple that
correlation but here we have greater
than one
THC the CBD which allows the TV
overwhelm the CBD contribution learn if
you're familiar but if you would this is
my hand gesture road we call blood serum
levels so THC you smoke it's up and
you're down fast
as you add CBD that mellows the rise and
prolongs the effect so if you if you're
consuming a type of cannabis as a long
no two parts to you see the one part C
to be your high while actually lasts
longer
TAC alone because of the pharmacology of
the CVD and the body but this was still
vote too edgy for analogy analogy the
states is indistinguishable from the
type one but it's a type two which
that's not all in the market that's a
smell something good and that's a fire
has energy and then for something to go
it's only 14% to you you see in 8% APA
that I was like 14 percent but then even
you consume it again it's a really
enjoyable experience you still really
get all of the relief and it's like
getting saintly stones but this was a
good enough for her this is actually my
favorite world but when we added more
CBD essentially became character
Samantha in the trick with this
retirement reading is keeping the flavor
constant across all these different
category profiles but more importantly
how do you develop a parental set of
line
that can breed true so that out of
thousand seeds they all have this
chemical profile that is predictive of
not only the terpene concentration of
flavor and aroma but also predicted
above the cannabinoid ratio and
concentrations and that's a little bit
more trendy right then with any plant or
human must isolate one trait at a time
it's must it's very similar to
conducting an experiment if you're
growing in your grow room and you change
the humidity the temperature and your
nutrients how do you know what affected
the plant you changed your outcome so
the same thing goes for greeting and
Ryan lead actually I'd like to bring him
up after my talk because he's probably
the most knowledgeable as it pertains to
candidates in Kennedy's breeding
properly in the world and he didn't
describe all of the ins and outs of
whether it's a singular or a single
nuclear treaty
you know the informatics behind that
what we're good at is supplying the
infrastructure to create these novel
products and
the crux of it is how do we go from
where we are today at this industry
about like there's a lot of noise out
there and there's no talk of innovation
is a you know there's a lot of music a
lot of eating smoking a lot of drinking
but not a lot of people talk about where
we're gonna go next year okay
how we gonna protect our marketing is
moving forward look you know everyone
says I'm great big shining right now
right cheese cakes and pork chops
everywhere
so Tyson lay the trait create current
aligned that takes time
one of our pet projects are color traits
obviously and what's nice is if you
particularly a really great parental
it's all for pulling it hybridize it
with an olive green and then you
germinate that that class you'd like
this nice and mix but then when you
depth to that class
the purple trade balances between every
part of the plant if you have a hundred
plants lined up and around you're
walking down you can see the purple tree
on the top side of the leaf only on the
bottom civilities only on the pistil
whole may be turned pink or the flowers
are four prominent leaves are green and
the leaves of purple flowers are green
and it's really neat the way the
training bouncing all around right well
if you want that trait to come back you
have to pick the plants where you want
the trait to be then you have to sell
them and walk that trade in one piece at
a time right
many people use males and females to
breathe and it's difficult to get
segregation that way right you can talk
to us later but it's almost
counterintuitive I'm not sure any plant
breeding projects in the world that's
still go about it that way instead they
use ethylene blockers to create
segregation so you have clear
populations you can isolate those traits
and in the future obviously we'll do a
haploid lines and thing
creating new juicers which then you can
pass all those traits of a really nice
and smoothly but I just want to show you
some of the innovations that have
happened in past few years so you can
kind of see what it what the trajectory
of technology in the plant space looks
like as shown these are three OGIS with
different animal cannabinoid
concentrations staying you know there's
virtually indistinguishable between each
other so to be able to conduct patient
panels or research with these is very
very awesome because it's almost like
having that that that cannabinoid less
control and GW patented but another
series of plans from and that this
article is our prisoners in with dr.
Ethan Rousseau and Kevin cemented called
pharmacological foundations of cannabis
kilobars has published this year
here are three lines with st. earthy
profile the same flavors and aroma seen
by the structure the one on your far
left is one to one TCB in THC one of the
middle is approximately one to one THC
and CBD then the one on the right is one
to one CBBC
yeah so this is where we're introducing
the propyl Zen grab constant chemical
the flavor aroma so when people try
these different things that get
pronounced different experiences that's
highlighted by the can enjoyed
pharmacology and this is where you start
looking at these different market
segments as well look at the people who
want to get really Skeletor ji people
we're not soccer moms what they like the
CBD CBD v-line guava jam is essentially
this this cultivar it's at one that one
cup CPD contest last year and it gives
you an experience somewhere between
nicotine and caffeine without the
jitters it's completely different than
THC but it's a pronounced effect
pronounced mood enhancement and these
subtle effects in here
it's are exactly what the masses are
looking for and this is the type of
technology to make you tasty and
flavorful and to get into programs you
can try it both in their minds on
cannabis even more than they already are
some other innovation it's here this is
showing how you breathe TV out of the
line using propyl CBD on the left is a
one-to-one CVD b2c videos you move
across you see the gold and the doughnut
getting larger and larger and that means
@c v dve we're breeding out the THC in
replacing with Stevi division the
planting of far right has less than 0.1%
ta DCA so it's obviously the attempt but
it's still producing 10 to 12 percent
panda noise and all of them are turfed
out depending on which which plants are
looking at again those plants we have
this TC monitor and the universal symbol
which makes people think that there's th
CNN but like less than 0.1% is not much
time piny is a series also in the
foundations paper on the left is mostly
THC on the right as most of the CBD in
the Middle's of one to one these plants
have turfed out there's plants in this
family one of the parentals produces
four and a half percent triangle mode
which is crazy
my name is pretty harsh though you know
when you start when you start producing
flowers consumption you I can smell how
many do we smell seem unique really
that's like I remember walking at my
friend's basement like it smells like
dog again yeah so so this pie eating
cult apart though it's very interesting
if you put enough in your scene or
carefully or lining a minute it's
smooths out the finding a lot so it's
more palatable but endurance runners
like there's a group of about ten altar
runners and
from that just love crying anymore the
one it gives them enough of a pain
reduction that they can do their 50 or
100 mile ride which is insane but also
the time that the painting makes them
aware of the track and not excited to
jump off a cliff
yeah and if you don't know already
cannabis is considered a
performance-enhancing drug for ultra
runners and long distance athletes so
it's banned because of that reason
because it helps you turn your mind off
and you know your mind controls that
they think so that's a factor here to
here is not some really tasty CVG lines
on the left you have about 7% CVG and
20% THC these all smell like delicious
pineapple and I believe the one on the
left is actually a cultivar called the
happy pineapple that molecular farms
cruises and then as you see the light
gray and the donut getting larger and
larger you can see again breeding out
the THC and the placing that with CBT
and keeping a flavor which is supposed
to mean I mean and very carefully pretty
consistent so they all smell how does my
sweet listening finding in flavors but
that very different cannabinoid
concentrations which results in very
different effects and I can tell you
that the CPG also does what you need
kind of does where it mitigates a lot of
the adverse events of THC it it cools it
down a little bit so you don't get that
you know panic attack or worried about
something said to model 10 years ago and
then the CPG and CBD which we've done
pretty much the same thing with and you
can see here everything extra data here
so again 20 minutes okay perfect got a
ton of time for questions so the whole
premise of those counters
educate each caught up on innovations
happen chemically in the cannabis plant
world and then open the floor to
questions I think my good friend Ryan II
up here to help me answer this he's way
smarter than me at that stuff
and that's it so do you leverage people
are smart so again that's like to remind
everyone that in the past we had no
regulations and in the future it's gonna
be heavily regulated period we're
somewhere in the middle and what may
throw our technology company right so we
want to bridge the gap between the two
and you know it's important because
technology is not just about science and
data and numbers it's about people and
stories and the general goal has always
been to find the problem and then create
the solution and those solutions have
helped people they just can't be
something that's a good idea that's
turned into a product and something it's
like that's not no successful products
are created a successful products are
created by saying look at all the people
that don't like
how do you make that crates of the trade
like another how do we create something
tastes better how do we create something
that smelled a mold and mildew resistant
and all those great things which this
plant is so plastic and dynamic you know
it's a corn and peanuts and dogs you
could just push it one way or the other
you know before you gotta get into Iowa
plan it's a plan
they're crazy different that they don't
give us a quit and then creating those
genetics to be stable in multiple
environments and if it's an asexual
propagated clone I'm kind of going off
from attention it could vary a lot from
whether it's out your greenhouse endure
the the chemo type of that genotype will
change depending on the environment
because of epigenetics now a lot of the
seeds that would produce that are
homozygous chemically and
morphologically they actually can endure
different environments and have more
stability across those environments so
the future is going to be you know
homozygous seed production today we're
stuck in this
sexual clonal production world and I
just love to see where it goes and I
hope you would enjoy the talk but this
day to do this plant can't read
everything right there baby Paul Parker
and ACA are ICRS dr. Dee's original
everybody says and applications for this
plant February minor minded of the
largest pharmaceutical cannabis company
in the world as GW Pharma and they still
get all of their cannabinoids from
plants so innovations in the plant space
will directly impact Pharma and vice
versa I'm sure so you have any questions
or comments I'd love to answer them join
the talk
and here's a Mike Mike Andy works up
here
yeah okay that's questions I have a
quick question on the analytical testing
specifically around the ball of litter
beads mostly looking at testing of those
terpenes from the perspective of the
planets elfin breeding perspective and
than a consumer product you would think
that there would be some change in
makeup of those volatile terpenes and
through the sheer dry process judy
comments around appropriate time to
perform that testing from both plain
reading and then also you know the
finished product perspective is it a web
type sample that should be submitted
during further for you know the breeding
inflammation in the finished product for
the consumer information
well obviously want to test the product
if you have Sally left product however
if it were commodity and you were
pushing that what product is it fresh
goes and they would perhaps it makes
more sense is what
typically to get a Filofax report its
pre-packaging like literally moments
before packaging so that they can
guarantee the shelf life of that 60 days
to be true to the find effects if you
know did the proper packaging with seals
then actually the degradation occurs
faster well it's not stored properly
imperious bastard in mes turkey profile
changes during recruitment training
process if you were looking to protect
you know some makeup of that those
turkey knees you know as an IP video
generate in with cadet lien on the
product itself the plan you know playing
I guess plant I feed and packets on the
plan shouldn't be it actually tested on
the plan B for its curative or is there
attorney so I hey Beth hi mark
they're next on The Price is Right and
next
right gonna bid on this chair oh my god
$10 1520's
so I also want to ask you a bunch of
patents but we'll talk about that later
I have a question about the homozygous
nature of these seeds and so know
there's an artist Natalie Jeremy Jane
Caro we didn't know you familiar there
Natalie Jeremy Jacobs she is an artist
if you did an experiment some years ago
called many trees and she took clones of
trees and planted them in a variety of
different locations to basically show
how it impacts how things grow can you
explain a little bit of the science
behind how stable steel lines can
actually produce more stability in
different environments there's a
question
well just do the killing and Conway
answer any question you want
and then again say that I have a parser
so
almost like honesty now Howard wire
seats were robust chemically than points
and basically like how is it that like
because of the variability that can
happen in different environments how is
it possible to have stable seeds that
produce more stable results in different
environments so you can so when we're
breeding we can only control the
genetics of the plant right and an
average genetic sorrow produces
environmental effect
there's across environments is something
that you're gonna have land area so but
you know creating homes like a seed
really allows us to have that uniformity
to start exploring an asexual
propagation in itself is stressful in
the planet and our study showed that the
more stress you click on that plant the
more it has the tendency you know people
say oh it lost its vigor or its genetic
drift or whatever it goes a lot of times
those asexually propagated clones and it
know stressed out whether their mothers
and their rootbound you know vetted
that's just not the most of the best way
to do that for that planet is you want
all those switches turned on and if you
plant is stressed out because it's been
a section of propagated to be locked
down whatever that has a tendency to be
more near sitting on romantic and
annoyed in the oil concentration goes
down and the whole thing way that we've
seen the sticks that it is a plant those
those plants in the ground during the
lengthening season so in the spring
under the sun you get to your circadian
led them back you have another little
bit of growth and that can assume that a
lot of those switches out other ways are
this drifted down to the tissue culture
and
as vigorous growth back to the
vegetative stage but as for the seeds
versus clones they it's just it's so
notable the difference between how a
seed the form to clone performance from
the bigger side of the resistance to
pests pathogens it's quite notable and
we're seeing through the tissue cultures
of these companies that can live do it
now the testing you know we realize that
it's plants that acquiring as I close to
my stress disorder there's plants
acquire leave marks call them stress
events but it's also this bacteria
viruses and they grow they lived with
the plant was one of the petition
cultures able to do is bring it back
down to the meristem and eliminate all
those external forces on CD brought back
fresh plant which is really close to
what we had the see it's one of the
benefits that we have no see the
trade-off is at the current environment
a lot of these seeds are hybrid seeds
and they're kind of all over the place
phenotypically Aquila typically
that uniformity so well that's not the
point right you can buy 10 Z's and get
10 FINA well that was someone who's
saying naturally to me you know it's
it's a really important thing to have
it's me not thinking and you know
typically in regular agriculture that's
something that's relegated to the plant
breeders it's not you know an everyday
gardener thing they go they look for
plants usually in horticulture producers
produce that's all they do don't go look
for the variation so it's something that
our community is on the top too which is
great you know it's distributed platform
where a lot of different people are
looking for all the different flavors in
fact so it's you don't have one person's
perspective like yep so as a proper
introduction to Ryan he died many years
ago he does 11 importation into Canada
for seeds you you get through our
partnership for farm the Canada that's
really regulated system where you can't
just bring genetics into the system of
licensed growers they have to document
where all the receipts come from so we
sold pitch and I think some of these
into these companies any other question
everybody wants to give straight Eman
eyes I'm not sure it's a proper term for
feminazis actually diagnosis speeds by
engine we talked about that agents money
you should probably read these words it
comes from the Greek word for mm so
there's you know so Canisius just means
that the breeding is done through two
female plants that we use a chemical
manipulation to induce pollen over to us
and that we can breed you know we can
use that quality fermenting process and
originally the the season came on the
market from that fashion of some of
these other early companies the methods
that they use to generate that seed and
all these inherent problems with
intersexuality so people throwing plants
patent you know female plants will be
former seeds and obviously as tennis
cultivator for flowers that's not idea
so I think that really painted the
reputation of what we call feminized
seeds on the market and people you know
really wanted to stay with these regular
male-female crosses the problem is is
actually using males is pretty terrible
a to select pollen donors for cannabis
because the plants themselves don't
express the traits of interest leaves is
kind of rationale of grass analogy is
like if you're breeding humans for
breast size it's pretty easy to cheesy
peanuts right but how do you choose the
males how do you choose the males that
have that
four large breasts when they don't
express that straight right so when
we're using for jelly female crosses and
that some lurk we do to Pedro we really
see that there's this huge game you can
get you're doing positive selection for
chemistry on both parentals it just did
speeds on their breathing and it's also
beautiful in your state in these plants
you don't have to go through and
eliminate the males run spending
resources of time you know and a lot of
these companies are offering these gen
accepts tasks where you're paying so you
pay $10 to see look you pay $15 to go
and have the plants axed right and
that's just not really an efficient use
of resources so there's a lot of
benefits of using and remember that's a
trait right so if you're feminizing
seeds grow and you have
you wrote that and they'll pick two more
females from lazada feminize that then
you have a thousand and maybe one mill
and you pick the best one every 100,000
only one now so you can breathe that
trade out just the same as any trade
right how do you recommend doing that to
get to the guy who reaches typically
what senator we're asking in editors as
the major hormone controls that
chemicals it's the same track those
gasses so if you count these inhibitors
was a silver compound and health silver
thiosulfate
you can also use colloidal silver you
spray it on your plant that blocks the
ethylene receptor and house is all about
colloidal silver there's some individual
the Internet need wouldn't drag budget
colloidal silver people think that maybe
it does mats but if you drink too much
you turn blue
yeah look I'm just going to Google on
that
would go into a nerdy school so you know
pickles when people pass out from
drinking to get on marker done with AZ
spray and silver nitrate of people so
the Turner skin brand and they wake up
and have like a black face sorry wrong
time right Justin sorry no the gender
from the seed shape you can't be a seed
shape like anything it's just a little
more interesting but at this point in
time you can you can germinate the seeds
with your Monsanto you can use your seat
chipper
any other questions well that's it
[Applause]
you