hi there friends Shango Los from shaping
fire and I am here again with Dr Ethan
Russo good friend of ours and we are
going to be talking about cannabis
hyperemesis syndrome today and if you
are new to CHS I encourage you to listen
to shaping Fire episode 80 where Dr
Russo and I talk about cannabis
hyperemesis syndrome in detail but today
we are talking about CHS specifically to
talk about Dr Russo's new paper on the
topic debunking some of the the the
myths that are being circulated about
CHS so the recent article we're
discussing today is called uh
cannabinoid hyperemisis syndrome genetic
sucess susceptibility to toxic exposure
so Ethan thank you for being here today
um this new paper
uh is very necessary to clear the air
about what many people think the causes
are to CHS and very freely share their
opinions online about what causes CHS
but are not keeping up with the science
and um your review paper's goal as far
as I understand it is to help clear up
those understandings so as we move
forward um both those of us who are
cannabis enthusiasts and are susceptible
to to having CHS but also all of us who
speak online and to conferences so that
we understand the state of the science
and we can be spreading appropriate
information so so let's start at the top
um I think that for many people who are
are seeing this they may be new to uh
CHS as uh as an ailment so um uh while
people can find out all about it in
detail on shaping fire uh episode 80
would you please just summarize for us
what CHS is to bring everybody up to
speed sure thanks Shango so canabo
hyperemesis syndrome or CHS was first
described 20 years ago in 204 in
Australia in eight patients who
presented unbeknownst to each other with
a similar set of signs and symptoms
which consisted of nausea vomiting
abdominal pain
and an
unusual uh manifestation that they would
spend hours at times taking hot showers
or baths to reduce symptoms and all of
these were chronic users of high THC
cannabis so that was 20 years ago but
the description really hasn't changed
this Syndrome has become more prevalent
it seems some by virtue of recogn
of the syndrome but also associated with
the higher potency cannabis and
particularly concentrates that have
become more generally available it
Remains the case that this is far more
prevalent in the US and Canada where
there is access to such materials as
compared to the rest of the
world so we are seeing an increase
amount of CHS prevalence in people um
because the um the potency of the
products that we have are increasing and
we're talking about to some degree
higher THC um uh flour but really what
we're talking about is oil concentrates
and dabbing right quite often um in our
surve published a couple of years ago
the average intake was four grams a day
of high THC material among CHS sufferers
I know so um when we spoke um during
aping Fire episode 80 um you were very
clear that uh in the early days we did
not know what the cause was um which
caused science to happen right and so uh
you came on the show to talk about um
what was not the cause and what you had
found was the cause or the pathway to
the cause which gave us a better idea of
what we were dealing with now I'm going
to ask you in a moment to go through the
list with me of the various things that
you debunk in your new paper that are
not the cause but you were very uh clear
on episode 80 that we do know what the
genetic mutations are in a human that
makes them susceptible to
CHS um let's cement that in right now
will you describe the genetic mutations
that are at the root of CHS sure so it
was apparent to me over time that there
was a small minority of cannabis users
that seem susceptible to
CHS and these were distinct from a lot
of people we know that used high amounts
of cannabis but had never had similar
symptoms so what was the difference um
although as we'll discuss people had
implicated things like
pesticides uh the symptoms didn't match
and I felt that the cause of the
susceptibility to ch
must be genetic explaining why some
people got it and some people did not um
so we really started
there and so um I know for most folks um
hearing you talk about the AL will not
be anything that anyone understands but
but but there are certainly people who
are listening and watching who are um
you know legit scientists so for that
those folks in the audience would you go
through and hit where the mutations are
sure so our first candidate was the gene
that encodes the CB1 receptor canabo one
receptor where THC works and our endoc
canabo the canabo within our body work
but we didn't see a mutation there and
this will be important later I think
when we discuss distinctions from other
syndromes that are mistaken for
CHS our other two hypotheses were that
this had something to do with the
enzymes that break down uh THC in the
body um specifically something called
cyp2c9 and we did see statistically
significant difference that this gene or
mutation on a gene which called a snip
or um single nucleotide polymorphism was
present statistically significantly more
in people with CHS as opposed to our
control group which was people used High
volumes of cannabis again averaging four
grams a day but did not have CHS so we
did see a mutation there uh the third
hypothesis which also proved true was a
mutation on what's called trip
V1 trip V1 is a receptor that has to do
with pain and it's triggered by heat and
ethanol otherwise known as alcohol um
and acid um and uh this mutation helped
explain why the Heat or capsacin the
chili pepper extract on the skin
temporarily reduces symtoms uh so those
were two um we found two mutations on
genes affecting dopamine dopamine is a
very important neurotransmitter in the
brain and problems with it are
associated with addiction as well as
psychosis
schizophrenia um and a whole host of
other Psych atric problems having two
genes that were statistically
significantly present in the CHS group
as compared to the high volume cannabis
users that didn't have CHS again
indicated something important at the
root of it and we know that a drug that
blocks do dopamine haloperidol is one of
the things that is used in emergency
rooms to try to stop the on nause and
vomiting whereas more common drugs to
treat nause and vomiting don't work in
this syndrome um finally there was a
mutation on a gene called abca1 that has
to do with cholesterol
metabolism this is really unexpected but
um has some important implications in
that uh mutations there may make these
people susceptible to Alzheimer disease
uh coronary artery disease and diabetes
mtis later in
life so the reason why we're here is to
remove some of the untrue information
that's being spread around and the
impetus for um Dr Russo uh publishing
this article is very specific um would
you please explain to us um what
happened um to cause you to uh go
through the effort to put out the paper
well I'm afraid we're dealing with a
post-truth world uh where science is
being ignored or challenged um but I
kept hearing that well it must be this
or it must be that and people are really
devoted to trying disprove the fact that
uh the CHS occurs due to cannabis usage
or synthetic
cannaboids that hit the same CB1
receptor um so among these
misconceptions uh have been pesticide
exposure now I am the first one to say
that pesticides in cannabis is a huge
problem where there isn't sufficient
screening testing going on I published
on this in 2016 to show the rampant
contamination that was present in the
Washington State Legal Market uh but the
fact is as bad as those chemicals are
and as many problems as they can create
over time the symptoms that they produce
don't match CHS at
all so um people are very often online
saying it's got to be pesticides or this
you know this kind of pedde or or Eagle
20 or and then everybody's got an
anecdotal story of how it happened to
their their Uncle cousin trimmer
whatever right but but these individual
stories do not add up to science because
you have looked at um a larger pool of
both data and people sure additionally
we've had people who've documented that
uh the Cannabis they used was from a hom
grow with no pesticide use at all um so
it it just doesn't fit um and
unfortunately we're dealing with some a
lot of Wishful Thinking here in relation
to this
diagnosis so um another category that is
common um to blame for CHS is is neem um
uh uh there's a lot of talk about oh you
know people use neem and and this is
what happens when you smoke cannabis
that has been um treated with neem or
worse so when you concentrate it into an
oil and then Dab Oil with neem in in it
um what does the science say well it
really doesn't fit and I take this one
personally because I've used neem uh in
my organic gardening for many years and
I admit I've eaten berries uh the same
day I've sprayed with it no
repercussions but that's only an
anecdote the truth is um that neem is a
considered a safe organic pesticide for
the most part
um I scoured the literature on
toxicities associated with neem oil and
it's one of its active ingredients
called aaon and again we've got a
situation where the symptoms don't fit
there have been rare cases of toxicity
one associated with an a suicide attempt
um but we've got a mismatch additionally
is that
araon has an extremely high boiling
point it's questionable that you would
even recruit it out of cannabis by
smoking even though uh the the lit tip
of a cannabis joint is uh in the
hundreds of degrees celsus uh so it uh
it really is a situation that once again
can't explain the syndrome and again
wishful thinking too right because we
wish we could just point to ah it is
this chemical and let's just remove that
but it's far more complex because the
precursors are actually our genetic
makeup sure additionally um neem is
typically used pre flowering as the
cannabis plant uh is growing it
dissipates entirely in 3 to 4 days um
and I I just think if you did analyses
for a zaratin or neem on flower you'd
rarely find it and the concentrations
couldn't possibly explain the few cases
of toxicity that have been observed
mostly in people who drank a some
significant amount of uh a or as thata
and fluid and even if somebody um was
Ill advised and they use neem in the you
know seventh week of flower or something
um you know while that is not going to
be a necessarily good experience for the
Cannabis Enthusiast the um the diagnoses
for CHS are so spread out with so many
different sources that we know that a a
very rare opportunity like that is going
to be the cause no again uh statistics
would not explain this I know um another
uh potential or or rumored cause for CHS
that that you debunk in the paper is uh
hop Laten viroid and so would you go
through that analysis too sure so a
virid is sort of a primitive virus and
this has been rampant um in the
cultivation of cannabis it does stunt
the growth of the plant and can uh limit
its potency but here's the thing it not
only has there never been a case of hop
latent vroid showed in a human there are
no cases of any plant virus or vroid
affecting humans we are sufficiently
different from Plants uh fellow living
creatures but we're sufficiently
different that there's no likelihood uh
that any infectious agent of this pipe
uh could uh affect a human let alone
with
CHS so so now we get to the big one so
um we'll come at this a couple different
ways the first is that um as the
definition of cannabis hyperemesis
syndrome evolved um some were wondering
if it was cyclic vomiting syndrome then
uh recently we have run into that um a
uh significant scientific journal group
them together which got your dander up
and you wanted to clarify sure so uh I'd
like you to do both at the same time
right would you would you address uh
what cyclic vomiting
is how it is
not um
CHS and the error that's made in the
scientific journal sure so this is in
the Journal of
gastroenterology and they said basically
that CHS was a subset of cyclic vomiting
syndrome I took UMD at this because uh
CVS cyclic vomiting syndrome is
something that I'm very familiar with as
a neurologist particularly as a
pediatric neurologist so
CVS cyclic vomiting syndrome typically
presents in a child or or a teenager who
has episod episodic nauseum vomiting
without other explanation and they might
get an an advanced workup uh invasive
studies scans you name it um but what
this is what's known as a form fruit
frustrated form of migraine the natural
history of cyclic vomiting syndrome is
this is a child or teenager who has a
family history of migraine typically
their mother and they get the symptoms
of nause and vomiting without a headache
but as they get older the migraine with
the headache will establish itself
interestingly cyclic vomiting syndrome
like many forms of migraine is very
amenable to treatment with cannabis
whether it be acute or is a preventive
but you can see how this has created
confusion however I'm quite critical in
that uh people with nause and vomiting
typically end up in emergency
departments and unless the doctor is
willing to spend the time to really ask
the right questions it's simple to have
this confusion finally can we really
tell the difference well um in fact
there is that mut on the CB1 Gene
cnr1 um there is a mutation in the
cyclic rening syndrome that we did not
find in the cannabinoid hyperemesis
syndrome patients so we have a the
capability of distinguishing these based
on Laboratory
Testing so um I want to finish up
talking about um um the various canabo
and their role in CHS but I want to I
want to hit this this I want to
summarize what you just said very
clearly that while we are still
researching
CHS we have got enough science done at
this point that we understand that CHS
is not called by caused by pesticides
it's not caused by neem and it's not uh
CVS and what we know is that uh to
develop
CHS uh um you must have the pre-existing
gene
mutations and then you need to embibe a
whole lot of cannabis generally speaking
generally speaking upwards of uh you
know four grams of concentrate a day
generally speaking with each person
being you know having some variation do
I have the summary right yeah pretty
much um you know everybody might have a
different threshold for this I should
also point out that anybody who suddenly
has exposure to too high a dose of THC
may get sick and vomit but that's very
different from having this chronic
cyclic uh
situation um so we really are able to
distinguish it does require actually
talking to patients in detail which is
really not the model of current medicine
in this country I'm afraid right okay so
um I want to talk about how you finish
the paper which I found very interesting
because you know as somebody who is um
in cannabis media I get reached out to
by people who are experiencing CHS and
um they're you know by definition
they're a cannabis Enthusiast right they
they're they're using a lot of cannabis
every day which is how that in
cooperation with their gene mutations
causes these symptoms and so uh people
say oh I'm I'm going to try to switch to
just doing CB BD or I'm going to switch
to just CBG or um for this particular
autoimmune I'm going to try just
thca and um your your paper goes through
each of the popular cannabinoids that
that patients have tried to shift
through kind of
denying the Doom scenario of of actually
not being able to use cannabis anymore
and and now we have research that talks
about why to shift to another
cannabinoid is is not really going to
help um would you delineate that sure so
again we've implicated herbal cannabis
and THC in uh triggering CHS symptoms
but it will occur with any drug or
cannabinoid that stimulates the CB1
receptor so this would include synthetic
Delta 8 it would include canaban
CBN it might involve CBD the problem
there is twofold number one it's
extremely hard to uh have a CBD
preparation that isn't going to have
some amount of
THC uh that's one um and two is that uh
CBD over time may increase in nide
levels and this possibly also is a
trigger to CHS symptoms if the levels
are too high um so there're those you
mentioned CBG as you know uh we've done
a lot of work on published on uh canaba
gereral I think it's a wonderful agent
um it is not
intoxicating uh it does not stimulate
the CB1 receptor with any particular
potency um on its own it's not an
anti-emetic it's not um one that's
usually used for vomiting it's likely
could be helpful
in reducing anxiety with the syndrome
and possibly the pain but I doubt it
would be an effective preventive on its
own there are CBG only plants and
preparations that are available in
contrast to CBD which unless it was
developed from an isolate is is unlikely
you mentioned the acid cannabinoids thca
is antiemetic it uh helps reduce
vomiting uh but the problem is it's not
stable and uh it's breakdown product is
THC so one sees the pitfall there
potentially how about cbda cannabidiolic
acid so this is uh CBD before it's
decarbox in animals that has a strong
anti-emetic effect um we don't have
enough information from anybody who's
tried this to know whether
cbda on its own might be um help ful in
this situation right now the only
effective treatment uh that will work in
the long-terms abstinence from Cannabis
or other agents that stimulate CB1 and
that includes synthetic
cannaboids uh because it's well
established in people that aren't using
herbal cannabis but have had CHS in
relation to the synthetic agents that
stimulate the CB1 receptor all right so
let's let's look forward so um you know
uh you have been right on the front
lines of cannabis hyperemesis syndrome
for the whole 20 years that we've been
looking at it you have been following
the research from the early days when it
was first um defined and described um
you have participated in most of the
early research so so you you know where
we're at
today um you have spent efforts through
this paper debunking the things that it
is not so that um we have a better grasp
of of what CH is CHS is both so that we
can research it and so we have good
information going throughout the
Cannabis scene um I'm curious to know
where you would like to see research
happen next to further our understanding
of CHS and hopefully relieve the
symptoms of the Cannabis enthusiasts
that are developing it sure so we have
plans now we'd like to um we're involved
in putting together a Consortium of
researchers to apply to the National
Institutes of Health for a grant to
study CHS in depth we would like to have
hundreds of patients who undergo the
genomic testing to look at the five Gene
candidates that we've identified and
possibly others uh additionally we'd
like to do metabolomic testing this
would involve a sample of saliva that's
analyzed for its chemical composition to
see if a CHS attack produces biochemical
changes that we can identify as
markers um so that would be part of it
additionally we need much better
investigation of the
psychiatric accompaniment to CHS which
we've mentioned
um the tendency towards addiction mood
disorders anxiety depression and others
um so that's the idea of the research it
would be very expensive so in this
instance uh we need a grant uh we'll try
the government um we'll see I'm not
confident that um there's going to be
great funding opportunities and biomed
research at a federal
level so um for people who are
interested to know more about CHS or
want to get involved clearly they're
shaping Fire episode 80 where you can
get in the in-depth look at CHS but what
if people want to get involved
financially in supporting their work
would they contact UM your company cros
science that way if they want to get
involved with funding sure um couple of
things first um the three papers that
we've published on canabo hyperemesis
syndrome are available free no copyright
problems because it's my personal
website at Ethan russ. org at the
library tab in the search engine if you
put
hyperemesis Hy p r e m uh e
sis there there will also be Links at
the bottom of this video so you don't
have to write
and finally we have a website what is
CHS that's what- is-
cs.com that has a resource page with
links to the Articles again uh more
information at a nice level that I think
is easy to understand and um access to
the uh
CHS screening uh test uh that is
available commercially great well Dr
Russo thank you so much for sharing your
time with us and and you know your
life's research as well and thank you
also for you know a lot of people think
of uh you know Ivory to Ivory Tower
science and and sometimes scientists
don't get involved with the the
nitty-gritty of it but but you know you
are very um you are part and parcel of
the Cannabis scene and and I appreciate
you having um the interest in debunking
some of this incorrect information um
because all of us who enjoy cannabis are
at risk so thank you for your time today
and thank you for your research thank
you for the opportunity right on thank
you friends so thank you for being here
today if you want to learn more that's
shaping Fire episode 80 and you can look
for the links to Dr Russo's websites uh
below this one for shaping fire I am
Shango Los thanks for being
here for