welcome everyone to the 11:30 B Sunday
presentation cannabis and hemp social
media for 2020 and insiders guide to
organic Instagram griller please silence
your cell phones and they haven't
already done that
I'm Shanga Lowe's host of the shaping
fire podcast if you like listening to
smart interviews with the top minds in
cannabis I invite you to check out the
show at shaping fire calm we also have
an extraordinary YouTube channel with
over 150 speaker videos I recorded at
events just like this one in fact our
speaker Ryan Waxman already appears on
the channel teaching about living soil
and avocado tech Brian Laxman is an
accomplished probiotic grower and
sought-after speaker on living soil
cultivation he is co-founder of living
soil solutions through his successful
use of it Ryan has gained insight on how
to build a social media following today
he's going to share that insight with us
please welcome Ryan Madson what's up
don't worry I've been away for a while
so it feels good to come back I've kind
of gone through some things on Instagram
with using some marketing companies and
stuff so I hope to give you guys an
insider's look on what it really takes
to build your Instagram organically so
it kind of ties it into the way that I
like to grow cannabis and the same way
that I like to grow my Instagram account
so for 2020 I really hope that you guys
start to see that social media is king
and then if you guys aren't on at least
Instagram especially for your larger
brands you're really missing out so I
hope to kind of educate you guys and
then like you guys so that at least
you'll start that Instagram and it is a
daily thing all right
all right so who remembers the mass
groups pays anybody in there all right
so that's kind of where I started I
started learning about content creation
that kind of stuff
and because it was all cannabis related
it was pretty easy to gain followers so
I just worked on making sure that my
content tempted proving so the first
viral photo that I ever had was this
photo right here I was done in my
basement and I just started growing the
cover crop improving clones you see a
little one here and then as that one
started to grow I would add the cover
crop a lot of people back then weren't
really showing that so that's how I was
able to start building a profile on mass
groups if you guys remember like Wiz
Khalifa little Wayne if you guys went to
that show this was my first its mass
roots photo that actually was featured
so when it on the platform there that
meant that pretty much every single
person would be able to see your photo
so in hindsight that kind of like gave
me that injection of social media at
work it felt good to open up that
platform and see you know a thousand
people liking your stuff
so unfortunately massroots ended up
getting shut down I believe they went
bankrupt and reported losses of forty
four million dollars so to run these
social media things that's huge
one thing that I did learn with the
massroots pro platform is that basically
I am building my house the same as you
guys on somebody else's land so remember
that if the littlest thing happens all
that work I mean I spent unfortunately I
couldn't get to my match roots account
but I had over 10,000 followers and that
took me about two years to build so that
was really two years waster for me the
next one that I learned about was
content creation again so I started
teaching myself about canva I was
showing out living so if you grow roots
a lot easier than synthetic salts and
this was my first viral content on that
platform unfortunately like I said
massroots got shut down so the next
thing to my attention was the doobie
platform any of you guys were on that
doobie platform as well ya know
on that one so I worked really hard to
do the same thing content creation kind
of the same stuff king same game plan
basically and I was able to build the
largest of following on that app over
49,000 followers
again unfortunately Dubey didn't really
understand the cannabis industry market
so they're kind of just showing girls
and bikinis and that kind of stuff and
there wasn't really any real breeders
any real growers on the platform and so
the interest started to die down
I think they and they lost their
following late August 2018 so just
pretty recently The Doobie start to fall
off as well all right so so then I
actually worked with this man right here
I'm having some other larger brands
around the state through massroots and
through doobie people started to see our
content and that's really when I wanted
to start giving back so we created our
first event it was on September 11th we
were trying to get a bunch of veterans
to come out for free
we had the blooper bus and we all adapt
and back then especially it was pretty
nostalgic everyone kind of enjoyed it
and I was hoping to move forward with
growing on that doobie app unfortunately
that it worked out for me so I started
teaching myself Instagram so this was my
Instagram at the time I was doing
basically the same thing that I was
doing on mass routes and doobie
unfortunately on Instagram there's so
many people on that platform that it's
hard to compete so I was working every
day the same way on mass rooms and
doobie and I was only able to build my
falling to about 2,000 followers so I
really started to focus on what improves
engagement so more showing more faces
showing more of the guys that I'm
hanging out which
the backend of things that you would
think are pretty mundane cut your grows
or your dispensaries that's actually
what people like to see on social media
especially in the Midwest back then
people really like to see us just
messing with plants learning how to grow
cannabis and so I kept the engagement
basically with these two things making
sure that I started to learn about
hashtags and then making sure that every
post that I made had a GU attack so that
would be like the same thing today if
you guys are taking photos making sure
that I said the Denver Mart or you can
also look up where it says Indo Expo
show and then that will actually geotag
right here where you are so a lot more
people will be able to see your content
just using more hashtags and just using
geo tags from there I really started to
dive into what it takes to build an
Instagram account and really that comes
back to the same way when you're trying
to build something like a website you
have to adhere by instagrams algorithm
so what I would basically do is I would
not created my profile right three or
three organic cannabis that is basically
like your email if you will you do never
you never really want to change that
because all those likes all those tags
that people have as soon as you change
that name all of that stuff disappears
so it's kind of like a musician or
something like that when you're on that
platform you never want to change that
you aren't able to change this this is
more for SEO so I like to use emojis
because most people when they look at
your profile they're not really going to
read everything they're gonna scan so
this sticks out when I like somebody's
photo you'll actually see my name and
then living soil cannabis underneath
that with a little brain so if you guys
have business accounts on Instagram this
is this is worth gold right here this is
how people find you so you want to have
something on there not your name like
reality most people don't know me as
Brian most people know me as 3 or 3
organic cannabis so it's kind of
pointless for me to put
name right here because nobody's going
to be looking for that but they are
looking for living soil cannabis then I
would once you sign up for a business
account you're able to use hashtags in
real time so this was who I was working
for back in the day and so I would just
kind of show people that I was using my
Instagram to educate I was using I was
living soil instructor at that time I
was working at Buffalo I was also
growing from green farms
I was also the communications director
for a Denver normal and then I was also
cross promoting back then on the Doobie
act then he would use your the URL that
you want to try to promote and back then
I had only spoken that mechanical Expo
so I'm proud to say that this is my
fourth time speaking at Indo Expo and I
can attribute most of this just from
this Instagram account so you really can
build brands just on Instagram all right
I wanted to so that was the first time
I've ever got a hundred likes so I don't
know if you guys have ever got that real
quick but it's over you're dealing I
feel like it's kind of coming keeps you
going forward when you start to realize
that people are starting to pay
attention to the content that you're
producing does anybody see anything
pretty weird or nostalgia or wise on
this infographic newspapers write
newspapers um I'm sure most of you guys
in here I'm a small-time guy I can't
compete with a Brandon spending seven
hundred nineteen dollars on that but the
one thing that you will not see yet is
there's nothing being spent on social
media at least on Instagram Facebook
you're not even allowed to so that
allows us our small time guys to start
to compete with these bigger brands by
just putting in the work on these social
media platforms I would imagine as we go
nationwide for legalization that
Instagram Facebook will begin to allow
you guys to spend money and promote your
posts but at this time you're not
allowed to so that gives us that even
playing field right
with a small-time guy Instagram and
Facebook although Facebook Osnes owns
Instagram they're vastly different
platforms so what would work on Facebook
is not going to work on Instagram and in
my opinion for cannabis Facebook is
starting to die off
there's about you know there's about 1
million people actively every month on
Instagram and that's actually obviously
a huge place to start to build your
profiles start to get that word out
Instagram because growth is going at 5
percent per quarter and then Facebook is
only a three snapchat at two so you can
see that this is where the growth is
going well if you're gonna spend your
time and I know a lot of you guys are
probably also farmers you don't have a
lot of time I start to just focus on
that one platform and for me everything
has come from Instagram even though I
have been off massroots and I happened
on do be the only time I've actually
made monetary gains in my life is from
Instagram so the platform data is really
starting to come through if you're
posting things on Facebook and Instagram
you're going to see 23% less engagement
on Facebook than you would with the same
photo on Instagram there's brands that
are on Facebook that are promoting and
they've seen 10 times less engagement on
that platform
compared to Instagram so it's not just
me saying this that data is also
starting to show that the majority of
people are starting to move towards mr.
day and then of course that engagement
on platform is 0.09% Twitter 0.40
I'm sorry 2004 8% and then this is
actually pretty impressive for the
entire platform 1.6 percent engagement I
don't know if you guys really understand
those numbers but that is huge for a app
that means there's a lot of people of
that billion people they're checking in
every day looking at their Instagram
feed and that's what we want we want
eyeballs on our content so Instagram was
bought by Facebook
April 9th 2012 for a billion dollars and
they actually reached that billion
monthly
subscribe our users on June 20th 2018 so
it really hasn't been that many years
until everybody started to flocking
towards Instagram Instagram made six
point one eight billion dollars and 2018
they made nine point oh eight billion
dollars in 2019 and they're projected to
make twelve point three two billion
dollars in 2020 so you can tell that
with that amount of money that they're
starting to make that you continue to
improve the platform and where big money
is that's how you know that they're not
gonna fall to the wayside like some of
these other apps that I've been talking
about here who here understands
influencer marketing right so basically
what that is is somebody has a large
profile usually those are like Instagram
models and they take a photo of a
product snap it and then this company
would pay them for doing that when a lot
of those influencer influential
marketing campaigns where asked which
platforms you like to use seventy nine
or seventy three seventy nine percent of
the people chose Instagram so I really
don't want to keep harping on this but
the data and everything is showing that
the entire movement is moving away from
anything really but Instagram maybe a
little bit of tik-tok as well so these
are brands that are actually built on
the Instagram platform solely on
influencer marking and I would imagine
most ladies know this crap you guys
ladies are part of this and then if
you're a workout guy
workout lady bang energy drinks so if
you'll notice they kind of do the same
setup all big brands will use emojis and
then they're trying to get you to go to
something on their year or URL no matter
what brands you are whether you're got a
hundred million followers or you have a
thousand followers you get one link so
the goal is to try to get people to
start to learn more about you using that
URL fashion OVA choose
this post probably five six times a day
really getting their content out there
where Bank Energy probably posts just a
few times so you guys can see that you
know you start posting more times per
day if you're able to do that the more
following and you're going to start to
achieve so last year 95 million photos
were shared per day on Instagram 1
billion of those people were on the
platform every single day
500 million stories are being shared
every single day 63% of Instagram users
log on at least once a day and this is
the metric that everyone should care
about most people are on the entire
platform are on there for at least 28
minutes a day this is huge compared to
any other platform so that's why I keep
my focus on Instagram so instagrams goal
is really to keep you addicted to their
platform they want that 28 minutes to go
up to 32 then to 36 as time goes on one
of the easiest ways for them to do that
is to create certain things like this
Instagram stories is basically like
snapchat so they continue to improve
their platform to steal a lot of that
traffic that's going on to the other
platforms and I imagine in 2020
Instagram is going to continue to do
these things the problem is is that
cannabis is really not allowed on
Instagram so even if you are creating
fantastic content
none of our stuff as far as late 2019
and now in the 20 20 goes on the explore
page and that's really how you build
your account on Instagram so we have to
think through these things to try to
find ways for us to work together to try
to help promote each other stuff so
that's why we tagged each other in the
stories hopefully you can start tagging
more of your friends in the actual daily
posts because none of our stuff is
hitting that Explorer page and this is
carousel was created last year and this
goal is for every single in your post
instead of them when you're going
through your feet you see that one photo
now that carousel
to keep more people on the platform so
you're able to post up to ten photos on
that carousel and that's really where I
feel like the next the next breakthrough
is for us as canvas farmers to start to
show as many photos as we can to try to
continue to fill that engagement with
all of the negative things that are
happening with Instagram and Facebook
has anybody had their account deleted on
Facebook Instagram yeah so you guys know
how it is hardening that is my account
is taking me over three and a half years
to build so if they deleted that
tomorrow to be honest I don't know where
it would be because Instagram really is
building up everything that I'm doing
business-wise branding wise so it's it's
really it's really important to stay
focused on making sure that you guys
understand how the algorithm works and
that's what I'm gonna teach you guys
today so the youth is basically the ones
that are on the platform itself these
numbers I've actually started to climb
late in 2019 so as you guys can see this
stuff isn't going away it's only being
consumed more and more does anybody know
what this is everybody knows your Kylie
Jenner as I'm sure all right so then I
would say the majority of the internet
really doesn't like the Kardashians so
somebody came up with a way to beat her
top photo that was done in 2018 of her
daughter stormy so they just posted an A
and so that they wanted to break the
world record please like this age and I
like this slide because it kind of shows
the power of Instagram we're trying to
do this on obviously a microcosm scale
but if your entire cannabis community
gets behind you your stuff can also kind
of go viral like this so as to date
we're close to fifty three million likes
just on an egg so I would hope that you
guys really start to see there really is
power behind this once those accounts
start to grow and I would give a tip of
the hat to come
called 7/10 labs here in Denver those
guys really understand social media and
their stuff is still trying to go there
a lot of their stuff still goes viral
and that's because they have such a
strong following and you really have to
admire that
in this day and age to try to fill that
stuff up they have quality products I
have nothing to do with 7/10 apps but I
just admire their work everything that
they're doing from product creation to
social media to being around in the
community is the reason why they're able
to combat some of these negative things
that have been happening to a lot of
these cannabis accounts so last year I
was approached by a marketing company
that told me that they could improve my
Instagram account and I sat down in a
meeting with a few of their few of the
people in that marketing firm and they
talked about follow for follow and all
these kind of like silly things that
don't even really work anymore
fortunately for me I started to find out
the day I actually knew more about
Instagram than this marketing company
but I asked them please to not add fake
followers please I don't need fake likes
that kind of stuff and they assured me
that that wasn't going to happen
unfortunately for me that's exactly what
did happen I almost lost my Instagram
account last year so I feel for a few
those people that raised their hand
before this is a nightmare
for a cannabis Instagram account so
basically what had happened was I gave
my password and my username to that
marketing firm they then outsource that
to a third party and all around the
world people started to log into my
Instagram account which means I don't
know how you guys feel but that's almost
like like maybe not as extreme to a bank
account but it's pretty close especially
if you've worked that hard to try to
build that Instagram up so now everybody
has my banking information for Instagram
and again a lot of this stuff I took I
took these three but there was a lot
more log in not only attempts but actual
logins that where people were successful
so if somebody was a militia
they kind of deleted my entire mount and
I have no control over that whatsoever I
hate this okay so this is basically what
they started to do they started spamming
in my DMS which by the way Instagram
watches that stuff so back in the day
I'm sure some of us used to hey man can
I get a couple pounds and then and the
DM that kind of stuff that all the
Instagram algorithm watches all of that
now so a lot of those seed breeders out
there that keep getting their accounts
deleted I can assure them it's because
they're doing business within that
direct message so if they stopped doing
that a lot of their accounts will stop
being tweeted so if you guys aren't
talking business that kind of stuff
within that direct message there's a
chance that you are going to get deleted
and of course if you're spamming people
which they are doing this to thousands
of people right so basically what
they're doing is hey my name is Brian I
work with living soil solutions I'd love
to connect with you sometime thousands
and thousands and thousands of times
every single week some people obviously
get annoyed with that so somebody hacked
into my account and changed everything
again this is a nightmare situation for
me I have no idea what language this is
I had no idea what they had done so it
took me weeks to try to get my Instagram
account credentials back which so
obviously slows down branding or all of
those things and then the dreaded dead
followers ghosts followers these are the
kind of people that started following me
so my account jumped up right and they
were I would go into those meetings they
say oh look look at how many followers
you have now I'm not sure if you guys
understand how that the algorithm at
least works now from twenty nineteen and
twenty to twenty twenty but about seven
to ten percent of your followers are
gonna see your content when you first
post and then those followers are going
to dictate if they like that stuff that
they're engaging I've been making
comments are they sending in to other
people if that is happening then those
photos go on to the next round of your
followers and your content tends to grow
sometimes virally that way
but it's all up to those followers so if
I have a bunch of ghost followers when
I'm posting my posts are literally going
into the ether
there's nobody seeing that content so to
cheat the system in 2019 2020 on
Instagram was foolish maybe when we like
2008-2009 when a lot of that automation
stuff would work a lot of people would
you could kind of you could kind of talk
back in Vegas there'd be 50,000
followers with a hundred likes on a
photo that's a fake right that's a fake
account and in my in my opinion that's
basically like not having account no
one's going to engage that people think
it's silly so I encourage you guys that
if you do have a bunch of ghost
followers this kind of stuff where they
don't need to take the time to post a
photo you can go within your Instagram
account and start to remove those people
and then this is basically Instagram on
the front porch me on their lawn pumping
that shotgun saying if you continue to
do this we are going to delete your
account and this just happened to me
just a few months ago so I I can't
express enough why this is so
disheartening is because I have to work
on my Instagram to throw it the way that
I have organically every single day so
to have that deleted would be
heartbreaking so basically once this
once this comes out I have probably
about a week to two weeks to change
things so I have to make sure that any
kind of program that I've ever logged in
before any kind of third-party app that
is associated with my Instagram I have
to make sure that I log out of that and
delete that from my actual phone itself
or Instagram is going to continue to
notice that if I did nothing here they
would have deleted my account and just
recently this is basically
what is that ninety basically almost a
month ago I got this message and this
comes from still people that do follow
me sometimes they'll go through the feed
and like a lot of photos real quickly
Instagram sees that as a automation
technique and they actually shut down my
account for him for a week every single
day I would tell them that this was a
mistake
and I still wasn't able to log into my
account alright so this is kind of the
bread and butter this is what I want to
teach you guys today this is the way to
build your organically build your
Instagram account I may not have that
22,000 followers that the marketing
companies touted as a good thing but I
do have real followers so when I first
started out again I make sure that this
is up here this is the metric that most
of you to have a business account really
should care about is that how many
people are coming to your profile every
single week my goal with the amount of
followers that I have is to try to get
that up to a thousand every single week
if you notice I have a lower post
profile so if there's something that
really didn't do well or maybe it's an
older post that had you know 34 likes
two years ago I'll just delete that post
because everything comes down to this
algorithm the more followers that I have
the better the algorithm looks and the
less people that I'm following so a lot
of facebook you kind of use follow for
follow if you're friends with somebody
they follow you you follow them back but
on Instagram that algorithms really
looks at that so if no one's posting on
the people that you're following that's
again just the ghost account that's if
it's worthless so there's no reason to
follow people unless they're posting I
would say at least once a week
that they're posting even once a month
it's pointless to follow them I changed
my category to entrepreneur and that
seemed to also boost my following as
well when I changed it from just it's at
college and university so whatever you
guys find some people like to put public
figure
some people later I would imagine a lot
of people would like to put entrepreneur
sometime a brand or business but this is
another way that the algorithm finds
your account so not only am I an
entrepreneur but I'm a living soil
cannabis entrepreneurs and that's the
way the algorithm sees that I've been
rep Sun leaf seed and Dominion seed
company Duke diamond and Derek they're
actually out there today if you guys
want to check out their their seeds and
stuff but it's brands that I admire and
so I put that at the top of the list
because I want people to know that these
are the people that I'm associated with
a business account you're able to then
have touch hashtags and touch applicants
so I'm able to show off that not only do
I work hand in hand with seed companies
I am a public speaker and I also spoke
around the country at these places and
hats off to Shango most because I also
in Portland gave a talk on leaving soil
that is kind of gone pretty well I would
say on that Club I think I think we're
over twenty thousand watches yeah so
that's another way that you can continue
to build your platform through Instagram
is by code promoting so I try to get an
action item so I show a little video
with a finger pointing down again this
is a living soil video and then this
goes to shengo's youtube so it's really
easy for anybody that finds out about me
to find out more about me and I try to
make that as easy as possible I then
have little highlights of what I've done
throughout the the week and then of
course my posts so for 2020 this is kind
of the way that Instagram wants you to
start doing hashtags and tagging people
where you're actually writing it in the
context of what you're saying in that
text bar so instead of just you know
these are the same same photos this is a
gentleman and Oklahoma I thought it was
funny so I
I reposted it I don't know if you guys
have been out to Oklahoma but especially
this time last year this was the kind of
stuff that a lot of these guys were
throwing so I thought I was funny made a
little meme
this gentleman has very little on here
just a few hashtags every single hashtag
that you have is going to go to that to
that main platform so if I have organic
cannabis and you click on that hashtag
it goes to all those organic cannabis
photos as soon as this is posted that's
going to go to the most recent but my
goal is to get seen your goal is to get
seen so you're using those hashtags but
you want to try to find hashtags that
you can rank for because they haven't
what's called top post top nine if you
can get one of your post to be in that
top nine sometimes that will last for
years and then that's really how people
start to find you so I write this out I
tagged two people that are with I start
to look up and research hashtags that I
feel like I can rank for I give credit
because this obviously isn't my photo I
give shoutouts to people that I admire
over the years and as you guys can see I
get way more engagement by doing it this
way so hashtags is really the basis of
Instagram and this is where you guys
really need to take the time to start to
do the research I would say start off
with 10 at a time so I would research 10
hashtags for that week find out what
they are all you really need to do is go
into your Instagram it's a little search
icon type in a organic cannabis hit that
tag and all of those photos especially
that top 9 will pop up so it'll show you
like if you hit cannabis right now I
guarantee it's still at twenty point
four million tags so when we make a post
what you want to do is try to get a
little bit
these larger hashtags so I know when I
make a post most of these hashtags might
last 15 minutes where people are singing
it because so many people are using that
hashtag that it gets lost in the feed
but at the same time 15 minutes on a
large hashtag like that you might get up
and reflects if it's quality photo then
I go down and I try to do like the
medium-sized stuff so these hashtags
when I make a post would probably last
maybe 15 20 minutes 30 minutes depending
on how many people are on the platform
for that day and then I do more like a
niche type stuff that is relevant to me
so I'm really big on quality we we kind
of jumped on the bandwagon of a girl
like a pro and then these two tags I
obviously create so if you have a brand
create something that that is relevant
to you it doesn't even really matter if
a lot of people see that because not
many people are using living soil
solutions hashtag but if they do go and
click that they're going to see all of
my posts or my business partners posts
so it's really important to make sure
that you guys use a few that go out and
then all the way up to the top where
there's millions of people looking at
that on a daily basis Instagram stories
you guys using Instagram stories this is
kind of the new frontier if you're not
seeing a lot of action on your posts I
assure you if you do have a quality
following you'll see a lot of action on
your stories a lot of people don't even
want to scroll through the feed anymore
they just want to sit there and hold
their phone and sit there and watch the
stories scroll so I encourage you guys
this is more of like the daily kind of
stuff so if you're just daily here at
the end of Expo show take a quick photo
put that in your stories if it's
something that you know you haven't seen
a buddy in a long time and you're making
a photo and you want something to be
permanent then that's what I would post
up in your actual post fee where people
will see that usually for years to come
and Instagram stories is a little bit
different than just your normal hashtags
Instagram stories only last with 24
hours so our goal is to go big so we
never want to use niche type hashtags
unless we're at a like an in each type
of thing otherwise you want to use these
larger hashtags so if you're doing
something with cannabis like obviously a
4/20 sticky hashtag it's going to be a
lot pop a lot more popular than just my
living soil solutions now many people
are going to see that and then again it
only lasts for 24 hours
so who's heard of Gary beep like I
crushed it so this really is the secret
of how I've been able to organically
build my Instagram from 4,000 followers
to 17,000 followers with no gimmicks and
it's the dollar 80 principle so
basically what I do is I go around and I
put my two cents in on these top nine
photos for these 10 hashtags that I've
just done research on so every day I'm
putting my two cents in on those top
nine and then that's what I allows me to
get to that dollar 80 so this stuff
usually takes probably an hour or two of
my time every single day there really is
no secret there's no automation anymore
that's kind of like going to the gym you
they put in the work and you do this
formula you will see your Instagram grow
I guarantee you and if you stick with
this stuff for 90 days I assure you
you're going to start getting hundreds
of sometimes thousands of followers a
week because you're posting your two
cents on those top nine photos and
sometimes those top nine photos will
last for years so sometimes I'll put
like hey check out organic Canada 3 or 3
organic cannabis I'm repping suddenly
seeds at Indo Expo and out and I'll post
that or if there's somebody that makes
like a really good photo
hey great photo somebody's been working
out that kind of stuff
hey man swole that kind of stuff so
you're really trying to engage with your
audience without making it come off as
spam does everybody kind of get how this
yeah and then this is it in real time so
I just click on organic marijuana these
are the top posts for that hashtag and
then I just go through those top nine
start to scroll down like the photo add
a comment
and I do that for all top nine and I do
that for ten hashtags every single day
and I promise you stick with that for 90
days and your account will explode but
there is no sort of shortcut so I see
another gentleman I I agreed with that
little meme hashtag to make sure that
the account owner sees it and then I
just keep it moving i if I'm following
someone I make sure that I go through
and I like every single one of their
photos for that day I'm not one of these
guys that I don't like that photo so I'm
not gonna like it
my goal is to build a brand on this to
Graham so all the people that I follow
already I like them so I'm going to give
them a like every time that I do put a
like on their photo it pops up three or
three organic cannabis like this photo
so that means that when people that are
also following me when they see that
same photo they're able to also see that
three or three organic cannabis like
that photo there's some more stuff from
Indo Expo last year
so like some of my friends here right
they also like that photo and that's why
anybody that I'm following I make sure
that I like their photo as best as I can
and try to keep up that several times a
day because this is also brandy people
you know if you get 863 likes on a photo
that probably means you know double that
amount of people actually probably saw
that photo so it's a good metric for me
to be able to gauge how people like my
content whether they didn't like that
content and then this is my these are
the amount of followers that I've
actually gotten in real time again I've
been shadow band last year does anybody
know what that means
so shadow banning is when I'm using my
hashtags and it it's not showing up in
that hashtag feed so I put organic
cannabis click on that it doesn't show
up in that hashtag that's what's known
as shadow band that's how they punish
you if you will for not doing what
instagrams asking and I got punished
pretty heavily with this because I was
using automation software if this sounds
too daunting for you guys especially I
mean it really is an hour and a half to
two hours every single day of going
through and lighting stuff on Instagram
to be able to build your profile my
opinion is then focused on LinkedIn I
think this is going to be huge for 2020
and beyond and it's very easy to gain
traction I love you guys on LinkedIn as
well yeah it's pretty confusing though
right I mean you kind of look through
there and there's there's still kind of
a lot of spam stuff but you guys know
who owns LinkedIn
nobody Microsoft Microsoft clones
LinkedIn so there's deep money behind
this so that's another platform that's
not gonna fail like
foods would like to be that's gonna run
out of money so I would put my time and
attention to some of these that you know
we're gonna stick around for a long time
and there's not really that many people
that engaged on LinkedIn so it's a lot
easier to start to build that brand I
would go brand with that kind of stuff
and show people your other profiles then
they at the end of the day my goal is to
give people whether they look me up by
my name Brian Waksman
or by my Instagram handle that a lot of
things start to pop up on on the Google
search engines now if you have a website
usually you have to hire somebody that
really understands SEO to start to get
to the top of that but a hat would be if
you can start to improve your social
media profiles Google loves those
profiles especially YouTube that kind of
stuff cuz they own that platform so
they'll put your information at the top
of that that the top 10 search speed and
that's really where anybody at least a
nowadays seems to go if you're not in
that top 10 most people don't go to the
page 2 page 3 and the easiest way to get
to that top 10 is through social media
so I left this open because I really
like to engage with you guys on
questions so guys have a few questions
so I think tick tock is is going to be
huge right now it's kind of gimmicky and
it's young but I definitely feel like
it's going to here to stay so that is
probably something you know probably
this year I'll start to research and
learn on my own but right now I just
don't have enough knowledge uptick talk
to send a help anyone right now I have a
couple questions you said that cannabis
and devils not allowed on Instagram are
you talking about
sales of canvas micarta is the cannabis
products Instagram will not allow you to
pay to promote and that's really how a
lot of these marketing companies get by
with stuff so if I was selling teapots
right I can pay to have those teapots
promoted on that platform but because
cannabis is federally legal they will
not allow you to promote so right now
all of us are on the same playing field
is some of these large brands and this
is that small little window that some of
you guys can continue to build your
brand's that's why I was shown that
infographic how much money is really
starting to be spent on advertising
cannabis none of that money can be spent
on these social media platforms at this
time but you're also you changed just a
plant mark up for people to sell lights
or supporting products or containers
it's just there's some brands that can
get away with that but if you're using
the hashtag cannabis or something like
that the algorithm is going to
eventually see that okay then you said
the 7:10 lab guys were super rad across
the having a great page so I go to the
opening a 220,000 likes or followers but
their pages private so some people
believe that Instagram isn't going to
delete your account if you keep it
private
they have such a following in such a
known
around the country that they're able to
do that in my opinion if you're a
business especially a cannabis business
there it's silly to keep your profile
private because no one's going to be
able to see that unless you already have
that brand but for most of us in this
room we're trying to build that brand so
if we keep that profile private no one's
going to see that's going to probably
end a bunion book knows no pricing
whatsoever more questions I know you got
on the train
yes sir the the algorithm likes it when
you physically hit that button so I
would honestly I would move away from
anything automated especially for 2020
and Instagram hates automation because
especially on these third party
platforms you guys are spending money
with them eventually they want us to
spend money on their platform so that's
why they're not allowing us to be on
that explore page and that kind of stuff
because they really want us to do it
correctly or you're gonna get hammered
like I did last year
HootSuite was cool like five years ago
that's anything automated really is
dying off even with the influencer
marketing that I was talking about from
before right
Instagram hates influencer marketing
because those big brands are using those
Instagram models to promote everything
so that's why they in my opinion that's
why they got rid of the likes last year
for the majority of the accounts because
you take away those lights from likes
from the influencer pages and nobody
really knows how powerful that account
is on Instagram anymore
it'll just say so many people and
thousands of others of others like that
photo
no your that's what I mean you're kind
of you're out there in the ocean if you
will and there's really no way I mean
one day Instagram to come and delete
your account and that's what I meant
from before Lee we are building our
houses on somebody other else's land and
they can come and take that away from us
at any time so that's why I wanted to
show you guys in real time what if
Instagram will start to do and start to
threaten you if you do not play by the
rules they're very secretive in the way
the algorithm works the same way that
Google is for a lot of those webmasters
trying to figure out how to get you or
brands on that top 10 list is the same
thing with Instagram everybody sits
around and tries to figure out what is
the best way to promote can you speak a
little further into LinkedIn
yes it's kind of the same way I mean
right now my strategy on LinkedIn is
just a post quality content and you
don't really have to be on it as much
because Microsoft is throwing a lot of
money into that because they want to
compete with Instagram the majority of
the people since they're already posting
on Instagram they just don't have enough
time to go and do these other platforms
so how do we get more people to come to
LinkedIn before we start to encourage
other people to see these profiles so
you can post pretty gimmicky stuff on
LinkedIn it was still kind of like a
thousand two thousand people see that or
on Instagram I mean you really have to
have quality content get a thousand
likes we are out of time thank you very
much to Brian watts
you