one thing I want to point out is that
you know social media like Facebook is a
really great way to recruit people
because you can find them so easily but
I also want to encourage you that if
you're gonna found your own organization
as soon as you've started to recruit
your people and you start doing planning
for events get off Facebook because
Facebook is not protected speech and the
the statements that you make in private
communications are not in any way
private um get yourself some you know
encryption right start using an app like
signal on your phone so your
conversations with other people that
you're organizing with are encrypted and
is something that the NSA cannot get
their hands on start to use a mailing
list like and rise up so that you know
that your archives are being encrypted
and and preserved um even though we
enjoy a lot of Liberty here in
Washington I'm working with people all
the time across the country who are in
states like Idaho and and you are still
targets and we're still targets here in
Washington so err on the safe side do
your recruiting with something like
Facebook or Twitter but then when you
start bringing together core members
transition