so hair is great to run into you today
at NCI a here in San Jose and you know
everybody kind of got freaked out in
surprise to find out that you're no
longer had forever flowering greenhouses
because we all know you like you're at
every convention and you know we all
know you as being the person who built
you know forever flowering into the epic
thing it is by being everywhere but now
you're not there anymore and so I'm glad
I ran into you because I wanted to know
what you're up to now and after talking
with you for a little bit it sounds like
you've got some opportunities but you're
also looking for some kind of
opportunities so I just wanted to take a
second and find out what you're up to
let everybody know so because you'd like
everybody who's watching is on your team
right so so what do you got going on now
post forever flowering well I appreciate
you saying all that stuff I appreciate
everybody's support right now I took the
job with a distribution company and so
I'm actually going out farm to farm
sourcing trim at the moment they do all
kinds of things but my job primarily
at the moment is defined trend so I'm
connected with a lot of farms and the
funny thing is as far as I normally
would wouldn't connect with that I'll
believe I'm now connecting with because
of my notoriety I guess you could say
and so being able to connect with those
farms has been kind of cool because now
I'm actually seeing a side of people and
things that I normally would see those
with that company and then it also turns
into talking about greenhouses allowed
you so now a lot of people have searched
out for me to still get green house
advice right and so not that I like the
word consultant I like more of strategy
or buy three of those kind of words but
people still want my opinion and so I'm
willing to give that opinion and of
course I want to monetize it so yeah I'm
not really interested in trying to sell
or resell goods as much as I'm happy to
sell the advice and we'll work with a
lot of the connections that I have in
the industry and even the community too
farmers in whatever capacity they
request so you got got like two hustles
going right now here you got the the
sourcing trim for business partner one
and then obviously people are gonna be
asking you about greenhouses labor
collie forever now alright cuz you're
you know industry expert so let's talk
about the troopers right so so what kind
of opportunities like are you looking
for people who have got their license
and have got trim that they want to sell
on the open market does that is that the
kind of people you're looking to connect
with yeah and it's kind of fun because
you know managing a company for 11 years
like I did came with a lot of pressures
of you know a lot of decisions to make
and things like that so basically now
it's kind of listening to what other
people are doing and just going out and
doing something that is really kind of
fun in a way because I'm not selling
something that I'm trying to buy
something it's a nicer yeah and I'm
connecting with the same group of people
if not these same people that I've
connected with before so it's on a
different level for a different purpose
but it's still within my community that
I love so much and the people that
actually trust and support me as well
that are coming out and you know it
might not be a career move some of my
going went for managing a company to
take another
whatever but like I said without taking
a break this was a quick way to jump
into something that I feel like I can
you know bring value to and also do a
pretty good job at and I'd have to
really think and make so many critical
decisions you know maybe sleep better at
night in some cases so a lot of that
stress is relieved and now going out and
doing that's been kind of fun but like I
said now I'm getting hired to actually
going to Vegas next week to consult on a
greenhouse project that merely want my
advice they don't really need to buy
pick my brain and they're willing to pay
me for it and so I figured out a way to
come up with a rate sheet that kind of
discusses a few different services
whether it's giving a presentation to
helping people that have never
understood or dealt with the green house
before or to people that are already on
their way into it and the biggest one
now is green house rescue there's so
many green house people that are either
getting into an existing order of built
one and maybe don't have the right head
grow or maybe they are putting the
pieces together properly working harder
not smarter a lot of those things I can
address pretty fairly easily and it's
something I feel like I'm pretty good at
and so the green house rescue a lot of
capacity you know kind of coining it
taking off you know that actually makes
a lot of sense too because when you were
a guest on my shape and fire podcast one
of the things like you've kept on coming
back to is a lot of your job was just
stopping people from doing the stuff
they were doing wrong right
it's like it's like the greenhouse
itself you know if you if you build it
right you're in good shape and then but
then when how people choose to use it
you know gets them in all sorts of
trouble right down to using black fabric
bags instead of brown right it was
amazing over the course of the last year
so the people that I've met
two farms that had our greenhouses I
felt like understood what we were all
about or the message that I was laying
down and I came to the realization and a
lot of people didn't quite I mean they
bought product or greenhouses from me
and things but they still didn't quite
get the concept and so I feel like I'm
still saying the same story and trying
to hold the same space that I did before
because that information I feel like his
by the way it's still the same
information it's helping people but like
I said you know even people that I'm the
closest to might not have seen my
presentations or heard my message before
so how about anybody you can avoid
hearing you because you were everywhere
that's what I thought and I feel like
sometimes I feel like I've been
everywhere and said it and other times I
felt like man nobody's heard anything
because I'm out here just repeating
myself and going over
same things you know what the greenhouse
is the ground covers the colors the
clear skins different little things
trapping air and the default is to turn
on a fan rather than open it up and stop
traffic airs I mean it's just methods to
the madness and unfortunately in
California we lost a lot of brands or
people that were originally pioneering
people or companies due to regulations
so with those people being gone we have
a whole new crop of people that in some
ways need that education our industry
has got such churn dude
it's looks like or and then you don't
got all these new states coming online
yeah and then since you did I mean you
did my show a couple times but but you
know you're kind of everywhere right you
did everybody yeah so so there's people
who are coming across you as the
greenhouse expert in everybody's back
catalogue right I think you're on my
show like like a year and a half ago
right people still write to me to say oh
my god that was a great show like how do
we get in contact with you know yeah and
so you know as people come across all
the media that you've been in I can
imagine that still calling you up you
know thinking you're still where you
were but you're all like nope freelance
now bit in like let me solve your
problems for cheaper yeah and I got a
mix of that here today I saw people that
knew or followed kind of the story or
kind of saw
things were going in my transition and
gave me a lot of accolades and support
today and there was people that didn't
know and learn today and like I was
saying people just want to hear the
advice or or work with me in the sense
that I do have a lot of connections to
source a lot of things to make a
business work or to fix a business
that's having problems yeah and actually
I heard you say that stuff a couple
times to people like bring people up to
speed and you know I'm like you know you
and I've been pals for a while now but I
thought it was very honorable that you
were talking any [ __ ] about your old
employer right right like a lot of
people like you know when they're not
somewhere anymore they talk a lot of
crap right he put him on blast yeah
totally and that's that's not your way
you're just like you know parting the
ways doing my own thing now yeah there's
a lot of honor in that well I appreciate
that I mean I tried to do my best in the
11 years that I was there and treated
like it was my own company and I was a
partial owner wasn't a majority owner
and you know after
years my time is kind of I guess you
could say and so it's actually been a
nice breath of fresh air even though
transitions can be tough but you know
the cannabis industry still has a lot to
offer for people and I'm glad that I've
been here so long so that I do have
these connections and
our support an appreciative of stuff you
know like it's hard to believe how
appreciated people are to my commitment
to
industry well also you're a giver right
like you know yeah I mean like you and I
get it off right away but there's no
doubt man you introduced me to people at
Emerald cup your shirt or sermon you
told people like yeah he's not he's not
a local humble guy but he's overhead so
I'm sure you do that to all sorts of for
all sorts of folks and so you know just
like why I hunted you down today you
know like you know people want to get
back yeah yeah and I don't do it for
everybody but I definitely do it for the
people that I find the same community
spirit the passion for the planet you
know what I mean
I think we can see each other you know
through a crowd sometimes and sort out
who's who even from being outside
blazing a doobie yeah and I versus
standing in line at the bar yeah right
and so you know some of those things
give it that community effort that we're
really a part of it makes us remember
and see each other every time we're here
versus being at the bar
you know maybe remembering each other or
not it's usually not for the same
meaning that we put to it and why we're
here yeah so so let's wrap this up by
talking about like the kind of
opportunities are looking for right
because it's kind of the goal of life
you know me doing this inside I wanted
to get you plugged in replugged in a new
ways rain and so you got the trim thing
going on should people reach out to you
if they have trim for sale yeah
definitely so what are you looking for
specific I'm looking for state permitted
trim and it can be in various quality
there's a various price range for that
quality it needs to pass testing for
contaminants it's a micro process so
they test it for everything and even the
returns and then we basically quarantine
it for two weeks while the testing is
going on
we come out and cash out on the spot we
can even do wire transfers so it's not a
terms of 30 or 45 days or anything other
than that yes the testing give us a
minute we'll be right back and then we
cash out and that works really well and
it seems to be compared to what I'm
hearing a pretty good opportunity and
then with the greenhouse consulting I'm
creating a rate card that's going to
have different services different ways
for people to basically utilize my
information and my connections within
the industry and so like as far as the
greenhouses people should contact you if
if they are considering a greenhouse and
they want to understand it better and
they want to think about what vendor to
go to and if they've got a greenhouse
that's maybe underperforming or they
want it to perform better or they've got
like you know when greenhouses go bad
and they never got a situation because
like everybody knows you're like the
greenhouse save King because you're
always out at greenhouses seem like
worst-case scenario it's all true and
it's all been cannabis that's the other
thing like there's plenty of greenhouse
experts of greenhouse people out there
that way
I'm sure and the thing that I know is
the cannabis side of everything related
to greenhouses for more than eleven
years because when I moved to Humble in
1992 I was really chasing down cannabis
more than anything
black boxing and like Depp is part of
that greenhouses eventually became part
of that yeah I turned he didn't do it
career for the last 11 years he'll be
really on the spot for you know ground
zero for cannabis greenhouses seeing all
the stumbling blocks and things that
people go through and really they're
usually right there if we switch a
couple things up or layer things a
little bit more properly things can take
off pretty quickly so I'm there and I
can be there for the long haul or I can
be there for the one day you know here's
what I have to say and sometimes that's
a vetting process you but like you said
I've been around a little while and I do
have some good references together yeah
yeah all right so then so then you got
the trim of the greenhouses are you also
like open for opportunities like like if
somebody and like oh my god Eric Brant
said we'd be perfect for this
positioners like like like if people got
like you know job opportunities do you
want to hear about those - yeah I'd love
to hear from those I'm always down to
hear about what's going
I'm always excited to hear what other
companies are doing I like to be
innovative and creative at the same time
me and that's the thing about this
industry it's still blossoming and
really expanding yes my whole thing is
you know I love to see opportunity for
everybody and I always try to create it
for other people as well even if I'm
working with them before them and so I
feel like if somebody has that maybe for
me I'm willing to look for sure alright
so then how do people get a hold of you
if they've got one of these things they
want to talk to you about if it's the
trim I'm Eric er I see at bockscar
supply cocom and then if you want to get
a hold of me just for the greenhouses
you can get a hold of me at Eric at
Jasmine farms calm and that's ER I see
Eric at Jasmine farms I know you want to
plug your Instagram - oh yeah it's like
dipped greenhouse light underscore DEP
underscore greenhouse and I'm still
providing content like they used to on
my old account I'm still you know
answering dm's and you know trying to
build up my account it's not what it
used to be but at the same time I'm
still trying to provide a lot of that
info
because I'm still going out to
greenhouses and creating that content
and things like that so I'm trying to
make it available for people you know
for free too yeah around will do you've
been like you know you're like one of
the people in that industry was like
universally loved and and and you've got
a lot to share and you're smart as hell
so I'm sure that you are going to like
you know figure out after these
in-between hustles where you want to
really be so best of luck to you and I
think should they get a couple minutes
with me it's always good soon all right