all right everybody want to take a seat
we are going to get going
welcome to the 2 o'clock
panel on choosing your extraction
technology I am your host with camel
Shango Lo and I'm also host of the
shaving fire podcast if you enjoy
listening to interviews with top people
in the Canada's game I encourage you to
grab flier the door on your way out and
tune in to my podcast where we listen to
conversations like this each and every
week I would like to first introduce our
guest today starting to write directly
to my right Corey Chavez from Summit
extraction system in the middle is dr.
George snatcher from covert and ibn dr.
Sheldon Ronald jr. from allatheena
environmental sciences welcomed Walters
so these are merely highlight the each
speakers bio I encourage you to google
them or approach them after the panel to
find out more information on these
gentlemen are so smart that they go on
for paragraphs and then we wouldn't have
time for your questions so starting at
the far end as Sheldon protal junior PhD
is chief executive and science officer
of Alpena City
Idina Environmental Services Athena
specializes in designing and building
the tools needed to produce and purify
biomolecules and then developing
applications for those biomolecules
Athena has a diverse product portfolio
of over 205 and that our solar of the
world for basic science and commercial
uses in the middle is Jorge Sanchez is
founder and CEO of Coburg an innovative
extraction of purification systems
company you will need PhD in
an MBA the pride management and MS in
electrical engineering technology and
numerous patents granted and ending in
durban memories Corey Shaw SGS CEO and
co-founder of some extraction systems on
Loveland Colorado a manufacturer of
closed-loop Duty extraction systems
queries also founders that will Durango
a marijuana reform organization that
coordinated with national activists to
advocate for marijuana decriminalization
and regulation the weight of the form
has been dealt with this panel here I've
got a series of questions that I'm going
to ask the gentlemen and starting one
end and we'll start at the other end and
hopefully getting a little bit of
conversation going and we'll take about
10 to 15 minutes at the end for your
questions so we're going to start with
with a question on the far end or
Rochelle in there so Shelly I work with
clients who have chosen their products
for market first and then they choose
their extraction technology to suit the
product of a guideline but I've also
worked with clients who first choose
their preferred extraction method and
then they design the product on what
those technologies can do so where do
you suggest that a new cannabis company
looking to extract starts their decision
making process well as might each tech
entrepreneurship University the first
thing I'd say ask your customer what do
they want so I would I would argue that
you want to start with the customer what
does the customer need
what does the customer trying to
accomplish what a problem when you're
solving for the customer build your
formulations based on on that
information and then decide what the
extractions are bouncing
patient process would be to meet the
specifications to every rhythm of
succession law Houston as well because
reading a customer gives you markets and
yoga without its opponent innovation
because it does probably like invasive
cost but pretty much if you want to
examine market tomorrow you to listen
yeah so I knowing the important like a
great big component of choosing your
special technology certain extraction
methods are well-suited to killer and
odd there's some extraction up it's
better more versatile than others so
knowing that end prize you'd like to
create whether that high-end concentrate
shatter or wax visible it's it rides
your pen or
use edible product or topical cream
those are kind of the major categories
vaporizing fans concentrated edible and
topical products if there's one of those
categories in particular of appealing to
your company and we can work backwards
from that to determine which extraction
method is best suited there's some
extraction methods that are generally
there well students work for all the end
product and then there's other
technologies that you can add your
initial extraction system to further
purify the product particularly on such
dive into that a little bit more as we
go in product doing your end product is
of course very important what are you
put the chronic your pre pre market and
if you don't know and maybe a comments
more or necks gosh method more
versatility is
so this will speak so there's a wide
range of opinion regarding the use of
hydrocarbons like butane propane for
extraction
you know they get great taste and good
return by percent but so if you know how
to remove your business solvents in the
industry leading to fail lab tests and
sometimes a dangerous product to the
public to what degree do you think that
these technologies will continue to be
top-tier options for commercial candice
extractors well again unfortunately to
the previous question what exactly we
need to discuss there are different
solvents and their difference of
teachers and the plant equal an extra
seven teachers they're also a low
efficiency Devon there are also wood and
water school give us water except one
part use multiple nominations was that
well you see were expecting and it is
important feature of us for once to get
separate ways because simple forward
water you may achieve as an extra
attending moon the water that's very
expensive process because they have to
feed it
it's a long process so see you Julius
that is a process that cannabis
automatic eat but then some ability of
see with you it's very tricky to set the
point to dissolve and it can result with
YouTube and water salt and alcohol
soluble edibles of what you need to set
up the impact point of the certain
temperature and pressure in order to
simply filter actually you take more
that you need again coming back to the
question what example you need to strap
the truly future stock oils they're
nonpolar solvents that can help ease it
up if you want to extract supplements
what's the news
I will say there general solar
technologies like my preteens and
alcohols and hexane and future different
always use because they generate very
well and it can make wrong with you
if you know your properties will isolate
or isolate and anything else but the
first step to conversion of all these
from the production that gives you
with the consequence that would so
couple of sort of parallel things to
consider when you're choosing what
solvents work with solvent recovery is
very important
so how expensive it is going to be to
recover that solvent
how much energy you're going to Queens
per system because the more difficult
the solvent recovery is and higher the
higher cause poor the economics on your
process another aspect is it's in this
particular industry everyone is being
very I would say eco friendly so a
sustainable environment record which is
really cool to watch and kind of fun
coming out of pharmaceutical industry to
watch that it's constraint and involving
with a very very strong go friendly
environmentally responsible mindset so
when you think in those terms think
about how is the solvent don't you
recover and it's not recovered just a
little bit doesn't leak out what damage
is going to do to my employee myself and
what damage could possibly do to the
environment count by minimize died and
then the other aspect to is then the end
amount of some solvents are more
economical to work with so the sort of
this multi-faceted and I hate to use
this term - but it's coming down the
pipe regulation so you know you've got
OSHA regulations to start with but sorry
folks
coming soon and they're going to require
certain controls in place that you can
guarantee to remove that salt from your
system so I think you know long-term
thinking in terms of all these aspects
environmental responsibility economics
and what regulatory issues am I going to
be dealing with down the road a bit
yeah I think more than you want to your
question was what concerns over residual
Falconer is the children's cabinet my
hydrocarbon office like direct be okay
because we're talking about products or
customers right and people are really
concerned about you know Pho and be a
show and envy the core skills a lot of
lap up in removing residual also get Ron
yeah so um I think much more assertive
how many years ago one of the great
demands that our industry is creating
higher quality better person solvents
are becoming more readily
or light hydrocarbons amusing and
cocaine that means 99.99 hopefully more
9 or as close to hundred aqua percent
purity so solvent distributors gas
distributors are getting better as
providing concentrate manufacturers with
higher purity solvents
to create great pharmaceutical-grade
solidly so that's a good trend that
minimizing that concern is always such
an alumnus close to pure chemical form
to just detainer just propane the best
also filtration at this position
closed-loop systems are proving filter
media and process improvements such as
doing a butane or propane distillation
prior to introducing solvents actual
candidate extraction but just building
the solvent south prior to doing a
traction around that removes a lot of
traditional family
heavy metals and we work in that may
have ended up in a solvent so there's a
number of ways filtration media
distillation iron extraction on that you
know my residual qualities mmm product
and then also the number of great
technology after step one which I called
it
step one recent turmoil through the age
of extraction you can use white film
system to totally remove residual almond
in the process also rationing in
separate CBD THC compound to break this
the residual Collins beer
you're isolating the compound in the
process alternating above so there's a
number of techniques and trends and in
the industry that are improving the
quality impurity
your children eh-oh
right so before you go on I'm
questioning whether or not great light
it's big moon are you in the back able
to hear Cory yeah okay great cool just
want to make sure yeah Ocean Lakes
resolution okay all right all right now
that - all right great so so for the
next question let's see here
we're back to starting with Dorset issue
with so so if you're kind of a lot to us
I know that a lot of people I expecting
us to be talking about a present
existing I jack but as far as
entrepreneurs in the market and what
people are asking for we're talking
about Robin just so pressing flowers
with a little bit of heat has come a
long way from using the hair
straightener to the new scaled up
presses that output a flood of brands at
one time and yet they don't really feel
ready for large-scale commercial uses
that said the returns look pretty good
and often on par with BHO and the purity
without question because they don't use
any moment at all
many believe that the chemical
processing is the future but the
technology or has not been upscaled yet
so what are your thoughts on the current
state of blossom style extraction
technology and where do they end or
again this is Russians
that user you need a concentrate or just
oil from the pot because we move
president you get usually in a plant
ecology about 30 percent in bed we will
be cheaper said this is lost and when
you use a system like with a little
podcast and you really are concentrate
where the world is a point was has
concentrated 60 to 85 percent and when a
boulder concentrate you also are used
service activity in the solvent to be
able to use that always here like evil
products you can count with certain
traditions efficient only gums is that
if you have a suit for about Rendon it's
very simple very clever to do that in
tutoring one on it is it works mostly on
Thomas because if you have to process
think that the subtle patiently so
usually if you want to purchase power
switch rather than change
poetry's eventually right
I think broadly present other mechanical
methods of extraction are great but as
you indicated that their difficulty
producing scale so that's really the key
key point to choosing your technology
and what is your probably why would you
put how much compromise you really need
product if it's small amount you mean a
Robin pres or another animal movements
activism night water bath over hash like
bags or bubble hash wash machine those
are much simpler and much less expensive
methods of extraction occurred with saw
debase extraction but all the maze
extraction to get a win in terms of
issues
process to put every day so I think
Roger brothers are are really good for
contour authentic Martha's they
typically get a shadows reduced through
a Robin president typically a premium
product in this dispensary is not very
well every well-known in just general
the general market that's why I can
serve a mark on for product that whole
forgotten in the know know how know
about different extraction methods are a
little bit more I tuned the industry I
request that work bubble hash
concentrate but then though they not
efficient method of production for
edible oil
or any other form of concentration at
scale in a production ten o'clock I
would say the one advantage to the price
type or mechanical abstraction system we
have it is not no confuse the material
with the we call it adventitious agent a
solvent that was not normally there so
at some markets it's going to have a
benefit because you're not going to have
exposed to these extra agents on the
other hand you get a very different
product so I think again gentleman said
it often times look back to which
customer and what kind of product or
they want to going the server poisons in
the market
I think somebody can figure out how to
scale it it's very competitive but I
think that scaling issue and that's
probably around the corner because of
course that they use similar types of
technologies with other seed oils and
that's not a very very large scale so
there's a particular case and it's only
a matter of time before some engineer
figures it out and there doesn't seem to
be a lot of people think about that
technology now might be good like or
even is it how does do revive and keep
it you know the temperatures have gotten
so low at this point it does a pretty
decent job with server
like that yeah unfortunately probably
it's probably just for because we were
having and not it purpler now maybe but
it's also I think yet to be my voice
wasn't pretty can do with the downstream
right so what other processes that
you're going to go through as well of
course I'm sure I'm going to get at the
Ellen's I've seen our question with I
think a lot impressed these two factors
extractor is like the select ability
using a solvent so I and then efficiency
the extraction process by plated rasa
prices probably proficient Buffett and
has really no select ability that would
be drawback or if you're just trying to
extract air working from the plantings
it's okay but it's not as likable I get
this goes back to the original round of
questions when we're talking about what
you're producing and for a lot kind of a
customer because if you're looking if
you're looking for use a product that
you whole plants right so especially for
your protagonist discussion in a take
medical so we're thinking a lot about
whole brand healing immersed in a
technology that's going to pull out you
know to learn attaboy
to be used at ice
that certainly broadens is not going to
be an appropriate technology yeah so I
remember that so so all three of you
gentlemen have expertise on a wide range
of extraction technologies but I also
expect that you each probably have at
least one solution that you feel to be
you know either the best or at least the
one that you most recommend to cannabis
entrepreneurs who are moving into
extraction and so my question is what
are you recommending to people right now
we're going into business as your
preferred solution so we want sort of
Sonia okay so where do our group works
on the downstream side so we actually
don't have a preferred method for people
like me don't narrow it down down I mean
what does that mean sure
so the downstream side so it's the way
we view the materials working with
there's a crude crude oil extract has
hundreds of compounds in it that's what
we refer to extraction as an upstream so
that's even upstream from that at the
plant itself to grow the plant under
certain conditions the plant makes
certain combination of the different
phytochemicals
that have their various activities the
next step is to extract those chemicals
out - it's called crude crude material
which is what most folks are working
with right now and then our idea is that
you go one step further now and you
start separating all those components of
the plant into their individual chemical
constituents and then because the two
things and so that that after the
extract will be refer to as the
downstream certification so for those of
us that work more on the downstream side
where we're trying to separate
everything we've developed it a really
technical regard to how you extract and
so our systems can handle any type of
material coming off the extraction and
so intentionally we're not worried too
much about whether it's using co2 freon
butane or in the other types of solvents
because our system is designed to be
able to separate all that's left out I
think so your your starting point is not
the flower or trim your starting point
is the oil and after your posting about
what to do with it that going forward
that's right
well our company designs different
systems hexane routine alcohol what is
team water but we're here talking about
a solvent called pre-owned is the most
most litigious to extract samples CBD
THC and entering and curative Rio is as
with this plant because business
activity we measures over 95% efficiency
attacks which is very very you know each
delete any possible setting after you
have desta talked about the pool parties
were not into the default on expert and
we wanted to a concentrate or isolate we
won this ISIL this experts or assistant
like HPLC and we get like a tinnitus at
UCB GE and we separate the service
another
so in our case are using pre-owned it's
advantage because of course the be 40
minus 30 degree C that means that you
know what some temperature is well in
gaseous state so Molly he took the clock
Torretta G and you can like prepared to
unfold in deviating water point compared
to few days of audio and always hear
Chile's kind of competitive together
girls on the same types of Rihanna's the
problem of toxic I also data Association
said concentration in violence takes the
world for hours while April Santha
course Eugene and Marvel can make you
printed employment and this was an
immediate violence Bob it happens it has
a compulsion for work with robotics ties
together what without by obtaining with
a refrigerator it's not mistaken and
part of medicine to extraction succeed
looking for gbng is law so as reading
about this technology integration prism
and the number the returned numbers were
pretty astonishing you know it
how long does technology in around
because you actually downloading and
call up some of my extractions are
living that you heard about this pure
project
using freon drop rate on and so on and
then equip them of the interview that
you saw how hard was the technology
visit the purified without radiance
geopipes is normal in the last year's as
we enter the cannabis killed before that
or told us we were doing aromatics and
Primus in favor of marketing exception
of growth model of oils of 32 different
and being naughty for a long time is the
residual industry it's approved by FDA
since 2001 and in Europe's misogyny
report for very poor and struggling
muscle being around food so we found it
been proven in other industry but it is
a rival candidate is the part that's
more not necessarily technology though
yes because kind of individual spin of
all so you just respond to general soul
whatever out there and when we talk
about traction about box care about
boredom I certainly see a lot of the
property are the machines available
commercially yet for candidate or are
you silly nothing started load that
you're still learning how to produce
energy for for specifically candidates
one yes there's elbow I was publishing
they start about 20 concentrate and our
last machine expect officers
so we have a lot of storage section cool
thank you I once spent a little more
time on this because the technology that
I had Africa I'm not sure if all of you
that here so ticklish in you Corey
so so are you recommending the people
down why both of the closure some
extraction where I work is manufacture
closed loop
butane extraction so the reason we
decided to build our business around
others play hydrocarbon such as propane
it's simply more efficiency and
versatility in product being engraved
with like hydrocarbon extract and the
whole spectrum from old kettle oil
highly purified oils
vaporizer cartridges topical creams and
then you need to butane raw concentrates
as a shatter it's difficult to reverse
engineer concentrate your maths
independence so ptn offers great
versatility in terms of attempt rods you
can create our art women we focus on
producing old cannabis oil that can be
further refined to whichever particular
type of a product our customers are
making so versatility is really
important because we operate as
relatively low pressures especially
considered here - supercritical co2 raw
material cause of that component of the
extractor are much less so electronic
equipment cost is very attractive or
butane attractive and then cycle time is
very important how long it takes to
reduce our oil giving months
so you can extraction do to our bathroom
fast now there's a number of advantages
and Duquesne solvent well established in
our industry and concentrates are
produced via detain extract especially
because of its ability to preserve
curbing robot labor aromatic plant for
that reason you can extract one more
High Times Cannabis Cup rewards more
concentrate or
I mean have them talk and that's the
road there right because butane you know
you came down oil keeps the Turks on
point at a fantastic well you really
need to know who your processor is and
as they're getting rid of the residual
solvents it's amazing how many cups
you'll go to and and you know you see
the oil at like great color and the
judges will taste it or not saying what
are they do things but then the testing
comes back and they all blown their
numbers on residual solvents and you
know that that the extractor will lead
that it was great because they sent a
thousand dollars to enter and in all of
the samples as well but well they had
the extraction done they didn't know how
to clean up after well I'll play that
jumping regulated environments where
extraction dates or solvent extraction
is regulated the residual solvent amount
usually you can
you can parts per million is a tablished
regulated and before you're able to take
us all there is extract to the market
you have to have no passion that tested
so the actual amounts parts per million
vary state to state the pl become more
standardized over time
Plus in regulated markets
you can't release extracts or edibles or
any solvents team oils that were derived
in holidays crashed into the market that
don't meet those you know 50 to rational
so the candidate comes good you know
that there are a little relaxed in terms
of who can enter who consumed in
concentrated collapse so like types of
higher residual solvent and no type of
settings that an actual
that's our medical are on our
recreational yeah very true so the next
question is is going to go in a totally
different direction but considering
we're speaking to you know candidate
Oscar Newars who are looking to buy
extraction cliff equipment instead of
labs you've all worked in extraction
labs to some degree or another and had
assistance helping you along the way
look lighting so for those in the room
who be taking your advice to the bank
when they use it to build their
extraction companies what attributes
should they look for in extraction lab
staff there are a lot of mighty the
kinds of people that can be hired for
the lab what would you recommend to be
some attributes that business owners
look for in lab extractions staff and
we'll start off with usual
all right so staffing the medical you
want to bring in they're not expert
yourself in the chemistry behind systems
I I would definitely look for
experienced chemist or a biochemist who
is done in types of extractions maybe
not necessarily on cannabis but services
maybe in the flavor of pregnancy markets
or a lot of these folks will have
expertise in doing extractions handling
the equipment doing the chemistry that's
required and understanding how the
process can vary and those sorts of
things so that does become one
technical background your be person
should have at least I would say five
years more experience with the wine
recommendation and then the staff
support that person could be anywhere
from someone with an associate's degree
on up
but trainable they're going to have to
learn the chemistry of the process and
any systems do run out of air pressure
of some degree there's a little bit of
you know I know I don't like arthritis
aesthetically yet you want to make sure
that they understand the rules behind
the chemistry and biochemistry of
operating systems all that is certainly
one thing that we had our systems and
also you know identities were given
earlier you need to avoid this bottom
select extract within two to three hours
maybe the best person to operate our
machine is to the reservation condition
first novels one on the side the future
one of the earliest sources healing and
have so much consistency of attack they
don't need to even think about tap
temperature one hand the solid will
they have a low temperature of thousands
upon 20 weeks and days law nominating
that's you to change maybe some very
climate play you have broadly in your
life that machine and for high degree of
doctor and said that not I don't think
there's a high educational market leader
Colonel Muammar yet
wasn't even operate equipment including
a lot of distance are adding
semi-automated or automated building so
they don't think unless you're producing
a very highly formulated very refined
product that you need to have goats are
about chemist or amount of chemists have
a lot of consultants electing help you
going to establish your SOPs your
standard operating procedures review the
perfect extraction was your frog lab you
don't necessarily have to increase your
arrow I'm having degree workers
so emotionally well we have a little
controversy here I could really just I
disagree with that I'm an investor -
okay I want to be experienced person on
staff with one foot money in here so
that's another side the gentleman or
corrector in students are owned by
Harper you can use well so a lot of
these instruments by design are intended
begins of years and maybe even get away
with using an experienced person I would
feel more comfortable with an
experienced person you also have to be
mindful how your investors are going to
view it because that's another dynamic
it comes into this Jerrod tried to raise
to half a million dollars and to operate
some of these instruments your investors
what I see that items who have the
expertise or somebody on staff tub I
mean that's my perspective as an
investor I would want that could I exert
evoke that I work with regularly because
you know your your your train staff is
not necessarily there of the everyday
because you can job threat an active
learner and you'll be able to run your
Wow on every day it's on your worst day
that you need to add something strained
and I think that there's a lot things
like my things up with things so that is
wrong and they can they will happen if I
could mr. Wolman on developing override
very quickly you want to have an expert
around this callback reps we've got time
enough just for a couple questions
could I just wondered when you have an
investment in two buildings you call
lawns and talking to somebody
knowledgeable good point
true another question is something that
about eight years ago I sold the first
butane extractor to the industry bill
could you think about answering all the
guys that were doing the extraction
didn't have a lot of experience in the
market we have a lot of education what
they were looking for so full spectrum
extractions were kind of what they were
going at meal maybe oil checks they did
not a select now you're in a highly
selective industry where they're trying
to play and targeting
making an extractor that can be more
selective but the way that we're going
to go is the way it is going we're going
to start extracting everything from to
fight with these post operation
processes take one so I think you know
all right into place
go upscale large production you're not
going to be trying to make anything a
plan B they are seeing everything I want
and then after the fact cigarette you
want to slice out but right now you want
to contributing and then later you need
to build into you know something else
now linked to pregnant not state like
page one extractions is pulling out off
your your full cannabis oil it happens
really much a lot of close to the charts
but admit it total at other solvents to
make sure target all the people here in
the plant can do just one even ethanol
fuel Jews broad as they are they're not
highly flavor that one to prevail that's
true hidden in Basel that have stage 1
and stage 2 is ography or
rationalization and you really further
separating those compounds if you have a
product number spotters so you have time
for one more question we have one return
it spring on there you are you late
another go salsa signatory on and be
resource retired becoming puzzle but the
bigger issue where we do with all the
customers together either point point if
you have to separate them
- virtue like the Triton for three or
four and different Rios salt ever dishes
but they all have like people 24 2002
same point one within the television
very have you you have to be to it you
cannot you have some been everything and
George Brown you dozen are refillable
thank you with all the temples such
continues you have so we didn't waiting
of instruction offered we have to
maintain a proposal to people today who
have fought our way away regular said
consolable at adult but amusing after
like we work for 20 minutes feel and
then run ethanol so we tell you an old
ugly also and although like most of them
inside because you don't think you have
to do this isolation process if you have
but while you would solve have to Amman
tasks together you're wanted half
correct
great so before we wrap up I just want
to plug the next family starting here at
3 o'clock which is gonna be on working
together in marketing co-branding do min
so I encourage you to be here for that
let's take our panels for today dr.
Shelton Bravo dr. data