so Josh and Kelly I'm really glad that
you took a second to hang out with me
you know I gotta admit I can fanboy a
little bit because I have been following
your work for a while and through your
products is actually was the first I had
thought about amending with all-natural
ingredients back several years ago now
but because of that I've known the two
of you as as as living soil kind of
educators right and then you know they
all kind of come together a living soil
and permaculture and just general
healthy living right and you know now
that I have the opportunity to interview
people about probiotics and probiotic
growing of cannabis you know I see what
I think is a kind of a new rise and in
probiotics and living soil and KNF which
is taking off everybody wants to talk
about but I don't I don't have the depth
at YouTube you go back you know you know
decades or maybe more right and so I
wanted to get your perspective what are
you two seeing from you know traveling
to teach and your customer feedback and
and just what you also get from living I
think between Nelson and Canada and
Southern Oregon so you get you've got a
really good perspective so so what are
you seeing as far as like this what I'm
experiencing is this this is this
massive increase in probiotic cannabis
interest yeah we've been thinking of it
as in talking about it with some
colleagues and lady at Juliet skunk
magazine is really awesome we've been
talking about it as like a Green
Renaissance some people like to say the
green rush but it's like not a rush it's
it's a it's a renaissance because in a
way all these years we've been like my
silly ating underneath the earth and
just working on our web and our
connection
making it alright make sure we all have
the right food and in a way it's like a
fruiting of all of our knowledge right
now and so we're seeing an amazing
amount of farms making the transform the
transformation into natural farming and
also we're seeing the system come out
with a lot of stopping points for
pesticides and a lot of testing that's
kind of almost making you know synthetic
growing dangerous and not yummy might be
failing products and stuff so well I
also think that you know we're we're not
believing them this any more a big AG a
big farm of big corporations and we are
starting to question that and it is
giving not only educational flow to
people but it's also freeing them from
like these ideologies that we used to
have and I think that you know the the
growing that Josh and I have been
partaking in for 25 years is so in now
because it involves health and it
involves like breaking that myth of
being taught that only an NDK is the
only way that you can feed your plants
which is like touch such a joke as well
as you know a pharmacies are the only
way that you can treat your ailments so
it's been really fantastic seeing people
question and I think that you know once
you're given like a really big sort of
bad idea then it's making people
question and people are questioning it
and then they're using into their own
gardens and they're like oh my god this
is totally amazing so I think that it's
the right time and also I also think
sorry is that I think that um it's
leading by example to it's not meeting
it's not needing to force you know away
on someone or anything that's just
saying hey this is the way we're doing
it and it resonates and people you know
try the ganja they see the differences
the lab reports everything shows that
the natural systems are the better way
to go so the leading by example and then
the proof sort of coming out in the
pudding with the laboratories it kind of
solidifies it that this this is what's
to investing it must feel kind of pretty
miraculous to you guys for for do you
know you know 25 years ago right when
you started this and people were all
like you know NPK synthetics oh what do
you what kind of hippie stuff are you
guys talking about and now over the
course of time
think that instead of you trying to push
it on others people are coming and now
that you pushed it on yes but you being
there as a resource right instead of
that people are coming you it's like
please teach me right that must be kind
of astonishing it's really we're
incredibly humbled by it because you
know we never put ourselves out there to
be you know a leader or an educator it
just became it just became natural and
it was something that we felt like we
had to offer and it resonated with
people and we're seeing big changes on
the farm so yes it's it's amazing to see
the growth of it and for us it's the
light at the end of the tunnel there's
so much doom and gloom in the world
there's so many things that are just for
texting into a dark hole so I just want
to believe that there is hope there and
it's not just wanting to leave there is
hope and and this is the hope you know
and so it to have something positive to
grab on to that's where the true change
comes from inspiration equals change
forcing ideologies on someone it can
create opposition and that's nice
resistance yes and I think since we've
been doing it so long we know that it
works and so like Josh said you know
it's showing people are flowers or our
huge vegetables or you know taking soil
test samples
to see Wow we've got everything that we
need there in order to grow great crops
and yeah just so many years into it you
know we've had lots of failures we've
had lots of successes we've we've we
really tweaked our recipes and we've
come up with like a lot of our own
fermenting that works for us in our zone
and our area and what kind of plants can
we pull out and what Queen we use in
nature or what can we grow in our own
gardens to create that herbal biomass
that you know if your nutrient deficient
and a specific nutrient in your soil
then what is it that you can grow to
help bring you know that into your soils
and there's been a lot of trial and
error to get to where we are and and
that's where their groundbreaking part
comes right because you know a lot of
times when this information is not
available because you know when you all
started learning this the the internet
didn't make the information possible
right so you'd run into somebody over
the course of moving yourself around the
world and you're like oh my gosh this
person told me yeah and then you go and
you try it yourself or you know a few
seasons every which way and then now
you've got your own best patenting your
own best practices and that's a huge
deal it is and we have traveled the
world quite quite a lot in our
relationship we've been together for 25
year over 25 years now and we have a 21
year old child and we've travelled the
world the whole time we've done disaster
relief we've worked with women and
children and birth we've seen how
nutrition affects women and babies and
placenta as we've seen how nutrition
affects the food which makes them women
me
even they may be eating a lot but
they're malnourished so nutrition and
well-being has been a major part of our
life and so for having it all come
together and one kind of modality right
now is incredibly powerful we also know
that with you know compounds like
dicamba and the defoliating agents that
are out in the world right now we're
losing millions of acres every year to
contaminants we are charged up and
inspired like we would almost like give
up sleeping and eating if we had to just
to continue to put the message out there
that there is a different way we can
survive and thrive on this earth without
these degenerate systems something you
invest into it and to bring it back to
the cannabis industry it really fits
into what it is that we're doing because
there's so many people that have to
reduce their cost in order to stay in
this industry the big corporate guys
that are in the big takeovers and
they're doing a lot of NPK well they're
bringing down the price program so much
that our focus is now on small farmers
to be able to stay in the game and
reducing your impact on the earth
reducing your impact on how much you're
spending really comes from nature so how
can you make Stone Soup yeah you know it
really is it's a Stone Soup and we came
up with a lot of different recipes off
of nothing and Josh was talking about
you know going to different areas and
opening up clinics well we were having
to start clinics with nothing what is it
that we can take from the area and the
region and the zones that we're in to
create something amazing to create a
soup that can nourish every I'm now
taking a bit of a Moringa tree and just
putting it into hot water and having
them drink Moringa Tekin
changed their health and well-being you
know people it's amazing and you know
it's a passion so um one of the things
that inspired me of y'all is that you
are active educators right like you you
don't miss an opportunity to both both
share your successes and and how you got
there and and so you're speaking all
over the place and for a lot of us you
know we are learning about probiotic
gardening in all of its forms online
right you know you know either you know
websites or forums like the probiotic
farmers alliance on Facebook where
people are coming together to share
information and that's awesome right
because we can rapid prototype ideas
really fast when you've got when you've
got well like like pro bike farmers
lines 30,000 people right maybe maybe
that's a little bit too big but point
being a lot of people working together
can can hone down a question really
quickly and get to an answer it also in
these days when everybody's all stressed
out there's more people flaming each
other online and and it's it's difficult
to learn in some of these environments
now and and I'm continually trying to
support or you know encourage people to
keep teaching each other right because
when when when when the internet sites
are filled with arguments everybody just
wants to walk away right and and that
might be good sometimes to take a break
from a lot of the political stuff but
learning about how to take better care
of ourselves to grow better cannabis
plants to grow better food
we don't necessarily really want to take
a break from that so I just wanted to
hear your thoughts about you know the
kind of idea of like each one teach one
where where where where yourselves as
leaders thought leaders in the in the
probiotic and cannabis growing community
and me because I have you know access to
an audience what what are your thoughts
about what everybody should be doing to
continually make sure we're teaching
each other well I think it's really
interesting
first off what sparks me is that there's
a differentiation even in our language
between the word health and happiness
why is it that health and happiness are
two separate words and I really feel
like when we're gaining information or
we're gaining health through information
out there I think that it's incredibly
important that it also makes you happy
yeah that's true
you know it needs to make you feel good
so the information that we always put
out is something that's going to make
people feel good and it's also going to
give you health so if we didn't separate
those two words of health and happiness
and we really might not even be in this
predicament so I really encourage people
to continue to find education and about
health and well-being through what makes
you happy if you're seeing something on
the internet that's not making you happy
it's probably not healthy either so you
know really be drawn to whatever makes
you feel good and you know we we like to
draw wisdom from our elders so you know
we're just one cog and the whole wheel
and you know we have a lot to learn
still
and Bob Snodgrass you know as a part you
know close family member of ours and you
know his big teaching which i think is
amiss a beautiful thing to say is that
he really believes that there's a bell
curve to consciousness into
understanding of things and he you know
when he created the glass pipes with the
gold and the silver he created something
that was magical and instead of keeping
that secret to himself and making a
million dollars and not teaching anyone
at his algebra teacher taught him that
you know Humanity is learning at a
really slow rate and as soon as everyone
starts teaching each other
consciousness rises and it rises up and
we all grow and it's like the hundredth
monkey idea so we you know we've taken
that similar type of approach you know
we we are in the middle of our evolution
we're learning and growing as we as we
you know as we grow older and we think
that it's really powerful to be able to
share that message and to not create
divisive nasaan the internet I think is
really a really important thing you
don't have to put out something and
react to someone's answer if someone's
gonna come at you or whether they're a
troll or whether there's someone that
doesn't believe in you that's okay yeah
that's also known as conversation and if
you don't have the right words to come
out and prove that what you know you're
saying is right then hey challenge
yourself find the right the right words
but but don't don't take it as a
stifling thing let's let's move forward
let's all share our information because
that's what's getting us where we're
going and we're moving pretty fast right
now with our knowledge and also the
Buddhists say I just love this that
there's only two emotions and all
emotions are based under these two and
that's love and fear so if there's anger
that's coming out on the internet or
something that you feel angry within
yourself and there's some kind of a fear
that you really need to address to turn
that into love because love is the
happiness love is the health and love
that that's where we all need to and
so really encouraging people to go with
the love and let go of the fear and I'd
also like to say you know that's a big
reason why we created the pure
certification which is it was created
because there was no organic
certification and it seemed like there
was just product going onto the shelf
with no actual you know form of
accountability you know there was like
how do you prove that that's good
there's no system involved so we thought
you know well the USDA is in the end and
modern agriculture has never been
something to you know to learn from
because there's so many broken things in
there so you know we're gonna make
something that's different we're gonna
say this is all organic and it meets all
the USDA standards by getting toxicity
reports and soil tests and water tests
the farmer would do that on their own
why do they need to pay someone to tell
them what they're doing is right so
we've created a format where it's like a
in each one teach one type of a
situation where you know we put a format
out and it's it's a it's a community
monitored community supported
certification so we've said here's all
the things that we know this is why
closed loops matter because its health
its well-being you you know what's going
in your products you there's no
surprises afterwards and it's empowering
it's empowering to say oh look at that
tree it's filled with calcium or it has
trace minerals because it has really
deep roots you know part of our
traveling was going to Hawaii and
learning about natural farming and a
long time ago we're learning about
natural farming and we're living on the
land and we started looking at bio
dynamics and rudolf steiner like oh the
horns and the grounder almost like the
same as IMO's and well that's because
people that are connected to the earth
are getting the same type of information
and maybe a different forum a bit from
about modality of teaching so we never
said we're only KN effort we're only
natural farming or we're only
permaculture or were only bio dynamics
we're all of it we're humans you're
pro-life we're human beings we come from
the earth and we take out cigarette
butts when they're there and all the
thing with the peer certification that
josh didn't mention that i think is
really important is that there's
we have over 85 farms that are jumping
on this because they were already on
that path and maybe people now are
saying oh I want to do this and now I'm
really inspired through love through
held through happiness to better my
practices on my farm so there's so many
people that you know like us who have
been growing for you know three decades
that were like hey I fit right into this
I have already been doing that and then
it starts to create a higher
consciousness and then you've got the
egg your bell curve that Josh was
talking about and once you have more and
more people than it does shoot right up
because everybody is on the same
intention and our intention here is
healthy pure cannabis one of the things
that I like that you you both espouse is
this idea of sharing all the information
and that letting people choose for
themselves and one of the things that I
like is that y'all share everything
that's in your products right and we're
in this time where a lot of people are
trying to monetize yeah intellectual
property right I won't let you techno my
trade secret right or I have SOPs for
extraction but because our oil looks so
good I'm not going to tell you right and
like I'm I'm you know I don't own this
IPO and I'm alright so so what have you
learned from your own example of sharing
your inputs because a lot of people
would be afraid to write exactly what's
in the product on the bottle cuz they're
like oh someone's gonna copy me but I
know that you have shared your inputs
and dragonfly' earth medicine has
thrived so so what's been your
experience with essentially given a
given in a way and then still being able
to sell your product well people coming
back to us who have used our recipes and
given us flowers that blow me away is so
totally amazing and then they're just
really excited and they also say my
health is also improved my flowers and
my growing has improved and my health is
improved and I've gotten off all of
these different pharmaceuticals just
because I tried out your recipe because
they trusted it yes they knew what was
in there
now we've done different businesses
throughout the years and we never felt
like someone taking our idea was a
direct challenge to us we felt like
we're very innovative people we're very
charged up we're wanting to learn all
the time of all of a sudden someone all
of a sudden 10 companies come out with a
bunch of micronized errs and bacteria
awesome awesome
and everybody so we got people all over
the place that invented it yeah awesome
that's a that's a that's a point of it's
it's a compliment a compliment yeah and
so maybe we have to continue to
challenge ourself to come up with a new
innovative product one innovative
product may not be enough for the world
to make change so you know dragon fire
medicine is unique we recognize you know
that we're sharing everything and and
people haven't taken it at any and if
they do they maybe they'll just be an
impostor and that's trying to do the
same thing whatever it is it really
doesn't matter to us because just like
you know sharing everything if more and
more people are doing it it's just a
positive thing to there because born
well you have to be the only ones that
know everything we don't want to be that
person we're writing a book so we've
been reading a book for like three years
maybe more and more information more and
more like you know exciting ideas come
up so we'll be sharing that and
hopefully people will take it and run
with it and utilize it and maybe write a
book off of that and I think shared
information is how we can better our
humanity right well thank you both for
your leadership and a little bit of time
that you're able to give me today and
and and for anybody else who wants to
find their products here at dragonfly
Earth Medicine calm yes all right also
have de emperor farms calm which
highlights the pure certification what a
closed-loop system is and all the farms
that are implied
implementing these these actions right
now cool thank you