so so the reason why I wanted to come
over and talk to you today Patrick is
that I got turned on to your product
actually it's right here the happy
endings tea mix when I was visiting
Wonderland nursery just Southie here in
humble and it was Kevin chaudhary who
told me about it and and he had one of
your big you know 55-gallon drums or
whatever and and um and he was all
excited that I had just gotten delivered
and I'm all like alright well if if
Kevin Jodrey is a inspiration to me and
I and I you know I take his advices
being really high-quality and he's all
excited because he's got a new 55-gallon
drum of your product I'm all like what
the hell is this product right and so um
so I got a guy I got up in just a few
bags in there right and um and I I can
admit I don't have a lot of experience
with compost tea but I had some and then
and then I used yours and it did it did
two things that I had never really come
across before number one the stuff
phoned an amazing amount like two it was
a common out of mine my buckets and and
I'm gonna ask you about the foam in a
moment but my response was if if I think
I'm looking for a foam and this has got
a ton of foam maybe that's some kind of
benchmark of good right so I'm like
alright I like that but the real test
was when I started pouring it on my
plants I was feeding you know once to
you know once and a half one or two
times a week with it straight at 100%
but then I was also diluting it down to
like 30% and using it foliar and and it
took under a week for everybody to perk
back up the colors to darken and and you
know when when the plants that are
really good mood and sunshine the leaves
come up and they like look all praying
right everybody's everybody's praying or
saluting I like that too so so I you
know I was like what what is this stuff
right magic it's magic right and so so I
started so so so so then I started like
I kind of sort of
you down and we cross paths a couple
times and so now I'm to the point now
that I'm recommending this to people
awesome and and and I'm realizing that
it would be good for everybody if I
stopped by here at your lab and asked
you something the the general questions
that everybody asks me so that instead
of me trying to do it myself every time
I could just like sending them the link
right so so so the first couple
questions I have for you are gonna be
real basic stuff okay and then and then
I've got a couple that for the people
who already know about compost tea and
are interested in know more and then
we'll be done so okay so let's let's
start at the very basics you know a lot
of people especially the indoor scene
folks have been trained to use you know
bottled nutrients some of them
synthetics some of them high in salts
and and you know they all have different
roles but you know the natural the
organic the healthier compost folks all
of them come back to you know you can
dump almost all of that stuff and just
go with compost tea but honestly a lot
of people are like aren't I no compost
tea this is good I don't know why so so
what what is it about compost tea that
makes it so great for both your cannabis
plants and like also your food and
ornamental plants at home tall plants
it's it's actually an amazing thing that
there's a lot of research going on right
now but um basically what we're looking
at is in nature's way of feeding plants
is done through a biological system in
the soil between the roots and the soil
with they call it the mycorrhizae system
as a general term which involves the
roots bacteria fungus different
different little animals in the soil and
basically a compost tea is is your is
your making an incubator for those those
beneficial organisms that help feed your
plants so um a compost tea brewer is a
water air and and your initial starting
whatever you're starting with bacteria
there were either from worm castings or
powdered mycorrhizae that you can
that they've cultivated in farms
Kakashi's another good starting point
root balls from local healthy soils
another good starting point
but basically the idea of a compost tea
is your is your incubating the
beneficial bacteria and feeding them
back in your plants you know million
fold a billion fold so you're just
boosting that natural system up into
overdrive now one thing you have to be
weary of is that the tea brewer is an
incubator so you have to be careful of
what you know what you put in is going
to multiply under the right
circumstances so you want to stay away
from fresh guano's for e.coli because
then you can actually poison what
situation a biohazard and I've heard
tales of a few people getting sick over
it but basically you're gonna incubate
them but your product doesn't have any I
wanna know so I don't know if you're
gonna use gorals what you can if you
want a more of a fertilizer tea is I
suggest you Adam after the brewing
process so there's not a chance for the
multiplication to happen but that's
basically compost teas in a nutshell and
they are an amazing there are many ways
to brew them and they do benefit almost
every plan I've ever put them put on
them yeah citrus growers in Florida are
big on it so um it just boosts that
natural biology in the soil right on so
you're taking you're taking a like a
living soil environment where you would
normally have these healthy microbes and
by by brewing a compost tea and and
adding it you're creating this like like
biotic soil where where everything's so
much more thriving and do I understand
it correctly that that you know
generally speaking what's happening is
this did this microbe community that
you're feeding which is is is in the
rhizosphere right which is the area
around the roots it essentially makes a
buffet in the soil so whatever your
plant whether it be cannabis or whatever
all of the inputs that the plant wants
are there at its beck and call so it
doesn't have to struggle to get them
they're all there no that's a big
misconception is
we have to add phosphorus when it's
flowering but in nature if you think
about it a fruit tree doesn't go to
another area one that needs nitrogen or
it needs phosphorus yeah hey if it's
there it takes the one that needs it and
some of the research that's done is
there's a little receptors that actually
leave the root to look for what they
need so there'll be a receptor for
nitrogen or phosphate or potassium so so
yeah if if you build a real healthy soil
you know it takes things when they when
they need it the salt based nutrients
are charged particles and when you put
them in water so that's basically the
mechanism to go into the room nothing
will move in nature unless unless it's
being pushed or pulled and it's either
gravity pulling it down or plus and
minus charges
that's the nuts and so salts are really
a delicate thing because they're kind of
force-fed it's kind of like shoving an
IV into the root it has the root has no
control of any it's kind like force-feed
it actually moves a much life force
feeding so so there is a place for salts
in nature they're a good transport agent
but um it's kind of I look at it like a
meal you know we we eat things that used
to be alive every culture in the world
eats things that used to be alive
because it has all the elements of life
and things that used to be living but
adding a little bit of salt our spice is
really important for that meal to to
taste better and I look at a lot that
way in nature you know there's some good
natural salts to use I've never use a
synthetic salt but Epsom salt is one
natural salt it's real good magnesium
source so um yeah carbon based nutrients
are kind of the key and for a while yeah
the industry was real big on salts but
again they're tricky to use and they can
burn plants and you know and this is not
good at as good as organic you know a
Miracle Grow to tomatoes not as good as
a chicken corn or chicken food tomatoes
well I know that when I my parents
generation you know everybody was in
love with like chemistry and technology
and science was gonna solve everything
right and and and sometimes you go down
that path enough and you realize okay
actually if we come all the way back to
how nature does stuff itself we're
actually gonna get
better results and absolutely you know
where the salts originally came from
they were left over bomb-making material
from World War two oh and so the
nitrates are variant so they were trying
to figure out ways to use and it turns
out plants yeah it was like you know
putting plants on steroids but they also
point in the soil they poison the water
supply so there's a lot of downsides
that the salt chemicals a funny side
note I was actually once stopped at an
airport and my TSA because I had not
yours but somebody else's compost tea
packets that I had gotten in a
convention as samples and and as soon as
they read fertilizer they won't they ran
all the bomb tests on them and I'm like
I'm like really dude I'm just organic
you know like but that was funny so
ammonium nitrate is but is that one oh
well it triggered the supervisor agent
so um so yeah alright so a compost tea
brewer when I first learned about that
I'm like oh my god I need to get this so
I can some kind of piece of technology
to be able to brew this and it wasn't
until I actually watched some of your
videos online that I realized that a
compost tea brewer is not really like
some kind of sensational piece of
technology that's difficult it's
essentially oh and I also realized so
you need that you need to feed you know
oxygen into it and and I tried it with
just a simple aquarium bubbler which
doesn't have enough right you need a lot
of air so you need it you need a pretty
good size you know still only like 20
bucks but yeah you do you need a decent
size air pump and and and it's gonna be
bubbling into a 5-gallon bucket they can
get in any hardware store and and you
put in water um and then and then you
put in the product and then it just goes
so it sounds like it's a piece of gear
but it's it's not really through it yeah
it's basically you're setting up you
need a water supply you need a vessel
for the water and in the tea that you
put in and a good air a good air source
there's different methods of circulating
the water or air stones are real
simple and cheap you can get started for
you want a really good air pump as is as
much as you can afford you can't go too
big of air so I'm an air pump a good
clean air stone some clean water you
want to stay away the chlorine is is in
in municipal water to keep the
biologicals activity from happening so
the less chlorine the better and whether
you're on a well or you can dechlorinate
your water in different ways you can
also collect rainwater which is high oh
that that's a great place three modern
lake water will all brew some amazing
teas so the water is important the water
the air and the temperature are kind of
main variables that you're dealing with
and as far as the inputs are an infinite
of a variety of inputs but if you're
using good healthy organisms that break
down soil like what's naturally in a
compost what's naturally in the belly of
a worm so the worm castings have all
that natural or you know biological
activity so what we're going to do is
multiply those and that's the basic idea
of a tea and it just turns out it works
really well and yet you also have to
feed do we didn't talk a whole lot about
that you need in order for something to
live it needs food water a place to live
and an oxygen so that's what we're
providing the simplest form of food is a
sugar because that's what the simplest
form of food is and all all life loves
sugar so you can use molasses or or any
kind of good sugar you can also use
starches you know fish have a lot of
nutrients and sugar but it takes a
little longer to brew them because you
got to break down those starches into
simple sugars with your product that you
have to add molasses everything's in
there we have aa nice powder and
molasses source that's not real strong
it's like the bark there's someone's
kind of flaky but um turned out yeah it
feeds them really nicely and that's
honestly one of the things that I liked
about your product because you know I'm
busy doing everything else and sometimes
I'll read online that people have got
these complex recipes and all these
things I need to buy and really I need
this to be kind of like a set it and
forget it
things thing that's what I needed to
yeah right so I just take the
hey you know or whatnot the whole bag
but I scooped out what I need for my
five gallon bucket and I put in my air
and I'm done right it's not like I need
to make you know also go get the
molasses and all that kind of stuff so I
like the kind of one-stop shopping knob
of it it's a great starter it has
everything you need but again if you can
add some local biology like if you can
go out to a local soil that's healthy
and add some of those root masses into
that or your worm castings or compost
that's all beneficial you're all just
going to you're going to add it in
there's plenty inside this like all the
meals the fishbone of in the crab they
all covered in bacteria so it once you
put it in the water it activates and it
all starts breaking down so there's
plenty of bacteria in the tea mix but it
never hurts add some more that's local
one of my buddies who uses your stuff
and I was funny because I always thought
his plans were good but I didn't know he
uses you used your stuff until
afterwards he actually also takes um
just like grasses from this yard and
just Chuck's on in there and he started
doing that for just simple like fpj is
like like fermented plant juices and
he's like well I'll put it in my compost
tea too and and and and all of those
grasses are filled with our cupboard by
local yeah microbes you know that things
like a place to live um I have I have
diam acacia Cerf MIT which is a lot of
surface area molecule so that's a real
nice house form but you once some people
throw in hey just have them some surface
area that they can grab on to or so
they're not just floating around they're
like holding on and I think it's easier
for a lot of animals to have a place to
ground London I like that you said they
need a home I like that that makes a lot
of sense you know it's like this
universal yeah something to anchor on
Jim yeah all right so so now the part I
was really interested in the foam part
right cuz like I have I feel before I
became a little more dedicated to your
product I tried some some other stuff
and you know since I'm in the industry
people are constantly giving these stuff
to trial and I try everything because I
want to stay educated well some of the
stuff doesn't foam very much
right and you know yeah email their
customer service knowing you know it's
fine it's a good product but her but
then I used your stuff and it just like
it it really foam as well and I'm not an
you know if somebody's thinking about
using it you're like oh my gosh I don't
wanna make a mess it's not like it's
always it's not like it's like that kind
of a mess but if you've got a
five-gallon bucket
sometimes it'll foam up an inch but the
foam is thick and it so stands up and so
it's not making a mess but uh but
intuitively I want to think that some
alive stuff right because it's making
the phone and I don't know if that's
true or not so what makes the whole that
that's how I look you know we're we're
you're multiplying living organisms
living organisms produce co2 so once
they can only turn oxygen and sugar into
co2 so um to me the foam is an
indication of the biological activity in
the tea when you start off there's very
little and then will go through a growth
cycle and you have to kind of figure out
due to your temperature water conditions
how much minerals in your water chlorine
in your water how much air flow
determines the length of the brew time
and you can actually I think it's a
great indication of where you're at in
the tea cycle because you're going to
the population is going to increase and
explode and then it'll start eating
itself and the food's gone and the
poisons are in the we know the their
excrements are in the water so it
actually poisons them and then they will
die off so the level of foam increases
as how I look at it in created sio2 foam
is what it is at co2 bubbles so that's
coming from the living it and it will go
to a maximum and then die off it's
usually anywhere from two to five days
typically it's two days so if it's co2 I
would say that it's pretty fair to say
that it's in there their exhalation well
I mean it might be their excretion - but
one way or another it's their it's their
waste pot it's respiration and it is
right for animals breathe in oxygen and
mix it with water than in sugar and
you're buying me breathe out co2 that's
what we do so that's it that is a good
indication of the biological octave and
then not only that the smell I'm big on
sweet fresh
he smells and I like the tea one has a
little bit of ocean spill because I have
some fish in there but um sweet and
earthy and then once it will die off
that will sour a bit and yeah I'm not
big on using at that point I think some
people do but at that point I like just
to toss it in the compost pile so so
alright so so so I brew my tea you know
I've got I've made my little my bubbler
my five gallon and I and I put my dose
of powder in there and and it foams up
and I've reached my like like apex of
foam right so I know everything is the
most alive and and you know feel free to
tell me if I'm wrong but at that point
um I will you know take out the air and
and I will use it in one of two ways
either I will walk out to my garden and
I've got a you know I got a smaller
bucket and I'll just like to it
and a hundred percent and um I'll just
put like put a little bit in you know
whatever how much I can spread it out
right I'll put a dose if you will and in
everybody near near where the stem is
hitting the soil and then and then and
then I just generally believe that I
should finish it with a little bit of
fresh water so it gets down more towards
the roots now that how you doing
absolutely you can also you can dilute
it before you do that but it's a little
more work you know carrying it around
but hand watering is really nice there's
always gonna be a biofilm that you know
some people like to pump it with drip
lines because some of these they use it
on big farms and the irrigation lines
will get a biofilm inside and water
logging in right yeah yeah so so hand
watering is labor-intensive but it's
probably the best way and I use it
absolutely fresh because you can't
bottle a living you know it dies in a
bottle right they living things shelf
life would be like 72 hours it's not
that long no it's not even that I don't
know how long it is but some there are
some bottle teas but they think they
can't be as good as a real fresh right
out you want the maximum numbers so it's
like brew it and you
and in the in the viola the good thing
about the biological activity is for the
file the by organisms is they they're
not really given um PK or any nutrients
they're just facilitating the transfer
of a nutrients from the soil so there's
no real burning involved you can't you
can dilute it I'll you know some people
dilute it ten to one some people use it
pure you know as a test I like to
maximize you know push things that limit
so I've used pure key without any
dilution on every watering throughout a
cycle and it is fine I mean things are a
little bit too nitrogen II they're low a
little dark green but everything is very
healthy and well and for people whose
plants don't look robust and dark green
like it's better to be on that side then
the kind of emaciated and kind of
yellowing kind of things like the
compost tea just makes them you know
camouflage green like serious in what
you meant about foliar feeding that
that's another thing it's very there's a
lot of the good things going on there
but again everything in nature is
looking for somewhere to live and in
colonize so when you when you add
compost tea to the foyer what happens is
a lot of those microorganisms populate
the leaf and so when another mold comes
along or a mite or something that's
actually physically taken up they have
to have to move on so so having that
high biodiversity to your planet so you
can't see it but it does colonize on
your plant it's it's a nice that's a
nice nice natural way for protecting
your plant from a lot of other
microorganisms so you're filling that
vacuum exactly where like a spider mite
or a powdery mildew or a future boat
Rytas would would become an opportunist
and jump in there
you're like knitting in it we're already
gonna fill it with these healthy
microbes so there's already somebody
live in there exactly yeah so many years
an indoor you try to you know everything
so clean it's just a real nice place for
a predator to come in or something bad
and take over that's why indoor growers
can have real problems do there is no
biodiversity you know in the morning
biodiversity he'll have the better I
mean I'm real
so so i I've sprayed it fully or just a
handful of times I'm still experimenting
with it and um actually the first time I
did it I sprayed it at a hundred percent
and I came back the next day a little
freaked out because I thought I had
gotten some kind of purple powdery
mildew and it wasn't that at all it was
just as some of the droplets had dried
with the compost and so you know I just
sprayed everything off and learned from
it right but but but since you you do
use it all the time what percentage of
compost tea to fresh water do you
recommend for foliar you know that's
that's a good and spraying - if you have
a really fine mist there are some of
those little animals are getting kind of
big so when those when you get put in
those little micro bursts it actually
shouldn't can shred them up and kill
himself you definitely don't want to
have it on a high mess when you're doing
it I actually like to UM like when
they're small I dip them completely
upside down until a fresh batch of teeth
that you dipped up you do there's a plan
to get the entire thing like a flea dip
or something but just cut completely
coat the plant and then yeah just and
also the tea can have some residue in it
so you know you want to be even might
want to strain it if you're going to
spray it but yeah there's form a scale
based prayers are fine they just don't
have it a real fine mist and your baby
should be okay it's okay just do it
before it's flowering there's probably
good ideas so you know we've already
kind of established that you can't
really do it too much right like if
anything your plant might become like
you know very dark green and in many
cases that's that's better than the
opposite side but if somebody wanted to
do in an optimized amount where they are
they're benefiting the plant as much as
they can but they're also not overdoing
it because they you know a lot of
especially patients right they're on
budgets and they want to be able to use
it but not too much so what would you
recommend as a as a good regular feeding
regime typically what I do is I always
like when I transplant like to water and
tea to just to set that biological
activity upfront I'm a little lazy so I
don't bruise
often I might hit them three times four
times and you can actually water the day
before you harvest it's not you know
this it's fine
but um you can use it to the very end
into the very beginning clones all the
way to to the very end you know last
days of flowering
I usually hit them two or three times
but I always like to hit them at first
you know once they're transplanted just
to set up that buy a lot extra
biological activity and then you know
and another thing I think is kind of
important for psychoactive plants I
think there needs to be a little bit of
stress involved you know look don't over
water your plants I guess is be they let
it if you're going to err err on the
side will let them droop a tiny bit
instead of over water and you keep the
roots wet so because your roots are real
important to keep healthy that that's
that's the beginning that's you know
that's the main or that everything gets
absorbed so you want a lot of surface
area in your reach that's that's one
thing about the tea I have something I
have to say have some biological I can't
we just strip the roots of that old
brown scale so you should have nice
light fluffy roots so that was kind of
engineered into the tea which I think
kind of makes it a little bit makes it
work really well is the number of
ingredients I used to make healthy roots
because that's what that's where it
starts so don't over water the plant so
but yeah two or three waterings of fresh
water and a tea water you should be fine
so so to kind of unpack that a little
bit you're suggesting that at the
beginning at transplant maybe hit it you
know you know two or three times in a
row because you're building up the
community but after that like maybe
every third or fourth I said it was just
the first watering that when I trance so
you don't use it throughout the whole
cycle no well I do but I do use it maybe
once when I first walked and then I
might do three weeks old break our water
and then hit him with tea again when
they when they transition from
vegetation of flower it's a good time to
hit them because they need they need a
bunch of nutrients at that's all so are
you suggesting that that once hmm
so it's starting to think I'm trying to
think about it more like an inoculant at
this absolutely asleep it's an amazing
enough so I'm putting it in and I don't
necessarily have to do it again every
week because they're they're they live
as long as you have a nice healthy soil
and another another issue if you've used
salts in your cell before like another
one of those bug boosters called
monopotassium phosphate it's in all the
big numbers yeah for bloom boosters that
actually can just damage your soil and
keep things from living and actually
lock out sort of nutrients so if you
have a good living soil starting off
with yeah I did yeah you don't have to
keep the sole the plant feeds itself
from the soil you just want a real
healthy soil and that's what ocean belly
does it makes it a real wide spectrum of
them super so right on
alright so I've got I got one more
questions before we talk about how folks
can get it right so so you know I talk
to a lot of folks especially when I met
conventions right and they're all like
you know we're doing 50 acres you know
and as soon as they say 50 acres I'm
thinking of mids right but but a lot of
these a lot of these growers you know
who are even working big a lot of these
folks want to do you know healthy
probiotic at scale and you know a lot of
people who are small batch compost tea
living soil you know maybe even Korean
natural farming nerds like like I am
they get to a point where they're like
alright well that's that's fine for a
home grower or a patient grow but but
but we're gonna do a couple acres or
more you already mentioned once that
yeah you probably don't want to put the
compost down your water line because
there's residue and they're gonna be
aware of that first so so maybe just put
water down your lines but do you have
any recommendations for people who want
to scale it up to use it at size well
yeah absolutely owns one of my job is
that I inspect farms for our program so
I do see a lot of big scale farms and
humbled in Southern Oregon and what you
bake it with us on these farms are dry
ingredients and big tea Brewers if
they're they're you know 250 gallon
pallet kind of square ones is kind of a
minimum up to they'll group you know
three four thousand gallon tanks but
they're almost in every form I see now
because they are so beneficial and it's
they're so cost effect
you know as far as a natural fertilizer
you can add you absolutely can add in
nutrients you know to feed your plants
also so it's actually one of the most
cost-effective ways but it's done all
the time and they're they're just big
reservoirs that they brew it up in and
um you know for most of the commercial
growers the things that they're looking
for are helpful plant right because hey
you just need that but also it helps
resist pests so that's good and and they
want good yields right and this
absolutely both you know compost even
boots the yields and then and then of
course everybody needs you know bag
appeal right and what I have found and
granted I'm still pretty new with the
compost tea thing but um my coloration
seems to go up the the amount and
variety of the colors in in the hares go
up I like to think that there's more
trichomes I don't know if that's true
yet but it seems to boost all the
categories that you want if your end
goal is to sell right so there's some
there's some project bugs we use at home
when it's just for our just for our head
right but but but people who need to
make their margins they need to worry
about these other categories and I think
it does all of that - yeah that cost
effective is real important on big scale
farms you know they're they're not using
body nutrients it's ridiculous to ship
water yeah so you add your own water
on-site news you say substantial amount
of money so um what was the question
again I think you I think your email
that that yes it does increase your
yields your mag appeal and maximize the
potential genetics it just don't know
wonder love that thank you vet it
maximizes the potential of the genetics
I'm gonna use that I think you know it's
built in the genetics but you're letting
it express itself silly and you do
usually get a lot more terpenes and
things usually
like tomatoes you know when you grow an
organic or aerosol base for like they're
better they taste better it's hard to
quantify but it's a-you know when you're
using a market knows it yeah the market
absolutely knows and people are becoming
more and more aware especially the
pesticides and that you know you you
have to find other methods and for years
it was kind of in you know a nasty part
of our business and but the consumers
are important in their more demanding as
they should be so the depth that
definitely the direction I see in the
industry is definitely going organic in
high quality and that's that's what it
just cost effective end it's a better
product there's no doubt about that I'm
actually really excited about my tomato
plants this year cuz you know I grow a
girl few every year because you know
even though you buy tomato plants at the
store it's still nice to have some at
home right
and so my tomato plants are near my
personal patient plants right so just a
few of them and and so you know I give
some of my cannabis plants which is why
I originally got into it but then like
I'm given some love with the tomato
plants as well so I'm looking forward to
that experiment no worse community
gardens I donate a lot and they get
amazing amazing results in vegetable
gardens yeah compost teas help all
plants you know grab you know I think
they using the long golf courses and you
know it's just really it bringing in
brings out it makes you your plants
healthy and inoculate it's a grand
inoculate against against um it's just
biodiversity
it's basically what you're doing yeah
you're you're you're you're you're
you're supporting nature to do nature
like maybe a bionic way that's a real
interesting area if there was just the
tip of the iceberg what we're finding
out there's tons of information readily
available on brewing compost teas it's
not difficult like you said it seems a
little daunting but basically an air
source of vessel and some clean water
and start go from there right on so so
so I get my my tea when I come down here
to well south of Istanbul when I go down
to visit farms and stuff I just get it
locally down there but you know I live
up in Washington and there's people
watching the video who live all over the
place where can people score
this stuff the happy that the Happy
Endings team vixx like like is it is
easy to buy yeah so actually we just got
on Amazon oh alright what are you going
Amazon's like you reversal Jun orig free
shipping so I throw that in there so me
I go on Amazon and um we'll get it or
you can ask your local store and I would
love to be on store shelves that's
always great but yeah go on Amazon it's
Universal so on Amazon you want a Google
Happy Endings team agree but people
which would probably I spelled a
different GRE a.m. Oh so catch that it's
green bicycles as the company but it's
gr e a and a brilliant marketing move on
yeah making it harder for people upon
yeah totally know but anyways yeah if
you search on my Amazon you'll get it
into act it turns out there are people
from Maine to Hawaii that are actually
finding out about this through
word-of-mouth alpha I imagine but now
things are going real well um we want to
sell a lot of it and we're just starting
to and really glad to come down to my
laboratory so we can talk about my
product and thank you yeah right on and
so if you wanna make it really easy you
could look in the comments and in the
first comment there's gonna be a link to
it on Amazon which makes everything easy
but hey thanks for having me over right
throat my website oh what's your website
yeah green bicycles calm and also let's
plug your YouTube channel to this thing
that's beautiful that's like well did
you ever see my on the first hi times
Cup in America no I didn't know that and
they were using your product that was me
oh that was you personally I know it's
mom right on that bad boy awesome well
cool thanks for having me in your lab
take Mary Jane awesome thank you