we welcome Doug Jacobs Doug is technical
adviser for canvas customers and grow
dam he has been growing canvas since he
was 13 and has been consulting
professionally for commercial
horticulture since he's been in college
he has depth in both cannabis as well as
ornamental and other commercial growing
operations today who will be speaking
about technology assisted crop
optimization and irrigation please put
together what are the important things
you need to measure as growers what is
plant steering and how to create an
irrigation strategy so first things
first what is precision growing simply
put precision growing is growing more
with less less water or less nutrients
less labor with the grow of increasing
yield potency labor while reducing the
use of labor water and nutrients and
increasing your profitability but also
becoming more sustainable as growers
reducing the amount of runoff we put
into the environment and reducing the
amount of natural resources we consume
precision growing is an integrated
approach that takes into account the
genetic that you're growing the climate
that you have in root zone management
and root zone management is basically
influencing the root zone of the crop in
order to steer it in a certain direction
to optimize growth so has growers what
can we control we controller to camp the
environment the temperature leaf
temperature humidity co2 light intensity
in the root zone we can select substrate
and that substrate determines the
availability in nutrients the air to
water ratio the electrical connectivity
so what nutrients we apply how quality
of them and how there are available to
the plant so first things first what do
we need to measure as growers in order
to optimize growth so obviously climate
climate conditions are important but
it's not just the minimum or maximum of
the day it's the actual trends so seeing
how the climate reacts to lights coming
on the plants up taking and transpiring
and so it's important to select the
system that allows you to see these
trends over the course of the day so you
can avoid any spikes that happen when
they're transitioning from night to day
or date tonight within the root zone
it's important to know the amount of
runoff your substrate is is putting off
but also what was the water content the
EC and the temperature of your root zone
crop registration so crop registration
is probably the most underutilized tool
in cannabis measuring plant height is a
really important measure is my plant
developing on time am i creating the
right structure is there something
preventing it from growing the same way
it was growing the last time looking at
leaf color you know allows you to see is
my plant imbalance is it getting enough
nutrition is there disease affecting it
a stem color again it tells you is the
plant in stress is it supposed to be
purple or you know is it under stress is
there bug attacking it is there disease
stem diameter stem diameter can be used
to track the rate of growth of the plant
and again if you can compare it to
previous crops you can catch a problem
before it really affects the whole crop
flower development you know measuring
diameter flower initiation when it first
puts flowers out how those flowers
develop over the site
I can really tell you well am i doing
something wrong has there been a problem
so it really really is helpful so so
plants during 101 so so once you're able
to control your climate and irrigation
you have baseline measurements to
compare from previous crops you can
start using irrigation and climate as a
tool to steer plant growth in a desired
direction that you want so vegetative
growth and vegetative growth is focusing
on growing leaves and stems the plans
tend to be more vigorous vegetative
steering can be used at any stage of
growth not just in the early stages but
within the flower farms to age in order
to prevent the crop from finishing to
fast and then generous exterior so
generally steering is focusing on
flowering
sends the signal to the plant that it
needs to reproduce foots all of its
energy into the flowers can be used to
make small compact plants it can be used
to slow down the growth of mothers if
you don't want them to stretch and grow
too quickly steering can be used to
increase the yield potency back appeal
by decreasing inner normal spacing so so
so obviously switching the lights to
twelve twelve initiates flower but you
can also steer the crop through through
climate
so having overall higher temperatures is
more vegetative while having overall
lower temperatures is more generative
sort of mimicking the natural natural
seasonal changes the plant would
experience in its environment difference
differences between day and night time
temperature having smaller decreases
between night and day temperature tends
to be more vegetative while having very
large and increasing differences between
night and day tends to be more
generative changes in temperature so
having very gradual changes in
I'm sure between night and day tends to
be more vegetative while having great
fast and quick changes is more general
it's a lot of stress on the plant
humidity so having slides wrong but
having a higher humidity in bed and to
make the plant more active while having
a lower humidity in flower makes it more
generative air exchanges of pipe
temperature this is more for for
greenhouses but you tend to have less
air exchanges in fetch they're trying to
have higher temperatures you're trying
to increase co2 where is an in
generative you're probably trying to
drop humidity so you might have more air
exchanges pipe temperature that's more
for greenhouse that you'd have a higher
temperature more heat to keep the family
or vegetative and then reducing that to
be more generative so it's life Erika
plants doing with irrigation so having
increasing or overall higher water
content tends to be more more vegetative
so this is manipulating the water
content within the root zone decreasing
water content and lower corner lower
water content overall is more generative
you're sort of tying the plant we're
taking away resources put your energy
into growing flowers
dodj it's dry here so water content
decreases overnight and manipulating
when do you start and stop irrigation so
having smaller decreases overnight or
irrigating earlier in the day and
irrigating up to the end of the day is
more vegetative they're applying more
water to their plant vigor dryvax
overnight or starting an irrigation
later and endings earlier is more
generative you're taking away of
resources from the plant you're drying
back harder you're stressing it out so
you're making it more generative
irrigation frequency so high frequency
of irrigation think of an aeroponic
system the more time I can apply
irrigations the faster I can get that
plant to grow where conversely once I
start taking away
and make it less frequent I'm sending
the signal complaint hey you have less
resources put your energy into
reproducing it's more generative ECS of
substrate e CS and dripper pcs tend to
be lower in veg and hired flour you're
providing the food that the plant needs
to grow and produce flowers and resin
substrate temperatures having higher
substrate temperatures again are making
the plant more active of taking more
water and in generative stage you're
probably trying to to slow that plant
down decreasing the substrate
temperature so once you know this we can
start creating an irrigation strategy
designed around what you're trying to
accomplish at what stage of growth but
the first thing you have to do before
you know creating an irrigation strategy
you have to collect select the substrate
and understand how that substrate
performs the density of the substrate
will affect the water holding capacity
drive ax feed how easy is refreshed and
held in the substrate fiber orientation
of particle size will influence the
irrigation capacity of the growing media
vertical fibers tend to be more free
draining more vegetative horizontal
fibers tend to hold more water and are
more generative the amount of substrate
you have also plays a role in how you
irrigate so having a small small tiny
volume of substrate requires you to
irrigate more often while having a
larger volume of substrate or it allows
you to irrigate less frequently and so
you'll typically see in commercial
greenhouses where growers are using a
small volume of substrate to fetch the
plant out to get it very vegetative to
grow very fast then they stick it on
another substrate volume that's much
larger so allows you to take away
irrigations and be more generative so
the initial wet up sets the stage with a
whole grow cycle and it will carry all
the way through the entire life of the
plant at scale of wetting limes and
watering blooms can save a lot of labour
and reduce water consumption and they're
actually much more affordable
you think but even just watering lawn
with a coarse spray is just a just as
effective and this be more likely to be
used but all methods require that you
make three slow passes to fully wet up
that substrate and done with some larger
substrate volumes you have to do more
than three times it key to just a
nutrient solution is required from the
spark from the start especially with
rock wall because rock wall has no
nutrient in em so we recommend that you
condition your rock wall in a 1 to 5 EC
just for clanks and going up from there
using a no using no nutrient or a low
strength solution at at the start wall
great week and stop plants and you know
carry all the way through the growth
cycle so after you do the initial wet up
it's important to check the weights of
your substrate to ensure that they're
fully saturated tray weights should be
recorded after initial saturation and
after cuttings are placed regular
measurements should be taken of those
trays to determine when to apply the
first irrigations same goes for block
weights after you went up that block you
need to test a couple of those blocks to
ensure that they're all been wet up
correctly and they're all the same you
probably want to check to see between
batches if they're all wetting up the
same because if you have one batch that
all it's less water or more water it's
gonna change the way you irrigate the
first time depending on environment and
genetic you should wait until the tray
or the block reaches about 30 to 50
percent less the initial wait before
applying the first irrigation so hand
watering and dipping in trays is not a
precise way to apply variation cannabis
industry could really benefit from
adopting commercial systems for growing
plants Evan flow systems are the most
commonly used at scale but nmt systems
can also be used to really
control the application of water after
you know initial cuttings are placed or
that these reduced labor and also allow
the crop to be more consistent in
uniform because if you're hand watering
you know one block may get more water
than the other and then one block will
dry out faster than the other and you'll
notice in your canopy you know there's
that one plant that just fell behind the
rest of them so before talking about
irrigation strategy for veg and flower
we're going to suss rooting in so
picture here is an example the first two
dry backs for young tomatoes and blocks
over a five day period the blocks drive
back slowly from a very high water
content down to about twenty percent
this is not typical the big big
drawbacks like printer like this proof
of good rooting in but but also could be
very generative they slow the plant
growth down notice that you don't apply
water to that plant over the course of a
week it's just gonna sit there and not
grow so it's recommended depending on
the substrate and the genetic to apply
more frequent irrigations in the
beginning before allowing the substrate
to dry back and if you don't have a
water content sensor you can't be
measure it with a sensor itself you can
measure the weight of the block to
determine the first time you irrigate
this graph here is the ideal irrigation
tract don't focus on the the frequency
it doesn't matter it changes depending
on your substrate so ideal irrigation is
broken up into three phases the first
phase builds up wider water content
dilutes the nutrient solution in the
substrate and it's providing new
solutions for the plant to uptake the
goal is to gradually build up water
content to achieve drain on time without
channeling without pushing out the water
straight through and into draining and
p-two the timing a first drain is
important because it keeps the EC in the
substrate under control well the plant
is working its hardest achieving drain
too early will will not only create
channels but would not allow for proper
reefs a chwarae ssin of the substrate it
will not be wet correctly getting
drained too late
spikes the EC when the plants working
its hardest causing unnecessary trip
stress that affects the plant growth in
p3 we stopped irrigation several hours
before sunset
lights off starting to dry back before
the end of day adjusting this drive act
can play a significant role not only in
root development but how you're steering
the crop so general principles to
consider on creating an irrigation
strategy first the golden rule the
golden rule is transpiration before the
year before irrigation you want the
plant to actively start up taking water
before you apply that irrigation
typically if you have a sensor you're
looking for a one and a half to two
percent dry back before that your first
irrigation in pute and p1 typically
larger volumes are used in the morning
to build up water content and achieved
rain on time ideally a 1% dry back or at
least a 30 minute rest time is needed
between irrigations in order to prevent
channeling in p2 smaller volumes are
used to to maintain the the ideal water
content in DC typically you want to
achieve
one to two percent drive act between
each irrigation but for some varieties
that don't like wet feet you can do a
three to four percent dry back between
each irrigation event and it hasn't been
studied well but some growers do like to
achieve much bigger drive acts within
the day in order to be more generative
but it's not recommended to do this
early on because they will make it much
harder for you to read what your your
growing media and mp3 stop time has a
significant effect on route development
and crop steering and should be adjusted
carefully throughout the cycle the goal
is steering the crop or steadily
increasing drive acts towards the end of
cycle to be incredibly genitive at the
end typically you're achieving 10 to 15
percent drive acts overnight and veg and
ugly flower but in late flower you can
achieve 20 to 30 percent drive acts
overnight to to increase that jeté of
steering and the most important thing is
volume of water applied is directly
related to the amount of substrate
you're feeding so here's an example of
substrate volumes and their irrigation
shot sizes so the volume of substrate
determines how much water you're
applying this is true for all types of
growing media 3% shot sizes are more
vegetative so basically you're taking
the volume of substrate you have so you
have a liter of substrate I'm gonna
apply a 30 mil shot every time if I want
to be more generative I'll apply a 6%
shot or something larger than that you
can adjust these shot sizes but
generally you should stay between three
to six percent shot size range in order
to prevent channeling or under feeding
of the substrate start times start and
stop times in relation to dry back
adjusting the start and stop times
controls the dry back overnight plays a
significant role in how its developed
the numbers here at reference so it's
important to know that you don't want to
just jump from one of these to the other
and you want to make very small
adjustments over several days in order
to work
into the steering that you're trying to
do and at the end of cycle you you want
to achieve these bigger drawbacks
towards the end so in addition to in
addition to irrigation strategy playing
a role in crop steering it controls the
EC in the root zone so you can actually
play with water content EC by jesting
the amount of water applied and its
frequency so short water events prevent
drain rates water content and raise ez c
it's more vegetative long water events
creates more drain and lowers water
content and lowers EC a high frequency
of watering increases the amount of
water and lowers EC raises water content
is more vegetative less frequent
waterings decreases the amount of water
it raises the EC in the root zone and
lowers water content it's more
generative so measuring drain it isn't
critically important to measure how much
water is applied for how much drain is
achieved on a daily basis this is a
measure of how much water the plant is
using a check on plant health and
ensures irrigation systems are working
correctly it helps to ensure that you're
not only over watering or under watering
ideally this should be used as a
measurement every day to create your
next day's irrigation strategy it's also
important to know when you achieve the
first drain of the day this will help
you prevent channeling in the root zone
depending on substrate type you want to
want to achieve drain one to three hours
after that first irrigation achieving
drain to really causes channeling and
makes it much harder to rewetting media
drain percent adverse expected radiation
for vegetables so the amount of drain
needed depends on climate conditions and
how the plants are performing under low
light conditions and wild climate
conditions less drain is required
because the plants are not taking up as
much water under high light
density and really hot humid
environments require higher volumes of
drain in order to maintain stable water
content in EC in the root zone but it
also makes sure's to even out any
inconsistencies in the plant so it's
like if you have one plant that's higher
or lower and water content that cheating
drain should allow you to even those out
using the precision drain volumes listed
here it's not only good for plant growth
but for your bottom line reducing the
amount of nutrient of water that you're
sending it down the drain and it's
better for the environment drain EC is
not representative of what's in the
substrate do not use drain EC or pH as a
primary indicator for adjusting EC and
pH concentrations at the dripper hi are
you seeing the drain is normal as the
drain contains the old nutrients that
were held in the substrate pH of the of
the drain is influenced by the plant's
interaction with the nutrient solution
and can be used as a indicator of how
the plants performing but it shouldn't
be your deciding factor on how you feed
that plant really you need to correlate
what's going on in the drain and the
root zone and what how the plant is
actually performing substrate EC in
relation to that into radiation and for
vegetables substrate EC needs to be
adjusted based on light and climate as
well substrate EC can be significantly
higher than we think
so you can see vegetables under low
light conditions for tomatoes you can
have an EC as high as 8 in the root zone
it's not uncommon to see to the 3 ec s
and veg in getting up to 5 6 plus EC and
flower as we discussed discussed
previously substrate EC can be
controlled by manipulating the frequency
and volume of the irrigation in general
EC of the dripper should never be
changed more than 0.5 EC per day and you
should never apply just plain water in
the middle of a cycle so now that you
have all this information you can make
your own schedule
II see water content climate set points
throughout the growth cycle having these
clear set points can be used with proper
registration and historical data to
ensure that the promise is developing
consistently can help your staff catch
problems before they spread and the
historical data can allow you to have a
baseline so when you start conduct
conducting texts with different
substrates with different nutrients with
different growing techniques you can
compare how they they affect that crop
or that genetic so in summary precision
growing is a continuously develop is
important for continuously developing
high quality plants yield and cost
management plants can be steered by
climate irrigation and labor plants
responds to irrigation strategies are
the same regardless of substrate and the
more relevant information you have as a
grower the more data you have that you
can use to compare to the better off
you're gonna be
and that's my presentation yes sir
I mean it depends on on what growing
media you use I mean some substrates you
require you haven't have run off but
that's something that grow tin is
focusing on is zero discharged
agriculture so it's possible and you
just have to pick the right substrate
that allows you to do it okay
if what if you're using like super seems
like rock wool type of environment what
if you use another super soil and you're
using a compost teas and really organic
do you need to measure that EC content
coming out and do I need to water it to
the point where it's actually draining
every day if it's it's completely
organic you don't need to achieve drain
every day I mean the problem with using
organic nutrient solutions in a drip
irrigation system is that you can't use
pressure compensation because that's not
true it's very hard to use pressure
compensated systems because you have to
flush the lines almost every time
between each irrigation so assuming you
don't have that problem you can't use
organics it does work for soil the same
way as it worked for rock wall
the difference being you will have to
achieve probably more drain at certain
stages than you would with other
substrates more questions
don't she's not allowed to ask questions
does she know you're Silver's what a low
rate do you recommend irrigating Wroclaw
and why Oh
so for rockwool my typical typically
recommend a low flow rate so 1/2 gallon
per hour or less in order to prevent
channeling because Rockville is more
porous so if you throw a lot of water
really quickly you will create channels
in the growing media you won't be wet it
correctly questions you know you're just
a little bit of barest you can do it
there you go thank you
so you asked if I already suggested
doing measurements on a daily basis you
know kind of in the morning in the
afternoon to assess your cycles is there
any value in increasing the frequency of
those measurements during the day yeah
so I mean it's um the one would be like
when do you cheat drain and how much it
drain maybe you've achieved at a certain
point of the day but it's hard enough to
get somebody to measure their drain and
the amount of water applied on a daily
basis I'd usually start there but I
think another point would be when do you
achieve that dream so that's the tipping
point you're looking for yeah thank you
we've got time for one more question if
you've got it all right that looks like
it thank you very much
[Music]