so John thank you so much for taking
some time out of your busy schedule this
morning that chat with me
I had a great tour yesterday here at 7
acres and meeting your staff who were
like all surprisingly joyful and super
knowledgeable so it was it was both fun
to see what real seriously scaled
cannabis was is look you know turning
out to be but also to see you know a
staff that's really joyful in producing
the cannabis plant in a very structured
and analytical environment right so what
I wanted to talk to you about though
today you know as as you know part of
the you know the company's visionary
team right you helped influence the
direction of the company and one of the
reasons why I wanted to come here and
meet you in person
it's because I've watched some of your
videos of your public speaking gigs and
you are a hardcore whole plant guy like
I am right and and and to hear the words
coming out of your mouth about the
importance of sticking with whole plant
not only warms my heart but I gotta say
it's becoming increasingly rare in
scaled cannabis companies because as as
people scale up manufacturing and whole
plant are kind of two ends of a scale
and so you get people starting to cut
corners and use isolates or take apart
the plant and then put it back together
in the extraction and that you know it's
not what the plants about for me so I
wanted to ask you to kind of share with
all of us what your vision is for how do
you scale a company large enough that
you are able to provide flower for you
know soon an entire country and yet
still hold to your whole plant ideals so
it's been a challenge absolutely
for me it started by giving the team
here so there's six hundred and fifty
people behind us a very
vision to really grow great it's gonna
grow great catalyst to really give the
plant the same attention and love we
would give it if we're growing four
plants at home or a couple of lights you
know in the old world and when we gave
that vision and then started hiring
really smart people they never wavered
from that North Star of to put it very
plainly great cannabis and how that
aligns with what we're doing is we think
whole plant or I think whole plant is
you know historically a better medicine
you know I'm not a doctor but you know
I've seen enough anecdotally over 15
years to see the effect than the on
throwing effect in order to walk from
your podcast as well
you know I think that's also there's
more safety involved so I like to say we
have a 10,000 year informal safety study
on on flower and called simple extract
use where we've shown it's relatively
safe for people and you know some of
your guesses at exceptionally safe for
people but from a business perspective
when I put that out on when you do hard
things well that's where you build a
defense around your business so it might
take you longer to get going it might
cost you a bit more investment but what
you have at the end is more valuable
business so our view is if we can make
great flower we can have a great
business selling flower to Canadians
which we think you know flower and
pre-rolls
you know it's going to be a half or so
of the market but more importantly that
becomes the key ingredient when we get
into derivative products and we start to
look at making whole plant oils or
tinctures whole plant dates and
eventually using whole plant products
for you know other topicals and things
like that that's what's going to
differentiate us and because you put the
work in here to create the ingredients
that's what gives us an advantage of the
business right on so I I've seen some of
your videos from idea City where you wax
poetic about the importance of whole
plant right it's beautiful right it's
like it's like good song and I'm like oh
speaking made-up and I want to get a
little bit of that now cuz I bet you you
know you involved you were involved with
a whole bunch of like seriously deep
pocket investment class
people and those are generally the folks
who are pushing people in your position
to cheapen up right and move away from
whole plant because it's cheaper or
easier or more efficient or whatever
right and and you have to constantly
push back to that and a lot of these
folks these investment folks they do not
they don't have a cannabis background
right so whole plan or not it's widgets
to a lot some of these folks right so so
how do you explain to these folks
why whole plant is important to be
preserved at scale and it makes smart
money absolutely so you know this
company we've raised almost a quarter
billion dollars of capital for the
business so I have to always make sure I
remind myself you know investors are not
here to fund my hopes and dreams now
they're here to make a good business but
if I can align those two that's where I
get the most satisfaction and when I've
been really proud of our team being able
to do that for the past five years what
it came down to with education about why
this might be harder it might take us
longer but it's going to give us a
better more defensible business over
time and let me give you an example
let's say two companies want to put the
market you know a cannabinoid edible
let's say for a CBD dominant wellness
edible whether it's a gummy or the
format doesn't matter for now if we go
and we breed a very specific plant for
it grow it in a very specific way
process extract and manufacture in a
specific way so we have a whole plant
product and I love
ethan were so set on your podcast about
go back to the genetics and breed what
you want don't remix it in the lab now
we have a product that maybe not every
consumer is going to care about but the
consumers are really care about that we
think will be more brand loyal and
potentially pay more over time you know
better for our business compare that
against if we just wanted to put ten
milligrams of generic CD nice ligament
we might have a good business this year
we might have a good business next year
but what happens when Jameson's vitamins
so the biggest vitamin company in Canada
I believe wants to make that same
product they can call it the same vendor
let's get the same CBD isolate and they
are way better than we are about putting
vitamin powders into products they've
been doing for a long time so all of a
sudden we lose that competitive
advantage we've built in the plants
we've lose lost that differentiation to
speak to consumers and actually we're
behind because they have better
relationships with national drugstores
and national retailers and at the end of
the day we will lose as a business and
that's what we've educated our
shareholders and investors about that's
what we educate our management team on
how are we gonna win over the long run
and I think that's what plant and for me
personally what could be better than
that aligns exactly with you know my
personal vision on why cannabis works
and how it works and and let's you know
be serious it's not a coincidence that
those two came together but there's a
lot of work to get everybody on the bus
driving in the same direction yeah right
on and it's interesting too because to
hear you talk about you know you you
know your product and the customers and
the whole plant you know in my head you
know I'm always thinking about whole
plant for patients right is a bit I'm a
very you know the shows very patient
centric my backgrounds very patient
centric and and yet you know while
there's a lot of isolate type products
in the market that that more rep type
users are using if you give them a whole
plant product you get all these like
positive responses because it's a better
experience for everybody right anybody
who has access to whole plant products
ends up loving them right
so but I know your background because
you and I have had some time in the car
together and you know I know you're back
on this patient oriented right you know
you were you were working in Canada
reaching out for patients helping to
provide helping to get the the early
compassionate care retailers you know in
business and staying in business so
you're not like one of these these these
other entrepreneurs who you know solder
dry-cleaning you know company and and
are coming over from the Green Rush
right and then you've been around for a
long time so to what degree do you think
that it informs your decisions here at
well you know technically you're at
supreme but today we're at seven acres
you're Rowland's at supreme helping
guide these businesses to what degree do
you think that's informed because of the
time you put in dealing with real sick
people every day I think one of my
biggest advances as an entrepreneur in
cannabis I don't think this plant was
invented a couple of years ago and I
think a lot of people think it's new you
know the for your American viewers this
is gonna be very hot in Canada it was a
unique concept as a business to say
people who smoke cannabis whether it's
medical or recreational or wellness
whatever your purpose is if you smoke
cannabis you want good cannabis you want
to look good smell good tastes good 90%
of people watching I assume you're gonna
think duh you know everybody knows that
in the Canadian space that was a
revolutionary idea which is less of a
couple of dots and more of a concerning
question for for the rest of the
industry but that's we approached it and
what we we started with flour that was
all you could do in the Canadian
industry and we said look and we're
gonna sell flour whether we might pick
different genetics to cultivate
depending if it's a medical product at
the end of the day or our recreational
consumer at the end of the day but what
we found was there drivers for people
that are smoking their cannabis for
whatever reason
are the same right they wanted to smell
nice they want it to taste nice they
don't want a black ash and then they
want whatever that effect they're
seeking is so to build a platform that
can grow good cannabis that smells good
tastes good burns nice that think of
that as an agnostic platform we can put
you know high CBD strains on like some
of them we grow now that's maybe more
wellness suited or medical student well
we're starting to just scratch the
surface on minor cannabinoids or we can
grow high THC for whatever that purpose
is but the platform is the same grow
good cannabis and when we get into our
derivative products it's that good
cannabis you know whole plant cannabis
that we treat very gently in our
extractions and formulations that we
believe is going to help make us
different over time right on so um it's
funny because when I talk to cannabis
entrepreneurs many of them like the
monopoly mindset like they don't want
anybody else in the market I mean like
look at Florida right like and we're
we're you know they would just be happy
to be the only one providing cannabis to
everybody but you know you're very
encouraging of other entrepreneurs and
and and helping people come up and
giving people good advice and so so
let's finish up with this there are
people not only in Canada in the United
States but really all around the world
who are putting together cannabis
companies and they have got to decide
what their vision is for their company
and and what kind of quality products
they're gonna put out and where they're
gonna draw their lines right you know
clearly you and I both talked about
whole plant a lot but it's very hard for
some new people to the business of
cannabis to step into the power that
comes with producing whole plant
cannabis products what advice would you
offer to entrepreneurs who are at the
formulating stages of their business to
encourage them to go whole plant for
ever
is benefit so today first if you're
starting a cannabis business generally
forget the cannabis word and just focus
on the business part meaning you start
with your customer you know who do you
want to sell to what are you gonna sell
them what are you gonna do to delight
them or make them feel better or
whatever your business purpose is and
then start working back you know what
can I sell that product for what's it
gonna cost me to produce what kind of
infrastructure facilities do I need or
licenses and staff and really understand
is that a viable business first you know
something is very important to
understand cannabis is not a magical
product in a business sense you know
it's got margins like anything else it's
got cost it's got competition
so start first does your business make
sense what I would encourage people to
think about is his whole plant a way
that you can differentiate your business
and make it more successful over time
make yourself less subject to the
competition of large non cannabis
companies who at some point soon are
going to start buying isolates and
dropping them into products to make
yourself if you're not a big fan of
large corporate cannabis and maybe you
think they're not doing a great job
producing high quality products or are
flour or whole plant products find that
niche or that white space that you want
to drive a Mack truck through to make
your business successful and my belief
is when we survey the market in Canada
or we look at a lot of the US what we
find is if you look at smaller companies
there's a lot of people doing really
great things with the plant mostly
staying whole plant and they have a
really core committed consumer group
that's very happy to work with them when
you go to some of the more scaled
companies it's more just most supply
chain and distribution and being there
and sometimes the products aren't as
good as maybe they should be
and I think we should look at that as a
big opportunity to take market share to
take consumers over time to be
successful and I mean that whether
you're a lifestyle business where your
goal is to have you know your family and
friends employed and everyone makes a
decent paycheck or your company you know
like ours I mean don't get me wrong we'd
love to earn the monopoly overtime and
compete people out of the market and be
the last guy standing we don't want to
do that because the law made it that way
that's not fun for me we don't want to
do that because you know the police went
knocked on the door the people that came
before us I also don't agree that we
want to produce better products that
make consumers love us more and we went
over the long run but I think whether
you're big or small you got to go back
to that fundamental concept what's gonna
make you different consumers only have a
limited amount of funds to spend even if
they have insurance of limited amount of
insurance coverage to spend why are they
gonna choose to spend that with you and
I think that that mindset is no
different than if I'm going to start
selling widgets or cell phones or
anything else it's figure out that
product that makes you special and
unique and tell that story to your
customers and for us and I think for a
lot of people if you look on the whole
plant sign you're gonna find very
fertile territory
to build a brand differentiated products
and make a successful business you are
gonna work hard yeah you are gonna work
harder yeah so man thank you so much for
sticking to your guns about old plan
there's a lot of whole plant people that
kind of like the lower echelon where
where I am but but guys like you who are
dealing with 9 figure businesses you
know whole plant is beaten out of most
everybody and the fact that that you're
sticking to it and creating a model and
and and making money so that people see
that it's possible you know I think that
it just it encourages everybody that we
might be able to have a whole prime
future so thanks Allah to Shane
you