I first met even a Miss on a tour
he led of this one garden and right here
is on a street like a days about
beautiful fruits that he was growing and
I was doing it all organically this
incredible
ethan miss Osen board certified
neurologists with a long-term interest
in the discipline plans this led to a
second career focused on the therapeutic
application of campus and other herbal
treatments his busted sod since
childhood and was the founder of the
Blackfoot organic fruit and flower
operation one of the first state
certified organic farms in Montana and
his sole exotic exotic produce at the
middle of farmers market for two years
in the nineteen nineties he has lit up a
salon for ten years and slowly turned
his available quarter acre in tomorrow
is strictly organic and every landscape
let's please give a warm welcome to dr.
Ethan result
thank you for coming really great I go
all over the world giving talks about
dismal plants whether it's nice to just
drive a little bit up a brother and be
able to speak to come on people so
anyway this is the introductory slide
and you'll see a picture of a book by
Michael Phillips holistic orchard we're
talking about today is derived from that
but as I was reading I think it's
fantastic
what kind of those tremendously feeling
they're the only Christmas mocha day
yeah is that for the person who just
wants to know how to do it it's a little
bit better than if you buy the book you
may find yourself making notes for all
you'd like to do it later we try to help
with that by distilling some of the key
ingredients with spray portions that are
needed in the hand optically see if you
have questions about any of this my
email is up there pretty easy my name I
will get back to
la for instance McFly in Manila Scotia
tomorrow and Newfoundland on Friday for
other talks not not the same way anyway
next place so yes that is a picture of
me by Ellis Beach members to who to me
was just this crappy old lady but a
bundle later that she would slide you
know you've quite an active leftist and
on New England politics even them so key
questions that people have why do you go
to the trouble
well one answer is because this block by
another it is because we think it's
important and there are arguments from
people all over the world about whether
nutritionally it's better to grow
organically it is and then there's the
whole environmental aspect
about ready it's critically important to
me that I do things organically and I've
heard approach decades from people that
it's impossible to go good fruit without
synthetic pesticides which is not
terrible and for years I was asking
everyone do you know of a preventive
organic spray program that you can just
do proactively to be able to grow good
at perfect and everyone said no that's a
nice idea of an unknowable penny and
then about six years ago Michael
Phillips came out with this book and it
was exactly what proverbial doctor
ordered or even three so here the
reasons it's definitely safer it's
ecologically sound you're working with
rather than against
the idea of this great program that
we're going to do it's going to be okay
for the good bugs and repel the bad bugs
but not necessarily kill anything just
keep things in proper balance it's a
sustainable approach and again there is
positive evidence of nutritional
benefits sometimes bigger pretty clearly
more of these secondary metabolites
things like bio flavonoids that help
prevent aging by this degenerative
diseases but it's very satisfying and
how many people before this can say my
food is 100% on Amazon not discounted
from the regular price I was happy
oh Christ when I first came out he has a
website that's really good and there's a
blog that goes along with it and he
figures the book in the back this is
like me sometimes he takes a lot of the
answer is email but when I had questions
that weren't handled in the book like
God why won't my when straight afraid it
will at least give it a try but remember
your resources here too if you remember
the print Club take a picture of your
diseased or damaged trigger Bushman send
it around and get that opinions next one
place kind of organic growing it's
realizing how fruit grows and what most
fruit trees that we count or designed to
grow up before us - yeah it's an
environment where there's lots of stuff
that falls off leaves and twigs but I'm
not a cosmetic gardener if you took the
tour of my place
that doesn't necessarily look right but
the results are really good so a lot of
that stuff that we cosmetically
breakaways actually good for the plant
will break down and provide nutrition
Harbor good organisms that need to be
there so you can promote this by using
we're called ravioli which s so these
are the thin 2 inch or less branches
from hardwoods and done you can check
these to get this chip or you're gonna
spend a lot of time beat them in one by
the line might be better
do they have a bigger of worship chipper
a bigger property next please and this
is what they look like a dealing they're
different shades and this is like solid
nutrition for the trees and can be
spread just like mulch you'll be amazed
next please just close up being leased
up quickly this song gets incorporated
into the soil
next please um apparently though we're
going to be talking about this
preventive organic spray program that
Michael Phillips develop so what's it
all about again the idea is a general
spray that's a tonic for the plants
providing things that needs on keeping
things in ecological balance the idea is
to improve for growth the vigor and the
nutrient
when properly done and my spraying he
recommends every seven to fourteen days
throughout the season the season starts
earlier I usually start in late February
and go through September might be one
spray late the season and help break
down some of the leaves and other stuff
that's falling on the trees but what
this will do is markedly reduce
predation by bad bugs so the need in the
spray that we're going to talk about has
some panty feeding property it sort of
tastes bad for the bugs and go somewhere
else but it's not harmful to pollinators
I got plenty of mason bees and other
pollinators in the garden providing we
don't have a spring like this one so if
you didn't have a great he'll go welcome
to the club but we don't want to be in a
lot of the components of the spray or
antifungal goodness notes in our
environment that's our biggest problem
things like peach leaf curl blacks
bottom
are really an issue in this felony
despite the fact that it reduces those
pathogenic disease formation fungi it
improves the micro rifle growth of the
soil Michael rise ir1 chai that grow
around degrees and it's a symbiotic
relationship both get something out of
it punch I have a place to grow and it
helps provide nutrients to the tree
itself through the grades additionally
this spring will reduce both bacterial
and viral diseases so the real base to
this is pure organic neem oil now
there's tons of neem oil on the market I
use a brain called ahi'm son I'm gonna
pass this around and ask you to be
really careful this is like melted
butter here it's the consistency of
butter it must have been warmed up as
normally it'll be more
look like butter that's been on the
counter for a few minutes this is
expensive but if you by default you can
start the refrigerated for long periods
of time and what I do is I buy little
bottles like this and measure up 75
milliliters that's five tablespoons in
each one that I keep in the fridge and
then when I'm ready to spray just grab
one and set it up on the comment
so we would go from left to right we've
got the neem oil this is what it looks
like in the bridge when it's warmed up
it looks like that middle and then you
need a soap to emulsify it break it up
and little tiny droplets will spread
through the spraying up float on top and
the scud be done one people asked me if
you can store the spray the answer is no
you cannot it's got to be done on the
spot next please
second component is hydrolyzed fish
fertilizer
now there's again this is not fish
emulsion
that's just fish that are ground up this
is different this is broken down a
little bit with enzymes and it's much
more fire what we hold of the plant
I also doesn't smell as bad since this
is a distinct product as compared to
fish emulsion that you might be more
familiar yes
that's Neptune and honor if you got the
handout all the stuff here on
including the price itself next please
question to those available if you want
to make your own I think that Dakota
Dallas can be worth the time we'll have
time for questions at the end so I don't
have an answer
outstanding issues so the next one is
liquid count then this is also
hydrolyzed no we do have Kalpana Beach
this is made from good stuff and non
polluted areas the key thing here is
this got one more tax factors trace
minerals primarily using these is folded
so foliar feeding means they are
spraying on Belize but also some next
please the next ingredient are
beneficial microbes this is the brand
that I have use you can choose this
three different ways
this one comes pre-mixed you can magnify
it because this is a little bit pricey
but you can mix this and
mix it with a little bit of molasses and
you let it ferment again because this
has got a combination of bacteria and
fungi in it you let it ferment for a
while until it gets the right pH and
then you can increase the guilt 24 so
you can count this you can brew this you
can buy it just premix that can't be
expended for the people that want to
make compost tea they need that again a
little bit more labor-intensive that's
what we end up with this liquid and
we've got to aerate it for a few days it
really is a lot very good for plants and
can be used as a fertilizer but because
I travel a lot it's better if I can just
make stuff on the spot next this is
blackstrap molasses make sure it's
organic
you don't let it sulfur because that's
gonna kill the the good bonus then
you've got max this is in the mix
because it nourishes the beneficial
microbes so when you spray it they've
got something that grown perfect
next please finally a spreader sticker
there various of these this was called
thermos 70 it's the only when I found
that
listed as organic us in various forever
Snickers on the market but he might come
out to get this one or what to see if
there are others their commodity market
there
and next place so I realize that I'm not
gonna be able to read this too long but
you don't have to because we provided
the students but this is what we call
orchard spray rates and the stinking
from Michaels blood it's just he didn't
have a table like this and we've killed
this all the way from like doing a
corridor pint at once all the way up to
a hundred gallons he's got a relatively
bigger operation and extreme northern
New Hampshire and he uses 100 tractor
that that's what I use
[Music]
so this is the meet again this is a
little used to be a different maker this
is passed by the wayside I did the Apple
for almost forty years but it shows you
the transition from the green even more
solid need to one of the most like when
it's heated up the heating is not that
much 105 degrees Fahrenheit it's all you
don't want to do anything over 120
degrees
my 50 degrees Celsius because that'll
kill the bugs next please
so it's absolutely necessary that you
have clean water idiots now that's right
you do that one of two ways either a
good filtered water or because if you're
on numb district 19 water is chlorinated
you should second water out overnight or
they can out gas the floor again
otherwise it's gonna kill the good bugs
okay so that's very important you can
use distilled water but it's going to be
wait way too expensive so you know I've
got a water filter in the kitchen
I've got no problem with it so we heat
up a bunch of water for something less
than 50 degrees Celsius because he want
that work to keep the mean suspended
that's very important and the reason
that you can't story please this is
about the effect of microbes and so if
you do buy the profile for example and
one of its wrong this is what it's got
in it lactobacilli and bifida bacteria
these are things that you find in yogurt
they're on vegetables if you do
lacto-fermentation of vegetables you've
got same kinds of bugs so one of these
you can drink
see now it's poor they weren't your
plants to drink and it's got again these
yeasts there are other beneficial
bacteria it's a sea bear remember
through the names and to meet this brood
what you do is you use 3/4 of a cup of
beneficial microbes quarter cup of
Blackstrap gallon Philip the gentleman
chug up keep it at 90 degrees Fahrenheit
until the pH is 3.8 or less that's about
a week's worth and then it will store
for several weeks at open temperature
and you've got 20 times more for the
same price so like anything else there's
no investment of money next place this
pH paper is readily accessible together
Raintree or sports happen to you just
dip the strip and when it's the same
colors the three-pointer they're so not
her little bit of kitchen chemistry
next please and as I mentioned you can
get the premix this by the way and it's
the same but the difference is this
[Music]
now this next part is only for the
hardcore Michael Phillips is into doing
a lot of herbal teas as an additional
supplement plans and this is usually a
one-seater proposition and these are
things you can find readily on Vashon
when I first did it I had to go to an
herbal herbal early interested friend's
house and get Humphrey but I knew that
we had horsetail down by tram Harbor I
got those Nettles
everywhere but the first one is comfrey
when we're going to recommend comfrey
it's a really interesting plant
it is invasive however the company that
used to be called horizon is not called
sprinkling the dismal myself of Russian
high credit concrete and it's in terms
of its constituents the good stuff in it
it's exactly the same but it'll just
grow abundantly every year but it won't
spread okay so I really recommend that
I've got that standard through the dirt
what this does nobody thinks it's
aerates the soil and really recruits
calcium from deep in the ground but in
the spring you can cut some of this down
you cover it with hot water and you brew
it for a week what this is
there is service another tonic to the
plant produces trace minerals
it also has empty fungal properties is
very good to add to the minutes next one
horse tail basically if you go area
standing water
there's a creek nearby there's after the
horse hills readily identifiable what
this does it's very strong and silica so
like this what's it seen but this is in
a form where you can spray it on the
planet and it really toughen up the
plant and helps prevent predation from
bugs like just like that plant drop so
that's the main ingredient there the
next one is the nettle tea not morning
you've got to be hardcore to do this
because what's the stuff from that it's
pretty great no it can be stored at
ambient temperature outside temperature
as long as it's out of the Sun and I
just use it throughout the season
basically what I've done here is they
fill up five gallon buckets you know
food grade one of the hardware stores as
I said dump the hot water on it again
that should be chlorine free or a
builder and let it sit for a week and
then you can store it and I do a quarter
beach get into the mix throughout the
season next please
you don't need to go to the step but you
can put
airlocks on them and you know they're
pretty good told they start throwing
fudge
in them which looks bad remember why
you'd be spraying this on their plant
but yeah it's good fun okay this is what
the makes looks like all together sort
of muddy but I think you'll appreciate
that you don't see good loves of oil on
top it's actually well mixed
particularly if you've got that water
temperature right you'll see tiny
droplets of needs and the bottom will
will look just like the top that's
that's done right
next please just some notes about things
let's see what you need to mention isn't
pointed out keep recommends everyone to
two weeds rough season I've done it
every two weeks I can't manage once a
week you've dropped the fish which is
fertilizer of course for the nitrogen
component he dropped that about the
beginning of June we do the various
herbal teas from the tide met when the
nettle flowers that's the time to make
it that's the time to start by doing it
you do that through the beginning
I'm done with that bird the neem oil
should be refrigerated particularly if
we're gonna buy a football if you leave
it out and were meant to get it up
bottle you can't do that forever
I what I'd really recommend it's
definitely well if you think is
reasonable on your fianc which lasts me
a couple of seasons I pour out 75
milliliters and these little jars they
go into French too and once again the
fish and kelp should be hydrolyzed and
the effect of microbes is as is or you
can multiply them burning to make your
own compost tea the black strap keep in
mind if you're not work used to working
with molasses very qatari stuff that's
going to be warmed up to in the water to
get it to mix otherwise if you're
worried about how all this smells what
I'd like to say is that that complete
mix with a fish needs smells like a Thai
restaurant full production let's drop
the fish it just smells in a bit of
night there's really nothing
[Music]
these are only a few of the emails that
are really organic and pull that arm
even consider a guarantee you don't hurt
the trouble of doing this with the wrong
braveness another thing that comes up is
how much trouble the business really
well how important is your first I can
tell you that I've seen a lot of fruit
operations
there's a lot of money very before I was
doing this we inherited some delicious
ham and I happen to know we were really
getting between the birds and monkey
berry there is no production but as
you'll see we're doing really well with
no money during the reason is because of
this appropriate with the right setup I
can get this down to weirder than doing
it out every two weeks that's eluded us
from the time that say okay I'm going to
spray until I'm done and things are set
them out to air out is an hour okay so
now we're every two weeks of me is a
good investment I think well worth while
there is some initial outlay for this
stuff some ingredients are pricey but to
me in wall with water on next place in
terms of other equipment I use a
backpack sprayer 20 only trees that
we've got spraying something like twelve
or fourteen
punching berries this is all on a
quarter-acre so I can do the one thing
all the berries and roses and fruit
trees that I want to spray with 140 on
application every two weeks I started
out the best the solo I figured up a
German trader it should be really good
liable but I've gone through it one a
season this is a manual one where you're
spraying with the right hand you're
pumping off all the time to the left and
I'm afraid that when these go that's it
it can be service but service is like 40
bucks an hour and god you can't take one
of these apart and put it back to the
other in less than a couple of hours so
yeah
abundant so I went through two of these
and another similar
rhetoric out lies if you do get dust you
do want to spring for the better
shoulder pads and the waistband if
you're like the beatings of a certain
age and have a bad back
this weighs 40 pounds when it's fall and
you want to distribute that weight I can
tell you I've never heard like that
doing this I've hurt my back plenty
other ways and you probably want to get
with these to stick it on next I started
by pure us a couple of months ago away
I got an automatic car for the first
time in my life and listen because I've
wanted that it's because manual cars
barely really exist anymore against some
yeah and I felt the same way about the
sprayer if you could do it me in LA
that's what I thought I should do but I
was wrong because it breaks down so I
decided okay I'm going to spend the
extra twenty bucks or whatever it is
electric and this is actually pretty
neat it's a lithium battery and all the
sudden you're not doing this all the
time it also is much steadier and much
faster and because there's not the wear
and tear I think it's going to last so
it costs a little more but for the time
they actually come spring is half as
much and then clean that's much easier
too because you just put some water in
there letter read this is been using and
so far really happy yeah
times important next please
or is that your story by this I was out
there one morning and saw when the
neighbors don't worry it's all organic
I'm not sure he's ready to my realtor a
few days later and she said well which
house wasn't down at all this stuff is
absolutely safe as I pointed out you can
drink it I got this why you want to the
fact is you don't need to be getting
this on your clothes
it does smell when the fishes minute and
so I found out for the first couple of
sprays that GU all yeah not gonna wash
these clothes and take a second shower
again more time so I'm kind of X to
costume nothing it's really cheap again
you get a bunch of these and so I just
cover up and I'm gonna take this top off
my clothes are fine so that's the way to
do it so yeah you don't need to breathe
next so what does all this do well
starting in the winter it really
provides a good wakeup for the plant get
things started I think if you do this
you'll really notice that you have but
break and then you spray and then all
the sudden things go
y-yeah you know between the rain and
general Sun and merge that's a factor
but boy it's different once you start
spraying with the apples I noticed that
they were much larger the flavor was
better I have not had any more alcohol
maggot I should mention that the year
before it started this a trade tried the
little net things where you go around a
little fruit and put these babies on I
hated that job I spent like five hours
doing it it didn't work I was really
happy
never did that
yeah so much rather spend an hour every
two weeks during analysis the bags don't
do anything except supposedly keep the
bikes up with abrasive mention already
totally eliminated the mummy girly and
senior man and then everywhere else
there's a marked increase in yield with
appears I if you spray on the day we're
this bright Sun which is going to be
anytime in july/august here we have a
chance that to get a photo sensitivity
reaction on some of them needs to get
black spots and won't show it I roses
not usually fun is a fruit but we get a
terrible of black Leafs like that it's
not eradicated it's still there but it's
controlled we've got really good roses
no it's more like I do spray those
raspberries
better slice and you know strawberries
bigger better tasting plants I highly
recommend to see pictures of in a few
minutes is in Illinois we are preparing
of all great he's tried mulberries is in
boy
so yeah this is a grapefruit not well
known to most modern Americans but most
beautifully here you don't mind bread
mix the walkway because it stains but
lovely wonderful for freshmen really buy
some spray I now have persimmons the
stager persimmon and we'll see coming up
also a blue crab passion flower of
government for eight a couple of times
really nice flowers so let's show some
elements next place LM going ever very
for a treehouse I try to keep it so
again you know you don't want to be
picking small I admire people grow sweet
cherries but no I try to keep it with
every
that's crazy so there's an amateur and
they look like what trying to pick them
when they're all black but the birds
people I found that the aluminum of my
water sphere tape works very well our
dog also likes these so I decided that
I'll just share with the birds and
easily fit Robins next serve got dog
won't breeze in the colander and this
was my best year on the advert cause
this year I will be God
I think they're really pretty but I only
got three this year okay next I've got
one apple tree left and it's Cortland it
seems to be a biennial bearers not
necessarily supposed to be but I ended
up bringing
it's more than we can eat but it seemed
next so let's clean I don't see bugs
spray yeah miss Canada this year
no this year are quite a little baby not
really not much at all
next please I got two real girls like
that about this one small trade Wow
and later next that's one of the
passiflora national flowers pretty good
or something that's supposed to be a
tropical plant from Brazil next appears
in the next place
there's the acquaintance I'm pleased to
say after being frustrated with this
tree for several years I've got about
ten this year for some reason
just once I'd probably need a ladder for
those next blueberries in the best every
couple of days they're really pretty
clean this is what they look like so in
other words since their growth with
grace is really pretty few weeks from
now by next and the next one this was a
plan the Buffalo currents or right
and it's normally a tremendous amount of
sour cherries but this year cause the
trees just covered if you deceive you
like because it's imported that to get
about that if you get affirm Raintree
the first year I started out and leaped
out about a week before it throws
it came back the next year of the early
crew and slowly slowly it's got the
point where it's now about 15 Tennessee
last year there were about a hundred I
couldn't find my pictures it's really a
beautiful tree in all seasons
it's both big green it's got these
peculiar little blossoms and end up with
food that's ill orange like this a lot
of people may not be familiar with
persimmons but this will be ready
summer after Thanksgiving so it's sort
of the catheter the season line the
fruit would be ready have double beets
inverted fallen off so you've got these
yellow orange fruit on the bitter traits
really pretty striking anyway that's the
country girl and there's a 70 happy
dance with questions
[Music]
all of this stuff can be sprayed around
the basement but in the goes on the
branches and Trunks to the trailer the
very ready to spray again what we're
doing this is beefing it up with its
natural protection
[Music]
winter and spring on record in one of
the driest summers
why should point out to with a mulch
I've got an inch layer of mulch
i watered maybe three times as here okay
rubbish for this whole thing I want
those trees to have deep roots in terms
of nutrition that's easily chips
yeah then the radio wood chips of the
best coming out yeah less than two inch
diameter that's good bit of labour the
chip these otherwise you want to use her
glutes all their best around here but
yeah you don't want cedar Cedars got a
pungent throat sorry how hard
the question about in the springtime
with the spraying you have to be careful
about the blooming time and then you do
coming to the tree will be in full bloom
and still spray or I've done it in every
stage you know different trees are going
to be a different stages and Michael
addresses that the book is well I really
watch this I've sprayed I've gone out
the same day and seen plenty of
pollinators working on the same stuff
that got sprayed a few hours before so
clearly it's not exporting them from
nearest
I've got a question about your recipe
like on a four gallon line here you
start with four gallons of water and
then add these other things to do other
I don't know quick and how I do it is
something along the lines of all I heat
up the water
I put in the molasses and get that mixed
in the Negroes in this is sort of waters
warm already
so the need goes in while it's still
warm and that's already been mixed with
the Bronner soak so that emulsifies then
I went downstairs and person the fish I
put in the microbes they put in the kelp
and the spreader sticker that goes in
the sprayers then I have any herbal teas
if I'm using them and then I fill up the
rest with warm water and then you go
straight to work you don't let it sit
because you want to keep things warm
keep in mind when it comes out with a
spray it's kind of cool
kill me in that way what you don't want
to do except for one or two hot so
they're killing your beneficial microbes
but no you don't mix it all I just stay
out of the water together how much water
I missing something
worth it how does a cordial expressive
in the tea I use a quart of each so how
do you determine how much to spray any
particular plan you've got small
blueberry patch got big trees probably
can't over these though but how do you
make sure you get them enough ah it's
good question particularly with the
electorate sprayer it comes up nicely
and evenly
I knew it so that it looks like I'm
giving some on each leaf gonna be fruit
and on the stones a little bit on the
ground as you said we can't have too
much occasionally
[Music]
quickly some of the trees are bigger
than the tops but the plant will slow
down some respect I think there's a lot
of leeway it's a curious question what
is neat oil this
it's got insurance or ingredients that
come along with it all right turbine
blades so these are essential oils
thicker more oily more small like do I
have room temperature but you know good
thing about the book is if you really
want to dig in
he's got a lot of explanation for the
reasons behind this also he can dig up
the references there in America he can
get it under a very scientific level you
want yeah but that's important to do I
need aggressive Florida
do you have a fertilizer program in
addition to the spray or is this a hard
lesson I bulk I do this and that's it
the exception is I use organic
fertilizers of spring and fall just a
little graze because you know they're
not native here and it's a special tax
again from Raintree its passive yes it
lands additionally I haven't provided
compost or nitrogen in any form anything
last and it's thrown like crazy
you spray on me degrading women yeah
good question you don't want to spray
unless you've got like four hours for
things to say no this year isn't our
problem some years is really a problem
particularly the spray get that right
again say it's going to be sunny you
probably Grutter oh and get it on as I
mentioned if it's bright Sun in the
afternoon it's possibly get some
photosensitivity reactions a lot of this
would be because they're going to be
droplets on the plant that acts like a
magnifying glass to the sunrise
ladies so it's not necessarily chemical
magnification we have to do is type of
Awesome
he said enzymes are breaking it down so
it's not a big protein that smaller yeah
it would be considered like a
fermentation so it's treated with
enzymes what it means is that the planet
can get benefit of the nitrogen and
other nutrients really quickly because
it doesn't have to break them down and
you can't benefit of not smelling as bad
[Music]
with the chips last long
[Applause]
[Music]
yeah I think it's great I admire people
that have a discipline do the big pluses
that said I'm not sure I'm needed
between the spray and the thick layer of
Polish
I talked about disease-resistant
varieties which i think is the great
foundation
yeah sure I did in relation
[Music]
is it an optimum if you had any time
that you do a double dose of need in the
winter and last spring in the fall
Freitas
like just in the editor you to be humble
but fish in the fall that help break
down the residual leaves and stuff oh I
got excited if you have too much mean
you sittin there cooling down and coming
up your sprayer you know again system
that experiment do you have to lose
plenty of the chips like and dishes
no I can't eat interested blasted my
third season they weren't very small but
yeah I think you can dig down see what's
going on in the soil again I have
another water pistol
[Music]
also trying to be friends yeah electric
fences work to support my chance
yeah well there's a guy Johnny you know
I am serious about the dog because my
wife when I was here we are in the jar
regularly eating my plants that stop
so I was just looking in the book about
that moment Barry business and talk
about a little source there grab and I
didn't see that but sure I've never seen
it before
sure yeah there it is you can do about
mommy birdies you want to disturb the
material around the tree - so around the
bush and you want to replenish pine
needles preferably each season that
alone but the spray does a great job
later steamy mrs. forest land it's
described in the spray really there's no
I'll take one more
if do you mulch all the way out to the
leaf line on the tree or just yeah
that's the best advice that the
surrounding soil
but jumped out would be the least amount