so Matt why don't you give us a little
walkthrough of the front part of the
garden here all right so we got some
Southfork seeds some genetics we got
from our boys over in Trinity County
these are dirty cookies and this one
right here is a sherbert bloodhound and
then we have a golden lemons cross with
bloodhound so pretty exciting we got
some what are those called
unicorn farts from Erakat HBK and we got
some what else we got back here some
really nice diamond masters from hdk we
got some zuki from the boys over in the
valley for you nice plants we started
all these and whether we start these
April 14th
so getting pretty big no we started them
in January we put them outside April 14
HBK
she's getting big
nicely chirpy stone topping her got some
diamond masters oh gee respect from
Southfork seeds we run a lot of
Southfork seeds their genetics do great
over here on the coast
they're pretty local too right yeah yeah
so it's a nice to use somebody who's
breeding their stuff in your st. bio
region exactly yep Kevin Kevin from
wunderlanders where you put us on to to
southfork seeds a couple years ago and
we fell in love with them so we're
rocking pretty heavy awesome man thanks
for the walk through that Yemen I see