so Nate thank you so much for having me
back on your farm um you know last time
when we were here in the spring we just
shot that great video about your like
very large Google culture deployment
would you give a sort of reminder of the
the size and general dimensions of the
hookah culture deployment yeah it's a
sixty three hundred square feet and it's
just a small flat area the mounds or the
the hills run from 25 feet up to 75 feet
long so so we talked to you in the
spring you know this was the rnd part of
your property you've got your your
proper greenhouses where you do other
kinds of living soil probiotic and KNF
growing but who cultural is like in your
heart right yeah so you wanted to do
this this year and and just kind of see
you know how it went and and when we
last talked a lot of your concern was
whether or not the immaturity of the
hookah culture because you had just
built them was gonna impact the flower
and whether or not you were gonna get
any yield I've seen them but I'll let
you go ahead and say it so how did you
have some success yeah yeah I think we
did it's uh it's good to go down and see
the plants happy and have some nice big
buds on there it wasn't it wasn't always
like that
we had some some issues along the way
with drought I would say it was probably
the biggest thing that we had hit our
plants as we were digging these these
hugo mounds out we we actually decided
to escalate down into the ground a
little bit we started all of our
material was saturated completely wet
but this took a lot longer than we
thought to get it all done and as we
were digging out replant or refilling
spreading out the materials they were
drying out and as we got to the very
last one or was actually the second to
last one we deemed it
to be a little too much of a a burden to
try and get it wet enough to to plant
into it so we cut it short on the last
one we're gonna try to get it all dug
out here before before the rain hits
after we harvest here and get that one
so so if you had this kind of drought
condition because your materials you've
started with the materials wet but
before you could get him in the huugle
hole they got dry and so you're
essentially packing dry holes I would
think that you probably took water and
just drench the hell out of them is that
it was that your first line of defense
yeah it was we you know going into this
whole thing it's the water conservation
is the the idea behind it and the fact
that you're gonna have these really big
deep nutrient-rich beds full of
microbiology but it it wasn't the case
going into this first year it it was dry
unworkable no sticks and you could see
it in the plants as the time went on and
in the early stages they seemed like
they may be kind of bottom down a little
bit or maybe weren't growing as fast as
they should a lot of yellow leaf from
from drought conditions so you know it
wasn't all it wasn't all easy but
actually none of it was you know every
year moving forward is gonna be much
more much easier because of what we did
this year so we're excited about that so
we were talking about how you were gonna
you know as you know you are both a
cannabis farmer and also very much a
business owner and you feel that no more
than this year right I've heard before
and you know you were talking about like
okay you've got your regular greenhouses
and you were gonna devote x-variable of
resources to this R&amp;D project and the
Google beds but actually ended up being
quite a bit of resources to dig out the
holes and fill them and put the whole
thing and you were just like you know
I'm okay with hookah cultures for the
future but it'd be really great
to get enough abundant crop to make this
worthwhile and to at least be in the
black for the year right on that growing
area totally would you say that you have
got other an abundant enough enough of a
crop where it was worth the overall
effort I think so yeah I it's you know
time will tell we have a weaker still
left to harvest we're just getting ready
to start to pull the first ones down
it's probably gonna be two weeks before
the last ones come down so a better idea
then but I think we're gonna be
somewhere around 60% of our typical
yield I wouldn't say that the youth of
the Google cultures necessarily impacted
the plants I mean there are certainly
some things that you may want to do
different and better as you make your
best practices but you know we were
seeing coal as the size of your arm you
know it was it's it's visually
impressive what would you say is some
aspect of it that that you're looking to
improve next year just the soil
structure in the beds I would say is the
main thing we used a lot of the native
soil that we have down there and wood
were the two main things that went into
it our native soil is very rocky and
very clay like so it's not the easiest
to work so our goal over over the course
of the fall and into the winter and
yoonah to the spring is gonna be just
continually adding layers of mulch to
these beds and and get the organic
matter built up in there get mycelium
networks built up in there get
microbiology built up in there
all of this through permaculture
practices or maybe doing some mushroom
logs and some different things so yeah
it's it's gonna be it's gonna be fun
throughout the winter I'm looking
forward to having some downtime from
farming and concentrate on building the
bed
yeah I think everybody's like excited
for and looking forward to harvest to at
least move on to different things you
know different tasks for the day I was
happy for you to see that you were able
to do some food inter planting - because
you know part of the idea is that that
you've got your cannabis plants up top
but you're also running you know
companion plants that are you know you
know positively alio Pathak with the
cannabis but also to grow some food you
know to reap you know benefit from that
as well so so how did that go um it
actually was a complete mistake this
year we uh we were and are planting or
planning on doing a bunch of
polycultures and Inter plantings and you
know making these beds you know just
full of abundance are you saying that
was a volunteer volunteer bury
everything that came up underneath was
volunteer actually we have pumpkin
squash there's tobacco down there wait
so it was everything that was in your
compost and then you then used to fill
the Google culture that starts popping
up yeah that's actually pretty cool
so another one of your goals was going
to be to use as many of the nutrients
both the rod a nutrients just so yours
throwing on to amend the soil but also
the inputs for your can F ferments
you're gonna try to source as much of
that as possible right here on your
acreage so you can you know keep the
circle tight how did that go pretty good
we we did a lot of harvesting early in
the year and preparing our f PJs and our
F F J's
maybe the fermented plant juice and
fruit juices and also we did some stuff
for pesticides we did a habanero ffj
did also our ellaby's with our goat milk
see that and we did a little bit of a
sea water but beyond that we didn't get
into much of the other K&amp;F stuff but
that stuff we've got a pretty good hold
on and we're we're getting ready to move
further on into the into the regimens
and even outside of the permits it
seemed like you use a lot of the
biomaterial that was on the property
like you know you turned me on to how
rich of for stuff is last time I was
here right and so the more I look into
it the more like I realize that stuff is
like soft magic you know yeah so so you
used a lot of that and obviously you
used a lot of brush because it looks
like you kept on even after you dug the
Whoville you kept on putting stuff on
there and just so the idea was for it to
break down so so where did you source
some of that stuff to we just around
anywhere we could we got most of our
forest stuff from just off of the the
full Sun flat and our homestead flat a
lot of the other stuff that went into
the plant matter and the wood came from
a PG&amp;E Extension that we're working on
we're bringing we're bringing power to
our place and we had a lot of brush and
tree clearing to do and we were able to
gather up all of that stuff and get it
down there and get that stuff in there
and feeling really good about the the
ability to use that stuff oh right on
cool yeah well thank you again for the
tour this spring because that was really
not only exciting but it was really
inspiring right to see who GU culture
deployed on that level and thanks for
having us back to take more pictures and
to chat more about it absolutely
you