hey there friends Shango here from
shaping fire and uh I'm here with Dan
Jimmy of gnome automatics um and we're
neighbors right uh I live on Bashon
Island he lives just over the water from
me in Port Orchard and so I'm over here
pretty regularly like fishing or crabing
or just looking at our Gardens and I'm
over here today and Dan is showing me
the present state of his garden and I'm
all like whoa whoa whoa whoa whoa hold
on man if you're going to show me all of
this incredible Garden um let's go ahead
and take some photos and and get some
you know share it with everybody right
and so he's like yeah all right let's
set up some chairs so here we are right
so so thanks Dan for giving me a couple
minutes to like look at your garden of
course dude I'm just glad your
excitement brought us to this point you
know I'm excited about it this year and
um it's been fun so it's way better than
what I had last year and we could talk
about that too yeah actually we we
thought about doing this video last year
and then we just kind of stoned it and
didn't get to it but I'm glad now we
waited till this year because this
year's Garden is so much better yeah me
too so Dan what I'm thinking is let's
talk a little bit about the Cannabis
stuff that you're growing and then we'll
talk a little bit about the food stuff
since you know this is your home garden
corre and so you're providing food for
your family too so let's start with that
y um so so first of all like you your
main thing is uh breeding autof flowers
correct and uh you know you're
nationally known for that that's great
and you've been selling seeds for years
um but what's behind us here is uh some
new projects that you're working on so
um so why don't you tell us about that
first and as as you show them I'll show
some close-ups so go ahead absolutely so
behind us what you're seeing is the
actual 304 project that's come to a
close uh for the season and I say come
to a close you know we're working on it
and I'm super thrilled about it dude um
you know as you said nationally known
and I've gotten you've been selling
seeds there has been some good ones that
have come out but there hasn't been
anything as excited as I am for this
um there are several attributes I've
been hunting for the last few years
things that I've been trying to improve
from feedback from people out there I
know my Turk game was weak but I think
that we've turned that around you ran
your nose through here a little bit
earlier and uh I think things have
shifted on that point yeah it's huge gas
too right like like getting gas in an
Autoflower is hard right it's real hard
and that's the thing like it's there
right now we know they're volon it seems
to be even stranger and auto flowers it
tends to go away quicker sometimes we
just tend to lose it when it comes close
to harvest so we'll see how they come
out how they dry and see what's left
after that process as far as the turps
the second thing I'm super thrilled
about is what we've seen in testing
especially with Phil grown autos and
Farms is a lot of time cover crop can
outcompete the auto growth whether it be
from weather stress or anything that's
keeping them small or even in that
infancy stage where they're waiting to
take root sometimes the cover crop are
out you know out compete I have had that
problem myself the plant is growing but
the cover crop is passing it and it
chokes it out and that has become a I
don't want to say a big roadblock but a
common roadblock that I have seen over
the last couple years with farmers and
conversation and I have been looking for
a cultiv bar that can do two things for
the farmer transplant stability as we
all know Autos they can be transplanted
but you have to you know be diligent
about it and there's a timing window and
it can be done but I was looking for
something that can take a little bit
longer window and a smaller container
and still end up like what's behind us
here right you know we're in six got 10t
centers in here and majority of these
are 6t or taller I think the smallest
one in here was 6t these are the biggest
Auto flowers that I've seen and after
this year I've grown like 180 some
Autoflower varieties and I've never seen
anything this uh chunky or tall well and
these are the first ones that I've had
come out consisten consistently across a
lot I started 175 of these this year uh
150 made it out here out of that 150 it
got thinned down most males were removed
except for one two males and then two
females were then reversed uh for a
little bit of uh just a little bit of
play and something uh new just trying to
kind of keep some diversity in there and
just to see what happens I want to see
what ratios happen if we get an increase
of female just to see so the the 304 is
already in the market already so this is
the new generation uh is this are these
f3s or what so that's correct so there
are f3s that are currently available in
the market as reg only these are making
the F4 the selections were done from
what I called the pink selection from
the end of last summer which were pink
flowers as well as pink uh pistols so it
was a Private Selection working for the
F4 they were the larger of the group
they were late season last year they
were specifically ran to look for the
mold mildew as well as their rapidness
to growth to harvest these are over 90
days now I think cuz they were started
at June 1st um it's definitely Beyond 90
days but you're you're not growing for
flower you're actually seeded so it
makes sense that you would be growing
more than 90 days so that you could get
really nice finished zebra striped seeds
well correct yeah you beat me to the
punch there like I would definitely say
these are easily takeable between 70 and
80 days which is what I want and that's
6 and seven and 8T from germination to
finish to this size behind us 70 to 80
days so um I'm sure that anybody who is
familiar with autoflowers and is seeing
this is all like how how are these so
chunky and big and you know certainly we
all know the importance of good genetics
right it doesn't matter if it's
autoflowers or photos or tomatoes right
it's like good genetics are super
important so so setting that aside for a
minute what the hell else are you doing
because everything around here is so
huge and and I'm sure that people are
going to be like what the what the hell
else is he using cuz because um you know
you're not an a+b kind of chemical guy
you're not force feeding them no these
the nothing in here is force fed at all
everything that is sitting around us is
100% fed through the line only on water
um now I do incorporate compost te's uh
worm casting te's are my base um this
gives me an opportunity here too I'm
getting ready to do a little work with
Luna and we're going to put together a
compost tea so stay tuned for that uh
we're going to do a collaboration
together and we'll go over the kind of
compost tea I typically use and I think
we're going to set up one that she uses
and recommendations and kind of show so
that you know stay tuned for that more
on that later but um the rest of it uh
behind us all the Autos are in a
seven-year Hogle bed that's chopped and
dropped every year uh um some dry
amendments are added throughout you know
the winter months but then mulch back
over and then cover crops and that's
about it like so pretty much it's it's
um a pre fortified substrate yep you
don't feed them during the season but
you keep the microbes um vibrant by um
by reinforcing them with uh compost
cheese 100% all right and I think the
biggest thing for me over wintering I've
tried multiple different things in here
as far as like mulching layers over
wintering to kind of keep that alive on
the soil surface straw does good but you
have to deal with a lot of grass you're
going to have to cut it out you pull it
out you're going to lose some root mass
when you do that it's not a big deal uh
but again it can come up but what I have
found and I am lucky is I have a friend
who is a woodworker and he turns tables
and bowls and stuff like that and he
gives me these giant contractor bags of
nothing but hardwood shavings now it's
not chunk it's real thin shavings and
you can see it behind us and has become
the perfect mulching layer to keep that
top surface moist and the microbes alive
all the way to the surface
I think that's key being able to have
the roots go take full advantage of the
area that they're in one of the things
that's important about uh using this
type of oh yeah there's some right here
this this type of uh what did you call
these shavings yeah shavings I use these
to and uh Leon Morrison taught me
something really important about these
because a lot of people are concerned
about um uh using wood chips on top
because the biological processes they go
through can actually suck nitrogen out
of your soil right but these when you
get them from someone who turns wood
these are all precured right so they're
they're denatured and so they take a lot
longer time to break down and they break
down in a different way which means that
they're not um stealing the nitrogen
from your soil I use those too and I
swear by them if you can get your hands
on them oh absolutely 100% you know and
I'm fortunate enough to get those bags
actually he pesters me about like hey I
got like six of these bags you want them
yep sure do and we've gotten it down to
a rhythm now he usually hits me up in
the spring and in the fall or in the
winter you know when the crops come down
but he knows out here mulching yeah
right on so it's a really good cover if
you can get your hands on it you know
somebody use it right on so those are
the 304s autof flowers behind us y so so
um Dan doesn't really as far as I'm
aware of uh breed photo periods all that
much anymore no I only use them for new
source of genetics to make uh you know
to bring in new lines so these photo
these photo periods this is all your
head stash right yeah yeah right on so
majority of it yeah so so clearly the
autof flowers are well ahead of the
photo periods which I'll tuck in some
photos here um why don't you tell us um
uh about uh you know plug plug the
people who you respect that you're
growing their photo periods this year
yeah so you know I've got like most
Growers and most people in the Cannabis
industry I have a freezer full of seeds
and I had some stuff that I collected
from years of people who I looked up to
as well as I have watched um their
breeding practices and stuff over the
years and you know I didn't want some of
these seeds to go to the wayte and I
picked a couple of them that just you
know W newer and some that I've had from
years go um ital Foundation from
California and then dead pan head from
Oregon I think he's in Oregon that's
what I come to understand but I've got
some of their cultivars out here this
year and I was looking to go old school
I would like there's a lot of indicia
influence out here og3 uh white gas
there's triangle Kush M10 and then the
Platinum p so nice little mix and some
stuff to play with uh to bring in new
you know genetics into the Auto World so
I get both the head stash and then the
auto males and the pollen donors are
gone way before it becomes a danger to
the photo periods in here some of the
pre- flowers got pollinated and that's
just enough for me to take a look at the
seed if the photo period comes out to
something I like which I got to give
credit to one and it's the TK M10 cross
the um the Platinum PI from itall from
itall yeah it is way ahead of the group
there's two side by side as you can see
and I'm sure he'll have pictures for you
guys to see here later um you can tell
that they they look nothing alike the
only reason you know they're from the
the same you know group of seeds is cuz
they're labeled but that one is stand
out it is it's amazing it's way ahead
it's going to I would say what would you
maybe two weeks left on that plant maybe
three and that was no light depth just
you know L natural something I was
looking for out of what two four six but
however many are in the row yeah and
living here in the Pacific Northwest
we're always looking for anything that's
a fast flower 100% it also makes my life
easy as an auto breeder too yeah yeah
right right so cool so we've talked
about your Autoflower this year the
three for and your photo periods for
your head stash and photo period
explanation or exploration um let's talk
about this freaking tomato plant here um
so so so I know that these are just two
tomato plants cuz I brought them to you
from Vashon Island correct how the hell
did this monstrosity happen um that
monstrosity is a direct result of an
above ground hoole bed mhm uh so
basically like the same thing that's
buried behind us but in 100 gallon
country line Farm tank drill the bottom
out logs layers and leaf mulch and you
know um have you been taken um uh fruit
off of it yet oh yeah we've had fruit
out of it um I think it's gotten too
shaded now it's been uh kind of slowed
down on the fruit production but
everything starting to finally ripen up
which is nice but it's loaded there's
pounds of tomatoes Z inside there right
yeah it really took off this year and
it's same treatment you know worm
castings tea um and some foler another
thing that's looking good even though
it's in your first year is is um your
strawberries um I remember when you sent
me the picture of the box that you had
made and you were all like baked and was
late and you were all like like look
what I made dude and so um it looks
really good thank you yeah and so it
looks like we're at the end of your
strawberry season but it looks like you
got a hell a lot yeah I was really
impressed you know I mean as you can see
you know behind you there or in front of
you here we've got the three pots that
the donors came from but they did turn
around really well and started producing
I expect by next next summer it'll be
really nice it was kind of A Midsummer
thing trying to get these thinned out
and trying to kind of get my corn SL
Berry Patch going kind of another you
know new area to play in yeah and the
berries like since it's their first year
it's not all grown in you've got gaps so
they can they can expand and stuff so by
next year it'll be all full oh that'll
be crazy back in there with berries that
year it'll be really nice yeah um you
know not a lot of people grow corn in
the Pacific Northwest where we live
because the summer like this summer is
hella short and it doesn't doesn't get
hot nope and um and I know last year uh
you grew corn and um all you grew was a
bunch of swearing yeah pretty much but
then but then this year you've been
given corn to like all your neighbors
and everything so so so a like you know
why did you decide to bother with corn
in the Pacific Northwest when it was
probably going to be a fail and and um
what did you do different this year
versus last year that you're actually
getting like buttloads of corn yeah um
so the corn thing is Nostalgia for me my
grandfather used to grow yards and yards
and yards of corn we always grew yards
of corn we always love it it's a great
summertime treat the boy absolutely just
smashes it um so that was the area of
the old greenhouse and that soil was
worked initially because it was sand I
was growing in ground back then you know
new experimentation trying to figure out
the ground so I was like I don't want to
really waste this there's nothing really
going on here I was like corn would be a
good idea so the first year with all the
swearing was learning my phenotypes you
know I bought several different
varieties from the local Ace Hardware
and
one out of the group produced a couple
ears the rest were nothing but
ornamental for Halloween yeah there you
go this year however uh one of the
things that impacted me last year too
was crowding I got too excited and
didn't thin enough um but this year the
cultivar that did produced the couple
ears we had last year produced in
numbers and I wish I could give you the
name but I can't remember it but I did
find it today's hardware and it's a 65
day cultivar so with our [ __ ] weather I
applied the same knowledge to Auto
flowers and growing cannabis here if it
has a short flowering period maybe we'll
actually get something and it worked out
fantastic uh this is actually heirloom
this year it was saved from the corn
from last year that actually made it
since I didn't need it I figured [ __ ] it
save it yeah yeah so but it did great
this year we saved a few more ears and
I'm just going keep it going so when I
showed up and after I said all my like
holy crap comments because this Garden
is so it's so much larger than last year
not like number of plants but but each
plant is so much bigger and um you know
we grow a lot of the same things
especially since we're friends and and I
get your seeds right but your stuff is
so much bigger than it's ever been and
one of the things that you
do
um excuse me guys sorry about that there
there's a road nearby yeah so um one of
the things that you do is um uh you run
lines to water right yeah and um you
know I'm a big fan of hand watering so
that I can you know adjust the water for
different plants but I got to tell you
I'm getting closer and closer to the
idea of installing water lines because
this just shows the magic of consistent
small amounts of watering so when I
water the plant is the the pot is all
super wet and then it gets all hella dry
and then it gets wet and then it gets
dry and and um and you know it would
probably be better if I was doing a
little bit every day right but but you
know I'm working to I tend to do like
every other day right and that kind of
makes the the the case even more that I
should have some kind of drip irrigation
going so um why don't we just take a
second and just like plug drip
irrigation as a theme uh drip as a theme
do it just plain and simple with the
wood mulch and the consistent watering
my plants are bigger than they ever have
been and I'm saving water that's the
other big thing that I think people are
missing I'm literally saving water these
lines don't run all the time I have have
it I mean I come out here to look when I
do the compost te's obviously I'm
looking at it and I can see if the top
layer is starting to dry back but it
doesn't dry back because I have
everything on timers everything comes in
and if you want good consistent yields
with healthy plants across the board I
mean you can see here I mean even the
hle bed has spray heads that consistent
top layer again it comes back to what I
said earlier if those roots can use that
top fraction of that soil that's a
fraction area they're able to pour more
fruit from if you can protect it and
keep that alive I think that's why
you're seeing what we're see in here
today yeah I've just had a really just
like put all that this is what you're
seeing is what I'm practicing like it's
a direct result of what I'm saying right
here just that consistent watering and a
mulch around so um the last thing I want
to finish up with is just um you know I
have seen your Gardens now many years in
a row correct and and every year they
get better um what have you learned from
this year that you already know that you
want to incorporate next year and as
something new learned something new
learned definitely needs some more air
flow uh definitely need more you've
already got fans all over the place
still not enough eh still not enough uh
there's microclimates in here still um
like I'll see tiny little pockets of PM
where I don't see it anywhere else and
that frustrates me like I don't I know
it's like unavoidable to keep it outside
of and I'm not you know we're not going
to live in a powdery Miler free zone
here yeah it's ignorant to think about
but I've got a pretty good grip on where
the microclimates are in here but I
still would like to improve air flow um
I think would be the next thing um I'm
definitely going to switch some of the
irrigation heads the like we were
talking about earlier when we move these
pots the drip irrigation that had the
the laser cut holes in them you can work
them into the soil you can layer them
all the way down and it keeps that
moisture even throughout that pot low
and consistent that way they always have
that source of water I think that's
something I'm definitely going to
improve cuz I kind of hbri it if you
look down through here and maybe you can
grab some shot you'll see some that have
heads in the top some that I've come
back through and retrofitted with the
actual buried lines and the buried lines
plants are definitely I think they're
more robust if I'm looking down through
here to be honest I got to agree too so
but yeah right cool man that's and then
um one thing that I learned from last
year that I want they Incorporated this
year that was a success I think is
important to talk about was being um
prophylactic with my mites I had a very
bad M issue last year for some reason
this side of this where I'm at over here
the two spot loves to thrive and got in
early with californicus and stayed
consistent monthly with it and it really
kicked their rear in I'm really
impressed with the californ Smite yep I
I don't have any thrips this year like I
had one leaf I found earlier and then my
two spot has been nil I found two leavs
I think through all my scouting and as
you can see I prune heavily and yeah
they're definitely a beast to have in
the garden right on yeah cool dude well
uh I know this was unexpected so thank
you for taking some time and sitting
down with us and giving us this very
intimate uh tour of your uh this year's
Garden thanks a lot man absolutely dude
I'm glad to have you here you know um
it's always a pleasure to have you in
here I'd like to show you this stuff so
right on cool right on everybody thanks
for being here take care this is Dan
Jimmy from gome automatics and Shango
from shaping Fire have a great day have
a great
day cool
good I think it went well I do too good
yep