I tell you who I am and what I do I want
to leave why it went so when I was hurt
my dad was 18 years old he was the first
person in his family to go to college
and he took a quarter out of college in
order to to the court about college
letter to paper can't afford anyone and
that quarter you got droplets Vietnam he
came back from Vietnam to totally change
me
if you fast-forward 30 years I was 22
when I figured out that that room in the
basement with the lights and the plants
in it what he was doing let me tell you
in tomatoes 12 years later David for
Veterans Day in 2014 we've just taken
down our first to go harvest of
marijuana so when you under it and when
you ask why I do what I do and where I
get the energy to graze multiple round
in and run a business and be the
president of cannabis clients I do this
every day for my death they do this
every day for the veterans we can't get
access to medicine that we know works
for them and help make their bites
better I do this for the mothers and
fathers those children are suffering the
terminally ill diseases or miss grant
hands are suffering and they can you get
access that we know it works and they do
this for us wives and the mothers and
daughters whose husbands and brothers
and fathers are sitting in jail Prasanna
plant two people who wanted to buy it
it's time to raise their consciousness
to stop this insanity
[Applause]
so my name is Daniele results and I am
serving my second term as a
democratically elected president for the
cannabis wine you guys including in this
position not really sure why I'd like to
think it's because mercurial optimism
and charming good looks and I think it's
much much deeper I think that I had s
and it's because of my comprehension as
an industry as a business owner and it
being part of this industry since long
before was legal I think it's my vision
of how we collectively want community to
a poem and I think it's my empathy for
all parties involved willing and
unwilling the no identities and their
feelings just as important as ours good
listener or good leaders we listen to
all sides of the point we empower people
to work with issues that are important
to them and to bring multiple
perspectives to the table so that we
compound and find a solution that works
for everybody and they see many policy
makers or regulatory regulators in this
room knows that there are a whole lot of
opinions beside the cannabis industry
and it would make your hands jobs a
whole lot easier if we could all come to
agreement and find common ground before
we showed up
phone calls emails and that's exactly
what the cannabis alliance does the
campus life is made of producers
processors retailers labs transport
companies
we're also made up of other associations
patience empathy is ancillary businesses
whether to employees and simmers
computers turn their control us we read
appliance or advocating the betterment
of everyone a socially conscious
industry the cares about employee wages
the cares about our communities patient
access with portal of health care the
environment as well as our bottom lines
I feel really silly to business person
to my marketing expert would kill me if
I didn't mention that I've also we are
lazy to use your processor in Bellingham
Washington
the produces pesticide-free
medical-grade award-winning cannabis
using 100% LED technology and water
reclamation systems to give you an idea
that we do give you an idea what that
means we use 50% less power consumption
and normal indoor grills that use a GPS
and which is approximately enough to
power 150 homes per year in our current
situation we went using 550 gallons of
water at age 14 which the you mentioned
my husband team up today the water
equation system we didn't make these
choices to save money it's not
we made these choices because it's the
right thing to do it is the greatest
good and those morals of values that
drive our decisions and our business
practices of trailblaze and are exactly
the same morals and values that ivory
Canada's Alliance and our board members
share it's been an honor and a privilege
to volunteer with us lands I know you
obviously you guys have no interest in
starting an industry in every
Association this new every regulatory
procedure is new its total chaos I mean
and the Jinni floor is really daunting
but the people who make up the members
of Canada's alliance by title ways their
startup companies and their family
obligations to invest in the greater
good they have a vision of where they
thought the cannabis industry to go and
they have tactics about how to get there
they might not know it all right there
in their heads but they're surrounded by
the people that are also offering ideas
bouncing off each other
so that we can actually get to what we
know cannabis industry is capable of
doing the members of the Canada
industries will fight or not just what
is good for their bottom line but it was
what is fair and good for all of us
which is a really stellar lead-up to our
opening speaker if you want to talk up
fighting for what's best for all of us
not just
[Music]
if you want to talk about someone who's
dedicated to what miss Meera from All
Humans not just those who share that
doesnõt mutual benefits our openings
because it does just that he doesn't
just talk the talk and feel that way but
he takes me action to support that
stance he's you know the time is the
time together is committed to protecting
our natural resources something that
everybody who lives in specific
questions treasures probably a little
bit more tremors he is committed to
protecting our civil rights is committed
to protecting our state rights which in
this headache means the right to legal
adults in medical using enemas before I
tell you are nobody speak there isn't a
she didn't know we have two fantastic
sponsors that brought me here today
canis basics
[Applause]
like any normal
that are proud of team up as the
sponsors for watching the Attorney
General the bathroom since keynote
speaker
Candace visits the washington-based
company topicals manufacturer
established in 1995 focusing on the
whole plant extraction and the
synergistic relationship between
cannabinoids terpenoids and other
mechanical constituents and even is
terpenoid is fine or anywhere candidates
with a staple that both retail space
going back to the early nineties the
Washington Medical Marijuana space and
they literally kicked the doors open to
the mainstream market place for cannabis
topicals and Washington cannabis is a
law teaching force in Washington State
defining Canada's health and beauty aids
giving her the term and removing these
types of products that Washington state
controlled seven faster removing these
products Washington City built such as
an actor to the first Google anything
cannabis out of any state people to
notice time canvas nation founder all
corner is an active number of community
and the guiding force normal women
[Applause]
Washington's the normal limit of
Washington of our marvelous group of
women dedicated to ending marijuana
prohibition and promoting civil justice
normal women are committed to elevating
women's voices in our democracy through
outreach education and community they
live the change they want to see in the
world please join our booth Washington
as legislative sessions of difference in
support of home grow so it's fun yes and
employment productions yeah
[Music]
and now without further ado I'd like to
introduce our amazing keynote speaker
Washington state attorney general Bob
Ferguson
[Applause]
Bob Ferguson is a fourth generation
Washingtonian he is a champion of civil
rights a tireless defender of democracy
and in his memory public service under
his leadership in the last year alone in
the Washington attorney general's office
successfully sued President Trump and
successfully triumphs nificant a steamer
technique pieces
[Applause]
with the whole world watching Bob
Ferguson consistently stands up from
Washington's legal and moral right to
regulate cannabis and to take a new
approach to the failed war on drugs in
fact no other Attorney General has done
more challenge and a stand up to US
Attorney General Sessions and is stowed
certainly alts and flawed positions on
campus we thank you for your courage for
your commitment and for your service
we're proud to have you today the
Attorney General's Office and every
record I'd like to get a walk
[Applause]