hey there everybody well microphone
really gets it going doesn't it yeah
yeah it's like right on the edge of even
needing it
so thanks for small to David and Keira
for introducing me or for you know
animates me for inviting me to come to
speak with you today I'm Sheng colos I
am the host of the shaping fire podcast
I'm also the founder of the bash on
Island Marijuana entrepreneurs Alliance
we work on - one Island to find new
channels for product for our medical
growers which is now wrapped up but the
the organization's still exist as an
educational organization I'm also a
former brand strategist and then CEO of
Green Line farms and I'm a longtime
canvas business consultant for both
medical and 502 so the point of the talk
today is going to be to suggest a
strategy that you can use to find a job
in cannabis that is not the same
strategy that everybody else is using
one thing that that works in life but
also especially works well when looking
for a job is find out what everybody
else is doing and then do something else
because everybody else is doing that one
strategy and so whatever sex success
there is to be had from that strategy is
probably going to be taken advantage of
by somebody else so simply because of
the numbers so we're gonna start in a
really kind of an odd place we're going
to start with are you sure you want a
job in cannabis and obviously if you're
here you're pretty sure that you do but
we're going to go through this because
part of the idea of it talk today is
that we're going to leverage your
passion for working in cannabis to get a
job and so by going through this quick
little exercise will
right alright so so first of all um if
you really want to work in canvas
because you've got to be passionate
about it because when it comes right
down to it working in cannabis is
working at a start-up and working at
startups is really hard it's not like a
normal job where you you know you can
punch in and punch out you know when
you're gonna get paid you've got some
stability we don't have any of that in
the cannabis industry yet and and you
know we have to be after 18 years we
never had that in medical ever either
and so you know you can probably expect
a good five to ten years before we get
anything that looks close to stability
so let's talk for a second about the
downsides or the challenges of working
at a startup you know you need to be the
kind of person who's going to be down
but I'm working on unexpected duties if
you're the kind of person who's like
well you know that's not my department
you know working at a start-up might not
be for you because you are going to
essentially be an employee in every
department you know you might be a
grower but some days you might need to
do packaging you might be a packager but
some days they might need you to file
stuff at HR you might be an HR person
and you might end up doing deliveries
now if you're the kind of person who's
going to be all I don't know what I do
well you know startups might not be for
you because you've got to be willing to
wear a lot of hats um also
if you live so close to the bone that if
you get paid a couple days late you may
want to have awarenesses around that too
because so many
5:02 folk are also running so close to
the bone that I see constantly folks are
you know one day three days a week late
simply because their cash flow is such a
drag now if you're gonna get a job at a
highly funded company and they even have
an HR person and you know the late of
that definitely goes down but more often
than not the 502 companies are doing
everything they can on a shoestring and
making their capital go as far as it can
and if they just made a big purchase so
that they can process it into product
they may not they may end up a roll the
dice and lost and they're like we don't
have payroll for like five days and you
know as an employee you need to be
willing to suck it up a little bit now I
don't mean let let your company take
advantage of you because you know we are
all our own company right and we need to
defend our own you know rights in the
world but at the same time there is such
thing as taking one for the team and and
you know having your pay will be a
little late is something that happens at
startups all the time so you need to
have like little emotional flexibility
on that and then of course there is the
hours right you know there's a lot of
variety of the kinds of jobs in Canada
there's there's hourly jobs and those
are pretty much you do your hours you
get paid for menu
but you know if you get a salary
position you need to understand that
there's a certain amount of that that is
open-ended you are paid salary for as
many hours as you're needed now granted
you may decide that the agreement that
you made with your employer is not
something that you're okay with anymore
and so you decide to leave because
they're asking 60 hours for 40 hours pay
which makes your hourly wage atrocious
right um but there's something to be
said for sweat equity right you know
when I started The Bachelor Island
Maryland entrepreneurs Alliance I wasn't
getting paid at all and actually I never
got paid for it but it was because I put
in the time to make it happen that I
learned connections and got the
networking done so that then I could
launch the rest of my consulting career
and podcast and all this other cool
stuff that's happening now similarly if
you're getting a job at a startup you
know
expecting to only work 40 hours is
probably a little unrealistic you know
50 is probably a little more realistic
and if you're the kind of person who's
like you know it's five I got plans I
have no pull some tubes I have to go you
know that's not really the kind of
startup mentality I'm getting is because
almost everybody in the industry does
but but the idea that you've got
somewhere better to be is the part that
I'm talking about and if you've got if
you go into it wit like I only want to
do my own job and I got somewhere else
to be it startups might not be the thing
for you so um also you need to be aware
that working and working in cannabis has
got some challenges for example being
judged by other people you know a lot of
people who are working in chemists they
have to deal with you know what their
aunt said or what their grandparents say
especially if you're hoping to get some
inheritance and I see this all the time
where people have got challenges they're
like oh man cannabis is my passion but
my family is like getting down on me or
maybe you need to get an apartment right
and you're applying for a new partner
and they look at your job and they're
like oh I don't know this company what
is this in your life Canada's industry
they're like no we don't want you to
find around here well they might want to
say that they just wouldn't call you
back right but that happens or how about
going to apply for a car and they find
out that your incomes from the cannabis
industry and they don't want to go fill
the cannabis money you know to pay off
your karma this stuff happens I mean
those of us who are cannabis business
owners we're still having a hard time
finding banks that will take our money
anyway so we can pay you your payroll
right so these kinds of challenges are
all doubled down as far as being a
start-up that's in cannabis and then
finally there is risk involved you know
cannabis companies go down all the time
and it is it's it's messy it is
high-risk the regulations are changing
there's moratoriums that suddenly make
your company illegal and the county that
you're in it is an exceptionally high
risk to job and and and sometimes they
don't even have to close sometimes all
they have to do is just reorganize they
can reorganize and decide you know what
when we fired for this we hired nine
people and you know we think we can do
it up for the three people and that
means that frees up six salaries to do
other things and now we're going to go
hire a bigger sales name you can be on
the low Internet and so these are the
challenges notices you need to be
prepared for now if you're if you heard
all that you're like yeah I can make all
that happen well then we get to talk
about the upsides right because we're
you mean cannabis is awesome and I am
very lucky to have you know lived in a
time where when I worked in the dot-com
boom they said you know oh we all have
these once-in-a-lifetime jobs and now I
get to twice in a lifetime we work right
because I've got two brand new
industries so if you can handle all that
risk we were just talking about well
number one you get paid to work legally
with weed which is awesome right it's
the kind of stuff that we used to like
joke about hi in college value someday
man and then like now we're living
someday and that's really cool and and
so also you know being involved in a
brand new industry it's it's too late
the ends exciting and you are
participating in building something that
has an system before and because of that
you get to put your mark on an industry
you can help make the rules and it's not
very often that you get to participate
in industry where you will be able to
play a role in making the rules and then
it up self is cool on the outside of
your compensation package also there is
a certain advantage if you're the kind
of person who likes to be on edge to be
able to work in something that's taboo
right I mean I I like it when I tell
people what I do for a living and you
can kind of see you know you know the
people who don't immediately like ask me
for a job are the other folks are going
kind of a little gas you know and and
that's cool because because I like to
you know I'd like to get that reaction a
little bit you know
being brought up with a bit less maybe
causes that so
but also there's other really important
things like thank asked upward mobility
there is no other industry right now
where you can move up in the ranks
faster than cannabis you know I've
already seen people who started a year
and a half ago is a budtender they did a
really good job suddenly now they were
like the supervising budtender and then
they moved into the operations manager
and they are opening closing the store
and then they got poked by another
company to to help run operations and
the processing facility and now they've
got you know a real salary and and
they're like okay well do I want to stay
here in Washington or do I want to go to
be hope go where I'm being posed to come
to in the matter right furthermore um it
happens fast the the talent pool is tiny
tiny right now and so once you get your
foot in the door if you're doing a good
job you can expect a quick leave up
early mobile position um also it means
that you can switch companies pretty
easily you know there is kind of a you
know a certain amount of glass ceiling
being a budtender because there's only
so many so they're only so high to go in
retail right but but there's so much
reform asmath where people who are
already working in the industry that if
you have done a good job in a bunt
header you understand the 502 rules if
you've proven that you've got management
skills it's very easy for you to jump to
another company and and and be able to
move through you know a you know but
tender glass ceiling that way and so
there's there's a lot of this linear
mobility between companies and you know
managers are used to it you know it's
not like other industries where they're
all I've added you're leaving those
other company you're just gonna leave us
well yeah I'm probably gonna do that but
you might get two years out of me and
you need me and I need you so let's
dance you know it's a different scene
and so you know to a certain degree
working in cannabis is like musical
chairs where we're you know folks who
are attending this event they're coming
in and then their musical up and then up
again and then and then you know the
folks who come to an event like this in
a year they're gonna come in because
we're all new we're all new and that
allows for a lot more flexibility and
honestly negotiation in your
compensation package too and then
finally I touched on this a moment but
the skills you learn here in Washington
can be worth mad
in another state in a very short period
of time you know we are very lucky that
we are in Washington because we can get
our start here before all the other
states are have even gotten out of the
gate and so it is not uncommon now for
me to see people who started their gig
in Washington they they were huge into
learning about their job they studied
every aspect of it they stayed after
they ask questions they took positions
of management and and they learned jobs
that weren't theirs and so they got a
reputation for being good at it well now
they're being headhunted by a company in
Ohio or Florida or Arkansas or you know
wherever and and you know run by
recently got pending on it now suddenly
he's in Chicago right he's in Chicago
and he's building out five extraction
facilities and they treat him like a
rock star and you know he is a rock star
you know he's got mad skills but you
know when he started he was just an
extractor that people respected in
Washington right and now you know there
are there's national news stories about
his badass company in Chicago that can
be you we are still in the early days of
this industry where if you get started
now you can earn your stripes in
Washington and then go to another state
you know where your family lives or
where you like the weather better or you
just want to explore because maybe you
were going to do grew up in Washington
so anyway with that
know we're all very firmly established
the fact that we're all passionate about
being a cannabis and want to do this so
here's the formula that I have used my
entire life I actually learned this from
my folks growing up and I've used it in
all sorts of industries and it works
really really well in cannabis so so
here we go and this is the part of
you're taking notes you're gonna wanna
take notes on so what's the best tactic
to find the way to the job you want
choose the company that you want to work
for don't wait for them to post a job
you know it's important for you to
answer the ads when people are asking
because that's low-hanging fruit but
that ad that you're responding to
thousands of other people are very
likely responding to that ad as well
because the company's step and said
we're looking for folks I get this
deluge of resumes but now you're just in
with everybody else and you're not
really all that special and it makes it
harder to get the job makes it harder to
keep your job because they we got them
from an open call we can you know get
somebody just like them again doing the
same thing and when it comes time to let
people go unless you've really made
yourself look impressive to the company
you'll be one of the first people to get
rid of it because you were easy you know
and and we see that time and time again
that being able to stay at a company a
long time and you can start that with
day one and how you find them
so flip the script flip the script by
choosing the company that you want and
the job and you're interested and then
going after it very literally start by
making a list of ten companies in
cannabis that you want to work for that
you feel high about that you think
they're cool maybe their brand maybe
their product maybe the kind of
extraction technique they work on maybe
that they respect their employees maybe
they're into a diverse environment
whatever
that you feel is attracting you to that
company make a list of ten of those
companies and I don't need to make a
list of three companies or you make a
list of seven and then you kind of run
out of gas no go through and push and
find ten companies to target because the
secret is in the numbers right the more
people you contact the better you're
increasing the likelihood that you're
going to find a job now if what I said
you know
think about the companies that you want
to work with based on what they do right
if you're like I don't know what these
companies do or I don't know why I like
these companies well then you haven't
done your homework yet you need to do
more homework these companies want to
hire somebody who already has an
awareness of the industry now you don't
have to come from cannabis but you have
to at least understand the differences
between the companies you know find out
who the people are behind the company
where they do business read their
website so so you aren't developing your
tastes in a company that you want to
work for so that you can tell them why
you want to be there
so after you've got this list of 10
companies do your homework very
specifically about those 10 companies
think of each one of them as a target I
always recommend finding out who the
visionary is at the company find out who
that principal is because they're all
gonna have one they're gonna have the
person who had the idea and put it
together and decided that we're gonna
make this happen and it's those those
people
it's those people who will be most
responsive to the resume that you're
gonna send them that says I am
passionate or how you chose to do things
and if you're if you're passionate about
how you chose to do things um you're
already getting your foot in the door
because they're excited the visionary
could be like oh he loves or she loves
the decision that I made myself to to
run my company this way and so so that's
that's a warming a point for you so so
then you know after you've done this
research you've got your ten jobs our
ten companies that you want to work for
and you know who the visionary is now
you want to write your cover letter
because you know we're assuming that you
already have your professional
experiences page right now and if you
need help with writing a resume you know
the good folks at Veridian staffing are
the people to talk to that's not really
what we're talking about today but
you're going to write a cover letter
that is unique for each individual
company now they can have the same spine
they can be similar but you don't want
to take the same one and just go you
know ten times send it out you want to
write that resume the cover letter that
says why you think their company is
badass why you want to work for them and
what you think that you can add that
goes along with what you respect about
them if you're an extractor talk about
what you like about their extraction why
you hold it in esteem and what you think
you can add to their team if you are an
awesome administrator middle manager
tell them why you like how their company
is run or their brand or or even their
product line that you just think they've
got great pre-rolls whatever it is that
you love about that company write that
in a letter and you know sometimes when
we write cover letters we write them in
such a way so we sound my business e you
know you like clean up your language and
stuff you want to do that to a certain
degree but when you're writing a
passionate cover letter speak from your
heart you know you don't need to use
that business narrative language all the
time because if you think about it the
person who's reading it they are in
cannabis they started their company
because they're jazzed by again let them
hear some of your excitement don't be
shy about it don't don't get rid of the
Jazz enos in your writing voice just to
sound more professional because honestly
there aren't a lot of professional folks
in cannabis and that's really not a
standard that that a lot of people are
going by you know we want you to you
know you know shut up the work on time
we want you to know how to interact with
your other employees and we want to be
able to do your job really well but a
level of professionalism is not
something that is really you know a big
demand in the industry just yet and use
that to your advantage so
one thing that I learned today
from Kara from Veridian staffing during
her introduction for the for the folks
that are here today
she mentioned don't put in your cover
letters that you're a patient and you
know what that makes a lot of sense you
know back when Washington only had
medical cannabis it was important that
we've all heard our cover letters that
were a patient we get patients needs we
want to be involved in taking care of
your patients that was that was the [ __ ]
but now that now that medical has gone
away if you put in your cover letter
that you are a patient and so you
identify with the needs you're putting
the employer in an uncomfortable
position because you're coming up
against all sorts of laws that make them
not be able to tell you know because you
may be sick
jekko all right so um so you want to not
mention that you are sick and that
you're using cannabis or some way that's
that's your own business and it's better
for the employer to not know that
because you know they're concerned with
people what if we bring them in for an
interview and and they own the interview
and then we say no and then they come
back to us with a suit saying hats
because I got you know whatever you may
have they would just won't call you
because they don't want to even play
with that that risk of a lawsuit so so
don't mention your patient if you are
alright so um
after you have attached this fabulous
cover letter that you've written with
passion about the things that you like
about the company because you've
targeted this company and you've done
your homework now you send it to them
and this is the part that people kind of
roll their eyes about because we are
talking about redundancy here you want
to make sure that you try to get that
letter in the hands of the decision
makers any way you can so first and most
obvious you're going to put it in an
envelope and you're going to send it to
the principal the visionary the person
who started the company so that they
receive it with their mail and they open
it that is the most reliable way we have
to get it in their hands right you're
going to do that same thing but you're
going to send it attention HR and if you
can figure out who the HR person is if
they even have one you know more power
to you right you know you could even
call them up and say hand HR person okay
thanks juice you know and then and then
write it down and same thing now you do
it because you've done your
reconnaissance
so now you've sent them two letters
right you've send one to the principal
once one to the HR herself oh but they
may not like paper right and so now you
want that same thing via email so if you
can find the emails of the principal
that's right - it's amazing how many
principals have got their emails public
because they spoke at some events or or
they're on they're on an email list
that's that's online or who knows so
search them out search out their name
and the word email and see if you can
find it easily that way similarly if you
can when you're on your phones you know
kind of sneakily calling them you can
ask for the HR person's email address
and they they will likely not give it to
you they'll say oh please submit your
resume via our website thank you and but
you know maybe maybe you got somebody
covering for the receptionist whose it
was actually usually well enjoyed - my
god and her not her addresses boom
you're like thank you you know take
advantage with the chaos in the system
to your own advantage right and so and
so so now so now you said you've sent
this for different ways or two ways you
know you've sent it to be a mail you
send it via the internet to two
different people and now you're gonna
drop it off in person so most of these
you know they may not have facilities
that you can tour or get into but most
of them have got a front door that you
can open and startle the hell out of
everybody and they got walk-in traffic
and so it'll print it up on a decent
printer put it in the envelope and
and drop it off I always suggest putting
the visionaries name on it again I
probably wouldn't drop off - not one for
the visionary and one for HR just just
put the visionaries name on it because
chances are their reception it's going
to open it anyway but now now you know
that who you made sure you delivered it
themselves know some of the pushback I
get from folks about this is that you
know every dungeon see is going to annoy
them right because if you're successful
they've now gotten five communications
from you that you want a job from them
yeah in this many than this amount of
the time that might work against you but
number one chances are they're not going
to get all five communications from you
they're either going to not see the
emails or it's going to come the mail
and end up on somebody's desk and
forgotten or you know they're gonna get
the one that you handed them at the
front door and then take it with them to
lunch and then it's gonna get lost in
their car chances are they're not going
to get you're not going to successfully
ping them five times you know maybe
we'll see two of them maybe they'll see
three of them but you are only in the
game if they see your resume and then
sometimes you know they say you know uh
Moran doesn't really sit with you until
you've encountered it three times and
then maybe we'll make a purchase same
goes for getting a job the first time
the visionary sees your your resume they
may not even read it and the second time
they're like man is person is insistent
and then the third time they actually
read it is a damn good cover letter you
know I can feel their passion let's look
at their work experience yeah man this
works so this person likes my company
they like what I did with it and they
seem like your passion and they'd be
like a hammer on the office common for
our interviews right that's what we're
that is the goal of what trying to get
that interview and and the way you can
do that best is by doing everything you
can to get the resume in the
decision-makers hands and that's that's
what we're talking about here
then finally I suggest following calling
in a week and asking to talk to the
principal of engineering the HR person
and see if you can get something live on
the phone you know you're you're calling
the follow up to make sure they got your
resume and you know you know damn well
they did because you sent it five
different ways but this creates an
opportunity for them to save you oh yeah
we did get it that was pretty great I
was supposed to call you instead of an
interview I'm so glad you called me you
are making that person's job easier and
that's what we want to do we want to do
everything we can to make their job so
easy to hire us
so really your job is to get your resume
in the hands of the decision-maker and
you know that makes it it gives you kind
of a whole different thing than oh my
job is to get a job well yeah that is
but you need to break that out your job
is to target 10:00 do your homework send
it to them redundant ly and follow up
and make that opportunity where they ask
you to come in for the interview I'm
assuming that your passion and your
interest and your skill set is going to
shine when you're in an interview but
but you need to get to that point first
so so you know when you are done you
will have ten really great resumes with
awesome and passion cover letters in the
ends of ten different companies and I'll
tell you something you are going to be
ahead of everybody who's not in this
room right nobody's doing this no people
you know even in this room there's a lot
of folks we're going to hear the
strategy and then not do it because they
just they don't have the fire to do it
right but but if you do it you will be
in the you know top two or three percent
of people who are looking for a job in
canvas and that's that's really all you
need is you need to have something that
the other people are not doing and the
strategy is it so why does this work so
well
so having a plan on how you are going to
get a job is more than just anybody else
has got to having this plan working the
plan working it through to the end
is is you implementing your own secret
to success and you know when when you're
sitting there in the interview and
you're talking to the HR person or to
the principal and they're all like
smiling because they got three copies of
your resume and they read your letter
and they're like man you really targeted
us you know you're here because we read
the thing and you're thinking yourself I
knew there were nine other companies
typically we're not going to talk about
that but what they're seeing they're
seeing your excitement that you you can
get things done that you've got the
follow-through you've got passion you've
got you know a plan you're gonna make an
awesome employee you know that
interviews will already have done they
just want to make sure that you're not
like a serial or at that and and so good
luck with that part
so so yeah I want to also say you yeah
go ahead and apply for the other jobs
that people are applying for it too
right because I'm not a big fan of you
know keeping all of one's eggs in a
single bicycle I know you know apply for
the jobs where they are listed in order
listed and on monster.com or craigslist
or whatever but that's not really where
you want to spend the most of your time
you want to do this kind of a plan where
you are being assertive and you're going
after the job you want right because
like the jobs that are listed on
Craigslist those are the jobs that are
available and you're like well I guess I
could take it to get my foot in the door
and you might need to take a job to get
your foot in the door anyway but how
much cooler is it to go to a company
that you already want to work for and
apply for a job that you want to do
instead of just taking you know the
low-hanging fruit of what's on
Craigslist and well you know I guess I
could do that like the aim higher and
then and then if you get a lower job you
know be grateful for that gig and then
and they get that experience and start
you know maybe another couple and then
do this
so there are so many jobs that are not
advertised people don't realize that the
majority of the jobs are not advertised
um so here are some examples so no one
has time to write or post the job
listing oh my god this is so common
they're all startups you know there's
probably not a dedicated HR person no
one likes hiring staff except maybe me
and and so when you are when you are
taking the initiative you have solved
the challenge they have of no one
wanting to write the damn map they also
have they have a job post at summer but
you have not seen it right so so maybe
you're looking at all the common places
but you know whoever is doing the thing
they're using their brother-in-law's you
know employment website that none of us
have heard of right now well we got the
job post we're not sure why we haven't
gotten any resumes in yet and and so so
suddenly they get yours in and they're
like oh yeah you know we cover one of
theirs let's interview them right and so
there's that possibility
um they aren't about to let someone go
this happens all the time you talk to
502 owners they all got that one
employee that they're like you know I
would love to get rid of them but I
don't have time to write the ad and and
they just don't have the there's not
ready to let them go but they wouldn't
really like to it's like give me a
reason to let them go you know and
sometimes it's because they like you'll
break something severe or something I
don't know I got my reason but maybe the
reason could just be that you showed up
and so you are causing the impetus to
create room for yourself
so maybe they have an employee they
don't like but they've not decided to
let them go yet and they haven't really
thought about letting the go but they
just don't like them and you think your
resume that says I like you I like your
company I'm badass of what you need to
hire me for let's do this and they're
like oh you know what I didn't like this
other employee but I didn't realize that
there was an alternative until you gave
them the alternative you're creating
these opportunities that didn't exist
before for them to hire you
also they need help but they've not
really thought about hiring somebody
well you know they've got their tight
team of five people this is how they've
done it for the last eight months and
they've been working their butts off but
it never really occurred to them well
you know you could make your life a lot
easier if you hired another person and
you know a lot of these companies don't
actually have you know a lot of budget
to hire another person but you know the
the amount of cannabis being sold is
going up and up every month these
companies that have not been in the
black are now starting to get in the
black and maybe it hadn't occurred to
them you know what maybe we should hire
somebody and maybe they don't have an ad
out but when they read your cover letter
they're like well I think it's time to
hire somebody
and then my favorite is the last one and
this is how I've gotten the majority of
my jobs in my life and definitely all
the kick-ass jobs I've got it's that you
win the visionary gets their hands on
your resume they read it and they're
like hell yes this person gets me they
get the company they get what we want to
do I'm gonna make a job for them and
it's you know I think it's probably
having eight or nine times in my life it
happens all the time and then after you
know I've always asked to speak to my
friends kids about this this strategy
and I hear back from that was like oh
you know so so
snowboarding company they weren't even
hiring but then when they got my resume
that said they don't have a snowboarder
and I love their company and I've been
to you know competitions and I've rooted
for their teams and like they asked me
for interview they made a job for me I
mean I'm delivering mail but I'm in at
Burton or wherever right you know this
could be you the idea of being able to
happen reach the visionary who can very
literally with a yeah yeah bring them in
for an interview create a job for you
there's a lot of power in reaching that
person and it happens all of the time so
two four six so there's there's six
different ways that a job could exist
for you that is not advertised and the
companies hire you doesn't even know
they need you yet this is why the
strategy works
so your odds are also way up because no
one else is applying for a job this way
and chances are they may not even be
getting very many resumes because a lot
of folks take the take the low road
on to the Craigslist jobs and you know
they send those they'll come to
something like this because I hope I can
I can get up and go and be there for a
few hours on Sunday but not a lot of
people are putting in the effort to
target companies and go to the kind of
work that we're talking about doing and
honestly you know the strategy of time
but this is not a lot of work right you
can do most of this in an afternoon you
just have to like stay focused and not
let yourself get distracted and you know
stay sober enough to do it and and you
know the time commitment is not a lot
what it is it's it's the hard commitment
that's a lot and that's why I'm talking
about getting a job in cannabis with
your passion today right this is not
this is not luck this is you activating
your passion to get something done
because you've got clear intent and that
clear intent will come through your
cover letter and it will just explode
all over the floor in your interview and
you'll have a job
so Canada's jobs are a game of odds you
know by by targeting the companies that
you want versus taking the ones that are
applying you are increasing your odds of
getting a job by writing your great
cover letter you're increasing your odds
and then by being redundant and getting
to them you're increasing your odds and
and they're if you were serious about
doing this increasing your odds and
decreasing your risk is what how you
want to play this game and and you're
going to be the only person in the room
doing that for them
so I mean I've seen this work time and
time again both for myself and for
people that I work with and for folks
that I consult for and it's really
amazing because that now I know so many
people who who own cannabis businesses
and and so many the visionaries they
feel like people
don't hear them they think they don't
understand their vision anymore and
they're all stuck with the day-to-day
operations BS stuff and they're not
getting the necessarily do all of the
the passionate stuff that they kind of
envision at the beginning because in the
end you know the fantasy working in
cannabis or the fantasy of starting a
job in cannabis is very much unlike
going to work every day especially if
it's everyday you know if you've heard
of the visionary you're working seven
days a week and to have your resume come
in where you are speaking the secret
language of why what they're doing is
cool people respond to that in a very
serious way
so that's the strategy I suggest that
you do each step do it today do not put
this off and
follow through because just sending them
the resume may not be enough without you
following up a call
so I've got a little bit extra time so
I'll take like three questions if
anybody's got some questions
right now that's a really good point so
Dave says what if there are not and
Animas companies within your area to
commute and you know when I talk about
this in other industries what I
recommend people do is you take a you
take a map and you kind of draw an
outline of where you're willing to
commute and then you find companies
within that area that you think are cool
now now that works a lot easier when
it's not just one industry if you've got
more flexibility in your industry but
since we're talking about only cannabis
what Dave's talking about is is correct
especially if you live in a county with
a moratorium right so in that case so
today saying that there's there's only
for cannabis companies that are close
enough to commute to and I would say
just write them even better for those
for you know it's hard to what you can
you know if they don't exist yet you
can't write to them but you know as part
of doing the R&amp;D to get the job you know
watch for new companies to you know you
can you can see the the landscape usage
boards that go up before they set up
shop you know and you know write to them
before they even exist as a company well
you're right you know the fact that the
canvas companies are not evenly
distributed around the state means that
anybody in you know King County
generally is in a way better position
that somebody who's like way north you
know we're the Canadian border
who the visionaries are by going to your
local box floor and where do you buy
yeah there's a there's a lot of creative
ways to find out who the visionary is
you know you can you can find out who
they are by you know looking at
interviews that they may have done in
don't magazine or Northwest leave Google
their name look at their you know search
the company name and a LinkedIn right
you could even call that same
receptionist that gave you the HR
person's email address maybe the year
you can say oh you know I'm calling what
what's the name of the person who
founded the company and they'll probably
give it to you pretty easily so just
just be you know a little little
creative about it it's not really hard a
lot of most of these visionaries you
know I've got a nice dose of ego but you
need to run a company and because of
that they're usually somewhere you know
out and about talking about how badass
their company is anyway
my best advice for somebody who wants to
start their own cannabis company is to
do something that does not require a
license
the hardest companies to run are the
ones that are licensed by the state
it's like what is they
correct because you don't you know you
need to get certified by the state but
you don't necessarily have to be to get
a license the hoops that you have to go
through to obtain your processor license
or your growers license or god help you
a retail store and and just to have you
know where you live I have a moratorium
the regulations are so ugly in
Washington and the opportunities are so
rich in quarterly industries you know
maybe you're going to invent like the
new super cool bomb or you're you're
going you know you want to do a
lifestyle brand and put out clothes or
you've got you know like the heavy
weights like who knew there was an Indus
and wicks right but there's a couple
really great companies that are making
money net I mean
invent something really cool that
dabbers are gonna love right you know
dampers have got so much discretionary
income to be able to buy the things of
their passion they will buy your Google
invention and so so similarly with
services right maybe maybe you are an
accountant at REI or like a bookkeeper
at REI and like you love your you know
you love a REI and stuff but you want to
do something a little more edgy well
maybe you start a service firm that
specializes in catering to the cannabis
industry and now suddenly you know
you're the you're the first person that
does your specialty for only cannabis
clients right and maybe you're doing
that while we were still working in
Ariane you're doing this you know one
day a week person so so that that would
be my best recommendation is to find
something that you're excited about that
you are willing to sell and to try to
stay out of anything that requires the
license at this point one more question
yes
at this time
report what's appropriate at that stage
right on let's let's answer that
question a couple ways so she's asking
about what happens if you have your
interview and then they say no thanks so
the first thing would be if you really
want that company apply again in six
months and you know you know three
months is a little bit on the fast side
um they might decide that you're in your
attend and you don't really want that
but definitely six months I mean all
these companies they radically change
every couple months so it's six months
you know the person in HR who
interviewed you may not even be there
anymore right and so and their needs and
maybe they just got another round of
financing so now they can hire a lot
more people so so that's number one go
back to the same company that you're all
juiced about in six months but more to
your question wait what is the specific
part of your question
so do that Oh IRA and then the second
part is go look for a job at a different
company don't sweat right because except
for maybe where Dave lives where there's
only four companies there's lots of
cannabis companies where we're generally
like you were in the Seattle land area
right and so so just you know don't
don't get too bummed out and I mean I
certainly have got like two or three
brands in the state that I think are
super cool and then I was looking for a
job I would go there and if they told me
no I'd be like crestfallen but the game
is not to only be able to get a job with
solstice right the game is to get a job
in Canada's period so if you interview
with the super cool cool and they're not
ready for you it doesn't mean that
you're a bad person or you're not ever
going to be able to work with them it
means it's not the right fit right now
so go back to them in six months and in
the meantime the shift of somebody else
on your list so if you are into this
kind of idea you can find out more the
kind of stuff like this by listening my
podcast shaping fire you can get on that
list at shaving fire comm and also you
can
through my website at Shango glows calm
and I think that's it I'm gonna be
around for a while oh let me plug some
other things that are going on here
today as well at 2 o'clock we're gonna
have a panel right here with some live
cannabis business owners and we're going
to talk about their preferences we're
going to talk to somebody who is hiring
for sales somebody who's hiring as a
processor of a serial job applicant and
and we've got we have a visionary here
we're in the flesh to kind of you know
confirm what I've been saying to you and
then also if you are the kind of person
who wants to attach a headshot we
actually have got somebody taking and
shots for 25 bucks so you know hopefully
you dressed appropriately today and
you've got your smile on so anyway I'm
around if you want to talk to me thanks
for joining
[Applause]