hey there good morning everybody welcome
to the 10:30 presentation by Jodi bukas
on hem the new frontier I am Chiklis
host of the shaping fire podcast if you
like listening to smart interviews with
the top minds in cannabis I invite you
to check out shaping fire and shaping
fire calm we also have a killer YouTube
channel with over 150 videos that I
recorded events just like this one in
fact we've got a great video with our
next speaker joni bukas on designing
efficient cultivation operations so you
can check all that out at Chapin fire
calm gestures for shaping fire on
YouTube Jodie Lucas has been on the
forefront of highly efficient state of
the art canvas groves facilities for the
last nine years Jodie has design built
and retrofitted well over a million
square feet of some of the biggest
licensed producers in the world today
you're going to be in a treat as he
presents his new talk today he'll be
presenting hemp the new frontier les
Europe for Joanie locust you're too
generous so yes my name is Jodie bukas
smart oak roses company that I founded
about five or six years ago brief
description of what we do as you were
just told do a lot of design builds of
green house as well as indoor we do have
some touch points on outdoor I'm
specifically going into the hemp
industry from the last couple of years
now but our primary focus over the last
decade has been building high efficient
groves we work with companies such as
canopy growth a war up we've done some
consulting for tilray a lot of stuff in
the US but those our biggest clients and
we worked on multiple
comments to date as well South America
we're doing some land development
projects as well as Australia Plus move
forward into him the new frontier now I
know hemp has been around for a long
time in the title of the talk new
frontiers really regards to the
explosion of the CBD market you know him
goes back thousands and thousands of
years longer than we even know and you
know we know that industrial hemp has
been in the game for a very very long
time
which is slowly sucking ramp up more in
the US markets and thankfully now that
we have the farm bill that's gonna allow
us to really push into that OCD and for
fiber hemp now what I've seen in the
market the last couple years that since
we've been involved doing consulting and
said enough farms I myself do have some
farmland down in southern Colorado
we're running outs some variations of
variation greenhouses doing a lot of
data capture over the last couple of
years over the plans to scale
tremendously were getting ready to
launch a farm in southern Texas about
2000 acres looking at about another two
or three thousand acres there's a lot of
people looking from the campus space
getting into him there's some challenges
with that now some of you if you do come
from the cannabis space you know that so
the last ten years 12 years as we pushed
into of regulatory environments there
was a lot of you know ramping up and
learning curves to understand growing
commercially from growing in your closet
your basement garage etc now that we've
kind of seen some of that markets
stabilized a little bit across the US
market
you know now we're in a second boom of
health and CVD now the US market is
starting to lead the CBD markets on the
planet so to speak although there are
some countries that have been doing CBD
you know for quite some time and we know
that some of that has been being
imported into the US market for reasons
of lack of availability of the market
and consistency in the market but
pushing it from campus into hemp is a
little different it's a little
challenging you know nutrition is a
little different we're growing outdoor
that's different so there's a lot of
variables mixed into that so it's it's
not a long one if you're coming from
cannabis commercial cultivation to get
into hip now it does put some people
ahead of the curve because we have an
understanding of the plane itself is
it's not a standard crop does have some
special requirements you know nutrition
being a big big one water which we'll
get a little bit more into later but
this crossover can't put some people a
little ahead of the curve
you know I myself in using you know what
we've learned over the last decade in a
regulatory commercial environments and
we're applying that into the hip market
now fortunately pimp is going to be a
little less restrictive although
currently the FDA is meeting to work on
regulations with the USDA we do have
some insights of what is going on in
those regulations we work with a couple
scientists that have been asked to be on
the advisory board for legislation which
does help us get an understanding when
we actually go into solar clients to say
hey this is how things are moving this
is what's actually being written down
these are the things that they're
looking at
now total was a little bit more base on
that we know that big pharma his
lobbying heavily in heart against the
CBD market we saw this happen two years
ago when there was a major pullback from
the FDA on hemp companies that were
putting up products in the market and
they were labeled improperly and I don't
know if you interviewed been paying
attention to what's going on in the news
or what's going on in the business
industry on the head side but it wiped
out six or seven of the largest and
companies two years ago shut them down
so we know the big pharma is against it
but we know they are waiting on the
sidelines waiting for regulations be put
in place so they can also step in I mean
you've got company inside the Amazon
they released a products I believe about
three or four months ago CES is coming
to the marketplace Walgreens you know
and they tread very lightly and some of
these come with a very conservative like
CVS but they're stepping into it because
they know that it's going to be a very
big industry but without the regulations
of place everyone's still being very
cautious so something that has to be
paid attention to but I think it's not
going to be as tight of a loopholes you
know that we see in cannabis especially
on the value about product side that's
where you're gonna see a lot of the
strangleholds being put in place
let's jump forward a little bit you know
getting into any new industry cannabis
was a tough one moving targets
you know hemp is as well there's there
are some fundamentals that's you need to
be aware of and he needs to be educated
before you to say hey let's grab some
seeds and less throw in the ground or
get some starters get some clones
because if you do that you're gonna find
yourself in a world of pain
research is massive when it comes to
getting involved in the industry you
need to know what you're looking at
everything from the farm operator even
if you're just trying to get some dirt
for yourself outside of an operating
farm now there's some advantages to
working with farms because you know
there's traditional farms that five six
seven generations that have been around
for a long time some of these you know
these people are struggling and it's sad
to see in him can also be a big help to
turn some of these farms around and save
big AG as we see it today once you are
able to do some research and you know
you find yourself a farm or find some
dirt to work with you want to create a
strategy and strategy is a multiple in
multiple levels to that everything from
business plan compliance how are you
going to distribute how are even a
process who's going to process are you
going to do it where you going to do
that
you know you have to put a plan in place
and be able to follow that plan and push
through I mean this is a business just
like anything else you know what there's
a lot of money to be made and that's
without a doubt but there's a lot of
risk as well and research and educating
yourself it's gonna be the best way to
pay attention to risk assessment because
anytime you start a business you have to
pay attention on both sides there's a
profitability and there's risk and we
always want to try to slide that scale
on the risk assessment side as low as
possible especially if you're using your
own money or for even more so if you're
raising money and capital to invest into
your business the compliance I know
we're a little you know we're a little
kind of the great area with that
specifically States more more states are
coming online for example Texas just
passed their hemp bill even though it is
federally legal not all states I've
gotten on board with what hims gonna
look like for them so that is one thing
you need to pay attention to contact the
agricultural department
you know there's several divisions
within state government as well as local
municipalities that are gonna want to
weigh in or they're gonna have some
comments to make so go and ask these
people are very helpful in most cases
that we've been in quite a few states
where it was an open door sit down I
mean we were just in California and
Sonoma and Sonoma County they were very
very helpful and very open about what
their position was and they were willing
to help to make sure that you were going
to be set up properly
so take the time find out what's going
on where you want to grow business plane
is a big deal I've seen a lot of
businesses try to start a business with
that one they don't have to be you know
next-level you don't have to have an MBA
from Harvard / a genius in the business
world to put a business plan together
do some research if you don't know
what's entailed in business plans but
these are going to help steer you in the
right direction from a business
perspective you know there's two sides
of the business those operations and
there's business we always recommend or
myself specifically recommends if you
know the cultivation side don't try to
learn the business side if you don't
know much about it
get someone involved it's worth the time
it's worth the effort because at the end
of the day the operations can do what it
can to its best ability if you don't
have a good financial plane and a
business model that you're gonna be in
the world pain it's for that question so
let's move on to the better parts of
hemp the cultivation now you know most
of these crops are grown outdoors so you
know a lot of people think you just drop
some seeds in the ground you're good to
go
I actually I get a lot of calls I spoke
with a woman the other day she was told
oh yeah we're gonna drive by 40 acres it
was a pre-existing farm they were
growing corn you know there's some
structures on site there's barns some
silos no equipment no irrigation shears
think no if there's water rights and
she's told you can you just go and get
some genetics and drop them in the
ground and you're good to go
so I started asking questions first
question well how much capital do you
oh I have about $200,000 I said well man
what are you gonna do $200,000
have you done any research whatsoever oh
no my friend told me that it's it's it's
easy I guess get some seeds put him in
the ground he said do you know which
seeds costs you have any concept of
labor who's going to take care of the
plants how are you gonna feed them how
you're gonna water them how they're
gonna be trimmed how you're gonna
harvest them and then she had no idea
none but just because people are telling
her hey this is easy it doesn't take
much so there's all these different
components that are involved in it and
yet one thing we always like to do is we
look at weather studies is one of our
first components you know you want to
take a look at the last 10 15 years
Colorado for example has impossible hail
storms especially down south or anything
that's close to little to the range
mountain ranges you can access this
information pretty much online but these
are things you want to pay attention to
you know temperature spikes over a
10-year period how hot is it getting was
the hottest point was the driest point
humidity rain levels you want to be
prepared and weather is a big component
yes you're growing outside a lot of
people do it farming as is an outside
you know agricultural application you
know but temp is a little different than
other crops you know the farm that we're
working with like said fit generation
immigrant watermelon pumpkins and
cabbage
well they do water applications a little
bit different than we require for him
they're watering 12 to every 12 to 13
days and won't survive that the
gentleman ran him for the last four
years and he was not even able to
pound per plant even planting by May
fifteenth reason why water so weather
and having knowledge of of what's going
on this is a big part you know soil
water those two are major components and
growing these plants too much water too
little water there was too little so it
started happening as the grouse arts dry
now then it's cracking the cracks then
expose the roots next thing you know the
plants shut down or die
I mean little they will dry from the
roots up into the plant so a soil water
you know these two components itself are
bigger than most people think you need
to know what's in the soil you need to
know what's in the water a lot of these
farms and a lot of applications coming
from water Asian they're coming from
wells and wells could be very high in
iron iron will kill at your plants
without question also we've seen arsenic
as well in well water as you know to go
along with iron you know so there are
some things you need to be aware of and
understand what's in the soil and the
water because those are two biggest
components outside of the weather
weather we have no control over soil and
the water you do so you need to take
samples you need to understand what's in
there then you can actually build a
strategic nutrition application for your
plants and your harvest and your crops
you know nutrition is a big one we've
come across a lot of hemp farms that
we've seen general applications of you
know everything from Simplot CSI you
know some of the just the major
manufacturers of
new nutrition or fertilizers for other
crops you know you know for vegetables
fruits what have you not to say they
don't work but there's no micronutrients
there's no calcium supplementation
there's some certain things or specific
things that are missing and yes NPK can
get you there but NDK is not going to
increase CBD levels spike and increase
yields especially if it's not given in
the right doses you know so general
farming you know these guys are great at
what they do in those crops but again
you know hemp has special requirements
sure he could get away with it but you
know what do the research because if you
put a proper program together you're
gonna see better yields and you'll see
higher CBD levels what we're seeing
outdoor on the top of the chart is
depending on genetics is anywhere from
14 to 16 percent on CBD levels now
depending on how that gets processed
after harvest dried those conditions
they can drop that cb2 level by anywhere
from four to five percent so next thing
you know you're harvesting at fifteen
fourteen by the time you get it for a
processor to come and look at it or to
sell it we already done the ten percent
so all these things matter and how you
you're doing it because the higher the
CBD and percentage the more valuable the
crop is and right now what we're seeing
is there's a lot of pillaging going on
there's you know for example Colorado
doesn't have a lot of processing that so
we've got guys coming from other states
and blocking everybody on the head and
beat them down for the biomass kind of
to the degree of you know what will buy
for twenty five dollars a pound
by us or you don't sell it and it's
unfortunate because people work hard
guys are putting on very long days and
then you got guys strong are mean
because they can't get rid of it
so you know having the highest EP Global
Content that you can is also very
important which kind of falls back and
starts flowing into the genetic aspect
between nutrition with your soil and
water again like I'm saying it will
increase your CVD levels ultimately if
you start building greenhouses which is
something we're starting to do for a
different type of supply chain you're
gonna go year-round and you're going to
see higher CBD levels because you're
able to control the environment a whole
lot more than just going outside we seen
greenhouse
hit numbers as high as 20 to 23 percent
but again you know the capital venture
there's is a bit more costly but you can
harvest five times a year and in a
single structure of depending on how you
set up your harvesting genetics genetics
is a big component in this hemp game so
to speak there's a lot of people
claiming feminized genetics but
unfortunately what's being sold at
market it's not feminized these guys are
breeding or trying to breed feminized
genetics outside can't do that but we
never happened
there will be cross-contamination
so currently as we see right now we know
about seven or eight major lawsuits for
hundreds of millions of dollars because
they were buying genetics that were
being labeled as feminized and then they
kicked out out of the fact as part of
their defense there's no such thing as
truly feminized genetics there's a four
to seven percent chance of man's that
study that's actually in the marketplace
has been published was also attached to
a case study that was done of breeding
feminized seeds outside so that in
itself the problematic so there's
companies that have bought and spent
millions of dollars on seeds have spent
more money on actual their farms and
getting things set up and then their
crops got pollinated and they've lost
millions and millions of dollars this
goes back to research
researching what you're getting and
especially in the genetic side is
extremely important because you don't
want to be caught in that situation
where you get well you know almost at
the end and you're not even realizing
you there's you know crops of him called
name next thing you know you're looking
in September and you go wait a second
why am I seeing seeds something that you
just need to be aware of there's some
great genetics in the market something
fantastic genetics but you have to be
aware of what you're buying there's some
guys that have been selling industrial
hemp that's CBD and guys have run them
out makes they know they're getting 2%
3% CBD also lawsuits happening so so
going back to the first comment I was
making research you know know what
you're getting you know what you're
looking at ask talk to people you know a
lot of people are very open about you
and what they're doing to a degree of
well where you're getting your genetics
from oh well we get it from h.t.t.h
seeds or we're getting it from blossom
seeds you know pay attention and know
what you're buying and get most of the
time if it sounds too good to be true it
is most of the time I can tell you right
now the average cost of a quote
feminized seed is about a dollar in the
marketplace we're going to see that
shift because the seed industry is a
booming opportunity in the market as
well because there's not enough genetics
and people are scrambling to try to get
them to market or get them to you know
operators but there's people that are
jumping in that bandwagon and they're
they're throwing a lot of nonsense and
fake things into the mix I think we will
see that price on genetics start to
slide down within the next two to three
years that makes three to five years is
going to be interesting to see because
even though there's a lot of people
getting involved right now
last year we saw probably about 60% crop
failures and what happened even here in
Oregon Morgan struggled because of early
rains and early and high humidity levels
so there was a lot of you know botrytis
of Bruce areum a lot of blood mold that
was happening to get larger yields here
in Oregon but that becomes a problem if
there's too much humidity so there was a
lot of crop failures here as well but
getting back to the genetic side of
things the you know there several
options or seeds
there's clones there starters you know
the starters aren't gonna always
guarantee you even if they're common
feminized as well they're not guaranteed
to be feminized you know so what we've
suggested is you know tour clients that
have bought some of these starters
they're gonna have to walk through all
their crops and eyeball every single
plant to make sure they're not gonna get
a meal and you better know what you're
looking at because if you skip past one
or two I mean it could wipe out a fair
amount of your crop pollen goes very far
and then it doesn't take much to push it
not a lot of breeze will get it where it
needs to go
clones that's another marketplace that
we're seeing pop up a lot last year or
going into this season clothes are great
but you need to know you know what
you're dealing with when it comes to
generational cuttings you know how old
are the mothers where do they come from
how are they being taken care of I mean
there's a lot of components with that as
well so it's you have to again you have
to educate yourself and know what you're
dealing with and if you're going to go
buy clothes go to the farm and look
because one of the biggest problems I've
seen with farms offering or nurseries
offer evening explodes as the mothers
are root bound and I'll tell you a
little thing about group down mothers
they will cut production down by 50 to
75 percent and that's a fact
we've seen this in the cannabis space
those mothers are sitting in containers
too long they're they're gonna get
stressed and the offspring are gonna
give you literally 50 to 75% unless a
video that they should and I've seen
this myself a lot seven or eight years
ago at my own facility back in Colorado
the crew wasn't changing mothers and
Tommy fashion and I'd like to rotate
them every two to three months depending
on how many cuttings were taking we ran
on a harvest and I mean I'd walk past
the room and I looked in and I go what
are we growing in here and it was dark
star dark stars a large yield er very
much cuter and I looked in the room and
it was learning look like oh gee look
like golf ball-sized nuts and when we
waited out it was on a seventy percent
lower from that harvest to the prior
because
others will move out so educate yourself
research to know what you're buying
you know IPM pressures are a big deal in
outdoor you get into green door you can
control a bit more naturally indoors
where it's gonna be your best option
but also know what your pressures are
know what other farms are growing around
you know what the wind patterns are like
know if it is an outdoor farm how they
sprain and who's spring because that's
all aerial application so these are the
things that need to pay attention to as
well because you don't want to be too
close to a farm or downwind and they're
coming in they're spraying you know
traditional cross which they could
pretty much spray whatever they want you
know including Eagle 20 so you have to
be aware of applications of fungicides
pesticides surrounding you then the
other portion is the pressures as far as
pest
you know how in patterns is someone
growing grapes upstream from you because
you know grapes have a large tendency to
produce a lot of powdery mildew as well
as other problems but if you're in a
wind pattern that come it's going to be
pushed your way how are you gonna deal
with that you know anybody - pest
management is a very big deal as well
you know bug control you know there's a
lot of ways that you can handle that
with outdoor crops but again it all
circles back to research understanding
educating what you're getting yourself
into
if you're able to spend some time and do
your due diligence I mean and honestly
due diligence should take you a couple
months to three months on average is
what we've seen to get a good idea of
where you want to grow what you want to
grow how you want to grow it the
marketplace genetics and all these
components I mean you'll be in a good
then a much better spot to be successful
you know and and the reward is gonna be
great at least for the next three four
or five years you know because you know
supply and the US market is is not
consistent and it's all over the map
last year Revlon a colleague of mine
brokered a deal for 250,000 kilos for
one purchase with Revlon just one
company they wiped out 60 or 70 percent
of what was available in the US market
so now imagine when you got companies
like the Amazons coming in and the CVS's
and adult food companies all these other
companies are wanting to get into the
industry and they're researching you
know value products right now the supply
is is at the bottom wrong compared to
the demand so there's a lot of a lot of
room to get in now and set up and get
through the next few years before you
see a major you know pushback in the
market or we'll start to see that price
volatility start to hit it might be
longer but just what I've seen and
traveling across the country and you
know talking to new farms coming online
it seems to be reasonable you know three
or four years is a good time to get in
you just have to be smart
and if you do it right and execute
that's the other thing you have to
execute it's a lot of hard work it is
there's there's no way around it there's
no fast solution to make money but if
you do it right I mean you're gonna look
anywhere from you know 40,000 per acre
on the low side up to 120 130 thousand
dollars as it grows those are real
numbers we see them all the time so you
know my job here is to give you guys an
education on what I've learned what I've
seen and give you enough for you to stop
if you're ready to jump in you know be
able to ask some questions
at least adjust where you're going and
maybe steer your ship a little bit
different so that you're going to be
successful because that's the reason for
all these seminars is for everyone to be
successful and that's about a look at
great do we have some questions
thank you very much when you were saying
the indoor CVD was getting twenty to
twenty three percent what was at TVC
numbers they were still point zero three
or less told to you cleared the whole
told th da TCA so so test result based
on federal and you know mandates yeah
now the touch base will not a little bit
more and maybe I'm giving up a little
too much of my business manager probably
would agree sometimes I'm just you know
mr. talkie you know there are ways to
monitor your crops and testing early and
this is something that we did on
cannabis about five or six years ago
maybe actually about six or seven years
ago we started harvesting or taking
cuttings from plants and getting them
tested prior to maturity dates and what
we started discovering was and I don't
quite a few genetics you know CB
profiles and THC cannabis were higher
three weeks out from maturity or harvest
and that has it got closer the TC rose
and the Kevin Waits drops so one thing
that we've started doing last season
it's the same kind of thing even on
outdoor crops and greenhouses as well
you can start taking samples and see
what your profiles look like because
there is a point that they're gonna be
at their widest and then they're gonna
start to close and change so you know
physiological aspect of the plan changes
as it was closed for maturity so doesn't
make sense yeah I thought they were more
in relationship with the entire
I realize they are came together yeah I
mean they they do they shift and every
Jeanette's a little different you know
there's a lot of similarities you know a
greenhouse you're gonna see a higher
level and the reason beams because it's
consistent if you're getting the same
amount of par value every day because
you can control that it's if your light
DEP being in the wintertime you know
you're removing a lot of the variables
you have no control over by going into
greenhouse and the great thing about
greenhouses too is when it comes with
processing it's a lot faster to get
processed because there's no dust
there's no dirt there's no bugs or it's
clean so that stuff if you process a lot
faster into the degree of the processing
facility I can do 15 or 20 thousand
thousand pounds a day can hit the top
into that market or the top of number if
it's greenhouse product if it's outdoor
depend on location it might hit ten
because there comes a point in time
they're gonna have to stop clean break
down clean break down so there are some
advantages
big advantages to the greenhouse but
that's why you're gonna see the higher
CBD numbers okay how much did interested
to use you know we do a lot of cherry
wine as you know what we like just
because the dynamic range it has the HD
one is something else for you know we
use a lot of but you know in this day
and day and age it's really gonna be
about endgame you know and and what you
want to offer to the market you know we
have some guys are pushing more CBN or
CBG genetics so again it's this is part
of the research is you know where do you
want to be in that column you know that
cog in the wheel where do you where do
you want to find your niche and you know
when you educate yourself and have an
understanding of that and seeing what's
there and what's missing you fill those
gaps because then it gives you a better
chance of being successful
hi Jodi thank you for the presentation
yeah you made a reference point to hemp
and industrial and agate I made
commercial greenhouse researcher and
most of my effort is aimed at helping
small to medium size operations in
hydroponic food edible crop production
okay so could you speak a bit to the
potential of him is that something that
we're aiming towards the big growers and
it's the traditional cannabis crop that
small and medium-sized operations should
focus on so you know hemp as a whole and
see if it's going to go across the board
to industrial hemp so you know CBD is
exploding right now naturally but what
we're also seeing is a large increase
and just even fiber hemp being grown as
well but this is all very large-scale
and even on the greenhouse side you know
we're working on North Carolina right
now we're doing about five acres of
green house for CBD other projects that
we're talking to potential clients
that's small I mean we have some clients
are talking three four hundred acres of
glass for him but CBD specifically for
medical applications cannabis seems like
it's going to be on the smaller side
because there's a lot of regulations
around it's very restrictive I mean
we've done some very large projects and
Leamington Canada for example we did a
thirty five acre conversion from bell
peppers to strawberries to all cannabis
very unique situation but we rarely see
large greenhouse application
or canvas we're seeing acres you know
handfuls but not hundred thirty fifty
not very often and I don't that answered
your question at all but no no no this
is a group in North Carolina is actually
based out of New York yeah um I was
wondering if you could tell me about
what you are spending per square foot on
your greenhouses about you know where
does that live and then also could you
speak to the strains that have CBN as
well as CBD Kent burg and curious about
that
you know start it's the genetics you'll
have to top my head I actually and I
don't have it in front of me so my
laptop and this is not mine but there's
a list and maybe I can give you my
contact information I have a list of the
king amount of Kentucky specifically of
you know approved genetics so to speak
from a federal perspective and that
gives some of those ranges and it's it's
a very long list I think there's like 50
or 60 at this point it's it's it's
pretty big and I think it does classify
you know a broad CBD or CBN Sakichi so
maybe that's something I can get some
information to you about greenhouses
that's that's kind of a moving target or
I even call a loaded question because
it's really about you know what you're
trying to do I mean there's so many
variations of glazing alone you know
whatever
from plastic poly the polycarbonate
acrylic glass all those things affect
price whether you're gonna pour pad or
you're just gonna do gravel I mean so it
could range anywhere from you know $40
$50 a square foot on the very low end
which would probably give you like sheet
metal citing you know very basic
greenhouse you know all the way up to
120 130 dollars a square foot you don't
actually get to the higher end we're
talking you know full light depth glass
concrete you know doing underground as
well and mechanical systems you know co2
generation some applications if it's
possible that demographic geothermal
there's a lot of components with that
but you know the higher in greenhouses
you know we're gonna give you a a lot
more control very close to end or not
the same but it still gonna give you a
very close you know one first one just
about so to speak
hi Jodi hi you mentioned briefly about
Canada what do you think of the can come
to the market and would you say we have
to just stick with industrial or CBD or
indoor or outdoor um when it comes to
him we're talking about him specifically
Canada is still kind of trying to find
itself in the cannabis market and there
are some companies that are dabbling on
the hand side for sure you know there
was just so Acronis just released there
you know did a report on they're
dropping 300 million dollars into the
hemp industry but in the US market the
problem of Canada is where it's located
in the hemisphere it's hard to run a lot
of outdoor crops because they just don't
have enough summer you don't like
Edmonton for example we're doing a large
indoor project there they have three
months of summer that's it the rest of
it is it's you know coming in out of the
cold or going into the cold so you know
the hip there are some hemp farms but
it's going to be challenging for them
because they just don't have the weather
for it now they didn't build the
greenhouses and they could do just fine
and then then it comes out to a play of
capital how much capital they have to
spend you know circling back to your
last question
you know industrial hemp versus CBD
there's avenues for both you know the
both are exciting you know I mean the
industrial hemp is exciting just the
fact of you know we can get rid of the
plastics we can get rid of all these
things that are killing our planet you
know a hip in itself can you know
if you've if anyone sent research like
Chernobyl right now they're working on
trying to start remediating the
radiation and and has that ability to
clean land so you know there's a lot of
exciting things and there's there's
passive both I mean there's ways to
travel down both and make money
I mean without question it really boils
down to you know what do you want to do
you know what interests you you know
what do you feel passionate about that's
always for me the best route to take if
I'm extremely passionate about this and
not that I'm always gonna go down the
path that it's something that excites me
so I mean maybe that's a good way for
you to take a look at it hopefully
that's helpful to finish off Jodi I've
got a question myself what form of CVD
are you encouraging your clients to have
produced on the end right on one side
you've got people producing CBD isolate
which the genetics may be more available
because you're not looking for the as
large of a terpene profile but ISIL it
doesn't have the scientific health
support but people are still buying
crazy to put it in everything and on the
other side you've got people we're
having a finished product that is going
to be a full spectrum or full inch
spectrum oil with medical applications
and people generally are like a little
grossed CBD but that end product is
really important so what do you
recommend for folks yeah again you need
to figure out what your endgame is going
to be you know if you like from my
perspective ultimately what I want to do
is be a supplier and I want to be able
to supply medical grade CBD I want us to
be able to supply CBD that's available
for valium at products like lotions and
cream
and you know that's what stuff it's
really about what are you where do you
want to be you know I mean it's still so
wide open and yes on the the US market
right now it's becoming you know a huge
thing that people are looking and
throwing hundreds of millions of dollars
at like cannabis was seven eight years
ago right but it's just really you got
to make that decision and it's hard to
say I mean it most of the clients that
we talked to they already have in their
mind what they want to do and you know
an isolate is generally what we're
seeing seventy to eighty percent of the
market going towards it's like you know
what we and a lot of guys we just want
to do biomass we want to grow it we
don't have someone pick it up and then
they process it that's all we want to do
and that's that's a great model I mean
it's simple you know and keeps it easy
for from a business perspective but you
know I think ants I can't speak for
people you know clients generally
already have an idea or a concept well
thank you very much let's hear it for
Joanie Lucas thank you
[Applause]