tonight's demo is from Jeff Church also
known globally as Canada's Reverend Jeff
has mastered every modern extraction
technique and most of the ancient ones
he has travelled the world to both learn
exotic techniques as well as spread
modern techniques from the United States
he is a longtime patient advocate from
way back he has been in the front of the
laws helping humans get relieved since
the very early days here in Washington
Jeff is presently an extractor and hash
maker at 5:02 processor puffin farms and
he continues to consult everywhere Jeff
is absolutely one of my mentors but even
more so I'm really honored to call my
friend please welcome Jeff
[Applause]
it's awesome to see such a huge crowd
here and just just amazing so tonight
we've got ethanol hash oil along the
topic so you know a lot of you guys call
it at the moment a soil of people color
full extract canvas involve eco re so
there's a lot of different names but
basically what it boils down to is the
best method for the extraction and
that's ethanol and so that's why I
prefer to call it ethanol Nashville
rather than becasue person oil Rick
Simpson is great guy definitely helped a
lot of people find this oil but it has
nothing to do a bit at this point you
know and so that's where I've drawn a
little bit so tonight we'll make ethanol
our bull I'll describe how to make
ethanol hot dog it's a flammable solvent
so we're not going to actually perform
the extraction here tonight so basically
there's there's a few different things
Vico a lot of people refer to that as a
full extract cannabis oil right so it's
a full plant you take every part of the
plant some people even the rinse of the
plant and they take that and they do an
ethanol extraction on it and you know a
lot of people do a warm long soak so 24
hours or longer from some people and you
end up with a really green extract
that's full of every constituent that's
in the plant and so for a lot of people
that is the medicine that's what they
want that's what they're after
for me personally I just really love I
love extracting the resin of the flame
you know I'm not as into all of the
other constituents that are in the
plants
you know like chlorophyll I'm not really
interested in having that in something
that I smoke you know so so I'm more
into this quick kind of cold extraction
method so basically you've got feet oh
you've got quick watch quick watch is
kind of like a way to make a really nice
hash oil at home without having to use
butane you know you can do promise and
process is a great method as well to
make that show but if you want to use a
solvent you can take isopropyl alcohol
is what people used to use and I don't
recommend that anymore
but they have a quick iso method quizzo
is what people would call it and you can
do the same thing with ethanol with 95%
ethanol and do a quick extraction and
get something that's going to be nice
for smoking it's not gonna have much of
the green in there at all but you know
that's that's one one thing that people
do with it so people do this whole full
extracts canvas oil that's really
everything that's in the plant extracted
into the oil or you can do weight on the
other end this really quick wash that's
just going to get the resin heads of the
plant it's not going to contain it
everything else there's also along the
souks on flour as you can do any number
of things under the Sun you know with
ethanol which makes it a really
versatile and really easy to kind of
common in what process you want to based
on what your final product is going to
be what your final product is that you
desire so what you need to make ethanol
hash oil at home it's really simple you
need some ethanol and so this right here
is Everclear it's 95% alcohol you need a
beating
cannabis of course per you need a jar to
do the extraction you need a coffee
filter for doing a filtration
form of you know a press really works
well so this is a Taylor racer you don't
handle this right in there and press out
the last bits of the ethanol and you
need somewhere to store it you know a a
syringe works really well for ethanol
it's nice for dosing you can kind of see
where what amount you're actually using
and then a method of clicking the
ethanol off and a method of D carbonate
so for cooking the ethanol off what
we've gone to is a race paper and so the
rice cooker really is that perfect tool
for home you can run an extension cord
outside because none of this should ever
be done inside when you're cooking on
solvents in it but very interesting you
guys are gonna forget to have your house
if you do it and eventually it's let's
play pull the butane extraction in in
your kitchen but still it's not
something that you want to do so you can
run your extension cord out you can set
this thing up and the beauty about the
rice cooker is you're not gonna scorch
your oil because it's gonna turn off
before it's done you know this this is
meant to boil water so it's going to get
quite hot you know possibly up to 300
degrees but when it's got a it's got a
sensor in there
though they'll tell that the temperature
is spiked and they'll shut it off so the
switch gets thrown so so what what I go
for what I'm doing and ethanol
extraction at home is I really want just
beautiful golden picture and so you guys
can come and see this later so this is
what I made at home just in preparation
for this class so so what I like to do
is freeze the material and the ethanol
overnight so I like the deep freezer
this is colder than my you know freezer
that I've got with all the rest of my
food at home the deep freezer gets that
ethanol to that perfect temperature
where you definitely still pour it it's
not syrup Gerrits it's not like really
slushy you know which if you use like
dried ice to chill it and get into that
slushy kind of territory and so you put
it in there overnight then you take and
pour your ethanol over your cannabis and
I prefer not to kinda I don't want the
green that's inside of it all of the
resin is on the outside of the plant
material and the ethanol is going to
saturate through it and the extraction
of period that I'm doing if I ground it
my yield would probably be a little bit
better but better of what it would be
full of other constituents that are
inside the cell walls when when you
break the plant material you're
extracting what's exposed and so it's
not really what I'm aiming for some
people really like to have that green
hash oil for for eating and you know
that's that's a great method you would
definitely want to grind it if that was
the case so right just using buds yes I
used flowers for this they were actually
some old flowers that I just happen to
have around
somehow wasn't his folks it was it was a
perfect extraction that material so you
pour the ethanol over the material and
put it right back into the freezer and
let it soak for three hours and so
that's kind of the quick extraction
timeframe that you can get into to the
deep freeze and not have to worry about
I could probably extend that to five
hours if I really want to it and I have
to worry about too much of chlorophyll
being extracted but three hours I just
really like that number it seems to
always work well for people on the other
hand definitely will go for a 24 hour or
even one month long soaks if they're
really trying to fully digest every last
bit of what is in the cannabis plant but
to each their own you know I really love
hashish like I said so so I'm more on
the resin side of it rather than the
plant material side of it sure we will
talk about tea card I didn't yeah
there's definitely you know if you d
card some people say it's easier to
perform the extraction you're going to
get a more complete extraction I feel
like ethanol such a great solvent that
it gets the majority of what I'm going
after anyways he'll think it's really
necessary to D carpet and I really like
a acid form teacher and so in the acid
form teacher you're going to have all of
your terpene content there if you
haven't d carved your material for the
extraction so that's one thing to think
put your goal to smoke or to eat it's to
have a versatile oil that you can use
for it's going to be high in
cannabinoids so this stuff here was D
card so with the intention of eating but
it's very small so yeah it's something
and you know it could have more terpenes
in it if I didn't department it would
have tasted a lot better I could have
gone with a more gentle approach to it
but I went and put some heat on there
and and make sure the D part so now that
what most people are looking for an
ethanol hash oil for at this point is to
eat you know a lot of people are after
the RSO or the Zico for a cancer
Richmond you know and so that's that's
really you know where they go but you
can definitely make that with a quick
extraction you don't have to have all
those other constituents in there they
may play key roles to have to you know
to the healing but the cannabinoids
themselves have all been shown to help
cancer you know so it's kind of I'm not
sure what part of the plant really is is
healing us I just know that okay so the
point of reason the economic for is to
lower the temperature extraction so the
plant material is frozen the ethanol is
frozen then when you combine the two
certain constituents aren't dissolvable
like chlorophyll chlorophyll is not
resolvable freezing temperature or it's
not as readily dissolve so over time
you're still gonna get chlorophyll to
extract if you leave it in the freezer
for long enough but but starting cold
allows you not to have these undesired
constituents that come over yes so
please hold your questions in the end
Jeff's got a lot to do it
so all the questions write it down we'll
definitely talk questions at the end
here question so you freeze the material
for three hours and then what I like to
do is just a simple coffee filter I put
it into the jar and then I fold over
most of it but leave just a little bit
unattached there so this there's an
airflow so there's this a space for
airflow in here so then then you just
take your your cannabis and and ethanol
and you pour it right on over over it
and then I'll take after everything's
poured out of it I take and put the
plant material in here and it's kind of
hard to squeeze right here like this and
one prop that I didn't bring tonight
it's a nice two cup measuring cup a
glass measuring cup and you can just
kind of set it on there and get your
squeeze going and not really lose
anything and then pour that into the cup
you break through the filter and so this
right here is the filtered extract you
guys can all it be in the event come up
here open it up and smell if you'd like
to you can actually smell some of the
dirt means it's really heavy with
alcohol so it's hard to smell but and
then this is this is the final coil over
here the wash but so you take this after
it's filtered and you put it into the
rice cooker flip the switch on and
within about half an hour with the lid
on all of the ethanol for the most part
most of the ethanol I should say is gum
and it still has quite a bit to our
beans in there there's a little bit left
it's not very well dee carbonate anyway
so at that point you have a couple
options if you just have the rice cooker
you can take and push down on the switch
a little bit and ill pop right back up
so just hold it for like two seconds and
then let it back up and then do it again
and repeat until you start to see the
oil form little bubbles and so when it
forms the little bubbles you stop as the
boiling starts to slow back down you can
do that process again and then continue
that until the boiling has finished and
that's that's an easy way to deke art
it's not the most elegant it's going to
destroy some of the THC in your next
rack but it's going to get you Adi
carpet product without having to go
through a lot of extra hassle so if
you're if you're just trying to make it
a quick easy extract you can go there if
you want to take it one step further you
can have a pot on a hot plate with oil
in it and you keep that boil up use a
candy thermometer - 250 260 degrees
somewhere in that range and you take
your oil the rice cooker and pour it
into a jar well it's still warm so it's
easy to get out of there and then set it
in this in the pot of oil and D carbon
that way and so that's gonna take you
know anywhere from 20 minutes if you
focused a very small amount of oil 20
minutes from the time the oil reaches
that tutor
these 260 degrees also take a few
minutes for it to warm up up to a couple
hours if you have a large amount of oil
there a 450 curve then you can watch it
boil of what's boiling off is ethanol
terpenes and carbon dioxide so when the
carboxylic acid is is broken by the heat
of the teach the acid turns into TC
delta-9 and so that's that's kind of you
know the D car process during that
process co2 is produced so it's just
it's broken off and you know that when
the slowing of the bubbling happens the
majority of your of your extract has
been D carved or not too little but in
in this pot you'll know that your heat
is is pretty much break so then from
there C so that's from there you've got
a few different options you can put your
extract into a jar it would be really
hard when you try to get it out so it's
not the ideal container for it to be
warming up that jar then trying to scoop
a little bit out I really like to pack
it into syringes because they are kind
of the easiest way to do something you
know you can see how much you just
dispensed see get an idea of how much
how many milligrams of cannabinoids
you're getting in your system if you
have a rough idea of what your extract
is which something but this method is
probably gonna be like a 60% cannabinoid
content at least if you do a cold
extraction and you can definitely get
higher than that but if you soak it for
longer you're gonna get lower than that
for sure
you know probably this mom one-month
soak would get you like a 30% depending
on what your starting material is could
he be in more than that that's really
really bad at starting material but but
yeah so I really like these syringes and
and we've been using is actually glass
on glass syringes and so the glass it
doesn't react with any terpenes it's not
going to be broken down so there's not
much terpene content left in Indy car
boy because you've cooked a lot of those
off during the deeper process but
there's definitely some left in there
too it means our solvents so passing it
into glass it's much better than packing
it into something that has any type of
plastic so Pilon and and any type of
plastic is going to absorb those
terpenes and give off plasticizers I
mean we enough of them already with all
the food that we eat that's packed in
plastic so probably the best to stay
away from it if you're making yourself
medicine so that's the the first way to
do it is to pack it into a syringe or a
jar and do it while it's hot right out
of the rice cooker or if it's already in
jars or pinch bother you you're you're
ready to write up to the detox process
it's the easiest way the oil is going to
be so thick that when you get it into
the syringe you literally can't i'm you
know i push on the syringe and there's
no motion there at all
so to dispense out of these syringes you
would just put it into a cup of hot
water or rather than the hot water and
the sink and that's that's one way to
get the pure pure oil out another route
that's really popular is to had some
sort of viscosity agent one way or
another so a lot of people use hemp seed
oil
MCT medium train-track you'll attract
which is a fractionated coconut oil is a
really popular one for people to add and
you can mix that in when it's hot and
then once you've loaded into the
syringes then you'll be able to squirt
it right out of the syringe and eat it
on the go without having to heat it at
all
so and it'll also help with the
absorption into your body so some people
really like to eat the oil just Rob
without having anything added to it some
people like to have something added to
it to help carry it into the body and
carry the syringe so I think that's
that's pretty much that's an all hash
oil from cannabis into the syringe it's
really an easy method of extraction so
you guys have some questions I'd love to
answer
yeah sure it depends on the purity of
your teeth you know so it's all about
your starting material what what did you
put in for cannabinoids you're going to
get out a lesser amount such as those
maybe some left in your material but
that's pretty much what you're going to
get out
yeah
well okay so so it's really hard to kind
of nail that down I think that it's it's
gonna be dependent on your illness that
you're trying to take it for that's
really the big thing I know that a very
popular thing that people are doing is
the 60 and 90 days so they'll try to get
60 grams a full extract cannabis oil in
90 days and so you start off with a
grain of rice besides those and that
seems to be what pretty much everybody
can tolerate it might be a little bit
much for for inexperienced users but a
grain of rice seems to be about right
you can start with half that if you're
really an experienced and then move your
way up to a gram of day at the end of 90
days so it'll take 60 grams to get you
90 days and that seems to be a popular
treatment I'm not a doctor I really
don't I can't save that's what's gonna
cure 80 but not you know but it seems to
be a perfect popular thing that people
are claiming to have really good success
with right so I mean you you can still
take to material down to a testing lab
so if you made a batch of oil here in
Washington state like I'm pretty sure
the analytical 360 would test your oil
for me so just go down through this see
how the location are and they'll they'll
do it and then you know how many
milligrams are in how much and you'd be
able to do so yourself by milligrams if
you want but most people don't have labs
like that you know have access to that
so we're lucky here yeah yes to respond
to the first question about using Keith
who's been my experience what advantage
we're using keep over flower' you
already have the trichomes and all of
this is a method of strip mining what's
on the outside when you lose key you
don't have plant material chlorophyll
isn't such a big deal you get gold a lot
easier and there's less need to
winterize because it's less fat to pull
out all those waxes right you can do the
extraction hot and not have to worry
against a chlorophyll as long as the
Keith wasn't too green right yeah even
so the tops stuff but the rest of that
seven is largely trichomes even broken
and drop the issue of a lot of
chlorophyll and you can be a little
longer and warmer in yours
not just in sunny Los excuse me just
cellulose left yeah we give it a sliding
scale and your yield that three-hour
mark yes
so what I got here was probably two and
a half grams from an ounce so you know
it was a little less than 10% on the
yield when I make ethanol hash low for
502 we're not using flour we're using
leaf and bottom buds right so it's like
all the little little pieces so you know
if I want to
everything has its home you know so if
if it's good for this type of extraction
we use it over there if it's not so this
just happens to be where everything goes
there but we get about five percent
yield and we'll come up with about 60
percent cannabinoid content
the oil there as well so that's doing
the cold extraction three hours of just
a follow-up on that with the 582 how
much how much would you say your trim
goes to this type of extractions pho
well we're committed quite a bit of it
so pretty much everything you know we
moved to extracting flowers for all of
our co2 oil we have sugar leaf to make
bubble - and then pretty much everything
else like all of the things that are the
small buds and the rest of the not as
resin asleep but still has a tiny bit
you know there's a bit more shade leaf
that all goes to so a whole tier threes
worth is what we're processing into
ethanol
and so it's not out yet but it's coming
the whole mother started with
computerize to take some other greenery
out of it so winterization is happening
with ethanol and then in a coal fire so
we're doing ethanol in a cold
environment and so the lipids that you
would be winterizing out of an extract
that's a seal to extract would not even
come out because they're going to stay
in the matrix they're going to stay
locked in there because they're the
conditions for them to be dissolved or
not there it's too cold and it's in
ethanol so ethanol doesn't you can't
dissolve most lipids in ethanol they can
flow I was worried about what you're not
worried but so you're looking at the 5%
water and that is all right compressed
and then we run
if you can go or not yeah I mean yeah I
don't know I wouldn't say that I'll be
like I think you're gonna cook off some
of that water in your decaf process so
that's that's really and actually you
know a lot of people used to use water
as a buffer in there D card so they
didn't toss them in there and they would
know because of how the water boiled out
when and when it was ready when it was
deeper yeah so I think that if you're d
carving it's not a big issue and I've
never even met my co2 winterization I've
never had an issue with water
except for from the smoke to process you
know we didn't extract water so yes what
do you think of the method of D carving
the bugs before you can use them with
the would have been a mason jars so that
the third mean supposedly stay in there
rather than doing that yeah I mean you
know there's all kinds of different ways
to do it and that's another another
thing that you could do you could take
this tincture even and set that into you
know a hot bat right but then you're
gonna have you know a closed environment
with the solvent that's that's boiling
away and I just I feel like you know
that that could be dangerous
in a home environment you know it's not
something I was trying to recommend yeah
but it's it's still impossible in the
terpenes if you're aiming for an alcohol
teacher rather than an RSO of oil you
could totally retain the tincture or
retain the terpenes and have the
tincture being activated but you're
going to change the terpenes from what
they were on a flower to a degraded
version of that just like the THC is to
creating down the terpenes are also
going to create down something you'll
still be present Clemens yeah
so Mike advice my experience not that
I've done this
we hope larger jar and the Bollier and
you need to periodically open it perfect
because the solvent will vaporize him
and you'll hear the lid pan so you want
to use a headspace by having a volume
above the liquid and burp it when it
pops yep and but then when you burp it
oops apply it now I understand that
stage
to keep the terms of heating and break
in the car all right well I mean it's
gonna force the terpenes out right it's
good for seven all it's gonna force
terpenes up so you'll end up with a
hacksaw eventually if you had the lid
off so tonight here season's question
right though is she might be carving the
flower and a mason jar sealed prior to
you to double right yeah so so I mean
you know you can totally do that as well
d carbon tiny tiny laughs and then
extract any ounce material
how much did water-pipe work for me so
but given your mileage may be a little
bit different but nothing on how fluffy
is if you grind it down like I don't
suggest definitely be able to use less
ethanol but it's totally fine to grind
it especially if you're just eating it
there ain't not smoking it get the
cannabinoid side of the plant material
and give it out in the most efficient
way and that would be saving you ethanol
by grinding forget about the little bit
of green you're gonna have in there your
cost of production is lowered if you
know but it is a cost yeah so back on
the keep subject can you go into the
ratios starting material amount to keeps
you know how much alcohol you'll need
saturated yeah you know I mean I don't
really I haven't really recorded
anything on he's extraction about
ultimate really know definitively it's
just you know I would say that you're
probably going to need more ethanol than
you would work for a flower extraction
right to be able to get all the
cannabinoids because there's going to be
a saturation flavor team so it's not
just you know cover it till like with
flour that's all you do you just cover
the flour material make sure that's all
in the in the alcohol and you've got the
extraction with Keith if you just
covered it that's really not enough
you're gonna have to have a lot more
ethanol to perform that extraction
double it says yeah I'm sorry yes
they're a bit like so now we're doing
all this mystery right
what do you deal with that co2 material
you think about going to be a general I
love it I love it so that's exactly what
happens with it so I don't perform the
extraction myself okay that's exactly
what happens with the plant material
it's a great method use every part of
the plant that you can there's going to
be something I've actually keeps
material after it was co2 extracted and
tested the key is 20% THC and so that's
great ethanol actual extraction material
I agree and I think that wipe them so
I'm curious about it is that we did
something similar in my brother's farm
and process back some ways and we got a
one-to-one but like a hi CDC I've never
chromium profile which was quite an
interesting you know and with your
medicine Creek analytics so I don't know
if that's something where you want to go
and check the and out enjoy differences
post rip and then maybe even the lower
leave if you'd like isolate the strain
variance something I've got I mean I
would say that the CBC it would be and
my you know my knowledge it's what an
easier extracting instrument then THC
acid so it's going to come over first in
the co2 extraction so that's what my
experience is but I mean just same kind
of the opposite maybe the co2 or BHO
sure pho could be totally different
not exactly yeah but we had a 20% CDC
extract it was a co2 quick fraction that
we took off the very very beginning of
the run really and so it was yeah really
really high I think it was 40% terpenes
and 20% CNBC's seriously yeah you know
but that's not a product that's out on
the mark
[Applause]
you sterilized how you stare like dry
set so tri-set sterilizations up in it
so you know I ran into this issue with
braked in the medical days and we had
some bubble hash that tested positive or
some nasty microbeads and so we're like
oh my gosh what's going on here and so
when you do dry step you do it cold and
then this cold hatch gets brought out
and it collects and condenses moisture
from the atmosphere and you can actually
have some issues with psoriasis having
microbes if you're doing eco or you know
that's an actual wouldn't eat though
ethanol hatch so you don't have any
worries about that as long as you're
performing to the extraction pretty
quick because ethanol can kill any of
those bacteria but if you're pressing
rosin from it it's an issue and so what
we decided to do was we did a UVC light
treatment right out of the tumbler so
the moment came out of the freezer came
out the tumbler we got that hash and we
in thin layers to the UVC light
treatment to it and never had a
microbial issue with it so it basically
stopped any other microbes from being
able to bloom into that heat so I don't
know that's exactly BG lines are
available
a vapor lock my daughter up or very
neutral oscillations yeah you know the
13 wants to keep up a purple diversify
the rating they have individuals that
they have everyone on the Left would
talk to has not moved the decimal point
to the right you have 54,000 rules
coming out the thing don't do that you
have to have it in a nice contained
contain the contraption basically like
we build a box for our UVC light and
then I actually had an extension cord
going way to the other end of the lab
and because it's I believe is like a
lose elements created this there's some
nasty kind of stuff that's created when
the UVC light burning so I always had it
you know
I switch over on the end of the
extension cord switch about allowed it
for it to sit there for a little bit
came by opens it up before I was doing
stuff so Mosul it didn't take some extra
caution and yeah they sell them on
Amazon they can get up there good time
for each button switch they use the
lights at Home Depot for $18 get three
different boys put it on they walk out
the room push fit of site yeah
yep you act like you don't want to look
at a couple more questions anymore
alright that's it