when I first interviewed Kevin on my
shaping fire podcast he said
with zero shame that he has been a
trapper her all his life I thought that
was so not only do I not hear many
people use the word trafficker but to
see someone who stepped into it and own
it and was proud of it and wrote a
prohibition all the way to legalization
and it is now a leader in his community
I'm like damn straight these are the
kinds of things that make a hero to me
he has deep roots in both Oakland and in
Mobile County he is probative
prohibition-era
turned license and he's savvy and
successful in both he's created the most
important genetics hub in the United
States and the mult County at his
nursery Wonderland nursery not only is
he wildly successful himself but has
become a leader in that community you
know it's one thing to be a producer and
sell your products and just generally be
a good person but then to take that and
to become a leader in your community ban
people together work with policy changes
work with the laws and then go and
mentor new entrepreneurs new breeders
who are coming up and to fill the vacuum
that he's created behind him so that so
that there's new folks that kind of
leadership is rare in our industry if
somebody was not just trying to chase
dollars he's an all-around good guy and
I consider it a privilege to be his
friend my honor to present Kevin
there's so much for having me here I was
excited I follow what you guys doing
it's awesome that you as a community get
together in and work on Kenneth and and
cultural stuff and in community it's
it's I would say a losing element in our
society we're really we're becoming very
small man I really correct cultivators
spiritual cultivators so thank you so
much but let me come here um my
conversations typically are on that
though typically people reman to talk
about a direction a thing my success is
in survival I have successfully been in
cannabis since I was 12 years old and
I've had this unbelievably long storied
life of cannabis but here it is very
different time period where all of a
sudden cannabis is normally cannabis
tennis became business cannabis is the
culture and we have the pride but the
product is a business and this is this
is this discussion that I'm going to
have tonight it's when I talk about
turkeys in a little different manner
because you've had Ethan Russo speak to
you who is Iraq considered above the
state of the art of the subject right
now
then you had been Alexander here who's a
brilliant young man who is very
intelligent in plant derived hurts
solvent assignment so that's not my
direction my direction primarily is in
to assist people with genetic packaging
meaning I
the right varieties so that your
farmville business succeeds my
interpretation of the business is what's
accurate I have a tremendous number of
people I deal with they're brilliant
scientists and brilliant
that's what they do so people get
confused they want to ask me about a
hospital yeah that's not lady dude I got
to sell the atom I'm gonna tell you
we're flying the atom I tell you how
yeah so this conversation it became a
business we're not talking about get a
friendly conversation it was another
therapy apart it's not is your canvas
selling and people have this huge
misconception of how terpene is
interrelate with that of that and I
think that that had to be more important
than how we determine hi because you've
got a lot to existing you know and you
have to read a damn thing if you didn't
want to there's so much genetic material
available right now that if you just
went into it and took a look you say hey
I have enough to cover all my rights
now the question
optimizing for what you do and so this
conversations going to start with me
being a kid breaking up fails and
landrace cannabis so when I was a kid on
the East Coast I was involved in a
criminal family that was large this was
under the mexicanrunner travelers and as
you'll die I got to access all this ball
cannabis coming in from the chefs and
what it did was it allowed me to get I
want to say a reference point of what
cannabis was from its original origin so
it would come from these countries and
this was all pretty documented meaning
that was organized distribution
organized delivery and so it's about the
course of the year the loans would come
in and we would break these up and then
BAM and move around so he would start to
know hey this was Colombian and
Panamanian and this was Thai and this
was stuff from a family when we grew out
some of those Afghani seeds one year
maybe 7912
quite a case in 93 ended time so in 1790
girl goes out and the seeds in my
grandmother's jar and she had a stunning
organic garden and so we're able to put
the seeds into this beautiful fertile
blowing whistle and we finished down and
I heard it was smoke and I remember
being so caught up with how rich it was
but how different it was because of that
that was the first poppy grow this is
going back to you know the settings and
so I couldn't believe what those seeds
are translated into they have didn't say
where it's definitely an easy
a lot of flowers from the bags but we
grew them in variety and all of a sudden
of smoke and the progeny four pounds
that would be able to you know what's
the saying to this and I can taste the
similarities but there's something
missing and something added and so I
just remember this I don't leave my
goodness this is just something that
makes me strong and what I do categorize
stuff mentally trash people not to
others so I remember those so I go for
me and Bailey need to use and then I go
into the military and when I went into
the military this was during the high of
the drug war I was a salvage divers and
I just get dropped on helicopters under
boats filled with billions of dollars in
profits in the Pacific and we diagram
investors and I started to be back on
the ships with all the land raised hot
again and I started to see and smell
walls and I started just starting to
categorize and I started to see the
cannabis that was being produced in
California this would have been the mid
80s and I started to see California
cannabis I started to see all these
profiles and laboratory profiles and
tastes and tones and at that time we
cannabis was with cannabis and it came
in a million arrays but it's all
classified basically as good time to
thank choice for that but it didn't make
a difference to lose the food products
move on and you started to see this more
than any California up in a non cattle
that would have been you know it
aids-related later I started to really
see flavonoids come and I said
everything tastes the same it was
because of that and so we started as
soon as all the sudden that want to
change the entire tone about manners all
this leg one so people will leave the
canvas space like what people believe we
can this tastes like Afghanistan many
people around the where I started to see
was the impact of what's on your tennis
tennis itself so I started doing all
this this consulting and humble was a
legal consultant but it was the only way
you can see any other quantity is to be
able to really work with a lot these new
max of operations one tremendous variety
of strains within their operations and I
would then be able to employ any type of
variety I wanted any one of these
operations and by changing and input I
would change how we perceive that
strained of it and so what we do again
down to is that when you're talking
about a profile of turkeys everything
what influences it so when someone says
to you I have a terpene profile I was
asking what what not the Candice because
the influence you're not able to
separate from and so it's such a big
deal that when I'm doing something like
the Emerald cup is a judge where I judge
them right there are thousand sins
I take a pen and I know things that
taste exceptionally similar and I keep
track of those of those samples and at
the end of the cup I go back and they
usually from the same Congo suppliers
and so what we found was the Kampala
suppliers on Sonoma using the great
waste had a much higher residual sugar
load which brought up which brought up a
flavonoid profile in the Kansas Turpin
ativ things like this they drive these
numbers
a higher overall number does that
necessarily be it's better and when I'm
Ben and I had a discussion in Hollywood
wants to know I brought up his paper to
show and it was a term profile
strawberry-banana thought that I had and
it came out in California seems about 5%
is tops or again goes up to 15 but we
must quantify differently because where
this process of three times California
is considered a really hot straight turn
to live I have two point five strawberry
that's happiness number that if you look
at profiles women throw their way but
the problem is it sells to $1,000 a
pound because it makes an exceptionally
immunity concentrate so I shared it to
bed Cindy goes in lab because turn
people say that has no value so many
projects I had so many that I had
learned how to use a computer
spreadsheet I remember all this [ __ ]
what it did was it let me start to see
what was the impact of any flavor on the
cannabis and what was the impact on the
environment then it started to take a
little deeper and I started going you
know what this train was a killer while
it was grown and produced and sifted
loose if it's the keyword under metal
halide and this particular cutting
sifted under HPS that means of the
whoever threw it well found it they
found something that was developed in a
specific environment like a specific
nutrient in a specific environmental
situation and all those things
contribute rapidly to how you received
herpes it has put you back to the point
where it's so big that I don't think
people need to see it it's so big
they just look at this is this and this
is my list and look at my numbers my
numbers of big but the problem is you're
looking at terms and you look at a 40
maybe I think there's like 240 in
cannabis Ben has a lab in in Illinois
from the vet that came in he has a lab
in Illinois that he can access and
whether to start sending all these
varieties for this lab is we want to
find out why do I have a common copy
right now we only can see a specific
amount it's the missing pieces that
matter so we can take a look a better
idea what is this in this situation
produced here it has this particular
value you can produce it someplace else
and transfer the ballot and see that's
the part that's tough for most people
because cannabis producers you get
things from people and you say hey this
was awesome of you but you take it into
an environment and when you put it into
your environment you're a web browser so
you have exceptional lighting except
what cool and so you have an ability to
do some different stuff but it changes
the plan on a county level and it
reflects in a certain role we choose
those plants and we put into a GPS room
and all of a sudden all the monitors
smoothly right off and because it wasn't
in a hot room when you chosen and so the
profit people
it's such an understanding of I'm just
producing pot because for most people
they're really not dealers some people
ask me what I know they're drug dealer
what happens to love growing pot it's
alright genetics
who owns dispensaries
the other day I said listen you can
understand in abundance triple-a market
which is visual it's gonna always be a
monetary market there's no time don't
spoken in some forms it's little tiny
pieces so they can put all the heat on
and one time and get all my models and
cemeteries and go it's complete but if
that triple-a visual piece with that
bass goes into someone who spoke
civilian form by the second head all the
model terms have flared off because the
heat that moves through the junk so I
started telling all that if you put into
a pre-roll market its assets paternity
market and if you've gone into into this
market it's a model market have to see
it that way because they don't care
about the flavor as much as they care
about the nose and the visual drug
smugglers wanted in the mouth and you
you have to take a look and say well
then what lines work with that we take
stuff like right now the best
think of is the old herbal cut because
the old herbal kind is really a
descendant of everything for a bush
purple kush to mend over or whatever you
want to call it into every other modern
hot strain right now where the Girl
Scout cookie that's this cherry pie all
of that is to better
why is that all of those strings are
primarily sold to people smoking in
Portal and it's because of the way that
that plant has an ability to hold a
suspect our being that doesn't burn off
but releases this plentiful flavor in
your mouth all time and so for people
were in the pre-roll market we need to
look into those directions and if you're
not you need to look at the other
direction I think that most individuals
really unaware of their impact with what
you're doing to their their life just
like I use the example of Rakesh so I
have a very specific royal push push was
a line created in humble by a man named
Ann Laura so in a broccoli reader he
passed away but about a year and a half
two years ago footba sudden heart attack
like there were seven his nose so bright
passes away but he does did reading
project boy because but he does the
essay on three thousand plants on the
coast so his search was up three
thousand progeny puts out three thousand
and he doesn't mean how to be another
man Noah coast and he selects this one
incredible color so I hope this car it
gives it to me I hold it we use it to
propagate we sell it as a cutting and
it's the basis of every royal fish plant
now because window got busted I kept
that cut and hid it and when he came
back into the world I gave it back to
him and the whole line continued it's a
top five in the you see where every time
it's entered into the animal called
anything unconscious
Kampai because it's just such a unique
terpenes signature so we go guy this is
incredible and it's got such a
resistance it's all these traits of a
phenomena so we just didn't love with
this pretty planet
well indoor same things it's coming well
I've transferred in a camp on a hotter
drier environment and lo and behold my
studying royal cushion is pretty good
because it had been sifted in an
environment that is clean so you are
sifting the way you're producing and so
for people that are producing in hi
Robin it's exceptionally windy those
type of situations you're going to get
less production but those in your
varietals but you have happen is what
was happening to the waxes in the plant
it literally actually some of your model
services so when you see this hi
circulatory window research plant under
the same circumstances some of those
things allow you to have a radically
different response to the cannabis so I
take remember the nursery nursery
thousand gardeners across the state so
you can is different than most people
because I look at it in hundred fifty to
two hundred million dollars like your
range of production now I'm not making
that money for brows I don't my fingers
on that reduction nominal and so that
lets me see what really happens and let
me see the pulses of these things and
it's crucial because otherwise how we're
gonna know that's all right I've been
really accurate with it but it's little
things like the Royal cushion the wrong
circumstance and so they were able to do
well with it but not to the degree they
would have it be put it back to its
colder environment you wouldn't run it
in norm
we have to be careful with light depth
strains so when I simple
like that this way you're going to go
through an artificially high temperature
in me to where what you taught that [ __ ]
it's spice and anybody that's done you
know standard operating houses you've
got you're gonna have two million a
greenhouse
this isn't beautiful but if you're not a
guy you're gonna have spicy
humidity and temperature and you need to
make sure the varieties that you're
using are not primarily for definitely
serve your purposes so you don't
remember there was every variety that
you mess around was sifted from indoor
work so all the seed lines I've worked
with all under HBS so that's what I'm
saying I don't know the impact of what I
did I transfer that plant from HBS and
the other brother what if I get a
radically different morphology the plant
changes shape dramatically I sift for
outdoor normally it precludes the enjoy
it every now and then strange the touch
that means that it works in both
directions but sometimes it doesn't and
that's just the way it is so you know if
you're if your tennis producer if you
say
you want to make sure that you're
sifting stop that works in your specific
circumstance and using the foods that
you're using because that's reproduction
methodology if it will influence what
you're choosing what you find what works
for you in that specific and if you're
not good at this part
you go get people that run dispensaries
successful once again absolutely
position myself straight up they got us
out just didn't get wet no yeah I might
once whatever again you need those
answers and understand so we're clear on
that the imports that are coming into
this are so big that I don't think
anybody has any idea really what surfing
profile that plant asperity you've grown
that goddamn thing Spacey mundo well
you're not and all I see is these
notices so you know Nina brought that I
still have you I wanna see I still got
the original paper well then that still
pop down right over the university and
say hey I have a new relationship with
Bill with the University of California
I say hey send you over to your sites to
bother I want to talk to your professors
I said can we met by attorneys by the
famine bread so we can start figuring
out straight not only use fibers but I
was trying to figure out a way to what's
not what because
so explain to me the fundamentals so
that I don't make mistakes so write it
as I said let's take a look at Canada is
a simple body so I broke it up into four
face
categories I wrote it up tools content
arts and fruits and waters because to me
as a distributor so on the motion we
vide is that basically covers the
spectrum the way let us kind of break it
up is basically like you're seeing
propylene limonene I mean because I buy
right where the problem is and essential
oil tech so burn that [ __ ] show me one
essay that says what happened when
you've earned it probably prison so
therefore you use in data that isn't
accurate and you're pretending like it
is and you're running wild liquor I
forget you're a genius
and I'm like look we need art meant but
not in the perception which means there
must be a precursor term somewhere
that's affecting it something to the
increase in it
let's see any of this crap so I broke it
up into four divisions to make easy for
myself
lo and behold I create a competition and
use those four divisions the next thing
I know I've got a guy named Johnny Bruce
who's at UCLA brilliant professor one
challenge is my search because what made
you do that I said it makes sense to me
because you sell they will fire disaster
go prove me wrong
oh it was I was writing all this up so
if you want to have the guidance again
you can pull all this paper so it's a
thirty or forty page PC did I get a
six-hour medical conference in Vegas on
this topic because it was the first time
they had enough samples put together
that let them will get terpene profiles
and using crafting technology was pretty
neat I've done deceiving technology that
let me see visually shirts to see
relationships and so he showed me this
incredible interrelationships that
basically kept training and limonene
which is rules earth subsets through
floral subsets and so he goes you were
completely right in your simplified rate
down and so the planet isn't the same
and I'm so damn smart instead if I
simplify 42,000 in the form then maybe
you can't do and it makes it kind of
easy because we can take a look at those
markets now it's a fuel market from a
market floral market earth market where
those markets exist and where's my
distribution in those markets and so I
know that if I'm in if under certain
situations I know that it sort of
happened
the floor which is dreaming in in this
area and someone says never losing isn't
funny
which one which mean a dream is like 9
or 10 different ones I have two of them
one of them would qualify under a fruit
flavor who one would go under a floor
because it goes more amazed so which one
you have to be honest individual because
we can't go by out of line and even if
you mentor a specific cutting is so
crucial because so I produce pho it
sells 120 watts of Graham that's how
you'll like holy [ __ ] because otherwise
we're gonna get a point out so I love
the specific things and we do tests and
we find out that's the one that people
like then I can do anything I want any
pissed I want on because it's not gonna
give me the goddamn picture so you can
snap shot to a keyhole and I said wow
emails to people is a Fisher I know
normally so my perception is so accurate
that it completely negates my choices
because I'm not making choices I'm just
doing something that doesn't make any
sense
and
me it's crucial that you go about this
have to pick the right varieties for the
application for your purposes and so I
know what I do for my own situation
where I I break up those four categories
take a look at these subsets and I say
hey how much of a distribution does my
arm have to have in these respective
areas where do people like earths that's
a segment then where are you seen where
you see the fruits happy uplifted people
necessarily going into cartridges now
because it's going into women older
people changing where's the gas anybody
that has over Italy because opiate
addiction America's on control and well
he hasn't I've been running businesses I
asked my mom why by the way my coach I
hope your problem happens with Opie's I
don't know beans sir can this varietals
how to really be exceptionally effective
another replacing and so if you're in
California everybody's drugged up in
mind that Samuels because no one is
gonna get any effect but how do you use
the fruit to drive
specifically this is just straight up
but what's the point of that I want to
teach you free we want to buy twice
right you just fall where it is I don't
once but I might rely so when you buy to
us go on through I want you to chase the
state of California
to buy all of that extra a lot of state
that me up because if people buy the
only price in all the way that's the bad
thing so how do we do that
look for these things that work for us
we start to be intelligent about so if
you ever then go into the pet market
then those of those rights are beans
those things go that direction but if
you're going to go into pretty roles
that it has to be earnest and gas is
primarily because those things are going
to hold the flavor through the end of it
if we want to develop through on what
gasps we have to bring it in and then we
can combine it start to have it in
varieties you can actually mix cannabis
in a container and put it in the joint
and no one would ever know the
difference because I do with
concentrates all the time where our
blending concentrates and give it to you
as a better product because I said
listen I think you need to delivery the
citrus but I'm gonna lay this one in
here let me figure out the ratios and I
just weigh it out so I can kind of
recreate it again
I just made the shape because what
people doing for wine and it will then a
wine affect how they use so there's no
difference it's combining it
in figure out haven't you people love
the citrus but they burn out quickly
because they don't get high long enough
so what am I gonna do I do some jazz
with it so I do some gas with some
citrus and now they're building subsets
with each one so earth and every little
thing below it basically going to go
with Turkey and a single word you
describe in the South China Sea and so
it makes it kind of easy and that's when
we use everybody there's a lot of people
around I'll put them outside too so I
can see the enormous they leave oh wow I
didn't expect to be sober outside yet no
idea
then we take the plan put it inside me
all the crazy terrible Wow and it was
just like nice to do
thus if for indoor so heavier when I
started transferred outside I mean this
terrible mistake because I was on 1212
triggered and so on pushing my plans are
officially late because I don't have a
45 switch or twelve switch and it's
recently same thing it also has
characteristics that work for that
indoor HPS you know at that time it was
all hydroponic once we stripped it into
organic
you know Roman systems and their
cultivation decades ago but only their
romantic systems it would start
traveling to spend what is the input on
the organic components to McGinnis and
to meet water was something of a
supernatural propagating effects and it
was one but it's so environmentally
destructive to mining that I don't use
it I just try to stay away from this
year I realize that I was doing what the
image growing property or environment
indiscernible Crescent mine of the earth
dry the UNITA so so water doesn't work
so it sort of you work with we work with
some of the fish products that they
bring them they bring some of those
flavors in I noticed that when I was in
Hawaii cannabis that was grown with his
ship I thought it was the soil does I'm
in Hawaii I'm growing I'm smoking I'm
putting all this is this is Molokai
there's a small tiny then I went back
honorable counties my friend had a farm
and he grow using that material over the
hills and it was the same profile and I
said cold it wasn't the moment I saw it
was the patient it mess so actually
trapped all this crap doesn't really
notice me what am I really
and that's a lot of salt a disease they
all distinctly put a playground so
cutting-edge put the flavor on advanced
movements book the flavor I change
present flavor on it and it was more
relative those methodologies and you
know if someone who's actually active
addition any profits they can start to
tell you which one you use it because
they all have a little bit different
bite and why is that too late so
different and the mineral - or something
so those little tiny salty to change my
campus for a while there - and so this
is huge because you can talk there about
getting so many inexperienced they're
gonna wanna buy twice and buy stuff when
we go hey let's go use all this [ __ ]
let's go make more more in reality of it
is if you wanted the nastiest term
profile it was really the most genuine
get it done the opposite plant using the
services of our protective so if I want
experience that full range in what I'm
supposed to experience I would have a
plant at its worst condition period and
ideally not even try to remind the
biology from the where came from so I
just like your stomach biology you have
the stuff in your gut affects how you
function the stuff in the soil changes
paid off so I had specific motorized I
to drive some of it up takes well that
changes the quality plan when I'm sure
it has a selfless change in tone so your
microorganisms effect is also so happy
impact on what you're doing with
cannabis and I think that at one time
you know I used to see people and the
patient so what I get is I get a number
on a chart right tell me what strain you
Brewin you remember you can't resolve
this little busy little separation and a
problem determining what I'm doing
[Music]
elaborate stuff that I was getting isn't
really where it's coming from
Landry's areas whether the human being
presented on it that should solve it
arrived so it's not Larry's it's just
that it's real and brace pockets so it
was just kind of no pain is supreme real
and she no more well than we don't
anything I'm doing these things in life
and people difficulty job people who say
hey listen I'm gonna start to work with
what I have here and so to me that's I
saw some candidates that don't refer
that's that's phenomenal because it's
really easy and depending on what
they're fermenting on what they're
driving in from you start getting a
profile and you are relaxing in the
mouth itself and that's
jump up and down
don't you sold times before you know
turn Testament know what appalls you
either beat other notice on this
riveting I'm good the same thing people
always come to me
[Music]
make sure I stay away and I try to give
this information people I'm around
because I present them with genetic
packages okay these things are good in
these circumstances and here I'll give
you a sample of it you produced it using
this methodology so I can can kind of
give you the list of the inputs are used
and what we did and where need
yes and then I know where you are so me
and cuz all the criminality it so work
and then we can find what do we know
about this so that you know in don't
know that and what ladies
hmm you can put yourself in the
situation is away from how to lock it
we're in a market that have fuel citrus
and does not say mr. decade you better
get them both together to get around and
get the mold together means you work
together on these safety projects it's
very hard to do a population sit by
yourself and most people really are not
qualified to make the decision
what's your qualification how many
people you've dived into money none then
you're not right back
so let's [ __ ] the right guy you
ascertains quality of cannabis flowers
let's get you in here to make this
decision and help us out are we going
the right round
do you like the profile we work hard
work out would you buy it twice and
you're going to get this info it's so
important one one thing else is the data
back of am I going the right direction
of what I'm doing because that's the
most of all today is just straight run
oh my god in a row in the parking
because they're not talking not sharing
because we come from such a private
culture I am blanking on plot it freaked
me out but I didn't have any other
option I had such a clear vision one day
of death so I had come out of where I
was at and enter normal cannabis and I
made that entrance in now I'm not sure
what the lender Street is named after my
words can't figure out I wonder how we
didn't land in federal prison
[Music]
so you get together with Roos and you
start to work so every year I like get
one killer cultivar - so every year
let's mistake
constantly and then I take these things
that are red-hot and I shared them with
people who could use a goddamn help
I don't want state laws like the single
this comes to maybe they're things
because it's sorted for your application
just trust him and then all of a sudden
you got somebody else's surviving even
they need them you have no idea who's
going to give you a leg up on
combinations of street show you don't
know it and it's going to get worse
and this is how you really function is
marketability separation commercial
schlagg saunas go big on let's all calm
down boys go ahead there has to be a
place for craft to be passed me it's
just that
how you had people do one a lot it's not
going to be things over price either
that's gonna be exceptionally marketed
that's a whole lot of skill set this one
is how fair price the canvas and you
only were going to be able to do this
begin into varietals that have a high
velocity and you start to work those
those are those varieties and everything
goes I know that it goes on yes
and so when you not hold on G's they're
earning I hold og that are family i
holding jeans in a sense because we
change their community they want citrus
this year and money gas next year the
wire connects here what's the examples
of those ghost SFP and lemon blood by
Morales age right
so it lets me use the very specific
lines that people interpreted as see
citrusy or earthy or all within the
ocean realm I make sure I hold them and
then I just know that this market is not
bad I love 20 years at
and you just let that step run because
they're not going to have the population
will shift within them so basically easy
once you start to build up your
libraries once you start to get your
turf divisions broke it down when they
start to really see what works with you
on your farm and is exceptional you get
out into the public or just going to get
yourself some honest feedback we haven't
had a the why California central line
guys so my guys always come in and want
to tell you that you stupid and even do
it straight up and it basically telling
you you're uneducated so I spent the day
with this guy most of the day I heard I
was uneducated but at the end of the day
he was a while what does qualify to
Jenny pot I said exactly because
cannabis is complex it's not had a lack
of all in terms so why don't I show you
don't know and so because of that you
have to be able to handle the effect and
so if you can't adjust and how much I
can smoke in a row
vision how much I'm blowing through the
signal sitting there in hot weather like
I said you wouldn't get away because
quality I'm not trying to make something
become something can you taste my
favorite one is can you taste the berry
in it
no but if I hope a little bit more
reading terms I start realizing with all
the scientific stuff that's coming with
rot-resistant that our reading programs
haven't changed dramatically over time
but primarily when you're working with
with with reading observing drove all
this how to say with a complimentary
complimentary box people start looking
towards crap together and it all jams up
and you're like wait a second I want
dissimilar stuff to come together form
Union I don't watches the bunch of [ __ ]
don't in a basket that's that's not that
attractive in anyone and what are we
trying to put together and the problem
you better for me is that it's never
gonna be a sexy male it's going to do
this because I'm used to using example
my son's an international and my
daughter is 36 - I'm like a genetic runt
what happened
see is the names and you're going to do
the same thing because people don't
understand it's totally not as simple
you can always go through population and
find outliers but once you're going to
put it together so there's a greater
population so that I don't just find the
only one that fit the bill I have 40
that fit the goddamn bill and I was 40 I
thought the one that could handle more
logically but loading a Lin than another
one that have to trigger so to finish
but first and it gets enough wax they
keep the mono isn't it's got enough
secondary bonds to hold in the thing
that's a good rule but I have to go
through a big population to do this and
so in your breathing ah cestus that's
what I have to look at scientific stuff
is going to help us tremendously 5 plus
it's a wonderful tool because it lets us
take a look that's why I love I love so
much I love the technology because it
cuts all the [ __ ] stories are out of
room I've read it's not you stole from
him I'm sure
[Music]
because you screwing people over like
these guys
this kid it wasn't real so he reads this
stream and he sells a girl to dispensary
in Sacramento business and stuff
maybe name it and it becomes green
ribbon ribbon he comes it's unbelievable
strain of it monitor festival day so I
hold this a moment holds the funny good
so I hold this cup and I'm talking
parrot seven years later I'm here but in
the meantime the second years old this
guy it's been credited to a dispensary
in Sacramento as the creators they read
it they did it if only people who had so
I have this it's at all these different
breeding projects it's all over the
place I mean everything and we're
friends and one day says hey and it's
the same as yours
and I said how it's easy you got robbed
because I know where I got it from and I
know you know the really must be the
greater the planet and so he got screwed
by the dispensary and so we just renamed
green ribbon where we we call the career
evidence really does like green candy
cane every green crackerjack but since
it's been called the river so long it's
just I I made sure his name that
attaches we put it out like that because
how's anybody gonna trust you it you
wouldn't jump over all their crap and
the problem is that
that's what the dole game is really
about faith and trust and so that's why
I'm having such a miserable time right
now with the new industry because nobody
hasn't in faith and trust and so you
guys let Mary creates us in front of the
stream 52 days and or 26% o and th
because up all songs editor it has every
knowing you want which means it have
solutely moves from dispensary markets
legal markets or with that shape you
sculpt it into complex nasty little
beasts so you come back and get it again
but lo and behold he gets ripped you
know you you this what you use it and so
far mostly because it allows you to take
a little to see what you use and find
out what's inside this what's the other
buyers
we found some weird stuff where we
notice that all the oh geez that have
two super numbers have let us come right
in here so I know that all my own genes
that have higher numbers involve doesn't
spawn in those so somewhere that the day
something came into what was happening
but you want to see all this to know
because that might be where the tall is
kind of rough that's why this one those
inhabitants because it's in that piece
if we identify those what will make
things
so I hunted all the CVS down admission
you changed all the CDs [ __ ] right ESMA
see you hunt for a while because it was
what was eating but it's five those
would have been so much easier because
I'm going to let me understand better
what I was looking at and I would have
been able to see better him sustaining
genetic lines is where humans live
so when I started getting I started
getting material from Pakistan and
started letting me see this when they
started let me see what was coming from
Pakistan directly and started below
that's all these numbers of ratios a
common trouble
we're not looking at the right
population say it doesn't exist it
exists five right here same with you
terms nice I'm going to stuff you just
gonna go into the work but what most
people looked at what is lazy work
there's not any population since I put
ten seeds out and you should take those
ten seeds and you should cross the damn
things and get a thousand seeds out of
that and go through that population then
you find an outlier that work with you
and people look that's a lot of work to
understand
because ultimately what is the person
interface with you that's all they know
is that they don't give a [ __ ] about
anything else and so if you're one
Spanish pleased with it numbers only one
I've got a five-star service in the Bay
Area that I use to work with they're
friends of mine constantly because I
know what five-star wine should look
like and so he just comes up he lets me
feed him non-stop with every single new
thing I'm playing with after I run my
own se I stop and so we've run it
through him so it just lets us see what
it looks like because he produces
everything indoor organically and I'm
outdoor God so his work lets me see my
beautiful cuts in a different format and
sometimes there is awesome and sometimes
they're better than your damn that was
really pretty nursing and so you have to
be able to get you some partners get you
some people to the different artists
take a look and see what's really moving
you go to dispensary people I want in
the dispensaries got 400 selections I go
few million something tasty and I got
the [ __ ] oh these are the ones that are
fly out the door and I'm not skipper
come on turtle lean on me night oh I've
been any news words
so people understand and you present
them in these arrays because cannot stop
the [ __ ] this little gang right here
where I think I'm better than Yunus and
it's about what's walking what's the
basis
experience in these different directions
so that this way people can experience
which I'm going to give them and you're
you're able to really get among them and
that's where our pieces are I think
we're running out of time talk to us
your questions out
so 6026
right so last thing is even though this
incredibly excessively hot dry so now
we're going back to the website the
canvas varieties that were chosen for
those situations when the temperature
changes or it gets bored it's conversing
moister change in tone and that's where
in your is a strong because they can
keep the damn thing the same all the
time but they don't ever ever get the
wax is high up and so what you get is
will never get a sense with dirt being
put on an indoor that touches about
bottle terpene yes because i can protect
that and i begin a higher percentage of
cannabinoids in a specific indoor
because I so you'd like
you know I mean typically I would say
not the average smoker but if you were a
store and was in the summer from June to
September if you see 90 days of torture
sales but then as soon as September 1
it's telling everybody come interns
Network so all the back to work now is
Seattle s'mores so how long we we're
going to experience this in a minute and
remember I didn't I just created an
entire bed letting like rebuy Bakugan
inside that little potency bridles
that's about a 10 but it's fun Richard
miles is full-bodied I said hey listen
but while the tourists walking is coming
in the stuff at are small its friendly
people and then I make a stick and I'm
just like me that's normal
to really want to spend what are these
markets that are going to come in in
these windows and only these people
gonna be and what would they like to
experience and I think so much of it is
you know this beautiful expressive in
the full this ears there's nothing you
use that doesn't have an impact it's
just really about what people try to
because of the soul from our black
market type right where you're going to
get the most out of your way so the
problem is your load this plant up and
you're you're pushing it to a level and
you can because we keep adding more
bacteria and we can push this
they're rated hot so we can create the
situation but the plants so loaded up
there it's unhealthy and that's what so
many pathogenic routes come from so I'm
back to upload my motor problems went
away you don't say like it disappeared
dramatically don't do is increase my
skull you open up the skull and so when
you're when you're talking about getting
food into canvas in terms of flaws as
long as I have adequate amount of
bacteria going I'm going to have a take
on that sauce it's the hardest one all
day but I'm gonna get it I don't want to
drive it too heavy if I go too much
poloidal a it's tynus sharp going too
much of this direction leaves up a
vegetarian ideally I go to a pop in the
cat world so a lot of it is just
building which which variety of canvas
that you're growing works well with the
mixed reviews so then the bacteria
dominate the culture of bacteria that
you're using and just with the compost
teas depending on what how most eaten so
if I use a synergy tea which is an
excellent team I use that as a
vegetative tea because I think that's a
50 fungal 50 bacteria right so I get
good into mix and it drives me
but then when I switch in a fly on tea
from green bicycles that one has more of
like a limestone play it pageants home
to the cannabis that's sharp
and I did that's why I'm using that
means that rock because it has such a
beautiful it just activates it but it
leaves a nice clean clear we pulled up
and pull the tops out there
and I use these a lot because these are
the big competitions but doesn't a
competition - and I get a couple hundred
samples that come in
you see a thousand so unless you see a
big population and that's important to
say listen thousand this one clearly
stood out and that methodology did it
we're back up on the inputs and rely on
the genetic form and finally I think we
thought it was I still didn't wish I had
a magnet because we used to look like
when cattle a graph like used to be
doing difference and only being hot so
awesome
it was the most wonderful thing happen
economy California experienced wild oval
but those areas have gone and I just
really don't want to I got to love my
god I'm looking over my lap said you're
right about their hostility shape and
the main point is if your market you
want the flavor you're Canada's you're
selling to a store and the people there
in that store love that stuff don't
change that's what you don't don't break
what's not wrong it's just you don't
know you know but you lay out your base
mix lay this stuff out and let the
oxidation again is it good because you
can't even you can't you can't detect it
so it's going it's a quick question you
see the feature of my cannabis culture
areas like the
and we talked about like market demand
on regional boundaries time to at least
it allows you to have historically
production zones and and you can build
up ran from that that's the whole
question pane and they that champagne is
for grapes common production methodology
so same methodology of former a choices
so this way they can share anybody's
wine anybody else because it's not the
great that makes you a needs the same
every process that defines the house
envoy and burgundy which is the
appellation that defines the burden so
all the champagne
one group each little Appalachians here
[Music]
so we prescribe future this this role
that does the whole day of time so all
the some applause roll the dice will
never be rolling on time straight up and
this one is can clearly separate
yourself in cannabis from the curriculum
how do you define yourself and how to
get you along
since and how many people have to merge
to do that it's better than commodities
margarine superior than crap and if you
wanted to small the exactly what already
bought like for me like my farm I
brought my father ten pounds so I had to
build me be a lot larger farm
I made my farm ten thousand square feet
because it was being craft and I know
that I can move all those ten thousand
so I don't worry about it so why do I
want to stress on your farm
so what I recommend to people is
diversify what you do like you've got to
have some more skill sets in the game
when I when I go to do what I do I look
at it from a bunch of the respectives at
once because I realized a long time ago
I could be wrong because I knew that i
sat there a selfie front I said oh [ __ ]
the nursery guy stores I was done I had
a pretty messed up a tree and I realized
that I didn't have the tree cover guy
because every single branch was
dependent on the hole and I didn't have
a home and so I said all Christ so this
is
so I was surprised how my so-called
brothers I know but like what you're
going to realize though is that we're
not in that time period though you're
another time period now it's yourself
table mentally
did you agree to get in the deal
nobody honest is ever gotten [ __ ] by
shady person you had to win Oh sounds
too good to be true
while women participate