so Nate thank you so much for having me
over to the farm today the tour was like
exhilarating actually I have never seen
Google culture deployed at such a size
you know permaculture classes and stuff
you'll see one or a couple and of course
I've seen lots of books where where you
get a side view of one so you understand
how they're built but your your Google
culture field is like astonishing right
and it's really cool right now because
you know some of them are finished and
you're already planted into them whereas
other of them are still like these holes
and you're building them out I'll never
be able to describe it as well as you
will so so just tell us about that that
Google culture deployment
yeah well it's a it's been a challenge
from the beginning we've we hope to have
everything done by the Solstice and here
we are a couple weeks past that and
we're still working on it so we've we've
had a lot of issues sourcing material to
put into our hue goals we have a lot of
downed wood we've been bringing in PG&amp;E
for some for some electricity so we've
done some brush clearing some tree
thinning stuff like that so we've had
some sources just getting it down to the
farm and and into its proper home has
been a big challenge give people an idea
of how big it is right because for most
people they'll be like getting stuff
your hookah culture is simply just grab
that
but like you need a hell of a lot yeah
yeah so we're doing sixty three hundred
square feet is the size of our of our
plot and you know we're doing somewhere
around 14 or 15 hue goals that average
from 25 feet wide all the way up to
almost 75 feet wide so it's a lot of
biomass it takes because that's all
going into the ground it is it is and
and we've seen different methods of
doing Hugo culture and mounting it up
just on your native soil we decided to
actually trench out some some holes and
esque of eight three feet down and
backfill with rotten firewood that we've
had around the property
in some of these down trees to get in
there so getting it all down in to where
it needs to go has been a challenge but
but it's almost all there and it feels
good now that it's there so yeah I
believe in ila I like that you
incorporated those big those big bags
that I saw last time I was here that I
posted to my Instagram what were those
with those 300 gallons 200 gallon 200
gallons and so um you know it's one
thing to see the the big tree sections
there and then you're filling it in with
you know brush and the the natural
forest what did you call it fluff for
stuff that's on the ground yeah but then
you know by by you pouring all of that
you know aged and loved active living
soil on it you're you're pretty much
inoculating it with all the best parts
of your last several seasons right I
mean that's the idea we're hoping so
yeah that's kind of what we're shooting
for is the mound of decaying firewood
below mixed with some of the native soil
that's been excavated out we've ran into
tons of rock so that's been a challenge
as getting some of the big boulders out
of there but we're really excited about
repurposing the rocks so as it's
challenging it's also allowing us to do
other things around the property with
them but yeah we've got the we've got
the native soil back in there and then
the living soil to add some more
microbes to our fungus from the rotting
firewood and then we basically with the
four stuff and the potting soil we top
it off with one more layer of natural
soil that's been excavated out or
collected from the perimeters in
different areas try not to take too much
from one area to kind of do the wild
creature so it mixed up a little bit
from here a little bit from there right
right for one reason for diversity of
different areas but also you don't want
to take too much from one area right
yeah and strip it right right exactly um
you know the the you know on one end
you've got the Google cultures that are
you're literally building out today as
soon as I get out of your way right and
you've got the other ones that already
planted and you know any plant when it
gets trans
is gonna have some amount of shock and
so they're all like you know ten days in
and they're all kind of rebounding yeah
that must have a whole lot of complex
feels for you right because here we are
in the first licensed and taxed season
in California and you're trying to do
two things you're both trying you're
you're deploying this new growing tech I
mean not that it's new that it's never
existed before but being introduced to
both your farm and cannabis in general
but but you're also doing this I'm not
like the highest pressure cannabis
season in California ever where
everybody's trying to make money and not
lose the farm because everything's kind
of a mess right now that must mean there
must be challenges in that for you to
both be wanting to do this creatively
and sustainably and good for the
environment but also know that you can
give you if you screw up and it's a big
deal oh it's definitely a big deal I
think I explained to you earlier that
the place that we're cultivating is
typically about half of our our yield in
years past and looking down at it right
now it's a it's definitely an unsettling
feeling to to see how small everything
is at this point of the year but we did
try to make up for that a little bit by
increasing plant counts we're going more
in a
and in the same area so we're just
hoping that it's gonna fill in and do
what it needs to do I'm I'm cautiously
optimistic but I think it's I think it's
gonna be okay the one thing that we were
kind of contemplating too was maybe to
just have the have the square footage
sit sit dormant for this year and plant
a cover crop on it um but we decided
that it was worth the challenge to go
ahead and take it on and it's so far
it's turning out okay I think it's not
gonna be a total failure but it's not
gonna be the most epic thing we knew
that coming in - we knew that we'd heard
you know some trials and tribulations
other places that inspired us and we
also feel that with hopefully the market
being as low as it can get right now you
know that it's not going to affect us
too much and that the price per unit is
lower so at least you're using soil
that's already alive you know because
you use the soil from the 200 pound bag
or the 200 gallon bags and put them in
there you know a lot of people who will
build a Google culture from scratch
they'll use you know fresh you know
potting soil or something and then
they'll inoculate this and that and then
it really takes a year for it to kind of
all kind of gel together but by using
the soil that's already activated in it
I would think that as soon as your roots
of your newly transplanted plants hit
down its be like hitting the mother lode
and they're gonna like oh you know you
know here here's a raizou sphere here's
a here's you know the mycelium here's
everybody and then they'll and then I
guess that's the I hope right yeah
fingers crossed for sure right on so so
you said that you increased your plant
counts this year to give you more more
room for error essentially and and I
think you said that you're you're about
three times the size of what your
medical 215 grow was yeah yeah I think
somewhere around there we're not all
completely planted yet so it's it's
still up in the air but somewhere in
that neighborhood so one of the reasons
that
visited you before and why I just I'm
generally attracted to moon time
medicinals product is is because you use
KNF inputs right you're not a big fan of
bottled stuff and a lot of what you're
putting in starts on the farm and then
you know you fpj it and then you're
putting it on your own plants so so
everything's happening here
so two-part question number one can you
tell me a little bit about what you're
growing on the property that you're then
then then you're then fermenting and
then also what it's been like to scale
up from you know where you've been the
last several years growing for what was
essentially a third of what you've got
going you know that kind of scaling you
know you're not using small mason jars
anymore right things get much bigger at
that point so so kind of color that in
for us would you yeah so so previously
using K and F on our veggie garden is
essentially the only experience that
we've had in it in previous years and we
do 2,000 square feet in the veggie
garden so when training is a good
training but when you scale it up to 13
5 you know it's a it's a challenge and
like you said starting out with mason
jars we've actually started to employ
our pickling crocks
that we've used in previous years for
kim cheese and Krauts and things like
that so i've got three large crocks that
we ferment various things we do horse
tail that's just harvested locally on
the property
will do pea shoots from our cover crops
that's one thing that we grow purposely
for that we'll do lemon balm to add for
terpenes to to our plants we're hoping
that the the correlation there
translates straight to our plants will
do trying to think what else would do
some of our cannabis plants will do our
males will do get some comfrey comfrey
comes along for sure that'll go in there
at times thistle just anything that
grows around the property and is
it's very vigorous and doesn't show much
susceptibility to anything is what we
like to use thistles is a really good
one in the horse tail probably two
really good examples of that but but
yeah beyond that we've we've got into
the L a B and we've got into some of the
other stuff we're just scratching the
surface on some of the on some of the
more complicated I guess ok enough
ferments we're really excited about
getting the fish going we're gonna
source some fish from for mountain
shelter Co from a commercial fisherman
so that'll be good you know if you're
gonna do that you should listen to the
the interview I did with Chris Trump he
talks about how while you're doing that
for your plans also do something for
your own fish sauce for your house you
know and he's all like he's all like you
wouldn't think you want to eat it but oh
my god it's so good so I might I might
need to get some of that from you too
yeah um so so let's talk a little bit
about the trade-off of you know right so
you're you're you know you've never been
a big bottle guy and now you're really
going whole into producing your own
inputs it takes time right it takes the
time to eat yourself educated to collect
the stuff on the property to go through
and ferment it you have to wait for it
to ferment then you're straining and and
you know bottling part doesn't take much
time and then and then implementing it
whereas other people are all like and
they open the bottle and they go to town
right yeah what do you see the trade-off
being behind the the time that it takes
to produce the the ferments and the the
your yield increases versus saving the
time and using a bottle and you know
because that's a that's a trade-off and
I and I know you weigh those in very
particular ways yeah I certainly do I
feel a lot of the nutrients in the
bottle and ingredients that I use tend
to be really expensive they're high
quality
the nutrients or microbes and I've just
found that with the way the markets
going the way the margins are shrinking
that that is the best way that I know of
to to increase my bottom line is to take
out the things that I can certainly
control and we we love microbes we'd
love to put as many different microbes
as we can into the soil that's been our
strategy in years past but now we're
just trying to make them on our own by
doing the IMO boxes and and you know
doing different doing different things
to harness what we have locally and try
and use that as our goal and I feel like
the time that that takes is directly
equivalent if not a money savings to
going and buying a bottle of nutrients
somewhere and you know it goes without
saying the environmental impact of the
of the waste and stuff like that the
micro plastics or or something yeah it
totally gets you and you know like this
you know you're a probiotic grower right
and so the idea that you're producing
your own inputs
I would think offers a lot of
self-satisfaction - right like I'm doing
it my way dammit you know that kind of
doing yeah so um so the last question I
have for you is that you know this is a
really you know this is a
once-in-a-lifetime summer this summer
because you know people have shifted to
the licensed and taxed environment and
you know you've been a farmer for years
and years and you got into your cycle of
how you spread your time when you do
things and you get into a you know a
farmer routine but then this year you're
you're having to deal with like all this
other random stuff like like find a
distributor develop packaging develop
your new website and and logos you know
you know find extraction partners go to
County meetings go to your track and
trace class
and and and in okay work with PG need a
fight to try to get your power here what
you know what's your experience been
this year that's unique in trying to do
all of that bureaucratic stuff while
you're also actually just trying to be a
farmer yeah it's it's been a big
challenge we we staffed up a little bit
from years past I guess just recently
initially I tried to try to do it with
just me and my lead cultivator and I
found that I was being pulled in way too
many different directions and we needed
to bring a couple more guys in so we
brought in a couple new hires they've
been great additions and they've they've
picked up on a lot of things they've
brought a lot of their own knowledge in
which is good from the from the Humboldt
State botany and Forestry Department so
we've had we've had a lot of really good
help and I'm lucky to have yeah I feel
like that's that's been the the big
thing is while I love to be out and
getting my hands dirty I need to free
myself up and be able to do some things
in heaven some people that I can really
rely on even with the really high
quality everyone's distracted by legal
and licensed related stuff that they've
got it - are you finding that that you
and your people are kind of behind -
just because it's such an
extraordinarily yeah you know it's
already showing some benefits and
you know it's it's good to see it's good
to get it done it all the way something
that we strongly water conservation is
the thing that really is kind of stood
out with me on this project and how much
those plants is gonna just soak up all
the water so cool well I'm excited to
see it cuz I've just you know I've never
seen Google culture deployed at that
size at all for anything they even food
but then to see with my favorite plant
on it it's really exciting so so so
we'll come back in in September when
they're all looking beautiful and and
we'll bring the drone with us yeah and
we'll get some we'll get some good above
shots so sorry thanks for your time best
of luck man thank you for right