all right but you want to put your cell
phones on vibrate and have a deeper into
GaN welcome everybody to the two o'clock
panel if you are looking from grandmomma
make sure you know that this is not
paralyzed cultivation is actually
designing and marching handed confused
products so only you are my plate I am
your vote for the panel and also both of
the shaping fire podcast
Shango go if you enjoyed this names you
experts at the top of the canvas field
talking about their discipline I
encourage you to pick up a hook card and
here's the work and to listen to my show
I also want to invite you all to a party
tonight that is being thrown by don't
magazine they have they have reserved
the route I have two Clarendon hotel and
are have legal throwdown so everyone is
invited our our panel today will be
ultra Val will talk about forty minutes
and then will be some time at the end
for question so if you think of a
question during the panel you don't need
to rewrite it down so that you don't
forget and and also if you if you want
to show us how to friends partners and
loved one you can feel free to find the
recording of this panel on my youtube
channel at Shango books
so first let's welcome our guests from
the far side we've got a tripped up
from empower oil in the middle is Nancy
Whiteman from water Grande and on right
next to me we've got James Dix from LA
our dispensary so well with all of you
so so these are merely highlights of
each speakers bio they are all very
accomplished professionals but just to
give you an idea who we have with us
today truth whoa Michael they're just on
the far end he is founder of empower
body here need one of the country's top
ten Canada's companies behind on
magazine and empowered bodies here
provides both hemp and Candice infuse
healing topical products and one an
array of local and national product
Awards in the middle Danby is co-founder
and co-owner a lot of grants which
produces wine animals you want to
extract a lot of digital lot of red the
Colorado's number one health producer by
revenue and now has expanded Oregon
Nevada and soon Illinois and the
entities responsible for partnerships
and latency greetings domestically and
internationally and she's got an MBA
from University of Massachusetts at
Amherst and on the board of the Canada's
business Goliath James Dix is head of
patient services for modern wellness
center right here in Scottsdale Arizona
modern is the provider of Kiva products
grappa States and Jay has extraordinary
experience with understanding patient
needs and reducing suffering using
cannabis
elements so very happy to have this an
experience count-o how we're going to do
this is best series of questions we're
going to start in one end and then the
other and then hopefully enlisted a
little bit of conversations around um so
so let's get going so let's start with
you here Jane and then we'll work our
way down
oh I get that
point out that you know that the topic
is kind of general with designing and
marketing of Canada's imbue spot so
you'll notice a little bit of the
difference in the answers because Jane
and Nancy are both while they both are
topical thereafter teas and edibles
insurance on the end is more about
hopping so we're going to read a little
creative on how we work questions but
don't don't know understand long
so Jane patients require a wide range of
doses you know some as well as two and a
half milligrams and others do up to and
over a hundred milligrams of THC even
border before considering the CBD
component so you know from the hippies
of a product designer when designing a
limited range of products that are
getting going the market for public sale
what do you think are the best default
settings dosages to bring from market or
patient you want to thank you
initiatives in Russia Asia
our products are five milligrams
and our high grams chopped apart and I
often take people on the chocolate a
hundred days of Bari have many of their
problems every letter but I for me
unless the pages in 104 I do have an
important occasion
I generally started by going over 2.5
cement I medicate the station at night
for 10 days so then I'm heading
information at night for 10 days the
best observer in their age is never have
hands before and then that makes a
transition someday a lot emails are not
white and do not to me you have to do it
it might not be everyone so so to
reorient you had independent when
designed products for the market
specifically because patients leave such
a wide range how do you know what
milligrams bring the market that's idiot
emotionally so you know we have two
options with the Kiva confessions
they're danced by milligram auctioneer
and family as a treatment and Russian
whatever that movies the people is
coming in as recreation you have to camp
artists if you sign up into what you
know so for example when I get like
people are home
it's unfortunate I love Graham swear
that I have a perimeter is 50 milligrams
of mind to iron my wall so something
your answer is on subdivide Bowl Noah
grant in whatever the product is right
great okay well to some sort of an
interesting question there's certainty
murder fest in this one is the dotage of
the individual donated products and in
Colorado we are mandated by law on the
adult side of the market so you have a
maximum of 100
the products on the right side and they
have to be 28 into no more than 10
milligrams unit so that part of the
dissent Stone Medical has more
flexibility now we have chosen to have a
range of dosages within our digital
products and we have a line of gummies
and heart lozenges and caramels and
other confectionery we have an option
the real answer
shondo is that only really truly know
what is most I could do because there's
something variables to that there's
individual metabolism there is the
condition that they treated their how
the body processes animal so our our
philosophy is to provide people with a
range of options so that they can
experiment and see with me what works
for them that we currently have products
that are 28 + 2 5 10 and 20 milligrams
division and we rough amount
Micra just a two-week time so I think
our basic a lot to be and what we help
promote the industry is start low and go
slow
is it not completely for people who are
new to candidates and vehicles
the last thing the probably wanted
somebody has not uncomfortable as
barriers to that and so we spend a lot
of time out of the field talking about
tenders about animal metabolism and how
people experience them and how they
should be working with their patients
and their customers and because of
Colorado Minnesota State and we're
particularly going to live to torrent
and movie who really have a child a
little thing work and always really
encouraging people to start low and
guess what their body can tolerate
before having a hundred kind of our
quantity on sure yet so careful to be an
apple into their hands I wanted over the
last two thousand five of and
or relationships and network that I
don't like go under 45 percent online
per unit for example in either CVD or
change in 2003 fabulous about a decision
that said I won't like you and on the
edibles because I love them starting at
you would punch 5mm there it's
interesting because one how's the
edibles you know there seems to be a lot
of the needs for variety up to around 25
milligrams people sweet spot you know
they went be at two point five and it
might be at 15 and sometimes this
different depending on who they're
purchasing from so there's a lot of a
lot of different than me up to 25 but if
something these above 25 milligram a
chances are likely that they are eating
to taste so much GHD to deal with no
kitronik pain or whatever their issue is
that they're probably gaining home and
so fast that third you know they're
gonna really be dating art and so these
are the people who take you know 100
milligram hard break it in half and half
now half later and so as far as the
product designer goes it sounds like has
a lot of variety of low end and it going
slow and great start Monica yeah there
you go
the silicon still know where we can
start on the other night so this much
for you trip this so so as far as on
infuse topicals go you know Canada stop
them to become very popular through pain
relief but there's a lot of debate in
with product designer
that carrier oils are because some are
seeking to be on top of the derma for
some little writes that hang them up red
others who are self for pain early and
so you have to break through the derma
so I'd like to hear from you when your
are on carrier oils for both of those
applications and then we'll come this
direction up great so I first like you
probably one for an emergency room is
one towards faster than better than an
ER well however you come to the MoMA so
you have to choose a different sugar
little Cupid you lots of people like to
use coconut oil grapeseed oil I've heard
noggin I will but first one is my
favorite because it's light and I hope
you all are doing pop this with your
label we are an object optical and
we have Ungerman store in come in and
what the question they are thoughtful is
they're expensive
is there a chance without a builder to
this console and I always try to stop
them and say you're asking the person is
because we're in - you can step all
night so nothing's really no canvas up
but you know I try it ejected Lee most
of the canvas oil the knowledge is
basically an amenity times not topics in
the room until I come back
and I guess for a lot of patience no
stability is a big deal so especially
trying to get relief water bed work in a
collection Avenue I don't see your eyes
lips actually because they are smart and
users who are super to use our products
are not normally
codify necklace okay so in baseless is a
crystalline power form of just teach the
a or sweetie
I like using they don't smell like
whether that said most of the people
really capable really doesn't canvas on
the other form and we thought at first
we find the Gateway Eileen
[Music]
any any idea so what happened is is that
she's using the the CBD here in the CBD
or th da that's been blatantly separated
from the rest of the whole plant and so
you're not getting to the terpene
profile which is the aromatherapy of the
plan right and so she knows specifically
that she's are want to use th ba and or
CBD in reply so if you peel off the
terpenes in that day it doesn't and you
can use the positive aspects she's going
with but without without the smell that
would let lets your co-workers know with
the three and pardon us because the such
a little in use in my product also
nitrogen profiles that are beneficial
for pain inflammation is a trauma
so it's combining the three classic
energy in the formulation to clinical
depression great so much in Virginia you
know do you make a fifty-fifty Hanako
happy de I know it is what is it going
to mmm P and we're a really long time
made it work for everything right right
so so this next question we'll start
with immunity so so we're an
international day so we're going to
primarily I'm going to ask the question
in a way that we be speaking about
patience right but I know that you're
you working a lot of black market so
feel free to you know speak to that as
well but one be my I do not have infused
product manufacturers using artificial
ingredients of their products you know
colors sometimes they're using sugar and
it will talk about patient that's not
necessarily going to be best for
something with a compromised immune
system so in your experience how
important is it to avoid artificial
colors and flavors and sugar using these
inputs when making commercially
available edibles for the greater market
we all know that lots of people are
getting authorization and using medical
products or for light enjoyment as well
but in because we are here in Arizona
we're taking primarily in a medical way
so so please it's an eating question and
I will answer the couple different ways
the first is that there's actually
objective data that you
to be here tomorrow with Joe Harris from
be an analytic community speaking there
have been so I'm from Colorado in and
worse than Colorado Boulder and having
cancer at all things politically correct
and if it's at all natural so if there
was ever a place in the universe where
there's going to be people pushing back
on artisan colors and flavors and all
the rest of that it would be Boulder
Colorado and I have to tell you that I
definitely see images with you before as
all use in doesn't matter than most
people truthfully people will say it
matters but when it comes to what people
actually purchase we all know that we're
not a piece of dip right there are
plenty of products out there that have
artificial colors or flavors and
certainly almost every popular edible
product in Colorado has sugar mine
included and they all do just fine being
in the track sooner free product it
barely a blip on the screen of what is
sold so you know you guys can draw your
own conclusions about what I'm saying
certainly a perfect world if you are
compromised immune system or medical
issues in a perfect world it's probably
best to avoid all of those things on the
other hand if you're even coming this
this big I don't know that's a huge
shift personally if for some patients
the only way they can have be palatable
but they gain I am that's right yes yeah
so I I do adding a page when I'm
faulting them and I ask them what kind
of dietary decisions they develop on and
then I just call their lead and you know
there's teachers and honey you know
kinda animals that unions in cages that
are you know gateway sugar
um but I kinda concur with her even
though you know on the encirclement and
non-gmo organic defense rating them I
get quite like that but my little
fifteen now in the dark
Winston Churchill adjacent our
convenience helpers are genetically done
if I they were hot for the skin healthy
I need to put a German and a lap but
yeah a senior honey um since you're all
business people since you're here I'm
going to contextualise this little bit
worse business point of view even though
that wasn't exactly the question I
recognize that when you step back and
look at animal torture right now it's
not a highly segmented market and what I
mean by that is you know I have people
who come to me with some regularity
almost whispering things I have and I'm
always very polite and you know I think
you know unless ones like NBA with me
don't even tells me but they don't want
to tell us
and they do and always something closing
this she like it's working on a team
laws as you know and and what I really
want to say to that generally is into
the world you might have an issue that I
in the cannabis world you're going to go
out of business in about a month right
because the industry just isn't
segmented enough at this point of time
and the market is large enough for us to
have all these different locations so we
all want to do good in the world
but right now doing good in the proteins
that you have to stay afloat as a
business right so you have to take that
reality into account you know before you
come out with products that are so super
an issue that there just isn't enough of
a market to support them that's kind of
business reality island from my
perceptive yeah I think that's a good
way I was down in California speaking
and Buddha gave me a sample which ended
up being the best out of what I've ever
had and it was instead of fun version
and so it was the Persian style jelly
and it was delicious
I had want to do the fact that it was
Persian style jelly that it was again as
edible but when the packaging you know
we talked about in each of the niche
market first of all you have to know
what gives you is and then you have
joining in your candidates out of the
jelly so delicious so so so so Jane what
the challenges with marketing topical to
that patients want to use it sparingly
to save money and yet the whole thing
with topical that you maybe use
regularly throughout the day so you know
you work a lot with patients what part
of anything that you can share about
encouraging patient compliance to use
the topical when they're at with a ton
of trying to save money but I'm not
using pop so I have a strange analogy
link you to paint in the night when they
come into the first time and I tell them
they're like a car with a lever base and
the one hanging image so I tell them on
that TV and should not reward if you're
division for 30 days you need to get at
least 30 days and I compare it I did
this here we are on Amol online okay
you're going to be delivered a much
bigger bag to me you don't know if your
body's working that you know we
translation so I get them on
and then I start talking about computing
job will turn around I say to them you
know it dis is best used when your pores
are open after a shower or you can grab
a few mama tell you have gone through
the top lock don't make that resolve for
three to five days start unit using at
night for good reason I want you to know
they it determine our offices you got it
is not but I don't set any false
expectations I don't plan out and I
teach fourth grade I am that
authoritative here waitress but they
understand and they don't go home and
call me the nine days day Almighty eat
it work because they know they know you
can take time so when people come in the
day I'm heated here is I did / call my
prescriptions down the mother and our
people disappoint because you're going
to get me awesome oh my gosh you know
and so I say to people sure you on in
Kansas to musicals you give it a month
two months three months and three months
reaching which is quantity and
accommodation where your reduced rate
you know if you have minimum but you
know everything takes time it took you
time to get a big to develop it and you
can try to get you off focus people want
instance
all digital media and I'm sorry but we
going to go back to the lighting crane
right now because you get all these
candies knocked at the Furious equipment
did you want to lay it let me go
corollary to this so we don't have a
chuckles but we do have a family of
extended-release castle to my knowledge
the only and release castle on the
market but it is the theory to the more
things which aim is talking about that
we have to do a lot of training with you
to understand and we need to build up
your system so for any amenities product
not just for Canada so I think it's an
expectation is the key to having you
have successful experiences with these
types of products the un's is love I run
this a lot so you know everybody
different so for some people they apply
the oil and women in it would be a
bigger problem my patience that's it
we have a location to let us know that
it took three days for them to get labs
and results and what analysis were the
analogy is that your honor than analysis
needs to be boosted
people are tradition right so when
you're applying them when you're
applying about the products to treat you
know pain your inhalation what you're
doing is in through here by ability to
take care of itself
in that spot over and over and over
again so the client you know classes up
at the day in the beginning will allow
the mutton cooling afternoon once or
twice a day or every other day you know
two weeks later so little analysis okay
when you were designing your packaging
how would you weigh how to you know
explain the usage of it because you want
them enough compliance that it helps we
also don't want to say that small feet
on weeks so don't want to wait it out
for yourself or the package suppliers
well that's a great question
so I recommend a cleanser put it where
it hurts
coming in pratik right
the most oxygen at maths and interaction
by my package it says to bury me I
guarantee ya soul on this next question
rift certainly at that problems that
were back here done in from this way so
I know this is kind of general question
but when were to elicit conversation so
so for generations infused products were
made from trim which until recently with
no tracks right and I hope you can do it
but today now infused product designers
have an array of mirin materials that
they can choose from they can go from
trims a whole flower to purchasing
extracted would added product designer
you've got a lot of options so so what
advice would you offer a hot designer in
the room considering one material to use
for their in cheese box
well the first thing to the pieman have
a sooner source so even into your mind
extracted oil you go to the farm labor
map check out another grown package of
large be how they care for their plant
see what kind of chemicals even that
trying to or DNA really where that right
so no you know you're producing that
it's actually a very interesting
question so even in visiting Colorado
since 2010 and back in the day there was
no extract as well that you can buy and
I would like it into our Katie before in
Motor Company you said I want to build
cars you believe this fantastic first
you need to learn onyx deal right but
now we have choices so one of the
answers to the question depends on what
it is that you're trying to do so
Trixie was talking before about I slid
which are the purest format you can get
the other big trend in let's see right
now is dead fluid which is usually we
start out with an extract said well you
know co2 would extract the oil is the
most general one in Egypt and secondary
technique which is called twelve ounces
which there's actually a variety of ways
to do this solution I mean with it the
strips out after the chlorophyll it
opens ourselves to some church okay and
the turkey in addition to adding smell
to the product although we have
traditional data set and and they're
also the determinant of whether an
individual like indica or sativa feels
like a sativa
so what you're trying to make in the
class specific animal that has some
properties in it
pima's not cultivated we can talk about
later too but you wouldn't want to use
an extracted well that had gone through
this process you either want to extract
it yourself or you want to buy will be a
lot of collocation around so there's
that variable on what you're trying to
do that the other issue is just what
what are your capabilities as it
happening to do your own extraction
requires equipment a recorded guilt that
and the requires more time so you know
we read you about my extraction of oil
devices live and we also have co2
extractors and four years ago mutating
structures which we chose taken down but
you know one of the things that happened
is capture for you to the first level
extraction with the trend whether you're
using co2 or whether using solvent
systems work a level secondary process
that has to happen where your winter on
your removing the black soot and it has
a lot of time to the process so if
you're very kind of all you company like
we are there is a big advantage to you
and extract oil and using the
tell me some of the properties with the
turkey that had these things up
instantly so it is not the home great
for answer real answer is it depends if
you are trying to get what we call the
entourage effect or get the added
everything the plans that you probably
wanted to your attraction to yoga so I'm
in a dingy John here I am you know this
years ago in a hand would you be trim
today I don't know but that right now
you're had an engineering major animals
at random or is there deserve reason why
that you're worth what number one you
know it quality and call me up and quit
I laugh on it look at like how to trim
that was one out semantical place it is
not a pretty sight
does not believe that the people that
are successful
you that padded on occasion Colorado
Japan to give a different perspective
most ethical companies in Colorado still
make your edibles from trim and they
extracted themselves really the
extracted oil industry is just starting
to really take hold in Colorado and to
have an option that larger companies are
looking at it obediently absolutely
beautiful trim with love THC and CBD
that rival you know a whole plant and
you know you get more on the coal plant
that you have to pay for a lot of times
much for it
so from an economics point of view I
would say if you're not in a state that
has a robot extracted oil awesome for
you jump shy away from trim it's a great
way to point right have to know your
source be added even within any
particular state you can have people who
are producing high-quality trim and
beloved wishes my life over tracks right
grant oh so now I know your source and
then go to the facility and see how to
get you to rate the loan
time for able to quickly learn up one of
the things that we do in trend I highly
encourage anybody issues into Genesis we
track and measure every possible metric
there is contra we measure the potency
we measure the smell of color
the final meal after which rise
everything is measured as - the strain
levels so when were negotiating prices
on shrimp we do if Rene's a lot of mal
chattel over target I want to clarify
the loading remember ultimately I think
that you're talking about changers
active everything ships not moving
traveling directly to main thread yes
and and you're talking about lying to me
turning it into an extract right so I
you into an oil user by clicking a photo
like in other words people that trying
to visit don't use trim just straight up
meeting product to product
yeah yeah it is and to know this so you
can use pesticide on flower or other
plant and have their flower path or
pesticide test but the German will pass
so be really careful about that field
you know Emporium in the strictest test
regulation of the nation and it's really
important that we as we mature in our
life so they will start with you on this
last question
so what consideration should use product
designers think about when it comes to
shelf-life that's a great one so we
first started out we have in our lineup
a variety of base good and under time we
completely phase them out because we
found the arts we thought was really
things that have long shelf life the
only way that we could figure out how to
make a brownie class from where the two
weeks is with a multimeter
we didn't want to do now that said I
have good friends in the industry who do
they taste good and they have to get out
somehow and shelf-life we never did
so we dealt with as much as a great
whole thing so we just everything is one
of our core criteria for salon Jeanne
process is that it has a shelf life of
at least six months and we also do shelf
like testings we actually when you're
making products we actually have a
little thing that we put in many kind of
simulates different durations long shelf
so it's a really really important
consideration in a state like ours which
is a fairly good-sized obtain for us to
get out to the western slope which is
you know we're in folders so that's a
good five to six hour drive we're only
sending our couriers or outside couriers
out there once a week so you know we
have a product that begins to get
stamper to week you're going to end up
having customers in on station we're not
very happy with it
so we have a we have a small basis and
under mm perfect so when we order at
home and I'm not by much comprised of
German surprise Malo the kitchen
it's only a week order and we turn on
the bevel living [__] and it's kind of
amazing to me how badly the patients are
because I am a the other day in LA
because ml by month if you have picture
is impression they know anyone and you
know you don't have to move to keep
those work in our favor that we turn me
on that plane and I don't want to camp
around the inside is actually a really
good it really is like a retailers right
because if your distributor is willing
to deliver to you more often it not only
does it mean that you got thresher
products but also your revenue stream is
going to be more balanced because you're
not putting out larger sums of money
every two weeks it's a consistent amount
that's really a cycle just Imani happen
so top it with a little bit difference
again not our Boyle County or someone
deletes I'm usually important I'm
currently working on lotion and
not put after ingredient coalition and
how to have a great shelf life is
actually pretty challenging so I think I
found what we need in order to do it
naturally loop with punch right service
bubbling out then right on
so again Patrick all questions do we
have a yes
when I stand on the feet up in is a
really big part of the West's job and
what you guys recommend Adam education
for dyslexia and what you go are you
about doing that was the best way to get
make sure that about your Australian
arms in the proper way but fortunately I
can manage on that were actually the
process of building out a much more
in-depth training programs and we go
into the dispensaries and do much
entertaining and adventury and we're
actually partnering with that
in my own company to really help them
understand not just the basics of you
know start or go slow but really helping
them understand how animals are
metabolized in the body and in a little
bit deeper into that now in Colorado we
have some very large very large content
as well you know 15 17 store chain and
they do have a lot more training
material themselves but the average
smaller dispensary chains were the wrong
ones
in general I think it's the
responsibility of manufacturers to be
bringing that information to them and
helping them do the very best apt for
their customers I agree also and after
that we go to the winter training both
in the dispensaries that we're all
driven program where we're bringing in
at our facility and take off teaching
classes there
so we have a hotel team they go down and
they do they do giveaways and they
educate by gender disability and
education but in their timing if I'm
saying give me the quality good your
budget isn't talking dimension a lot in
general immediately a lot more awareness
intervene on view courses you're
currently market for you will see there
being market for edible infused products
with other cannabinoids as I played for
an entire spectrum absolutely guaranteed
question yeah yeah he's billion
basically what he happens is there a
market for other cannabinoids and
specifically other now I didn't use
products and absolutely the answer that
I can find both PvP and PvE that realize
my product as well so one of the things
that happening on the extraction worlds
is that people the ability to extract
getting more precise
and so they are beginning to be able to
consistently pull off the other
cannabinoid at least some of them
there's 100 three of them so but I'm CVG
PDMP you know the Chief Justice
mentioned and be queer the future of the
industry is coming and animals included
is to really leverage that is only to
extract precisely and then just stop
things the different ratios to attract
democratical concerns and creates to the
big experiences now that I think we're
quite a ways away from being able to
Jian effectively because we don't really
have a lot of experience or database of
duty time yet but that's where it's
going if you look at very conditional
products you know you see it's our
galaxy HP in Fiji LAFD be an acylium
paas they industry is moving and you
know you can you can come up with all
these types of do wonderful things but
until you and I look into this
contenders to talk about they're going
to sit there so you not be careful they
can comes open up too early with that
each product tree without the education
like research to back so you know a lot
of people with a lot of good intentions
are way ahead of time
point it you're going to design product
that it is using a minor cannabinoid
make sure you know your suppliers in the
same business to you the I thought that
happened in Oregon totally came out as a
really great CDN tab that helps you go
to sleep and then they started selling
the heck out of them and then there's a
fireman under and known as well as
escalating CBM so that we have got time
for over budget desert who makes your
progress let me get let me sirs on what
makes that product we begin to create to
do to the word and Medicaid would fax
your foundation that this is a medical
product it's really a regulatory
distinction as opposed to a distinction
of the product itself we have in
Colorado we have an employee of adult
use because the same problems in both
market there's not anything that makes a
medical products medical company
formulation point of view it's just the
Challenger which household
we have time for our questionnaires
yes only that country's economic
question Billy whew fortunately I played
and fortunately prior to have different
Android region Korea top deeper level in
a product market as opposed to more
common problems with that little
boutique that when a mood of a reunion
we cook using it capital or some other
product as that Android interview
vehicle top idli you can't so I'll sit
I'll take the first leg of this question
when I first start out and the three and
we will start make make a not comments
about old England is on the castle mine
got reaction was the typical grassroots
committee you know we're trying to get
away from the middle
why would somebody want to take a
cannabis bill but you know as time
progresses you see the advantage I think
in the opportunity and matter of choice
I think both methods of obtaining your
medicine are going to be here to stay
I see a lot of people bringing castles
in cinder every's and I think that
goodnight I mean people being chosen so
there's a certain percentage of people
that just will never you know I didn't
the other thing that I would say about I
agree with the choice and the other
thing is that different people pies
metabolize things differently and
there's different levels of bioavailable
ee depending on people how people create
their capsules navigate they're edible
and different people just try the
different things work well for them so
that implemented choices even just
beyond me do I want to trade or joint
want a castle to lose house entire body
great fantastic so before we finish I
want to make sure I plug again the dole
magazine party is evening at the rock on
the roof of the Clarendon hotel rooftop
and other than that although also the
next panel will include tropical athlete
Mark Washington wish be fantastic and so
let us thank Trista hotel
Nancy
Oh