her name yeah good morning to you here
we go
so Catherine thank you so much for
sharing some of your time with me you
know the reason why I'm so excited to
talk to you was that yesterday on the
tour here at 7 acres you know you were
the one of the first people that I met
and and you were surrounded by
beneficial insects and and I'm like ooh
my people all right and and and as you
you know gave me your part of the tour
I realized that you were doing something
that a lot of other folks in cannabis
say they do but in practice they don't
and that's integrated pest management so
for many folks you ask somebody you know
what their strategies are for IPM and
they'll say we spray which is just like
one thing or you say what's your
integrated pest management they're like
oh we use beneficial bugs and that's
just one thing but when I came here
you're responsible for millions and
millions of dollars of plans and and you
showed me a whole array of strategies
that you use to keep the pest pressure
down and you integrate them and and I'm
like oh my gosh this is legit integrated
pest management and so I'm really glad
that you had a little time this morning
so that maybe you can lay out the
strategy to give folks an idea of what
it looks like scaled and done with a
proper budget right so so would you
please start with you know kind of just
walk us through your strategy for
keeping pests pressure low here at 7
acres so we we do a very integrated
approach so I work with production
sanitation our own department and our
focuses more on prevention and not
reaction so we've found over the years
that the best way to keep our press
pressure down is to not have them in the
first place
so we track
we have our scouts they track everything
so if there's a plant alive on our
facility one of our trained IPM staff is
looking at that plant once a week it's
very intensive but we we track
everything that could be weird-looking
or Oh what is this and we do it so often
so we can react quickly to any issues
that may arise and I can you know call
one of our suppliers and say I need X
and I have it next week and we don't see
anything the week after we also work
with sanitation so they're doing a
phenomenal job in this facility and that
is actually the key to a successful IPM
program is the cleanliness we're not
seeing any recurrence or very minimal
reoccurrence of pests in rooms and we
work together very closely it's I don't
know what you just switch deer spray to
on turnover but it is working please
keep that up we also do formal
monitoring with sticky cards in all our
rooms and our beneficial insects is
actually the our soldiers on the ground
that that are really helping us so it's
a very intensive program we receive our
bugs on one day and the next day they
are throughout the facilities so in in
any given week for insects we're
applying 350 to 400 thousand in a flower
room and and they will hunt out all the
all the little bad guys and keep them at
a very very low pressure which is
amazing so let's start at the beginning
and I'll poke a little bit at each of
those okay absolutely
so first of all you mentioned your
scouting staff right and and I was able
to see it was amazing to find out that
all of these analytics and your scouting
team everybody's all connected by
computers and spreadsheets and and when
folks are scouting and they find
something wrong with a plant that plant
is marked and it's put on the
spreadsheet and
on a map of the room so you know exactly
where it is so then you can monitor the
plants around it I was fully involved
what I want my question is though is the
you had all this big color code of all
the different things that the scouts are
looking for yes and some of those things
I didn't even know what they were so
will you give us an idea of the variety
of things that the scouts are scouting
for oh absolutely so primarily they're
looking for pest damage it's quite easy
to see fun fact about humans as we can
see more shades of green than anything
else so when you're confronted in a room
with that many plants it seems like a
daunting task but once you do it a few
times you actually oh that doesn't look
right
what is that and then we'll look and see
okay no it's it's nothing or it could be
pest damage they're looking for bud rot
like mold they're looking at root
structures so if we see a plant and the
leaves might be a little off-color so
you know we're pulling down the root
bags and taking a look and saying okay
well they're okay now what is their
damage on there they're looking a whole
stalk all the leaves everything which is
it's a lot but they look for that
looking for pretty much anything that
doesn't belong so once once you've been
in in the rooms a few times you you get
to even though every strain it's
different you get to know generally what
cannabis looks like so when you see
something mm-hmm that doesn't belong and
then we jump in and and and figure out
what it is so we look for physical
damage harm to the buds pass any for
material that doesn't belong in there
the the sheet there the spreadsheet that
you showed me where you were marking off
the individual plants they had that long
list on the right-hand side with color
coding how many different categories do
you think there were four four things
that the scouts had to check off if I
had to guess I'm guessing there's maybe
like fourteen or fifteen categor
of the types of damage they're looking
for mm-hmm that's about right it it's
anything that could damage the product
the final product and we also want to
recognize okay is this an isolated
incident or is this spreading so if we
find reoccurring instances we have a
number code as well so I can look at
that map and say okay well we found this
on this side of the room and the same
thing the next week on this side of the
room that might be caused by staff
movement in and out of the rows and if
we pinpoint something and then we start
seeing it all around okay well this is
something that is is spreading from this
point so we can go in and make the
decision do we is this going to affect
our crop do we cut cut the loss and and
get rid of the plant or is there a way
that we can treat this should I just do
a hot spot treatment and bombard this
area with personal s or sworsky or lace
wings depending on what it is so even
before the scouts are going in and going
down this very specific list of things
that they might take off I'm assuming
that just because everybody was in such
heavy gear right that that is probably
step one is just to make sure that the
people are not bringing in stuff from
the outside then they're not moving it
from room to room so will you give us a
like a brief understanding of how the
gear we wear and you know the magic
things we're all stepping on let's give
us a little context for what that stuff
is doing yeah so everything is
controlled it's it's almost like a
research facility tape you wear your
street clothes in but then you are
issued a clean uniform every day
there's an outside company that loggers
them and brings them in I think it's
twice a week
so you change into that in our change
rooms you have dedicated shoes for some
to wear all the rooms are and going into
the rooms if we have a very set order
that you can go into the rooms so our
nursery and our vegetative rooms where
all the production crops are coming from
it's a very set order you can you can go
from one to another to another but if
you have to go backwards you're going
out you're taking a shower you're
getting a new uniform interested into
every room you're wearing gloves a
hairnet it's more at all times in zone 2
even in the hallways and we have we use
isopropyl alcohol 70% to clean our
clothes and that's what you get every
room to like yes you showed me around
every room it's like present your hands
present your hands and at first I mean I
have to at the second room I'm like oh
no I did that in the other room like
ever and they're like no let's let's do
it again
every room yeah and going in and out we
have food baths for your shoes even
though they're dedicated to zone 2 I
mean it's where there's all kinds of
operations and debris so it's I don't
they just changed it I believe it's stir
back that's in there now and it just is
just way at the bottom of your shoe and
if there's a room that may have a
potential problem in it it's restricted
even more so our tolerance is actually
kind of akin to ornamental crop
greenhouses in that if we can isolate an
issue to a room it's a very low
occurrence and we will find it in
another room so the staff going in there
have even more procedures to follow so
when they're exiting that room they're
taking off their hair net and their
gloves they exit the room we encourage
them to not interact with other staff
members in the hallway if they have to
go into another room shower and change
your uniform we go through a lot well
you know that's what I was thinking too
is I really enjoyed the fact that yo
don't use Tyvek suits cuz like you know
I tore in Tyvek all the time and that
stuff gets used once and it's gone and
it ends up in a landfill somewhere but I
like the solution here where I didn't
see any tie back but everyone was
wearing seven acres like I guess they'd
consider like golf shirts long sleeve
golf shirts and and what are essentially
like like sweat pants or like hospital
pants and like a scrub pants which has
pockets there you go
and so um and you just send those off
ahead be washed and come back and and I
like that because you know there's
already enough environmental degradation
from our industry from the light usage
and doop tubes and all this other stuff
you know being able to at least get rid
of Tyvek at least we're going in the
right direction right so so let's talk
with my favorite part the bugs just
so-so
so when it comes to the bugs you know I
look at deploying beneficial insects and
predatory mites and two different
flavors the first flavor is preventative
we don't have a problem today but we
don't want to have a problem tomorrow
and then we've got what you're calling
hot spot treatment where okay we need to
bombard this area so so what are your
your general bugs for prevention that
you go for and and and because you're
you want to play defense for particular
types of passes we generally use
beneficial insects that are poly phages
so they eat a variety of things
so we do green lacewing larvae for
primarily
a fence but I mean they everything so if
there's something and it comes across
them they're gonna eat it we do have two
sachets that are breeding systems
that'll both extend the life of the
mites that are in there so we use for
skiing californica for white fly and
spider mites respectively that you know
they the sachets are cool and they have
on the carrier there's a fungus and
there's actually two kinds of mites in
there
they have feeder mites the swierski eat
and little holes and they crawl out but
they'll they'll breed and have eggs so
actually later on today I'll be ripping
open some of ours and seeing if they're
still viable we're get about three weeks
out of them in the in the flower rooms
which is pretty nice and it's good to
point out though when you get the
sachets you know rookies sometimes will
receive the sachets and they're like
ripping him open that's not how they
work you know know if you just looked
for movement you might be seeing a
feeder might you don't know so you need
actually a microscope of some sort or
even a really good hand loop you need
about sixty to eighty times
magnification to see the difference
because they are very similar in size
but once you see the difference between
them it's very obvious that is not what
I'm looking for and we do soil
applications to deal with larval stages
of well fungus gnats primarily so we do
nematodes and give it to us I can't
pronounce the first ones three-eighths
ratty only laps hang on it's really good
so it's alright so that is your primary
defense team right you're putting those
in on a regular schedule constantly and
heavily because you know what do they
say an ounce of prevention is worth a
pound of cure or something like that and
so but sometimes and you may not have
run into it in this in this facility yet
but but sometimes things fall apart
right and and you've got a hot spot and
and you've got an invader so so talk us
through how your system would show that
how that would show up in your system
and then how you would respond to it we
would find the damage first one of your
Scouts yeah one of the scouts
sometimes even the the guram staff they
they spend a lot of time in the crops
and it's a highlight actually if
everybody is a day they come down to our
station we found something weird you see
it but it our reaction is pest dependent
so our reaction to say a fence is going
to be vastly different from Fritz so it
depends on the life cycle of the past
how quickly it can multiply what stage
of development the plant is currently at
if it's if it's cooling down and that's
gonna slow their lifecycle down I might
just go do a beneficial application as a
hot spot so I will reallocate some from
another room I run a little extra
everywhere so we have that leeway or I
will call a supplier and say hey I need
you know parasitic wasps next
because I have this and sometimes it
will be a cult of the plant if it's if
the pressure on the plan is bad enough
or if it's a certain type of past like
we when you have the very quick breeding
paths like white flies or aphids their
life cycle if you look at it it's the
definition of exponential growth and
that is very hard to control it is
better just to put a plastic bag over
that plant cut it down and get it out
sometimes an insecticidal soap we will
use we try not to spray as much as
possible maybe almost never I think the
last time we did a spray was at four
months ago and it will it's a call on a
case-by-case basis so if it's something
like a threat or a spider mite and it's
one plant in a room we're gonna heavily
do foliate that plant and that I'm gonna
put as many predators as I can on that
plant and all around it and then we will
watch it over the next two weeks and
make sure that it hasn't record if if
there's multiple cases in a room I'm
gonna status that room and you know
people going in and out are very very
limited and that way it won't spread to
the rest of the facility I wish I wish
you had wasps in one of the rooms went
on when I was on tour yesterday cuz
that's really cool I've only ever seen
them you know in books and in theory
right you know I we've got we've got
lots of lots of different types of wasps
on Vashon Island where I live and I
understand that not involve more
stinging and you know there's a lot you
know not all lost or threats right most
are our friends and Aaron and pollinator
allies right but then when I was going
through you know beneficial insects and
learning for the first time like five or
six years ago and I saw that there were
wasps I'm like who the hell is gonna let
wasps go in their grow and then as you
read about them they're like you're like
wow that's really cool it just feels it
feels extreme did you run into when you
know when you're getting the staff used
to coexisting with wasps in the room
did you have to convince anybody it's an
explanation definitely because like that
you hear wasp and what but the ones that
we use are parasitic so if we need to
those actually lost for great for
reaction and less so for prevention so
you you need that pest in order for them
to survive and and be viable as a as a
beneficial insect in your crop if you
don't it's better just not to use it and
use a mite instead but if you have to
bring them in you you let everybody know
these are specific they're they don't
have stingers as you know them they're
not a bumble bee or a wasp they're not
gonna hurt you they're attacking the if
it's like an aphid they're gonna attack
that aphid and what they're doing is
they're injecting their eggs in there
and then it hatches and it's they're not
gonna hurt you they aren't gonna fly at
you and they do get stuck on our sticky
cards but it it's one of those it
they're really great if you have an
issue just try to get one in there
because they're they're top notch as a
reaction well so so I know it's seven
acres you have a blend of cultivators
right some folks have cultivated
cannabis in the past and there's
straight-up heritage growers but also
there's some people that you bring in
and you train them up over the course of
a couple years to be really good
cultivator folk on the team right is
there and I know I didn't I didn't warn
you I bought this ahead of time so is
there any particular incorrect
expectation that you get from the the
people who have already got growing
experience about doing integrated pest
management that you're finding is pretty
common and you often need to train out
of folks spraying spraying is your per
minute
that is the go-to and it's been a go-to
for decades and it's it's a different
approach in that we will have some and
we will use it if we want to but it we
want the cleanest product possible so
for spraying it's very time consuming it
disrupts all our operations especially
at this scale and it is awful I don't I
don't like doing it the team some of
them are ok but it I would much rather
not do that but that that one is a big
one and it's a lot of so integrated pest
management especially cannabis is very
it's a new concept so it's a lot of
trying to explain oh yeah you are
finding these you know a cricket or
something in in a hallway I would like
to know about that because then the next
couple days I'm crawling around on the
floor looking for the hole and one of
the other big ones is you're not ever
going to be pest free ever that that is
wholly unrealistic but you take measures
to keep it at such a level that it's
manageable for you and it's not going to
cause any kind of economic loss and the
more vigilant you are tracking that type
of those types of things you can part of
my coming nip it in the bud right before
it gets to a problem yeah so you're not
going to be able to get rid of all of
them but keep them lonely yes you keep
them very lonely and they don't know
what to do no chances are you know our
place we might come up and just eat it
everybody yeah well Katherine thank you
so much for your time of in your joy
about this right I really enjoyed your
part of the tour yesterday and and I
knew that as soon as I met you I'm like
oh I want to talk to her some more so
thank you very much
thank you very much there's a lot of fun
fantastic
you