hey there I am here with Ari singer of
dynamite inoculants a new product for
fungally inoculating your living soil
the products come all the way from
Israel and I asked Ari for a little bit
of his time today here at Indo Expo
Portland because I'm happy to say that
Dyna Mike is now a sponsor of the
shaping fire podcast so that's great so
to help introduce everybody to what this
product is and the great success I've
been having with it on Vashon Island
where I live
I am sorry to give me a few minutes so
that we could all hang out so alright
it's nice to see you thank you so much
to you again thank you so much for
having me yeah so let's start like it
with the basics right would you explain
to us what dynamite does to give people
a frame of context on how to think about
it
alright so assuming someone is watching
this he probably knows a whole bunch
about mycorrhizal fungi from listen to
your show and the guests who have been
on it
what sets dynamite apart is the
concentration the ease of use it's a
one-time application thing one and done
pretty much when you transplant into
your growing media and it can be soil it
can be cocoa it could be a wide array of
growing media's and what the fungus does
it creates this secondary network or
root system secondary root system so to
speak it creates a - Network which then
allows the plant to absorb more
nutrients water and minerals which are
physically and chemically out of the
plant's reach so that's pretty much what
it's essentially making a superhighway a
fungal superhighway throughout the pot
right correct so that it expands the
reach of the root zone exactly and if
you have if you're growing in let's say
companion planting or nature trees and
plants actually use this fungal network
to communicate amongst themselves so
they can actually transfer nutrients and
water in a forest from one tree to
another with this fungal Network so it's
pretty cool stuff yeah well so far I've
gotten really good results on it and you
know you gave me a whole bunch of
samples last time we got together and
I've been handing them out to patients
on Vashon Island to use in their grows
and one of the things I've been doing to
explain to them is not only like you
know you're helping your pot have a
superhighway of mycelium so that all the
nutrients can be grabbed by the plant
but also you know there's we all know
the benefits of no-till right the idea
that you know traditionally we'll use
new soil every run throughout the old
soil and and so you've always got this
new virgin soil without mycelium
networks in it and so every year you
have to that has to regrow right right
and so people love no-till because if
you're just gonna if you're just gonna
like harvest the other plant and then
put your new start next to it there's
pre-existing mycelial networks so that
that superhighway already exists but
what I tell people is that you know if
you have to wait through your whole
season for that mycelial network to grow
there's all this time where your plant
is not pulling in all the nutrients that
it could be and so you have to wait for
a ramp-up period for your soil to get
tasty right right but but but using
dynamite I have found an incredible jump
up in my plants from the beginning
because I take some of the granules and
I make my little hole and I and I dust
it in there and and then I transplant
into that and if you explain this so
much better than I do
explain the magic that happens when when
the roots come in contact with the
dynamite grains so there's a
communication a hormonal signal that the
plant will send out to the fungus and
it's not like the fungus is just
knocking on every single plant's door
and you know asking hey can I show up
right so the plant will actually send
out hormones to get the fungus to
come to it right and then that's when
the interaction will happen so it's not
like every single plant will want a
mycorrhizal Association it needs right
if it's getting everything it can
already it won't have this symbiotic
relationship but if it does work if you
do inoculate it at an early stage when
it doesn't have everything available it
will create the symbiotic relationship
and the earlier you inoculate your
plants the better off you are because
that way you create this secondary root
system right away right so when you're
when your roots are very small and they
have nowhere to really grab nutrients
from or water right you're in the small
container that fungal Network will
really help the plants absorb more at an
earlier stage and we've seen I mean you
can see literally five six inch
differences in height and also in stem
girth just you know within a month of
inoculating plants that's it's the
earlier you get it the better off you
are
so I heard you say that before right and
I'm like all right well if the earlier
the better I want to use this with my
clones which is not what's on the
package right and I'm like well what the
hell it's a free sample I'm gonna give
this a try so so what I did is I took my
my clean spring water that we get on
Vashon and and I you know I took took
some of the granules and I mix it in
there right yeah and I put that in the
water beneath the clones in the tray
with my hope was that some of that would
get soaked up into the plugs and then
the roots would somehow get turned on
and like really reach for those right so
that the rooting would have been faster
and it totally worked right so so I
don't know if it was supposed to work
that way but it did and I got I got
better routing more roots more fine hair
and in a faster period I mean like 12
days for that was Rick ridiculous and so
I mean are you and other people doing
that or is that and we've it's it's
pretty cool when we launch dynamite we
had two application methods but all of a
sudden you know all these different
growers who have other approaches to
inoculating their play
are shown as you know they're sending us
a video of them taking dynamite pouring
it into a bucket of water and then just
dunking they're their route riots or
their their the rapid rooters whatever
there's yeah whatever the plug is and
they're just dipping them in you know
soaking them in the water and that's it
right cuz they I mean the fungi are
microscopic so they'll latch on to you
know a media and then obviously you have
the people who are just mixing it into
their soil or into their cocoa or coco
peat whatever it is so it's it's pretty
cool every almost every day we get a
video on Instagram of another grower you
know transplant time and one week ago to
now seeing these massive differences and
they're playing around with it kind of
exploring the cool thing about Dinah
Mike is that the granules will break
apart the moment they come into contact
with water which is not common with a
lot of other inoculants where they the
carrier is very firm yeah so with
dynamite the moment it comes into
contact with water will just break apart
in that way those roots can get you know
can either penetrate those granules or
get into contact directly with the the
the spores the hyphae and the root
fragments so it's a whole inoculum a
dynamite and as a user it makes it much
easier to break it up with your fingers
and do you know by hand applications as
well because some of the other micro
inoculants in the market they are so
hard you're all like boom put this
Boulder here boom and so but actually
while we're on the topic of comparing
dynamite to other folks in the market
and we won't use any names but it was
funny to hear the talk around your booth
here today about some of your
competitors coming up to you and saying
like how is this possible right why
don't you explain a little bit about the
concentration and and and why that was
one of the things that makes dynamite
especially sweet so because we're
dealing with microscopic organisms if
your concentration is low the chances of
inoculating a plant decrease and the
lower your concentration the slimmer the
chances of inoculation are with dynamite
with what makes it unique is that you're
getting 900 propagules a gram of two
species of endo mycorrhizal fungi
Akito mycorrhizal fungi don't have any
any relationships with cannabis so
they're not in dynamite we chose to
specific fungi which have that have
symbiotic relationships with cannabis
so the concentration is super super
important remember Jeff lowenfeld saying
was that a plant has about 20 billion
cells in its roots so if you're trying
to take a very low concentrated product
and inoculating these 20 billion cells
you're gonna have to dump a lot of the
product in there and it might not be
financially feasible or you know it
might not make sense but with dynamite
you're getting a highly concentrated
product so it's at 900 properties per
gram you're getting a very concentrated
product at an application rate which is
just about the same as any of the other
products out there on the market right
now so you're getting more bang for your
buck exactly exactly and the larger the
concentration the more likely you are to
inoculate your plants successfully and
that's one of the things that sets us
apart is is the high concentration and
that's part of our IP we don't have a
patent on it but we do not reveal our
secrets because like I said earlier
today we had someone from a competing
company comment approached us and asked
us how we got you do 900 yeah yeah but
it's important to also note though that
like even though this may be the first
time you're hearing dynamite it's not
like they just like whip this together
in a bathtub right this is a product
that was researched at a university and
then kind of got spun out into this
for-profit give us just a little snippet
of where it's from scientifically 30
years 25 years of R&amp;D at volcon II
Institute in Israel which is the leading
Agricultural Research Centre in Israel
and from there it's spun off and that's
what we've been doing ever since we
and you know formulating new products
different concentrations different
application methods trying to really
dial in on the exact exact combination
of strains of carriers also which will
allow plants and growers to maximize
their yields and their plans health
right on so before we wrap up I know the
product you know you've been giving out
samples all across the US for like six
months which is how I and a bunch of
people have gotten it and we're all
sending you videos and stuff so so if
you want to actually see the the
informal studies go to the dynamic
inoculants Instagram where they're
posting I've all the photos that people
are sending along but but but really as
far as it being for sale you've only
been getting registered in the states in
like the last two months alright so so
when people see the video and they're
like I want to check this stuff out
where can they get it
so right now grow generation just picked
us up there nationwide they have about
twenty six or seven stores across the
nation hope Tech hydroponics in
Bellingham fed city hydro in Federal Way
so these are Washington local so are
they how many states or is it because
because registration takes time we
haven't been able to get into all these
stores physically because you're not
allowed to sell them on the shelves yet
until it's registered so we just got
registered in California so you can be
expecting to see dynamite be in stores
in California
Portland's coming along so Oregon also
Washington State Colorado as well so the
major states were recreational cannabis
has been legalized already so that's
where we're at already right on is there
anybody who's selling it online
like any online grow shops where people
in states that you haven't gotten into
goodbye and had it shipped to so Hope
Tech hydroponics is one of them grow
generation I'm sure will be also and you
can reach out to them and we're gonna be
getting to more stories in the near
future but we're still we're still a
small company so to speak so this is
what the packaging looks like this is
what you're gonna be looking for and you
know if you if you watch the shaping
fire podcast you know that or listen to
it or if you or if you watch the YouTube
channel
you know that we don't take money from
synthetic nutrients right we are very
much into regenerative agriculture
healthy living soil growing and so when
I came across Dino Mike and I'm like
this is exactly the kind of thing that
fits within my values and a lot of
people in the audience so I'm really
grateful that you responded positively
in my pitch and are now gonna have
commercials on the show I am super
stoked to have commercials on the show
I've been listening to your show for
about a year already in and everything
you've been putting out has been amazing
and it's it's it's our honor to be
advertising on the show and super stoked
for the opportunity awesome well I hope
you quick growth of the company thank
you very much appreciate it