hi there friends this video you're about
to watch is a companion video for
shaping Fire episode 110 with special
guest Ethan Russo all about the
scientific aspects of Delta 8 THC I
figured it was kind of hard to focus
only on the medicinal aspects of Delta
hthc when there is so much discussion
about the legal aspects of whether or
not Delta 8 THC is actually legal from
the US farm bill or not and I'm not a
legal expert so I went and I got you one
we're very happy that Kos science um had
a webinar last week that included a
section on the legality of Delta 8 and
their guest attorney Lauren Ruck has
graciously offered her part of the
webinar um to you so that you can check
it out um at the time this was a paid
webinar and so they're they're willing
to pull out this little piece for you so
that you can get a really good solid
understanding of the legality or
illegality of Delta 8 THC so thank you
to Kos science and especially thank you
for attorney Lauren Ruck for sharing
this PE peas with us I hope you enjoy
it laurren began her career in
litigation spent a decade litigating a
wide variety of cases and uh after her
mom used cannabis uh to address terminal
illness Lauren uh became a cannabis
Advocate and and from there has
pioneered one of the most
successful uh practices dedicated to the
Cannabis industry uh she is a
contributor to marijuana Ventures
magazine and serves in leadership
positions in a wide variety of cannabis
associations around the country and she
serves clients in many states and has
been a driving force in legalization in
the state of New York welcome Lauren
thank you so much um Ethan Anisha I'm so
happy to be here and to you know share a
stage with you I guess we're going back
to when Ethan and I first met in 2019 I
had the opportunity to be his moderator
at the emerald cup and it's been a
tremendous working collaboration since
then so very happy to be here um and you
know excited to discuss all matters d8
um legal matters um okay um Julie you
gonna share the screen there we go
okay all right um so as Ethan described
in far greater detail and using actual
science um d8 is a psychoactive
intoxicating cannaboid that occurs
naturally in cannabis plants um
including cannabis that meets the
definition of hemp and we'll get into
that in a little bit um albeit in very
small quantities um as most of you
probably know distribution of medical
and Adult Ed cannabis is supposed to be
limited to intrastate activity meaning
no Interstate Comm Commerce um and sold
strictly in medical or adult use retail
dispensaries um yet Delta 8 can be found
almost anywhere you can order it through
the mail you can purchase it at a local
Wellness store even at gas stations or
Big Chain grossers so probably wondering
how that's possible um and it's because
most d8 does come from hemp and um hemp
is federally legal right um so I really
wish it was that simple um go on to the
next slide Julie
please um okay so as of today there is
virtually no consistency in application
or enforcement between federal and state
law or between and among the various
States regarding hemp derived cannaboids
incl clud and especially Delta 8 um as
I'll explain in a bit there does seem to
be some legal precedent providing
stability in this area literally
evolving in real time case decided just
last week or the week before so I'll
talk about that in a little bit um but
first I want to take a quick step back
uh to give you a very basic
understanding of the legal framework of
hemp under the 2018 farm bill um so the
2018 Farm Bill defined hemp to include
all derivatives extracts cannaboids
isomers acids salts and salts of isomer
with a Delta 9 tetrahydrocannabinol
concentration of not more than 3% on a
dry weight basis so they're really
referring to hemp biomass or floral
material when they talk about that dry
weight basis um hemp if it meets this
definition is excluded from the
definition of marijuana which is
classified as a schedule one substance
under the federal Controlled Substances
Act um yet THC including those naturally
occurring in the cannabis plant as well
as their synthetic equivalence were made
controlled schedule one substances um so
right away we have this immediate
tension and conflict with respect to
hemp derived THC and the courts and the
daa are publicly grappling with this
issue um most delta8 on the market as
Ethan noted is not naturally occurring
um rather most de8 on the market has
been converted or synthesized from CBD
um and this is critical because while
the DEA consistently maintains that
cannaboids which naturally derive from
hemp are hemp and are thus Exempted from
the CSA uh the DEA feels very
differently about cannabinoids that have
been synthesized or chemically treated
go on to the next
slide okay so the DEA has taken you know
a pretty strong position on the matter
um according to the DEA the synthesizing
process renders this otherwise legal
substance illegal um in mid August of
2020 the DEA promulgated an interim
final rule which purports to classify as
a schedule one substance all synthetic
tetrahydrocannabinols so this includes
THC thcb thca and Delta 8 um in various
letters and correspondence issued by the
DEA in 2021 uh regarding programs in
Alabama and Florida uh DEA maintained
that synthetic cannaboids including hemp
derived delta8 that was converted from
CBD is illegal under the CSA yet hemp
derived THC that met the D9
concentration 3% total THC or less are
not so now looking at some of the final
finished products not just the floral
material or the biomass um and then most
recently while indicating that new rules
are coming um you know in February of
2023 DEA reiterated that Delta 8 that
has been converted from CBD is in fact a
controlled substance so following the
dea's line of reasoning if the DEA
naturally occurs in hemp and that hemp
was grown in a 2018 Farm Bill State the
legal inquiry can stop as naturally
occurring cannaboids are clearly exempt
from the CSA pursuant to the 2018 farm
bill but if the d8 has been converted
from CBD the legal status is far less
clear um and then anyone who's
considering Distributing Delta 8 of
course is going to turn on your appetite
for risk um so now I want to talk a
little bit about state laws um if you
could go to the next slide great um so
even after resolving this matter from a
federal perspective we have to now turn
to state law and as with everything
involving cannabis state laws differ on
how to treat d8 and until very recently
the state was for states the trend was
for states to come down very hard on on
Delta 8 um so legal status really does
vary from Gray to outright
illegal um some states which had not yet
operated under the 2018 Farm Bill have
not updated their definitions of hemp to
include isomer derivatives extracts and
or canabo um so Delta 8 very unclear as
to the legal status in those States um
other states deem any form of THC a
controlled substance um some states such
as in New York regulate d8 specifically
um many states simply follow the FDA
particularly when it comes to the
inclusion of cannaboids including hemp
Drive cannaboids in food and beverage
products and we know the FDA follows the
DEA so a little bit of a circular
argument there um and still no analyst
that no analysis of uh hemp derived
cannabinoids would be complete without
considering the federal analog Act of 19
86 um d8 could be considered an analog
because it shares structures similar to
schedule one drugs or because the actual
intended effect is substantially similar
to or in some instances greater than a
schedule one drug lots of basis to
consider whether Delta H should be
regulated like THC if you're
sufficiently confused it's okay so our
most legal experts um all of this
confusion was sure to spark lawsuits and
the wave has certainly decidedly begun
um so multiple States including New York
Arkansas Alabama Oklahoma Oregon have
passed laws that restrict or otherwise
render illegal production and sale of
delta8 products um of Delta eight
generally and products that contain
Delta 8 and the lawsuits have begun to
try to take those laws down after the
next slide
please okay so um perhaps our federal
court system will resolve this tension
um starting with a decision earlier this
month uh the case is styled Biogen
versus Sanders it was brought in federal
court in the eastern distri district of
Arkansas um the plaintiffs were Biogen
of um LLC of fville a drippers vape shop
of green Brier the cigarette store of
Colorado doing business as Smoker
Friendly and Sky Marketing Corp of Texas
doing business as Hometown hero um this
was a big win because what the
plaintiffs ultimately do did was
preclude enforcement of this law on the
night before the law was supposed to
take effect so it was a very big uh
legal deal um this lawsuit named the
governor Sarah hucke Sanders the
Attorney General of the state the
directors of the Arkansas Department of
Finance and admin the Tobacco Control
Board the State Department of
Agriculture the state plant board and
the 28 Prosecuting attorneys as the of
the state as defendants so they named
everybody who has any impact or any
finger on the pulse of the enforcement
and administration of this law in
Arkansas um the plaintiff sought an
injunction prohibiting enforcement of
this bill um the bill criminalized all
hemp products produced as a result of
synthetic chemical process and any other
psychoactive substance that was derived
there from um the plaintiffs did argue
that the Act was preempted by the 2018
farm bill and that the act's provisions
were unconstitutionally vague and
ambiguous um and the court agreed um and
entered in a junction barring the state
from enforcing the ACT um in its ruling
the court made a series of
pronouncements which they do apply only
to the law in Arkansas but they could
nonetheless establish a precedent upon
which all similar prohibitive State
programs could be invalidated um so to
this end the Court ruled that the ACT is
preempted by federal law a concept known
as conflict preemption because Arkansas
has already joined the 2018 farm bill
and the 2018 Farm Bill does not limit
its application to Method by which
derivatives extracts and cannaboids are
produced as long as the downstream
products result from plants that contain
less than 3% THC they are legal hemp um
very important here the state did reject
any notion of testing based upon a post
decarbo decarbox silation method um this
is something that has been profer by
various states in the DEA um as this
reads qualifiers into the definition of
hemp beyond that was what was intended
by the 2018 farm
bill um the court also found that the
Act was preempted by federal law on a a
concept known as Express preemption um
so Al those States are in fact allowed
to regulate the production growing and
cultivation of hemp more strictly than
federal law they cannot restrict
interstate commerce of hemp products
including hemp derived products if those
products derive from lawful hemp so here
the ACT um in Arkansas would have
precluded Commerce of hemp derived
delta8 products that were lawfully
produced in other states and then the
court found that the Act was vague and
thus void you know laws can be very ill
conceived um but the court found that
the Act contained terms that would
confuse even an exceptionally
intelligent reader um to this end the
Act contained terms like Contin
continuous Transportation synthetic
substances psychotic psychoactive
substance none of which were actually
defined in the statute um the ACT also
made references to dangers of misuse
risks to the public all of which are
highly subjective um so this was hardly
a basis upon which the court felt
wielding criminal sanctions or criminal
penalties was appropriate go on to the
next slide so still thinking about
Distributing d8 maybe um you know if
you're thinking about a distribution
strategy that involves Delta 8 and you
want to mitigate legal exposure you know
know science um make sure you really
want to spend your resources on a
product that as Ethan said likely only
exists owing to Federal illegality of
cannabis um you definitely want to
retain an attorney who is expert and
fluent in hemp regulation these laws are
changing on a weekly sometimes daily
basis analysis that we've done in one
state a month ago likely to be stale so
you really got to keep up with with the
with the regulations as they change um
and don't just rely on your lawyers you
have to become an expert in all matters
hemp um we're expecting a new iteration
of the farm bill this year um this could
resolve all outstanding matters
regarding intoxicating cannaboids
regardless of their hemp derived or
cannabis derived um so you got to be
your own expert um you have to retain
attorneys and you have to have an
ongoing dialogue um because any
distribution strategy has to be very
flexible and adaptable we would
recommend maintaining low production
runs giving how quickly the regulatory
landscape changes in this area um we
would recommend strong representations
and warranties in written contracts
where was the hemp grone how the
products were produced how to shift the
risk of Regulatory Compliance what
happens if somebody gets hurt and then
be sure to seek indemnification because
um you know of course representations
and warranties are very little if you
don't have legal recourse to enforce
them um so those are my practice
pointers uh to the extent that anyone is
interested in engaging in the d8 uh
space even after hearing um Ethan's
presentation and knowing that there are
really far Superior Products out there
um so thank you for staying with me I
know the science is far sexier than the
legal technicalities um and ultimately
while this legal exercise is somewhat
thrilling for us lawyers um we do
continue to strive for consistency and
application we're looking for Clear
rules that are easy to to follow that
are rooted in actual science of course
not racial animosity or any desire to
suppress political speech which is how
cannabis wound up on the Controlled
Substances Act in the first instance um
so ultimately um we just really need to
stay on top of Delta 8 the distribution
of Delta 8 and and decide for ourselves
whether this is you know a cannaboid and
product that we want to continue
promoting as we see further
liberalization of cannabis
generally and that's
it