hey this is Shango I'm at the Washington
coast this weekend sampling five
different outdoor growers that I picked
up at Emerald cup from the Emerald
triangle area from this past summer and
I noticed something that four of the
five companies were selling their stuff
in mason jars right which you know this
this for example this flower from
scarlet fire is fabulous right and it's
in a mason jar which has been totally
perfectly appropriate for medical until
now you know they're great for someone
else's in but but with the new you know
regulated market that's not gonna be
it's not going to be okay
and so everybody's gonna have to be
getting packaging and the crazy thing is
is if four of the five of the farms that
I'm sampling this weekend all need
packaging that means that there is a
hell of a lot of work that is coming up
for designers in California and that's
who I'm thinking about today you know my
gosh all the graphic designers all the
package designers all like the naming
designers brand strategists all have got
so much kick-ass work coming up for them
in the near future right if you're
already in with cannabis companies and
like you're down with cannabis and
you're an edgy designer oh my gosh
you've got a whole bunch of really good
work to do and I know what it's like to
to be working with a client that I
especially am into their product
whatever it is if like if I'm into it
like like when I write commercials for
living soil companies right like you
know people who are like you know
probiotic I love I love that kind of
stuff so when I'm writing their
commercials for the podcast I'm like
into it right and so so same thing I
would think for designers who are about
to be able to enjoy all these these you
know designing the package for the
product and then also designing the
package that holds the product at retail
right plus all the the billboards a new
magazine ads and Super Bowl commercials
oh man this is a good time to be a
designer in California so I'm thinking
about you folk today and I hope you
really enjoy it and appreciate this
because this is this is a time in a
place in California for for designers
and
and I hope you enjoy it