Wow that's just incredible setup and you
know some I come here I was born three
things one make sure you have great
shows the first thing I look at this
category it's actually it's all this
this stuff that you know more the
Denmark
Andrew you don't have coffee it is that
- so how many people read this book if
you have this book right now - Amazon or
somebody else this is my second book
taking the nutrients and now I have a
meeting with one giant horse needs a
three boasted - trilogy and that makes
me Lord of the Rings
years ago Canada's here before campus
plastic appeared out of nowhere and and
we started to eat plastic this is what
partner it is and we played with plastic
and we had a vision fertilizers of
appeared out of doors today using you
know horse manure and this great stuff
leaves people spraying these foods we
wouldn't have blemishes on it they
invented you know instant coffee and we
had a small D better living through
chemistry and we had a television
channel there were only three stations
and one of the choices
was mr. wizard and he was on and he
would talk about science and he had his
little baby assistant sponsored by
General
and you knew growing weed because the
light was always purple coming and this
is the original Purple Haze and you will
be whatever you could grow but nobody
else would find it and when you grew you
know is mostly sticks and still rules
and scenes and it was not very good
queen election had a PhD in chemistry
and you can do economics and it required
me to be in chemistry in order to be
able to do economics now today we don't
have a little oil of anything you know
instant popcorn over one of our TV
dinners this is our instant coffee
counters we won't have tall homes we
carry around
in our telephones magazines and there
come on it's just the curl world but we
still you know rely on chemistry
very often when we're growing and
particularly if we're growing
commercially and we have an
overabundance of reliance on chemistry
and relax and unfortunately gardeners
and some cannabis gardeners in
particularly now we spritz them because
impractical and we want to say well you
know it's kind of crazy
what kind of minute of marijuana as
Mataji was playing in the chemistry you
know it just doesn't make any sense to
me
and you know it's not the moral and it's
not ethical to be bringing something
that you're selling or giving away a
family member or a using yourself that
has a chemical dominican girls like you
do it's just not for us not ethical it's
absolutely not right some things are so
obvious it don't really be the same so
why is my stand because we're going to
have big pharma you know who else coming
down our butts and they're going to be
definitely things a different way than
we think it wouldn't be able to
distinguish ourselves by being the clean
green
not a big corporate stuff so our goals
today are figure out that it wasn't
really amazing cannabis easily without
using chemicals and using the soil
whatever to be able to do it I can get
them all talk about the slide as well
who both involves plants taking
photosynthetic energy and using it not
to produce the but not to release the
Judeans but reduce the treeless of one
of those Japanese food and so they
reduced the rate under 60 days which
they drip out of the roots piece of
their roots this is the roots of what
most plants [ __ ] actually paid out and
it produces in order to be able to
attract Japanese bacteria so this is in
fact Japanese these bacteria eat these
exudates and they can turn are eaten by
them and they poop out the excess and
that excess contains that Japanese food
that goes to the plant same thing with
the fungus down there
japanese material or attempting to
polish there's a lot of the garden pool
the plant would change the exit date
itself to produce a different kind of
molecule to attract a different kind of
food so it's it's it's self-control so I
want American performed well it just
changes the it to date because American
food you should be thinking to sweat and
and think about extra days because your
affection dating right now your sweat is
attractive bacteria and Punjab and
they're attracting ozone you're covered
with roses so if you disappeared write
down your shapes would stay here because
of all the chromosomes that are I mean
it sounds like fun until you see some of
the pictures of you in a couple minutes
this particular picture called exit
gates happens to be kind of actually
that's the dental white blood cells so
not only go out to get you know get
tracked bacteria but these guys go out
and they lock up things that the plant
doesn't want to take off like arsenic so
these actually dates to do some pretty
amazing thing
and of course it's bacteria Monday they
all contain antibiotics and whatnot and
so there are no all sorts of things in
the soil fascinating fascinating the
plants trying to get the largest and the
most diverse population that can't
that's what protects the plant diversity
diversity because diversity populations
in control center get center and again
god help the republicans if they don't
understand they're in a teaspoon of good
soil there should be 500 billion to a
trillion bacteria and archaea now
bacteria you know is what i had the
first edition of the book second edition
of the book pet archaea because that
didn't know they existed in the first
edition was written these were only at
the oceans they were only in geysers and
now they discovered they're in the soil
now they discover that the dominant in
the sec organism the second step of the
nitrogen fixing the you've never heard
of them because they were discovered in
1878 and and making textbooks until 1898
is the third branch of life our team
they look like bacteria that ever
different a different thing you look at
month these guys over the bacteria
needed sugars and they break them simple
to digest that it's the ends of long
carbon molecules and that
bringing in a breathe it's a to bacteria
it could have been a petri dish ideal
condition to six weeks later the earth
is covered with 20 feet of bacteria now
you know they're unbelievable and they
formed a slime in order to colonize and
to present themselves and to communicate
with each other
and this slide is very very important to
what we do because the slime think about
brushing your teeth in the morning
you're brushing off the bacterial slime
you're all licking your teeth right now
it's okay when it doesn't you use a lot
of energy to get that smell off because
it's really strong follow bacteria
talking to each other and producing a pH
above 7 so if our soils have bacterial
dominance then they have a pH of of 7
and have all of the slime which sticks
to little individual particles before
and causes them to stick to each other
so soil structure and create to come
from bacterial slime this is where it
starts and then that he's personally at
14 feet of invisible one behind 14th we
can't see it but it's there and those
invisible from Ivy you know local thing
that they're exactly like plant cells
fungus people understand take a minute
or studying
they don't have that little chloroplast
in there they can be given a chlorophyll
and then through those that currently
stuck together pieces of soil and making
a bigger intolerance of soil and their
bricks these things are getting stuck
together they've got you know pore
spaces so we get pore spaces air the
bigger guys the grains they hold the
border
this is business soils talking bacteria
and fungus Unum and these bacteria they
digest extra severally by tripping
enzymes gasses out of their bodies
breaks their little stuff when they take
it back into their bodies so when they
dominated in the soil instead of having
a pH above 7 we have a pH below 7 and
they are unbelievably strong acids here
is a fun play the great Indian twosome
have some fellows work to get some of
the nutrients out of that rock therefore
not and they go out some and bring back
new trees for the plant in return for
those accidents some of them just decay
stuff break things down some of them
actually attach essentially to the plan
and remix it and those are the
mycorrhizae fungi and they bring that
phosphorus and nitrogen in zinc and
copper in Africa
Romanies you and water to the brain and
if you don't have your plants dolphin
96% of all plants for Michael mediation
symbiotic with these funds and cannabis
happens to be a very very big
partnership former so here's how they
work
you got two celiac sitting in the
someone who says he's had to make a
little bit of baloney today baloney
sandwich would be really nice and so
what does it do well that goes and mixes
up the exudates okay this is got to get
the right actually date it puts the
extra these out into the soil
alright catches the right fungus and
then the pointless reels it in and the
fungus one end of it goes into the plant
there's the entry point unbelievable
picture just spectacular
okay be ready and these days it's so
easy it's
you let me do this oh sorry Bridget back
because the plate says hey don't want me
no extra days and so it's a perfect
relationship and they're both very happy
and what's even better is there it isn't
the bologna sandwich
we'll see link very happy it continues
to nurture this relationship and what's
nothing cool is that it shares
mycorrhizal associations and plants next
to each other even if they're different
kinds of plants america than a redwood
tree sometimes it's not always what we
do and how we do pretty amazing now
there are seven different kinds of
mycorrhizal one's right there are two of
them an important to agriculture and
there's only one that we care about
it's an indoor bike rifle which means
that it's invisible you can't see it
less you stain it in endo these ends of
those traits in the room more than the
ecto which is the other kind and this is
what they look like when they're
insights we buy my third book you can
read all about all this boring as
possible dogs not very exciting but you
need to understand is that what you are
for me
is a mycorrhizae or Michael rise up my
rising world and what's farming it is a
set a root settle and a Michael kreizel
function so you are not buying Michael
rise up and if they're selling product
this label Michael rise up your label to
grow you're selling like the rise with
one giant and Michael rise up is the
partnership between the foot tell you
the rule that forms when you put the
mechanism down okay craziness and here's
what you have one that associated
cannabis feels like it's an investment
secular and it's or micellar the secular
person as these little practice though
grounding there is a little vesicle
contains liquids that that's where the
transfer takes place between this will
get at the plant and then tree-like
structures that are ocular so it's
called the secular and about our brush
dealer buys the fungi these are uh still
looks like little trees they're inside
the cells can't see unless you sustain
them so here they are stinging now is
the problem is the problem in our
endemic so we know as an emulator Isaac
relationship it used to be called
Verizon fancier than it has 50 different
engines on all the different labels that
you pick up because they keep renaming
the damn thing and finally we've gotten
to the point where we know that DNA and
so from now on it's called Bryce Vegas
interests CDs and that he ranked them
one thing other than remember to buy all
the worldly routes books soon as this
talk right now lots of things into
proceedings because this is the stuff
that makes your cameras parole well and
I'm talking really well and if you want
a different one just for fun
see some wonderful pictures Google Wow
Michael rise and you'll see the kind
that I've been using lately these are
the old means almost lost equal material
errors as a Vegas everyday only nervous
about me to be free other ones but
impressive things in to receive these is
what you want and if you want to see
anything else on the label you're going
up and rich you're wasting your time
because this is the only one that forms
the partnership with the Kennedys there
is a vibe a big point there is a need
from the lab test that I did wow that's
a big plan well they don't get the sense
of how big that is maybe you don't give
a sense how that is he putting on a
gigantic frying pan that's not a little
so it was Wow right turned out
unfortunately
oh man plants can't wait to get sport so
yeah it's a big big big difference big
difference you could've stopped on the
scenes we should want to infect the
plant right away scenes if you can if
you mind homes you put it on right away
as soon as you get it you get it has to
touch the roofs there's a communication
from the plant to the mycorrhizae fungi
this is poop over here and so they've
got to be there you won't find it in
compost you have to add it to your soils
and you want to put it not only on the
seeds but in the soil mix it around
[Music]
well this is its drought situations they
use that water to feed the plant as
people discovered until only three or
four years ago there was a gigantic job
and they those that didn't use my
grassle fun tonight lost their crop
those that did have them but they
provide protection for things like
nematode for a couple reasons first of
all they're coated with because they're
fungus they're cold with a kite okay
how did you think about you know
and a hamburger hamburger
coated with you know gonna take the
hamburger without the shrimp because
it's easier to eat easier to get through
this provides some protection you know
and of course Michael has a fun day that
white stuff is pretty hard to get
through to get that stuff you got that
slime okay so it creates a PAH they also
have their own Rises if you're kind of
thing it's called a microsphere
and so then that can own sort of soil
food that they're feeding all sorts of
organisms knocking down the whole front
I see what you're doing stuff now
so in fungus slide the bacteria slide
the pH above 7 slime for fungus below so
two different kinds of Slingbox
so here's what's going on in this one
you've got you know all this bacteria
fungi being attracted by the enzyme
insides the M there's the dead bar I
being the attracted by the exudates
and they in turn attract the for the ZOA
we eat them and the nematodes that have
been pulled out the excesses me blankets
been I'm out of this pool turns out to
be a form of nitrogen ammonia okay
fallen always but if you have nitrogen
fixing bacteria they take that in turn
it into so and it's going to take that
stuff and turn it into thank you
so the fungally dominated is going to
stay is upon you and if you've got
funding to plants that like lovely
nominees as soils they need that and
other plants they like nitrates both of
the place that way that clearly
dominated soils well guess what cannabis
like bacteria technology disorders so
you want to use things that attracted
the bacteria okay and the masses and
nowheres follows this company stop right
soils why use cover crops that didn't
make it to fixing cuz that's really good
stuff helps to plan
this happens to be some stuff that you
can
follow whatever little bit of focus you
don't want have just pure bacterial some
of these plants have fun give some sort
of structure oh and then I mentioned
that they've recently discovered that
these bacteria they talk to each other
using electricity in this new stuff that
people keep talking about called
terpenes and talking toppings wait a
minute
they just like us so they communicate in
turn to each other like a net big tip
there anyway here's a little Free Syrian
speaking to one identify bacteria using
turkey as theirs as their language so
you've got fertilizer bags okay the
bacteria the fungi
they've been attracted by the action is
simple this is and they're then eaten
and scrap metal fertilizers feathers
protozoa and nematodes so let's take a
look at the part is over this is an
amoeba nobody we said they saw on my
always you class but nobody ever did so
against the picture and this protozoa
that everybody did study
they assume you forgot didn't you that's
the name come on Paramecium each one of
these Paramecium will be you 10,000
bacterium addiction and then poop out
the excess that's a lot of food a lot of
these guys you've got tremendous amount
of food so am I gonna think about a Zola
T to cite them with anterior that you've
done in your soils that's last picture
is what they look like I'm not going to
respond but they look like an electron
microscope anyway t it's easy you just
take strong or a cobra protozoa put it
into a bubbler or just put it in a
bucket of water stir that through three
times a day after two and three days
you'll be able to see the pepper BC
running on in there after ten days of
the soil their site I'm like man alright
then you have never told us you got the
40 or 50 nematodes in that teaspoon of
soil you know somehow we're good also
berkeley doing it for white they had
never told us in the customer good ones
the bad one have to support these little
things we get inside the roots their
plants turn yellow you know they are
differentiated by their mouthparts
and you know this one is one
probably don't want that at my kitchen
sink but that's just sort of a broker
spatula that's not a drill and it's just
waving water in bacteria into the mouth
this is the one you want to worry about
other than workers it sticks straight
into you and then sucks out a lot less
than your body this one attacks dogs
cause it's awkward so other than that
now they're kind of fun these are some
of the benefit ones they can attack the
bad guys they get in here they get a
little bacteria the bacteria start to
grow inside the bad guy the eggs that
they lay inside at and then they eat the
bacteria meanwhile the bacteria has been
eating the bug in the munich gets really
ugly they leave and they always make
sure they take a little bit of the
bacteria weather so that they can repeat
what they need to do with attachments or
negatives so that they really work and
you get the right ones and there's lots
of them being studied now and it's
certainly something you want
all sorts of things you can see these
things by being something called
overlays a funnel which is just
basically made it but it's in the book
and you gather these things these are
soil organisms they're taking those
bound together particles of soil and
they're moving between them creating
colors as they run through as larvae
States in there even slowing each other
and all this stuff it's unbelievable and
these tunnels act as air spaces and pore
spaces and hiding places and when it
rains the band is pushed out the waiter
comes in so again soil structure it's
all about the soil food web it's not
about you or me it's about what the soil
you ever study they say dog-eat-dog
things are getting eaten then they're
getting eaten again and pooped out and
eat and poop out and eventually ends up
there the bacteria the fungi and
eventually if a plant surrounded it once
that kind of food it goes into the plant
so you got all sorts acutely going on
down there it's just you know it's like
Congress
fights in there different kinds of mites
and you want to know the difference
between the orbited the ganas in length
because one of them eats fungi and you
know one of them eats plant material and
so if you had once and eat the fungi and
you know you've been fine giant in your
soil etc all the stuff is killing things
and very terrible stuff he's almost gone
you know and then of course is that the
base of things that are in the soil food
bears poop in the woods that whole part
of the soil food web that bears
organisms as well food web I start from
repeating this of those have heard this
talk that's my window a date with Alaska
if you look carefully not so carefully
you'll see that we do is open and you'll
see that there's just a screen there
that bears looking in through the screen
you see a little crease and neck pushing
here that's where my head was at
nanosecond my wife
see you outside the window an angel -
ima see you loose begin they poop in the
woods you know that's all part of the
soil for you that you mama and you watch
one spring I happen to catch a pair of
calories I'm sorry Tina
I'm sorry okay now we do other things to
the soil you know you have to be
thinking about it so one of the things
we were trained to do day one was going
to soil structure is up here and of
course we do things like we spray we
start having problems and you know who
knows what the state is they're in
pieces visit school so we go and seek
expert advice at Lowe's or to American
you know like this in terms of the soil
because I'm getting the stuff for free
it's my garage - I thought he didn't
either so it's the plan until it's out
of Poland and you're there you go holy
[ __ ] the plants tiny and it's everything
because you guilt and now you have to
become that means this is supposed to be
fun this is supposed to be easy money
right develop that's what the technical
companies attacking us so anyway I want
to stop using these chemicals to create
these situations we've ended with no
partnerships dependency and of course
that you start getting diseases because
once these things start to go what do
you do what the might goes back and it's
really easy to do if you use compost you
can use T's mulches and you can use
compost as everything okay
you buy that amount of the compost this
over the area going with now the part to
take a look at and you're going to end
up with no mycorrhizae fungi because
it's not in compost you have to get that
it's only there the plant sends out the
signals for plants in the
with culture they will tell you the
compost tea is all prod the Cooperative
Extension Service isn't allowed to
mention it because I kind of receive
them so whether they know I always say
that the Cooperative Extension Service
that's the president of Harvard
University that's that's their first to
count push team machine and they have
about ten of them now they turn the
entire campus in your green space
everything they have know how they
compost including their exams
and enough power it's good enough for me
and you park your car our yard your
party your card accomplice teacher now
you use compost tea and you can make
bubbling up it in and they're clearly
government and it is protective stuff
and it's one wonderful and if you don't
have the time to make compost tea and
there's lots of different kinds of
Grover you can make your own you can
make compost extract well incidentally
it was a Brewers here they're just
protecting both over here synergy and
over here there's one of the biggest
ones I've ever seen absolutely
spectacular you can make an extract I
just simply take the compost and
cheesecloth just in water for 15 minutes
and I kind of multiply it together
Austin takes away ground but you get
good stuff out of that column so it's a
great way to go as well green stuff is
good for you know bacteria the brown
stuff was good for function cymbals
Network the enemy is to increase the
fight Michael biomass now there are two
things I've learned since I spoke here
last year the first one we're talking
about right now it's all day might won't
buy all the leader and inventions I go
with a biomass and you've been looking
up at
might put biomass we want the creeks the
second thing we're going to talk about
at the end of my talk here and it's
gonna make it kind of light but you know
my hopes all the nutrients they cycle
the nutrients they they recycle the
nutrients and so if you have high
microbial biomass you get all things
considered and of not plowed soil for
the poop but if you have normal song
that you're growing into infinity good
stuff to it you just like over the
biomass it has over 500 is great it's
over 800 you don't have to clean the
soil holy crow and if you remember when
the biomass drops when the plant stops
producing extra days right before it
starts so you can go ahead of your time
money anyway
biomass very very important and you know
you want to have big healthy plants good
biomass in your soil you've got the best
opportunity
Tricia's plants good turkey in your
plans big plans this is my second book
you know and we tend the rest is
building so every time you think about
going to see we down that see we they
feeding plan it's got 56 different
nutrients in it they're all the eight
ten of them are feeding their plan
that's the only one of the plant beans
now in the US again they had seen me is
the micro
the plant and so in that regard very
good very healthy you know 17 18
elements if you play cards with that but
if you do the combination it turns out
you know that it's like 56 zillion
trillion different kinds of molecules
can be made by various combinations you
know they're all made 1,400 nutrients 5%
of the stuff that you peel the rest of
it 95% of what is in a plant water
oxygen carbon you know the specials
each channel designed for one kind of
molecule each channel made by every
individual cell themselves each channel
sometimes only two or three molecules to
come through like Borg it'll be very
very boring before the flower so they're
feeding their plants this these are the
only things that may be kept this is the
III Corps of all the nutrients and how
they get into the plastic
things but the soil we have creates is
impeccable biomass so that those
nutrients are available all the time you
know it all starts with those actually
days that the plan puts out you're
feeding microbes we're going organic
you're not feeding the plant and you
kind of concentrate on those microbes as
much as possible okay so the end game is
that biomass you want to make sure you
test your soils okay because we know the
least amount is missing is no one's
gonna screw you up because that really
you can't guess by looking at don't
think they know by looking that they
believe your plant needs nitrogen that's
[ __ ] there are a hundred different
reasons why a planetary the yellow
leaders okay just happens to be nicer to
someone that's easy produces upright
about as good as a gardener and our work
it's crazy
test your soil biologically so who
whether in other places do you wrote a
micro bio meter test and get a chemical
test to that you need to know what's in
it okay these cells are important and
what goes on to these cells depend on
what in that sort in their billions of
these cells like in this little period
right here and five to fifty plant cells
tomahawk you know not here you know
these are small these are really small
next lines but anyway this how many
atoms are in an individual plant cell
estimating that plant cell and so each
one of these apples you don't realize
all the stuff that you're giving it and
we don't ever think about these things
with all the noise it's okay inside
every single cell of a plan there are a
thousand different kinds of things
owners now remember they're totally
simply doing it help atoms in there
there are thousand different kinds of
it's a ten thousand each one of them is
just lonely in every single cell them
unbelievable in terms sure is like crazy
from not so that you can follow a
training that we go around the earth you
know thirty million car trained over
there hundred twenty times that's how
much sugars but these every white planet
it's just a staggering number
the only thing that comes close all
those k-cups
unbelievable but they work best at 78°
that's why your glands work best at that
temperature so you want to keep it at
that temperature you possibly can
no mostly will be perseverant keep the
temperature at 19 is 78 degrees but you
only can do this stuff just because I
want to kick the screen soil is make
sure it's clean and pure organic as
smell nice that smell is Chloe's from
the substance being produced by
streptococci a bacterial the kind of
stuff that we use in medicines it's
called goe that we're sailin ever a
pupil it's a condominium for the soil
food so you would have very best we
possibly can a nice mix wanna make it a
beautiful condominium a Sloan
condominium
you know not a word ricotta media we
want to make a luxury condominium for
the best stuff you want to want to fill
up with the rate things are gonna be
able to take care of the pests okay you
want to keep them under control
biologically if you can them you're
going to be thinking about consumption
out competition interference and
reduction
okay got faith like a soil for many and
this isn't the questions you have to ask
and you ask yourself these questions
because you can answer them you won't
have problems anymore yeah not that easy
they require a little bit of work but
you need to do it we've got competition
coming down the road but you cannot
believe and get those people Harvard
we're using that compost tea for there
so we've got to be the top of this stuff
right now you know we have it's not
necessarily be taking the bad problem
you know trips gotta go that vanilla
might work you know little vanilla track
for example be clever about how we do
this stuff and use the right nights for
my little business to sell these women I
have used the right kinds of stuff for
each one and we have to we have to pay
it's solvents sometimes they come and
teach us how to do this stuff and when
we have a bad end of the station
yeah the commander bring them in so that
they didn't tell us what we need we need
to be using cover crops to add to the
soil too many of us might throw in our
soil they each grow oh my god just have
all that time making good soil then
what's in the
or even because it's outside and you
never speak greatly
I'm here to Hannover for god sakes and
take notes and helmet Konishi you want
to soak up as much of this stuff as you
possibly can use that rascal [ __ ]
it's just absolutely
Wow all the reason he discovered it is
that he discovered himself ability
discovery but he discovered that it
would be too big competence and he won
the International pumpkin contest two
years unbelievable it needs the right
lights and we're going to be talking
about lights just for 2 minutes at the
end here my friend sinned and can't show
you a new Michael a plasma white most
efficient endeavor and the reason why
I'm excited about it because thus far is
the best let's base organics and so what
goes together pet no I mean it's it's
just the way it's supposed to happen and
the LEDs and the HIV to be no they don't
this new mask the lighting never seen a
plastic like you're about to see one
today five minutes anyway when I think
the right stuff I particular tension to
what your stuff does to the other stuff
so when you use a light is that might
open your books for these herbs it might
be actually open but breathe it might
actually be killing off our lovely place
do that so there's a synergistic effect
of all of your stuff together gotta stop
with the amenities this video will be
IDM no do you use IBM worklight usually
the right things that enhances it so
it's a whole different thing
it's just what fun is fun to use bucks
to watch a praying mantis you know bring
your cheesy they get them pulp what
you're doing and the pervasive teeth it
all never thought cell banks that straw
cover there's definitely use they don't
have microbial biomass eventually the
Bible you know by a microbial leader and
that you want to use compost working
possibly 10 and blames compost team and
runnings the right knowledge is so Brown
villages are for fungal breathing
launches of artwork cameras these people
just go get your grass clippings your
plants when you take them that bill
Plante if you're not going to use the
leaves for oil
I got he was right there on the plant
you're growing gee willikers reuse and
recycle
those extra days those excellent plant
spends fifty to sixty percent of its
photosynthetic energy producing those
entities it's in the soil throw it out
this good stuff
yeah and test it test let me say the any
test the most I'm not going to ask
because the last time I did it another
soul
I was soldered by people afterwards they
were embarrassed nobody raised their
feet as many people your test you've got
a text okay that's good that's good so
there's the bio ever tested Samantha
left so that test you know even cosmic
tips why because informations power
information is power and you're stupid
if you don't get that information so
information is power
what's nice is instead of plants
outdoors plants to our plants it doesn't
matter whether they're inside or outside
in fact you know we're getting the point
where I hate the Santa Canyon or wrong
it was something that most of our son
likes the way that you're going to be
their bigger facilities so nice like
this you know and so who would like this
make a tremendous amounts of sense so
you definitely use you want to use
Google Google is the Canada's grow his
best friend but you know Donald Trump is
great at one if they occasionally
there's smoke in the victims on Google
you know playing Flushing
hands down okay sorry
you know so you read my bucket doesn't
seem to make any sense to flush with you
really understand what happens in that
cell and you see those little channels
with it nutrients go in and things come
out of it wait a minute how could it
possibly work it doesn't okay you know
it want to use Google because of the big
bad guys sorry
basically get anytime we want you know
you also carry a cell phone you're out
there in the vehicle looking at your
plan to do something wrong don't wait
after dinner get the injury
we live in a terrific world and again
you can death the big guys are all doing
this in spades we don't stay a couple
steps ahead we just happen alright so I
always said to people if you're not
convinced just thinking about this and
all the Redwoods ones that happen to
burn down you know they have been
growing 500 years 600 years there's 750
feet tall how they grow you know
whatever they teamed with Michael's just
like you
thank you very much
you