hey everybody I am here today with Tyler
Marquardt who's a good friend of mine
he's a longtime cannabis cultivator and
hash maker but today we're going to talk
about something totally different
Tyler I have been friends for a long
time and he has recently completed a
series of sessions of ketamine under
doctors care I guess so it's like legal
official ketamine instead of ketamine
you got from a friend so um so we wanted
to talk about that a little bit because
ketamine therapy to my knowledge is
pretty new and to come across somebody
who has has done a full round of it and
is also you know has got a recreational
drug background so let's share some of
our vocabulary right I thought that
would be really interesting to hear
about it from somebody who's already a
psycho not so Tyler thank you so much
for taking some time this morning and
chatting with us absolutely thank you
for having me here around so so let's
let's figure out you know I know that
you were aware of ketamine at all of us
who have done like exploration with
drugs you know generally know that
ketamine exists because it's a horse
tranquilizer and and people joke about K
holes and stuff but um but but at some
point you were reintroduced to it as a
medicine something that you thought was
going to help offer you some kind of
relief so when you lay that out for us
and kind of like let us know what what
attracted you to it like let alone
getting doctors help and getting
ketamine yeah so I was born with the
genetic liver disorder and IBS and that
had caused serious depression and
anxiety
specifically with food so every time you
eat food it causes intestinal spasms and
other issues that are very detrimental
and hard to deal with so you have to
become forcing yourself to basically eat
food and that you get anxiety every time
you eat so over the last 38 years of
dealing with this it just
built and built and built and got worse
then I had gotten arrested in 2011 and
convicted for a court trial for running
a medical marijuana dispensary and that
just kind of added to everything so the
depression hit really really hard and
then I needed something to kind of help
with that because regular psychotherapy
wasn't working anything it exercised
wasn't doing it and I needed something
to really push myself beyond the level
of what society was giving me with basic
sacrifice stuff that we'd normally go
through you know so you know you knew
you knew you were depressed and you
wanted things to change and you tried
you tried therapy and clearly you tried
weed and exercise and you're like you're
going down the list you're like none of
this stuff is working yeah and so so
like you know ketamine is kind of a a
typical response to depression right
right so so what what turned you onto
that as being a solution so you know
being on Instagram in a couple other
places social media sites I had good
connections with other Psychonauts and
and and doctors and and started doing
research about what options that were
out there a friend of ours Allison
Drayson who works at the clinic that I
went to she had posted something about
the therapy being available so that kind
of sparked my interest I had tried
ketamine like once before as a teenager
and did not enjoy the experience was not
ready for it or whatever the deal was
and and so I never really thought about
it or anything like that and then
started doing more research into there's
a book called the ketamine Papers which
kind of lays out a bunch of different
experiments that were done over the
years so I read that a little bit and
just became a little bit more interested
and it really got to the point where the
depression was so heavy oh I was
suicidal and like it's really struggling
to deal with moving forward in life
because of the stomach issues and other
stuff that was related to it
so I end up just being like you know
what like I'm just gonna give this a try
and if it works great if it doesn't then
I get to you know how
a second second somatic experience in
you know for a couple hours or something
like that and but it did it really
changed my life after the sessions were
done so when you originally read about
ketamine as a potentially providing
relief for depression how was it
described to you that got your attention
you're like oh this is this is something
I had not considered before like what
was the kind of means supposed to do it
was it was interesting because some of
the papers had said like um there was a
female individual patient who was
struggling with depression anxiety and
she had taken one treatment and was
cured from her issues after one
treatment and I was like wow that's
amazing and now of course the paper said
no this is not not all patients are like
this other patients do require other
lengthier treatments some patients don't
respond to the treatment so it's like
any other pharmaceutical it's like
cannabis you know one may work for
somebody and it may not work well for
others but for the people that does work
well and it seems like it works well for
majority of the people it doesn't make a
major change so I was very much
interested in like it's either gonna
change or I'm gonna kill myself so
that's pretty much where it came down to
I was homeless living in my car and like
you know just trying to figure out what
where my next step was because the
biggest issue with the digestive tract
issue is like I have to spend a majority
of my money on food and not just
McDonald's or like fast foods or
anything like has to be good food that
has nutritious value so that was like a
majority of the issue of where I was
headed it was like I need either change
now or we end this and so I figured hey
let's give this one one last chance and
see where it goes I had tried micro
dosing psilocybin but struggled with the
digestive tract issues of it so it
wasn't something that really worked well
for me on a day-to-day basis and this
seemed like it was you go in for the
session the session is over and then you
go back to life and it's maybe a slow
gradual build back up but it'll get you
where you need to be and so that became
very interesting
and like I said it was more just like it
we give this a try or we end it and
that's it and so I tried committing
suicide a couple times because of the
digestive tract issues once as a
teenager and then once in my 20s and and
so I was like you know this is I'm just
getting tired of this it's tired of
waking up every morning and painting
tired of like having to like relieve
myself from in a situation to go to the
bathroom or do something like that
and it just became mentally exhausting
and physically exhausting as well so
something had to happen either I get
better or I go away right now and so so
so let's talk about what it's like
because you know very likely there are
other people who are listening who are
depressed or have one of the other
attributes that that ketamine can be
used for and they're all like but what a
weird visit that's got to be going into
an office asking for you know
potentially hallucinogenic doses of
ketamine yes that's so um so you know I
know that you went to doctors to neo
agar walls clinic who has been on the
shaping fire podcast and you know we've
had speak many times because Sunil is
great right and and you were you were
kind of encouraged to come in by our
mutual friend Allison Grayson so you
already kind of knew the people involved
with the clinic yeah but um will you you
you know remind us of the name of the
clinic where it is and and essentially
like what your first experience was
going in there yes so the Ames Institute
is located in Seattle on East Lake and
it's a easily accessible place to get to
and the people who work there are all
wonderful people going into that office
really makes you feel like you have the
potential to change your life everybody
is super carrying everybody is super
calm there's a wonderful ambiance in the
office so it's very inviting when you go
in there it's not a cold sterile
doctor's office kind of feel which was
very something that I was pretty much
always against like I don't want to have
to take Western medicine
- like you know deal with it because it
usually causes other problems or
something of that nature right and
looking at their website you can tell
that this is gonna be a different
experience right because they I don't
remember it exactly but it says
something like you know ketamine therapy
cannabis therapy psychedelics therapy in
you're like oh I like this menu yeah
it's not exactly like popping in your
regular doctor's office yeah totally so
so so was you know did you go in and
have a ketamine experience your first
time or was there like intake first yeah
so there's gonna take they kind of get
you to prepare it and they want to go
through to see like kind of what your
experiences are with psychedelic
experiences so that they know okay are
you prepared for what's gonna happen
have you ever had something like this
before because if you've never had that
experience before and this is your first
time in that setting it could be very
very overwhelming and because you're not
in a comfortable setting that you know
you're not in your house or something
like that so it can be overwhelming if
you are custom to these kind of
experiences psychedelic experiences you
will definitely have an easier walking
into the office so understanding of
what's happening sure and then the
actual ketamine sessions themselves are
are taking place in such a way that you
you feel extremely comfortable they make
you feel very they offer the opportunity
for comfort there and in a variety of
different ways most of the sessions take
place in like a reclining chair where
they'll put like a weighted blanket on
you keep you warm
they'll also run aromatherapy in the
office as well so you have very warming
kind of smells when you come in and then
they also introduce music which is kind
of like a instrumental Eastern style of
music that's very calming and relaxing
and helps you get into that kind of
transient state that added with Brooks
here it is they offer these blindfolds
which was developed by Alex gray who is
an artist and I'll Psychonauts I go now
probably these the most well-known
psychic
some of the group here but these are
very interesting in the fact that
they're raised and the insides are cut
out so it allows you to open your eyes
while the black out action is still
happening
so it'll increase the effect the visual
effects of the ketamine which is a very
important part of the experience and so
so what one thing I want to toss in here
just a shift the pronouns you're using
at this point because since you're
moving into telling us what your
ketamine experience was like for you I
want to be clear that this is not a
commercial for the clinic or anything
the reason why we're talking about this
is that I wanted us to be able to hear
Tyler's experienced first person so that
any of us who also want to get involved
can find this kind of care wherever so
so at this point let's shift it from
what the Ames Institute did for you to
versus like I and so like what what was
going on for you because I think that
you'll know your story will be told in a
different way yes so so on the day that
you first went for an in-office ketamine
experience which so did you know it was
going to be wholly synergetic before you
started I had a feeling that it would
probably be something like that I didn't
realize how intense it would be so that
was interesting to me and I mean I've
done a fair amount of hallucinogens
before so I knew the experience but but
when you first told me about it that you
were getting gonna get involved with
this almost a year ago I was thinking
like a whole like paralysis right like
you like you were just gonna be in your
head and kind of frozen and that was
going to be it and then when you first
described this story that you're about
to tell us I'm all like what the hell
you do
yeah yeah so so so you thought that you
might loose Nate but but most of you
just wanted to check out this this new
yeah yeah seems true yeah that you know
or allowed access for it so yeah so the
experience I sat down into this
reclining chair that they provided for
me and put the blankets on everything
it's an inner muscular injection so I
got the injection into my shoulder now I
am a slightly different wired than most
people most people generally are kind of
in an anesthetic state and they just lay
there for the hour and a half time
period and kind of just soak in the
experience apparently I am a very wild
child and was like flailing everywhere
and I almost fell out of the chair
during the experience so on to the
second experience they moved me to the
floor on a mattress where Serena was
like you didn't have as far that's all
the safer I think for everybody here cuz
I almost punch the nurse in the face
apparently at one point came over to the
help and I was like rah so you're
flailing right if most people get really
sedated right up and they just lay there
and they have this mental experience
that is healing while they are in this
sedated state
why were you flailing around were you
having like active hallucinations that
you were responding to or were you just
like feeling you know like oh I've got
ants in my bloodstream or whatever yeah
what was the nature of your flailing I
guess so the way it worked was when they
give you the injection I got the
injection right into the arm and they
put it in and it's within maybe 15
seconds you'll immediately you start
feeling warm in your arm and then you
smell the ketamine which is interesting
and then within 15 seconds you start
drifting off slowly into another
dimension so that's pretty nice like
it's not a rocket shot into like another
dimension but it is an out-of-body
experience so you do leave your your
person and go somewhere else in your mom
finally dimethyltryptamine like DMT
exactly it's very much like DMT in that
sense except for with DMT you seem just
all of a sudden being rock it is that
yeah and this isn't much more like your
honor like maybe like a magic carpet or
a cloud and being brought up to like an
escalator to like the next dimension so
the softness of it is really nice for
somebody who maybe isn't excuse to that
kind of DMT like jet fuel experience but
you know when you get there it is a very
DMT like experience where there's a lot
of moving shapes and colors a lot of
sound of grinding and stuff like that a
very intense overwhelming a lot of the
issues I think I had with the flailing
and the and stuff like that is because
of my liver and I processed drugs very
differently than other people because of
that liver enzyme disorder so you know
like if you were to take the ketamine it
may give you an experience that's like
longer and and more stable whereas I get
a very hard intense experience for a
shorter duration and so because my liver
is just like you know let's take
everything in and like this seems great
you know and so that seems to be a bit
of an issue so they have to adjust some
of the things for the second treatment
for that as well too because like put
you on the floor first treatment was a
lot it was pretty heavy and so but again
everybody's different so they try to
figure out where you are to gauge it at
and but I think the heaviness of the
trip is the most important part because
it really resets your brain and it
really resets you to becoming accepting
of problems as opposed to being like
there's nothing we can do this problem
is gonna ruin me but a little wah you
end up becoming more like this is a
problem now how do we solve it kind of
issue and so after the first treatment I
felt slightly better less depressed not
a hundred percent pulled off but I felt
like I had shifted the paradigm to be
facing somewhere else even though you
were flailing would you would you call
it fun I would call it fun uh if some
people may call it a terrifying
experience I think it depends on how you
like to view life I enjoy psychedelics I
have always enjoyed psychedelics it's
probably one of my preferred drugs of
choice obviously cannabis being a
hallucinogen and so I think for me it
was a more comfortable experience
because that was something I was used to
it but it could could be slightly
terrifying for somebody who's not used
to that kind of psychedelic experience
but again one of those things is it's
terrifying because it's changing you
internally from what the nurse told me
was there's a ring in your head now
obviously not doctor I'm not gonna
probably pronounce this or do this
correctly but there's a ring of cellular
structures in your head that basically
ketamine rewires and that has to do with
like depression and anxiety and
associates with that and it literally
rewires the connections and those
portions of the brain and so that may
happen slowly over a multiple period of
time for me it took a few months for
that to work but you can feel the change
happening and it's interesting you can
you come out of the experience very
confused at first like to come down is a
little bit confusing but you work
yourself out of that after about 30
minutes and you do need somebody to pick
you up afterwards because you're not
able to like drive or do anything like
that well that reminds me a lot going
back to DMT right because folks who have
not tried something like DMT it's not
like like psilocybin or something where
where you take something and you're my
first person consciousness analogy is
still here but I am but there's there's
something on top of that right that
there's the hallucinogen on top of it
but you're still like essentially
walking around being you yeah right
whereas drugs like DMT and ketamine it's
more like you take your human you unplug
from reality
your first-person consciousness is gone
and you plug into another real
which is totally foreign and yet somehow
familiar and you're there for a while
and then it ends and then you unplug
from that reality and suddenly now
you're back in your body that is a
really strange experience not only every
time that you experience it but it was
certainly the first couple times yes and
um you're wiped out just from having
such an intensity experience like like
you aren't ready to nap for days sure
yeah afterwards the stuff for about six
hours after each session and you kind of
are after the six hour rest you're
better you're you're back on your feet
again and there's no issues or anything
like that but you're right it can be
overwhelming for some folks who are new
to the experience but you know I think
it's a it's a crucial point part of the
experience like without that part I
think it you wouldn't be able to move
forward so one thing I want to dive in a
little bit more is during the experience
while you are let's say checked out
right you are not having your first
person Tyler consciousness and yet you
have memories of what was happening
during your ketamine trip so so some
part of your brain is certainly running
and really busy right that may sound
like spooky to some people right yes and
and honestly maybe even that's
legitimate yeah that's some pretty
intense stuff that happens so but will
you talk a little bit more about what
that was like
like you're not conscious but but things
are happening in your mind you just talk
to that weirdness absolutely the the
mask really kind of enhances everything
when you wear the the the face mask
because at one point I accidentally
knocked the face mask off and then you
can see everybody in the room and you
see them as miss starlett it was
horrible actually because like the
individuals don't look like they should
look like they're you're hallucinating
like characters on them or they're
or something like that so it's a little
bit overwhelming you have to get the
mass spec on pretty quickly but when the
mask is on it's it's it's different
you're in this environment where it's
almost like the the environment around
you that you see is shifting like a
kaleidoscope it's a bunch of colors and
shapes colors and shapes are coming out
of the dimension that you're seeing and
they're moving and shifting almost like
a Rubik's Cube what would kind of so you
may see like a square color four or five
colors come out in a square shape and
then shift into a circle and then move
back into the the background of what
you're seeing some people experience and
like an entity or like a person or a
face I didn't have any experiences like
that this is essentially your your brain
just freestyling yeah like even though
there are themes to it like the you know
like gyrating geometrics and things like
that yeah um I would think that it's
pretty personal yeah and there are
consistencies through it like you do see
a lot of sacred geometry stuff like you
will see like shapes that like you would
see like paintings of and stuff like a
good if you if you do go look at Alex
Gray's paintings those those are
excellent representations of what the
experience is like colorful wise and
like you know he often shows like a lot
of people and you'll see their insides
and particularly see people or their
insides but the concept of the colors
and and the the like beyond third
dimensional look that comes to his
paintings are very similar to like what
you see and there are other artists out
there but he's obviously the most
accessible II sure well-known and so a
bad experience is visually overwhelming
for a lot of people and it was for me
too the first time I did it because they
you know you are getting a fair amount
of ketamine there's just no but you know
you then become used to it by the set
you know what you're getting yourself
into it
round two and round three even though
that you're not in control at all at
least you know what's coming down the
pike right exactly and you know it's
it's exciting it's a it's overwhelming
but it is leading to a better change and
you do feel the change afterwards
sometimes the change is you know like
using baseball is if you may hit a home
run and it changes it immediately but
sometimes you have to hit four singles
to score a run right and so the same
thing goes with and and and the goal the
scoring of the run is having these
unique experiences that we don't know
exactly what they are but they are
laying down new neural pathways which is
the ultimate goal so that when you come
down off the ketamine and you've had
like you know some time to rest and you
integrate you're actually integrating
new neural pathways which somehow will
leave the depression yeah I think what
the way it was explained to me and I'm
not a neurologist by any means but what
happens is you when you get into a
depressive state you get pathways that
get stuck and they don't like unhook or
changed into other pathways and they
just kind of become dominant pathways
and so the ketamine really just unplugs
those pathways and then wires them back
to where they should be or into new
pathways I'm obviously not I don't know
100 percent but that's kind of how it
was explained to me is like that ring
around your head is what controls those
those depressive thoughts and those
anxious thoughts and it's good to have
depressive thoughts it's also good to
have an anxious thoughts it's just not
good to have them all 90% of the time
right and so I think that's what this
does is it really helps loosen that grip
that the depression gets on the
neurological grip right and it just
takes hold of your brain and doesn't
gonna let go and this ketamine really
loosens that grip so you know you you
can still feel sad when sad things
happen because you don't want to be
walking around life and like you
somebody tell you oh hey your father
just passed away and you know you had a
great relationship with him and you're
like yeah there it is things happen you
want
able to grieve and I want to have the
full range of emotion right yeah you
just don't want to be constantly like
yeah everyday or just stuck in the
valley you know and so I think the
ketamine really helped me in a way kind
of loosen up it was a slow loosen up you
know when you're when you're anxious
you're tense and when you're depressed
you're like don't want to be around
anybody and the ketamine kinda just took
the tension away it took away the
consistent thought of wanting to kill
myself when that was all I mean I for
three or four months all I could think
about was how am I gonna do this
like what what's the way in which I'm
gonna do this because I don't wanna I
don't want to like suffer for a long
time I was trying to kill myself I just
wanted to end I don't want to do with
anymore and so it just kind of removed
that like overwhelming focus I had on
how am I gonna do this and then it was
it shifted more towards well no now I
got my [__] back together how do I get
out of being homeless how do I get out
of doing moving on from here and and and
just going and so it was it was
overwhelming but it was worth it it's
like it's like going on an adventure and
a safari and you get stuck in the jungle
and you didn't plan on it but you got
out and now you have an awesome story to
tell people for the rest of your life
that like I did some amazing things in
the jungle I ate plants I've never seen
before drank off of leaves and you know
did the and slept under trees and stuff
and it's like a rebirth yeah and it was
difficult it was hard it was
overwhelming but I
it changed my life it changed me for the
better it made me a stronger person so I
know that you did three of the
intramuscular shots in the clinic firs
and then um and then you you what's
called it a tranche at Roche approach
when you describe it it sounds like
doing liquid acid on it essentially it
is like us like a sugar cube yep a
little bit of oral ketamine in it yes
they had about 100 milligrams of
ketamine per dose I was told to take 100
milligrams per session at home and I
found that 200 milligrams was a little
bit better setting for me and so yeah so
I basically at that time period I was
living in my car sleeping in my car so
I'd set up the car in a way that I had
an air mattress put the SUV so I put the
back seats down put the air mattress in
there I had a couple heavy blankets and
then I had the the eye mask as well and
dr. Agrawal had mentioned you know you
really should play some music along with
it something that has like a calm
relaxation to it you know oftentimes you
hear that meditative music then you get
it like a yoga studio or something like
there's something you vibe with exactly
I chose the Grateful Dead for my first
session Dix picks volume number one
seemed to be a good idea and it went
really well this session the the troj
sessions are much softer than the
intramuscular sessions you can go off
into kind of a slight another dimension
like I when I was listening to the Dix
pics Grateful Dead session it felt like
I was on stage at the show that day like
Jerry was off to the right playing his
guitar Bob standing next to me I can
hear the boys banging on the drums in
the back and so that and you've got that
mask on running in your car right yep so
your your brain is creating the
experience of seeing the band yes to go
with the music
yeah and that's interesting so it was
really kind of like a happy experience
for me I've never seen the Grateful Dead
before and so like I was like
overwhelmed like oh my god Jerry
Garcia's play guitar right next to me
and so it was very came out of that one
was like a very happy attitude the other
two sessions that I did in my car I
actually downloaded music that was like
to a certain hearse 432 Hertz it's
supposed to be like a tone in which is a
healing tone and so that really helped
kind of like create like a own
mental cycling exactly and that I think
that music is because that was similar
to the music that Sunil had played in
the doctor's office and to jump back to
that temporarily really quickly one of
the experiences I had in there with him
was he I was on the floor and coming out
of the experience I was maybe the last
30 minutes of the the experience and I
had the mask off and I was my eyes are
open I could see the office very mildly
hallucinating but but not in a train
tranquil state kind of Sunil had asked
if he could meditate above my head so he
I was on the floor and he set back here
in Lotus and was meditating over me and
at the same time he would ring a singing
bowl singing bowl yes and every time he
rang the singing bowl I would howl
uncontrollably to the pitch that well
the bowl was making yeah and I was like
but you know I'm like and he's like okay
that's crazy
oh and so vicki was sick and it got to
the point where he gotten so much energy
moving through my body that my arm like
unwillingly went and just grabbed
Sunil's head and like just I held onto
his head and I could feel like an energy
beam coming out of his head like I could
feel his it's like human energy and I
told him I was like I feel all your
power and he didn't budge he just kept
it was awesome because he just kept you
know meditating and he was totally with
the situation any stain like exactly he
wasn't like what are you doing grabbing
me I have a doctor like this is
unprofessional like he went with it rode
with it and it was an amazing feeling
for me it really kind of like boosted my
energy I don't know if I was sucking
energy out of his head or if it was just
the the him allowing me to do that like
better personal vision contact yeah kind
of like made my energy like enhanced or
something of that nature so that was a
very interesting experience to me that
made me feel really good after the after
that comes out of the experience but
back to the churches the experience with
the the instrumental music at the the
was extremely beneficial after the
second and third troj I think it did a
total of four of them after the second
third roach session I was almost
completely like healed and I felt like a
completely different person
not in the sense that like I'm not Tyler
Marquardt anymore I'm Bob Johnson or
whatever it was more that like I had a
clarity in my head and and zero focused
towards depression zero focus on anxiety
I mean this is from me being 38 years of
eating and forcing myself to eat or
since being 13 years old smoking weed
before every single meal because that's
the only way I can get through eating a
meal is it's getting high and forcing
myself well certainly over the last year
you know you're doing these seven and
then and then integrating them you know
you're currently a less miserable friend
yes before before you got turned on to
the ketamine you know you were a good
friend yeah and you were freaking
miserable and a negative person yeah and
a lot of people had told me that and I
recognized that myself that I was not
happy it ruins personal relationships
ruined business relationships it ruined
dating relationships and so it was a
major problem in my life and I had to
change something you want to either way
right and you need to take care of
myself or him you know off myself so um
so let's uh let's move to wrap this up
so so this is a pretty specific video
right you're going to be talking about
ketamine at this level so so probably
the only people who are still with us
are people who are either depressed and
looking for solutions or people who are
looking at ketamine for other reasons
that they're looking for relief from and
and then maybe they're using this video
as part of their decision-making process
right yeah so what do you what would you
say or what are you going to say
to anybody who is watching who may be
considering ketamine therapy just like
you know if they were something that you
were chatting with and and they brought
it up and what do you have to say to
them directly to I don't know help them
figure out whether or not ketamine is
gonna be for them yeah I think it's one
of those situations where it's
individual so it's it's gonna be
different for everybody some people may
have a quick reaction to it some people
may not but it's worth it it's worth
trying it it's worth changing your life
for the better
because you can you that opportunity out
there is there and the nice part is is
some insurance companies do cover it
like I had unfortunately paid out of
pocket because I didn't have any health
insurance at the time but it was also
very affordable for the sense of what
you're looking for I'm not going to
comment on the what the pricing is
because I think the person changed so I
wouldn't be on point as far as that goes
but it is affordable it's less than rent
for a month for most people and so that
I think is there is a solution out there
and I think one of our biggest problems
is is we have this controlled substance
act which is limiting our ability to
access drugs that can really help people
and ketamine is on that that list and so
I think really getting that stuff
changed on the government level will
make a major impact in all of society's
life because people will have access
towards medication that can really
change their lives it worked for me it's
worked for a multitude of other people I
think it's starting to become more
accepted like just like psilocybin is 4
micro dosing and LSD is 4 micro dosing
now and I think people if you just have
the opportunity to to look into it a
little bit more and face that fear of
overwhelming psychedelic experience you
can get to a totally different place you
can be happy you can change who you are
I mean you're you're the best
representation of this because you and I
have a lot of interaction together on a
daily or weekly
the basis where we talk to each other
and you really did see that I was an
angry [__] you know and you have seen
me change to somebody who is less angry
and and and I don't have that mentality
anymore and and I'm just extremely
grateful for Sunil
for Allison and for all the other people
at the the clinic who helped me they and
everybody at the clinic is it couldn't
be a better person for that situation
mild temperaments just welcoming arms
you know I mean Sunil will give me a hug
every time I came to the office you know
like most doctors don't even come near
you or like shake your hand you know and
this doctor has given me a hug and
welcoming to the office so I think it's
you know when the individual is ready to
make the change because it's also like
the depression has to get to a point
where you need to admit you need to
acknowledge that you need to make a
change and I think that that's the
hardest thing right because the
opportunities out there for people but
now you have to take advantage of the
opportunity and that's the only way
you're gonna grow nobody can force you
to be happy nobody can force you to be
better you have to make that decision
yourself and say I want to be better I
want to make this change there are tools
out there for for me to access that in a
legal manner there are the Ames
Institute is not the only Institute in
the United States who's doing this
therapy there
I believe the therapies in Chicago in
New York as well I'm a hundred percent
sure where they were located but I know
there are other offices that are located
a friend of Mines father did the therapy
in New York but he did it under drip IV
as opposed to inner muscular but he he
did not have as much of a response to it
as I did
he's also old or too so I don't know if
that experience had any time with it but
but like I said first it's different for
every individual and I think really
looking into it and reading those
ketamine papers the book is actually
called ketamine papers and going on to
PubMed gov and doing other research
about ketamine and see
what's out there do the research because
you're the only one who's in control of
your life and you have the ability to
make the changes if you want to it can
be really hard and challenging and
overwhelming it's like when you're in
that state any action can be a
depressive action right like whether
your shoelaces are untied you trip and
fall you drop a glass they can just
spiral into just almost like a suicide
thought process because it's just your
world is crumbling but there's a light
at the end of the tunnel that light is
provided by ketamine and other
substances and I think people need to
get that negative mantra of drugs are
bad you know everything is bad in excess
some people react to things differently
I can eat cheeseburgers all day and not
gain any weight because I have IBS right
cheeseburgers aren't bad for me but you
know most of America is not doing too
good you know I think it's an individual
thing but again I think the
opportunities are out there and
opportunity is the biggest and best word
that we can have in our in our culture
because that's what leads to growth and
leads to the betterment and that
opportunity can only be taken when you
want it to right like if you want to
change then you can make it happen and
you'll figure it out and but just know
that the tools are out there to help you
and again even when you're on that when
you're consuming the tools and and after
you've consumed the tools it's still an
active process of wanting to be better
and and you you just need to change your
your whole mentality to bettering
yourself bettering the environment
around you not particularly like you
know doing KNF or like soil regeneration
but more like keeping your yourself
clean like showering and like needing
health self-care yeah self-care and
self-love and that kind of stuff which
is I think all very difficult for a lot
of people especially
in America where I think we're in a
state where the patriarchy is a big is a
big problem right and like people are
struggling with male-dominated
industries and male-dominated things and
a lot of that comes down to I think we
could have a major shift in society if
that male dominance thought process was
was rewired to a process of non
dominance but Association and
cooperation and and moving forward in a
way that everybody can have opportunity
and access to to opportunity because
that's really what it comes down I think
opportunity is the big big key here is
there is opportunity and and people can
take advantage of it but I think America
struggles right now with wanting to get
out of that classic materialistic
mindset which is you know has
overwhelmed us for the last 50 years I
think it's it can't be any surprise that
you know somebody with his bombastic of
a personality as you it would take like
a serious hallucinogen for you to find
the relief you're looking for but um
thank you for going to all the effort to
find the solutions so that we could keep
you around instead of and and thanks to
Allison and dr. Sunil for for helping
you get there and and then finally thank
you for sitting down this Sunday morning
and just kind of sharing some of your
story because you're you're on the front
edge of this and there's not a lot of
people who've done ketamine under
doctors care at this point and in
significantly less who are willing to
share your story so thank you brother
yes thank you you know talking about
depression anxiety is really difficult
and it but it does help so you know find
one person that you trust to talk to you
about it and I think it will definitely
change your life awesome cool well thank
you for sharing this time with us and
thank you for watching shaping fire I am
Shango Lowe's this is Tyler Marquardt
thanks
you