let me talk sure talk me through this
okay so what I'm gonna do is I'm just
gonna create a timeline this is a skunk
from 1981 I received it from an
individual who had it in a library and
ended going into flowering from stress
the reason why I wanted to show the vid
was one to just show the plant because
it's crisis anxious and the show that
the earth Fox technology it's wonderful
for recovering older genetics because
once you set this up the plant basically
balances out in its biology and its
uptake it normals out in the wave grows
morphologically and from here the
cuttings are beautiful to start working
the thing that occurred back in the
eighties all through the 90s forward was
we had beautiful cannabis and as we went
into indoor cultivation we had problems
controlling the smell and lo and behold
we got rid of a lot of these cannabis
varieties that are exceptionally unique
and the problem is is that we're trying
to assume that it was terpenes only that
made those smells and actually we
starting to understand now that it was
esters a plant alcohols and those are
unique to the plant and so you can't
really breed and reproduce some of these
odors with the modern varieties because
they're not carrying these esters
forward it's not just Terps alone that
make it tastes and trends change over
time and what was popular in the 80s was
not popular in the 90s and subscales we
popular in 2000's the direction that it
was taken makes it sometimes difficult
to go back to a location so if we were
seeking only fruity floral skunks for
years then it would be very difficult
now to go find these heavily burnt few
rubber skunks of the past and so that's
why these are these older plants are so
important that we can use them to bring
us back into a range of genetics that
reflect more what occurred at that time
period and then now we can make the
decisions as to what's really attractive
currently today using that population
and so these these older varieties are
crucial in cannabis for what we do
because it's there's no way to get back
into what was trendy in the past what
was really the foundation of the modern
cannabis lines and a lot of times we
realize that we went in the wrong
direction and so hopefully I can tap
into this and see
many many different directions to go in
flavor and chemo type in terms of high
but hopefully we're able to find some of
those rare alcohol esters that that
create some of these unbelievably
pungent funky smells the reason why you
knew a skunk was a skunk was it was
because it was an ester it was almost
instantly volatize and had it had
instantaneous aroma through the space
exceptionally difficult to capture it
because it's bonded so lightly but
that's what we want now is he's
incredibly loud bright explosive strains
the signature isn't an issue or legally
grown in the state if we work within our
boundaries these kind of cannabis
varieties are the new market this 81 I
have one from the 90s the hogs breath
and then a Grass Valley skunk that I
picked up through those four female
Praja Nader's and then the male skunks
that I'm sifting through now to go into
it hopefully over the next couple years
we really be able to start to pull out
some of the stuff from the past that
that really got most of us in the
cannabis and give us a lot more choices
and options than what we have today out
there just have visuals not to see you
just continuously talk and having the
map would be close and this timeline
gives you a reflection of from 1968 to
2017 so 68 was basically when you
started to have the huge influx of the
back to land movement the reclamation
people into Humble County by 81 we had a
full-blown outdoor situation that was
unparalleled this is where the
reputation of Humboldt was really built
by 1983 this is camp and it radically
changed canvas from this point forward
from this point forward we went into
cannabis that was no longer so
attractive it was more of a stealth type
cannabis and so as we went forward this
time you know 10 20 30 plus years 35
years we changed what cannabis was from
here and so if I breathe something from
this point or say from here I was
reflecting spittle populations and so in
order for me to get
back all the way into the past of these
varieties here I have to actually find a
plant from the past to bring this ripple
or I have to do a population so big you
know twenty thousand thirty thousand
plants of this size so that I can find
here or it's just easy to find the plant
and go here so we have a choice it's
bigger populations or go back in time to
find the plants that were taken so what
people realize is when you when you when
you have a line and when you take the X
Y and we cross somebody to do our F one
we have many potential progeny we can go
in any of these directions in skunks we
went this way with the with the more
floral and flute frooties lower smell
lower ester I just want to go back down
this line and go across the board and
start to pull out some of these things
that were so unbelievably attractive in
my memory and then resurrect them this
way and that's the whole point of the
skunk project is to come back out of the
floral fruits and go back in time enough
to get the gene pool so we can f2 f3 f4
and try to get it into more stable line
and now that we have the ability to do
this outside once again really what I'm
doing is I'm replicating 1968 to 1981
[Music]