hey it's Shango from the shaping fire
podcast you know a few weeks ago I was
at the Washington cannabis summit and
Kevin Jo Durie was there up from
Wonderland nursery in Humboldt County
where he lives
and he was on that cannabis as
agriculture panel and it was a fantastic
panel actually the whole panel was great
but you know I'm a big fan of Kevin Jody
and so I pulled out all the bits with
Kevin talking and edit them all together
and posting it here for you today and so
you know you can kind of considered a
whole bunch of Kevin Jody gems he talks
a little bit about terpenes of course he
talks a bit about strange choice a
little bit about russet mites and you
know a little bit of this and that but
this is all solid gold so thanks to the
canvas Alliance for letting me record
and thanks for Kevin for coming up and
sharing his insights with us here you go
Washington your exceptional instigator
work with my canvas is pretty expensive
in terms of my ways trying to get about
21 years and I always as even as child
believed we would end up here I knew
what some morning that Canada's
become except in a different view and I
approached it from that point of view
and so I try to understand as much as I
could about what I was doing so that I
would have a future I'm looking to some
point I end up here and I knew that I
would have to be allowed skillset to
survive so to speak and a lot of money
studying cannabis and working in this
was trying to understand primarily how
does one get cannabis to the table which
means are we headed to the market and
then it's really the most important
thing to me because that dictates
everything backwards and then we put
ethics with it you actually have a very
sustainable situation so we use combine
how do we get product to the table and
how do we do it in that the core manner
what you have with the cannabis is it
was held in check for so long
that what we did was we created an
entire of a library of genetics that
were improperly source what we did all
these years is we we chose canvas of the
stealth so we took away a lot of
desirability and smell and we use all
these illegal pesticides and fungicides
and PTR's plant growth regulators to
assist us and what happened over all
these years decades is that we created
the gene the week we chose varieties
that were Trinity and we
to have any bottleneck room and so what
you have is you have a secret population
in cannabis varieties that we use that
are inherently prone to all these
different pathogenic problems as
problems inherently in certain
circumstances exceptionally hungry for
exception at night nutrient loads
because everywhere always gave their
plants the most fertile soil the best
situation and when we select in that
situation what you select is plants that
thrive in perfection or I live in a
vacuum what I want to see is a play that
really doesn't is treated in a horrible
situation that didn't get that we
actually work with in Seoul I don't know
many campuses a nursery operated I have
a farm so I'm kind of herbal so I hope
hot stuff going on but I'm not primarily
for nursery work and in California
basically created the modern nursery
model in terms of walking store nursery
from it was never done prior to that and
I created the nursery problem
dispensaries where the dispensary itself
created in stock so the last ten years
I've been applying what I learned in the
thirty years prior and rather that what
we found was that most cultivators are
basically praying for success and
they're there unfortunately praying in
the wrong direction
because what they
cheese products that are trendy with no
consideration for where they're going to
cultivate it and no acceleration to the
cultivation methodologies or the
operators and no diversity and what
happens is all she pushes an example
just because it's just such a hot water
where we live in California so everyone
wants to grow algae but oh geez a
massive family it's sort of hanging a
lot of cultivar emoji you get you might
get one that's exceptionally high really
prone exceptionally the tracks prone and
now we have rusted and Brooklyns that
are everywhere the promos also epidermal
layers thick top hasn't resist and so
people use these inferior cultivars and
they wonder why they're in the little
crafting table of the entire time to
cultivate and so what we try to do
through the normal nursery model was do
population sense so our idea was I go to
large populations of lands and we find
the outliers we find plants
ability to resist naturally and this is
a normal agriculture Erasmus I looking
in that I get to tour all kinds of neat
the symphonies I get to see some really
interesting stuff but I had to go and do
a tour of the largest redwood nursery
propagation facility in the world
so Rita is the world's largest record
producer they're also the largest event
with nursery I meant to talk to the lady
grabber who's been cultivating there for
28 years
he's involved in a reading project
that'll take 150 years and so mainly
carries the first 30 Republic but he
took me out into the it was mother
library so to speak which was acres and
acres of forest and it was from every
thousand eight years of redwoods the
biologist selected one as the greatest
of that thousand acres and they brought
that Hellman as I had to tour entire
fire sort of nothing of trees but then
it is selected from thousand acre lives
and one of these trees was known and it
was I mean one hundred and eighty
percent greater growth than any other
red whatever the better recording but
they were intelligent enough to not
follow Robin they did not allow to prop
that Baltimore what they did is they put
it so many miles from the other plants
that work with so that these patches
he's forty to give a farce of that
specific were laid out so they had a
diversity so even though it's within the
same family the cultivars have been
separated and bereta but it takes my
hundred
20 years to do see propagation and so
this phrase was it takes a 100 years
before she gets sexy
I thought something that make understand
that what we're doing now is we're we're
that we're the beginning of this where
we're the foundation of this is
California for days in this world in
terms of poverty approach called our
selection how do we approach I most
people have no clue that that means it's
a it's a rate law a pair of hands maybe
because really most cultivators in
Canada said never been in mainstream
attire but Washington that can start or
that's been legal for a while now so
that's been very uh I only need to come
here for the years that I have because
you get seen integration at a level that
you don't have to California in
California don't want to observe
situation where I get to work with the
tremendous number of professors from
universities scientists from private
organizations because they can't touch
Guinness it's they can't happen in hand
so to speak we can't have it at a school
they can have better facilities and so
they fly guys like these that are
willing to play detective and we
chase problems that we have cultivars
deceiver resist and they come in and
analyze and say this one is virally
infected this one it's not let's see
what happens when we probe and so what
yes I have happening is you start having
this intersection between the science
component and the actual ad component
because the 200 Rafi different worlds
and it's me Sciences it's understanding
but it's back you've got a whole little
variables constant in order to solve for
X you can't do that as a farmer and I
apart - and I've been fireman for a
really long time and other organic level
and so it's it's an attempt to try to
understand how does one as a farmer take
the information from normal agricultural
practices that are so organically based
biologically driven and then apply it to
what we do and actually have some
success and your scene
trying to figure out how song and we
have to be able to understand some of
the stuff going on this time he won't
proactive in our approach and like I
said in Prior for me I like to work on
populations what I find is that if I
want to get a good good friend you might
find him in groovy too you might find it
a little better that's good 200 you
might find a really decent person mm you
get 20,000 you can find something
exceptional and that's how I see ken is
called the power selection to his
population and it's been very difficult
for us you can burn these black market
operations who here so these incredible
populations that I work with a highly
legal parent or not and I think as a
farm operator here it's but all the art
and all the work all prior stuff that
was all through the desire for people to
really bring the cameras where you were
really about it willing to take the risk
it's a hunt the product that is going to
work for you whatever your needs were
and that was a common need so it's fine
and if it was from the distal needs and
perfect than it is but personally each
that's training but it requires you to
be able to have enough of that ability
to understand what is it you're seeking
a kind of ascertain that and what we've
tried to do is we've frightened to take
these cultivars with these big
populations and then my use of
milwaukee's technology to map them and
what it does it allows people not to be
able to find in that called
you know an exceptionally academically
resistant cultivars that we have that
are exception for your problems I call
them either of their desire because of
their they're too risky for cultivators
to take a gamble on and so what happens
is you end up having to back down the
populations you work with you know to
find specific cultivars the markets
trendy but when you chase those trends
much a seesaw brightness of accuracy and
what we try to recommend individuals is
a diversity in terms of what would be
diverse in terms of resistance so that
we have the greatest chance of survival
of a portion of the ground and then we
work on diversity in terms of market
velocity how fast those products will be
through the system so you have things
that are trending very quickly but there
is smaller markets and things that are
very stable and in the larger markets
but lower price points and so you try to
get this clear intersection of what is
the plan that you're trying to work with
and how you get it to function for your
weighted unique the concept Marla
culture is an important one and we just
had this discussion this morning about
the banana and so the benefit because
six exhibit assault we don't want my
Nana's
was because it was no more than an
estate
ergonomic that went out all the bananas
and so they [ __ ] another than in Tikal
it's called Cavendish the Cavendish come
on so they have finished all the part
about the country that they introduced
it and lo and behold it works clearly
and it's resistant to Fusarium and
everybody's happy
well why did that kind of are rarely
succeed it wasn't about the resistance
as much as he thought it was because it
didn't have to be refrigerated when you
move it it can handle 45 to 55 degrees
on movement so it changed economic
consideration of that cultivar
dramatically it made it to where they
cheapen the price of shipping it so that
one was a resistant but it's cheaper to
move and then just in the last year is
another folder Fusarium that is
attacking the cat additional Department
so now we'll obviously another one of
these banana epidemics let them in have
and that's what I see within canvas we
see certain populations that are
exception and problem we notice when you
say who came in we noticed when what
pans been here for a long time the
background the 1518 years - I remember
when I first came in and I can be traced
it back in the Oregon roads or the road
scrubs with you can kind of see where
things will follow me
but then the growth light that came in
for us elected followed these these
issues are relatively even with a speed
of the statement is incredible and so
it's the same situation where the only
way you're going to find out resistance
on Mises Academy and so the entire team
everything is protected as possible all
the time in the production end of it but
really there's very little honor indeed
done in cannabis where they're actually
exposing these plants to these issues
and detest them there is some for me I
can do it because I own a nursery so my
nurse was a little different
nurseries because of my location of Mon
Ami and in English that is I supplied
people who produce touch for a long time
and so my estimate that the work that
the nursery creates money anywhere
between 150 to 200 million dollars a
year in product grown from the cutting
so last point years I might be about to
be 20 about to canvas on the dating so I
was differently I can create a hundred
million dollars myself but my nursery
stock created approximately that much
now and it's it's a huge responsibility
in your mind understand how you maintain
this kind of relationship with the
farmers and how he T people be solvent
how you keep the movement father and
what we see now is basically I've got
calls from somebody right grab something
from some onion known as any day that I
none and so for us you know in order to
make it work the way I do at the tonnage
grounds is if he only typically release
a cultivar a year after selection and so
what that does is it lets me take a
little plan and
Productions which is indoor/outdoor
greenhouse and went back and those four
different situations have rattle
different impacts on the collage
performance it's on the logical trades
desirability to the market and so all of
this stuff takes time so you have a
situation we were all operated using
stock that we gathered unless you start
to DNA into the beauty of the galaxy and
I love the nation so it's not pushing
abilities that I've used the tool
because it lets me get a really clear
moment where the pockets in America
diversity and that way we can start
saying listen less diversify what we're
working with genetically and then in
these things
what information we happen and how we
start to work with it and what a trustee
do all these ears which just costs of my
friends and the passages we don't
believe the stress was like us very
often with this i shared the bats which
are a disinformation she had the
bachelors are babies love spinning the
whole the proprietary didn't put it in a
situation where all these special
individual
well we were ranked in the canvas came
to the kinder I was to use this
fundamentally that's what makes up the
chemist and is made up of a pregnant or
are there any divisions how he is and to
meet that that's the most important part
because that's the human connection
that's what allows us have a different
industry mind that's what my skin is to
be unique in the way it is it allows us
to actually create an industry based off
of our relationship with the plant you
see very little relationship with planes
whose relationship we plant and I'm not
auntie business at all but that
shouldn't be the driving force all
weekends and so so much of the stuff
that we're trying to understand is is
highly take the information from very
intelligent scientists researchers
nursery operators who work with
regulatory process
and how do you take that information and
how to apply it to what you do because
that it's applicability to matters if
anything you get out of talking to me
it's really about again the product of
the table
everything else is conversation like
that's my main direction and I hope
today that we can get into some stuff
how do we do that so thank you very much
I think so much it is money driven
a little bit products that sold in
cannabis people that's mine may be much
more expensive they are
I mean what I wish I saw this article
years ago it was about that CDC specific
bacteria as I said that's fascinating I
said and how they're possibly targets by
itself so I read researched it I found
the company that made the drive and then
I found the real act product which was
the same product it was five bucks to
the Container there's a hundred bucks
again this early enterprise and so the
problem this campus people can't sue
really a lot of authority to come after
you in court we didn't have the ability
to say listen you've solely surprised
that you could on the snow well you can
now and I think with the accountability
you'll have a change in it but it's it's
we have some people all the time any
product you see this working that well
have that stuff checked because there's
nothing that knocks anything back
organically but the counter
slow mister process it doesn't just wipe
it out and so anything received and it's
moving too well it's too trendy it's too
pricey we just wait and then it comes
out of analyst and there's ultimately
you don't want the same cultivar every
part of the United States because it's
really not meant for it it's it's
shooting the geographical solvers so
this way here you're optimizing an
actual situation you're made into as a
vacuum we can
the world but that's the most expensive
form of Hiroshi and for a lot of
individuals I over this uh pretty
accurate in terms of probability but
it's going to be specific for you
location so you can share the
information in the data but ultimately
you better have to do another sifting
process to get the cultivar working the
dampness of coastal Washington versus
the interior dry you can reach me direct
I'm pretty easy accessible but and I'm
talking about which means rectify the
problem just an accessible to talk about
products yet this year the information
otherwise we'll do it collapses up as a
culture my luck in is so much because
it's all these small individuals have
made it up and I'm not against
corporations it's just how America's
growing but I'm definitely against
taking over an industry in at the hands
of the few and so for me I try to share
as much as I can and get as many
products into the market as possible I
can't share genetics in the states
that's illegal but the information is
definitely available so you can check me
out see me out for the thing I don't get
any mail and then you think we can chop
it up about what is it you're trying to
do what you struggling with and then
we'll take a look at what your market is
because the market determines where
you're going to put this drive so you
can't just grow stuff that you want to
grow people get into use with that
you have to grow things at the market
walls but the markets pretty big and you
have to be able to take a look at that
market that turned 18 that federal
courts in your specific and so much it
is trying to find other farmers around
use a similar geographical situations
environmental conditions cultivation
sameness and then you'll be able to work
in groups I'm lucky in the sense that I
had to provide genetics to the state of
California which is massive and it lets
me work with hunt Alice's people over
these years about how to perform for you
and there's locations and what happened
it wasn't resistant with their problems
and then we can start to take a look and
say hey this cultivar that was selected
for this shines here it does not do well
there and it would allow you to get that
information so yeah that's all that's
all Gary
don't build this situation of your
friends do you have to team up you
cannot be a solo producer I love where
our practice Mariah Tori and CEO got it
for somebody down the street and I know
claiming it's yours it's not what you
want to be able to do is work in
conjunction and and the combined
brainpower of many farmers is really
driven agricultural forward for
millennia and now science is handing it
over and it creates the situation where
there's only certain things that can
enter the market because they have the
energy of resistance but at that level
right now we're still in the level of
back to the table and you have to really
use conventional farming technology to
do it and so to be sharing the
information with your friends make me a
bit of the jeddak's available
everyone thinks that if I give you this
clone sort of take away my whole world -
well if your market is that small my god
you're really a bubble on itself so you
have to be able to just you know see it
like that and don't be careful who you
work with because otherwise you're not
gonna get
native act but for someone who's a
farmer who's trying to produce cannabis
or less understand I use varieties and
these mountains you team up there have a
lot collaboration on that I received as
any other way all the wives combined we
are a massive creepy so there is another
brand there's no brand in Washington
around I would read seven bill inaudible
interoperation and he gave me the
lecture on this he was a CEO of seven
billion dollar of distribution and he
said Kathy doesn't none of you were
brand he said it'll occur a brand is you
can be in 44 thousand stores at once
and within 24 hours you could be stopped
all because none of you guys are brands
you must work collectively the form
regional brands and then eventually over
time those things will become parts
powerhouse crimes but in the interim you
must work together and canvas especially
when we are humble like idols at find
those where everybody use a little mini
cane run in our little big world and you
don't even want to team up on anything
but not the money's drained I'll assist
so people are a lot more willing to work
together for a long period of time
priorities somebody's good to eat it's
humbling it's going to stand work
together and you have to be able to team
up in that in that respect and every
worker group they're so smart and so big
and I think all these guys are the giant
had farmers never revolutionize the
kingdom and they get very provide
because again this is especially
cultivar and so they have to go through
this process to learn and understand to
and so there's no chugging Vantage right
now except in terms of scope and scale
and efficiency of production but in
terms of knowledge of the cultivar I
work with the private understanding how
to work together we can build that we
really have this opportunity because you
choke to that each other the next
question I can't use their profiles
tomorrow you can't do that without your
actual
and you so much are indeed for other
companies on inputs and that I run all
the tests afterwards to see these things
and so I just did video on this because
it's so fascinating that you couldn't
this you could not tell the human could
not tell which samples came out of those
two bags but one of them was very high
in alpha beta ie0 campaign and the other
varietal was high you can't be no alpha
beta money so therefore one of them is
right one that's not right now they've
already people believe is that when you
add input you just increase the terms
it's like it's all going to move
linearly it doesn't they it's complex
and you can have bacteria that converts
turkeys and other turkeys you can have
all these enzymatic conversions to make
smell appear and so when you're looking
at that from that point of view it's
move its do people like the way it
smells
ultimately the big numbers are nice on
the display board at the store but the
bottom line is trying to eat turkeys
tomorrow right exceptionally inaccurate
and we
this for a while and highly favored
effective that's what the DNA comes in
and then it prints it now you're gonna
have more actual changes from an insult
shifts and what they do but on a gene
level the same but terms all over the
place and you don't know the difference
that's what we my mind was on comparing
these of these tests preparing this was
are indeed and no one in my circle we're
all career guys that we know chemistry
well you could not differentiate which
one was grown but one of them very high
I mean you know anion can't be really
don't some say in terms of Campion
writings but exact same training just
two different inputs so you know you
have harm could what you'll find is that
for you you're trying to find out what
creates the most distinctive desirable
impact on a customer and that's working
with your inputs and you're going to
discover what you use on your farm
drives in the direction you want and
that's what you care about but otherwise
what the turkeys signature
oh my god so variable is no word for him
and I think it's so complex that people
are trying to dumb it down too much it's
too big I think so another medicine they
did maybe they do apply with that we
think you apply between I was asked that
by a reporter and I had talked to the
economy they use it before start this
whole the face of control they pioneer
that in Canada so in homo economy they
probably wiped out a billion dollars
with the Canada they're spraying this up
continuously and so you can clean your
crop as much as you want but it's going
to come back and what we found was
cultivar selection on things that have a
higher resistance and then you work with
your beneficial it's that company you
work on a strategy of human or adults at
a creek that predation rate that's going
to have competed so I haven't blown away
at a pharmacy about apart and we saw
some bug's present so let's develop it
with some food which means that eating
something and so once we started to find
the silicon or diamonds on the bottle is
leads we like it they go and it's too
late do you salt for salt works really
well for this is a cheap it cymatics to
talk because they bleach the lead
Moloch's would and designed to talk it's
an actually look at culture on the plant
which then disqualifies you can style
the bride so depending on what point in
time you use some of these tools so
sulfur and everyn flowers will in effect
erotic and somatic stem Kurzweil because
what effective product in terms of bone
but the beneficial insects work it's
just that people don't do it at the
level you need to I'm talking you let it
get on everywhere those plans to be
juveniles and adults so that the adults
come out and will right to work and the
neutrals collar eyes at work basically I
was learning three times the normal
level of predation that was required but
I establish that crop loss
five to ten percent my friends lost 95%
do you think about the Kenneth you see
plants that have inherent levels of rest
when was the sense that are
significantly different than others I I
do and I always think it's do I want to
say at all record or a later do you see
plants I have like rhino skin they seem
to do better because when I when I do
intestine I have a tremendous number all
the bars at the test site certain ones
getting enacted certain ones don't at
different levels of investigation but
the problem is that the stuff that's
resistant you're selecting for that open
earlier yeah at least I know that what I
could say is hey we've had very good
success with this use this is a portion
of your crop because you don't want to
be so harmful for that way either
because now you produce other after that
problem so you have to kind of figure
out what you distribution based off of
market velocity and survivability and
you'll be able to kind of get yourself
into a situation that requires a
tremendous amount of preemptive or
active on it whatever happens