Hey Shengo from the shaping of fire
podcast
I want to thank Kevin Jody wonderland
nursery and the ganje for sharing this
video with us this is part 1 of 2 part 2
is going to come out later on this week
we're gonna add the link at that time
right here so you're pricing it now in
this video Kevin considers late 80s
really loud and skunky terpene profiles
that we found in weed then that have
gone away because during the times
people were getting busted and they
needed to have their you know weed smell
more you know fruity and floral than
dankey and skunky and so he wants to
come back to that so in this video he
discusses the terpene profiles that are
generally associated with really loud
strains from that time you know if
you're if you're interested in hearing
more from Kevin I recommend that you
check out the other shaping fire podcast
interview I did with him in 2017 all
about the early origins of the CBD
strains that started in California you
can find that out at the link here or
you can just go to the shaping fire calm
web site while you're there if you are
into terpenes make sure that you listen
to the interview I did with Ben from
true terpenes as well all about terpenes
and how they're used in your everyday
life and you know if you are into
terpenes and you want to buy some for
yourself or to use in production for a
product that you're making make sure you
go to this link to go to troupe to
Europeans and pick up some terpenes
because they're the ones who sponsor our
channel so thanks to Kevin and
Wonderland and the GaN GA and true
terpenes for all the support all right
here we go this is Kevin Wonderland I
was spending some time trying to take a
look better at the older strains from
late 80s early 90s which is to me is a
sweet spot of cannabis that it was this
incredible amount of varietals that
pooled to make those those varietals and
they were the only ones taken
out of play not due to obsolescence but
more to the fact that they were two
highly recognizable and something that I
call BC and that's before charcoal
so before choco filtration was really
prevalent and allowed individuals to
hide cannabis in discreet situations
some of these varietals from that time
period primarily what we call skunks
we're so well known to the scent that it
was an instant indicator that there was
cannabis being produced at this location
and so it completely took these strains
out and I've been going back in time to
dig through to repol this population out
because the the varietals were built at
that time for totally enjoyment from the
user's perspective and some of these
scents have been have been lost and it's
trying to mine them and find out where
they exist and so I've been working with
this strain called the hog out of San
Diego for a little while and it's a
beautiful skunk afghani combination and
the the the genetics that make it up go
back to that time this might have been
made you know 2025 years ago so a little
little later than where I'm speaking but
the the precursors the plants have made
it up combined and did this and so we
did an interest in test this year where
we ran a humic acid mix from a company
as a test to see what it would do on
production and when I ran all the Turpin
alysus I had the very analytics my lab
but I've used from the inception run my
trip profiles and so what I find which
was so interesting was that they had
some very extreme variances in in a one
specific area but the overall smell was
identical to the user you couldn't
differentiate between the two flowers
even though one of them was 1% campign
and the other one was 1% told pining
Alpha and Beta Pi means combined and one
of them is pining spine and the other
camphor is more of an herbal and so it
was amazing to me as I started to look
at these and try to understand from a
Terp profile analysis what the smell
really was and what was really taking
place
and so I started to wonder where does
the smell garlic come from in in garlic
and why does this flower of the hog have
such a heavy garlic odor so I went
through the basic dirt profiles and we
had you know alpha pioneer alpha pioneer
which of Heinz we had and then in the
and then and then the flip sample was it
had nope I need had caffeine but
basically the same level about 1% and so
that was really the only major
difference in the two and then Mayor
scene was dominant we had limonene which
is in mere scenes of Earth's and mosques
and lye meanings as citruses and we have
Lin aloo which is a spicy floral Finchel
which is a camphor Kaurava lean which is
a hoppy peppery humulin which is earthy
woody that we went into some of these
lighter ones which was a valance scene
which is an orange and then farness
scene which is woody trans neurology all
citrus apple roads near allah dog
barking woody and then a growl all I
can't really pronounce the word GU a IOL
and that's piney and so I took a look
and these were the major Terps that made
up what we talked about and I started to
do some research and I start trying to
find out where is this smell or that we
call like funky death and where does
these things come from and I started to
take a look and I started to find out
that farness scene which is farness all
is the precursor to all cesspit are
beans but farness seen the the Terp
itself is the death smell of aphids and
so plants exude that smell to drive
predation away from it because it smells
like insect death and then if a fits die
they release that odor which then tells
other athens that their death is present
and they should hide and so it started
to it drives some interest in terms of
you know are we picking up some of these
funky tones that are really bio
protectants and we're interpreting them
in a way that makes us perceive
something and so I started to take a
look at this and we started to go
through and we took a look and we'd find
that Jarrin Hall is the precursor for
all the mono Terps and farnesyl is the
precursor for all the sesqui Terps
and I started to take a look and trying
to understand you know what are what are
some of the reasons why this stuff works
why do we have some of these smells and
we've been talking about esters which
are alcohols and we find that you have
alcohols that are glycerides and glasses
Rides
are makeup fat and so almost all fats
and animals and plants are from
glycerides and that is from esters and
so we start to say as we go back we
always remember the sticky the oily the
greasy things that we don't see as much
anymore things that don't have the same
tactical fields same constituents that
make it up and and some of those things
I think are directly connected and so I
started to take a little look deeper and
as I started to go into this I started
to find that things like Valentin which
is orange which you can smell so clearly
in this you don't smell citrus in the
sense of lemon-lime through your hog
flour but you if you give it a squeeze
you're gonna have this our garlic and
you're gonna have this underlying citrus
tone but you can smell a distinct orange
over a lemon or lime and you have a
muskiness that typically would come from
mere scene but when you look at the
profile of a hog and an OG limonene
Mayer seen pining and we'll use the
pining sample instead of the camping
because like I said they smelled
identical when you compared them but for
OG Kush which is typically we would say
limonene piney mersin dominant it
couldn't be any different than the hog
and they both have similar profiles and
so I started going through this and I
started trying to understand better what
makes these things happen because we all
become very Terp aware but they're they
work in combination in conjunction with
each other and there's also conversions
and what I started to find was the
valence scene which is this incredibly
Valencia orange smell they take Valentin
and how to write this down so I get the
name straight but you can use bacteria
and they do this in perfume industry and
other industries and they use a bacteria
and it converts Vallon scene to a newt
Cottone and so a newt cotone is the
was valuable of all grapefruit Terps
and so this incredibly valuable
grapefruit Center can be converted from
valence scene biologically and so I
started to take a look at you know what
is what is garlic and why do we smell it
and why do we do and garlic is something
called an allison ester al Li CIN and it
doesn't release its smell
until you crush it but it's not because
you volatize dit as much as you've
crushed it and you've released enzymes
which then reacts and go to process and
then release this so there's all these
things that are taking place in how we
perceive smells and tones and when we're
looking at Terp reports and tert
profiles and i'm gonna go through a
bunch of these i'm gonna go through a
lot of these older over the next couple
of weeks as I get a chance I'll go
through some of these profiles
pertaining to some of these older
varieties I'm sifting through and what
it'll do is it'll let us kind of take a
look at what's a chart profile compared
to what's the actual strain what do we
really smell and when we look at these
things where do we not see these odors
meaning that I should see with all the
pines and Earth's I should see a lot
more in this thing but really what I
have is a sour funk a garlicky tone and
underlying orange and a little bit of
earth and it would make sense because we
have so many earthy Terps present but
the irony was when I started to compare
all these profiles I started to see such
similarities between things that we have
now and things that we had in the past
and it's primarily these alcohols that
make these differences in the strains
that were from the past and now that we
know that these esters are directly
related to the fat production in plants
and animals this thing starts to make
sense because we remember these strains
being so sticky and so greasy and we
assumed sticky from resins but perhaps
sticky from fats and so as we mine back
through these older strains and go dig
through these profiles I'll go and take
a look through the tert profiles and
we'll start to try to understand better
what are we looking at and a lot of it
is so that we can understand what makes
it attractive and what doesn't otherwise
it's just basically these simple
profiles of this this and this drive and
attraction this
and this give us a desire total amounts
solely dictate desirability and in a lot
of cases it's just not true and it
becomes confusing and misleading to us
in terms of production and when people
start to look at cannabinoid profiles
and then interpret early profiles and
that becomes the the basis of their
decision making process it's not
necessarily very accurate in terms of
how we perceive it through the mouth and
through the nose and so I spent some
time just over the Christmas break
having a few minutes to hang out and I
just went through and listed this stuff
and went through and started trying to
understand you know why do we have some
of these odors that we do and why do we
not and try to understand the subtleties
in it because it's always the subtlety
that determines quality it's not gross
characteristics it's always the fine
details both cars of cars they both get
you from point A to B one of them has a
better experience and so we would
typically consider that the better car
it's the same with cannabis whichever
one gives you the best experience how
you perceive it what it does for you in
terms of medical usage spiritual usage
however we want to define it but all
those characteristics are from
perception and when it comes to smell
we're so nuanced through the nose it's
such a direct connection from brains
brainstem to nostril that it it's primal
it goes all the way back and so we've
been keyed to smell and understand so
many things but with cannabis
we've been necked into some populations
now and there's this drive to bring out
higher louder strains and louder just
meaning more visible to the nostril
quickly which means more aromatic at
room temperature so that's more volatile
so that's more monoterpene derived and
we have so many these varietals now that
we're working in those directions but
ultimately is it is it giving you an
enjoyable experience and does it give
you the effect that you desire from that
Terr profile and a lot of the
information when you get into terpenes
is by protectants on how it affects
against tumors and cancer and bone loss
and tooth decay and I mean it's
unlimited what you can do with this but
the
none of this has been studied in a
smokeable form always in applied to a
thing it doesn't really apply to us in
the same way it's it's extrapolating
data from one set and putting it on
another and kind of pretending that it's
accurate and we really know that's not
the case and it's really more a matter
of trying to understand how do you
interpret the the cannabinoid profiles
the turpenoid profiles and also these
esters these alcohols that was so
dominant and present in these cannabis
varieties from the past that released
such an incredible smell that was so
distinctive to all people that
eventually these varieties had to get
removed from the system and so it's this
understanding that I'm trying to find as
to what drove such an incredible desire
in cannabis from those types and how do
we get back into some of those exotic
forms of cannabinoid combinations and
terpenoid alcohol combinations so that
we can get back into some of that
desirability on a different direction
and it's we're not working the same
populations that we're working which are
primarily right now with so much of the
og directions and I was just so
fascinated with because if we when we
talk about you know the mere seen piney
limonene where it's uplifting and then
brings you down the hog strains skunk
strains couldn't be any could be any
opposite in terms of where they lift you
up but they don't bring you down they
don't have that same type of sedative
effect even though the mere seen level
and this is relatively high it's you
know double the pines even more than the
crow Faline levels the only thing that
the the hog had that was really high was
trans and neural Adal and CIS Nala doll
and so between the two of them you were
looking at almost you know four four and
a half percent and that's citrusy Apple
rose that's barking woody and all these
complex tones that come into these
varieties that make them taste so so
green and green meaning you know
subtleties of the of the earth and the
forest within and we can pull out some
specific little pieces and I would say
you know you have some hoppy taste and
some wheatgrass or some lemongrass
present of that beautiful subtle orange
tone Mir seen is always this this
the component that when we crush this
and volatility volatility we can get it
to come out but so much of it is is in
my mind now as I see that we're having
biological conversions of alcohols to
other substances we're having enzymatic
conversions of something to something so
if garlic is an enzymatic conversion to
a scent then maybe we need to rethink
how we approach the smell components of
cannabis and I'm not a terpene scientist
I'm just fortunate enough to get to
listen to them frequently but I'm
somebody who's trying to understand
where is the the desire in cannabis
where do people like to go when it comes
to cannabis where is the directions of
cannabis and this entire population from
that you know that late Atle 90 time
period prior to really smell BC before
charcoal all of that was this incredible
cannabis population that was still
globally developed meaning that though
the world had produced all this
different cannabis varieties and they
had been clustered into these cannabis
zones and those zones of production
created these varieties and then lo and
behold as we go forward the demand of
the customer drives what people have but
black market forced some radical changes
because there was a limit in what
cannabis was available and cannabis that
was coming over at that time from say
the remnants of Colombia the remnants of
Mexico that cannabis was so much lower
quality than the indoor produced in
California that even though the end are
from California had these reduced snow
rates because we had turned them down
you still received a better
higher-quality product than what was
available so the market became
accustomed to that and then as we start
to go into medical marijuana and move
forward all of a sudden we had the
ability to produce cannabis again in a
protected manner which allowed us then
to have cannabis that was inherently
louder more distinct a higher signature
and that
brought the awareness back of hey
where's all this good smelly stuff we
had when we were younger and so we we go
back and we realize we've necked all
these things out and so I've been on
this hunt to pull stuff from that time
period back from globally and try to
locate these varieties so that we could
go into them and start to say what
creates these smells really we're all
looking for the skunk pee but the we and
we want it but we want the skunk pee on
a better chassis the skunk pee that
we're so caught up with in terms of
skunk it was always on the leafiest
cabbagey looking stuff you have ever
seen in your life it was never on really
solid flour it's very very rarely
primarily and a different type of
morphological bud characteristic and so
I don't know if I'm so much seeking to
go back but I'm going to seek into those
tones because it was also stunning
other varietals the burnt rubbers the
the heavy citrus pines that were just
dominant you don't see any of that
anymore not to the same degree no og is
piney like strains that were piney and
we just don't see them they're moderated
something's controlling these these
connections on how you perceive it and
so I think that as we go forward and we
start to dig and look through the
reports and then take a look at the
cannabis and actually consume and test
and say hey what are we seeing what
don't we see it starts to become very
informative because when I had two
samples run that were almost identical
in almost all characteristics little
fluctuations but in piney and kam Fein
no camping in one no pining and the
other but you couldn't put the you could
put the fly was in the same container
and no one could tell the difference so
it started to really make me realize you
know that some of these things that are
so characteristically known are either
subdued or enhanced by other terpenes
and what alcohols are present and the
degree that the alcohol is present and
that would be from a lot of it from the
the growing conditions the inputs
obviously because it changed profiles
here and you know your harvest time and
the curing windows and all these
different pieces that control it but
it's gonna be interesting as we go
forward because we're gonna start to be
able to take a look at profiles and
start to find some really interesting
markers
so that when we get into breeding and
we're able to start to mark for some of
these terpene indicators and look
through genetically do we have these
markers we should be able to start to go
back into some of these plants that were
extremely high in these volatile esters
and alcohols which are exceptionally
attractive but very hard to mine you
want seed and concentrates because of
the volatility and it just starts to
help us understand better what it is
we're producing what it is we're trying
to market to the public and when people
want you know unique varieties it's
unique because why what what defines
unique and so much of this is being able
to take your varietals and say they're
unique because people like them for this
it has an applicability here there's a
demand for it this way not just it has a
higher content than others because
ultimately that doesn't really
numerically it does make a difference on
a shelf but in terms of how people
perceive it radically different and so
when I spent the last you know half a
day trying to understand where's the
smell of garlic coming from when I don't
have any garlic terpenes or alcohols
present in the testing and we're only
looking at a truncated test it might be
say like 30 and there might be over 200
possible but those will be at levels
that would be so small it's it's
catalyst things that change things
things that precursors things that set
things in motion and so as we go forward
and we start to really have a more
in-depth test and we're able to look at
this a little different we'll be able to
start going in and moving some of these
populations in these directions I
believe and for me right now it's just a
fascinating time to be able to see this
and do this and actually have the chance
to understand what made some of these
things so attractive versus just had a
smell that was this because we have her
having a hell of a time trying to
replicate it
if skunk was easy to replicate you would
see terpene blenders blending it and it
would be present as a Terp to add the
things but I don't see skunk piss on
anything right now period so I know that
some of these things are exceptionally
hard to capture or create and it's what
made some of these varieties so
attractive and that's what that's what's
fun right now is we get
to hunt and do so the hog you you got me
curious because your smell is unique and
I for the life of me could not figure
out where it came from so thanks thanks
we attracted me so much that I put the
effort in and I hope this video signs a
little light on the chase of where these
things come from and remember I'm not
organic chemist and I don't claim to be
one and nor do I want to be one but I'm
someone who's fascinated with genetics
and what makes something desirable and
in these things we start to have
desirability just like when we look in
in cannabinoid profiles we can start to
find out that these cannabinoids
influence the way the body accepts other
cannabinoids and it directly affects how
you perceive this effect because it is
absolutely giving you in effect and the
understanding of that allows you to
better tailor in what you're seeking so
that as we move into these different
populations and people come in you're
able to give them better choices and
we're accurate choices and then they are
able to understand why they made the
choices which lets us drive directions
of breeding and plant choices towards
those directions so that we're not just
creating and hoping people like it but
we're actually marking some of these
incredibly attractive components that
individuals find attractive and figure
out how to apply so I hope you holiday
season went well and thanks for
listening to the vid and I hope we got
something positive out of it
you