thank you for being here everyone and
welcome to the eleven ten living the
soils channel the length of the Pam's
gonna be starting down and running about
fifty minutes till noon we're gonna do
about 40 45 minutes of a conversation
and then altering our guest speakers
we're very excited to take your question
so then we'll switch over and do 10-15
minutes of questions from you for those
of you who are new to probiotic
including soil and computer as beginner
building the soil with active microbe
life is is the progression of growing
versus what were used to experience
during the early provision into our days
where soil will might as well then
styrofoam super packet with nutrients
this new idea to talk about today
considers the soil as a living
participant and our goal is to foster
microorganism community
within your soil to of a plant so that
makes us as much soil armors as tanks
burners so first let's welcome our guest
from from the side with services and
acclaim and is a biologist partner and
co-author of several program and
regenerative agriculture books including
the hidden half of nature the microbial
roots of light had helped and also right
after this presentation she will be at
the manic microbes book of the booth
doing a book signing if you'd like to
meet her and get a copy of your website
to her left is about how does the
co-founder and co inventor and cheap
growth officer and procession but you
probably weren't familiar with them as a
modern microbes and the fabulous product
mammoth P he'll receive his PhD in
biological sciences specializing in soil
microbial ecology and plant microbe
actions and to his left cat jack
is a living soil educator
most of the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast these also order of keep
it simple organics and animal nursery
production greenhouse outdoor preschool
and organic hydroponic shop and online
store nearby here in Redmond Washington
and also at Kate i-s organics calm I am
shaking Lowe's hosts of the shaping fire
podcast if you enjoy hearing experts
like this talking about their particular
region of Kansas I encourage you to
check out my podcast at shaping fighter
calm there is a postcard or even in your
convention back so we're going to get
started right in let's see here so so in
let me start with you since you're on
the side so Vanessa so historically
cannabis growers have been taught to to
pack their candidacies soil with
isolated nutrients then all nutrients
that the plant needs but they're not
necessarily participating with each
other what is a method that you find
successful to transition towards waking
up the soil to alive more on the micro
communities as a whole instead of
individual sublights
I think for each thing I think about
said once once you realize that the soil
is really about not only physics and
chemistry but the missing link and
soiled it was really really started to
embrace and study and integrate into
growing practices instant biology
because in many ways it's the biology
that makes the physics the chemistry and
the movement of things in the soil
nutrients minerals and things like that
move from the soil into the green body
on the plant and normally when I talk
site I have this this particular slide
that I really like it was every time at
Ivan get it like I could just sort of
sort of sink into the world of soil and
a very unique area in soil that is
nanometers to millimeters right around
every single root and that space is
called the rhizosphere and the recipe is
a wire and a line clips that all of us
need to know about and we need to know
what
so I was taking that word part of it for
folks oh right so means River spear of
course is about it's an area of about
the root and it is in the rise
experiment what you really have is a
biological Azhar Vaz in our so in your
mind so you conjure up you know
somewhere in a minute easy you've got
these traders that are coming in with
where's that none of the other traders
have and so you have this constant
ceaseless back-and-forth train stuff but
what microbial communities are training
is really pretty mindfully
they are producing metabolites from what
they're consuming for energy and some of
these metabolites have medicinal effects
on plants Summa tablets function that
has growth hormones so let's think about
this community you have one sector of
life microbial and it's making what we
in our two-minute world would call
products and they are supplying those
products to degree bodies of plants and
what plants doing plants have their own
wares unique to them that may trade back
and its different sorts of nutrients for
hybrids or amino acids fats and proteins
parameters
yeah that's it so it's just starting to
lost their biological azar from it
so this is what we need to think about
when we think about soil and when you
think about whatever kind of plan you're
growing that this is what you're this is
really what you're defeating is you're
eating the Spanish that are bringing
their wares to biopic about why were
using synthetic nutrients and why that
is go into there why we think about is
microbial some occasional microbiology
of isn't minute five interactions in the
rhizosphere
and how microbes interact within the
plant process here
and there's a huge problem farmers face
- the chemical
although they're very intuitive we could
easily tie how and you can't fertilizers
are similan and
as elation to be implanted precision in
agriculture any campus blunder totally
get that the microbiology is less
intuitive and it takes more of a
learning curve but it's critical we see
in agriculture how farmers have been
trained to plus and that in fertilizers
for years and decades and what we see is
a decline in soil health that's very
very interesting because the Nexen
declines the biology in those schools to
facilitate you cycling so the microbes
can actually help liberate nutrient
timing and biomedical implants microbes
are critical delivering maximize 100 all
introduced efficiency in precision
agriculture canvas farming we want to
maximize the precision this is a
precision farming industry and to do
that we want to incorporate all our
inputs into the plant and we're going to
do that not only maximizing our
understanding applications of fertilizer
use but with incorporating biology and
microbiology to help with that we can't
accomplish that without incorporating
microbes which as they do in nature in
our Rose cycle nutrients to maximize the
bioavailability
of any nutrient that we add into our
substrate so the plants that say to them
I think they covered it really what I
would have is just to simplify the
process a little bit we put out organic
fertilizer or any organic all the
nutrients we have to keep in mind
more or less we're not directly feeding
that planet we're feeding as microbial
communities as a way scientist engineers
to support the way to take up so it's
important to keep that in mind and then
the only thing I like to consider is
just how valuable the processes to the
plant in the sense that it's
photosynthesize involved is like turning
and imaging and putting it back out to
the roots I think the statistic Irina's
up to 60% of certain plants that was
back out in the form of exudates the
sugar
proteins to directly feeding the
bacteria
and there's so much that we still don't
know about soil and you know what's
going on under our feet in terms of this
interaction that it almost feels
arrogant to me to think that we can come
up with us and that I program
even close we get from a healthy
biological process when nature is doing
what it does and I'm just and I was
saying what my favorite quotes is from a
good friend of mine Jeff long because he
always likes to say there's no one
fitting miracle-gro
this beautiful fantastic nature
depending on my cruel associations just
like tap and we're talking about
and for us the thing that we can avoid
that to maximize the health and develop
it quality meal or plant agriculture is
naive and I think understanding cutting
integrate those is a really important
next step for us to revolutionize
agriculture and and merge that with
biology to do so with this next question
when you start packing area tab
so so how they are growing in native
soil is has become increasingly popular
to the candidates normalizations we can
go outside alright so what is the
regenerative practice retired native
soils that how our cannabis growers can
use to rejuvenate local soils instead of
merely shipping in soils from elsewhere
yes so I'm a firm believer in Jesus was
it's what happens from a cultural
perspective farmers are bringing some of
those constantly there's no reason as an
annex partner we need to be any
different with our crops in terms of
that for me that touches or on soil
testing so we have this microbial side
of things where we have the biologic
cycling the nutrients make it available
but on the other end we need to look at
what's actually in that soil and giving
a soil test and analyzing
and what sorts of excesses and
efficiency means we may have an anatomy
of proper amounts of nutrients
micronutrients to balance that out it
was a long way and that's essentially
what conventional farming has been for a
long time so tying that aspect of soil
testing in farming with the microbial
side that I think is the future of
Agriculture
I think that's right - I want to
emphasize it I think we should think
about plants and being the foundation of
all life on Earth those primary
producers and everything else eats those
plants or eat things that eat plants and
plants that exists the best one and so
with that public school is actually the
foundation of all life because you can't
really grow plant about substrate or
dissin nutrients in that substrate or
soil and we also have to understand that
carbon is the currency of all life on
Earth and is definitely currency of soil
health and so making sure that you can
charge your soil with appropriate carbon
allows you to maintain this foundation
where you can having other ions that can
persist in as well
well if you look at soil health is
completely correlated with her that's
going to help sustain out on my career
eleven microbes are part of all black is
carbon-based and just the structure and
dead material carbon related material
they can hold on to the nutrients that
maximize cation exchange capacity in the
nutrient capacity that you're planting
girls again and happiness if you have a
very healthy soil you have a permit rich
soil that's full nutrients and they
become a microbial population that helps
cycle those nutrients naturally to make
human bioavailable form so your plants
can take them out I really like what you
said Shango about them or noticed at the
Miracle Grow the red one course for yes
with general but here's the deal
the foundation of our health was our
respective micro miles and so all this
stuff they call it have been talking
about is hardest new emerging and
merging area of science about the not
just these single microbes but the
microbial communities how it is that
they are interacting with one another
and how else they're interacting with
their host whether that's a person or a
planet and the more we learn about micro
biomes the more we are seeing how
critical they are or the health and
well-being of the plant host or the
person and so shameless question what
are some of your favorite you know
methods for regenerating sort of
presented soils so I I come at this as a
person who live here at sea on and built
a garden about 15 years ago and I will
tell you this tell you what very
embarrassing moments that myself as a
biologist and my husband as a geologist
and its really great to know about soil
you can laugh now we Bobby really test
our soil as we went about building this
garden so here we are with hot August
day dozens of plants and pots that have
been screening every four months to get
them out
into the ground and we're doing a talk
on Saturday so you can see the cracks
were we had it was lighter color than
the wall in this room and what my gut
told me was we never artists um and I
knew I needed that organic matter and I
said the problem of the soil that I can
see with my eye is lack of organic
matter
things are starving and malnourished in
this soil so I went into panic mode for
someone into panic mode and then I got a
really busy I got busy rounding up free
and inexpensive sources of organic
matter than my wheelbarrow painted with
flames which I'm actually not gonna
repaint with my gross and I loaded up
all kinds of organic matter from the
neighbors of leaves to coffee grounds
from the coffee shop to I made friends
with artists in the neighborhood to give
their woodchips and what I was
essentially doing is collecting
different sources of organic matter and
I would create lunches
I call these meals of mulches for my
microbial populations and how to layer
its on the soil and I would tell you
this there is no need to be digging all
of this organic matter into your soil is
really disruptive and disturbing to all
of these tiny tiny creatures that make
up the soil microbiome and after about
five years we went from soil is
that wall to something that is a dark
chocolatey color and what this led my
husband David and I to realize is that
in pretty short order you can restore
life to the soil and you can do it
faster than mother nature can do it and
what we were basically mimicking is
everything that happens in a forest I
mean plants have long long figured out
why do you think leaves fall off
deciduous trees and happen to land right
on top of the roots so I was thinking
about feeding the soil a little bit like
feeding they're eating our dog and that
is that put the food out and life will
come to the food and so that's that's
how I think about regenerating roses
I've done it and it did not take you
know a century or two if you take Mother
Asia to do just to get life into the
soil so in some ways you know I love to
vary from soil initially and I sort of
thought oh my god and that's kind of
like mine reclamation it's like their
them and that's what it looked like
we're dealing with your mother in from
Seattle together we've got glacial till
there's just not much on top of that so
we build soil from the top and then
anyway that's right it's very exciting
that's right that's why we're all you
know I'm just learning about notice
though and one of the things that you
said that it stuck out for me is that
when you're doing the rejuvenation of
the soil it doesn't necessarily mean dig
it up and bunch of bioactive or natural
supplements to break down and pour back
up a whole you're suggesting not
breaking up the mycelium traffic at all
and just top dressing for what it sounds
like
and in letting that soak down and
without any attic shuttles expertise
yeah that's pretty much correct unless
you're really truly / Reformation saying
that said having equipment on it you do
not rub tailors are really roto killers
or made xyt named Venice because think
about this we have to tie these
creatures on earth that live in the soil
beneath our feet and you take a roto
tiller or plow or some kind of implement
and you start stirring that up all you
are doing is being in killing the soil
microbiome and so if the soil microbial
is a source of nutrients and there's
this biological Bazaar and all of these
exchanges going on you don't want to be
cutting that up you want that intact
when you want that
and you know it you can't really say
that microbes have a brain that they
have ways of sensing what is in my meals
and launches and what is in mammoth
microbes
what is intact compost tea and they will
figure out a way to get to that and
incorporate it into their bodies and
then eventually into the soil and then
into the plan so yeah on this situation
from the perspective I know if you're
trying to write a cover crop
so they are trying
but what I found works or to know with
our growers that are growing
raised beds is to let me disturb the
couple first couple inches of this
little so we're not going very deep but
the the top layer there is is naturally
like this dirty in nature anyway but we
need to get the nutrients faster into
the rhizosphere cyclocross 36 hours have
to involve our first prop so it's a
little different situation when you have
a dark person's ability and I dunno guys
I'm doing exactly man described good
results - we just got with our claws and
because I work with slightly better
responses by good point is that there is
not really any only right way to do the
new soils right you're dealing with a a
living system that's going to respond to
all the efforts that you put into it but
also it's work against the teammate
trying to make up for the things that
are lacking as well and based on your
soil and your finances and what you may
already have
the closet your solution was not
necessarily to be just like a neighbors
solution so this is this is you know
takes a little bit of research maybe a
lot of good research and some patience
but in the end you can suss out the
solutions for yourself so so technically
we're gonna start with you and then
we're going to add and then back to
hammer so so a great deal of what makes
Canada scribe express the bold colors
that you love and back appeal and
develop cookies that just smell great
are the micronutrients right what one of
your favorite methods to decrease the
presence and bioavailability of
micronutrients so I think it comes back
to what you have making sure those
nutrients are available and having the
means to delivers nutrients to the
plants and that's the practical
application of know what nutrients you
have applying them when you need to and
having the right microbiome school mark
around right here
sighing little those nutrients that
simply and you can sense that they come
in different ways you can obviously test
your solos you can be very conscious of
what you're adding in and you can add in
everything with complete precision to
the high hand level as far as any kind
of micro minitec you want but then you
have to understand how those inputs are
transferring up to your plant nutrient
issue analysis if you can follow
nutrients from the bottom from the back
but moment of action gets into your soil
and your writing sphere and all those
new tunes up and then you can also look
at the nutrients and the responsive
implants initially so taking that step
by step understanding and everything we
do here and what we're talking about is
an experiment you know there's not one
right solution your different substrates
we're going to have different responses
to microbes and different region
influence micronutrient influence the
more complex the more complex decisions
going to be and I wanted to what was
said and then previous conversation you
know external health and then a living
soil and the microbiome is a huge thing
continuously more so important in
agriculture but there's this practical
balance in managed systems we are not
going to make nature because there is
this little disturbance it is implicit
with managing soil and managing across
and so we're trying to do is practically
apply a nature where it makes sense in
our managed systems and acknowledging
the functions of nature they can have
how to plug them in to your managed
systems and apply them to get the
benefits is the way we need to think
about this there's no way we're
recreating nature in a pot there's no
flavor creating nature in a bet nature's
in this term perhaps and hundreds of
years and that's what makes it what this
there's this huge scale that makes it as
complex as it is what we can do as
humans is understand that bring those in
there acknowledge our limitations and
benefits
like an ecologist said it's a really
good quick wheat harvest of the planet
we're pulling out organic matter and
nutrients those need to replace every
cycle and that's something that you
don't apply typically in nature so
that's it that's an important aspect to
consider in terms of the micronutrients
he touched on the soil testing when I
would say is so let's say what I
typically find them together this is
soils tend to be low and negative higher
copper and some kind of stick and so we
need to get those nutrients back in the
easiest way but the other option there's
a couple companies that take these
sulfates and and helium I see like
violin
and I'll be I'll be on another day in
Canada by Q lading and what has
essentially makes it a little bit you
guys are take that so these are things
that can be applied holding the
perspective or in case a small branch
and retest yourself and see how much
that raised the my confusion about but I
think that's one thing that a lot of
people don't consider is these
micronutrients and you're also being in
my care micronutrients from there as
well as
yeah I think we're probably all this
revenue sitting here and especially
probably mycorrhizae funds right and I
think that cultivation practices where
your microscope which our calculations
are are high are functioning a really
good way to get access to all these
nutrients that are bound up in the rocks
that are in the soil and they say rocks
I don't mean you know maybe boulders
weather particles rock particles that
are out of the soil they are made but
many of these minerals there's no tag
just listed out and here we have this
what drive that started a
co-evolutionary relationship with the
natural world millions of years ago
before there were plants they were micro
sponges they were the decomposers at
that time that were were decomposing the
organic matter is around plants came out
of the oceans and the underwater bodies
and the struct of relationships with
these my horizon sunshine that are every
bit as as
and specialized in intimate as those
that go on between pollinators and the
flowering plants so I think we've got
this piece of biology that is
long-standing ancient and when you've
got those micro bright sunshine it and
extend they're functionally basically
extending a plant's roots out of two
areas of the soil the plant would
otherwise not have access to and so I
think ways of encouraging the my prized
project so that they're making these
things the soil is the various micro
nutrients and minerals available to the
plant it's sort of like what if this is
some maybe this is a little too smart
how smart huh stuff but my greatest of
security issues but I would sort of like
it if the Postal Service could deliver
my package not just to my door but
inside out and inside the cupboard where
it is that I mean it and so I think this
is there's an sometimes being people are
starting to add things into the soil you
really want to make sure
they're biomechanical and one one way of
doing that is to make sure you've got
robust of microphones and populations
and and that you've got a plant it's
pushing the exudates out because that's
authorized not going to hand over any
minerals knows there's something on the
other hand so it's it's really having
this whole this whole system in the soil
between the plant and the microwave
great you know sort of do really well on
time I'm going to add a little question
that I didn't
since we're doing some a long time I
recognize a lot of faces in the audience
of people who are pretty dedicated to
living soil people and I've spoken with
before and I think that it would be a
missed opportunity to have you three
experts here without asking you you know
if people ask you questions in person
via email
other than get your soil tested which I
know would be probably uniform answer
other than get your soil tested what
would you say is one piece of advice
that you would offer folks that are
developing their living soil for their
farm that oh my gosh I wish they would
have known ax what does that think if
you just wish so that they're more
laid-back success and starting great do
you think about this a lot people all
the time I think one of the biggest gaps
this is inherent knowledge of what I
heard in groups actually do you know
there's my horizon understood there's
another kind of sympathetic fungi that
are available in products and in nature
of course
many different species and groups of
bacteria and they all have these
different functions and if you group
them all as microbes you're missing the
resolution that you need from precision
agriculture and that's
we need if we're going to apply migrants
with precision especially in our canvas
gross you know for example I was just
talking about us good work
they're not capable they are really
important symbiotic they will actually
infect your plant root and they'll
create my muscular sites in the cortical
cells of your plant roots and they
extend out major it's critical because
they extend out beyond the surface area
of your roots to take in more complaints
and take a cold water and there's
actually these things Jane Doe Hospice
Department like alluded in that
particular relationship it's really
important but that's all that lunch I
really does and so is it applicable for
your hydroponic system ask yourself that
question would implementations of
infection sites those are the type of
things that I would be asking as a
grower if I wasn't thinking into the you
know details of microbiology would have
bacteria do you know bacteria are very
handsome adequate capable they're really
not going to affect your plants early
beneficial
but they continued the psychic nutrients
nitrogen phosphorus potassium sulfur
micronutrients and make them
bioavailable they're not delivering them
to your plant they're making them
available so your plan can take them up
there's other species of trichoderma
that are really good at cycling carbon
ammonia creates an enzymes for carbon
degradation and breaks down them at the
in general and there's interactions
between all these things it's not simple
it takes some time to kind of soak
information but if you understand what
these groups are doing you can think
about what the importance is of those in
particularly grow and how you can apply
those with confidence that they're gonna
benefit your plan in a particular
environment that you have so we're going
to be more eligible and if you are a
physician
the world and how we're growing and
summer you know across the board
beneficial for different reasons that
excites your attack yeah I think talk
more with sort of organic and
conventional farmers that really
cannabis growers but one of the things
that I always find so interesting
especially if I go to somebody's arm and
this is what I would encourage everybody
knew particularly maybe the required
missile and recently are you thinking of
doing so I think it's really a good idea
to learn what you can about the history
of that of that land and look around of
the landscape and to see how is it that
things are happening like where some of
the native plant communities like what
kinds of plants do you see really
thriving talking with your neighbor
farmers because one of the you know this
depends maybe they're not going to tell
you more
you want to know you want to know okay
so they tried that didn't see might work
but I think I see a way maybe between
back so I think there's a lot to be
gained from talking with other
cultivators and from looking at the
landscape in which you're growing
tentative so just take note of things
like the direction that the Sun is
coming from and how you're thinking
maybe of sighting buildings with
sighting he feels it's time I was in a
outdoor Canada's Parliament summer and
he's they were getting hammered I don't
remember what direction the wind was
coming from but they said yeah I didn't
know when we set things up here that the
wind they always came out of the same
the sound but they had some of the
plants were staked they were getting so
beaten by the wind so it's paying
attention to sort of the physical and
natural features of a piece of property
so that you know so they could take
advantage of what it is you have there
so that would be my own history twice
yeah
but I think that's really important for
me I'm gonna take a totally different
approach to this and say there's a whole
bunch of people out there trying to sell
myself included in every college
evaluate what they can miss a look at
the ingredient list really take a smart
man why are you throwing the way you're
going and just really evaluate that
because I find a lot of people will pop
that in the rap you know 30 samples at
your back better garden don't apply all
of them all at once with no scientific
method then you really don't know what
they didn't think so I would say
challenge the claims of their looked at
agriculture if you really want to see
where products are successful if
greenhouses or agriculture than that
speaks volumes in ways like for example
my present fungus you know there is
information out there and educate
yourself on like we know that we can't
was formerly called Globus interosseous
Moschino cannabis also has been changed
to rise of things the regulares but you
can look on a label and see if it has it
on there and you can purchase that part
of Canada planner so you're not buying
back to my cries in which context
Congress necessarily plan the eat one
specific for your crop and then you can
look at score counts and saying okay
when this product has this port now is
it accurate that's another part of a
it's a starting point of these and then
take it back and run trials you know I
think fortunate your gardeners mean I
think you need to try and help move
things and testing out his ideas and his
products and see
something you wanted
well said they think the idea of making
sure you look at the ingredients and
maybe even ask questions and confirm
that's a good idea I was talking with
Kevin judging from Wonderland a nursery
the other day and he's like you know the
reason why we're finding out there's so
many hidden things in these products for
cannabis because it's horribly we could
sue them that they were selling us VX
right we had to just take it and we have
to be quiet because we were during the
Prohibition days but now now the
legitimate companies that we gotta be
some amount of legal standing some of
these companies that are selling
products with hidden ingredients are
going to be taken to tax so don't be
afraid of being a part of that so we go
ahead and we have time for a couple
questions we're using this awesome
device today check tech and all you need
to do is when I hand it or toss it to
you capture it and just talk to it
because it's microphone right here so so
I'm just got a question
Oh real come on excellent
dad Univision earlier supplements
you needed nutrients put a micro
you know I think we repeat the questions
had the leprechaun didn't take out
though hello notepad just you reject
every dude thank you so there he was
asking if these healing and
micronutrients are affecting the
microbial population that's a great
question
I know we copper present what we're
talking about so very very small yeah
copper sulfate on the other hand
yes tell micro so you do want to be
aware that I think Colin might be a
better person to answer this but in my
experience there
yeah just attack I'm going to think
that's exactly right you know like all
of us you had enough of any more things
whatever in the day we might return a
sneaky way and so you're not having
anything
really it just animal makes instead of
steeds effectuation Stefan yeah help me
my program population bacterium is
plunging bill chelate nutrients but
there's that process and evidence war
quickly available to the plant and so
there isn't that the delivery trade off
the chair that you're negotiating
and things like that I would risk it all
except for what tax and making a
commercial for the castle they bring up
one thing that I
is micronized pigments you are my cousin
phosphorus the plan
which has all these other benefits in
English so we do want to be careful in
that regard because a relation point
that it might get into the details on
but in others Allah research published
fingers out there where they even see
direct auto correlations with a negative
correlation with increased phosphorus
levels and decrease infection rates
mycorrhizae and infections it sounds
like a bad thing which we have to have
that in the success and that
relationship between that planet and a
particular punch i if you have excessive
buffers and there's ranged out there
that a critical range is then really
limit the infection and so thinking
about those things it's the interactions
are no black or white there's all these
interactions that's what makes a little
complicated
[Applause]
Wow it's music to my ears
yeah there has been few for me is
assertive
let's put it this way small part of our
me is it's maybe in the early stages of
a revolution no-till which means not
using the plat that's when you hear the
word no-till that means that farmers not
using a cloud that they're getting seeds
into the ground by dropping really just
a very small drop you see the moving on
so in an orchard situation which is
different as you have established trees
yeah some people are plows are also use
for lead control and so what the kind of
urgently wanted some fortunates are
doing this is they're doing cover crops
and allowing uh some weeds to come in
the rows between their trees because we
talked about all this life in the soil
and if you're running on an annual basis
or more frequently some kind of a plow
their rows between your trees you're
ripping that soil exposing it to erosion
off you know what remembers the
microbiome so some some fruit growers
are moving just more toward Noto as are
some video White Rose growers as well I
will tell you this I notice there in the
room that the outdoor campus apartment
over to as summer they were on the right
track with a lot of things but one of
the things that I didn't like seeing
as if there was an open soil in between
the roads where they had their plans and
and I just looked at that but there can
be plants growing here not cannabis
plants but other kind of plants that
could be walked upon and the whole thing
about a cover crop or why you want your
soil covered as we talked about exudates
the by hospitals are all these things a
plant is a food factory for the
microbiome so when I saw those bare
patches much like this this Iowa right
here on that after a girl farm I thought
wow they can be feeding a bunch of
microbes that are gonna be feeding the
cannabis plant so I would like to see
some kind of a cover crop it's walked
walkable and and get all of this covered
get get all of this covered up and so
that's sort of the idea was some you
know orchardist
we just you know grow things and ideas
on that yeah
but there's a penis I should know
there's some Japanese but it's a great
book and it talks about this cocktail
more detail if you're interested in it
but I think it into into these Outsiders
for a long time the micro these microbes
in microcosm
Pisco a second in general and culture
and migrant in general microgrid last
event sort of God probably city the
cleanest place that chemical fertilizer
over the next two decades it's a human
we work with a lot of many doors alot
strawbeary doors they think there's a
second high please
these compatibilities it has to scale it
has to bring a huge ROI on our way that
makes sense and has to fit right into
those management axes and so not all
practices I think up to the conventional
farming practices but again testing and
you know about the actual application to
visit us it's important to remember too
that you know the way that consumers
like going are towards living soil they
don't want pesticides they use they
don't want is used in one way or another
is tending towards living soil is it is
matter fact it's a it's a it's a
marketing minute for you to say if your
plants are growing and living soil so so
if you're thinking like oh man this is
just something else I'm going to have to
spend my time on you know so maybe that
both is self education but also giving
some help to the marketing department
because it's going to make your product
more desirable so I want to make how
about from
ten husky from keep it simple organics
and and big play and so couple of things
so so Colin is at the mammoth microbes
dude if you want to chat with him
further and and I will actually be
signing her look and do have copies
available to work out so you could buy
copies of her book also at the mammoth
micros food tab has got his food that
keep it simple organic food and also but
you can go to ki s organics calm to
listen to this fabulous podcast papa
growing cannabis with living soil if you
came in like halfway through this
presentation or if you just want to
watch it again or heavily your
co-workers watch it you'll be able to
see it starting Monday on my youtube
channel at youtube.com forward slash
chain know most and if you did listening
the super experts like this make sure
you check out my podcast at shading fire
calm thank you very much for attending
and have a great invention