hey there shangela sort of shaping fire
here today and today we're going to do a
little bit something different I've got
a couple my friends with me this is dan
from and Laurie and genetics and sebring
from Sebring seeds and the reason why I
asked them to join me today was because
you know the back in the medical days
growers would breed seeds and give them
away the patient's because seeds were
really hard to get a hold of and
nowadays as you know medical becomes
more of this green rush thing you know
people are moving into doing seeds
primarily for profit and that's a whole
new and different world and as we see
you know as the state goes for medical
director a tional a lot of the patient
products go away too and so this this
continuing legalization which
theoretically should be great for
patients actually continually impacts
patients in a negative way so as I
travel the countries checking out these
new markets I meet more and more people
who used to make seeds for patients and
then they decided they wanted to you
know get involved with legalization
which is totally legit but a lot of
those folks don't make seeds for
patients anymore and I think that
something is really lost when patients
have a harder time getting good quality
seeds for free and so then I met Dan and
Sebring and I met these guys because
we're all interested in Auto flours and
they have both given me hundreds of
packs of seeds to give to patients here
on Vashon Island and at the various
places that I get my auto flower stalks
and by you know from talking with both
of them and I'm gonna say some things I
think you should make them feel awkward
but I'm gonna say it in front of them
what these guys are doing breeding
specifically for patients and then
giving the seeds away is something that
I think is lost and I'm hoping that with
this video maybe we can inspire some
people to start giving away some
they're seeds you know there's not
there's no problem with the you know
selling some of the seeds right we all
have to pay our bills but I want to
encourage people to breathe protect
potentially with patients in mind and
then to give some of the seeds away
because that's what these guys have done
and for me it reminds me of the medical
days when people were really in it for
the patient's instead of what we're
seeing now where people are more and
more turning cannabis into a commodity
so Dan Sebring thank you for joining me
and so we're just gonna ask a couple
questions to kind of you know get you
set up at the mindset of giving away
seeds and maybe it'll inspire some
people to start breeding or we're making
seeds for the first time so Dan let's
start with you man so so I know you got
into breeding because of patience it
wasn't that you were breeding first and
then you moved over to patient-focused
up but that was your whole point so so
what brought you to breeding for
patience breathe through patience came
from me because of a medical aid of a
family member
I mean basically stage one cancer you
know a short end of it and she needs
some pain relief and we needed to put
turnaround and all those were the key
and that's and then I started seeing the
benefits from the quicker turnaround to
continue that down the road and then
basically share out beyond my you know
circle of friends and family needs I've
been too fortunate benefit of meeting
you and making sure that those seeds get
beyond that circle that when I initially
start grow right on but when they they
certainly have I fell a little bit like
Johnny Appleseed given my way to sow sow
see purring I know that you as well got
into it specifically for the patients
and what are your motivations so I had a
couple motivations one was being able to
do seed preservation because my like you
sort of see that fall off a lot of the
really good strings that used to be able
to get your hands on these days you
can't or
to pay a fortune to be able to get a
hold of them and even then they're not
necessarily what you think they are on
top of that I had family members that
were in need of medicine as well one
with epilepsy another one with arthritis
so I needed a variety of different
answers and I need ones that would be
grovyle and self sustainable by those
family members so I could show them how
to do everything and I see the autumn
flowers answered that for me in both
cases in varying amounts with different
THC levels but both of them acted as a
way that I could hand seeds to a family
member of shown hey you grow a tomato
great even grow this there's a set part
of the state this is all you've got to
do this is you're making medicine
process come back to me if you need more
seeds or if it's not quite right and
we'll work with you on the genetics to
you know work it in the direction it
needs to go in and then that just
expanded out to wanting to help other
people like you I saw that more and more
semion seeds will grow on commercial or
seed breeders or leaving breeding and
we're just going into commercial
cannabis and so as I saw that void
happening people like me and you started
trying to fill that and so yeah just
like you I want to see more people
donating more seeds to people around
them patients that they need setting up
to us and we'll help distribute over to
the patients to contact us like that
part of the community is being lost and
it's essential for part of keeping our
community as a whole the stronger we
make each other the stronger we make
ourselves the community and so let's
talk a little bit about the distribution
now don't get me wrong right like like
seeds are fun to share even if you only
have one pack right so so we're gonna be
talking about like some numbers of packs
here but don't think I can't distribute
that many seeds or I can't grow them you
know produce that many seeds and think
that this might not be free
you because it's just giving away a few
packs those are great last year I only
made you know a couple dozen packs but
they felt really good to give away so so
Dan you know what did you do to figure
out how to give away your packs to
people because I know some people they
feel a little awkward to be like like
like even if I have seeds I don't know
where to where to give them well you
know organization is like with your on
the island you know there's a outreach
to patients there and I was fortunately
connected with you and we had that look
there and then I've also made some cold
calls you know take a look for like
veteran organizations or you know other
medical collectives or you know just
take a it's a quick search and you can
find the people that actually need them
and then just reach out to them make a
phone call you know I it's been very
well-received every time I've made a
call especially since it's free
you know I'll cover the shipping on it
to make sure that these people can have
what they need in their hands at a price
that it's can be it's pretty you know
the chance to grow your own medications
at home and take care of whatever
ailment you may need and like you said
having the ability to take extra CDs to
just hand someone in stay here to joy
you know spreading that forward it's
just a it's a great feeling it's a good
way to you know strengthen the community
like we've been talking about and
Sebring I know that you've turned this
into kind of a manufacturing operation
like you're sending out seats like all
over the place
tell us a little bit about that so
they're receiving seats comm I ship out
any seeds to get sent in to me I go
through a sorghum
I only take the quality seeds and that's
what gets shipped out stuff that's
dark-colored plump not under guns all
the other guns get set aside and I've
got a purpose for those but those good
ones all get sorted out they get
individually packed in packs of 15 to 30
seeds and then as long as people are
willing to pay shipping we ship them all
over the world most of them qualify as
hemp we only send seeds we don't send
anything else but we absolutely do any
anybody who comes on the website and
says they want to order a pack we take
care of it and then not all the time but
as
I can afford it when people contact me
and they don't have the money even for
shipping we take care of that as well it
helps if we only have a limited number
of those that are legitimate so I've had
a pretty easy time of it so far it could
definitely get to a point where I'd have
to borrow less put a hard number on it
like this is how many you know free
shipping is we're gonna give out but
right now where it seems like everybody
it's pecan tech and he's been honest and
had integrity and you know really said
what's going on with them like I don't I
don't get that hey seventy-three seeds I
get the I'm a son trying to help my
grandmother she doesn't know how to grow
I need to grow medicine for her I'm
unemployed right now can you help me out
and my answer is always yes absolutely
because I've been that guy that's where
I came from
that's that's my root is being that
person and living in that community and
so to me they're doing what I'm doing
which is trying to take care of people
that are in their community that they
love it shouldn't be in pain that's
right so so like this actually I think
he actually realized that this was gonna
happen this is kind of like a spectrum
right like I only produce like you know
a couple dozen packs every year and I
grew us some of those the following year
and then I give them away and Dan dance
producing like hundreds of packs and he
bundles them up and then sends them into
organizations and Sebring's got people
reaching out to him from all over the
world and if they pay shipping handling
he sends them see so you know you can do
a little or you can do a ridiculous
amount like and or somewhere in the
middle right right and so you can do as
much and in the way that fits for your
life so the way that I bet these guys
was because we're all into autoflowering
candidates varieties right now because
all three of us haven't realized that
they're really good for patients and so
so Dan you know
did you choose to start breeding Auto
flowers specifically for the patients
that you helped you know douchebag when
I said earlier is quick turnaround time
you know and the Terr profiles and the
cannabinoids that we needed were right
there readily available at that quick
pace and it made sense too because at
the time I was ahead access to both you
know regular sex seats I could get males
and females with no problem I mean not
there's an issue with feminized you know
there's a lot of them available today
but it was at a time where I was able to
actually begin that selection process
and kind of cater it towards what I
needed how about you see me so I started
doing autos because family members
needed something that they could grow
like a tomato they needed just like Jeff
Lowenthal's
said they needed something they can put
in the ground indoor or outdoor do
nothing but water it for 80 to 90 days
harvest it hang it dry it medicine just
that fast there's no no learning curve
no nothing the barrier of entry is
incredibly low and seeing how well my
mother succeeded on doing that how
basically she went from constantly being
frustrated with me talking about photo
periods which could be a real pain at
times especially for new growers to oh
my god I can do this I can actually do
this like I love you and I need you but
not for this yeah which to me that was a
huge weight off of my shoulders to know
not only that I could give her self
sustainable seeds and that she could
make her own medicine and then that
didn't have to be one more thing I had
to do freeing up my time preferably to
spend quality time with her instead of
just staring sending her that yeah
exactly but then I realized you know
she's older she's retiring if she is
struggling with this most retirees are
struggling with this so the reality is
what I had in my hand was something I
needed to distribute to the masses
because there really is a whole
community out there that needs it from
what I've seen they're more or less
being ignored there's not a lot of
seekers that are buried
for retirement baby boomers even though
they're like one of the largest sects of
people intersections of the community
that need this kind of medicine you know
and they're they're passed the drug war
stuff in the you know the propaganda
they understand that it helps them and
they want it they just need people to to
come to their level like drop down to
their level and speak on their level in
their terms and give them a plant that
they can that they can succeed let's go
set them up for success that's what
we're trying to do right I'm cool and
you know of course it's cool to breed
for cannabis cups too right there we're
not saying that you have to do one or
the other what we're saying is that as
legalization and the Green Rush takes
over less and less people are really
paying attention and listening to the
patients and what they need people are
offering patient products and patient
seeds but you know you know a lot of the
time they're not actually patients need
it's just that people want to fill a
patient market also one of the reasons
that I turned into got turned on to Otto
flowers for patients because they're so
coburn right the plants usually top out
around three feet you know I grew some
six-footers this year but but really
three foot is cut on average and you
know you can literally tuck those
between your tomato plants and your
neighbors won't even necessarily ever
see them you know so that's pretty good
and and you brought up Jeff phloem fells
we should go ahead and plug his book
right she's got a new book on Otto
flowers for the absolute beginner that
comes out next month October 22nd 2019
and it's all do-it-yourself Otto flowers
and he it's it's it's not really for
pros it's for people new like your aunt
your mom or your grandma or somebody who
like sebring see said is is it's kind of
over the taboo and they need
medicine and they want a garnet for
themselves and so with Jeff Lomond
fellows book you can boom put that in
their hands and it gives them the
history of auto flower seeds some basic
growing technique where to get auto
flare flowers and you know a bit of
encouragement that like you can do it
right it's it's a very simple book for
beginners and it's very effective so so
that's cool yeah yeah so so okay so if
there are people out there who are like
oh man I would really like to produce
seeds for patients what advice would you
give them like what what one piece of
advice would you give them about getting
started then I would say if it get some
access to some regular seeds if you get
access to regular seeds don't be afraid
to the mail you know make sure that you
know you kind of isolate it too
especially if you have a larger crop and
collect that pollen and bring it over to
the female and that's where you can
begin I mean we could go into great
detail on that and the process and how
to but there's several online resources
for that so you know don't be afraid of
that mail they can't they're not as
scary as they are yeah males we've got
terrible reputations right because
they'll seed your crop and most and
nobody wants that
unless you're producing seeds right
correct and so you know it takes a
little while to get over the fact that
the male can be seen as a threat in the
garden and actually see it as a partner
in making seeds so Steven what one piece
of advice would you give somebody first
I'd like to segue back to if you do make
seeds accidentally and they're not
hermaphroditic cross I'll help you get
rid of them we'll get them right to the
patients that need them for for new
breeders people that want to get into
breeding I would say that they first of
all don't don't be scared to just get in
there the first thing you've got to do
is get over that stumbling block of just
you know not being afraid get in there
and just do it my first cross is where
total accidents we literally just
three plants and we took one and it was
a male and cross it to two others and
grew those up to see what was there but
that's really what you've got to do you
better understand the genetics they're
stored stashed away in each of the
parents that you're working with you
need to understand the parents too you
need to be able to identify what came
from each parent to help figure out the
you know Britain's genetic level what's
going on with them what you know what
was dominant what was recessive and from
there you can kind of start to work in
the direction you want to go
my biggest thing I would suggest to
people that want to start breeding first
and foremost is honestly pick up a book
on Mendelian genetics and even if it's
confusing just work your way through it
even today I'm still running crosses
where I'm working through charts to
figure out okay what's this what's that
I know the ratios of what I should get
out of a cross based on whether it's
dominant or recessive and it's a lot
more complicated these days with
advanced genetics but a lot of the
principles still apply so if you can
understand the simplest Mendelian
genetics you'll begin to understand in
the crosses that you make what it is you
see and that's the key really well that
said don't let that level of complexity
stop you right get in there and do it
you can just be a pollen sucker right
which was I thought I am I have not met
a breeding book and yet I've been
growing my own seeds year over year and
I get great plants right all you need to
do is have a female that you like and a
male that you like and put them near
each other and you will get seeds and
very often even accidentals seeds that
get made and you didn't even plan can be
great so so you know just certainly it's
one of these fun hobbies that you can
start and a novice pollen shucking level
and then go all the way to reading books
and
dominant recessive traits but don't let
that be your stopper because like you
know a lot of people don't have time to
read a science book and take notes don't
let that stop you just freaking do it
and give the seeds away because you know
putting the seeds in patient's hands is
the Goldmans so that's so if people want
to follow you on Instagram and you know
continue to pick up some of this
inspiration how do they watch it now
that I can find me at the full-duplex
underscore AFN or about the genetic page
at Mandalorian genetics on Instagram
great how about you Cirie you can find
me under sea bring seeds at Instagram at
YouTube work got some videos on how to
make silver thiosulfate as well as some
growing tips the sea bream seeds calm
website through Facebook pretty much
everywhere just look look for Sebring
seeds and if you find a link that sends
you to somebody with that name it's
probably me right so so last thing is
you know oh yeah those links are in in
the description below if you didn't if
you didn't catch it but you know the
point of this video is just to get you
thinking about making extra seeds and
giving them away to people it is a lot
of fun to make extra seeds put them in a
little package and give them away to
friends you build your commit cannabis
community you you you create the
opportunity for giving somebody a few
packs and then they go on and give them
to a few people and and most importantly
good genetics get into the hands of
patients so that they can be empowered
to grow their own medicine and you know
it doesn't matter if it's Auto flowers
either we love red plants too right
whatever you have
access to start reproducing the seeds
and giving them away one last thing so I
probably made these guys a little
awkward but I kind of like you know
using them for an example of dudes who
or let's just say people who who produce
seeds and give them away to patients
right these guys are just examples of
that right there are people like this in
your community and talk to them and
maybe get together and maybe also trade
with them and you know they didn't ask
me to do this I actually bugged them to
do this video and s to put them on a
little bit of a pedestal so that through
their stories and me saying hey these
guys have given away hundreds of packs
to patients because they value that well
you know everybody wins right so so also
do not like jump on them and be
demanding facts is you know you know if
you've got an organization you know
perhaps reach out to mandalorian
genetics if you are individuals or
organizations and you're willing to pay
shipping and handling maybe you reach
out to Sebring remember man these guys
have got like day jobs and they don't
have a ton of time for customer service
so they you know they try to get back to
everybody just be considerate be kind
you know and if you decide to reach out
for them but but instead of you know
focusing on getting their C's for free I
encourage you to go ahead and make your
own so especially since it's fall time
now and if you accidentally had a
sneaker mail in your garden just gather
those seeds and put them in ten packs
and give them away it'll be great so
guys thank you so much for for talking
with me and hopefully we will cause some
more people to grow and give away see so
thanks a lot thank you shave your boss
brother
you