Hey Shango here I want to give a little
context real quick before we watch the
video you know this was recorded in a
log cabin Grange Hall here on Vashon
Island and it does not make for a very
good video recording the acoustics are
bad the the heating is loud and we have
to turn off the lights so people can see
the slides now now if you're there at
the Vimy a meeting it's awesome it's
very homey and intimate but it doesn't
really really very well two video
cameras so so I know this isn't as good
of quality as some of the other stuff
that that I share with you but you know
this is a pretty rare talk for Ethan
Rousseau to give nowadays so I figured
that getting what you can is better than
not getting at all and you know it
sounds good you know but there's a
there's a you know there's some high
loud points and then it gets quiet so
you might have to adjust your volume a
little bit but all in all it's it's a
great piece and it's you know serious
analytical information for people who
take their there's their pain management
serious so here you go enjoy
please welcome
to start out by showing you the names
option
otherwise it's kind of shimmer people
are gonna think that they're getting off
with rendition of cannabis and various
ancient languages to conceive starting
from the top just point out a couple the
fourth one is Chinese the kanji for MA
and that's actually a pictograph it is
showing stalks of the camp drying comes
that down in the shack so anywhere I'm
trying to better be recognized as
cannabis then next class is kind of poem
in Hebrew which means aerobatic cane
which was a component of the holy
anointing oil and then in the Greek the
more familiar cannabis
the accent on the first syllable this
talk is the same one that a gift to
physicians in scientists there will be
some technical stuff I will try to
explain but CP one is the receptor in
the brain where THC works we have
natural and doggedness chemicals within
that work on the same stuff
so this is a happy accident of nature so
the cb1 receptor is highly expressed in
areas of the brain that relate to pain
that's nociception and includes the
cerebellum the limbic system which is
involved with emotional type issues
basal ganglia with movement also reward
pathways that relate to whether a drug
is addictive or not now interestingly
there's some parallels between the way
that cannabinoids work on pain and the
way that opioids work on pain although
they're really distinct and their main
differences is this the people reason
people die from heroin or other opioid
overdoses is because too much of it will
depress respiration it depresses an area
in the lower brainstem the medulla and
people quit breathing there is no amount
of THC or a cannabinoid that can do this
so there's no fatal overdose that's
possible with this kind of drug but the
endocannabinoid system in these natural
chemicals within this is not
brain it's throughout the body in the
gut it regulates things like how fast
things move and how much liquid there is
it's in the spinal cord
now that nerves in the body the
endocannabinoid system he has about 30
different roles but these were
summarized in 1998 by Professor de marzo
as relax eat sleep forget and protect
but it's involved in all these other
things pain memory whether you're gonna
vomit or not whether you're going to
have a seizure or not on how fast the
gut moves or how slowly it moves there
are
some of it is needed by the cb1 receptor
but there are a lot of other ways in
which this happens to some of her
relates to neurotransmitters those
chemical messengers in the brain there
are interactions as I mentioned with the
opioid system with gun an endogenous
system there so we've got a parallel
that morphine works in the same places
that natural chemicals called accounts
and endorphins work so what's the
mechanisms by which pain is produced
analgesia analgesia is pain reduction
this is endocannabinoid system he has a
baseline level of activity that's there
naturally if it's too low people are
going to have excess pain if the level
of things are high there's going to be
less pain
area to break all the periaqueductal
gray that's involved in a penetration
especially
also in here
balance we're cannabinoid it's like THC
or ten times more potent than opioids in
the nerves that make these relationships
and then it's also involved in the
spinal cord and this is responsible for
some associated phenomena pain that are
a little bit weird like hyperalgesia
that means that touch is perceived as
being really painful things like this
wind up where there's a buildup of these
pain mechanisms and these all relate to
mechanisms of inflammation as well and
things as simple as edge it is just a
mild form of neuropathic or nerve based
pain so what are the components of
cannabis we've mentioned THC the main
psychoactive component that works is the
non-intoxicating anti-inflammatory
component of cannabis but the rock
cannabinoids in the plant
tetrahydrocannabinol THC egg also has an
effect and then an especially important
one is a terpenoid when the aromatic
components of cannabis call Kerry
awfully now this one's interesting
because it's also working on another
cannabinoid receptor called CB 2 that's
active up in the body and relation and
inflammation and pain but doesn't
produce any psychoactive effects so a
chemical I carry awfully and then just
works on CB 2 doesn't produce a high but
does have benefits on pain and then this
is designed to show you how things used
so this is of a preparation that was
made by Parke Davis on a pharmaceutical
company about a hundred years ago
one more and although it may be hard to
read the components are morphine
cannabis and capsicum where are Chili
Peppers yeah so you've got three
plant-based drugs that work on the
doggedness systems of being they didn't
know all these chemical relationships
but this is an example of what we call
empirical discovery that people tried
these things
what's interesting about this
preparation probably better than
anything we've got through conventional
means today
they probably gave this the people after
surgery didn't let them go home
but as long ago as the 19th century it
was known that cannabinoids produced
opiates sparing meaning that when he
gave cannabis people required less
morphine for being controlled and then
it could be used to help get people off
of those kinds of drugs because it
treated to withdrawal symptoms too so
you may think this is a new finding but
we've known this for under 50 years it's
just that a lot of people would like you
to as I mentioned there are interactions
between cannabinoids and opioids teetsi
actually stimulates the production of
what's called beta endorphin that's one
of the natural chemicals within that has
an effect like morphine and it interacts
in this periaqueductal gray area the
opioid sparing I've mentioned but animal
studies that were done over a decade ago
also showed that when TC was present you
could prevent the development of
tolerance to the opioids tolerance means
you have to eventually give a higher and
higher dose to get the same level of
pain relief that that was necessary
previously it also produces a rekindling
this means that if you give a dose of
morphine and it wears off it's no longer
good at reducing pain a little bit of
THC will bring it back to where is that
good again and this is a
the patient's observed to the scientists
Diana silhouettes that did all these
nice studies then yeah I met her in 1999
and told her gee you know this stuffy
reporting is fascinating but did you
know that they knew the same thing a
hundred and fifty years ago anyway she
was always surprised at the time we
became friends bit more about CBD some
very interesting studies these are again
rat studies they keep cannabidiol two
rats that were trained to pretzel ever
to get heroin this is your tax dollars
at work
but there were actual changes in
expression of neurotransmitters in the
brain in areas that relate to addiction
that CBD produced and reduce the
cravings such that the authors of the
study suggested that CBD should be used
as a treatment in humans for heroin
craving and to prevent relapse so some
wisdom there now this one's a little
complicated these were studies that were
done in Europe they had a series of
nations that sustained damage to an area
of the brain called the insula what
happened and it was a variety of
different things
some had damage due to car accidents
some from stroke some from other
diseases but what happened was some of
these people were cigarette smokers and
when they had this injury to the insula
they quit smoking with no craving
anybody's was addicted to background
knows this isn't normal but they figured
out that the insula was a very important
area in relation to craving related to
addiction and it wasn't just as
cigarettes the same thing was shown
for cocaine alcohol and opiates like
heroin turns out as I see here in the
skin a very large time depresses the
insula and that's the blue thing you see
here that's the area of the brain and
what was interesting was this change was
produced without any particular sedation
or other major side effects CPD alone is
non-sedating and then there are other
mechanisms i've mentioned previously cb2
the non psychoactive receptor there's
been a lot of companies that have made
drugs that are selective for that that
hopefully would treat pain without
producing a high because that's what the
government likes what was important
about this was it reduced dopamine
release which is related to drugs that
tend to be addictive and rodents that
were trained to be addicted to cocaine
no longer would self administer in other
words it was a reduced addiction to
cocaine again carry awfully in this
natural component of cannabis is a
selective cb2 and in us to a drug that
works there and should do the same thing
so this is an area that needs to be
researched now an old study from the
1970s and basically what we see here is
there could be comparing the pain
relieving effects of codeine and TC this
is plane THC not cannabis to be like
marinol and basically 20 milligrams of
THC was the same as a hundred and twenty
milligrams of codeine
so take your choice be very high or be
very constipated
you just
roses on basically they showed
improvement these p-values are
statistical indications of how
significant of something has point no.2
means there would be a one two percent
chance that the result was spurious with
stood a chance and that's considered
significant however the problem was
anybody who's taken plane TV knows it's
not a very good job not very pleasant
two-thirds of the patients knew what
they've got this is an indication and
study was not blinded properly if people
can tell the difference between the drug
of the placebo excuse the result what
with a drug that psychoactive like plain
tea see clearly is it's a very hard
neuropathy nerve based pain in patients
with hiv/aids now is a typical study
that the government approves we had to
use NIDA cannabis they required that it
be a limited number of patients for a
limited amount of time and that they all
have used cannabis before so that's not
all the population and you can't
generalize this to everything but I
guess they were worried that someone
would freak out be a problem for them it
was effective there was a reduction in
pain and about half of the patients had
a 30% reduction in their nerve based
pain over the five days 30% is
considered highly significant to a
patient but there were a lot of side
effects as you can see in the table
anxiety and 25% sedation over he have
disorientation 16 paranoia 13% confusion
17% this isn't the profile of a drug
that the FDA is ever going to approve
this is a problem with all smoked and
vaporize studies to date with one
exception
yeah the end of the space medicine
fda-approved or by that many botanical
drug me from a planet well there is this
blueprint for this
it was formalized in 2015 basically you
don't need to see the fine print you
need to show safety efficacy and
consistency in phase one two three
clinical trials phase one means you give
it to normal people to see how long it
lasts in the blood and what their
reactions are feast two is you give it
to a limited number of patients with the
disease in question phase three is large
numbers of patients and again with all
this the trail for the botanicals is
eventually you've got to show everything
that's it in it all the different
components and that they are within
tight tolerances there's not great
variance over time um one drug that has
done this is the drug that I worked on a
development of with GW Pharmaceuticals
called Sativex have been big some halls
this was made from two different chemo
bars chemical varieties that's the
proper term for strains we have strains
of bacteria and strains of virus viruses
but although everybody likes the meme
there are no strains of cannabis
there are cooler birds in any event it
was from a high THC King refer and a
high CBD king referred that were
combined to meet what is essentially a
teacher and a spray in the mouth what's
called the early kutzle administration
and each spray has 2.7 of THC and two
point five milligrams
of CBD along with interpreter and other
components this if you took enough to
feel it it would have onset about 15 to
45 minutes it's a little slower a lot
slower than smoking a little bit faster
than purely swallowing this is grown in
what they call glass houses in England
we call grain houses it's in organic
media they're all female clones from
mother plants no fertilization it's all
tightly controlled as the temperature
humidity good bugs eat the bad bugs and
it's called integrated pest management
said no pesticides or anything else in
relation of pain there are a bunch of
studies that were done in neuropathic
pain pain associated with them mass etc
we'll share some of the studies and more
details however as I mentioned the
studies in the US have all been worth
NIDA cannabis of low potency very
limited duration if we pull all those
studies up until a few years ago with
smoked of vaporized cannabis it's a
total of 3 patient years so that would
be one patient smoking every day for
three years or it could be 300 nations
anyway you can do it now it's not a lot
in comparison a few years back there
were 6,000 patient years with the sound
effects in a big slice just in pain
studies so a tremendous gap on my the
u.s. is allowed with domestics of
like versus what a British company did
including some studies in us patients in
other words you can't really have a
domestic source of cannabis and
development as medicine but you can
import it from a foreign country that's
how much sense that makes basically
receded this whole industry to foreign
companies and then explains but why I've
worked for foreign companies for most of
the last 23 years so let's go into some
specific studies these are are with sat
effects of spray in the mouth this was a
study that was done for what's called
peripheral neuropathy pain with
allodynia le dynein means that a touch
is perceived as a burning it's a
phenomenon associated with things like
diabetic neuropathy it could also happen
as a toxic reaction to certain drugs
like chemotherapy etc so 125 patients
over five weeks all the patients
Paul says could be antidepressants and
trying to treat a nerve pain but all the
patients that fail
still need something else and this was
just added on you see if you could get
any improvement over the baseline and
this is what happens so we're looking at
ten point scale zeros no pain ten is
being you can imagine and it may not
look like much but if you look at
placebo you've got a half of what box
improvement as compared to the big
circles and the blue is a point and a
half and again doesn't seem really
amazing but for a pooled population
that's a significant difference and you
see the p-value is 0.04 that means it be
only afford chances in a thousand
or
in terms of how much people improved
again let's look at the 30% improvement
highly significant of pages again a big
difference between placebo and the
purple and sativex in the blue in
allodynia
this phenomenon of touch feeling like
burning it's not something that is
treated effectively by conventional
drugs however it was this statistically
significant improvement with the big
some also sativex
patients global impression of changes
basically are you better are you worse
how much and you see that this is skewed
to the left meaning that the Blues are a
lot higher than the purple so the vast
majority of people were somewhere
between minimally and very much improved
now the same idea in multiple sclerosis
ms is not something that people who
don't have it usually associate with
pain however a lot of people with MS do
have what's called central neuropathic
pain central neuropathic pain from
whatever cause it is extremely difficult
to treat rarely benefits from any
conventional medicine but there were 66
patients in this study for five weeks
again unimproved on the best medicine
conventionally applied
the same kind of thing once again
placebo you've got about a box and a
quarter improvement and about two and
three quarters on Sativex
five chances out of a thousand that this
is a spurious result that's about as
good as he get with this kind of study
and again the patient's global
impression of change is skewed towards
improvement
it was about four times more likely that
patients on and a big sum alt would
report improvement as compared to
patients with placebo
another study rheumatoid arthritis this
is the only study even though this is
old now has done almost fifteen years
ago it's the only study formal study of
a cannabis based medicine in rheumatoid
arthritis there were 58 patients the
design was a little bit weird the fellow
that did it said oh my patients are not
going to accept any side effects so they
decided they'd just give it at night
well this isn't a drug that lasts 24
hours so whatever you see here could
have been a lot better so they just gave
it a night up to six sprays for five
weeks and they looked at this two
different ways again by one measure
there was significant improvement box
and a half that's compared to a half a
box with placebo and this isn't pain in
the morning pain on movement
morning usually people that have this or
at the worst in the morning and then
they looked at a thing called the das 28
it's 28 questions that he asked patients
disease activity score drugs that
usually produce this kind of improvement
or what are called disease-modifying you
me see these advertised on TV they're
biologicals they cost thirty to fifty
thousand dollars a year and they have a
lot of potential nasty side effects like
creating tuberculosis when you didn't
have it before things like that
oh I am sorry to say if there's been no
follow-up on the study just because no
one picked it up and funded it
how about cancer pain they've been a
variety of studies with the same
preparation the first two studies phase
two studies were done in smaller groups
of patients the first study was done and
hospice patients in England and I
believe in Belgium and then the second
one was the larger number of patients
well we'll look at these so the two a
study was in a hospice population and so
these are patients that are already on
optimised opioids the highest dose that
they could use without terrible side
effects but with remaining pain that was
still not at an acceptable level plus a
bunch of other drugs typically these
patients are on five drugs to try and
treat the pain and again they're using a
zero to ten numerical rating scale fix
involves Sativex showed a significant
improvement as compared to placebo
p-value of 0.1 414 chances out of a
thousand and i think called the
continuous response also has improved
over placebo and 30 percent response
rate was seen in 43 percent of patients
and a big smalls and only 21 percent
as many placebo now what a really key in
on this one in this study they were not
just using the big suppose there was
placebo there was a high THC extract
with no CBD and there was the big small
source at effects the difference between
the high THC extract and sad events is
the presence of cannabidiol in Saturday
so if you look at the 30 percent level
the gray is the placebo response and
it's about the same as the response with
the high THC x-ray now compare that to
the orange which is the set of X THC and
CBD plus the other components and it was
statistically significantly better than
the two other preparations so this is
the first demonstration of the synergy
the additive effect on pain of having
multiple components or a whole cannabis
based medicine as compared to what would
have been primarily GNC alone so a
second face to study was done this is
what was called a dose range in studying
patients were instead of choosing their
own dose based on their response they
were placed within narrow
so the low dose was on one to four
sprays a day mid six to ten and high
range 11 to 16 now this did not go the
way it might expect sometimes less is
more
the high dose range turned out to be
poorly tolerated because of the degree
of side effects not a great surprise but
the efficacy was not there either what
was found was that group statistically
didn't show any improvement in pink so
that was left out and we'll look at the
low end and medium dose ranges and what
we see here is that any at any level
improvement there was this clear
difference between the placebo in the
gray and the low and medium doses of
sprays of Sativex in the green and if we
look at the two studies together again
there was a difference always a
difference a benefit of the real drug /
placebo again with statistical
significance as you see here are the
difference in the lengths of the bars Oh
then something an interesting was
happened something that the FDA will
totally ignore from the first study in
the hospice patients some of the
patients lived a lot longer than
expected so they have what's called an
open label safety extension study this
means that everybody knew they were
getting sativex and they continued on it
and to see what happened so 10% of
patients took it for six months and 5%
for more than a year before sick
to the disease or stopping it for
whatever reason two things happen one
wasn't a great surprise to me and that
was that they didn't have to escalate
the doses of sad facts over time to get
the same level of pain relief now bear
in mind these are people dying from
cancer that isn't what you'd expect
you'd expect it'd be more drug but the
real surprise was what you always see an
increase in opioid dose did not occur at
all we're talking again on average so a
really expected thing graduated doses of
opioids in patients dying of cancer just
didn't happen but because this was a
couple of examples this is a patient
with multiple sclerosis
she had disabling pain on Saturdays she
was able to lower not only get
improvement in pain but reduced her dose
of amitriptyline an antidepressant used
to treat pain from a very high dose of
150 milligrams to 25 milligrams a day
and she was better enough that she
returned to full-time work
counseling other patients and these are
patients I interfered and had permission
surely stories and pictures this is a
Dutch lady with sciatica although she
was Dutch she had never used cannabis
before she was on long-acting morphine
and this constant a high dose 180
milligrams reduced to 30 milligrams and
her pain diminished from 9 you're
appreciating dynamo 4 which is moderate
pain but tolerable now we're gonna go
through some other studies what I
haven't shown you is the results of the
phase 3 studies in cancer pain some of
these were done in the States but a
bunch of other countries around the
world now these three studies did not
read out so unfortunately the results
that were seen in the phase 2 studies
were not demonstrated in the face three
studies normally would say well that
shows it didn't work wasn't effective
but that really wasn't the case we knew
this because it worked fine with
statistical significance in the American
nations it did not work in the patients
outside the US but there was a clear
difference in the patients and I can
tell you from having spent time going to
clinics in Romania and Poland that those
patients were sick as hell in those
countries you've got to be near death to
get opioid treatment to begin with and
if you feel that you're in really bad
shape and it was demonstrable that these
patients were a lot sicker often near
death and they just
didn't respond so it was a problem with
the mandated patient selection basically
the FDA was so worried that well maybe
giving this cannabis face medicine will
give people cancer that they would only
given to patients who already had cancer
again that's dollars at work okay
now shifting gears this is a really
important study that came out a few
years ago they looked at what happened
to rates of opioid associated mortality
people dying of overdoses what happened
as states legalized medical
what happened there essica the of the
Sophia epidemic and have been increasing
rates of deaths over time however the
rate of increase was much lower in the
states where access became available and
the longer it was available the slower
of the rise was really significant
differences such that it was estimated
that 700 I'm sorry 1729 lives were saved
in 2010 and they said if the
relationship between medical cannabis
laws that opioid analgesic overdose
mortality is substantiated further word
enactment of laws to allow for the use
of medical cannabis may be advocated as
part of a comprehensive package of
policies to reduce the population risk
of opiate analgesics well it's been
another several years and everything
that's come out indicates the same thing
that when cannabis is available you see
fewer deaths due to opioid overdoses
some other studies very recent they
looked at various studies animal
humans and they did what's called a
meta-analysis this is where you combine
studies and crunch the numbers to see
what the stats and basically 90 percent
of studies before giving the humans
showed this synergy boosting effect
combining cannabinoids and opioids the
effective dose 50 the dose at which 50%
of people will find efficacy on pain of
morphine with THC is much lower
highly statistically
and as they pointed out the studies like
the ones I showed you within the big
symbols are not powered to show hope you
experience in other words we didn't want
people could lower their dose if they
had to like they were super constipated
but it wasn't the idea was to try and
maintain what they'd taken previously
and see if Nixon moles made a difference
this is a study a hundred and nineteen
patients using cannabis sixty-four
percent reduction in opioids while at
the same time there was this big
improvement forty five percent quality
of life measures some of that could have
been due to fewer opioid related
side-effects
Stacy Gruber at Harvard did this study
where patients were looked before they
were on cannabis and three months after
using cannabis medicinally there was a
marked improvement in depression called
for the Beck Depression Inventory
better sleep better quality of life the
people who had been on opioids cut them
in half reduction of about forty eight
percent also benzodiazepines drugs for
anxiety that are highly addictive also
about 50 percent down additionally their
cognitive ability how they think their
memory was also significantly improved
again possibly due to having lower doses
of opioids so the idea that you're going
to take cannabis and be a zombie and
just not true then an experimental study
on normal
humans looking at pain combining
cannabis with oxycodone a synthetic
opioid should some of the same things
have been shown in the animal work that
when you had a dose of oxycodone that
was too low to reduce experimental pain
became effective with a very low dose of
t26 patients by using relatively low
dose of cannabis 26 grams of month so
that's like average one joint a day 46
percent reported increased ability to
work or return to work on there's a
significant opioid sparing so 20
patients reduced to 5 that required
opioids after treatment and the p-value
was 22000 you never see that it means
that's real folks so but because there
was no placebo involved here the study
could have been done here and the FDA
would not accept it at all
another study done in Israel reported
this last year
Medical
large unselected population out of 344
patients a third run opioids 36% of
those could discontinue them nine almost
10% decrease their dose only 1% increase
and 51% were stable so again hope you
experience right this was it's really
unbelievable
for decades high doses and opioids have
been used for chronic non-cancer pain in
other words low back pain people with it
could be on opioids for years and was
never studied this way there was never a
long-term study to see if it worked
basically to boil down a bunch of stuff
they had 240 patients half were put on
an opioid Benjamin half on an honorable
beauty regimen after a year there was no
significant difference in the pain
mumbles Keenan intensity was actually
better than the people who are not on
opioids and as might not be a surprise
there were a lot more side effects in
the opioid group that was statistically
significant and basically what they
showed is that opioids don't work for
chronic non-cancer pain
what opioids should be use for is acute
pain you just had surgery or you were in
a car wreck or if you have cancer but if
you have a broken ankle and the pain
continues
so it's about time 20:18 that somebody
demonstrated this so what happens in a
situation where someone is addicted
dependent on opioids or they qualify as
having cannabis use disorder or whatever
that is cannabis can be used in
conjunction with no appearance as you've
seen even the people were dependent on
opioids but any close follow-up if
they're better after a while it is a
reasonable thing to try and reduce the
opioids and often patients do this on
their own
without a lot of instruction from
doctors if someone has a high level of
cannabis usage let's just say 10 grams a
day it's been demonstrated by my
colleague Dustin Sulak that they can be
reset citize does he call it what he has
to do is quit for the 48 hours and then
resume and half the prior dose and what
he's found is the efficacy on pain is
the same as it wasn't the higher dose so
much better to use less and get the same
effect so conclusions the
endocannabinoids system has a clinically
important role and mediation of pain
cannabis has a bunch
components especially THC CBD and some
of the terpenoids especially carry
awfully clinical trial success or
benefit of the drug is very dependent on
the preparation so just because
something were something different may
or may not work it has to be proven on
its own we've got one cannabis based
medicine that's been proven in a variety
of clinical trials on the bits and balls
approved in 30 countries just not here
something I didn't show a lot of the
side effect profile adverse event
profile of the big samosas a lot less
frequent those reported with
particularly conventional drugs we know
that there's a horrendous level opioid
addiction with mortality in this country
seventy seventy two thousand Americans
died in 2017 but we need something
[Applause]
yeah you know I can't quote your chapter
now but it's their Center criteria if
the generally to be rated this addictive
never having to use disorder with
indicate that you have a preoccupation
at the drug in question Mike you think
about cannabis all the time where you
spend a good part of your day
if you ask me other people that yeah
however any number of things
however it's not going to kill them so
we need to look at it a little bit
differently and deal with
I don't think there would be these kind
of problems if we have more balanced
preparations that he had a significant
amount of cannabidiol as well SDHC but
that's not what people generally ask for
we have an important question down here
about references for this material I'll
just go ahead and email me most of the
material that are presented aside from
the most recent studies was in a book
chapter that came out a few years ago
yeah even one of your examples I'm not
sure we just slide it was but you bring
up an important point we know from
animal study so if we're looking at pure
cannabidiol that up to a point a higher
dose gives you better pain control and
then it falls off it's called a biphasic
effect we see this with a lot of
cannabinoids it may surprise you to know
that TC we know that it reduces nausea
too high a dose that can produce much
but the trick with cannabidiol is when
it's a whole cannabis extract with a
terpenoid its present you don't get this
fall-off in the response to pain you get
no matter how high the dose is you
continue to get pain reduction so this
is really an important demonstration of
why we shouldn't be worried about using
isolates isolates are something that
better that the pharmaceutical industry
model which is oh yeah we know what the
target is and we use one drug botanical
medicine is that exactly the opposite
it's the idea that gee we've got a bunch
of components that act in concert and
produce an entourage effect and a better
benefit this experimental study done by
Rika Lele material showing this benefit
of having a whole cannabis extract that
CBD predominant preserves the pain
reducing effect rather than having it
fall off with CBD alone yes yes
well the birds are important but there
is some doggie carry awfully and there
are other components the roots have been
used traditionally as long as on the
tops have and they do have analgesic and
anti-inflammatory effects but they seem
to come from other components called
triterpene or it's free to land and
happy free dull and all and there are
few alkaloids not high concentration in
the roots whereas there none and the
tops the roots have gotten the attention
that they deserve and recently decades
but a lot of people are making artisanal
preparations with the roots and
reporting good result
so yeah I'm wrote an article with
Natasha and if you want to learn more
about the canvas root ball we actually
interviewed Natasha R is about canvas
repel medicine on shaping fire podcast
last year another question Linda using
the using the product for inflammatory
problems how soon should you expect to
see some results
does it build up or is it pretty
immediate and why do they pick the
amount of time instead well yeah two
different things if we're talking about
pain depending on the the method
administration people may notice things
pretty quickly treating inflammation is
going to take longer and with a stable
pain condition we see Tennessee
improvement over time for a prolonged
interval in I didn't show all the safety
extension studies with sativex but
typically patients who are using it a
long time actually decrease the number
it sprays a day that they utilize
they need it less to treat their pain so
there is a cumulative but in fact what
they choose from the studies depends on
what they think should happen and what
the powers that be will let them do okay
now part of the problem is a lot of the
pain studies that reported were done in
the prior decade and 5 weeks was enough
that isn't true
now most pain conditions the FDA will
say you have to treat for 12 weeks the
problem and that is we know from looking
at a bunch of studies that the longer
you treat the harder it is to show it a
benefit over placebo there's been a
marked increase in placebo effect over
the last 30 years and it's worse for a
drug for treating pain any drug that
psychoactive or in the case of cannabis
where the public thinks that this stuff
is miraculous the way people think is
that jeez you know this is my last shot
I really hope this is going to work and
of course I must be on this drug I'm not
getting placebo and you know the way the
brain works it's a huge problem right
now in medicine because many drugs that
we know work don't work all that often
and something has set a dinner Soloff
sertraline the antidepressant commonly
used they did 26 studies to show three
where there was benefit
always ask me but can you have annoyed
to Hamrick hyperemesis this is a
relatively new phenomenon described
there's several hundred case studies
reported but its more common than that
so this is a situation where it only
occurs in the context of people who use
very high amounts of cannabis on a
chronic basis only in that context and I
believe it's only in high THC
preparations what typically happens is
patient will develop terrible abdominal
pain the really characteristic thing is
they won't notice at some point that if
they take a hot bath or spend five hours
[Music]
but the B end up in the air are they get
expensive guests or intestinal workups
they don't see anything and get you know
given opioids or other drugs that don't
work these solution that this is one of
two things the obvious one is to stop
cannabis and that takes care of it what
is going on well nobody's sure but it
probably is this biphasic effect that in
certain air is the brain you're getting
an opposite effect at what you expect
from THC that is producing nausea and
vomiting and producing pain rather than
stopping it or I could have to do with
the down-regulation of the receptors
this is where they fold in in the cell
membrane instead of being out there
rub them on the abdomen it takes care of
it I will relate my story it feels like
it does it doesn't produce damage my
theory is that capsaicin works on a
receptor called trip v1 cannabidiol
works on the same receptor without being
burning so my theory was that you can
prevent cannabinoid hyperemesis syndrome
by having cannabidiol a few months ago
at a conference I met a young lady who
had this problem we talked about it and
I said well first you've got a cutback
or stop and then if you want to resume
you need to be looking for type 2 or
type 3 chemo first so those where
they're equal amounts of CBD and THC or
even CBD predominant I'm happy to say
that she was at the Emerald cup it
California a few weeks ago and she is
vastly better because she's using
cannabidiol so I think that is part of
the solution
Bernays regarding direct CVD versus THC
can follow one missus semantics the
original camp CBD was made by a broad by
using hemp refused in other words they
would use the seeds or fiber and then
the this refuse that was left was
chemically extracted and they get a tiny
amount of steeping be out of bed along
with a bunch of garbage and that was FA
CBD I know that's not the way you should
make medicine if you want cannabidiol
that you properly come from dedicated
high cannabidiol plants and from the
flowers that's where
there are now plants with whatever ratio
you'd want of high CBD usually low THC
plus a good interpreter profile it's
going to contribute to the therapeutic
benefit of the preparation so I will
state clearly I'm biased but that's the
way to think it should be one more can't
tell you you know these were they
weren't looking and craving than the
study wouldn't use this is an example of
what could happen if you use tight dose
CBD to treat addiction okay so it's a
good question but that wasn't what they
were looking at here how long the threat
was I suspect they relate to the
half-life of CBD so I'm gonna say
several hours and you know that and we
could find out experimentally when we
try this using kind of CBD to treat
people with addiction we'll find out how
long is it good for my suspicion is you
should treat the people three times a
day maybe even a little more you know I
would depend on whether they take it
orally or whether it's inhale