hey there friends it's chango from
shaping fire and i'm here with my good
friend dan jimmy from mandalorian
genetics and a lot of you have noticed
that dan has been uh kind of teasing
that he has a big announcement coming
and today is the day so we're here on my
patio for uh him to let us all know so
dan what's the story what's the big news
i guess we'll get into it shango um
we're gonna go through a name change um
and actually as of today it'll be the
name going forward
we're going to be switching to gnome
automatics and i think it's a good
direction and i think it's going to be
really beneficial for the company so
mandalorian genetics is a cool name and
we've all grown to love it and you know
a lot of people you know call you dan
mandalorian um it must have been a hard
choice to decide to leave mandalorian as
an as a brand and switch to anything at
all
absolutely it's honestly one of the
hardest decisions i think i've made over
the last couple years with the brand and
i think it's also one of the smartest
moves that we could have done we want to
embrace the change grow as a company and
having mandalorian
as a name moving forward as we grow
could be potentially dangerous for the
company yeah i can see how there'd be a
threat because um
you know uh the disney folks have got
lawyers they do have lawyers they and
like you know they probably have lawyers
for those lawyers so i think
to
sidestep and move forward it's the best
thing we can do yeah was often a good
move for small business owners like us
just kind of avoid that whole shtick
yeah so even though you liked the
mandalorian genetics name you're moving
on to gnome automatics um what is it
about the the name gnome automatics that
you identify with mostly the gnome side
uh the gnome side my cousin and i have
joke for years that i'm the gnome is on
the shorter one of the two and most of
you guys know that my cousin and i you
know run the mandalorian page in the
mandalorian genetics side of things and
he's always kind of called me a gnome
and he's also 6'4 so it's kind of
fitting
so i kind of identify that for
with that for a long time so i think the
gnome side is you know embodying me
into the brand a little bit more making
it more original and then the automatic
side is you know it's a it's a twist on
the word autos because that's where our
primary focus is we do work with
photoperiod plants but the automatics is
something i've embraced for a long time
so i think the marriage of the two is
really good for the brand
not only that like you know it's
definitely where you built your
reputation exactly that's where i came
from it's where i've you know showed
passion for a lot of years
so um you know some people might be
curious because you know there you know
if you look across the entire country
there are a couple different cannabis
companies that use the word gnome um do
you have any concerns about like brand
confusion or anything like that um not a
whole lot i mean i'm sure there may be a
little bit at first which is fine but i
think with you know that tie in with the
gnome automatics and the the way that we
advertise i think people get a clear
picture and this video helped too you
know makes it more intimate to all of
our followers and all of our customers
that they get a clear picture of what
we're doing and why we're doing it yeah
well you've always been really big with
the outreach with your customers right
right like a lot of a lot of folks in
the canvas industry um you know they
they make pronouncements to their
fan base and they don't really include
them but
when you reached out to me you're all
like you know i don't want to make this
name change
without everybody who follows the brand
knowing why and so they can come along
for the ride and i think that speaks a
lot to how you interact with everybody
by like kind of embracing folks you know
right and that's where my heart is too
is like i like to embrace i'd like to be
one-on-one and i feel like a better term
intimate with you know my customers and
the consumers of the seeds and you know
it's
just one more step
in the right direction yeah
so um so do we all need to change where
we follow you on social media like like
do we have to move over to a new
instagram page or are you going to be
able to keep the same mandalorian pages
and just change the name we're going to
be able to keep the same mandalorian
page you know and change the name
because fortunately with the gnome
automatics pairing we have a lot of
options to go down that road and what
that will do is it'll allow us to keep
the confusion low and then of course
with the full dupe plex page myself
you'll be able to see all the work and
everything coming out from there too
right on
so um so the gnome automatics page is up
today right correct right on and so if
you want to get on the new mailing list
that is going to be dedicated
to gnome automatics drops um they should
go to gnomeautomatics.com right correct
and if you misspell it we got those
domains too it'll redirect you to the
right spot right on so dan thank you so
much for taking the time to have a sit
down with me we're really excited for
this name change it you know not only
does it make sense as you grow as a
company
but i can imagine that you're excited
about diving into all this new gnome
related artwork too i am i'm thrilled
about it you know i'm really looking
forward to what we can do with it
there's a lot of good artists out there
that have done the work we have the
labeling we're waiting to finish up on
our illustrated version but i think it's
going to be exciting for everybody right
on
so uh so thanks for joining us this
morning here on the porch and um why
don't you go ahead and check out
gnomeautomatics.com and sign up for the
newsletter right now so you can find out
where the new drops are taking place
congratulations dan thank you shango
right on
you