hi there Shango from vimeo here and I'm
gonna show you something not commonly
seen by patients in marijuana
enthusiasts when you're not a grower
that first sight this looks like a
beautiful Northwest but already - I'm
almost ready to be harvested but if you
flip it over and get on in there this is
what mold looks like see the the gray
areas and towards the inside that is
where this big beautiful bud filled in
and there was not enough airflow to get
through and into all the flowers so then
this starts to grow on the inside this
is good because it can take over the
whole flower itself and then you lose
you know the whole cola but more
specifically to patients this can make
them even sicker and for folks who are
just you know cannabis enthusiasts you
don't want to smoke this because it
tastes bad will make you cough and if
you've got asthma
that's enough not a win so anyway moldy
moldy flour is not something that a lot
of folks see on the consumer and so just
wanted to show you
moldy weed