all right I guess I'm just gonna speak
up since there's no microphone here on
the podium welcome everybody to the
10:30 presentation propagation best
practices from commercial scale
cultivation for optimal growth if you
would please silence your cellphone's
I am Shango Lowe's host of the shaping
fire podcast if you like listening to
smart interviews with the top minds in
cannabis I invite you to check out the
show at shaping fire calm we also have
an extraordinary youtube channel with
over 150 speaker videos I recorded at
events just like this one
Doug Jacobs our speaker is already on
the channel and will be posting this
presentation next week
Doug Jacobs is technical advisor with
grodan providing expert consulting on
proven precision growing methods he has
extensive experience with indoor outdoor
and greenhouse hydroponics vertical
farms aquaculture and cea system design
today Doug will be speaking about proven
precision growing methods to optimize
crop production using irrigation
strategies and other operational factors
to produce the best quality plants using
the least amount of inputs and you
taught me on the side we're going to
talk a lot about mothers today so please
put it together for Doug Jacobs
good morning thanks to the excellent
introduction so yeah my name is doc
Jacobs I'm a technical advisor for Rodan
I started growing plants probably when I
was a baby than their parents did
rewards and tropicals in South Florida
you know like a lot of people in this
room I probably got involved with
cannabis early around 14 15 years old
you know drew a little bit sold a little
bit really was fascinated by the plant
got out of it probably right before
legalization started doing urban farming
vegetable consulting and building every
type of pot farms greenhouses got a lot
of cool experiences out of that and
about four years ago I started working
for grodan did you think I was gonna end
up doing cannabis again but happy to be
here we've been spending the last four
years helping to marry a commercial
vegetable production with cannabis
production so a little bit about grodan
you know for 50 years growing husband a
leader in manufacturing hydroponic
substrates for these commercial
horticulture industry with a focus on
informant formative and sustainability
we've developed propagation blocks plugs
slabs loose substrates for tomatoes
cucumbers peppers and obviously for
cannabis our goal has been to help
increase the sustainability of our
farmers around the world using less
water less the nutrient decreasing labor
costs while increasing yield and quality
in addition to making growing media we
have developed tools like the burden
grow sense water content sensor that
allows you to make
the water content and EC in the root
zone in real time giving you insights
this allows you to stupid plant growth
providing exactly what the plants need
they are not to grow drastically
reducing the amount of water nutrient to
grow those crops and we're going to be
building on this knowledge experience
over the next couple of years increasing
these tools and building substrate
specific to cannabis to increase your
sustainability profitability so today
we're going to talk about uniformity
where I talk a lot about growing mother
plants taking cuttings the veg phase and
a little bit about rock structures
primarily from the tomato industry and
how they might be applied to to cannabis
so uniformity in greenhouse and indoor
farming is a fundamental requirement for
making consistent quality plants the
farm design and plant care plan should
be developed with uniformity of mind
that is why modern greenhouses are tall
built to a large footprint with no
internal walls to create differences in
environment making a uniform climate for
for tank growth heating systems are
designed to deliver he irrigation the
informant uniformly and grower has left
the soil over 50 years ago to grown
Rodin because of improvements and
sustainability and uniformity it
provided so say 50 years ago a tomato
grower could get 10 kilograms per meter
squared and how we can get almost 100
uniformity really starts with with
another stock and propagation because it
can if you can repeat we throw that of
young plants and steer them correctly
from the start you can maximize
production and growth while all other
subsequent inputs labor client
to be optimized delivering the highest
quality cannabis plants time after time
so sourcing mother stock as you know is
probably the most important step to
creating uniform crop whether you're
getting rooted cuttings seeds tissue
culture starts you should take steps to
ensure you're not bringing pests and
disease into your tiered grows a test
batch of plants should be created and
run through a whole life cycle to
determine how they perform in your
facility you should take notes on how
these plants developed at every stage
how they reacted to pruning climate
irrigation conditions and climate
conditions will help you move these
plants into production other things in
crop registration which is not common in
cannabis should be taken on we should
find measurements that we need to to
take to see any cause this crop
developing is it's developing
differently from the last time I'm
through it and why because if you're not
taking these measurements you'll never
get any understanding of how the crop is
is developing so like taking notes on
route speed quality of the routes the
plant height stem diameter leaf and stem
color node spacing the the natural
structure of the cramp of the plant so
taking a none top plant putting into
production see how it develops on its
own and the making decision on how to
treat that plant later on but before you
can even grow your mother plants you
have to select the substrate type
determine how much volume is needed for
each mother an ideal planting density
all of which will define the irrigation
system requirements canvas while the
plants are typically kept in large
amounts of growing media you know five
to twenty five gallons of substrate and
water than three point a usually three
to six times per day is they're lucky
this is a carryover from black and gray
market days where you have limited space
to commit to your mother's plant count
restrictions of the
non-fans you could have so it's time to
sort of we look at this with growing
mothers and see if there's a better way
to get more consistency out of gonna
crop so having large mother people
having large mothers and large vines and
substrates has several drawbacks first
it increases the risk of one bad mob
spoiling a whole batch effects taking
large amounts of cuttings from a single
plant all at once creates a lot of
stress on the mother cannabis is a very
resilient plant to you otherwise
wouldn't know there's anything wrong
with it just by looking at it most of
the time the tipping you know third or
fourth of the plant off at one time it
does create a lot of stress and has a
cascading effect on all your subsequent
cuttings down the road and then finally
a labor perspective large mothers
sometimes require workers to get on the
ladders were constrained positions that
you know increase your liability as as
growers and owners so it's time to look
at maybe using a higher density of
mothers smaller mothers and smaller
substrates that are more reactive that
you can steer this increases this
decreases the threat that one mother
would pose to a whole batch of tanks and
using a smaller volume of substrates or
growing media especially something like
grow dad with a lot of group space would
allow you to use irrigation as a tool to
steer mother growth so when I talk about
crop steering for those who haven't been
to one of these presentations before
we're talking about the difference
between vegetative and generative growth
so vegetative growth simply put on
growing leaves and stems focusing on
building out the crop the plant where
general growth is I focus more on fruits
and flowers but I can use the steering
for both regardless at what stage so I
can be generative in my mother exactly
generative with
like regenerative and veg genitive and
flour I can be vegetative in all those
stages I think I think that's where the
problem starts is that a lot of growers
start out generative and upbeat
vegetative and end up hurting
development so a little more detail to
this you know so vegetative irrigation
strategies have to be higher water
contents you have smaller decreases
overnight in smaller dry box so
decreasing water content by and you do
this by manipulating the start and stop
times of irrigation your decent
frequencies typically higher so I think
of aeroponic systems the more times I
can deliver irrigations to the plant
without over saturating the root zone
the faster I can get it to grow each
seeds having lower Easy's allowing for
easier uptake of water is more
vegetative and then having an overall
higher substrate temperatures is more
fetch data and then generative on the
other side is is lower and decreasing
water contents again being manipulated
by these start and stop times of the
irrigations of the day irrigation
frequency though were typically
delivering the same volumes we're just
taking away the frequency and just
delivering a bigger shot of irrigation
so you know when I want to be more
vegetative I have smaller shot size but
overall I'm just changing the way I'm
applying the same amount of water
eces to the rehire ECS and generous
steering and then substrate temperatures
you know you've been making the natural
seasonal change by decreasing the roots
on tap like irrigation climate has a
significant effect on how the plants
grow and can be used as a tool to steer
growth how does the lighting pipe and
the environment affect later stage
development plants switching from
fluorescents to HVS or from LEDs to HBS
you know can cause a lot of problems so
you need to take note of these and
really see hey I'm going from a lower
lighting source to a higher
agents are so going from LEDs to HBS I
don't necessarily want to match the
intensities I may want to go lower to
prevent stressin from changing these
plans from from cuttings to veg to
flower so how can you effectively steer
mother plants back and forth to get
better cuttings faster while at the same
time managing growth so your mothers
don't grow out of control even when
taking their cuttings you need to take
note of the environmental conditions
that you're taking the cuttings in you
know having high light intensity low
humidity while taking the cuttings can
affect the the cutting quality same
thing with a mother to do I want a very
active mother on her highlight high
humidity high temperatures when I'm
taking the cuttings and then trying to
stick them that I probably wanna reduce
my light intensities at the time of
taking the cuttings super your roars
your workers will appreciate this as
well so as I mentioned before the weight
cannabis when the plants are cultivated
might need to be revisited so we're
going to talk previously briefly about
the method of propagation for
chrysanthemum flowers to see how it can
be adopted apply it to to cannabis
so chrysanthemum other plants are
typically grown at a very high density
30 to 40 plants per square metre 1.8 to
2.5 plants per square foot so this is
like sea of green style of growing this
allows high density mother's we grown
give you typically straighter cuttings
more vigorous cuttings the high density
hedge also reduces the threat of one mom
affect a whole batch of cuttings but how
does this delivery uniformity so when
they're gonna go santhu of others they
typically
all the plants have the same number of
these sets so they used leaf sets of the
determining factor of wanting to take
the cup to pinch the first half so after
the mothers of the planted and growing
for about four weeks until they hit four
or five leaves tall then the head and
the leaf is pinched creating a uniform
crop structure across all the mothers
here you see the the pinch on the fifth
leaf so keeping the number of leaves and
branches even across all the plants is
cheap keeping the growth rate the same
the low crop structure makes it easier
for growers to harvest the cuttings and
instead of taking only straight tops so
15 to 17 17 days after the first finish
two cuttings have taken these are all
straight tops it has the highest growth
potential so this first flush and I
think mushrooms that first flush of
mushrooms is usually the strongest then
subsequent flushes and cuttings can be
taken every every week or two during
this process you may end up with some
taller plants that may be jam-packed
between and before harvest as you see
here on all the cuttings are taking in
one day
so really traditionally with the
chrysanthemums there they're grown in
another country they're cut the footing
of a frigerator and then they're shipped
to the greenhouse and then the planted
at once so this is something some
cannabis growers are starting to
experiment with it's taking the cuttings
putting in the refrigerator and then
taking them out when they're ready to
stick so as to go through each
subsequent flush you'll need to maintain
an equal number of leaves and branches
between them other plants to keep them
growing at the same rate to figure out
how exactly this can be applied to
cannabis with all the different
cultivars that includes will take some
experimentation and crop registration
and what the ideal number of leaves the
growth speed and how many cuttings can
produce in what time frame once you've
done this a few times with each cultivar
you can create an ideal crop structure
density and develop schedule for cutting
specific to that variety so making some
other plants
between each harvest of cuttings the
growers will then go through these
plants almost daily to ensure that
they're growing informally leaves are
removed graduates so they're not doing
full strips of the plants because you
know the leaves are not only sold solar
panels they're the batteries the cold
water and the whole nutrients and they
help keep the plant in balance so if you
start ripping off the leaves excessively
or all at once it can throw other plants
out of out of balance some plants while
take water faster or slower than others
so it's something to be considerate of
so in chrysanthemums specifically that
keep these mothers for about 26 weeks
because they see a significant decrease
in cutting success rates after 26 weeks
but considering the success with
cannabis it might be even shorter we've
seen growers find that after 3 months of
having a mother planted cutting
successor it just takes a nosedive you
know where they were getting a 90 80 %
second success they got down to 60 50
percent I can't explain why was that
mother's been stressed out it's been
there too long it's it's time to time to
change it out so to take the most
uniform cuttings possible with the least
amount labor to Santa Cruz use this
specialty tool here to help ensure all
the cuttings are the same length
this plastic tool uses a flat surface
with the sharp edge that not only
supports the cutting as it's being taken
but also ensures all the cuttings are
the exact same length with a uniform
number of these sets with without the
need of additional labor so only new
growth head cuttings are taken even
those with cannabis you can take lower
growth cuttings and still have similar
success rate and some stem is left above
the note to protect it so you can grow
another
so it's important to have a clear visual
scale for the size cutting you wish to
make San Thurman growers use this visual
scale to group the cuttings together to
maintain uniformity so stem diameters
use to group the cutting this acts that
good or thin and by having this visual
and measurable standard to group the
cuttings together allows them to be
placed in batches so they all can grow
at the same rate in addition to keeping
the stem length diameter it's consistent
between the cuttings they also have to
ensure that the cuttings have the same
number of leaves so if you're lucky
enough to have spaced intercolonial room
you should should create a tray spacing
that does not require you to have to cut
off too many leaves in the tips which is
a contributing factor to creative
differences in growth rates so I mean
there's been some university studies in
Canada that found that just taking the
leaf tips reduces cutting success rate
anywhere from like seventy one fifty
percent so I mean we take leave tips off
because we're trying to cram a lot of
plants in one space that if we leave
more leaf tips on and technically more
leaves and then find it ideal spacing
they'll probably get healthier cuttings
so that same study done by the
University of Guelph found that cuttings
with three leaves as opposed to two
leaves had a 15% higher quality and
rooting which is pretty significant so
if you have that space in the luxury to
to spread out your cuttings and not do
the typical 98 72 or 50 plants per tray
you'll find that you know 20 to 25
plants in a tray tables will give you a
better quality
so now that we have uniformity in mom's
and some uniform make cuttings we now
have to place them and construct
substrate and have a way to maintain the
cuttings until the next stage of growth
first if you have the luxury of space
you'll need to find a good density that
allows you to grow these cuttings
without being overcrowded in the tray
substrate volume can be adjusted based
on how long you intend to keep the
cuttings in the nursery tray so you can
use a small small amount of substrate
and grow very small cutting and have a
transplant a very fast but if you use a
bigger volume so we're using a two inch
propagation cube you probably
accomplished a little bigger cutting and
if you have an irrigation system that
allows you to water it more frequently
without over saturating the root zone
you could probably accomplish some of
your veg in the cutting base so having a
larger volume so the timing and
frequency used to irrigate cuttings has
a tremendous effect on how the plants
develop so wandering too early seems to
be the biggest problem for most cannabis
growers especially in Rockwall Rockwell
has a a higher of water holding capacity
than most other substrates so if you
water too much too frequently you'll
have for root development so the idea
after the first stick your cuttings and
substrate you look the the growing media
dry that typically you could use weights
to determine when your water and then
when you go for that first irrigation
you don't want to submerge the cube
again you don't want to push up all that
airspace because it's gonna slow down
plant development so you may just want
to tap the bottoms of the blocks just
really just touch them just to give some
new nutrient and bring the water content
back up a little bit but not up to full
capacity because that will slow you down
and then watering too soon so you know
just
your hand does not necessarily the best
measure especially for if you're letting
your laborers do it so you may want to
actually report the weights of the trays
or the plugs and use math to determine
when to water especially for hard
routing varieties that such as it seemed
to take forever so now that you have
your selected substrate you have system
for irrigation that automates or your
propagation now you have to wet up your
substrate so commercially this is
typically done with with wedding lines
these are conveyor belt systems with
three three booms of water that slowly
move the blocks across a system that
what's up the lots automatically most of
us don't have access to this equipment
that depending on your skill it may make
sense to automate this process the other
option is a wedding card so same concept
except in my manual I have three wedding
booms I'm moving the the card slowly
over the Watts to allow the water to
saturate the box if I throw too much
water too fast on the substrate I could
potentially just bypass the substrate of
different parts that water won't sprint
out we'll just go down and out so you
really have to work on applying either
water really slowly or fully submerged
your blocks and plugs to get initial
saturation once you initially saturate
your substrate you then have to check
the weights it's the only way you can
determine if I clean it up correctly and
consistency consistently across the
batch so using weights as a measurement
to determine how about have I fully
saturated my substrate and when did your
date aren't probably the most important
tools you could use as a grower so again
yah weights weights the plugs and trees
and block students checked after initial
saturation to ensure that they've been
saturated correctly and it also helps
you determine hey is there something
with either the way up when it up or is
the substrate holding more or less water
and then am I gonna have to irrigate
sooner or later otherwise you're just
assuming everything is correct and
you're - Lee apply arrogation without
any consideration to what's going on in
the root zone so as you probably know
climate has a significant effect on how
cuttings developed often I see lowlights
and cutting rooms so less than the 70%
are 70 micromoles where in most other
earth culture crops 70 to 90 micromoles
is what's used just to supplement
natural sunlight at a greenhouse so this
low light intensity for cuttings
potentially slows down plant growth it
opens up the plants to diseases and
extreme humidity with low light
intensity can create Dino foiler
diseases so when you have plants in a
humidity dome with low light intensities
potentially high heat from a heat map or
the heat from the layers below it your
trading environment you create walls and
it's a lot of problems where people of
the top rebuilding problems are the
mildews and fungus those typically
started propagation so for example when
doing chrysanthemums this is a
chrysanthemum greenhouse in Holland they
do about how
many cuts per week when they lay out the
cuts they lay out a plastic tarp just
over top of all the cutting so you have
a big volume of air that makes it
consistent across the entire batch but
it's also keeping the moisture
potentially away from the leaf tips so
if you notice the cuttings that are at
the end developed differently than the
cuttings that are in the center so we
have to look at systems that allow us to
raise the humidity without creating
moisture on the canopy so it's a
revisiting of density and the cutting
traits but also trying to figure out
ways to grow cuttings without domes no
commercial crop other than cannabis is
used uses domes so to get the best
techniques possible you should look at a
system that maintains humidity between
70 90 percent lower should you know work
to ensure that the leaf temps the plant
temps themselves and not getting too
high so using a infrared thermometer
going in and checking hey so my root
zone tough to high or is the leader high
especially when you're first placing
those cuttings into the propagation
so managing transit transitions from
cuttings to the growth grow out stages a
critical time so where possible you
should work to adjust the climate of the
cuttings gradually over the course of
several days to Maxo of the environment
you plan to transplant into fairy-tale
your - to match the the climates can
cause a negative reaction that you will
not notice immediately
Kazi shot to the plants and slowing down
development and reducing quality so if I
go from my my propagation room is
sending it to 90 micro balls and a low
temperature to by my bedroom with you
know 200 to 300 micro balls you know
really high light intensity high high
heat no humidity you know you can really
mess up their cup and not know it
not know until weeks later so it's
really important to match those things
or get the cuttings used to that
environment prior to even putting them
in the new substrate again the same
thing is transitioning from lighting
types so if I go from florescent into
HPS or led to HBS I don't necessarily
want to match the light intensities I'd
probably want to go lower on the HBS or
really any just when you make that
transition you should probably make that
up the new environment temperature lower
just to keep the plants a little more
safe until they're ready to to take off
when to be moved into the new substrate
community
you can grow fast as I talked about
earlier irrigation strategy is a
critical tool on how the plants develop
each irrigation of top slide sends a
vegetative signal to the plant to grow
think of a house plants grow again in in
their atomic systems since the roots are
grown in air the drive acts are faster
allowing for more frequent irrigation
and drives growth and speed if the goal
is to to develop the root zone dryvax
are important part of this process
especially when rooting into a new
substrate volume is again where
measurements by weight sensors come into
play to help you determine when when
done to your game if the roots are
leaving the block it's most likely
because you're applying too much water
you're achieving too much drain or you
have water buildup in the table you know
if you're growing in the substrate you
typically want to keep the roots in that
substrate if you're promoting the growth
outside of the box you're opening
yourselves up to more disease so when I
go to transplant I have all these
exposed roots in the bottom I don't put
it into something else I'm going to
damage these roots and attention to open
it up to to a virus or a capital so an
irrigation system is really the only way
to get consistent and uniform reefs a
chwarae sinead eurasian even for
cuttings and an in vet
irrigation systems like flood tables NFT
systems that use shallow trays with a
small water food running process not
only allows you to automate the aeration
process but will help you maintain the
uniformity you've worked so hard to
create
so inconsistencies created by hand up in
trays and watering will carry through
the up throughout the entire lifecycle
plan
flood heights and dip times can be
adjusted to apply just the amount of
water to steer the plants as you see fit
hand watering is possible during
face but it creates a lot of
inconsistencies so when selecting your
engaging system for better for cuttings
it's important to have a system that
allows you to manipulate a flood height
so I may I may want to fly high that
first irrigation when I'm saturated
substrate may be the second one
but later ones I may just want to apply
very small just touch the bottom with
the blocks or the pop so I'm not
completely pushing out all the air from
the the growing media so here's an
example graph initial dry back from
abroad and small block for for tomato
crop so the drive I happen slowly over
the course of of four days
so you're going from a water content of
roughly 80% of a new submission of
saturation down to 30% and then I'm
giving it a feed and then I'm going Java
gamut so this strategy reads roots it
forces those feeder routes to come out
and search and the route into the new
substrate but after I've done that then
I can start using irrigation as a tool
to steer growth so once you bring them
to the new substrate then you can apply
the irrigation strategy so for generous
steering you'll want to apply larger
fiims of substrate or larger volumes of
irrigation with less frequency so in an
ebb and flow system this can consist of
flooding higher up the site the block
less frequently in drip this can be
accomplished by applying irrigation
volumes of 6% of the total substrate
size so say I have 1 litre of growing
media I would give it a 6% shot which
would be 60 mils the timing of these
irrigations will dictate the dry back so
if you wish to have to be more
generative you can wait longer to apply
the first year
of the day and you'll stop earlier in
the day today several hours before the
lights go off to to have an increase dry
vac overact this su result in a smaller
more compact plant with a better root
system inside the block if you want to
be more vegetative if you want the
plants to grow faster then you want to
apply a more vegetative strategy this is
a conference using smaller irrigations
each typically three percent or less
than the volume of growing media so
again one liter block I would be
applying a 30 mil shot or less in flood
systems you'd apply irrigations that
just touched the bottom of the block
half inch or less you will stolen to
ensure dry vaccine every night between
irrigations of at least one to two
percent if you have a sensor of water
content sensor that allows you to
measure those and drive X overnight of a
10 to 15 percent so this would mean you
might end up water earlier in the day
all the way throughout the days the
plants gonna tip up take water but
usually you need to wait for the plants
to start to drink before you dare do it
so you do want to let you don't want the
lights to come on and immediately start
applying water because this will slow
down growth so it's called transpiration
before irrigation so once you're able to
see that the plants are up taking water
either just you know about looking at it
or you have a sensor and you can start
applying this first irrigations of the
day this type of irrigation strategy
will result in healthy vigorous fast
growing plants and yeah just did you did
you a faster veg so so how does this
work in practice this chart shows how to
apply vegetative and gendered irrigation
strategy to grow Dan small blocks so
while the maximum wet wait the deep
water content stays the same the dry
weight is almost 100 grams less for
janitor steering the rest time between
is used to steer the plans with long
rest tires between our Dacians for more
vegetative growth while shorter rest
periods steer the plants more vegetative
the EC's of the applied irrigation
solutions are adjusted and used to steer
growth so high DC's creating a more
generative steer while lorry sees more
vegetative climate is also used in
conjunction with with irrigation to
steer the car and it's just important as
a irrigation strategy almost that
so finally that the structures of the
plants have a profound effect on uniform
development plants with different
numbers of leaves and branches will help
take water at different rates I get this
complaint from growers all the time it's
like I have some plans that are really
wet sometimes are really dry you know
some of that's a placement within the
room how much light they're getting a
lot of it has to do with that crop
structure are they even between the
batch so having different numbers of the
leaves and branches despite a great
excessive leaf removal pinching king
tree uptake inconsistencies in the days
calling their applications so when you
do go through and you do remove leaves
you probably have to make an adjustment
to your irrigation strategy in the days
following that those lethal illness
otherwise you're either over the water
along with the plants what's pictured
here is provided by a seed company
selling high-wire cucumbers specifically
this this chart here defines how the
plants should be delete into in relation
to fruit and flower development so as
the fruit is removed a leaf is removed
to keep the plants growing all the same
rate in imbalance so if I'm talking
about a 16 hectare to make that up
cucumber farm I want all those plans to
grow at the same rate back to organize
my labor plan for my harvest so all my
plants have to be exactly the same so in
my opinion heavy deleting and pinching
of cannabis creates a lot of
inconsistencies in the way the plants
grow I'm not saying don't remove your
leaves by nuts
I'm just saying you should look at
different ways of removing them and
maybe keeping it more balanced where as
opposed to doing all those to be things
one day or two days I'm doing it over
the course of several days this keeps
the plants healthy and vigorous they
also keeps you labor labor a little more
happy because by the end of the time at
end of the row they're probably just on
autopilot just dripping leaves and it
can cause damage to the crops so only
through the time and testing only one
day be able to have proven strategies
like like the chart here for cannabis so
very quickly to demonstrate discussing
any significant pinching process can be
on plaintiff element I just won't
discuss some pinchy techniques for
tomato so the single headed tomato plant
this is an unpopped you know it's very
strong it grows very fast you know it's
it's it's not typically done because it
requires a lot of climate steering to
keep the plants to bring to talk too
fast but I think this may be a good
different structure for campus plants is
you know instead of pinching early we
pinch later using pinching as a height
control method but what what needs to
happen is we need to figure out the
exact timing when two spaces bet so a
lot of reasons we can gin canvas is
because we were again we had limited
space for our mothers limited space for
cuttings limited space for fetch so we
weren't able to transplant and space the
veg plants on time so you had to pinch
to create the the side branches but if
you have more space and I can say I'm
going to space my plants one week out to
transplant then I could probably build
out the side and lower lower branches
better than taking off the head
so the
the other one is the tendency to
transplant on the second leave set so
this is this is the most common one for
tomatoes the second piece of the plant
is the head and the second we just
pulled off about 45 days after
transplanting out of cutting this plant
type is ready to transplant about 55
days after you've taken the cut so they
use climate and irrigation to control
the highlights plants so usually you are
keeping the day/night texts even you see
actually manipulating day night
difference of a bigger difference
between day and night the more stretch
out yet so if I want a less stretching
plan I can keep the temperatures even
this also helps with Smita tea control
so instead of dropping the temperature
is and then creating dewpoint I can keep
the temperature even have a higher
humidity a nighttime temperature which
really helps for climate control and
then finally finished on the first set
of truly is this this is for primarily
seeds I would not necessarily recommend
this for cannabis but it's an
interesting it's an interesting crop to
pinch it now you have two headed plant
they're all growing at the exact same
rate and now I've had a lot of control
the truck here sort of shows this when
to apply my things Asia developed arts
like this when do I when do I do my
first pinch when do I space the plants
in bed and then what kind of climate and
irrigation strategies do I need to use
to control the plant type thank you
season so in closing uniformity starts
with mothers cuttings and in the veg
phase consistent initial saturation
irrigation climate help maintain that
uniformity planting densities from
mother's cuttings and the later growth
stages need to be optimized to build the
most uniform crop structures possible
with the least amount of labor and
energy climate and irrigation stirring
should be applied used that everything
at every stage of growth from mothers
cuttings veg and throughout the
flowering cycle and lastly pruning has a
powerful effect on how the plants
develop and is a primary tool for
maintaining uniformity yeah all right
great
so we've got about five minutes for a
couple questions if you've got a
question put your hand up while I'm
getting to you I've got one for you
they're going so you're saying that the
studies said data and having more leaves
when you do your cutting is going to
actually be beneficial for the plant is
there a a high end of that where where
are the plant that we're pulling is too
big and it's going to put too much
pressure on the other root formation
that's the only tested three and four
leaf sets they did not test bigger
plants but not something interesting I
hope to look at that this year and I
have taken longer cuttings I'm sure
people here taking longer cuttings as
well so I think it's something to
explore what is what is the ideal
cannabis cutting length I don't think
anyone's really defined that we have
everybody doing different things until
people have the scientific data I've
done the Charles themselves and if you
probably will verify the variety of
cannabis
did you know the diameter of the Cuddy
on stem diameter no nothing's been done
yet on the stem thing already
I have to see that stuff but I think
makes it would make a difference
obviously you know or you know where
where it comes from the plant they
didn't study where it came from the
plant okay whether top companies or
bottom cuttings were better and they
found that there was really no
difference between the top of the bottom
it's not a question prior pension system
eight oh I dumped into a dozen I wasn't
sure if we be deal with cannabis when
the plant gets a little bit bigger
actually just this one
Yeah right there those are planted down
into the medium to create more freedom
do you think cannabis good I think you
can't do this I think this is for me is
really would make weaker cannabis plants
and know it makes weaker tomato plants
overall that these these plants are more
weak and this is not that the one that's
used anymore I've seen it done on
cannabis it's just I don't think it's
the right way and I think it's either on
top or a late top plant so it's like
because most people are using toffee has
a method for pretty side branches but
also for height control these that I've
let the plant grow on top it's gonna be
a massive plant so it's question do I
top into vet or do I top mid 4 meter
sweet flower second a flower or do i top
at a height so I think that's something
that needs to be explained how can you
use mother's floor before you have to
flow them into flower I mean keep people
to keep you mothers for years but it
seems like after after 3 to 4 months the
the success rates of the cuttings
declines rapidly I mean I think we
really don't know what diseases and
viruses affect cannabis and because it's
such a resilient plant and it's
resistant to so much that you wouldn't
know that there's something wrong with
it
you know I wasn't there so I guess we do
have good morning
so in lesson 9 easy dumps to dismiss
different looks with different lighting
and humidity to adjust their communities
humidity tents so I mean it depends on
what your grow room setup is it's hard
it's hard because we've all designed our
rings around domes and trays you know
for the chrysanthemum farms they have a
tray that hasn't built in kind of
structure that would support a tarp so
do I make a mini hoop overtop of today
can't put it over top of your rack
because now you're catching all that
heat in there and you're gonna melt your
cuttings so you have to figure out a way
to insulate the trays from possibly the
lights below and then maybe just a mini
hoop and then a plastic view over top
just to keep them moisture away from the
leaf tips the last question here when is
it too late to take our take our tops
anymore because we've moved too far in
the flowering process and the hormones
are starting to gather at the top to
form flowers and if we actually take the
cutting at that point we will actually
be impeding future flower which I'm I
taking cuttings are window.top well if
if someone's trying to do this for wave
control acts right that's a good
question I don't know and I think it
depends on the variety because you know
some varieties will stretch a lot more
than others so I think that's it's a
variety dependent thing I think that's
why it's a crop registration is
important because I don't think there's
we've so far seem to be applying the
same strategy to all cannabis plants but
they're all different they're all
significantly different terms of height
development and stretching and how
you know so I think it's it's specific
to variety they're not right now let's
put our hands together for
[Applause]
you