hey everybody and welcome to the 12:30
panel presentation regenerative
cultivation techniques and opportunities
please silence your cellphone's if you
haven't already done so I am shingle
doze hosted the shaping fire podcast if
you like listening to smart interviews
with the top minds in cannabis I invite
you to check out the show at shaping
fire calm we also have an extraordinary
youtube channel with over 150 speaker
videos i've recorded at events just like
this one in fact colin bell one of our
speakers already appears on the channel
several times teaching about various
aspects of microbes and microbiology so
first off we're going to introduce our
panelists starting from the far end
common Bala's co-founder of grow Sencha
and co-inventor of their flagship
product mammoth pea from mammoth
microbes Colin completed his PhD in soil
microbial ecology in 2009 as a research
scientist at Colorado State University
called published dozens of peer-reviewed
publications that were focused on
microbial mediated processes that
enhance plant growth khan left his
academic position in khammam State
University in March 2015 to launch gross
Sencha to his side is Jacob Pulitzer he
is the co-founder and director of
science and strategy of the cannabis
Conservancy a sustainable canvas
standards development and certification
body
Jacob is also the co-founder and board
chair of Southern Earth certified a
regenerative cannabis and help have the
certification non-profit he is a number
of Denver's Department of Public Health
and Environment Canada's systemic
sustainability workgroup and the
National cannabis industry associations
cannabis cultivation committee and to
his right is John Paul maxvill he is the
founder and CEO of waste farmers a
company developing people businesses and
brands who transform emerging and
emerging social environmental needs into
market-based opportunities John Paul
also leads back to 64 a cannabis
cultivation solutions partner that
provides a unified platform for premium
responsibly sourced growing media and
plant nutrition allowing the world's
leading cannabis producers to scale
efficiently and consists of JP is one of
Denver business
stop 40 under 40 so please welcome our
panels so the speakers ask me they want
to make sure that they they design their
answers most appropriate for the room so
in me I'm gonna give you four categories
and if you see yourself in this category
raise your hand if you would if you
would so if you're a cultivator raise
your hand please all right and then if
you are a dispensary owner or employee
all right and then if you are a
manufacturer all right and then other
all right there you go so there's a
general idea guys so so so let's see so
first of all let's get right into it
for this question we're gonna start with
Colin on the far end and then Jacob and
John Paul can jump in so Colin
regenerative cannabis agriculture is
increasing in popularity and importance
and the range of ways to practice it in
commercial cultivation is pretty huge so
what is an example of a regenerative
practice that is easy to get into that
has real benefits within a year you can
hear me okay so thank you everyone for
being here I'm gonna keep it pretty
simple and they keep it with management
ease on the science side regenerate to
replace regenerative cells as biology we
replace ourselves we grow ourselves or
in farming it's about making sure and I
think about this in terms of
sustainability also we're giving more
than we take away that's what I think
about when I think about my generative
practices and as soon as I think about
regenerative agriculture I think about
carbon and carbon is the currency of all
life on Earth and it's definitely the
currency of soil health and the problem
that we have in agriculture in general
agriculture is that we're taking carbon
out of the system as we break it up as
we kill it as we farm it we're losing
soil organic matter of school organic
carbon and that holds everything
for soil fertility nutrient holding
capacity water looking capacity and so
to answer that question what I think
about what I think about regenerative
agriculture has one simple thing that
you can do is think about the carbon how
are you madam or carbon into your soil
it's your substrate then you are taking
away and you can do that through a lot
of different means there's biochar as an
example and I just want to preface that
it's about how you're getting it on the
back end to you know thinking about
where all your inputs are originating
from is a part of regeneration and so
it's a big picture but if you think
about it in terms of how you can
maintain your soil you can add as little
as possible you really have to start
with thinking about the carbon in that
soil and that's a pretty big topic but
that's where I'm going to leave it right
now that's great Jacob same thing to you
so what's an example regenerative
practice that's easy to get into nest
benefits within a year yes I'd say from
a cultivation point of new practices
simple ones mulching you know you're
really trying to build and support the
soil health so that comes with not
having bare soil so mulching is a big
one I'm also like planting beneficial
insect Ares on your edges or in your
feet rose companion planting cover
cropping crop rotation reducing tillage
there's a whole lot of things it depends
on if you're starting where you are but
simple things and kind of also just it's
helpful to take a step back to where you
want to be and then how to do that with
the resources you have on hand
but I guess the goal is to really try to
improve your you know on-site soil
fertility so try to tackle one thing
this plant some concrete put some
chamomile you know different things like
that
that allow you slowly helped either you
know improve your soil quality and a
nutrient content or also reduce your you
know IPM needs I try to tell you know
bring nature into into your grow
and teach online this is question scared
to help me and I'll tell you why
just because talked about and I'm gonna
sound like a permaculture listen
permaculturist tend to sound like
[ __ ] I'm into that like you know
we're talking about you know thinking
about foals and we're talking about
thinking about systems and what we're
talking about now is are the best
practices which is a base layer of
regenerative thinking and so I think the
best return in a year is to start with
you know essence essence is something
that is you know the idea that no two
snowflakes look alike start with essence
of self essence of the property that you
know the place that you're growing and
really good to understand that at a deep
level I think that is the police to
start and the things that we're
discussing nowadays these best practices
are sort of the functional layers of
kind of the one foundational layer of
regenerative as a practice applied to
agriculture right on so for this special
were to start with you Jacob
and then John Paul and then column will
jump in again so since some of the
biggest advantages of regenerative
agriculture takes some time to evolve
right where it's the first question was
just about the first year most of the
cool stuff about regenerative because
five and ten years out since some of the
biggest advantages of regenerative
agriculture take some time we've all
let's talk about the things we can do
for the future but take action now
so Jacob what is a regenerative strategy
or series of techniques that take some
effort now will result in an outsized
advantage down the line yes obviously
thing about this and one its it kind of
come up with like a cultivation strategy
but I'm gonna use this opportunity now
so I guess when cultivation type
bringing genetics have
stick to your site that's going to
thrive in your specific microclimate and
deal with the pest that you have built
up take nutrients and survive you know
the the temperature swings and different
things like that but not everyone is
ready to start doing that so for me you
know seed sharing networks but I want to
kind of talk about supporting farmers
and supporting your workers and you know
creating a healthy positive filling work
environment which comes in from like
you're recruiting giving people
opportunities you know across the
spectrum to you know bring in some more
farmers and promote it but I think if
you're looking at like what's gonna pay
dividends long-term is building that
Network and you know teaching people how
to grow learning sharing knowledge you
know like we're in a situation now
especially if you're a small farmer
you're a homesteader you know there's
big corporations coming and we need to
band together and support each other
it's the only way we're all gonna
survive and I think building those
networks is taking that opportunity and
you know that comes into how do we
compensate or if there's you know
there's financial competition but I
think there's also a lot of other
benefits I would like to see your
generative farmer you should be growing
more than just cannabis you know you
shouldn't be mono copying you should be
supporting CSAs
or at least providing food to your
workers but I think it's providing and
you know that kind of fostering of an
environment of you know respecting the
mutual appreciation you're helping the
farmer farmers helping you or very
cetera and then the community in general
and I think that's what's really gonna
see dividends in the future it's rather
than styling us and thinking like oh I
have a secret sauce this is my IP this
is my you know edge you know we're all
trying to do the same thing when it
comes to regenerative ate path you know
forward and
a little bit and we're all learning from
each other so I think it's kind of
building that context rather than it
specific agricultural thing not great so
John Paul this is a more of a
permaculture timeline question right so
what's something that can be done now
that the benefits will cease its are
significant about five or ten years out
yes so how many of you are going
outdoors of all the cultivators so I
think you know specifically for you I
think on that baseline this soil health
first and foremost and I think soil
health has you know applications to
reduced inputs and and you know lower
input cost but also building soil carbon
and if we're able to develop a market
for carbon the potential for monetizing
ecosystem services monetizing you know
carbon credits and so I think from that
base level so health is number one and
investments you know whether it's show
carbon or microbes and I think you know
the world of microbes were just you know
you understand it you know more than
most of the world but I think we're just
beginning to understand the true
potential and you know but at a very
base level for outdoor growers it's it's
so yeah I really like what everyone's
sharing hearing from the essence on the
first conversation all the way down to
the practices and what I'm hearing is is
honestly it depends on who you are it
depends on where you're growing I think
ultimately farmers and farmers of the
grow organically in any kind of crop
understand you're not growing plant
you're growing soil and soils growing
plants so you've gotta focus on it and
it takes a long time to turn soil from a
degraded soil to a soil that I can
actually can sustain life on its own
minimal inputs and so that time line is
critical and we're talking decades in
some cases in extreme cases and so
that's a big deal I would say on a
broader level do you have plan and do
you have a goal if you don't have the
vision that destination that's where you
have to start you know and it's going to
be different depending on the necess of
your property and where you are
geographically do you have to capture
the water some places you do some places
that's not on them a major priority the
soil is always going to be important the
amount of inputs is always going to be
important your culture on your farm and
the people that you surround yourself
with that's sustainable living as far as
I'm concerned it's choices who do you
want to be around who do one hold it
this life with and so all this thing is
all these details are critical and you
know there's a plan there's a
destination there's a goal you have got
to understand what that is for you and
then you have strategies you have ways
to get there and then you have this
series of tactics that are steps along
your journey to make it happen
regenerative agriculture is and I have
going to do that this year it's like
this is how I'm going to live my life
and you'll always progress year after
year probably for your whole life to
continue to improve those types of
practices so it's a lifestyle and the
more you can turn your crop to a
sustainable level of of regenerative
agriculture you're gonna see benefits
not only economically from how you're
living but the quality of crops that
you're growing improve substantially
they're more organic lifestyles I think
we all know that if we've tried I've
seen some of the end products from that
one that's a great transition I'm going
to pass it down to JP here so because
I'm you know a lot of us have got
regenerative agriculture in our heart
right we want to do the right thing we
want to help the planet we don't want
the runoff from our property to be
causing damage on our neighbor's
properties but at the same time you know
margins are tight in cannabis and and
sometimes regenerative agriculture is
considered to be you know time consuming
and laborious and you gotta buy inputs
and sometimes it's just easier to buy a
bottled something on the shelf and go
with that
right but it's surprising how
financially smart doing regenerative
agriculture can be so so with you we'll
start with you on this one John Paul and
then Jacob and then Colin so to many
folks regenerative practices appear
expensive in the short term in time
labor and sometimes inputs but those of
us are further down the regenerative
path know that regenerative actually
saves money and increases yields both
now and over time so JP please describe
a way that you've seen regenerative
practices directly impact the bottom
line and create increase revenue sure so
you know I think I can apply it I think
to to our own company or a regenerative
company and do work with Carol Sanford
who's a really great thinker on
regenerative as applied to business and
I think you can translate that to
agriculture as well so if you haven't
seen her work I would highly recommend
looking into it but the idea again
starting with essence understanding our
essence as a company which you know
fortunately or unfortunately tendus
tends to stem from the founder depending
on who it is but and then really why
that's important is because in a
marketplace no one you know if essence
is unique and innate no one can copy it
if you understand that then it makes you
you know non-displaced on the market
then it's incinerate
for what we call our stakeholders in
traditional business or say in
agriculture you know it's tended to be
pretty biopic we have a
multi-stakeholder approach where we talk
about our customers are co-creators
which is you know the folks that work
with us and then supply chain community
the earth and then also investors and
how do we add value and you talked about
things in balance I think that another
term in terms of regeneration is
reciprocity in the system and so it
really is is about the critical reason I
pointed to question number one in terms
of like one of these best practices that
we can get to to return in a year is
because there's no best practice that
you can just adopt that you know what
might work for another might you know
not work for you might not work for the
property that you're on and there's an
old saying of like you know you could
take the engine of like a Mercedes and
BMW I don't know what car for BMW and
you know if you took the best pieces of
those and put those together in another
engine it wouldn't work because it's
about the you know it's about the whole
it's about the system and for us
understanding not only our essence but
then the essence of our customers which
is unique rightly so we work with
multi-state operators who want to grow
and want standardized operating
procedures but as you guys know like
every girl is different every room
within a Grove can be different right if
we're talking indoor and so to apply
best practices to that just just doesn't
work and so seeing customers from the
essence of what they want to achieve has
opened up a great deal of you know
ability for us to help make their lives
better and so from a farming perspective
you know again starting with yourself in
terms of the SA
what you want to achieve what the land
is able to achieve and getting to know
your in customers and their lives and
what they want to achieve I think really
helps to improve the value and that
exchange of value that reciprocity
across the system okay so I'm just
telling you said SOP is triggered
something so say for my answer to this
question on where to find you know
returns on this video getting certified
which kind of comes in to documentation
record-keeping writing down what you're
doing for a whole suite of reasons but
one is you know you should be planning
before this season figure out what's
going on in that season what worked with
dinner so that you can refer back to it
and build your own Farmers Almanac but
then also you know to have a genuine
interaction with the consumer consumers
are hungry for buying you know cannabis
have that is you know aligned with their
values you know they now have access to
information they're entitled to
information you know smart consumers we
all want that and they're they're
starting to ask for you know certified
products there is still a lot of
greenwashing in cannabis and so through
son-in and certified and the cannabis
Conservancy they're like you know simply
serve I think that we we work with
district distributors brands buyers for
regenerated farms sustainable farms to
try to guarantee them you know premiums
from their product and you know what I
would like to see is all of the
certifications working together to have
a organic you know certified shelf in
the dispensary and I think that's a big
thing is you know putting her and all
our money where our mouth is but like
opening our grows and with the consumer
you know I was seeing about this the
other day we're a lot like the winery
industry on some level and there
million wines out there and like I like
wine but like I couldn't tell you know
the differences between all these
different you know where those are
something but it's it if I could go to a
winery then I kind of had that
connection so I go to a farm I'm more
likely to have loyalty to that farmer
who want that farm to understand how it
was grown and I think you know having
that connection which the kind of a
certification does but then also you
know it's just different partnerships
that we can have with you know but
tenders in the dispensary of as best as
possible showing the consumer where and
how and who is growing their cannabis I
think is that's what really pays
dividends in with different sheets you
know regenerative farms when every other
farm out there and so so I think what
I've had to it's what's been shared is
you know we're talking about a wood and
we're also talking about this how I
think we've identified that how is
different depending on who you are what
your farm looks like the needs that you
have to get to this what but for me this
is also about a y-you know at the end of
the day we are people and we're all
driven by a why I know I am in
particular that's what we started
organic microbial company from the
University because we're bringing nature
to agriculture and that's what I've been
thinking about for decades
and I realize that my fundamental
scientific training could be applied to
bring value to farmers and help me
realize and live my wife and it's a good
thing you have to prosper
we should be able to live in abundance
as business owners of the growers but it
also and I'll tell you what I think is
the value is our Y you know we can reach
this destination but we live our whole
life in a journey and we'll hit our
goals as people who are trying to get to
a desk
no doubt about it you can walk in a
straight line and get places and our
whole lives are in that walk and if this
is how you want to live your life this
is how you want to manage your farm
that's way more valuable then maybe
getting as a extreme example a little
more yield buy porn a bunch of salt and
not given a difference you know this
means things to people and the mean
stuff to you and enriches your life and
at the end of the day you're not going
to think about that extra pound per crop
that you developed by using the salt
you're gonna think about how you live
your life the way you wanted to live
your life and you developed your farm
and you built your soil and it meant
something and it's there after you're
gone and honestly that's what we should
be doing focusing on a why and for me
this topic is all about the what you
know and it means something and it
drives us all up on this stage I'm sure
it drives a lot of you in that audience
also you know if it's not or why it's
not it requires extra work it requires a
whole different level of Management and
it's a different lifestyle for many many
people they wouldn't have it any other
way
you know I'd deal with them all the time
and I love it and so it's a choice
there's trade-offs
there's no perfection but the value can
go way beyond that extra whatever if
you're talking about money you know
you're talking with the wrong guy to
care less about a dollar I care about
the well in my life and I care about a
why that I have and we're allowed to
have one more why but this is a big one
and it's a special thing to follow and I
think it's more gratifying and more
rewarding than anything I'll ever look
at how bank account
and that doesn't mean you have to
sacrifice the other it's just a trade us
but you want to look at as a business
also
so I grieve that the so one of the
things that you didn't mention my my
grandfather was nominated as the
agricultural citizen in the century in
Wyoming and a lot of the things that he
could help pioneer were some of the
things we're trying to move beyond with
regard to regenerative AG and the reason
that I'm sort harping on this idea of
like you can't you know take best
practices and apply it without some
understanding of like a baseline the
essence right because that's what
industrial agriculture was it was really
like how do we take this method of what
we're doing and apply it across any
landscape will flap it will remove trees
will do all those things and where we're
living with the repercussions of that
right but for farmers and you know one
of the things you mentioned a challenge
with these things right with
regenerative organic and their standards
and typically with consumer advances
that we're putting the risk of these
things on the most vulnerable right
which is the farmer and that that's a
challenge but I think part of in terms
of the long-term horizon from my
perspective we have undervalued assets
and those undervalued assets are our
land that we have sort of looked at
really extracted like what what can we
take out of it but where we are with
climate right and what we need to do to
slow or maintain a climate that is
habitable for people is remove carbon
from the atmosphere that's a six
trillion dollar opportunity
right it's a while hemp and cannabis
might seem like a huge market it pales
in comparison to the market of what
carbon will be and so in terms of you
know how that frames how you manage
today for tomorrow I firmly believe that
the value of carbon in the next decade
hopefully sooner will be realized and
the practices and these regenerative
practices will be something that you
know returns the balance back to two
farmers and so you know I think that you
know the only way to change the system
that's sort of within a system and so
you know the system of the goddess is
capitalist and the system we got is you
know what we're dealing with today but I
think there's a huge opportunity and
there's six trillion dollar opportunity
to manage or that's a port word but to
bring systems back into balance and I
think the value of carbon in the soil is
going to be an enormous enormous
opportunity and I think farmers are
positioned very well who start working
towards that a day to to benefit from
that and in so doing benefit the people
they work with benefit the communities
where they grow community you know
benefit the ecosystem and so forth so so
one thing I want to add to that is so so
you're in the room and your think about
going into regenerative agriculture and
and like none of the three guys really
said you're gonna make more money so let
me be that person what we're finding is
with regenerative agriculture is when
you use it you're creating higher
yielding plants you spend a month less
money fighting pests because the plants
are stronger and they take care of the
pest resistance themselves you get a
marketing advantage because people want
to buy products that are aligned with
their value the quat the the value of
your property increases because you're
not dumping sulfates nutrients on it
and like colin was saying when he
brought brought out his boss for
scientists you just feel better about
life so if you're talking with your
business partners and you've got to
convince them to go regenerative there
is lots of evidence out there that shows
that you can actually make more money
going with regenerative techniques than
you can by using other techniques
alright so with that we're gonna move on
so so we're doing well on time and so
we're gonna ask you guys one more
questions that I didn't let you know
about in advance and we will have time
for questions so after this question I
will come out to you so so you know kind
of get your question in your head we'll
have a good ten minutes for it so so
guys you know one of the things that's
interesting about regenerative is is how
we have to balance the competitiveness
because we need to make sure that we're
in the market and we can sell our
products but at the same time we're not
competitive because we're all trying to
make regenerative cannabis agriculture a
thing right we want there to be more of
it both for just you know the quality of
cannabis and human life but but but also
because we want it to replace you know
traditional industrial agricultural
practices which could totally take over
a cannabis if we regenerative people
don't do something about it right so
here's my question that I'm Nessen we'll
start with JP and head down the line
there so in trying to balance the
competitiveness because we want to make
sure our products are sold but also we
also need to work together in community
as regenerative folk and family right
give one example that people can use to
you know create some kind of partnership
or community with their people who have
other farmers who are essentially their
competitors in the marketplace but
actually are all part of that
regenerative family sure so I think you
know I think you might have similar
experiences there like both of you but
like I think the canvas industry is it's
one where there is this notion of like
protecting
nation and it doesn't exist in other you
know sectors of Agriculture to the
extent that that it does in cannabis I
think what you're missing is a knowledge
share right and also just support
because if the truth is like this is its
heart and you know the people that can
understand best how hard it is or the
people doing it and so on an emotional
level it's beneficial right but then
there are you know lessons there are
bits of knowledge that can that can be
shared and you know we're we were
talking about sort of putting together
like a group of cultivators to just get
together not trying to sell [ __ ] but
just get together and just talk and
share it and because I think a lot of
growers feel pretty isolated this but we
understand and that's it that's a shame
because what that leads to is really
great people decided not to continue
forward right and so I think there needs
to be more and I think there's a dearth
of you know community beyond sort of
surface service level and I know you
know from a CEO perspective which is you
know pretty much most cultivators are
sort of the CEO it's a very isolating
you know activity you're sort of you
know solo and I think that a community
of people who can understand and go
beyond just empathy but sort of really
understand it is beneficial so there's
not a lot of it I think there is there
needs to be more with it I think getting
back to essence I think the essence
discussion removes this notion of
competitiveness
and what is really a neoliberal myth I
think is like the basis of essence is
like you can't be me right I can't be
you and depending on what you believe
right like we're we right whatever but
like that essence aspect is is critical
because if you understand that and you
stay true to it then you have no fear of
somebody you know there's no competition
in that respect so that's why I think
essence in this discussion of
regeneration is a very very critical
point to understand
thanks JP so Jacob you mentioned one
earlier that I really like which is the
regional seed swapping group right so
that's a that's a great idea what would
tell one thing is cuz like regenerate
it's like we're building this movement
and what we're seeing a lot and a little
bit in Colorado a lot in Northern
California we do a lot of her work out
there is being a regenerative farmer
abiding by these practices you know
working towards that has formed
partnerships with others similar like my
did you know social subscribing
individuals were in the distribution
manufacturing ranks where we are having
farmers now that are pre selling their
product for their ever harvest the end
there's takes a huge relief off of them
because they know that it's going to
have either the bagged appeal the
terpene profile you for me girls are
gonna be huge
I hope so coming up you know so it's
tough losing these you know kind of
arbitrary strain names that we'd be
giving you and really go into what the
turkey profile is so you know the
effects they're gonna have on us but
that's one that's another thing but I'm
having that but then I'm having the
quality that they know that you know
especially manufacturers you know so
they're coming down to the farms and
they're you know harvesting all of the
odds were bucking it right down there
you know and then taking it away and
paying for all that and the farmers just
gets us you know set them out right
there per pound that's a huge relief so
they don't have to worry about you know
the drying the curing all of that space
on-site we're also seeing you know
valleys and different
sheds where the cultivation of climates
are very similar are coming together and
you know sharing barn space big thing is
sharing harvesting you know
opportunities not everyone's gonna
harvest the exact same times instead of
having to hire another place you can
share you know there and really kind of
like the whole barn raising mentality of
back in the day easily translates into
you know into cannabis but then I think
a big part of that is also just having
those connections within the farmer
community to kind of know what's on the
back you know Mother Nature throws stuff
at us every single day it's really
helpful here's someone you know 20 miles
south like hey strips are coming through
you know we have this rustic way and
this is what I've done over the last 20
years - that works you know and so we're
not trying things on our own and taking
a salesman's word for it but we've got
farmers who've actually do it and you
know it's succeeding with one of the new
things I've been seeing is farmers -
companion planting with a can of meal
and are swearing that they're getting
boosted to see percentages and that
they're about to even better for making
you know hash and concentrate since they
get used thanks camomile so going cameo
like interspersed in the beds you know
but there's like some you know
particular strategies with it but I read
it from 10 farms in sugar you know that
they're like yeah it's working a piece
you know I like when those things are
like I feel pretty confident telling you
guys and you should check it out like
you know I haven't read any bad things
from it you know it might affect your
watering shutter use a little bit if you
really you know really dialed it in on
your trip I want to think about that but
like things like that rather than just
hearing it or reading about it you know
on social media or something about
having those farmers that are growing in
the same microclimate that you are at
what's working and what is in it yeah I
really love what everyone shared and I
think about the same things I think
about collaborative thing about behind
share
you know co-op is one of the things
that's a big word in in NorCal or
sun-grown cooperatives where people are
actually banding together
to take a distribution in hell it's more
of the distribution space in the
Northern California market where you
know if you're very armed for craft
farmers to out-compete everybody it's
just not realistic you have so much more
control of your channel if you're
working together at least in the state
of their companies you know and I think
about it from the micro to a perspective
and atlas product you know everyone
asked what I can competitors I go what
competitors the other companies that are
making microbes that I love and this
movement and this value and that's why
they're doing the same thing you're not
my competitors they're not allies
I'll sell their products right along
with mine and I want to encourage people
to use those products along with mine
they're ones like huh that's a little
different it's the power of a why you
know legitimate a farmer's syndrome
farmers all these concepts work well
together and if you collaborate
community line share it works it doesn't
have to be a fear-based competition and
honestly talk about the high high tide
rises all ships it's just true and it
starts with that that collaboration and
community in my opinion that's fantastic
all right so we got about 10 minutes for
questions
[Applause]
about ten minutes for questions I want
to let the three of you know that each
of you are invited to respond but don't
feel like you have to jump on a question
that you know you don't really have
anything on and we'll just move along
but but if all three of you want to get
on a question you know don't hesitate
Shango thanks guys
not all of us armours have filled in
soil that we can work with some of us
really want to bring on that
regenerative mindset to the way we do
things maybe in a greenhouse in
containers or in indoor spaces and can
you speak on some regenerative practices
for folks or in those situations
exciting as we all start getting a right
to grow a lot of us have been able to
grow in our backyards or in our house
and our tents and so what our solution
into the practices that we can do to be
in line with that kind of philosophy and
thinking
so if I'm like any door bro environment
or Jenna's a lid and soil if you can and
start to go in there and even if you're
growing in pots use that soil finest
phase compost it and get soil test so
it's a certain huge yeah so therefore
you're not guessing but you can really
dial in precisely how much nutrients
that soil needs and we're do you know
how to apply it when to apply it and
that's gonna gonna you know change a bit
and I think confidence we thought we
thought of that but like when it comes
like that BK stuff and and what we need
and you know this my biology but I think
also man enduro is as we do a lot of
sustainability for indoor grows is
looking at your like energy water and
waste streams and how he gives as simple
as how are you sourcing or products you
know if you can buy super sex and use
them by that rather than you know
plastic palletized you know bags of soil
and reduce your waste they're actually
measure what your waste is every week
and and what are you looking at what's
compostable what's you know plastics
recyclables and then what's just gonna
be soluble useful ways it's gonna go to
landfill and how you do it and what is
it I mean there's always gonna be gloves
you know you can't really get away from
that but kind of you don't really
fine-tune it and then your lighting
systems you know really look at your
ppfd and you know can you afford to get
new lights look at the lighting
efficiency of that so I'm like almost
per tool you really want I would say 1.9
or above so LEDs even double-ended and
it's just how much of the Energy's using
is going to be turned into usable light
and then look at your distribution of
your legs and try to you know have as
much biggest spacing as possible of
those lights you can reduce your lights
their time of day use and staggering of
rooms I mean all of those combined can
save you 20 to 30 percent of your
lighting which Fernando bro could be you
know forty fifty percent of your total
row cost so there are a lot of things
there but it's like using data to help
inform your decisions and really
tracking what that is
all right okay
yes so we're talking about soil not
planet through our products and in in
natural products out there that you can
probably mitigate a lot of that you know
I think there's composting techniques
depending on the point without where you
can get rid of my eggs probably burn out
through the heat of the composting a lot
of those insects it's a process though
to be clear you there's there's time
there's resources or a space and to
actually do that that you can do it and
so I would say also on the front end you
could improve or at least try to
identify your your sources of potential
contamination or her infection and work
on those processes so you don't invite
those messing whether they come in on
your clothes when they come in on your
soil identify that because you know once
you got em you got a minute and and
pests and pest pressures everywhere
that's nature you know there's no such
thing as no pressure
there's just levels of it and so it's a
probability game and you're playing the
probability getting there so yeah you
can treat everything you once you have
something you might always have a level
of it you want to keep it low enough
that you can manage and so thinking
about your front-end processes you know
people not only spores covering them but
you
Leyton potentially as soon as you grow
so forget the blush and so we have to
just look at battle that at how we're
managing well so I think one thing is
farmers are notorious for not valuing
their time and so what I would say is
you know this is like a DC front like
it's easy for me like you know we have
quality analytics that we deliver with
every batch of soil because we're
testing and we are testing those things
so you know exactly what comes into your
Grove because we know the impact that
pests can have you know and and how
important it is to have really good
understanding what's coming in on the
front end and so from my perspective
this is part of the reason why we exist
I think it's you know who you're working
with and the co-creators are the
suppliers that are supplying you goods
we shipped directly to growers for that
reason because we can manage the supply
chain and we know exactly you know it
came from our door and then to your door
we know you know the analytics when it
left our facility and arrived at your
door and so I think that's pretty
grateful and that's why we exist I would
say a couple things to think about the
media situation with the mics and all
that would be solarization is one thing
recovery in thick plastic you know
letting it really heat up predatory
mites and it potentially planting trap
plants in there depending on the mic so
plants the mites are gonna love that you
can then remove and take them off site
or just some ideas but things ever ties
into the whole regenerate thing is that
we're trying to create ecosystem to
mimic nature within our grossman each
it's going to work for us and nature
abhors a vacuum so if you have a really
well balanced ecosystem you're gonna
have mites but they'll never get to like
you know population explosion to where
they're going to be
huge problem you know they're really
gonna target your wheat plants which is
kind of nature indicating a plant
doesn't need to be here anyways and so
instead of using a lot of pesticides
over you know plants a little ten
percent more and then thin it out as
needed and just do that and then breed
of what you're really seeing on your
property all these plants are feeling it
right now or they're mic resistant never
had an issue this is genetics we want to
you know keep going so just somebody
else right got time for one last
question
how you doing this question is to
mammoth it's off the first time for just
get my first girl who September so I've
talked to you on the internet about
seeing somebody that was using your name
trying to make something but found out I
looked at the scene that the number was
on his hand see that it said man we
finished found you so sorry this company
must be somebody that there that's
worthy of the name last money would be
still in it I said you must be fainted
but my question is now using your
product by using product and my first
grow these said that your product keep
edge when I went to the Hydra story so
now my question is when using your
product is that something that I can use
when I build in Richmond of like when
I'm watering could I put it on my water
process for do I use it like what's the
weekly what's the timeframe that I
should be using a product first of all
congratulations glad you're getting the
grown thanks a lot yeah I have a lot of
imposters on it sorry about that
and yeah you know it's its nature its
nature in a bottle with precision
functionality yes you have a lot of
flexibility I want you to think about
the performance and the economics you
can use a continuous a lot of grossly
read results it's a point six mil for
gallon using it twice a week in your
feed if you have big if you have big V
tanks you could add in there and
then through the week there's so much
rain go ahead sorry no is that made the
point six four - ah destroy Balu yeah
that's a great question so across the
board at early on I used to have
different regimes for a soil versus
hydroponics through hydroponics and what
we realize is with regular applications
the data seems so similar with the
quality brings more results won't cause
an issue it's just a diminishing return
you're gonna find that balance where
you're not going to get deference for
every by that but the actual ad isn't so
you want to have that point where you
continue to see that increase with
increased application and once you find
that the linked okay that's where you're
gonna get it I'm happy to talk with you
offline on that too and we have to hook
you for the team as well since you've
got access to the real Colin and not one
of his online at a Thursday I'm so so so
thank you all for being here let's thank
our guests Colin Val
Jacob Pulitzer and John Paul Maxfield
thank you very much
if you want to see this presentation
again or if you want to show it to
friends or business partners it'll be on
the shaping fire YouTube page in about
two weeks so thank y'all for being here
you