so thank you for spending some time with
us today it was beautiful to see the
farm you know one of the reasons why I
wanted to come over and visit you Nick
was because you know you do something
that I haven't seen done much at all but
especially in commercial cannabis and
that is you do a lot of inner planting
right you do you do inter plant in where
there's the cannabis plants and then
plants that are around it but then also
you also do companion planting which I
would think is a different thing you
know plants that are doing a job right
attracting pests or or something like
that and you know most commercial
cannabis farms you get grids its
monoculture and and yours look
significantly different than that so so
tell me a little bit about the
experience that you've got with with not
using a monoculture and instead doing
tons of inter planting yeah so I would
say I've gone through some evolution of
like growing more from market style kind
of situations and that so I have done
like more like this is for managing for
easy harvest and this is for that but my
evolution has always been further
towards nature and that you know I spend
a lot of time out and about in the world
on foot and then living by fire and
under a tarp and and walking around the
woods and the canyons and paddling lakes
and oceans and so like I had this
imprinted in me all these natural spaces
and Ecology's that were really dynamic
and and never fragmented in straight
lines and so you know as I realized I
wanted to learn more about taking care
of food and and growing plants and
feeding myself from the land and that
way instead of the hunting and fishing
and walking the land I started it I just
like we started to inner plant like what
we were seeing
and then recognizing the benefits of
different plants and what they do and
starting to learn more about how plants
are interacting with their ecological
role what is that ecological role and
and so yeah you know that the foundation
that diversity all those different
plants are playing different roles at
different times of the year based on the
climate you're in you're gonna develop
your own spectrum of diversity and
complexity your matrix to whatever
degree you want because at the more
complex it is the the more intelligent
it is and so you know there's definitely
a lot of information so you can research
what different plants are doing but
there's needs to be more spent time
spent outside observing and and
interacting with plants without
necessarily having to understand them
completely but rather open up to
listening to the plant and see what a
good information it brings to you and
not that's where I feel like you know
the the relationship to the garden
becomes this listening this place of
listening and then interacting and
always trying to honor that space to
give back to it and to hold it in this
sacred manner that it's taking care of
you and not approach it with this idea
that I just want to get this one crop
out of here and it's going to this
market and I don't regardless I'm I just
want to figure out how to grow that one
well you know and it's I don't think you
know I don't think that's a very healthy
relationship it seems very like we're
taking too much from the space and so
what also happens in that case where you
take so much biomass from a place all at
once is you take stuff from it and so if
there's nothing else there to recover or
to feed the system you deplete it very
quickly and so modern agriculture is
depleting soils very rapidly which is
why there's such a kind of like
everybody is going and remineralizing
Andrea mending and all these things
because of this fear that it's not going
to be enough
and then they're also cropping the place
harder than maybe it can create so the
bringing things into a regenerative
place in requires bringing the
perennials into the garden and allowing
a root system of greater depth and
complexity that remains in the ground
all year to be there as the carbon sink
for the water to store and for more
growth to occur in that space it's it's
interesting because you've already
started harvesting for this year and and
your rows that you've already harvested
it looks like your garden is still full
because of all of the additional
planting and and I like your idea that
you know even after you've removed all
the cannabis biomass your garden is
still full and alive whereas in a mono
crop you remove all the biomass and
you've just got a you know bare place
right your garden is going to be very
much alive all winter long even even
once the once the plants have left
now this particular farming spot you've
only been here for about three years so
you you are you're helping you know
build and and you know help help give
that give a lance more personality and
bring it back to how it was before they
put up all these the this this timber
did you choose plants for the inter
planting and companion planting
intentionally because they were
indigenous to this area or because you
knew that they were positive companion
plants for cannabis or both both and I
would say in the development of the
garden I look at what's already there
and what plants are already there and I
I do my best to make sure that all those
plants are kind of like that I have some
level of care and and that I like those
plants you know like we don't want to
engage in the design of our space and
always point out what's not working so I
like to approach a new space regardless
of if it's been abused or if it's a
thriving grass or if
it's this and honor it for what it is
and how great that is and to try and
figure out how to partner with that
space to encourage that biological
because everywhere on the earth there's
biology that exists and even in less
productive places it's there to some
extent so really what we should be
trying to do is encouraging the
evolution of that biology to become more
and so establishing garden should be you
know more about aligning ourselves with
the culture of microbiology and ecology
of the place that it is and less
invasive action and less machine use and
less straight lines and more integrated
poly culture that incorporates some of
the things that are naturally there to
begin with as well as introduce things
that are really good at recovering
minerals and are have really extensive
root systems that are good at catching
excess nutrients that might be in the
beds where you're putting a lot of your
manures and your waste your your carbon
and mulches and so you know setting up
your guild and in in relation to a
hillside you know the downhill side is
where the nutrients leach and say you
want a recovery crop on the downhill
side so that when you do water if you
water you know usually on a hillside you
have to water in in this climate and and
when you do you whenever you put water
out there you want to make sure that if
you're putting a certain amount you want
all that water to be used the most
efficiently that it can so you want the
most extensive root system that can
recover those nutrients into biomass
which is the plant matter itself and
then that plant matter becomes the
biomass that feeds the soil again and
the more you care and maybe utilize
those crops to become biomass for the
microbiology the more that crop will
start to grow even more vigorously and
and I find this a lot especially with
like comfrey and these kinds of if you
let the crop just grow or if you let the
comfrey just grow and don't cut it and
use the
you'll see that it stalls out and flower
and it doesn't get any bigger but if you
use the biomass and cut it it the root
system grows more the plant grows bigger
and so our comfrey start to become
bigger and bigger and we've got monster
comfrey yeah yeah and that's you know
that's the the goal is to over grow your
garden space with biomass and then you
utilize the biomass that's in excess or
you manage the strongly competitive
varieties of weed species and use those
as bio biomass recovery so their root
systems are now valuable the bind weeds
the star thistles the things that people
don't want are all contributing in a
really good way to complexify aback by
ology so we shouldn't just be focused on
the crops we want to grow we need to
take into account the bigger ecological
picture so on the on the flip of that
though there are some crops that we do
want to grow and one of the things that
I thought was pretty cool it was that
you've got all of this food intermixed
with the cannabis plant so you've got
you know you've got your your comfrey
and you're thistles and your things that
you're probably not gonna do much with
but then you also got you know potatoes
and apples and and I think rutabaga you
had and so so tell us a little bit about
that about what you're pulling from the
garden that's both providing your income
through the cannabis but also feeding
you yeah a lot of it can feed us and a
lot of it that even can feed us we let
feed the garden too so a lot of our
crops are our crops that we eat you know
we grow thousands of pounds of potatoes
but they're also there for other
purposes so like we we use that crop in
particular to keep the rodents really
well fed and we've had zero issues with
any kind of rodents even though we have
tons of rodents in there so we have
you're just giving them something better
than cannabis talk you're you're super
charging the ground with lots of
nourishment and whether that starch gets
consumed by a person or by an arthropod
you know and the the more it stays in
that space the kind of more regenerative
the crop becomes so it's like every time
something leaves
a space it enters a the realm of
becoming energy-intensive so you have to
carry it somewhere and then you have to
drive it somewhere and then you have to
sell it and then somebody drives it to a
fridge that's turned on to ya story you
know but we're we're trying to move in
this direction of naturalizing systems
creating abundance it's always in the
ground and teaching people how to
establish those things around them so
that they can go outside and identify
the food and utilize it when they need
it and that it doesn't have to be as
much go to the market as it is to you
know understand what's growing around
you and participate in that process yeah
they they do this every day sometimes
it's triggered by an arrival sometimes
it's triggered by dogs barking it's hard
to say for sure they're pretty crazy
right on I got one more question for you
before before I let you get back to the
harvest which is exactly that right you
know a lot of a lot of the farms that I
tour not only are they on grids but
they're they're set up to be easily
mechanically harvested right they've got
they've got easy to walk rows and and
you know they've got areas that you can
pull the sled down and then chop and
drop and all that and and yours is like
the antithesis of that right here you
know your rows are a little bit like
this and they get wider and thinner and
and you know you've got you've got all
this companion planting right and so you
might have to like dig out the stem to
get to it you know to cut and and I you
know I can imagine a lot of these guys
that I've talked to who all they want to
talk about is scalability down in the
valley right you know we've got we've
got 40 acres of hydroponic greenhouse or
you know these these these types of
things where everything's super
mechanized you're
opposite so can you say a little bit
about your process and what I'm what I'm
looking for is you're not mechanized and
yet I just saw your your curing room
filled with plants everything looks
perfect and and and you know uniform
enough you know yeah how essentially how
are you doing that coming from what
looks to an outsider has a disorganized
garden but which is incredibly abundant
yeah yeah you know I think we in the art
of scaling like you can own you can't
scale craft beyond a certain point craft
to me craft cannabis or artisan cannabis
is something that stops at a pretty
small scale and so you know the the
mechanized piece only takes you further
down the path of commercial cannabis or
you know corporate cannabis and as we've
evolved we've played with the machines
we've played with the big Leafers and
and doing that and what that did and we
just haven't liked it you know it feels
abusive to an extent to the bud and it
feels like it's just losing a certain
level of sacredness and you know now we
do all the big leafing on the live
plants and prep really well for big
chunks of harvest to come in and that is
really helped us so we big leaf and then
we spend one day bringing lots in at
once we do a good job taking care of
those plants before its time and and so
the system's really good it and it only
takes like four people to kind of do the
whole thing efficiently we we might use
up to six or seven here and there when
things get tight in terms of weather or
some kind of component like that but but
yeah really it's for us it's we went
that direction and we just start going
further back the other direction more by
hand outgrowing what we can even dry
and then just only taking the
highest-quality into the to the shop and
then knowing that some is gonna end up
feeding the soil for next year yeah
that's that's not a bit bad at all you
know you grow a hundred percent of your
plants you you take the top fifty to
seventy-five percent and then the last
twenty five percent you just let drop
right there and now it's got all of the
nutrients that you know next to your
needs yeah and it's a really nice to
start that in the fall cut all the
branches and make little piles of
branches and bury those with mulch for
the winter and you create these little
pockets of of underground homes and so
you get a lot of underground biology
that lasts way longer and more places
for things to hunt and more places for
things to lay eggs and really focusing
on creating that habitat for the
evolution of the biology they become
more complex means continually layering
different sized chunks and branches and
layers of hay and manure in the spring
and and it just keeps getting better and
better and better so to a certain degree
your entire garden is like one big
google cuz everything just drops and
rots on top of each other season after
season and you know it was pretty
remarkable actually when you know you
actually pulled up the hay often so
you're you pulled it up at potatoes and
hold it up oh here's some you know cool
bugs and then but then the one time you
pulled it up and you bought brought up
some of the soil and it was I mean it
looks decadent right yeah and and and
and if I understand what you said
correctly you really only bring in hay
from elsewhere everything else is is
sourced from here on on your acreage do
you feel like you're you're missing out
with anything no no your mind everything
you need on the property I mean so the
we take care of animals and so animals
have some inputs and so our inputs that
come onto the farm always go through the
animals so we take care of the animals
so if if there's we're not getting them
out into the forest around pasture as
much because we're managing
it's business in this new place and all
this and we want to use them more in the
woods but we can't we'll bring them
minerals that they need if we can't get
them into the space where they can
acquire them for themselves
so you know our inputs are hay and
whatever the animals kind of need which
is just some minerals there's a really
good salts that for animals that are
important so so the important thing is
is that the process of the production is
surrounding the the biological breakdown
of anything that's coming into the
garden so anything that comes here goes
through a lot of biology before the
plants get any use out of it and so
that's how we think about everything and
then we think about our garden beds as
the digestion chambers for it all so we
don't do any you know like teas and we
don't do fermenting and we don't have
recipes for anything we just make sure
that we mulch really well that and have
a lot of home and diversity and space
and habitat for the biology to really
express its potential in that raizo
sphere and then that brings all the
wildlife and it really does increase and
stimulate the health of the whole area
the garden becomes this like birthing
point for all kinds of animals and the
return of different kinds of species of
snakes that we'd never seen here show up
on year three and you know so it's like
it keeps bringing the wildlife and the
deer get in there and it's all good you
know and it's so diverse that nothing
can really do too much damage to any one
thing so and it certainly helps with
with the balance sheet since you're also
running a company right you mean you're
saving a lot of money on inputs that
other people are putting in and your
flowers actually look better so you know
it's it's it's you know you might as
well save where you can especially since
you're in Oregon and the prices are here
so rock-bottom yeah and the bonus if
you're actually if you are actually a
small farm
and you know like just a cult a couple
people taking care because it's my wife
and I and and you know having animals
really helps because now when you do
spend money on the inputs you're also
creating food systems and you're
creating other benefits and so you're
getting a lot more bang for your buck
when you're running it through a herd
scenario where then you're able to make
all your own fertility or at least
enhance your fertility to a great degree
but the end goal really in a garden
becomes that the garden has enough
energy minerals and everything it needs
that just with simple human relationship
to all that biomass it doesn't need
anymore things to come to it so you try
to establish a certain level of
fertility and then if your system is
regenerative enough it never lets any
minerals or nutrients leach out of it
and so it recovers all of the important
stuff and makes it available later and
so your job becomes making the space for
the things you want to do better and
that's the real art of regenerative
agriculture is growing all your own
biomass to have a certain level of
carbon content in your soil so that the
production and the health is is high and
a big part of that is just having that
diverse habitat and allowing the voles
and the moles and the Gophers and the
snakes and the you know the things that
we're normally taught to be afraid of be
the things that are actually making the
spaces productive as it is that's the
shift we are all you know that we
believe in the most is that though we
can partner with all those components as
long as we take care of them in the your
you're living life forms are palpable
right you know we walk the garden and
unlike a lot of monocultures where it's
just plant plant by plant because you've
got all this other stuff you can feel it
the the the the bees and the wasps and
the little beetles I don't know what
their names are and then the garter
snake and they
you know you can you can you can feel
that you're in a living area instead of
a sterile area and you know it feels
good on my human yeah it feels good to
be in the garden yeah and that can only
benefit up up the plants plus you go
right into the soil right you're not in
bags and so underneath all your plants
are talking to each other
yeah and that's gotta help intertwine
with a diverse number of different kinds
of plants and we watch the relationships
of root systems working with each other
and there's some that take over nutrient
availability there's some that work in
opposition to let other plants grow and
it's not really this thing about being
mad at them or saying one is good or bad
it's just about understanding what's
going on and making the right choices
and putting the right things in the
right spaces and understanding the
relationship so you can manage them to
the least amount of like destructive
ways possible because that's the goal
you know is to be enhancing the
environment not destroying it yeah well
thank you so much for the tour thanks
for hosting us over here on your farm
that's been great to me so much for
coming in and really appreciate it right
on cool and the opportunity for this
platform that you have so thank you for
sharing your experience all right
you