all right cool so real thank you so much
for having us on the farm today you know
the property is so beautiful and you
know as everybody can see you know
you're on a mountaintop with 360 degree
views what a great place to make a farm
yeah and yet when you got here it was
not in good shape you know old forested
property with lots of heavy machinery
and yet you breathed life into it so so
let's start there what is it that you
did to help restore and regenerate the
soil on the property
yeah the areas that we were farming had
been gone had been logged and I've been
degraded by big machinery like you said
so they were hard pack so the soil was
really like dried out when you kind of
runt when you run machine over and
destroy all the biology in an area and
then it becomes hard the soil pores
closed down it doesn't absorb water and
so how to bring that that from that
state back into a biological state I
mean you really need to sink carbon and
you really need to sink biology back
into the dirt so first is we designated
our AG zones and we started digging
trenches not deep trenches but like 2 3
feet in some areas some areas of where
it was much more stable deeper and we
started burying our forestry products
are our forestry thinnings from wildfire
protection back into that those degraded
areas and then we would layer the hard
pack with compost with forests thinnings
with woodchips with any kind of
biological with any kind of plant but
you can find right and develop these
lasagna layers which now are like you
know quite deep and spongy and absorb
water and really like I like the idea
that you know obviously there's wildfire
issue here but it just seems rather
intuitive to be able to use all of the
the forest stuff and the tree fall and
all this to put it to good use
rebuilding the soil in the same
bioregion which also then increases the
safety of the farm itself and and your
neighbors honestly I mean in
permaculture stacking functions and so I
wouldn't I wasn't even thinking this way
years ago and you know I would import or
buy soil from the trucks and plastic
bags and they'd have to be shipped in
harvested keep my hogs where it's like
totally not sustainable practices and
the more I learned the more I realized
that all the resources I need to grow
amazing products and cannabis on my farm
are already here it's like biological
diversity in a forest with IMO's you
know indigenous microorganisms with Ray
Niall chips with the different you
shaniyah hanging from the oak leaves the
herbs the fungus the grasses it's all
already existing and that diversity is
the strength of a system a biological
system so just kind of mimicking my 72
acres in my garden areas and trying to
mimic the productivity of a forest
system I love the fact too that you
didn't bring in all of the soil products
you know we talk a lot on shaping fire
about bio regionalism of microorganisms
right so you might have a microbe from
Alaska that's used to an entirely
different environment so it does great
in Alaska but it doesn't do great here
right but by by wildcrafting your inputs
here on your property you're really just
moving the microbes around on your
property and so they're they're used to
thriving in in your environment and so
you don't have to like move all this
biology here have it crash and then
rebuild it you're you're skipping you
know that die-off step by using all of
your own forested stuff for I mean for
instance like we do the forest thing
then we would chip and we collect those
wood chips and we line all our paths
with the wood chips and and then over
winter the mike
organisms that were already in this area
are growing in our paths and so when we
brew a tea now we just go on our paths
and we dig up the white molds and and
the microorganisms in those paths and
just add it to the tea and it's changes
the smell of the tea it really like it
adds a lot of strength to the systems
that are already in place what a great
thing to be able to do I mean like I
make I brew tea too but you know I'm
using this person or that person's blend
right which I purchased which you know
since you know I live on Vashon Island
but you know I live really close to
Seattle so it's kind of rural City right
but you're very much out here and so
you're being able to target the specific
microbes you want just by producing them
on the island and then using the brewing
of the tea to essentially super
concentrate them and then feed them back
to themselves I love that I don't know
I'm not a scientist but I just by
experience it's working really well well
from the plants that I mean we're early
in the season here but the plants that I
saw we're already jumping ahead that you
know nobody was looked like they were
shocked at all from being transplanted
everybody's like you know up and going
appropriately for this time of year one
of the things that I found interesting
was you know I'll - are some farms and
they'll use you know some wood chip
mulch or or they might have a Google or
more but you have deployed wood and
parts of tree like everywhere it is
clearly the the number one input that
I've experienced from touring today and
I would think that that has to do with -
for two reasons number one you live in a
forest and so it's a resource you've got
a lot of but also you talked a lot about
preserving water here and and so you
really seem to be using that wood for
it's it's it's it's sponge capabilities
why do you tell us a little bit about
that because water is clearly so dire
here yeah I mean just like I was saying
it's a can the earth absorb rain and
where does it go once it's absorbed how
what trees are thriving and where's the
runoff going and so getting ground cover
on on every area that I can it's like
it's it starts microbiology going so
quick I mean any place that I put
woodchips worms show up within a month
or two and they're like I put wood chips
on the fruit trees and they're thriving
and they're retaining water and it just
holds it so building swales and then
laying wood chips in the Swale and then
and even and then wood chipping just any
in any area that is open is it's gonna
change the biology of the soil the soil
starts opening up because of the life
that it brings and there's different
wood chips like the hardy or wood from
the tree it's going to take a lot longer
to to to break down verses the rainy
ellipse from the leaves and the branches
is almost you know available much
quicker is remiel a tree species no it's
just the smaller branches so it's the
fingers the outer edges of the new
growth right on and it's more
biologically active and ready it's you
know it's softer wood that's why people
I guess use the green parts when they're
gonna make fermentation or something
right probably more biologically active
yeah and we try to bury all all types of
stuff into our who-ville's just then we
have stuff that's breaking down a little
slower and a lot of people are worried
about the nitrogen like pulling nitrogen
out of your plants but there's so if you
get the biology right and you get living
soils active it's breaking down and
producing at the same time so I don't I
think that's a key to the making the
jump from I'm adding nutrients to feed
my plant versus us being soil farmers
right and we're actually trying to you
know keep a healthy rhizosphere and so
long as we keep the soil healthy the
plant will be fine right
I mean try not used to it here use the
boring nutrients on it because it meets
nitrogen and I'm used that's how I grew
up
it's like this plant needs nitrogen but
that's because we were buying soil that
everything was spent right and then
there was no worms in your bag soil
there was no you know you could open up
the soil here and there's so many bugs
and different things happening that from
what I've learned from Elaine Ingram and
dragonfly earth medicine cohorts is that
it's just pulling nutrient to pull it
out it's like that
I guess there's different different
metaphors for it but like the
supermarket like you know there's all
these products into the supermarket but
until you have a living system the doors
are shut you open the doors and then all
of a sudden you're like whoa those are
already in there and with your you know
we've walked this property for a while
today and just like the the insects that
we're hearing right now as you move in
different height of your property and
then you're more AG land versus you're
more hard-packed like you know housing
areas and where you keep your equipment
we're actually running into different
sounds it's a melody of different types
of beetles and crickets and whatever you
have up here you know that kind of
diversity you want to model that in the
soil just as much right yeah I mean
there there's different systems like the
who goes down below had much more forest
products in them than this stuff up this
has more annual and more we just worked
this more from our compost from our
house and stuff like that um but there
are micro climates it's like warmer on
that side we're kind of like in bimbo
there's a river on the north of us and a
river on the southwest of us so we're
this island farm kind of if you if
you're driving down the freeway you see
just the mountain that we're on and
we're literally the whole top of this
island so we're kind of have these crazy
swirling wind patterns and a lot of
different things going on
one of the things that we had talked
about earlier was you know the need to
to slow down the water that's passing by
because you know for a lot of folks who
are who are lower down the mountain
there are there's there there's there's
Springs and there's rainfall and one way
or another the water comes down the
mountain and and different people can
use it but you know not only are you at
the top of the mountain but regulations
in California have changed a lot now so
that so that most people can't use
naturally occurring Springs on their
property or just above their property
and for you there is no just above your
property right so um so if you would
explain a little bit about how you are
trying to sink the water here instead of
letting any of it kind of move on past
you yeah I mean it's a challenge like
this is an ideal like if you're studying
land that's productive the top of the
mountain would not be the spot you would
want because usually silt would run off
the mountain and gather in the valleys
and most AG lands in the valleys and
water starts pouring out of the side of
the hill but we're at the top of the
hill luckily we have 72 acres and we
have a whole northern watershed area to
it for our domestic use
but cannabis regulations make us store
everything and only use rain catchment
so we've developed a series of three
ponds where all of our greenhouses
follow the roof catchment from our
greenhouses and our sheds and and my
father's house all flow into those and
then we siphon off that into our
reservoir so we do have like 700,000
gallons of rain catchment but more than
that is even on this space and this is
about six acres of top of the hill and
which it which has hills and flows
there's so many things we can do to just
soar to sink to divert to capture water
on this six acres as much as possible
and we haven't really done as much as we
can
there's still roads and we still do get
runoff but I'm much better than we were
so let's talk about a couple of those
strategies right because I think that
not only do a lot of different kinds of
farmers have to be creative when it
comes to creating and preserving water
on their property but also you know as
as everybody starts to get drier waters
having come more valuable what are the
couple of the strategies that you've
used on the property - to sink the water
and to keep it here I know and I'll get
you started but one that I thought that
was especially cool was as we were
walking down the road you're like oh
we're gonna we're gonna put catchment to
spread the natural road run off to the
side so why do you start there and then
this kind of tell us anything else say
that that along those lines
yeah like Road is a perfect example of
something that is that creates a runoff
like you wouldn't find a road in a
forest and so all the water that falls
around a tree is like I said the pores
in a in a forest all the mulch is there
the wood chips are there the grass and
all those soil pores are open whereas a
road we're driving on it we've killed
all the biology there steep in parts and
so the water just runs downhill
and so Department of Fish and Wildlife
and all the regulations have forced us
farmers to really limit rove road runoff
and which has been an amazing thing I
mean it's good very positive regulate
mean yeah the politics are a little
damaging on the other side but the
regulations I totally agree on and so
we've created swales in all of our roads
every you know forty to sixty feet so
all the road runoff will stop across the
road and ditch into the forest and so
our whole road system all the way down
to the bottom last summer we created
these swale systems so there's no more
like really intense Road Road ditching
it's made much less work for me in that
you know accounting for that where every
ounce of that water is going to go
with the Swale systems really does stop
road erosion and the forest around there
is now capturing wherever that pitches
off into the forest that's gonna capture
that other than that it's like I was
saying like just watch it and the rent
and the rainstorms see where the water
is and see where there's little zones
where maybe you can make a
water-retention it's not like building
ponds but building water retention zones
where you're not you're not trying to
store a lot of water but you're using
your land as the storage so if you just
create a little little like Swale that
looks like a horseshoe and then water
just sits there for a day or two and
then sinks in you've created a whole
bunch more water retention for
everything under that zone you um you
seem to really mean your dad lives here
right and so he's got this gorgeous
garden right bursting with color and
also you know you're really in the poly
culture right so you've got you've got
plants alongside and inside your beds
you've got all sorts of you know herbal
medicine botanicals you know just like
you know lining your beds lining the
road just kind of everywhere it would
seem to me that all these additional
plantings you know just act as a big
sponge and create this freeway down for
the for the water that you hold it tell
me a little bit about like the amount of
effort it was for you to add all this
poly culture because you know anybody
who's probably following this channel
realizes that we're all like you know
you know Pro poly culture and growing
cannabis all on its own monocultures is
just like not really all that positive
but a lot of people think that they
can't do it because it's like it takes
so much effort just to grow the cannabis
that I don't have enough time to do to
do all these other plantings and yet
you've got them everywhere so so so you
know how much labor did that add to your
season to be able to you know add this
crop
variety but also water sinks yeah I mean
I can't I couldn't do it alone so having
a team is very important sure and a team
that knows like I'm not fully I'm not an
herbalist or I'm I don't know all the
plant varieties so we have a team and we
talk about it we sit around the fire we
say hey what if we did this what if we
did that that's important but I think
that what I've learned is timing is
everything so as soon as I cut my
cannabis I'm throwing out cover crop and
then if I cover you know in the early
spring I'm throwing wildflower seed I
love that's like my favorite job is to
literally just have a bucket and go out
at the right time judging on what
weather and just throw seed so I just
try to throw seed everywhere and then I
do I have a nursery where I propagate
you know plants and plugging them in
here and there on the edges it's fun
it's not really extra labor but I mean
it's a learning curve so I've definitely
killed a lot of plants by putting them
at the wrong time I think timing is the
biggest learning curve on that yeah one
of the things I thought was cool so the
when you're referring to this nursery
you're talking about the one made out of
all of reclaimed materials right yeah so
I thought that was pretty cool too
because you know I I can see this theme
kind of running throughout your life
you're all like all right how diverse
how can I bring diversity as a solution
to each of these challenges that I've
got and how can I expand the
productivity of my land
trying to keep my my resource footprint
small and using what's here right and so
when we saw your nursery I mean it was
cool to go in and to see all the healthy
plants rocking along and then you're
like oh yeah this was from somewhere
else this was from somewhere else and
you know and you know G to find that it
was challenging to source the
second-hand material and so it actually
made it more laborious or did you find
that actually when
you shift your expectations to
reclaiming stuff that it just kind of is
everywhere yeah the latter bladders like
there's resources everywhere and
adjusting your designed to fit your
resources is part of that plan like you
might want a fully framed metal
greenhouse but this has actually worked
much better
we have proclaimed glass from I think
good guy in Eureka had a whole pile of
glass I still have like 50 sheets of it
um so we made glass windows out of that
and all the Redwood was from an old barn
and over in West Haven you know by the
coast and it was just rotting in the
ground so we picked that up for a huge
like almost a whole barn for like three
grand so we have this huge stack of
old-growth redwood just keep using it
and we're still using it like four years
later I like that idea you've got of not
forcing the solution to necessarily be
not forcing the solution to the problem
or to the challenge to be the one that
you expect it to be but instead kind of
hold space with the challenge and then
look around you for for what your
natural environment might suggest as a
solution I can learn from that myself I
mean we all good right it's like
permaculture or its life it's like if
you if you are attentive to what's in
front of you and you're in the moment
then ideas just flow and you know I'd
like to be well planned but like
gardening it's like you have to the best
gardening tool is farmer shadow so just
showing up up here and being here these
designs come a guy I've always wanted to
have like a full scale permaculture plan
for my whole land and then I do that and
then we start driving and talking and we
end up doing something different and I
think it's been much more creative I
think both are important because then
the planning process
brings in more thoughtful solutions and
you can go back to that so but forcing
stuff well one thing I've learned from
talking to permaculture people - is that
your permaculture plan I mean unless
you're doing it for a client right but
really a permaculture plan is never
finished because as soon as you're done
you're like alright this is perfect and
then you learn some more stuff and
you're like all right you're changing
things and so I think that's why people
enjoy living like you're living is
because it's a it's an active exercise
in artistry with nature right it's like
constant evolving and changing and as
soon as you make your map you're gonna
be changing your map probably yeah yeah
it's ever-changing I mean you get out
here and you get inspired where my dad
is a carpenter so he just ends up
building little sheds all over he built
this little like collective kitchen for
the workers on a trailer or Lizzie has
his girlfriend she's just like a wild
gardener so she sees a place that needs
a rose or a plant she'll just stick rose
in the forest somewhere you know it's
like you know you I mean part of it you
have to like be productive and stay in
business which is I guess that's my job
right and everybody else just kind of
you know but everyone else in the family
has much more like creative freedom like
to think that way I think that interplay
though that that really just brings home
the importance of family based heritage
cannabis farms everywhere but
specifically here in the Emerald
triangle right it's like it's a you know
the ornamental and food gardens and you
know adds to the poly culture and the
fact that you've got family here helps
keep you feel alive and passionate right
the the ecosystem of people who are up
here working on it is very unlike what I
see in some of the valleys when they are
setting up you know kind of corporate
cannabis monocultures which can be
interesting in their own right but
usually it's because people are
explaining some kind of new to new cool
technology or
or mechanism right and like that can be
cool but but honestly you know dirt on
the boots is a pretty great mechanism
and just having all your family here is
good too and its culture oh yeah
the homesteaders moved out to this land
before there was cannabis here and there
was the back to the land movement that
was anti corporate anti-war anti
industrial like and the beauty that that
life created for me when I was a child
of just like having this collective
vision of hundreds and hundreds of
people that wanted to live organically
and free and having you know less less
less rules and I mean that created so
much beauty that that's kind of what
we're trying to fight for in the whole
craft cannabis movement it's like yeah
cannabis is important but when you chew
you smoke it with and where you're
smoking and truth that it brings out
that's much more important so one of the
things I love when I when I get to tour
cannabis property farms is that every
now and then I'll come across something
that I've never seen before and it gets
me really excited and I saw such a thing
today I saw I saw your crater garden
right and I'm gonna be talking about
this for weeks probably and you know if
I understand it correctly essentially
you you dug out an area in order to
create windbreaks for it and you took
all the stones that you've been finding
on your property and have been making
terraces of them and the idea is that
the Sun beats on them all day they are
absorbing the warmth which extends the
length of your day is that it was that
your idea when you built it yeah and it
just creates a really hot microclimate
so if you can protect the wind in a
horseshoe pattern and then
the rocks act as like a moisture it
pulls moisture in when are when it's hot
it pulls moisture up and when it's cold
it kind of keeps moisture in will
actually mulch some of the grapes and
some of the hotter weather plants with
rock and this little zone is in a very
like warmer part of our property so some
of the sativas that are more equatorial
are gonna go there and we're gonna see
if they thrive like you know we're kind
of in this banana belt of humble up at
1,700 feet and so we don't get the fog
in the winter so the fog will roll in
right below our property and it's in
that crater garden it's still gonna be
hot in October November well alright so
first side note it must be gorgeous when
the clouds are below you and you're up
here I would like to see that sometime
but but also did you you know how did
the crater garden come about did you
have these these you know these
equatorial and Afghan African sativas
that you wanted to give them their best
chance and so you built the crater
garden for them or did you hear about a
crater garden you're like I will make
that and then I'll find something to
plant in it I mean I think it came about
how we were talking about before like
some of my workers I like just don't
tell them what to do sometimes they're
here and one of one of my workers just
like started building a crater garden
and I liked it so I said oh man this is
perfect this identified what it was and
then he actually ended up not finishing
it's a Lizzie came in and she started
developing it and it really just grew
organically like we were talking about
like it's been a community effort and
just before you came here it really got
together with tying it into the other
garden and so we like we're like oh my
god this is like this crater gardens
gonna be perfect for sativas so we
started built we built some wood sheds
and put our tanks like right above it to
act with one break and we're gonna plant
some more hedgerows some perennials and
trees above it so it will be this
so the idea just kind of developed from
being up here uh sorry um Sepp Holzer
is one of my gurus of permaculture and
he wrote a book where he was growing
bananas in the 5000 feet in Austria so
he found a black rock on his property
right in a zone that didn't get any wind
and so he would plant banana trees right
in that little zone and I think he built
the little green house and the snow so
like make it laughs for the winter but
in the summer he was pulling bananas out
of 5,000 feet in Austria jeez pretty
amazing so so in that same vein of like
you know a rare crop in a rare place
you've built this gorgeous crater garden
that looks cool it handles moisture well
and it's going to be warmer for longer
than the day what are you planning there
this year like like that's a special
place now right it's almost like an
altar in a lot of ways what do you what
are you what are you gonna grow there
because it's a small area I think we're
gonna grow this strain which is Lady
Africa which is a shesh Imani cross of
cherry pie with forbidden fruit which is
tangi teri pie and so we're gonna put
some of that and the sweet pink is a
sativa that I also source from a friend
um and that probability is gonna go
there too I did used to have Colombia go
old and Acapulco gold and I have some
rare seeds but I didn't start those
because the planet do so dumb the the
the strain you mentioned was ladies lady
Africa and the name of your farm is lady
sativa mm-hmm and so am I correct to
suggest that you made this cross here
yourself yeah I mean just like Bob Dylan
like does anybody have complete
authority over what they make so yes I
friends that brought me seeds and I
crossed some of those one of my friends
crossed the lady Africa or the session
money with cherry pie and then I cross
it with forbidden fruit where I'm going
with this is the fact that that
particular cultivars the bio regionalism
of them is really important right now
and you know even though you are
bringing land races in from Africa via
friends once once you once it got here
you started doing large-scale sips on
your own property in your own soil
to see you which-which Kiev ours we're
gonna love where you live right and then
you chose fie knows to plant this year
based on on your local area and and I
think that that's probably going to
become increasingly popular right as as
most of the industry moves to
commoditize cannabis where you know
you've got one hip strain that happens
to be you know mentioned in a magazine
and then everybody wants that it's like
okay you know for the PERT for a general
buying public that might be legitimate
but for people like you that are like
very seriously craft I think that you
know the things that you're growing on
your farm that tastes unique because
it's been grown in your soil is going to
become more prevalent and I'm guessing
that you agree with that because we saw
you're you're you're seated light depth
right and so you're producing your own
seeds would you tell us a little bit
about the importance for you for
producing your own seed and and why it's
important to do it on your own property
I mean the pulp process is so exciting
is to plant your whole land and then go
out and find the plant that's thriving
the most find the smells fine and then
you have your male garden and you're
pulling the ones that aren't what you
want and checking the structure and
smelling the turps and then thinking
gone home and like waking up at 2:00 in
the morning oh my god so
I breed like the old-school way where I
just have a male garden on another part
of my property and then I go and I
select out the plants that I love most
and are doing the best in my on my land
and then cross those with each other and
so it's just a constant selection of
like what's what's what's doing and and
I make enough crosses I mean I mean I
make so many I'll probably do 50
different seed types per year even more
and then and then mark them and then go
back and taste the flower and smell it
as it's getting harvested and like have
mental notes of which one was the right
one and then next year it's really a
really a joy to go through a green house
during a sift when the plants are
allowed to grow taller because like
sometimes if you're gonna do a huge sift
they need to stay small and and you
can't really see their full adult
expression I know but these light depth
seeded plants are you know are coming up
our shoulders now and to see you know a
whole line of them that came from the
same folks and yet you know this one's
got this you know deep purple but it's
only underneath the leaves and they're
all they're all expressing themselves in
different ways you know for those of us
who really love the plant that's really
cool to see so so so that we can all
kind of share in in your joy on this or
or nerdiness how we look at it what are
a couple of where some of the crosses
they just give us like you know two or
three that you are most excited about
this year
yeah the one we were talking about is
the pure cush line pop from Mean Gene
and Mendocino um which I grew I've grown
a few times and it's just an amazing
plant cross with fruit loops from
huckleberry hill farms up here and
humble so I'm taking my favorite from
one region crossing it with my favorite
from this region and the two together
hasn't been done yet so that I'm super
excited about that one what are the some
of the other ones that Lady Africa
forbidden fruit
like that one's really gonna come
together I did do a CB v cross last year
or the year before which I call ad
Benbow and that's a Lyon squibbitt which
is gone genetics he's out of Palm
Springs but it's like a Spanish variety
of CBD cross with another mean gene
strain which was Pina oh yeah and that
lines quip it hats like this mersin deep
purple and the Pina is much more fruity
and you smelled that today and that
that's been a really fun string because
it does so good around here it never
gets mauled it's just like it likes this
dry climate but it with the humble
climate it's like the buds are stacked
hard and like full of resin and that's
the CNE plan um but I have so many
crosses that I didn't plant this year
you know one of the things that I found
interesting is as we went through the
different gardens you had a lot of
crosses with names that I was not
familiar with and you know it's not like
I go deep into the history of crosses
you know I usually interview people who
are far more expert than that but but
what you kept on same as like oh I got
this from this farm or I got this from
this farm or this is this is oh this is
his reserved seed right yeah and it kind
of gave me a look inside of the farmer
to farmer trading of seeds yeah and and
certainly their seed swaps right yeah
but but what I was kind of picking up
from you was way more informal and and
like way more family to family almost
what can you say about the importance of
cannabis farmers within a bio region
trading seeds outside of Commerce oh
yeah I mean that's the whole history of
our of our community here is like we're
anti-commercial even some of the best I
mean most of the best things that I've
received have come through that channel
like I have the Green Lantern this year
stopped planting
7b plans of green lantern I didn't pay
for those seats I mean they're probably
worth you know hundreds and hundreds of
dollars on the market you can't even get
those seats but the person that in that
with the Emerald cup winner from
Ridgeline who got it from the same guy
that I got it from but he just like my
workers one of his best friends and
that's how they trick we trade and it's
the same thing within this community
it's like I don't need to buy anything
from anybody really because I get
inspiring conversations and I get food I
mean yes we have a commerce but I just
think that the craft movement it's gonna
be defined community that holds it tight
and talks and comes to the meetings and
really built this non commerce network
so the best things I get well thank you
for inviting me up to come and check out
your community and and meet some of your
people and meet your ladies that are
growing and I really appreciate both you
opening yourselves up and and also the
teaching that you shared with me so
thank you very much for you I really
appreciate meeting you right all right
thank you
you