hlp Vashon Island Washington it's the
wednesday morning scramble with myself
Susan McCabe and Luke McQuillan and our
special guest Shango lowes welcome thank
you think you're glad to be here come
Shango um tell us well tell us your role
right now in in the field of cannabis
sure well a little bit all over the
place right now here on the island I
continued to be the founder of what was
the local trade organization on the
island the Vashon Island marijuana
entrepreneurs alliance but with the
recent changes in the dismantling of
medical marijuana in the state we've
actually changed our name to get in the
spirit of that so now we're the Vashon
Island marijuana enthusiasts Alliance
originally we played the role of helping
medical marijuana producers on the
island find reliable and legal channels
to sell their products in the rest of
the state but since the medical industry
has been dismantled in the state there's
there's not much future in that anymore
so we switched over to the enthusiasts
alliance because now we're primarily an
education organization reaching out to
patients and and explaining marijuana
and and giving a lot of support for
patients on the island who don't know
where else to go so let's back up a
little bit tell us what the laws
regarding both medicinal and
recreational marijuana were before July
ok so so before July there were
recreational stores but there were also
um dedicated medical dispensaries that
were not licensed by the state and so
there was a competition between the
licensed stores and the unlicensed
stores and we had had medical in our
state for 18 years prior to this and
there were some concerns about the
competition from the recreational stores
and of course the state wanted to
capture more of their taxes and so they
decided that it was in our best interest
to dismantle the medical marijuana
stores and push those buyers to the
recreational stores and that finally
happened on in July as you said the
challenges is that while there
recreational stores will eventually have
them all the medical products they don't
have them yet no and so and the price is
much higher and so in the interim the
ones who are losing are our most
vulnerable population of patients
because they didn't have the political
strength that for-profit businesses did
to influence the legislature wow that's
interesting so the for-profit businesses
that sell recreational marijuana
basically prevailed certainly with the
state legislature and so are all the
medical dispensaries just out of
business yes they're they're all out of
business in fact we got a little press
here on Vashon a couple weeks ago
because our medical dispensary here on
the island never closed in july when
when the law changed simply because they
were never told the dispensaries were
were all sent letters from the state
saying the law has changed you must now
closed but you know we kind of slipped
through the cracks because we're in
unincorporated King County and so the
the article that was written about it
everybody was saying wasn't my
responsibility wasn't my responsibility
so anyway we had we had a the last
medical dispensary open in the state
until it until people noticed yeah so
what do you see as the future of legal
marijuana in Washington State well first
of all it's on the grow I mean every
month they're they're returning more and
more revenues as more people realize
that a lot of the the reefer madness
taboos of the last 50 years where we're
based on lies so so there are more and
more people preferring to enjoy cannabis
and and to you know often drink less as
well because even though alcohol is more
available it's it's more dangerous than
marijuana is expect and so but you know
even though I'm disappointed for the
patients for right now and every day I
work with patients who cannot find
access to the specialty cannabis
preparations that they look for I do
have faith that the recreational system
will come around because there's there's
people who are by these products it's a
family yeah but there's a there's a
matter of time for them to ramp up where
they can find the appropriate strains
hire people who know how to
the processes develop their package and
get him in the store and we're just
seeing the first inkling of that right
now but you know I figure a year from
now those products will exist like more
edibles and things of that nature that
so specifically probably Rick Simpson
oil very clean unflavored tinctures
because a lot of things in the
recreational store they're made for fun
and so they they add flavors and sugars
and you know real patients can't drink
THC infused soda pop um you know and so
um they there there's a lack we need
things that are stripped down and very
simple and not quite as sexy is a lot of
the stuff that's prep prep in the
recreational market right now so are
those preparations currently just
inaccessible for people who need them
medicinally um they're inaccessible
legally right so one you know
everybody's gone back to the black
market within the way they used to and
so you know if if you used to be on
seizure medication and then you got
turned on to medical cannabis prop
products and your seizures went away and
now the state says that you cannot have
those until they figure out how to
develop them and suddenly you're told to
go back to the pharmaceuticals most
patients are saying will forget that you
know the person that I used to buy from
in the medical industry is now just
selling out of their house and so I'm
going to continue to work with them and
so you're finding a lot more you know
what we call we like to call more though
the informal market then what we think
of it as the black market but the black
markets got such a bad and sound do it I
mean these are these are kind medical
providers who are artisans in their
craft providing for other people who are
trying to get relief from their ailments
and for now since a lot of those
products are not in the recreational
market people are finding their healing
where they can are those people at risk
of prosecution for selling in the
informal market they are they are and
how how adamant is the state being about
seeking those folks out and prosecuting
them so far it seems to be selective
enforcement it depends on how you're
going about your business because it
does seem that the state understands
that there's a gap here for example they
rolled out this new policy
see where they were going to you know
essentially bless and certify all these
new recreational stores as being medical
but but you know there's only a handful
of those right now because the
regulations or the the how you apply is
so complex and burdensome financially to
the recreational producers and so the
state understands that there's this gap
right now and so there doesn't seem to
be a huge push to put all of these
patient and patient providers behind
bars that said the folks who are
producing huge commercial amounts of
plans or are you know also having fights
on their property and then when the
police come you know that they're there
are guns there and you know it's it's
the way the way the King County sheriff
said it was you know if if there's no
problem there's no problem but if
there's a problem there's a problem and
so in this kind of gray area that we're
in right now there doesn't seem to be a
lot of interest at the state level to go
after these small family businesses that
are trying to provide for patients now
when the rec stores get this you know
there's their shelves are filled with
you know cannabis medicine type products
we may see that change two questions
number one others cannabis medical
products going to increase in price and
number two can you give us a sense of
how many growers are still going on
Vashon um so so for certain the prices
are higher there's no doubt about that
because the state is is is charging a
tax on in both both a a like a syntax of
vice tax and then also just a simple
sales tax and also you know when you
when you knew who your medical provider
was as a person you would be able to
let's say for example you're you're
looking to cure your cancer and you need
60 grams of Rick Simpson oil if you go
at a retail recreational store you're
going to pay 60 times the price for one
gram whereas if you were going to a
medical person they'd say oh well hey
i'm going to give you a discount because
your cancer patient and that's a
bag so we're gonna give you some money
off from that and since you're going to
buy 60 grams all at once we're also
going to give you you know a forty
percent discount because of a bulk
purchase but if you go to a recreational
store it's not like that it's 60 times
full price Wow and so um you know people
who are treating their cancer with
cannabis are absolutely getting their
medicine in the in the informal market
and then so your second question about
how many people are growing stole on the
island um you know the official answer
for you is zero right right but but you
know you go we know we know that's not
true though because fashions number one
cash crop for the last three years has
been cannabis so so we know that there
are you know we know that there are
growers on the island but they have all
returned to the to the shadows and deal
with smaller groups of people and
friends and things like that we have we
have several recreational growers on the
island like vashon velvet and Vashon
Island organics who are who are on the
island and represent us well in the
recreational market and have got very
very fine products but they you know
they don't necessarily spec they're not
processors so they are not preparing
these very specific medical value added
products they're growing really great
flower and then they pass them on to
processors and and then what the
processors do with it if there are their
own thing actually vashon velvet has got
this fantastic reputation because they
may not only are women owned and
operated they use LED lights that are
use much less electricity they recycle
their water and their their flower is so
exceptional that that they just roll
most of it into what are called
pre-rolls which we would think of as
joints and they sell them in in boxes
directly to the retailers and people
just love them and some people say that
they're they're the best pre-rolls in
the state and so so that's exciting do
they have to have a lot of security um
well I would the short answer is yes
because all of the medical growers in
the state have got you know video
cameras and gates or wall or wall
buildings and all of the video is
streamed to the state so they can look
at it at every
so to that degree yes but but you know
you could be far worse you know it's not
like it's a it's a bank where they all
got armed guards are there or anything
I'm glad to hear that yes i would that
would not make the business fun i want
to back up just a little bit because you
said something that alluded to the
notion that rick simpson oil cures
cancer is that proven um well the first
answer is yes i have seen it happen with
patients first hand now when i first
started in this i had only heard it
anecdotally but now i have seen i have
directed patients to places where they
can get rick simpson oil they've used it
and their cancer has gone away so and
all they were doing was using cannabis
oil and getting vitamin d not injections
but what are getting vitamin D as well
and and so I've seen it now firsthand
now while these studies have not been
legal in the United States they have
been happening in Europe and
specifically in England and so cannabis
has been proven to interrupt the cancer
spread and to cause it to repeal back
decrease the activity and eventually
remove tumors too it's difficult to put
them all in the same bucket because
there's lots of different types of
cancer right so for example when you're
using cannabis oil to fight lymphoma
you're going to shrink down the tumors
to you know a one or two percent of what
they were originally but often they
won't go away but you'll get tests tests
every three months and you'll you'll see
that they're not growing whereas other
more aggressive types of cancer you know
canvas might not be that effective
against simply because canvas doesn't
have enough time to help the cancer that
because the the course for for beating
cancer is three months and so you know
if somebody if you get someone who
staged for with an aggressive cancer it
may be too late for them but we're
really excited by all of the the true
scientific studies that are coming out
of Europe that show that that cannabis
stops and or
jurors cancer and you know the the
government has got a patent on using
cannabis to cure cancer and they have
for a couple decades o our government
yeah the US government holds this patent
and that's just a willing to talk about
it didn't they just legalize cannabis
research for medicinal purposes yeah
that really I'd say that's accurate
statement they have they have opened up
the the application process to let a
certain amount of institutions apply so
it's not just everybody it's still very
controlled but yes the increase that
they have decided to move forward with
the research we're talking with the
cannabis expert Shango Louis excuse me
Luke as we had a question no I said
that's good news it is good news and I
didn't know that all that research was
coming out of Europe if people want to
learn more about it the the website that
I direct patients to is project CBD dot
o RG it's a wonderful website run by our
friends at project CBD down in
California and they have done a lot of
the hard research for us if you go to
the website there's a section that says
conditions and then if you click on
conditions it shows you this a whole
page list of all the different
conditions that cannabis helps with and
when you click on the particular
condition it gives you links to all of
the scientific studies in pubmed.gov
showing the support for cancer helping
with Alzheimer's and cancer and
arthritis and autism and I mean it's a
it's an amazing list you know cannabis
was the primary part of the
pharmacopoeia before it was banned
suddenly you know we've been using
cannabis for generations upon
generations and then suddenly for for
political reasons you know they banned
it and and then the pharmaceutical
companies jumped in to fill the void so
they could sell their products well now
with the taboo decreasing and people
starting to realize more and more that
we were lied to for political reasons
people are realizing that the the old
reliable herb of marijuana is something
that that we should get back to using
and you know and you know it's not
addictive it is no one has ever died
from it it's very safe i mean the worst
thing that can happen is you can
accidentally overmedicate and and maybe
be uncomfortable and kind of paranoid
for 45 minutes I mean if that's your
worst symptom that's way better than any
other options for most of these ailments
that website does it have recipes on
there because I know that there's lots
of different combinations of what what
type of mixture that you give for each
type of medical condition do they have
those recipes on there or do you have to
sort of figure that out on your own or
are there places that you can actually
get specific stuff for specific ailments
you know this you that is a question
that's right on the edge of the kind of
information that's available publicly
mean this is this is what I teach I
speak often to doctor and natural path
groups explaining so before this ailment
you want to have something that's this
this many milligrams of THC in this many
milligrams of CBD oh and so and some
things you want to treat with more of an
indica strain and some things you want
to treat with more of a sativa strain to
talk your talk real generally about it
and so I don't know if that's
specifically on the project CBD org
website it's certainly inside of the the
studies that they're quoting for example
in in the UK they have a drug made by GW
pharmaceutical called Sativex and it is
used by patients and but but really if
you look at if you look what the
ingredients is it's it's simply a
one-to-one preparation of THC and CBD at
at three like three and a half
milligrams per dose and and use until
you have relief I mean heck we have
people on the island who make that as a
tincture you know and and it didn't have
to go through all of the laborious you
know whatever the british version of the
fda is um but but it's the way that
nature intended that healing to happen
instead of the the repackaging it as a
pharmaceutical product so so I know that
that's a long answer your question but
here you know but you know well I have
to admit that I was I had a really
severe back prod spinal stenosis and
lasted about two years until I couldn't
take any more and finally got surgery so
I was a green card recipient and some of
the things I was trying to specifically
I didn't want to get necessarily high
but I wanted to relieve some of the pain
and not take all the oxycodone or
anything that kind of medicine that
really was worse for me so I I was
having a difficult time finding that
particular combination that would really
help there wasn't a real hard and fast
recipe that I could use every time you
know I'd go to the medical marijuana
place and a lot of times there be you
know edibles were more what I would
light and rather do but that I found a
hard time getting to know what those
combinations were and what the balances
were and you know you're not alone with
what you're asking is a pretty
sophisticated question and is going to
be out of the experience of a lot of the
bud tenders that you would have spoken
to so for example number one um it was
certainly wouldn't recommend smoking
cannabis for that that is something that
you're going to want a tincture for or
potentially an edible I'm second because
you've got heavy neuropathic pain you're
going to want a lot of CBD in there to
boost your endocannabinoid system
because there's a there's you know
signaling issues mixed in with that and
then you were probably you know had had
actual physical pain issues and probably
especially at night because if you
rolled over you had pain with and woke
you up so then you have insomnia which
then I would recommend an indica
tincture on top of that to act as a
muscle relaxant and help you sleep and
so then so then I would have suggested
you know 10 to 20 milligrams of CBD a
day with a little bit of THC in there to
take advantage of the entourage
effectiveness how they work together and
then in the evening and indica tincture
to help your body relax and help you
slip into sleep boom but not a lot of
people have that level of sophistication
at the retail level well or that kind of
information because they're obviously
you're clear on how all this works we're
talking with Shango loves who is a
cannabis expert and vashon island ER you
just SAT here and gave a prescription
for stenosis pain which is fairly
complex I'm curious about how many
American physicians are
are latching on to this idea and
actually prescribing Canopus for cancer
or for spinal pain or other kinds of
pain well conditions the folks who both
know how to recommend a particular
cannabis preparation and are in favorite
they could probably fit in this room and
luckily though the number of doctors who
are becoming in favor of cannabis is
increasing greatly and the kind of
information that they need to feel
empowered to make these recommendations
are increasing and the likelihood of
them running into an insurance problem
practicing recommending cannabis is
decreasing and so we're on the right
side of history but there is not a lot
of it now a lot of not there's not a lot
of folks recommending that now and and
that those are the folks that i talked
to all the time because they don't even
necessarily want it to go on their
resume that they've learned this stuff
but their patients are asking about it
and so I am very often invited to you
know private homes where there's going
to be a room there's going to be a
couple you know Western doctors a couple
naturopaths a couple of nurses maybe a
patient or to somebody who's significant
other is really sick and so we just sit
around and talk and and I teach what I
have learned during my years of doing
this and so they have a better frame of
reference to put all the other
information that they're learning
because there's so much noise everybody
wants to talk about Canada and most of
the information is very low quality yeah
Wow Shango lows you are the president of
the imea vashon vashon island marijuana
enthusiasts a lot Alliance yes and you
have a fairly beyond the island career
as well in the in cannabis information
sure sure education outlook and now it's
about leaning more towards media so I
was doing a lot of brand strategy and
startup business consulting for medical
companies when they existed and then and
then they went away and then so and I've
worked with some recreational producers
as well but during the transition i
found that
what I had to offer him even though I've
you know I'm a lifelong brand strategist
and and and can talk business the part
that I had that was valuable was the
experience with cannabis business
specifically the development of products
and working with patients because that's
where my passion is working sounds
itions yeah I just you know I talked to
patients every day on the island who
come to me for advice and to get
direction about where they can get these
medicines either through the
recreational stores or elsewhere and and
so I moved into media so I've got I've
got a podcast at shaping fire calm that
one is actually launching in a week I
recently just left my role as a founder
of the podcast at ganj preneur calm I
did fifty four episodes for them but
decided it was time to go out on my own
so I could have a little more control
sure and so so shaping fire is going to
launch here in two weeks and I'm and I I
travel the country a lot spending a lot
of time in California right now teaching
both cannabis business owners and also
patients and sharing what I've what I've
learned so whoa okay you go okay I um
are there any stores in and I'm not
asking you necessary to name them per se
but are there some stores that have sort
of gotten on the bandwagon with medical
products marijuana products in Seattle
that patients here like on Vashon can go
to the short answer is yes the long
answer is no because the problem is is
that the stores may be on board but um
there's not enough being produced that
they can keep it on their shelves and so
you know they might get in some some
Rick Simpson oil and people notice it
and they tell their friend and they're
sold out in a day and so um so there are
there are there are like for example you
know Seattle cannabis company you know
they're there right off the the west
seattle bridge and you know they've got
a great staff that does you know that
educates folks but but they have a hard
time keeping this stuff on the shelf and
so we need more processors to produce
more of this medical product so that it
becomes available but you know nearby
you know we've got three directions
where we can take
fairies you know south you're right I
don't and the south end and so there are
there are recreational stores on all
three ends and you know we're to the
point now that we're just we being the
Vashon Island marijuana enthusiasts
Alliance we're just starting to develop
relationships with these folks so that
we can recommend them confidently i mean
i can i can say nice things about
seattle cannabis company on first
because I'm friends and I know several
of the bud tenders there and they come
out to vimeo meetings and i know they're
doing their own education and so so i
know that their fourth right folks who
are doing a good job so you know we
don't have a relationship with them but
there are more and more of the
recreational stores that are hiring
people specifically for that Shengo
lowes how do people get ahold of you to
get more information about medical
marijuana and and cannabis in general
how do they reach you well you can
certainly go to my website at Shango
lowes.com you can get in contact with me
there and you can also find out you know
upcoming events that i'm either speaking
at or happening here on the island
alright thank you so much for joining us
I hope you come back and update us as
the medical marijuana business grows
sure is puttin the plug a couple on
island events before I go oh yeah I know
so um so so first of all on october 7th
i've been invited to do a talk on
medical marijuana at the Vashon Senior
Center this will be the second time I've
spoken there last time it was standing
room only a real popular event and
that's um that's on Friday October 7th
at one o'clock in the afternoon and then
the next vinia meeting is wednesday
September 28th and our guest speaker is
farmer Tom lauerman who will be speaking
on harvesting and curing your summertime
outdoor home grow and that's at seven
p.m. at the Grange Hall and then for
cannabis folks on the island who are
interested in working in the cannabis
industry this Sunday September 18th I'll
be offering the keynote at the wanna
career fair in bellevue at the red lion
hotel and so they're going to have a
bunch of cannabis companies who are
hiring now they're meeting folks and
collecting resumes and there will also
be
cannabis employment experts talking
about how to prepare a resume for
cannabis and just generally giving good
advice and is this information also
available inch angle Oh stuff it
certainly is it's all available in the
events section at Shango low stock sh8
and gol OS com did your parents name you
that they did not I changed my name
about 20-some years ago when I moved to
California you and a whole lot of other
people thanks so much for joining us we
look forward to talking with you more
and in honor of that I've got a Bruce
Springsteen song okay what are you into
the fire