do you want to introduce our guests and
let our listeners know who
who we're having this sunday yeah
yeah we are i'm actually really excited
about this guest this week so we're
going to have shango los on
he is the host of a podcast called
shaping fire which is all about
the science and uh some technology as
well
of cannabis so um i actually
was not a fan of podcasts previously
because
it was kind of was the the age of this
american life and
sometimes they were good but sometimes
they weren't and i was just kind of like
a podcast i don't know maybe not super
interested in those
and somehow heard about uh
shangri-losi's shaping fire podcast and
started listening to it and i was just
absolutely mind blown by the guests he
had
their level of expertise he's a
phenomenal interviewer
so it was kind of it changed my world
from like i don't really like podcasts
to
figuring out that there was this
incredibly diverse world of wonderful
podcasts and podcast representers out
there
so i'm super excited to have him on this
week
um he is up in vashon island which is up
in the far reaches of the pacific
northwest
so he's going to be talking to us today
about autoflowers
i know that most of us who have been in
this industry for a while
like pre pre-64 and definitely pre-215
we probably have experienced autoflowers
as a root oralis
strain which was not very much fun
and they just weren't very good genetics
and they were just
weird plants right yeah so yeah things
have really changed from back then to
where they are now and autoflowers are
actually getting a really good rep
especially in places
like the far pacific northwest where you
have such a short growing season
you really can't grow a lot of the same
cultivars that we do down here
so um he's gonna yeah be talking to us
about all of that and i'm
super excited yeah yeah and the other
little
tricks you might have for growing up
there in the pacific northwest
we have shango yeah oh great come on
hey there wendy and sunshine thank you
for having me here
thanks for joining us mango thank you so
much yeah for joining us we really
appreciate you taking some time out to
uh to talk with us today
sure absolutely i've enjoyed your little
conversation that you were having about
smoke
we have been experiencing smoke up here
as well in uh
on vashon island in washington state
where i live
and one of the things that uh people are
very aware of here
is that you know um old smoke and
uh old soot doesn't have a smell to it
you know we know all about how
um uh terpenes volatilize off cannabis
and so over time cannabis smells less
and less
aromatic that's actually the same thing
for smoke as well
over time the the aspects of it that we
smell
from the burnt um you know natural uh
material and chemicals eventually those
those terpenes volatilize and go away as
well
and so just because our flowers don't
smell like smoke
doesn't mean that we shouldn't be aware
that they very well may have
uh you know soot-related toxins in them
it's a it's a very sticky wicket
yeah sticky wicket it is indeed i i'm
wondering too there's been a lot of talk
this year i don't know shane
if you've heard of this it was somewhat
new to me uh
well actually it's not really because i
tried it once a long time ago and was
like heck no
but there's a water curing process that
you can use where you're
literally submerging your flower into
water
and then changing that water out every
day and
it wicks off it basically like it you
know utilizes all the chlorophyll it
gets that all off and it also removes
many of the terpenes so you end up with
a very smooth smoke but there's not
a lot of flavor or nose to it
um so i wonder if for small home growers
that really are concerned that might be
something they could try
but like i said i all kind of doing it a
long time ago once and being like oh
heck no way too much work
yeah i agree with you on that i've only
tried that once before with one plan
you know uh you know being a host of a
podcast i i i try to
try everything once right and so i i
tried it once
and um i found that the
the plant material started to degrade
and so every time i was taking it out of
the water it was losing plant material
and
i didn't really care for that part of it
um and
uh and and for most of the people that i
work with
who are home growers i don't um have as
much uh to do with commercial growers
um you know as far as being hands-on i
live on vacheron island where
most of our growers are are outdoor
patients and folks
and so most of the folks were just
shaking their plants and blowing
uh the soot off so so most of the
patients are not having the problem most
of the problems that
we're having are folks in eastern
washington and of course down in oregon
who have got a large number of plants
and i'm not sure what their
their solutions are going to be you know
one one interesting thing to note as far
as the water curing
it's actually very common in eastern
washington where it's very
very dry and very dusty to harvest their
plants hang them upside
down like you would a side of beef or
something and spray them with the hose
and then the water just cascades off of
the plant
into this big muddy muddy pool
below it and then because the air is so
incredibly dry there the plants just
just dry with some fans and and there
you have it most people that's not going
to be a good option for them though
simply because living in the pacific
northwest if you're going to get your
whole plant
wet including the flower you are looking
for mold
yeah yeah we are the southern edge of
that pacific northwest
i consider us to be pacific northwest
we're like the very southern as
a part of it here in humboldt
yeah all of us who live in rain forests
yep yeah we've definitely you know like
i said we've we've played with the bud
washing technique previously
and we found that it just that the
oxidation that occurred was so rapid it
was really kind of hard to get around
but i don't know if that was because
of the vinegar and baking soda
and then you moved it to a hydrogen
peroxide and then you moved it to a
plain water rinse and
you know it was a decent amount of
product we were moving through so we
started moving through it
rather rapidly so i feel like maybe we
didn't
rinse it extremely well but you know
it's going to be interesting to see when
testing starts coming through
as to what this is going to look like
for commercial cultivators in california
especially with
our testing that requires less than 25
percent
contamination for foreign particles and
i don't know if that's 25
of the entire bud 25 of the buds have
something on them
or what might be the case uh processors
are definitely going to have their hands
full
this fall and winter though for certain
right right i hadn't thought about that
about the content for sure one thing for
sure they're going to be getting smoky
packs on the east coast for the
unlicensed market no doubt
they probably already are
[Laughter]
yeah actually we're we're getting almost
close to the top of the hour already
which is crazy i feel like we just
started
conversing but um real quick do you want
to kind of talk a little tiny moment
here
about some of the auto i know you're
you're a big proponent of the autoflower
right
oh yeah a big proponent of it you know
it's it's not something for every single
grower but it is definitely a good plant
for
a large swath of of the
you know the total number of people who
grow so
if you want me to seek into that i would
be happy to
yeah let's send let's do that at the top
of the hour let's go into that some more
and so yeah i'd be curious to
learn one thing that i've learned about
uh one thing i've learned from
teaching about autoflowers primarily to
patients for the last few years
um is one of the things i've learned is
what i've learned from folks down in
your area right because there's a lot of
resistance to autoflowers
from the traditional heritage growers
right off the bat because generally
speaking while there are some
larger um you know cultivars of
of autoflowers most of the plants are
smaller they
they they top out somewhere between
three and five feet
they're a little thinner in yield and
bud structure
um though the terpene profiles are
often incredible and there's a lot of
good terpene profiles on the market now
folks really love those monster trees
and and i talk to
folks who are heritage growers and
they're like listen the you know
everybody loves a beautiful tree right
you know especially down where you are
we all love the redwoods
but one of the things that really
brought um
large trees cannabis plants to
prominence was the 99
plant maximum because suddenly
if you only were allowed to run 99
plants legally
each one of those plants had to just be
incredible and
huge because you were limited in number
and so
that really added a lot to the mystique
of the big plant beyond just
the sheer beauty of it and so the the
people who
uh uh most quickly uh embrace
autoflowers are people who are not as
concerned about the 99 plant minimum
and so the four categories of those
people tend to be number one first and
foremost and
the folks that um you know i'm most
active teaching autoflowers to which is
patience
because you know while large
plants are certainly sexy they are
challenging for many patients who may
have mobility issues
or space issues or um
or you know an ability to break them
down and
and and work the plant themselves right
a lot of us when we're harvesting those
big plants we're on ladders we're using
multiple people sometimes
and this is just not something for
patients and so
right off the bat autoflowers were
something that were embraced by patients
because
they were they were a smaller commitment
you got you know high
cannabinoid profiles they smell good
they give a sense of success and and
probably most importantly
they give a sense of um
self um you know being able to take care
of yourself right uh being being uh
self getting getting your medicine thank
you self sufficient that's exactly what
i'm trying to get into
and and that's really important for
patients who are used to depending on
caregivers and doctors and
and you know very often uh they're also
depending on food banks and things like
that so to have a plant
that you can grow yourself and harvest
yourself and
and make your own medicine is is a
fantastic win so so that's the first
group of people the second group of
people
are home growers who are uh perhaps
growing
indoors where having a monster plant is
not
important in fact they may be growing in
a tent
and so some of the challenges with
regular seeds is that you know they can
often
outgrow the tent if you're not on top of
you know keeping them topped and trimmed
and all that but with auto flowers they
really fit
a four by four you know by 70 inch tent
really well where you don't have to top
them at all so it makes them very
convenient for an indoor tent
and also a lot of home growers also need
to use a certain amount
of discretion when they are at home now
i recognize that uh you know where you
live uh you
have a a personal plant minimum and so
that's great so people don't really have
to hide them as much
unless they are concerned with their
neighbors swiping them or something
but here in washington and for most of
the rest of the country
you still need to hide your plants
because we don't have
a legal number of plants that you can
grow in washington
without a medical card and that's still
how most of the country is
and so for people who still need to tuck
their cannabis plants in between their
tomatoes and their corn in their garden
autoflowers are a really fantastic
option because there's a lot of bang for
their buck
and and they tend to grow out uh
horizontally
instead of just upwards and uh and and
um many of them have got
phenotypically they don't look as much
like uh
cannabis plants i mean the leaves are
the the sun leaves are still
recognizable
but the plants themselves many of them
don't
have the the traditional structure so so
so that's the second category is
homeowners
the third or fourth category is
commercial thc
growers now this is something that i
have found more and more
commercial growers down in california
reaching out to me to talk
about this because they've realized that
right in the summertime uh
dearth of cannabis you know that that
july august time
when when all last year's outdoors is
long gone
there is some indoor around but really
everybody's getting ready for
uh depths to harvest and then and then
full terms to harvest
uh those growers who are looking to make
money mid-summer
are starting to grow auto flowers
because if they um
if they start them june 1st they're
ready to harvest
september 1st and if and if you happen
to live in a bioregion
in uh you know in the in the emerald
triangle area
where you get warmer in may you can
certainly start them as early as may 1st
and then oh my gosh you're done august
1st and you're bringing
fresh flowers to the market at a time
when not a lot of people have them
and so you get people growing them
either
to you know move into the flower market
uh but but honestly most of the people
who i've talked to
in your area who have been trying them
they're growing them
to put into the extraction market so
that they can bring
fresh flowers with unique terps and um
and they you know and they've got them
in in august so that's
that's for today yes i want to do a
follow-up
on the extraction but we do need to take
care of our top of the hour business
okay i'll hang tight okay okay hold on
we're gonna just take five minutes um
this has been sunshine johnson here with
wendy kornberg and we are here with
shango and we are
talking cannabis here on the ganja tree
show er
gotcha thanks so much so we're just
gonna take you guys down there we go
and not much to say you're listening to
the ganja tree right here on redwood
community radio
kmud garberville 91.1 fm and
hd1 kmue eureka 88.1
and hd1 klai leightonville at 90.3 fm
in shelter cove at 99.5
everywhere on the web at kmud.org
it's a couple minutes passed too gonna
bring you right back to ganja tree
thank you you're welcome
so shingo i have a question about the
autoflower now it does
i would say i'm a little bit adverse to
it because it just
just comes across as kind of commercial
to me i i don't know
i i don't know if it's going to have the
nuances and the
flavors and aromas that i'm used to but
if there's a good hash train i'd be i'd
be interested
well one of the interesting things is um
you know i'd actually say
the majority of them are good hash
trains for one particular reason which
is
a lot of people talk trash about
autoflowers because
they don't necessarily have the
tightness
of a rock hard indica flower like you
get growing
in there in the humboldt region but for
most of the rest of us in the country
our flowers don't finish like that
anyway so we're used to growing
flowers that are more open and and
autoflowers
since they are you know whatever uh you
know whatever traditional
uh cultivar that we like to grow crossed
into a root oralis ruderalis flowers are
typically very much more open
and so they give up their trichomes much
more um reasonably than trying to work
with
really rock hard buds which are which
are great for bag appeal and are sexy to
smoke
but to get them to open up during the
hashing process
has got some amount of challenges and
you're always going to lose trichomes on
the inside
whereas autoflowers so long as you find
something with a taste profile you like
and certainly you want to make sure
they've got
fragile trichomes in that particular
cultivar but they're just about
all open flowered which is why a lot of
people look at
autoflower and say oh i don't want to
grow these don't these don't have good
bag appeal
well they only have you know
questionable bag appeal
if you are from where you live and all
the flowers that you grow are gorgeous
and are you know magazines spread
quality
and but you live in a place where um you
know that is unique
in our country and in the world and so
for just about everybody else
um the tightness of the flower that you
can get in california or
indoor anywhere um a lot of people are
just really glad to have
good smelling plant with cannabinoids so
so i would say that
certainly autoflowers are great for hash
and and most of the people that i know
who are home growers and and you know
enjoy making ice water hash themselves
they grow their autoflower
[Music]
group of plants intentionally to make
hash
and so maybe they'll maybe they'll have
some full terms uh for
smoke and to take to parties because
they look sexy but then the hash that
they're making is from the autoflowers
you know one of my favorite autoflower
hash making
cultivars is is actually from
daniel at um at heart rock mountain he's
got this fantastic
cultivar called lion claw and uh it's
you know it's got all the full flavor
that you were saying that you were
concerned about missing from a full term
plant
um because it it's got that tang you get
from alcohol esters that
a lot of you know the early autoflowers
didn't have they were looking for
complexity
and the lion claw from from heart rock
mountain that's the first one that i
came across where
i got a reliable six-foot plant it had
the full
flavor that had great uh bud shape
and that looked kind of like a northern
lights five plant traditionally looks
like
and and they're really good the thing
about is is you gotta grow a lot of them
right i've probably
been involved with like i don't know
growing 80 85 different cultivars
and and there were a lot of losers
there's no question about it that there
were a lot of them that were just kind
of mediocre
but you got to remember like we're not
we're not in the same situation we were
10 years ago
where autoflowers didn't produce and
they smelled like crap and they didn't
smoke very well we're 10 years later and
while they might not
be the same as the like epic genetics
that come out of the humble um you know
in the emerald count
emerald um triangle area this is a
this is a game that's just getting
started and as more and more
of the solid heritage growers start to
move
into autoflowers because of how useful
they are
i think that we're going to find the
terpene profiles getting more along the
lines of what you expect
from a from a photo period but don't
think that the
the autoflowers don't smell good if
you're growing an autoflower and it
doesn't smell good it just means that
you've got the wrong
autoflower how so how did it mean
i think that part of part of the
problems that a lot of people have with
the autoflowers on the commercial market
is they're not in that you know
california's got this whole
idea that you need to be above 20 thc
and the autos that i've seen the testing
on them they're not coming back anywhere
close to that the closest i've seen was
a
high somewhere in the high teens for
total cannabinoids
and i think thc was resting around 14
and maybe for hash that works but even
the hashmakers that i know
don't really want to mess with something
that's that low in thc
so i don't know if california commercial
market is quite there yet with its
ability
to embrace the autoflower as it exists
but
i do love the idea of breeding it and
starting to you know taking those
breeding projects and dialing them in
after a few years i i think that there's
a lot of growers in your area that gave
them a try this year right
like for example i'm i'm familiar with
the folks at uh moon time medicinals
there in garberville
and uh they've got this beautiful huge
culture that they have
uncovered right and so uh if they run
their full terms there they do cat
a cough and catch some weather at the
end of the cycle
and so this year they grew um what
600 square foot no 6 000 square feet is
it anyway a huge ass
excuse me um hugo culture full of these
autoflowers
and they finished the end of august and
they were beautiful and they were able
to move them
into the extraction market now are
autoflowers going to be ready for the
california
flower only market now and that's kind
of a stretch but
but you also got to remember where you
are as far as
the the totality of the market you guys
are
growing olympic level plants and
genetics
and so yeah it's probably going to be
more for patients and home growers
and extraction and hashing at the
beginning
until they get some of that sexy bag
appeal that of the stuff that you
normally grow
and how are auto flowers
like what's the how were those
bred i mean could i take a strain of
mine and turn it into an
autoflower or what do you know much
about that process
well while i'm not breeding autoflowers
myself
i interact with a lot of breeders who
are doing it because
you know for i i have been carrying
the the gospel of autoflowers across the
country
with talks and so autoflower folks who
are breeding reach out to me and say hey
what are you what are you hearing what
are you learning what do you what do you
think of these seeds
and so um they are you know you
are choosing a ruderalis cultivar that
you like
you and and the root of ruralis um
you know lineage if you will has come
from siberia
um uh in russia and they have got very
short summers and very early
winters and so these plants were
discovered
that that are used to very short uh
summer time so as soon as they
are biologically mature they immediately
go into flower
and so that is where we get the short
season from
and then folks take their favorite um
regular cultivars like the one that you
have that might
be a um you know a farm specialty for
yours and they cross them
into the root oralis and then your first
wave you'll have a certain percentage
and then you'll sift those
and then uh and then normally this is
where i
you know i get become less involved at
this point but but normally by the
by the the second generation you have
yourself
at um you know at a significant number
of autoflowers and you're ready to
breed those for market um it does take a
bit of work it's certainly not as simple
as just pollen chucking like we all love
to you know eat you know everybody can
can do a simple cross um these take a
little more effort and more time to sift
and
instead of making a seed in a season
you're talking about more like three or
bringing your project indoors so
so the short answer is yeah you can
totally take your favorite strains from
your farm and make them autos
if you decide you want to take on that
project and
and while i've seen most of the
mainstream cultivars that have been auto
flowered
they do have a slightly different taste
because the root oralist does carry some
of its own flavor profile in there
but the more you work it um you know the
closer it can be
to your
[Music]
yeah i remember these two way way
way back maybe wendy does too the
rudoralis name the first time i heard it
was probably like
late 80s or something and they were kind
of popular with the gorilla growing
techniques too because the plants did
stay smaller and they were kind of
easier to tuck away and hide
under the bushes but that was the first
i heard of it
and then that was it they kind of maybe
they came and went but now they're
coming back
yeah we definitely played with that back
in the day
and um again it's not the same thing as
it was because back in the day
it was really not good i mean there was
it was literally we didn't even know the
term root
i mean we knew the term root or alice
but we called it ditch weed because it
was
like the stuff that grew in the ditches
and you just
i mean it didn't have flavor it didn't
have terpenes it really didn't get you
very high
it was much closer to what we consider
hemp nowadays
than what we are now terminologying uh
using the terminology of an autoflower
which is um yeah it's been interesting
i'm kind of wondering like
who is bringing it back because i don't
think this just popped into the scene
as these amazing autoflowers but yet i
haven't heard about the people like this
should have taken at least
you know three to four years to get the
right root or alice and
get the strain at least a little bit
stabilized so that your cultivars are
decent and then working that strain
through to
increase your cannabinoids and your
terpenes and yeah just like you were
saying shango
just uh working that line to increase
the positive aspects of what you want in
your cultivar and decreasing
those negative aspects that used to come
with with root or alice back in the day
it's it's funny that you say you know
you you you wish you know
you're surprised you hadn't heard of it
or you or you should have heard of it
and the thing is
is that autoflower people because of
the bad you know because of the trash
that is talked by
by many heritage outdoor breeders um
autoflower breeders uh were you know
laughed
off of forums and stuff and so um
the the the arrogance of of heritage
growers and people who just wanted to
grow big trees
caused the autoflower people to have to
create a community of their own
and so there actually is a huge
community of autoflower people natural
nationally that your listeners can
connect with at autoflower.net
because the autoflower breeders who you
know were pushed off these other forums
by just being laughed at
they're like fine we're going to take
our ball and go home and so they went
home and they started their own
uh breeding community and they have been
working together and trading genetics
and trading best practices and
you know developing the the the better
reuteralis that
you know imparts the timing but not the
taste
and now there's you know not only a lot
of commercial growers that are putting
out
excuse me commercial breeders that are
putting out you know commercial quality
seeds i mean heck
most of the commercial hemp market is
based on
um autoflower seeds but then also
there's so many bedroom uh breeders who
are breeding exceptional
seeds now that are available at
commercial scale that you can get
so uh one of the important things for
for all of us
in cannabis media to do is to you know
shake off
the reputation that autoflowers had 10
years ago
and and engage with modern breeders like
like dan jimmy at mandalorian genetics
and daniel at heart rock mountain who
i've already mentioned
and zero zero from spain and and das
mephisto who's uh doing
a line called a night owl under the
mephisto genetics
family like all these people are making
really
great flowers that are
flowers for now they're modernized
autoflowers that people are very happy
with
but again it really depends on what your
use
is if if you're trying to put an
autoflower versus traditional genetics
in california to be ready in october
well the traditional genetics are still
going to be better
but if you're trying to get plants to
harvest in august
if you're a patient if you're a home
grower or if you're going to want to
have
acres and acres of plants and you want
them all to be the same
so that you can harvest them uniformly
well then autoflowers is a godsend to
you
there's also i know that sunshine and i
have actually talked about this a little
bit and i know other commercial
cultivators too that have talked about
that in california specifically in order
to get a license
you have to declare what type of
cultivation style you use
it's either outdoor mixed light tier 1
or mixed light tier 2
or indoor and mixed light tier 1
means that you're using light
deprivation and under six watts per
square foot of supplemental lighting
so unfortunately that license costs
quite a bit more
you also have state and local licenses
state and local permit fees which are
generally more you have
excise fees which are generally more so
something like an autoflower that you
could
you know companion plant if as it were
throughout your full term
get that boost mid-season so that you
have a bit of a paycheck before
the market floods in the fall and then
harvest those out let your full terms
fill in
is something that is for me very
attractive
and um you know very interesting
as long as i know i can sell it i also
am
dragonfly earth medicine certified so we
have agreed in that contract
to not put anything to hydrocarbons so
it can't be blasted it would have to be
made
into either dry sift or ice water hash
um
possibly co2 but i try to avoid that
myself
and like i said just a few hashmakers
i've talked to
they haven't worked with autos yet and
they're like i don't know
i don't know would it work i don't know
so it's good to hear that there are
a lot of people that are using it for
hash and uh maybe that's something we'll
have to play with next year
you know it's kind of funny to think
about that even though california is a
leader in
everything cannabis because the rest of
the country
has got worse weather than you are you
you know california folks haven't really
necessarily
had the the need to explore outside of
traditional seeds
and in this probably maybe only this one
way
california might be catching up with
what the rest of us have been doing for
a few years
because we don't have your weather
well the mold
i taste mold every year in the eel river
valley
so yeah i have i shared some similar
issues that you have there up in
washington
living growing in the rainforest so to
speak
we we definitely don't grow certain
cultivars because of
the problem that you know the botrytis
and powdery mildew and things and we
just kind of learned to be
very picky about you know cultivars and
cultivar specific we're also again we
are
in an incredibly privileged and blessed
area for growing cannabis because it has
been done here for so long
that we have a lot of stabilized
genetics we have a lot of interest
coming back
into legacy california cultivation and
what those legacy cultivars are
so um we yeah we definitely have not
really seen the need
to you know play with the autoflowers
until again most recently with all of
our
prop 64 shenanigans and policy which
well i mean i will say for mold
or for botrytis in particular now of
course
i'm not talking about smoking the mold
this is after you remove the mold from
the plant
but actually having a little bit of
botrytis
on your plant that plant it will be
sweeter and better tasting i know that
sounds kind of crazy
but a little bit of mold will actually
give you
a little sweeter smoke and that's not
smoking the mold
that's just how the plant ripens with
that little
bit of mold on it so i carefully monitor
it and i don't want to get it obviously
it's going to greatly affect yields at
some point
and i just am careful how much of the
crop is a strain that does mold
but it's not necessarily it's you know
it is
it's the plant it will quicken its
ripening just a little bit
but if but it can also
keep you from getting your plant fully
ripe
as well with that mold so
it's not you know it's not the worst
thing in the world
but it's uh it pushes a stress response
in the plant as well so it'll actually
be like oh shoot
something's going on yeah like you're
saying i gotta finish faster
i need to push into you know the
trichome production and terpenes in
order to protect myself
um i i don't i i always hope for no mold
personally but
you know all of us cannabis growers by
the third week of september we're
starting to get
suspicious and a little anxious right
because we're all like checking the
weather
and making sure our air flow is good and
and watching for molds because when the
rains come
um you know crops can go bad uh quickly
if we're if we're outdoors
especially or in hoops or things like
that and
it is remarkable to have the experience
of seeing plants uh
you know that that magical last week
when you smell those mature terpene
profiles
and you're all like god i love being a
cannabis farmer you know and
you like we usually only get that one
time a year unless we dep as well
and and we smell them and everything to
get that experience
the first week of september when and
have
no mold and be able to harvest and have
everything hung and be done and
have it be september 15th by that point
and realize that
you know you you you harvested 95
of your plants perfectly healthy they
smell
great um it's a really startling diff
startingly different
growing experience than growing full
terms which
i adore right i've got nothing bad to
say about full terms
except for depending on where you live
they don't finish right and so
for those people autoflowers may be a
really good option
so how do those autoflowers ripen kind
of similar can you let them go
slightly over rice and they're still
good oh for sure yeah you can you can
definitely let them go it's one of the
things that's cool about autoflowers
is that um they've got a lot more
flexibility not only can you let them go
a little long
um let's say in case um
let's say you're planted and oh gosh you
have to evacuate right
if it takes you another week or so or
you know 10 days to
to harvest them um you've got a little
more you've got a little larger window
of opportunity than you do
trying to do that in october but here's
the thing that
really gets people's attention you know
most of us have got food um
gardens as well right because we want to
be self-sufficient
and one of the things that we do
throughout the summer is um
is um uh plant um
oh serial planning what's the phrase i'm
looking for
consecutive planning um
anyway where you where you plant some
this week and you plant some next week
and you plant some the next week
and so um you can do that with auto
flowers and so
you can uh take a plant that say for
example
a 92 day from germination to
um to harvest plant and you can plant
you know one group of them on uh
may 15th and another group on the on the
21st and another group on june 1st
so that instead of having to harvest all
your crop
within a week you can actually
harvest some every week over the course
of a month
which uh succession planning that's what
i'm trying to think of and
succession planting like this is in
wildly more
convenient than waiting waiting waiting
oh my god quick let's pull
everything as fast as we can
yeah yeah absolutely and that's that's
that changes things again for california
market
because we're always talking about the
drying space how much drying space do
you need and
how much more do you have to get and
what kind of you know
ada compliant government sanctioned
you know commercial building do i need
to dry my weed in
so um i'm getting more and more
convinced as this goes on
yeah you know a lot go ahead
i'll just have to see if i can get some
good melt out of it
and some good grief but i haven't really
seen it yet but i'm not
all that experienced
well i wish that we would have uh been
able to connect at uh emerald cup uh
sunshine i would have been able to
hand you some decent melt and then for
you to try
um you know it really depends on what
people experience as their air quotes
end of
season right because we all look at
different attributes for end of season
you know for some people it's you know
less sun and cooler days for some folks
it's fog for some folks like me it's
cooler nights below 55.
some folks it's it's rain it might come
early
um for people who have got these sorts
of problems at the end of their season
autoflowers are a great idea
and if people are particularly into the
size of the plants because they've got
um numerical limits uh being in the
ground
helps a lot most of the
smaller autoflowers that people see
pictures of
and and they find dissatisfying is
because these plants are
also in containers and they're not in
you know
you know 300 gallon you know huge
uh linen containers either they're
most people grow an autoflower in five
to seven
gallon pots and so they're on a deck or
they're indoors and so
the plants are not really given the
opportunity to
do you know be to their full potential
but if you are somewhere that is growing
an autoflower
either right in the ground or in
a large pot of of really active
living soil the plants really do
get bountiful and bigger and with larger
flowers and more
identifiable bud structure it's just
that there's not as many photographs of
those
on instagram for people to see because
again the people who were first adopters
of autoflowers are people
with less than ideal conditions for
growing
so let's just one of the things i wanted
to ask you about too
is the community of growers
where you live can you speak a little
bit about
about the growers where you are in the
community that you have do you have any
trade associations or
sure sure um so here on vashon island um
we have gone through a very significant
transition since
uh the normalization and the
the the existence of a licensed market
so historically vashon island
has been a very popular um unlicensed
underground cannabis growing community
we had good flowers coming out of here
we had
an array of good purple genetics like
ovp
which here is known as the original
vashon purple
and bands that would come to seattle
would intentionally
uh put their feelers out to to have
somebody come over to vashon island or
you know invite somebody to the show
that would bring them some
vashon grown flower during their tour so
that was cool and you know we
the island's been in some you know
popular magazines like like there's like
there's a classic early 80s playboy
episode that talks about
vashon cannabis and stuff so you know
there's a bit of a reputation but
but then when medical got started
suddenly became far more popular
because the underground growers
were kind of selling against each other
on the island
and there wasn't a lot of the flower
leaving the island so vashon had
incredible flower
at very low prices because these
talented growers were just
selling against each other in the same
community and so
the prices tended to go down
once once medical started
that's where i got involved more with
cannabis here on
vashon island by starting a trade
organization here
called vimeo originally it was the
vashon island
marijuana entrepreneurs alliance but
since licensing we've changed the e from
being entrepreneur to being enthusiasts
and so in the early days of vimeo what i
was doing was developing relationships
with
the dispensaries over town in seattle
and port orchard in tacoma
and we were moving the flowers that were
grown
on island into dispensaries
all around the seattle area and so that
was great you know farmers were happy
because they were getting more
for their pounds and also we started
doing things like bulk buying soil and
other soil amendments and inputs in bulk
as a group and then splitting them up so
that everybody could save money
and we started having meetings and and
then and then the
laws changed right like i know how prop
screwed so many of your people and the
same thing happened here
and so um they gave licenses to
a whole bunch of uh you know people who
were new to the industry and were not
part of the medical scene and then they
limited
the uh licenses and so
a lot of people who wanted to transition
from the
legalish medical market to the more
legal
licensed market were not given that
opportunity
but then as you all are experiencing
down there they started cracking down on
everybody else who doesn't have a
license and so it became
the people who were growing for the
medicinal market
and doing so with some amount of legal
protections
now don't have the stores to take their
product
and also are under much greater risk and
so we've seen this
we've seen this change from there being
maybe two dozen significant
you know traditional market growers back
in the day
and then you know a whole bunch of small
things but you know two dozen big ones
and granted we only have about
10 000 people on the island um and that
transition to oh my gosh
you know several hundred uh medical
growers on the island
but now the the
commercial scale black market
unlicensed folks are mostly gone
on the island and the medical people are
definitely gone because there's no
stores to sell into but what we have
now is a lot more people growing for
their own head
so you've got a lot of people who used
to be afraid to grow
you know five or ten plants for
themselves a lot more people
doing that for themselves so we've got a
much more decentralized grow for
yourself
environment here on the island and
the people who are not growing for
themselves are either buying in the
still existing you know heritage market
on the island
or honestly people go to the two stores
even though the prices are high and can
you believe it we don't test for
pesticides in washington
people the convenience and the variety
is really great because you you don't
find a lot of people growing sativas on
the island because
they can't grow outdoors here and not a
lot of people want to spend
12 or 13 weeks of electricity um
to essentially get the same for
the same price as you would a bag of
indica
or uh and so the market's really changed
here it's it's a very unusual thing
yeah one of the things that i want to
just recognize washington for
i think he's also a member of your
community
is it david rice he did he came from
humboldt
originally but one of the things is sun
grown if washington had not passed sun
grown with their legalization it might
have been harder for us in california
believe it or not
and i'm like really that was um jimmy
moberg from canistel farms
he also had a lot to do with getting sun
growing into washington
and i believe that that also helped us
here in california
i agree jeremy moberg is a he's a force
to be
reckoned with he uh he not only is a you
know high
energy person who does a lot of research
but um he doesn't take no for an answer
very often
and he's got a lot of inertia behind him
and so
i've i've interviewed him on my first
podcast on
for entrepreneur and we talked at length
about the importance of
sun grown both for cannabis culture but
also it was important to not
make all flour have to be grown indoor
with electricity i mean eventually we're
going to be growing indoor
with solar but the batteries are not
quite there yet but we will get there
eventually and the
you know one of the worst parts of
indoor will you know be gone and that'll
be great for everybody
but uh but you're right activists like
jeremy and
the sun growers association and of
course all of the
uh beautiful sun grown people that
you've got down there
it really took us working together
because you know
the politicians mostly they want what is
the minimum
that they have to put on the line to
make
this happen and doing the bare minimum
to protect yourself politically is
really
not going to necessarily make the best
policy
and for them to say okay we're going to
allow cannabis but oh gosh
people might get it outdoors so you have
to do it under lock and key in buildings
that is a that is a crisis of vision
that is people who are not
choosing to learn the bigger picture
um or they are being influenced by
indoor lobbyists
yeah i i think there's a lot of
influence going on
by lobbyists and i also think there's
some amount of
you know um kind of back pedaling that
the politicians have to do because
there's been so many decades of
stigmatizing cannabis but now that
it's so widely recognized and accepted
it's really hard for them to just be
like oops our bad
okay all cool just go and do you it's
more like well we're not going to
necessarily say this isn't dangerous
we're going to say that maybe you need
it if you
have a medical condition but we still
need to be
you know conscientious of keeping the
children
safe and you know there's really at
least in in california and a lot of the
western states
this real push of um
you know safety and environmental
concern
which are all very legit but it's funny
to talk about environmentalism and then
still allow you know so much indoor
cultivation
uh but yeah anyway i'm not gonna go too
far down that road because that's just a
whole wormhole
in and of itself but i definitely think
that sun grown
and outdoor is you know obviously kind
of where we need to be pushing
and having things like autoflowers is
something that could help those smaller
growers get through
some of these processes to to get to
where they would like to be which is
maybe just doing full term outdoor
there's one thing there's one thing
challenging about autoflowers that's
worth mentioning
and that is the fact that you cannot
clone autoflowers
and so there is an increased price uh
to growing uh auto flowers because
uh you know so much so many of us will
we will hunt for
the particular mom or moms that we
really like and then we will
clone heavily and now we have those
plants
but with autoflowers since you cannot
clone them
you have to germinate your seed
and most people germinate it in the
final
pot or or ground if that's what they're
going to do because they don't
transplant well and that means that
instead of
buying one pack of seeds and hunting it
for mothers and making
a few hundred or more clones off of that
you're if you want
600 plants you need to buy 600 seeds
and so there that is something for
people
to be aware of as well because that's
that's that is
not that's not a convenient aspect of
autos
so so shango you said if you want 600
plants you have to buy 600 seeds are
these being feminized or are they
straight run
both both um you know certainly the
feminized autoflower seeds
um are a hotter property and they are
more popular and they sell more
because generally the people who are
growing autoflowers in the first place
have got space time
or just convenience issues and man there
is nothing
more sad than you know mentoring or
helping out
a cannabis patient who grows seven
plants
and then four or five of them end up
being male
and they have to call them right and
then now they're down to two gosh that's
such a sad thing
and so the the kinds of people who are
are first to experiment with autoflowers
they're mostly getting feminized seeds
because they want to know
if they grow seven seeds they're going
to have seven medicine producing
plants and so certainly there are lots
of regular
um you know male female seeds available
in the autoflower market and they're
fabulous
uh but they're all those are not for
everybody either
we had a call in question from someone
who said that
everyone he knows who grows autoflowers
has a problem with hermaphrodites
could you call it that was certainly a
problem back in the day right um you
know
um i don't you know i can't ask the
caller
you know how many of their friends and
where do they live and what seeds do
they use and how long ago was that
but um you know hermaphrodites can
show up in regular seeds and in femme
seeds and in
autoflower seeds it's sloppy breeding
and you can sloppy breed in anything
um the sloppier stuff that i've received
from people yeah i'll see some bananas
right
um but i'll see some bananas in my
regular stuff as well from a sloppy
breeder so i would say
you know where you're getting your seeds
make sure they know what they're doing
and buy good genetics
i was gonna say there's been something
going on lately also because we have
some legacy cultivars that we've been
growing for
you know forever and still managed to
get
some real hermaphrodism this year and
i i don't know i i've talked with a lot
of people that are like what is going on
because this isn't normal
there's been i've seen quite a few grows
now a surprising number
that grew really good genetics from
really good breeders
and ended up having all kinds of very
bizarre things
happening the most notable was
a early bloom where it did not come out
of flower but then it started putting
out vegetative branches and then those
would go into bloom and that would put
out another vegetative branch
wow so they were getting all this like
different
kind of like a consecutive planting of
corn but it was all one plant
and and it was like i've i've seen that
once about five or six years ago with a
cultivar that we got
out of china creek and and it grew great
for the first year and it grew great for
the second year and the third year i did
exactly that and i've never seen it
since
until this year when i know four growers
different cultivars one of them
didn't tell me who the genetics or
cultivar was but at least two breeders
not related and so i and
well while i do agree that most
hermaphroditism is sloppy breeding
or it's a cookie genetic which just has
that tendency and then not good
cultivation strategies and their
cultural methodology is off and they're
you know
have light leaks and weird weirdness of
that sort
or watering issues but um but yeah it
kind of is interesting to see that
there's some weird things happening this
year too
and again i don't know with the
hermaphroditism and the autoflowers if
that's
something like you were saying if that
was current or
previous we never experienced that with
autoflowers way back in the day but
um like i said i only played with them
once and and then i was
not going to mess with it again for your
listeners who are very much interested
in um
plants that hermaphrodite or more
technically become intersex
um the podcast that i host
shaping fire we had a really good
interview recently
with uh with cannabis breeder ryan lee
also known as chimera and he goes uh
into detail about female only breeding
and we we talk at length about uh
what causes uh plants to go intersex and
the the variety
of pressures that could be put on a
plant to cause them
to to show um you know
both genders and so folks might want to
check that out uh if
if they're you know if they're nerds
about uh hermaphroditism
which uh which episode is that against
chango uh i wish i knew the number i'm
i'm gonna guess it's like uh
65. uh i don't know it off the top of my
head
but it's with ryan lee ryan lee okay
perfect i haven't heard that one yet
i'll have to i'll have to backtrack a
little bit i've been
working and not listening very much to
anything so
but yeah it's definitely an interesting
aspect
so far so good on my in-house genetics i
didn't have
any hermaphrodite going on or any
branches but
yeah interesting if there's any other
colors and colors
there are a few minutes to call into the
radio show and we can't
put you on the air but our engineer br
can take your questions and we can get
to you
get to it and the number is nine two
923-3911
so thank you caller i appreciate that
for bringing that up
you were asking earlier about you were
asking earlier about um
growing in the pacific northwest and um
uh
it's it's fun because most people
consider uh
indoor originating here in the pacific
northwest
and the first big jumps and lights um
you know starting here and and i must
admit i have not
dug deeply into that histories but um
it's it's a it's a common thing for me
to hear
even when i'm down in your area at
emerald cup people talking about
the early tech and and best practices
coming out of indoor
in this area and so you know we've got
really great indoor
in washington um but
when we have a good summer it's it's so
much more preferable to get the wide
open terpene profiles that you get under
the sun and of course it's
less expensive and it's easier to hide
and
um you know it just feels good to grow
in the ground
versus indoors or or in a tent
but one thing we've been experiencing is
that even though
the pacific northwest is going to be a
good
place to live for you know the rest of
my lifetime anyway
there is no doubt that the climate is
changing and so
um we are we will eventually have
um longer hotter summers
more like southern oregon but for the
moment
we are experiencing the increasingly wet
winters which means that uh when we used
to just
get like oh a little spot of rain the
end of september a little spot the first
week or two of october
and then about october 15th the rains
really started
our cold our nights going below 55
started six
weeks ago and our rain started four
weeks ago
and certainly there is a seasonal
variation
but but when you listen to the
meteorologists they're saying wow
every year the rains are starting
earlier and earlier
and and and that's another
benefit of autoflowers is that if if
your medicine
or your income is based on bringing in
agriculture it's a great idea to
have some autoflowers going as a backup
plan
in case like this year we have the worst
weather that we've had in a decade
for growing outdoor full-term cannabis
here and people are losing
you know easily 60 70 of their
outdoor uncovered plants even in hoop
houses because we've had so much fog and
cold
nights that puts the substrate to sleep
and so but the people who also um
had auto flowers and they hedged their
luck
they're like yeah you know i'm taking a
hit this year on my full terms
but i pulled in a whole bunch of autos
so
i'll still be able to you know take care
of either my medicine or
their customers uh you know for the time
being
that's interesting i feel like that um
some of the hermaphroditism we're
experiencing this year is because
like for me and most of us that have
been doing this for
quite some time we generally start our
seeds right in mid
february mid to end of february and
those were the plants that most of us
had the most trouble with
and i think it's because our our year
was just so weird this year it was so
cold for so much longer i think that the
plants possibly
kind of thought it was going into winter
and then all of a sudden it was summer
and then they just got confused and
you know that can just warp those kind
of that epigenetical potential of
a plant um so interesting you guys
you guys are getting our the longer
winters and we're getting these just a
shift of seasons almost
yeah i do remember that cold spell we
had
early early in the spring and
i did plant i did plant later which may
be why i didn't have
many issues with my seeds but yeah i
remember that
hey guys i got another listener question
about autoflowers
and she
i think she direct seated and she said
it took
two weeks longer than she expected and
what's the uh you know how long do they
go
does it depend on the variety because
this one was an og strain
sure well um yeah there's there is a
range there
they seem to depending on the the
original
um the cultivar that you're you're
breeding into
uh that will play a role and then
they're ten they're there are different
reuteralis cultivars that you can go
into and so
loose loosely autoflowers run into
60 90 and 100 day cultivars
mostly i've really only come across good
plants that are
90 to you know 90 to 100 days
and when i say good i mean i'm looking
for bigger plants there's there's
fantastic small plants that are 60 days
but that's just really not enough time
to get big for you know the kind of
effort that i'm looking for the when
the plants take longer when direct
seeded it's usually because the plant is
not being kept warm enough now certainly
i don't know what your
what the caller is doing but we
experienced that here ourselves a lot of
people tried to start their autoflower
seeds may first this year
and it was cold here um until
uh second week of june and
and so a lot of people who direct seeded
uh
in the beginning of may their plants
just sat there as sprigs until
june and then they started going off and
they they weren't entirely successful
whereas people who waited a month to
june 1st
so they direct seeded into a warm
substrate where
you know the microbe life was alive they
popped right up and these were the same
seeds right they popped some of them in
may and some of them in june
and so keeping the substrate warm i
don't think that in most cases
substrates are going to be you know as
warm in may in most parts of the country
one of the workarounds that we've used
is to
even though the plants don't like to be
transplanted
if you want to grow in the ground which
is always warmer you can start
in a 1 gallon and let the plant start
indoors and then in the first say
two two and a half weeks then go ahead
and transplant it outside that way the
you can transplant outdoors without
disturbing the root zone
and a lot of people get away with that
but you wanna you wanna make sure you
keep that root zone
so shango you've said a few times that
they don't like being transplanted
is that just that they're going through
some heavy transplant shock
or what what happened why what's the
deal with the transplanting
yeah that's exactly it it's the
transplant shock these plants don't live
very long
and we're all used to with photos we
transplant them
it slows them down for you know a little
bit and then they just come on right
back and that's no problem
but if a plant's only going to live for
90 days the
transplant shock slows them down enough
to make them really
you know disappointing plants so
when using autoflowers you want to do
your best to
transp or germinate in the soil you're
going to stay at and you don't want to
disturb
the roots and so you want to pack your
your one gallon
a little more tightly so that when you
if you were to transplant
into a larger container or the ground
that you don't
disturb the roots that will be in the
interior
of the soil so could you do a direct
seed and it seems to me like thinking
back to some traditional
agriculture what we used to do way back
in the day was you have these little
things called cloches or hot caps
and you would put that over your tomato
to germinate your tomato in ground
earlier and it was just like it created
a tiny miniature greenhouse
so i'm wondering uh if that would be
something that might work for that or if
you think it would still be
too cold regardless no i think that's a
great idea actually
um and and what's interesting too is
that uh
when we are direct seeding outdoors
we run into many more
mice and bird problems because normally
when we go outside we're already to
a you know 12 inch or more clone that
is not as susceptible to mouse and bird
but when you're putting an autoflower
seed that is this like delicious
newly alive morsel
uh birds and mice uh are way more likely
to attack them um uh once you what
four years ago or so um we lost like you
know 30
of these plants and it's like you know
when you're when you're buying them
right off the shelf and you're paying 10
bucks a seed
that that hurts you know and so i think
the idea of
a cloche or um you know a lot of people
just
take um you know plastic two-liter
bottles that would normally go into the
trash or the recycling
and they'll they'll cut off the bottoms
of those now certainly that's not gonna
work at commercial scale
but for somebody who's gonna do ten
plants in their yard that'll be great
yeah absolutely that's uh it's i mean
commercial scale even if
you're still paying ten dollars a seed
i don't know that starts to lose its
attractiveness pretty rapidly for me
at commercial levels you're not paying
ten dollars a seed though right
you're paying ten dollars a seed if
you're buying a pack right
um yeah at a commercial level if you're
buying a hundred or a thousand seeds
uh those seeds are more down like two or
three bucks
uh and uh you you might have a
um you know a a a commercial volume you
have to buy at that rate
but the vast majority still like like
we're all saying they're they're
the autoflower folks fall into two
categories patients and home growers who
are buying
like one or two or more packs and
they're growing those
or commercial scale people
and they are buying in in you know 100
500 or 5 000
counts and so they're very different
markets and honestly they're they're
different types of seeds too
there's far more variety in the um
in the i don't know the the patient and
home grower market than there are people
who
are creating uh large-scale seeds like
you know by far the the top commercial
grower or breeder is oregon's cbd seeds
that makes
plants for the hemp market and their
minimum buy is 5 000
seeds whereas you get to somebody who's
making
high quality thc plants
uh like daniel from hard rock mountain
you know he's doing 100 and 500 packs
into the light
licensed market um and much less that
you're going to buy one pack at a
dispensary
right absolutely so hey
i noticed that we're good
i was just going to say i noticed we're
getting to the top of the hour uh can i
plug a couple things before we suddenly
close
well you do fantastically so so
so um first i'd like to uh plug the
podcast so
um if if you are interested in
interviews with the top
minds in cannabis uh with an eye
towards regenerative first and patience
i encourage you to check out
my podcast shaping fire where we focus
on
uh cultivation technique uh solvent list
and hashing technique
and a lot of patient focused medical
cannabis topics
you can find that at shapingfire.com or
wherever you download your podcasts
we also have a very successful youtube
channel with over 200 videos
of different speakers and events that i
attend i just bring those back and
upload them to the youtube channel
and you can find that on youtube either
by searching
fire or my name shango lowe's and if
you're really into the autoflower topic
um there have been a couple odd more
autoflower episodes on shaping fire that
are
in depth but then on the youtube channel
there's also
uh videos of jeff lowenfels the soil
specialist talking about autoflowers
seth crawford from oregon cbd talking in
detail about the rise of the autoflower
market
and so just want to direct folks that uh
you know most people
enjoy listening to a podcast while
they're trimming or working in the
garden
and i invite you to check out
shapingfire.com and hang out with us
you that's amazing
i was telling people before you came on
that um i was not a fan of podcasts
until i found shaping fire and all of a
sudden
the whole world of you know all of the
information on podcasts became it just
shifted and i was like this is amazing i
had
no idea that there were podcasts like
that out there
and even if you're a commercial
cultivator and you go back to the
beginning of
of fire um episodes there's just really
important amazing stuff
[Music]
on the podcast and thank you so much for
having me on the show
thank you