hey everybody welcome back today we are
here with shingle loose and we are super
excited because he came all the way down
from Washington to see us he has a
podcast called shaping the fire and he
is the founder of Vashon Island
marijuana enthusiast Alliance it's a
really long name well first let's um the
podcast is actually shaping fire not
evil fart yet said shaping fire calm so
the Vashon Island marijuana
entrepreneurs Alliance was a trade
organization that started about five
years ago when medical was still in
Washington and and and what we did is we
found that so many of the growers on the
island were just selling against each
other on this on the island and so the
prices were crashing and we had on
familiar we had really great prices on
our island so I recognized this because
my friends raw growers I said let's
let's organize and start creating a
channel to dispensaries all around the
state so that's what we did ever all the
timers started working together and
group buying you know soil and nutrients
and things like that and and everybody
was happy because their prices went down
and the amount they got the further
flour went up unfortunately though
everything's changed now because they
killed medical in Washington tried to
roll it in so far unsuccessfully in
recreational and so all of those
heritage growers had to make a decision
about whether or not they wanted to just
stop being in cannabis or if they wanted
to go back to a black market and that's
a really hard decision for anybody to
make when this is something you've been
doing your whole life and it's why your
kids can go to summer camp right because
you've got this extra money yeah yeah
was that transition like when you talk
about this heritage transition to
commercial growing can you kind of touch
on that sure well originally when the
laws got passed they promised all the
medical people that they would have an
opportunity in the licensed cannabis
market and people were pretty skeptical
yeah promised right and unfortunately
what happened is that when when it
finally came time about the licenses
almost none of them were original
heritage medical people like just a
handful and it was it was a real
travesty they were more interested in
giving the money to a higher capitalized
folks from other industries when they
were making their qualification choices
right and so what they did is they took
a
preexisting you know it could use some
more regulation but you know it could a
pre-existing market with professionals
who already have the relationships set
them all aside and then install this
whole new system with all new people
from other industries and and you know a
lot of those companies hired medical
folk but but this is you know trying to
make good out of a difficult situation
and and the people who were with us
through the dark times and through
Prohibition who put in all the real work
over the decades most of those folks got
pushed out how does that well well where
I live on Vashon you know we went from
having a hundred and fifty six small
businesses that are all run by families
to having for larger licensed operations
right and you know the people who run
those operations on our island they're
actually very nice people right so we're
not against that but it's the fact that
so many people were pushed out and we're
no longer included right especially
since they're the people who who made
cannabis what it is right very similar
to what we're experiencing in the
Emerald triangle currently yeah well I
noticed yesterday the news that they
removed the one acre cap and that I mean
what that's going to do to shape
California cannabis is astonishing
you you've all the protections for
artisan growers for for specialty folks
yeah absolutely it's just a shame and so
they're gonna be supplanted by these
bigger folks I thought the idea to give
them five years to get the market set
for artists that was a really really
good idea I really wish that they had at
least given us the five year head start
ultimately it was why a lot of my family
and friends decided to go legal
I mean stepping from the black market
into a transparent world is really hard
if it's all you go back go back you know
and I mean you just can't you know and
so having that that cap would are the
the five-year limit would have been
really nice but either way um we really
love what you're doing
we appreciate you not only can'
educating the consumer but also trying
to you know organize groups to kind of
help the people who that's all they've
ever known stay protecting the integrity
of the Kim
growers need somebody to defend them and
since I will not a grower myself but all
my friends are growers I figured it'd be
a good opportunity to help folks who you
know growers they spend so much time
with the plant they don't necessarily
want to be out there in the front I just
want to be a load and to do their craft
right and I figure out well it's
something I can do to help thanks really
awesome that's really great of you and
not not only do they you know the only
thing that they've been doing is is
growing and they do it considerably well
but now they're branding and becoming a
marketer and who do you sell I mean
there's all these other facets that have
come into that and so it's really nice
to hear that there are people like
yourself out there helping yeah you know
and it sounds like this podcast is a
platform that that you're using to get
this information to your community and
beyond can you talk about the podcast
yeah thanks for asking yeah so it's the
shaping fire podcast at shaping fire
calm and every week I talk with some of
the top minds in international cannabis
from Kevin Jodrey of course he was on
the show recently talking about the
history of CBD and and where the
original plants came from and you know
dr. Ethan Russo talking about they know
cannabinoid system terpene profiles
right and so so every week oh and also
from down in this area mean gene has
been on the show from freeborn selection
so so every week I talked to somebody
and and unlike a lot of podcasts we're
not we're not really personality to bass
they're not they're not profile episodes
we take a different topic area every
week and the person speaks to that topic
so every episode is very educational
great yeah so it's a lot of fun Wow
exciting what else let's talk about
educating the consumer so we've been
having this big conversation about
terpenes versus THC do you want to touch
a little bit on this component well when
I was sitting out there in the judges
room earlier we were talking about how
helpful would be for every consumer to
have this kind of a judging experience
because it's so challenging when you're
first getting into cannabis and we're
all attracting all these new enthusiasts
now right yeah but you know they have to
they have to go and they have to spend
retail money to try one strain and then
retail money it's hard to build up your
experience like that if you're new
whereas you come to something like this
and I've got a whole bunch of samples in
front of me well I've got a
a really good understanding of what's
going on and you know probiotic like
Depp in in Northern California but by
the end of the time it would be great
that if anytime anybody comes into
cannabis we're like welcome to smoking
marijuana enjoy your sampler pack so you
can find out you know what you like what
works for you yeah absolutely no such a
great entry because it's hard when you
have to pay your you know 10 to 15
dollars a gram at a retail just to learn
what you like wouldn't that be nice if
we could access cannabis medicine in
that form because our brains are all
wired differently our experiences are
all wired differently we're arriving
differently on an individual 11 level
and so yeah I love that concept I think
we should push your scenario maybe get a
medical come to the tribe the other
thing I was laughing about as I was
walking up to chat with you too is that
um you know normally when you're at a
party and and and you've got your your
cannabis you like you don't want to say
leave it on a table somewhere but
there's so much out there because
everyone everybody's judging so much
that I'm like yeah my my stuff is safe
right where it is out in the open no
it's gonna yeah totally so that's funny
hilarious I love it okay wow it's so
great that you're here we're thrilled to
be here with you so just to sort of wrap
things up is there anything else you
want to throw out there in reference to
just where we're at with golden tarps
and well you know I heard that this set
really took a lot of effort to put
together and they were talking about all
that all the effort that that you know
the team and how long people have been
here they're that they're probably good
story behind that there Ryan truly is
where's the package so we're gonna head
up to the mate'll let's let's go check
on my sister
[Laughter]