so they utilize it mr. Peter Tosh their
famous song we love him you're listening
to voice of Vashon this is borderlines
and guess what we're doing a 420 show
because it's 420 I have on the air with
me mr. Shengo loose hello happy day to
you it's been a keynote in a lot of
stuff last time I met you Shango your
head was in a beehive I was like four
years ago and then and then things
happened and we went on this trajectory
and it found you it seems like yeah not
doing quite as much beekeeping anymore
but spending most of my time traveling
the country doing business consulting
and teaching how to use cannabis for
health responsibly additionally in the
destination legally you obviously great
so I'm so excited to have you here thank
you okay so bringing it on to a much
more micro level we have very relevant
to today very well timed thanks for
coming in on very short notice like hey
you want to come talk with me well
that's the that's the advantage of
working from home and working on the
island right if you want meet I'm here
boom and one thing that's on the table
right now on this little wee island of
ours is possible marijuana Bam and the
county's is hearing different opinions
right now Shango why don't we would you
need some finer points about what this
is sure sure I'll break it down so um
for this for the sake of clarity since
that's why you have you have me here
let's address the word damn right sure
because you know on the Facebook pages
people are saying we'll wait did varsa
really ask for a ban or do they just ask
for restricted zoning and and and that's
where that's where the rut is right
because as of right now and the reason
why there is no cannabis store on the
island today right is that the zoning is
already incredibly restricted on the
island the cannabis store would have to
be in a commercially zoned location okay
and then it also has to be a thousand
feet from any kind of licensed daycare
or school well because we've got a
downtown for that's pretty much the
whole downtown core yeah and then if you
look at the other parts of the island
you know Burton's not legal the docked
in stores too far Sal's a 2 and it's too
far south to say in business and it's
for sale not for rent the old portage
stores in bad shape and has most likely
reverted to residential zoning because
it's not used as commercial variants in
so many years kind of mocking and
there's nothing really appropriate in
your mingle MIT so that just means
downtown core and so you know in my role
as the founder of the cannabis Trade
Organization on the island vinia you
know when everybody was hot to trot for
getting their licenses and everything
you know I was approached by five or six
different groups to help them find a
location on the island yeah and so we
dug out the king county parcel viewer
and talked to landowners and and you
know worked out all the numbers and
realized that there's really only about
four locations on the island that could
actually even have a recreational store
and those are already occupied by
longtime bachelor on businesses yes so
in essence even if someone were to have
a license there's not really a location
today to put it okay and so we are left
with scratching our heads and going how
can we how are we going to do this
exactly and so the challenge with the
varsity posle was that they want to they
want to make it even more restrictive so
that there couldn't be a store here in
the downtown area if a location were to
arise and and and so that becomes a band
right because then that makes it 00
possibility so so you know they
certainly don't call it a ban and and
I've spoken with the vice president of
varsa this morning we had a nice
hour-long conversation and that was not
their intention right no they mostly
just want to you know keep cannabis out
of the hands of children which I support
that and and they feel that you know you
kind of have to be close to zero
tolerance so that we don't set a poor
example for children and that that we
have some difference of opinion on
tolerance because you know my role is as
a patient advocate and and for me I talk
to and work with patients on Vashon who
get relief every day from Canada's from
their Parkinson's or they're using it to
cure their cancer or they're using it
for their arthritis or they use it
topically for eczema or you know all of
these different people they come to me
and we talked and then i recommend for
them products in that they can get over
town and say I can't a West Seattle
which is a kind of us an ally of ours I
guess I'd say and and and and send them
on their way and and it is uniformly
inconvenient for them to go over town
and some of the patients you know
they're being sick it's expensive and a
lot of these folks they don't have a car
it's hard for them to get over town and
it would be so much more convenient if
we had a location on the island where
adults could get adult use cannabis for
their own enjoyment and you know anxiety
relief and just to have a good time and
patience could get patient-centric
products that they can use to get relief
and unfortunately the the VAR suppose
ille would take it would just allow that
right it was just completely gone and I
do encourage listeners to check out
varsa network o RG /a own to see their
position it's just in fairness and
transparency it's a good idea to see
what they're talking about the main
issues really if you boil it down their
position is that having retailers here
in the commercial zone would would send
a message of access and also community
talk tolerance and they don't want to
set that precedent for kids that's
really what it boils down to in essence
is just just access intolerance and if
you've ever always because I am a parent
of now 18 and 20 year olds but at the
time coming up through school I was not
parent who always got the community
attitudes survey right and I would fill
it out and with great interest I would
be short in that web site where the
findings I want to see I want to see I
didn't know we see them which is really
annoying cuz i have for your blood sweat
and tears and 10 pages that you know
into clicking on all these things and i
want to know I want to know how we roll
what is our island sentiment really and
even then there's little nuggets on the
website it would be really good to see
the entire thing
yeah yeah it certainly would be and you
know one of the interesting aspects
about it is that you know when when I
was speaking with them this morning I
was pointing out that you know if their
goal is truly to keep cannabis out of
the hands of children the best thing to
do would be actually to support a retail
store on the island because there's no
chance that kids are going to go in and
purchase cannabis at a store because
every single canister the store in the
state is on pins and needles just trying
to keep their license in fact in the
last study in Washington showed that
cannabis stores were ninety-four percent
compliant last year and that's ten
percent better than liquor stores were
and as we saw when we had Kevin burgundy
aerosol dispenser on Islands the the
amount of gray market growers
drastically decreased because people
like to be able to go to one location
where they can get their same strain of
preference for or their medicine in a
repeatable fashion and anybody who's
ever you know gone to buy pot from
somebody you know this is a different
strain every time I mean you have to
meet them on their schedule and it's you
know it's not as convenient as a retail
location and so the the studies that
have been done in both Washington and
Colorado show very clearly that when you
create a retail store youth access goes
down because it's sub-plan it's a good
part of the gray market and as an
Islander I mean everybody knows
everybody and you see it kind of walking
past the shop you're gonna know and it's
gonna be like somebody on the other side
of the islands are going to know you
know quickly yeah those things get
around here really so you can go tiptoe
and be stealth there's no hiding so I
like that idea because I mean you're
either out there and it's legal or it's
not and it does take kind of that that
gray area straight away and I love that
one of the interesting aspects of this
though is that while I thought it was
important to to alert our community to
varsus policy and how they were trying
to influence the zoning through the
community plan there really isn't there
never really was any likelihood that the
VAR suppl and was going to get adopted
I mean you know it's important for
people to participate in their democracy
and email you know Bradley Clark at King
County to to to voice their opinion but
King County was very clear that they do
not want to make a zoning cut out on
Vashon it's the same thing that happened
when editor wanted to move into k2 they
were very clear that they didn't want to
change the zoning for EDD appear to make
it unlike everywhere else in the county
similarly except now it's on the flip is
is you know our good friend councilman
joe McDermott he was very clear leg
listen we're not going to make a cut out
for Vashon Island just to make it more
restrictive than the rest of King County
and as we've been making the community
plan no version of it had an increased
restriction that being said as a
passionate patient advocate I needed to
make sure that you know we died of the
i's and cross the t's and people wait in
because you know a of concerned parents
can do a lot of damage sometimes hahaha
so I'm that parent that had weed tests
in my house because guess what they work
they totally work and that I think is
one of the best ways that you can nip
things in the bud kind of 100 is not
intended but they slip out I'm a
copywriter and you know I Harold that
right because you know even though some
people might think that giving your kids
a UA is invasive you are doing
responsible parenting in your home you
know the that kind of instruction should
come from the parent in the home and it
should not be something that should be a
island-wide regulatory issue correct
correct I think there's a lot to be said
for just starting at home and here's the
thing complete disclosure has there been
weeding my house absolutely do I have a
neurologist absolutely chief neurology
at Swedish is the first person that says
let's write this into your medical plan
if gabapentin isn't working for you I
have chronic my lightest I was looked at
in 2009 for probable MS and i still have
lesions on my spinal cord and it causes
whole lot of chaos I live with it every
day but did I have weed in my house have
I absolutely have I had some really
honest conversations with my children
had to yeah when and similarly you know
when I moved to the island you know the
reason why I finally made the jump I had
been coming here for years to visit and
volunteer on the organic food farms but
I finally made the jump after my brain
injury I had a traumatic brain injury
from a dual concussion and my
neurologist as well he's all like I
really think that medical marijuana
would be good for you and so I looked
into it and and you know it helped me
with my migraines and and it helped me I
don't know reset my neural net you know
one of the things that a lot of people
don't understand about medical marijuana
is you know it is not a bunch of people
smoke and joints I mean certainly
smoking is the appropriate medicine for
a lot of people no doubt but the vast
majority of them are going to be looking
for something to take orally you know
like us like a tincture and sometimes
inedible and there's so many different
ways that you can take medical cannabis
it's not it's not no it's not just for
stoners anymore right honestly it didn't
used to be either now the cannabis was
seventy percent of the pharmacopoeia
before it was prohibited and you know we
had used it as a society for thousands
of years and then it became politically
unpopular and here we are today and here
we are today let's get really
politically unpopular and play a song by
black uhuru sinsemilla we'll be back
right on black o mu stalk of sensimilla
and depending on where you look on
itunes you'll see it since Amelia since
Amina since Amelia sinsemilla you take
your pics here's a fun factoid do you
want to know what that is it's not as
important as it used to be but you know
in the in the 70s and stuff when
cannabis was coming from the tropic
areas they were growing it in these huge
fields and they didn't separate the boys
from the girls and so the girls would
get pollinated and they would start to
grow seeds and then they would just
harvest those and ship I'm here to the
United States well then it became the
Super
premium cannabis that they would go
through and when they started showing
sex they would pull out all the boys so
that the females would not spend their
plant energy making seeds and so they
started shipping seedless marijuana to
the United States and that blew
everybody away so that was the thing but
now as the US has developed its own
industry endure during prohibition and
now outdoor as well no seeds is kind of
an assumption it's like that's the given
yeah that's the standard and seeds have
to be sent out yeah that's true and
they're hard to find good ones sometimes
a good seat is hard to find you know
let's go back to what we were talking
about a little while ago the
quote-unquote marijuana ban on Vashon
Island and people have an opportunity to
make their voices heard one of them is
this evening yeah it is yeah this
evening is our islands yearly Town Hall
so the meeting is not specifically about
cannabis zoning but councilman McDermott
will be there the sheriff will be there
and in various other King County folks
you know and so we vas heights are
invited to show up and sign up and we
can speak on anything you want so if you
if you want to talk about law
enforcement on my own or zoning or
cannabis or the homeless issue or
whatever you can show up and that's
tonight at mcmurry middle school from 6
30 to 8 30 and I know that a lot of
folks in in favor of allowing cannabis
on the island are showing up and you
know even even if you're in favor of
those owning I just encourage people to
show up and voice your democratic rights
participate in the process certainly
since I'm an advocate for cannabis I
hope more of our people show up but but
that's important and you know also if if
you can't make it to the meeting you can
also email Bradley Clark I think you've
got the email address there i do is
Bradley it's be Radl ey Clark CLA RK at
king county gov and Brad's a really nice
guy so don't feel like you have to like
you know get all the hemet with him
about a potential ban you
a really nice guy he's objective and
he's just collecting our communities
feedback to give to King County Council
before they vote perfect that's awesome
I would love to hear about what you're
up to these days well I think you're
specifically talking about the
Kickstarter because you know Ivan I
travel the country now and I do know
keynote addresses at canvas conventions
and and do consulting for new startups
and mostly I teach medical care
providers both both licensed doctors and
naturopaths how to use cannabis in the
clinic but specifically this week on
monday i launched a media campaign
connected with a kickstarter and the
idea behind it is that it's far too
common that visitors come into a home
that have got cannabis edibles in them
and maybe they're in the fridge maybe
they're in a you know in a pantry or
something but they're unlabeled and so
the babysitter or the grandma you know
looks at the treats are like those look
like good treats I would like to eat
that brownie or that bag of gummy bears
or whatever it is and so and so they go
ahead and eat them and it is until after
the fact when they're uncomfortably
medicated that that they realize that
they that they were that they're getting
high and so what's the I pulled together
you know nearly a hundred so far of the
top cannabis companies in the country
who wanted to support you know labeling
in the home and we started this
Kickstarter which is simply is just
providing stickers to people to label
their container that they keep their
edibles in in their home and you know a
lot of people say well aren't there
already warning stickers on the on the
canvas packages well sure that's true
but you know people ignore them people
take that take the edibles out of it
people make brownies at their own home
the point is is that we want to start a
new habit in the scene we want to make
it a new assumption that if you have
cannabis edibles in your home you have
them in a container that is labeled from
the outside so that we decrease the
likelihood that visitors to our home
like babe users will accidentally be
medicated because it's just nobody wins
when somebody gets accidentally
medicaid's especially if they get over
medicated
really unpleasant if somebody if anybody
wants to look into it you can check out
that Kickstarter there's a instead of
giving it a very long Kickstarter link
you can just go to my website at WWF
Iron that's Sh ap ing F IR e.com forward
slash Kickstarter and it will go ahead
and and and forward you to the page and
you know you can get you can get you
know stickers for your home for as
little as five bucks and you know if you
if you are as you manage a you know a
parent organization on the island there
are larger packages for you in case you
want to get them and have them available
for your members it's just a way for the
cannabis industry businesses cannabis
enthusiasts and patients to all work
together to address this issue that is
becoming more common because simply
there's more cannabis and more homes now
than at any point since Prohibition and
it's something that we can we can
decrease the likelihood odd so we are I
have a feeling you're going to get
support on both sides of the fence where
this is concerned I totally agree guy
obviously people who are cannabis
positive they want to keep their
grandmas and babysitters from accident
going dose but but also you know
concerned parent types or folks that are
more concerned about cannabis at all
they're supporting it as well actually
we just launched on Monday and so we're
only four days in we're only we're
already twenty five percent of the way
to our goal because the supports been
pretty heavy-duty this is a great time
to let you know that the views and
opinions expressed on this program are
not necessarily those of the board staff
underwriters or donors a voice of a jean
and as an organization vov does not take
political positions we do support our
show host like me and their guests in
expressing their views as long as
they're not obscene or hate mongering
thanks for listening I think we'll be
avoiding this obscenities and hate
mongering today let's do that actually
funny fact I had quite a time because I
wanted to bring rap for 20 songs in as
well as reggae good luck finding a clean
one and there was a lot of ease down the
play was known I was going oh come on
alright i would like to move in to
another song but before that I want to
let you know that voice of a Sean will
record tonight's town-hall meeting and
it will be on voice of ash on television
and on boards VaShawn 0rg so if you
can't make it please tune in either to
the TV component or the radio component
and we got you covered all right let's
move back into it greetings from ja from
half pint will be back with Shango one
more time half pint greetings I bring
from Jah I wish I could do pot twice so
lame at it you are here in the studio
with me Heidi and Shengo loose LOL oh
and we are talking about all kinds of
things related to marijuana first we
started with vashon we started a little
bit into what chango is doing between
educating the educators basically and
and being a keynote everywhere and if
you go look at his website under events
the man is prolific he's everywhere it's
crazy I don't know when you're here like
I'm gonna actually freak out the next
time I say oh my God he's actually only
11 well luckily I mean I try to leave
the island as little as possible because
that's why I moved here yeah get out of
the city I tend to travel to speak off
the island about twice a month or so I
try to not do it more than that but then
you know you add a zinnia meeting like
actually this is a good point i should
plug the upcoming vimeo meeting so on
may 18th it's a thursday night at the
Grange Hall which is located in the
north end ferry dock parking lot at 7pm
we are having a guest speaker up from
Portland it's going to be a great fellow
by the name of Ben casa de and the topic
is all about terpenes and cannabis
aromatherapy what a lot of people don't
realize is you know they know about THC
and CBD as two components of cannabis
THC being the part that makes you feel
high and cvd the part that replenishes
your endocannabinoid system but they
don't realize that the smell of the
plant is actually incredibly healing as
well for you and so Ben's going to be
coming up and speaking to to everybody
who shows up
about how terpenes affect your body how
to use terpenes in your everyday life
even without cannabis and to help people
kind of choose the terpenes that they
might want when shopping for Canada's
awesome yeah it's going to be a great I
ask a question sure a few questions
what's the scoop these days on growing
your own sure motto so the overarching
response is that it is illegal to grow
your own cannabis in Washington period
and that's unfortunate because you know
most of the other states they allow
every resident to grow six plants but
here in Washington we did not do that
and so for you to be able to legally
grow at your home you need to have a an
authorization from your medical
authorization from your doctor and so if
you just have that authorization you're
allowed to grow for plants now if you
join the state's registry of patients
that for plants jumps up to six plants
okay and then there's a place at the
bottom of the authorization where you
can your doctor can write in that you
can actually have up to 15 plans if you
show need for it Wow but then you also
have to be on the registry and being on
the registry means that you know they
can come and check out your grow at your
home if they want yeah which I don't
know a lot of people who want to give
out that kind of right you're injured
danger yes so the registry has not been
very successful with the state so far
and so to repeat its for plants if you
have a medical authorization that goes
to six if you join the registry up to 15
with it written on your authorization
but but you know honestly the
enforcement of individual growing is so
low that what we have found on the
island is that you know the traditional
what people think of as black market
growers that were so prevalent on Vashon
in the 80s and 90s you know they have
just decreased and decreased because
first the medical industry was there and
there were there were shops to go to
which decrease the number of black
market growers and now that is also
and with recreational to a certain
degree the prices are still relatively
high in recreational so so you know
there still is price competition there
but um but the rise of growing has been
just individual people you know you know
retired professors you know parents in a
family where either they or their
children have got a medical need folks
who just like to get high and they
believe that they should have the right
so you know people get their hands on
seeds and clones you know one way or
another and then they just you know they
grow a handful plans on their back porch
just for themselves and that actually
has become the highest growing if you
will segment of the growing population
on the island it's a lot less growing
for business anymore and a lot more
people just growing just like they do
their tomato plants it's a DIY MJ very
cool I mean it's it's so for for plants
in the Pacific Northwest any idea what
that means in terms of actual usable
marijuana well goodness you know the
short answer I would say is no because
there's very much very very in the yield
of the plant based on the strain and how
well you tend to you know in the kinds
of nutrients you give you an error yeah
exactly did you think you can you know
you can have a plant that does poorly
and you get an ounce or less over off of
it but that you know you could also grow
a huge plant and get four ounces off it
and feel like a real winner you know
loosely when people push me I say you
know if you do your job right you know
pencil Alex 42 ounces and and when you
do better than that you can pat yourself
on the back yeah okay but honestly most
people they just they grow it because
you know what they say they say cannabis
is the gateway to horticulture because
people who have never really kept a
garden before once they get into
relationship with a cannabis plant and
they and they have that connection with
nature and there they got their hands in
the soil and the I don't know if it's
called husbandry for plants but there
but with the taking care of another life
charm series a very intimate and once
you do that suddenly you have achieved
changed your relationship with all
plants and so I
I see that you know catch on all the
time if that works that's a good thing
what I mean is an anti-anxiety to grow a
plant just adjusters growing in itself
yes and they're done you can either you
know make medicine out of it or a
teacher or edibles or just toke it and
one way or another it's probably
increasing your quality of life they're
actually studies not about growing
marijuana but just having your hands in
the dirt it's very cathartic and same
with being walking in the forest and
taking a jump into peace out I'm a big
fan of forest Baz yeah yeah it's the
thing it is it is a thing shank of us
thank you so much for coming on we're
going to keep the music going any
parting words well I would say you know
voice your opinion get involved with our
local politics come on out tonight if
you can email Bradley Clark if you can't
and and just remember that even if
people are holding an opinion that is
different than yours we're all neighbors
and treat each other with respect thank
you so much hang on thanks for having me
on to the music boys Vachon