check check one hey who's life here is
better because of marijuana right so who
else here knows a patient or a friend
who's getting relief from an ailment
because of cannabis right cannabis is
healing humans and that is the important
part the problem is is last spring House
bill 50 50 to pass which dismantled
medical marijuana in our state right so
now we have to shop at the recreational
stores we've got friends and family who
we love who are not able to access the
specific medical kind of marijuana that
they need at the recreational stores I
mean we all love the smoke weed and
they've got that at their recreational
stores but they don't necessarily have
the medicine you're not going to get
Rick Simpson oi you're not going to get
high CBD tabs I'm Shango low some from
the shaping fire podcast and I also
represent the Trade Organization of bash
on Arab that's one Island marijuana the
important thing for us to remember here
is that just because the legislators
change the law and there and the
regulators have told us that hey man I
know that you've got ailments I know
that your loved ones have got ailments
you just have to stop growing you have
to stop providing from them I don't
think that's legitimate illegitimate
laws are meant unjust laws are meant to
be ignored and that is what I'm
suggesting that you do today ignore the
new laws that set patient limits to only
four plants per person I don't know any
patient that can survive on four plants
a year that means one of two things that
he means that you either have to move
your grown indoors and not grow under
the beautiful sun or you have to grow
outdoors only and
they have four plants a year how are you
going to take care of yourself for an
entire year on for plants you can't do
that even if you're just rolling joints
right got healthy if you have to make
your own RSO you need pounds to be able
to extract it down and concentrate it to
make your RSO to keep your rheumatoid
arthritis at bay to try to solve your
cancer you're not going to do this with
four plants it's frustrating right
because as patients we're constantly
reaching out to our legislators to say
hey we know that need the cats out of
the bag we all know now that cannabis is
healthy it's not hurting us it's not
addictive it doesn't lead to all these
bad reefer madness things we're
concerned about so how are you going to
take the plants back out of the
patient's hands Camaro this is why I
suggest ignore the new rules ignore the
fact that you're only supposed to allow
to have four plants I mean we used to be
able to have 15 and many patients needed
25 for are you kidding me eventually our
state will get in line right all the
other states allow a realistic home grow
as start and then we'll expand from
there six plus plans from there
Washington is a good place retweet we're
at the head of the medical cannabis
movement we should expect that to
continue forward but we need to give
them a little time well alright we're
going to give them a little bit of time
to change their regulations but that
does not mean that we need to stop
growing now for plants keep growing 15
if that's what you need to provide for
yourself and your family and your loved
ones you know what if you need 30 do
that as well the important thing here is
to realize that cannabis is a human
right
does the does the government owned the
plant no does the LCB on the planet no
and it sure as hell is not owned by the
502 stores that are selling the
recreational marijuana we could really
own the plan it's ours and if you are
presently a patient if you are presently
a grower if you presently have family
and loved ones that are growing for each
other I encourage you to continue to
grow ignore the law give a loss some
time to evolve but in until then just
ignore it and go your own way if enough
of us do that we will be secure because
they cannot bust us all and when they
try to bust one after another you know
that that's going to come up in the
press and the press is going to say what
the hell is going on here they say we
have legalization in our state but we do
not have legalization we have
corporatization and commercialization of
the plant they have given us just enough
Liberty just enough Liberty so that they
can get their taxes that's not what it's
about marijuana cannabis is about
healing humans and that is what I
encourage you to do annual ignore the
new laws throw your plans and hold out
until the laws evolve to where we are I
am Shango Lohse if you're interested in
hearing more you can go to my website at
Shea gallows com free the plan thank you