legal marijuana is not something just
for the West Coast anymore Candace
reform is spreading like wildfire now
through the election process last week
licensed adult use marijuana states
expanded to include California Maine
Massachusetts and Nevada on top of the
existing Washington Colorado Oregon and
Alaska that makes eight states
additionally Arkansas Florida Montana
and North Dakota joined the other 25
states where medical cannabis is now
blessed and regulated and taxed Arizona
is the only state to have had a
marijuana initiative on the ballot this
year that failed to pass luckily though
while Arizona adult use didn't pass they
have a pre-existing medical marijuana
law to benefit Arizona patients what
this all means is that there's going to
be a whole lot of cannabis related
rulemaking at the state level in the
next year as we have seen from other
states already though that is likely
going to be an exceptionally messy
process we learn from dr. Dominic
Kaurava on the show two weeks ago that
even though cannabis policy transfer
from other states that are already legal
is becoming more common many of the
legislators and rule makers at the state
level have zero experience and knowledge
of cannabis and they very likely wish
they didn't have to learn about cannabis
at all every state has made cannabis
legalization way more complex than it
needs to be both because they are
unfamiliar with cannabis and rule makers
are still afraid of cannabis and think
it means violent crime will increase
when actually the opposite is true so
what we are certainly going to see going
forward is a patchwork of cannabis laws
that are different from state to state
with this much rulemaking going on all
once you can be assured that there will
be some backdoor deal-making between
legislators law enforcement business
people and others who will seek to exert
undue influence on how cannabis policy
is formed and I ask you who will be
watching these rule makers to ensure
that they follow appropriate laws
concerning governance and rulemaking for
new law no one that's right there is no
one response
to make sure that bureaucratic
regulators are performing their role in
a legal way in fact in Washington State
for example the liquor and cannabis for
has already been found guilty of meeting
secretly with law enforcement and others
but only after citizens caught them
doing it today's show is about citizen
oversight of cannabis law implementation
we are going to consider some of the
ways that lobbyists can try to influence
policy how regulators have attempted to
make rules in the shadows and we will
discuss some citizen oversight
strategies that you can use to help your
state regulators stay honest my guest
today is John Novak founder of 420 leaks
com 420 leaks com is a citizen oversight
organization that focuses on canvas
policy in Washington state their
researchers obtain hard to find
information through public records
requests as well as daily monitoring of
state bills rulemaking local ordinances
and news that will have an effect on
cannabis patients providers and
enthusiasts welcome with the show John
well thanks anko it's good to be here
I'm very appreciative that you asked me
to come on looking forward to it well I
know we've been trying to put this
together for a while I'm glad we finally
you know got a chance to do it so John
you know a lot of people they they kind
of like to have the idea that their
state regulators and legislators are
having their best interests at heart and
they like to just assume that their
government officials are following the
rules but unfortunately you know we know
that is not always the case so why don't
we start by giving a little bit of
context of why 420 leaks is necessary
from your extensive research who are
some of the other groups interested in
influencing cannabis reform at the state
level and why are they trying to
influence it that's a good question
there's of course we have you know all
the local activists who each have their
own issues a lot of it human
rights-based like the you know the home
grows and sharing d scheduling those
kinds of things and of course we have
business interests who are you know
looking out for their bottom line and
regulating the industry in improper ways
and all that kind of stuff and then we
have other tiers of interested parties
and what and those are more the biggest
ones I would say are the state age the
agency lobby firms and associations I
like for instance the association of
Washington cities and counties they have
they all have their big lobby group then
you have 0 for instance that it will be
liquor control board they have their own
lobby group Department of Health will
have their own lobby group and so those
kinds of groups are that's really the
what you see down there and then you
have kind of what i call the hidden
persuaders and they seem to be the ones
that are more from Wall Street firms
that are trying to come in and basically
run the show and we don't really see a
whole lot of their faces you see one or
two but for the most part you don't even
see them at all they do a lot of their
work behind the scenes but the state
agencies those are those have been the
hardest on this and they seem to have
the most impact as far as you know
regulating or i should say wriggling but
um Oh for instance like zoning stuff and
all that kind of stuff and one of the
biggest problems that we hear from those
guys is that they are scared of federal
law they say and implementing any of the
stuff at the state level they believe
leaves them open to prosecution so
that's a lot of the big push that they
have and when NM the other side of it
too is they all rely on federal funds
federal grants you know the Department
of Health gets grants for different
areas of health care
look a control board i'm not sure if
they have federal grant program in place
yet i've been to try to figure that out
but that and the cities in the counties
especially are really tight into that
they receive a lot of federal money so
the question that i'm trying to find out
is is the tax money from 50 to enough to
offset that i'm not quite sure yet so
that's but those are the biggest groups
that have been down there so what I'm
gathering here from from your answer is
that you know every state is going to
have lots of players that are trying to
move that are trying to influence policy
and you know some that you got some that
you're expecting but then like there's a
lot of extra folks with you know
priorities that are kind of in the
shadows and you know I guess it's abuse
is another group that you see a lot of
down there yeah I guess and probably law
enforcement too yeah so so putting
myself in the seat of the regulator or
the legislature who is you know the
target of the influence and also the
target of your research to help keep
them honest you know I guess it isn't
necessarily that they are trying to be
bad actors themselves it's just the fact
that they're being influenced from all
these different directions and you know
we need watchdogs in each state who are
who are making sure that folks are not
bending or breaking the rules in their
influence is that is that a pretty fair
way to look at it is that you know the
watchdog is just looking to make sure
that people are playing by the rules
well you very much so in our state
though keeping an eye on the legislators
is a little bit harder because they have
exempted themselves from most of the
public records so about the only way
that I can get public records on them as
if they were to make like a public
statement about a document that they
used in order to come up with a policy
something along those lines and then I
could ask them hey well I want to see
that document but other than that the
legislators are
pretty much off the boards and you can
ask but they're not under any kind of
requirement to turn over any records so
kind of one of the ways that I get
around that though is I'll go to the
agency side and say I want to see your
communications with no specific
legislators and sometimes I get it
sometimes I don't it's it's just a
matter of you know what what how much in
how much how much information that they
were actually willing to put down on
paper and send back and forth between
each other but as far as keeping tabs on
the legislators one of the better ways
is going to the public disclosure
commission website and following where
all the campaign contributions are going
that that's a very big part of this as
well go ahead so the work that you do is
obviously very arcane you know not a lot
of people know how to request these you
know these documents that you uncover
that that can show the corruption or the
bending of the rules or whatever you're
looking for and and so you know let's go
step by step you know to a certain
degree on how you decide what records
you want because you know you're talking
about getting these records but but
honestly to a novice like me I don't I
don't even know how you do that I mean
all I'm thinking about is that freedom
of information act and I don't even know
if that's the the appropriate you know
rule in this case for folks or who are
seeking to emulate you down the line
kind of just give us a you know a
blueprint of how you you know get these
documents at a state level well let's
start with just 50 to in general when it
passed the state the liquor now it's
called the liquor in cannabis board but
then it was called the Liquor Control
Board and each agency when there when a
when the legislature passes a bill and
puts a rulemaking power into the hands
of the state agencies like
was done with 50 to then the Liquor
Control Board go through a process of
gathering as much information from
various sources including the public
normally and and then they will put
together a package and then implement
the rule and in the in our state we have
an actual RCW that defines how that
information has to be maintained by the
agency and it's called the rulemaking
file so you can request that full file
and then they're supposed to give you
everything that they have on hand that
led them to the decision-making on that
specific on that specific rule like for
instance the thousand-foot rule for how
close cannabis businesses could be to a
school or a park or something like that
while there was a an actual rulemaking
process where they had to take input and
all that kind of stuff and document it
and keep it on file so you can ask for
that and and that's that's a simple step
to take with the agency's it's just
asking for their rulemaking file moving
out and in the case of the 502
rulemaking file we got a lot of
information from that originally and but
we started seeing that there was a lot
of information that was being left out
specific meetings that with law
enforcement that kind of stuff so he
kept digging further and asking further
and finally we we started getting some
of that information so it's II you have
to you not always know what you're going
to get of course when you asked for it
but you have to kind of get a general
idea of what you're looking for at least
you know give a general idea so when you
when you say ask for what does that
actually mean I mean is as simple as sin
an email to somebody and asking for it
i'm assuming that there was like some
application we have to fill out or
something isn't i well there's there's a
couple different ways you can do it you
can do it with a handwritten letter and
ask for you know specific documents and
and for since we're talking about the
liquor in cannabis board each agency has
their own Public Records Division and
they have their own rules set around it
there's like a small fee if they have to
scan over like hard copy documents and
into electronic version i might be a
charge there or printing and scanning so
minimum types of charges but basically
what it is you go to the liquor control
board and on their page you look for
public records on the on the side panel
and you go there and then they actually
give you an email address i believe it's
public records at LC bwa govt and you
just ask basically ask for what you want
the way I do it is I start off and I
just say public records request in the
subject line of the email and then I'll
say in the sudden the in the main body
of the message like this is a public
records request for the thousand-foot
rulemaking file I would like these in
electronic format if possible and
basically I sign my name my given my
phone number and send it off so it can
be as simple as that it can be is more
complicated if you're looking say for
you know specific tax disbursements to
specific agencies you know so it's you
can go general you can go very specific
it just all really depends on what
you're looking for wow that's really
interesting i'm actually surprised at
how easy it actually sounds like like it
is i mean that's a that's a that's a
request that sounds like just out of how
anybody else anybody could do it yes and
and also it sounds like there's a
certain amount of discretion on the
receiver of the email tube because
you're asking for whatever you're asking
for and that can be you know
you defined by the person on the
receiving side about you know how much
how much scope of work they're going to
do to answer your request so this
actually usually they will so for
instance let's say I hit the send button
I sent that request in then the agency
has five business days from there to
respond back to me to let me know okay
we got it they if they are not
completely sure of what you're asking
though they may ask you to clarify it
that might like restate in a way they
think that you're asking so then you
have to follow up and make sure yeah
that sounds good or if if it is what it
you asked for and they you feel that
they have it right in their head what
you want then you just you know let them
go but one of the things that you got to
keep on top at least respond back and
make sure that you're actually getting
or they're telling what they're telling
you is what you want and then they have
to give you a specific time period on
approximately how long they believe it
will take for them to do it and so it's
a it's a little bit of work but you know
in the long run for each individual one
it really doesn't take a whole lot of
time but it's again keeping tabs on
their responses and making sure you
respond back the right way right on cool
we're going to take our first short
break and be right back you are
listening to shaping fire as a business
owner you are incredibly busy in reality
you are responsible for everything your
company does you have so many
responsibilities every single day that
often you just don't have the time to
really dig into something as deeply as
you'd like you know there is more that
you could do to reach out to new
customers and to encourage loyalty and
the customers you already have but you
certainly don't have the time and you're
not ready to hire someone full time for
that role either for you i recommend
blunt branding blunt branding principles
Kirsten Nelson and Anthony Garcia are
focused on improving your bottom line
you know most marketing firms are
excited to make your low
ago packaging and website very pretty
but they leave responsibility for
improving your bottom line up to you
they don't want that kind of
responsibility but that is pretty much
the most important part of marketing
right Kirsten and Anthony will help you
engage new customers funnel them to your
point of sale and keep them coming back
to you and telling their friends no
doubt this is a paid commercial spot but
that does not mean they bought my
opinion I've worked with blunt branding
on three projects now for various
clients and every single time they have
done more than they have promised and
over delivered on results I love how
they generate new revenue and focus on
that as the goal instead of just making
me a pretty logo similarly every friend
I've referred them to has come back to
thank me and that just does not happen
every day so grab a pen and paper
because the website address is coming if
you want someone to implement marketing
programs that feed your bottom line give
blunt branding a call they will share
proven techniques to increase your
audience and generate sales while using
cutting-edge technology in the
background that make all of this easy
automatic and trackable go to shaping
fire calm forward slash blunt branding
to find out more you can also click the
link in our weekly newsletter blunt
branding marketing that makes you money
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire i'm your host Shango louis
and our guest this week is John Novak of
420 leaks calm so John before the break
we were talking about you know how to
get the the files targeted to know what
you're looking for and then how to go
ahead and put in a request for them and
you know it actually was surprisingly
easy compared to what I thought it was
going to look like and you know I know
that one of the things that you have
found is very often you will be asking
for particular documents and and they
should exist because you know most
states have some version of the Open
Meetings Act where where when when they
meet to talk about future regulations
and laws that they have to document that
but you found
that at least in Washington this wasn't
happening and and this is something that
people should be looking for to
potentially happen at every state so so
why don't you tell us a little bit about
that so people know what to look for
sure one of the things that we found
early on was that the liquor and
cannabis board were having secret
meetings with law enforcement and they
began publishing their calendar of
events and we are seeing that they have
having these public meetings and in the
big cities like Spokane Seattle and
Yakima but then they were also listing
that they were having meetings with
these different groups during the day
and according to our state law if two or
more of the board members meet together
it becomes an actual official meeting
the public needs to be notified and
their input needs to be considered and
they were not doing that so going
through the rulemaking file against
seeing their asking for their calendar
of events and you can kind of get an
idea okay well what's being publicized
openly and what's not and so that's kind
of how we started catching them on that
so so you know the the to say they're
having secret meetings I just want to I
want to drill down that on that a little
bit because you know that could be
hyperbole no secret seems to suggest
some kind of ill will you know do you
think that these were intentionally
being hidden or did they just not make
you no no no one put it in the file you
know was it does it seem like an
accidental oversight or does it feel
like they were intentionally trying to
keep this out of the file well that's
another great part of one of the things
you can ask for is the communications
between people and so we asked for all
communications as well on on this
specific thing and we started seeing
that
the meetings were being set up by the
liquor control board staff at the
request of law enforcement and a lot of
the concern was the law enforcement
wanted to have the full attention of the
liquor control board with the without
having to talk around the general public
they would just wanted their group their
message and that's you know that's all
well and good if you're having a meeting
with a you know an individual board
member but when you put the board
together that and then you're getting
into a whole different level of Public
Integrity there and so that was we could
see in the communications that that's
what they were trying to do they did
they did not want the public to be
participating to counter any message
that they were trying to get across it
must be really odd to read those those
emails that because you know when you
write an email you kinda you're talking
to other purse another person personally
and so you're speaking to them in like
regular language but they are going into
you know a bureaucratic file of
documentation you probably see some
things in those emails which which are
you know both odd but also kind of
telling like you can start to pull out
people's intent if you if you're reading
them in there you know if you read all
the messages right yeah you very much
can and for whatever reason they
continue to write their e-mails back and
forth and and and well some of the
things that we've got some of them
saying and basically just no they don't
for the most part these agencies don't
have a lot of good things to say about
the cannabis community I'll put it that
way so so how about like phone calls
like you know does everything happen via
email so that there's an official paper
trail or how would they document phone
calls that would take place like between
a you know a lobbyist and
and sign a regulator lobbyist and that's
a whole different side of public records
because they go under the sea public
disclosure Commission and I spent about
two years studying up on politics and
money and all that kind of stuff before
I got involved with actual political
action committee stuff because I wanted
to make sure that you know we followed
the rules and all that kind of stuff so
I don't really have complete answers for
you on lobby requirements and bills yet
but one of the things that I was
somewhat disappointed in finding out was
that when lobbyists right or present
bills there really is no requirement
that that be disclosed anyone the only
thing that is must be disclosed on the
lobby side is the if money is being
spent one way or the other for instance
if the lobbyists were to go and take
them out to dinner or give them a you
know some kind of gift or something
along those lines those kinds of things
have to be reported travel expenses all
that kind of stuff so but that was
really the only way that I found that
you can see what lobbyists are behind
what bills is one go down to the public
hearings and see who's you know coming
on board with them or to look and see
what lobby firms are contributing to
what candidates and and to which the
other side of lobbying to is not just
candidates that they give these
contributions to they also go to
committee caucuses party committees and
in those groups there's no limit on what
you can give to those there's the limit
on what you can give to a candidate but
so for instance a business lobby firm
had about 50 thousand dollars and i'd
say probably oh you know like 20,000 of
it may have gone out to about 20
different candidates at about a thousand
dollars each and then you'll see big
chunks of money being pushed to these
caucus or party committees where then
they the parties then distribute from
there but the caucus committees are more
issued driven apparently and so there's
a lot of wheels that need to be greased
by lobby money in order to get bills
passed and that has been both a very
eye-opening and very revealing part of
this whole study you know John it's the
biggest part is the biggest puzzle
though be there's a lot more pieces you
go to put together geo I think a puzzle
is actually a really good example
because as I as I as I sit here and
listen to you you know when you were
telling me about the master file that's
kept about the deliberations before you
know a regulation is made I was thinking
to myself wow it's great that they keep
all that stuff at one place it's very
transparent you know I mean yeah we need
to watch dog them to make sure that
everything goes in the file but that's
really great we can watch you know we
can watch how our regulations are made
well then and then you know your your
next set of information was all like oh
yeah we can't track this we can't track
that there's a lot of money you know you
to find out who the lobbyists are
working on something you need to go and
see who's in the room I mean and then it
suddenly that like just the store up my
my conception that that that this was
transparent now it suddenly feels very
not transparent and I can imagine you
having to read all of this you know i
would think that most of it is pretty
mundane you know nails and
communications and the
all of a sudden you find you know a
somebody saying something that refers to
something that you haven't seen anywhere
and then things start to unravel but you
have to like dig forever just to find
that this this doesn't sound very
transparent anymore no well yes and no
like the biggest details of course is
finding you know which lobbyist wrote
this bill which but to this senator to
this committee so that's that's the real
the legwork they don't think you know it
takes a lot more than just sending pipec
requests back and forth you know it does
take a lot of work and it can be very
time consuming and it's like a whole
whole other wing of activism that really
needs its own staff then you have again
back to the agency public records that's
almost again its own staff so it's a
it's a lot of work but and in any given
a year or two we also have these state
agencies will go crying to the
legislature saying that oh we're this is
costing us way too much way too many man
hours to find all these records and we
so yeah it's it's a constant tug-of-war
sounds like it's the the price of a
democracy though when you're doing this
research you just must be elated when
you find a thread to pull on though you
know if you're gonna if you're going to
spend a couple days trolling or not
troll I don't think that's right word
but anyway digging through a big pile of
documents and then you find one thing
you're like oh here's something that you
know could give me cause to make a new
records request because now you can get
more specific or somebody referring to
an idea or a meeting that is not in the
rest of the file that must be very
gratifying at that point because you're
like oh here's something to work with
well yeah it takes some a little bit of
training in your mind to listen a little
harder for key keywords well here's
here's an example there was a study
released by Department of Health and I
think in collaboration with a couple of
other agencies liquor control board and
stuff and they wanted to look at how 502
and all this was impacting our youth so
they came up with a study that they went
out to different high schools to see you
know where how it was affecting the kids
and some of the conclusions they came up
with were left me scratching my head so
but just by the sheer fact that they did
a study and sent people out makes you
realize aha there's a document there
there's a there's a list of questions
somewhere that they were asking people
so when I saw the the file of it was a
basically what the information that I
saw that led me to this was a PowerPoint
presentation put on by the department
health that they were going to they were
presenting to legislators so I was
reading down through all the slides and
I kept coming across these different
study points and a couple of them really
had me scratching my head so I was like
okay I need to see the study and what
we're all this information was coming
from because one of the things they were
claiming was that the minorities were
having a harder problem with it in the
schools then the white folks I'm like
this is sounding a little I don't want
to say racist but you know all the
research that I've seen in the past
showed that of blacks and whites use
cannabis at a pretty even rate so why
they were saying that the black kids in
school are having a harder time with it
and and you know I want to know more
so I asked for the actual study and that
I just got that a couple days ago I
haven't had a chance to go through and
look at it but despite you know seeing
on there they had it done a study that I
knew then okay I can ask for that study
yeah right on i follow that and it makes
for some pretty detailed reading I'm
sure so so hey we're gonna take it it's
you can it's it's a good way to put
yourself to sleep enjoy right on it's
time to take our second break so we will
be right back you are listening to
shaping fire look inside this crystal
ball with me for a moment I'm looking
just a couple months into the future I'm
seeing the future of the shaping fired
podcast the show sure has grown I've
continued to interview fascinating
cannabis industry luminaries and our
audience has gotten huge it has doubled
and redoubled and doubled again there
are high fives all around the shaping
fire world headquarters new listeners
are subscribing everyday and begin to
listen to the back catalogue of all the
great interviews there and that is where
the shaving fire audience learns about
your company you were incredibly smart
today to become an early adopter and
place a commercial in shaping fires
early episodes if you become an
advertiser on the shaping fire podcast
now today you are going to pay a
fraction of the cost will be asking in
just two months and yet all the audience
that listens to our back catalogue of
interviews will hear about your company
again and again it's a great deal for
you pay a small amount now because the
show is so new but take advantage of the
huge listening audience we will have
forever this crystal ball is not a smoke
dream do yourself a solid and contact us
today for rates on podcast and
newsletter advertising email hot spot at
shaping fire calm to find out more
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire i'm your host Shango lowson
our guest this week is John Novak of 420
leaks calm so John you know during the
show today you have described you know
a lot of detail oriented work a lot of
you know kind of pushing against the
bureaucracy but we know also with
important winds of being able to keep
regulators honest and essentially
defending the citizenry of the state and
the goal you know of course the show is
to inspire people in other states that
are you know just coming on line with
cannabis and and starting to normalize
and moving towards some kind of
legalization to inspire folks to you
know to watch their their own state
regulators so you know I got to ask you
you know what are some of the challenges
personally to doing this kind of work oh
the personal challenges a the hardest
one is just keeping yourself motivated
to go through all this boring stuff and
that especially when you get in you know
gigabyte after gigabyte of information
and that's that's one of the hardest
things to do trying to get other people
to help out that that's been a struggle
because you know it's not the funnest
reports due and the rewards you know you
may have to go weeks if not months
before you see any kind of results so it
that's a it's a good question yeah but
you know obviously you're doing it and
you're passionate about it and so you
know you've got to know that it's
important I mean somebody's got to watch
the government well you know why for you
do you feel that it's important that
that people like you stand up and watch
the government to make sure that they
are they are doing things by rule of law
well I actually started doing I would
say my skills on this came actually from
doing due diligence on stock for the
stock market and it takes a lot of going
through and reading all the the company
documents and and figuring out you know
where
money is coming in where it's going out
if they actually have a product and all
that kind of stuff so it just takes a
lot of going through a lot of boring
boring information but it's it is super
important to do if you take investing
seriously so that was kind of the
training that I had going into this so
and it really kind of started out for me
of course I wanted to see where all the
laws were going since I am a patient
myself but I also wanted to see how what
kind of environment I would be getting
myself into if I decided to enter into
the industry and that was really the
biggest push for me of why I wanted to
do all this because if I you know first
off we got you know let's let's be
honest here this is still against
federal law so there's a lot in and of
itself means you gotta so many different
areas of law that you got to make sure
your butt's covered on you got to follow
not only state law you got to follow
what the feds are doing kind of get an
idea of what other states are doing so
that attention to detail in and due
diligence is really what keep me might
push to do it the benefits of doing it
though are absolutely wonderful because
instead of relying on let's say what the
press is telling you what's going on or
what any individual legislator or even
any individual activist might be telling
you what's going on when you have the
actual documents in front of you you see
what's being said you see what's going
on you know you just you have a much
better understanding of the entire
situation because you're taking it from
the horse's mouth instead of you know
different spins on it and and that I
think is one of the most valuable parts
and of course the to a certain degree I
wish it was more keeping politicians and
the state agencies honest
and the biggest threat that if we don't
do this is that they'll just think that
nobody is watching and they can get it
away with whatever they want they don't
then you they'll take they won't take
the full steps to completely document
what they're doing at to the worst
extremes of corruption that we've you
know you hear about in the news and
unfortunately when I talk to other
activists and even some legislators and
people in this they stayed as a whole
our countries and local government is
becoming more corrupt than then more
honest these days so that is you know in
a lot of ways I think that this activism
really has more to do with about open
government that does about cannabis you
know this might be kind of a bittersweet
question but you know I know you've
dedicated well at least your life right
now to this because this is your your
main thing but you know how do you know
when you're succeeding because this
seems like you are you know you're
working on this ocean trove of
information you know how do you how do
you know when you're winning well the
easiest way to know that when you're
winning is of course you get attention
from the press or our legislators and
they'll come up and say hey we want to
change it you know what you what you're
seeing there we want to change that's
that's an immediate type of win and and
that can be very gratifying
unfortunately though most of the winds
come in ways that you you can kind of
see your information is influencing the
public debate even though your name is
not specifically mentioned I see that a
lot in the let's I won't bring up any
big names but some of the bigger
newspapers in this in the area
absolutely refused to have to publish my
name for 20 leaks or anything to do with
it
as they are interested in a
multi-billion dollar industry continuing
which I'm all for two but let's you know
let's do it honestly here guys but so I
do see a lot of that though when a
bigger story will come out and then
you'll and you'll kind of start hearing
about you know the debate let's say for
instance on the there was a massive leak
we're like a control board accidentally
turned over private information on
applicants well some of the cannabis
reporters jumped on that immediately but
then at the higher level of you know of
you know let's say like through seattle
times the you know the bigger the
Spokane chronicle or whatever the bigger
newspapers they didn't cover that until
the Liquor Control Board actually
started sending out letters to people
then the big news got in but still for
the most part we weren't we didn't get a
lot of credit for that link but then we
started seeing a bigger issue being
talked about about prayed about patient
privacy and so sometimes you don't get
the credit but you can see that your
point was made and the debate is
beginning and then so you have to kind
of a lot of it is you don't you don't
get a lot of credit for some of this
stuff but the debate moves forward and
that's really the end that should be the
the bottom line if the debate is moving
forward you're winning right on that
makes a lot of sense so let's let's
finish up with this last question John
so you know if if you know my goal with
the show is that I wanted to be able to
reach out to our listeners across the
country and maybe have them hear your
story about what you're doing in
Washington and inspire them to do that
in their own state because you know if
it takes your full time to do Washington
you know we need at least four
nine other people across the country to
be doing this so that each state can be
covered so so so somebody out there is
listening and they're listening to the
work that you're doing and it sounds you
know interesting and engaging to them
and they're thinking about doing this in
their own state what would you say to
them to help inspire them to move
forward you're gonna find this is both
the hardest and most but at the same
time most rewarding thing that you'll do
your you'll you're going to find a lot
of a lot of garbage in there that just
you know has no real revelant or a real
no meaning to exactly what it is you're
looking for but you have to keep going
one of the things that I that drives me
is the human rights angle that every
person out there should have the right
to plant a seed and take care of
themselves so when you have a focus like
that it kind of narrows down to a degree
what specifically you're going for so
and it helps so and the other thing it
does is it when you're sending out those
requests it puts those agencies on
notice that you're watching them and for
the most sometimes you know they're so
big they have so much money and
influence they don't really care but
when when you take that information and
then make it public and then suddenly
they take it a little more seriously and
that's that's what I begin defines that
you get not only do you get the
information that you're looking for in a
more complete picture but you also begin
to develop a reputation especially with
legislators that while they may not like
what you're doing they know why you're
doing it and for the most part they
really don't have a
much to say to the negative site on that
and being able to inform your fellow
activists with exactly what's going on
with these laws and so it helps it helps
your group to really define where the
issues you need to focus are a lot of us
get caught up and a lot of the
extraneous stuff and you know and the
Red Hat's versus the blue hats or should
we have like six plans first is eight
plants or four and a lot of times you
get groups that kind of split apart and
get trapped into a lot of that stuff
whereas if you you focus on specific
issues and you can see where the enemy
or the obstacle is it it becomes easier
when you go in with a handful of
documents especially when they're on
their own words and you can say this is
why it needs to be fixed and here in the
end actually that's another point of the
things you can find a lot of stuff
that's wrong and they do want to hear
some of that but really what they're
looking for is okay how do we make it
right but you cannot get to that step of
how do I make it right until you have
all the information in front of you and
that's the biggest part of why I think
this is most important John thank you
for all your hard work and thank you for
being on the show absolutely thank you
very much for having me John Novak is
founder of 420 leaks you can find out
more info at 420 leaks com you can email
john directly at 420 leaks @ gmail.com
and you can also call the activist leak
line at 20 6 9 15 3 4 50 you can find
more episodes of the shaping fire
podcast and subscribe to the show at
shaping fire calm and on Apple iTunes
stitcher and Google Play if you enjoyed
the show we'd really appreciate it if
you'd leave a positive review of the
podcast wherever you download your
review will help others
find the show so they can enjoy it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the weekly newsletter for
insights into the latest cannabis news
and product reviews on the shaping fire
website you will also find transcripts
of today's podcast as well for
information on me and where i'll be
speaking you can check out Shango Lohse
com does your company want to reach our
national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hot spot at shaping
fire calm to find out how thanks for
listening to shaping fire I've been your
host Shango lowes