[Music]
Cannabis smells really good most of us
buy cannabis based on its smell we
unscrew the mason jar stick our nose in
there and take a mighty whiff your body
tells you if you want that strain or not
during episode 11 we spend a lot of time
talking about cannabis terpenes with
world's famous neurologist and cannabis
researcher dr. Ethan Rousseau he
explained how THC CBD and the other
cannabinoids work in cooperation with
terpenes in the plant in what's called
the entourage effect the terpenes are
the plants aromatics they are why
cannabis smells so good whether it's
pine or chocolate citrus or skunker
any of the other aromas of cannabis one
of the essential aspects of healing with
cannabis simply is its smell if you
enjoy hearing Frank discussions that
dive deep into cannabis health business
and technique I encourage you to
subscribe to our newsletter every week
you'll receive a new podcast episode
delivered right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week
social media sites are becoming very
unreliable in showing folks every post
they want to see so sign up for the
shaping fire newsletter to make sure you
don't miss an episode you are listening
to shaping fire and I am your host
Shango 'lose my guest today is Ben
Cassidy co-founder of Tru terpenes we're
going to talk with Ben about cannabis
aromatics and aromatherapy how terpenes
are isolated for sale and how you can
use terpenes even without cannabis for
everyday healing and quality of life
welcome to the show then hey thanks for
having me on it's a real honour so you
know let's get right to it and talk
about where terpenes come from I mean we
know where they come from in nature but
how are isolated terpenes extracted or
manufactured one of my favorite things
about that question I think it's
probably you know once somebody gets
over the idea or starts to understand
what is a turkey and then they're
immediately like well how do you get
them so it's one of the ones that I get
asked the most and what I like to
initially say to people is you your ex
the probably a lot more familiar with
isolated terpenes than you think you
know and so let's just start with saying
that terpenes are separated from plant
material typically through two different
methods one of them is vacuum
distillation and one of them is steam
distillation and sometimes you can use
steam distillation in a vacuum
distillation setup but just to kind of
give a rough preliminary description of
vacuum distillation it's where we're
removing the atmosphere a lot of people
are starting to see these fancy
glassware setups for short path
distillation and other kind of high
level extractions within the cannabis
industry just know that the actual
purpose for these distillation setups
has been kind of more tailored towards
the essential oil industries for a long
time and so we're using the same
technology that's been around for a
while
to isolate terpenes with vacuum which
means like I said we remove the
atmosphere when you remove the
atmosphere you're basically making it
easier for things to boil off they don't
have to fight the vapor pressure for
them to become active in our in our in
an environment so vacuum distillation is
great because it allows you to use a
very little amount of energy and a
little amount of heat which means the
molecule doesn't get distorted or
destroyed steam distillation is a little
bit more widely used but it it allows
some of the molecules some of the
terpenes to kind of change in state
they're not necessarily just like they
were in the plants so there's kind of
positives
you know they steam distillation allows
for larger batch sizes and a little bit
less sophistication when it comes to
equipment vacuum distillation allows for
very very precise and gentle extraction
practices so yeah really it's a process
of taking raw plant material turning it
into an essential oil and then taking
that essential oil and slowly boiling
all of the individual components out of
it
oh one thing I'm not hearing any of that
is any chemical so so it sounds like the
two processes you've described so far
are actually pretty clean but if that is
correct you know there's there's
different industrial
applications or kind of distillation
procedures that somebody might take
plant material and they might use a
solvent under vacuum distillation or
steam distillation but in this case when
we're working with food grade and
sometimes above that grade chemicals
that people are going to be ingesting or
using in fragrances and in other kind of
related fields it's always been a really
important thing in our line of work
personally with our company to make sure
that there hasn't been any solvents used
in the process right on so so if that's
a good example I want to talk briefly
about the bad example you know a couple
weeks ago we had dr. Ethan Russo on the
show talking about terpenes and
cannabinoids in general and he surprised
me he said that some terpenes are
derived by they're coming from petroleum
refinement and it's a byproduct of that
what what tell me about that I don't
really know what they would do so give
me a little background so he actually
after listening that episode when I went
live which I just have to say is maybe
one of my favorite podcasts of all time
not just because I'm on your show at
this moment but really doesn't want to
know I loved it it inspired me to look a
little bit more into that because I had
a few ideas but I wasn't really sure
we've all you know a lot of people are
starting to hear at this point
especially when I go out and speak to
people you know people have heard
cannabis might have 200 terpenes and
that there's you know 30 or 40,000 in
nature and so it's a very diverse class
of chemicals so to say that something is
a terpene doesn't necessarily you know
it's not it's not a small class of
chemicals you're not going to
necessarily find the same terpenes in
cannabis that people are going to be
getting from these industrial sources
petroleum so when I looked into it what
I was able to find is people are
distilling in an industry has not really
people but industry has been distilling
petroleum for things like mineral
spirits kerosene naphtha and they they
as far as being a hydrocarbon molecule
they're very similar so I think for my
best guess without having reached out to
dr. Roy soda to confirm
based on what he was saying I think that
we can assume that any carbon-based
organic
substance that is you know made of
isoprene which is the building block of
terpenes can be considered a terpenes so
I think it's just such a wide diverse
class of chemicals that yes in fact many
of them can be derived from all sorts of
organic materials and you know a lot of
times we don't really think of mineral
spirits or kerosene gasoline you know it
seems so chemical in nature it doesn't
really seem like it's an organic product
but it really is you know that it's
derived from crude oil and through
distillation processes cleaned up so
that is kind of my best guess at this
point as to without having being able to
speak with him directly right on that
make sense and so it's not that we're
getting you know dhilae meaning from
citrus fruit and also from petroleum
it's a specific set of uncommon terpenes
that we would get from petroleum
production I believe and maybe you know
and maybe I I would even say those might
be some of the most prevalent terpenes
on the planet just because of how much
oil and how much crude oil is actually
distilled and then you know the number
of uses for kerosene and naphtha and
other kind of solvents of that nature
but yeah as far as the the ones that
we're all and at least in this community
quite interested in from my knowledge so
far I don't think you really need to be
concerned that it came out of gasoline
or crude oil producing gasoline for your
like your alpha-pinene or your mere
scene or Lynn Alou you know right on
cool well then that makes a good point
so even though there are truly trashy
terpenes they're not really the ones
that we work with in our sphere and so
so let's focus on our so let's talk
about the grades of terpenes because you
know one thing I have certainly read
people fighting about quality of
terpenes you know on Facebook and
different forums and and we all know how
ugly and inaccurate a lot of those
debates are so so let's go through you
know a couple different standards that
can be used to grade a turbine so I know
a lot of folks who are selling terpenes
they really push that they are organic
and food grade what does that mean to me
as you know as a purchaser as a consumer
of terpenes good question as far as food
grade go
is that really just means that the Food
and Drug Administration has placed this
substance on the approved food additives
list so you know our company really
focuses on only selling terpenes that
are found within cannabis and it just so
happens that we haven't ran into a
Caterpie and that was found in cannabis
that also was not found on the Food and
Drug Administration's list of approved
sources so in that case you know all of
the terpenes that we're working with our
food grade grass a lot some people might
not know grass stands for generally
recognized as safe that that means for
human consumption it doesn't mean that
it's you know it's free-range and you
can just bathe in the stuff it just
means that under the right circumstances
with proper product formulation that
this can be used in a cosmetic product
or at nutraceutical product or a food
product right on that makes sense and so
then the organic part that probably
refers to whatever your source plant
material was raised without pesticides I
so it definitely does if it's got like a
third-party certification on it for for
being organic but I actually have a
statement pulled up here it's actually
from it's an FDA FDA statement and
basically terpenes are by definition an
organic molecule they contain carbon
they they don't they don't exist outside
of being organic so the FDA FDA actually
allows all terpenes that are not
synthetically derived to be listed as an
organic substance because in isolation
they again it's a carbon containing
molecule it is organic I see that that's
like those of us who are nerds for
organic food we would call that little o
organic meaning yeah it's about it being
a natural source not necessarily whether
or not uses pesticides right which which
kind of brings me to the the point that
I usually bring along bring around with
that which is that what's most important
I think with surfing's is looking at you
know what else is in the solution it's
very difficult almost impossible to get
a
100% terpene solution or even a 99.9 and
most of them it's just very difficult to
do and so you need to really look at
what is in that other percentage and
that's that really it becomes what's
important you know a lot of the terpenes
are very similar by chemical nature they
have almost the exact molecular weight
of one another under the right
circumstances within the plant and
outside of the plant they can actually
turn from one to another so it's very
easy for limonene alpha-pinene and muir
seen for instance to kind of phase shift
between each other
given their their environment so you
might have a bottle of 99.9 percent
lemony and it doesn't mean that it's
contaminated with something it really
might mean that that final fraction in
there was some nursing and alpha pionen
that just could not be separated so
that's that's kind of what I like to
always bring it back around to is it's
with as far as these two Europeans go a
terpene is organic but you know the
package that it comes in and the other
substances and the solution is what we
really need to look at right on that
makes sense
so so in this industry do we really care
whether or not the original plant was
grown GMO or not is that is that
something that we want to be aware of
making purchases I you know I think you
have such a diverse crowd of people that
are consuming I think it's important to
make make sure that people are aware
beforehand that it came from you know
whatever they're consuming came from
non-gmo myself personally I come from
the camp that I I think that we should
investigate GMO I don't think that it's
something to be shunned but I also think
that everyone should be notified of what
they're consuming and people should have
the ability to opt out if they're not
interested and I think that you know if
that applies to food and I think it
applies to cannabis as well right on
that's a good point so that brings us up
to what is probably the most discussed
and possibly controversial part of what
isn't is not occurring because you know
terpenes got really hot and interesting
in being able to extract
anibus profiles right you know the first
time I saw this being done was at the
Emerald cup in let's see that would have
been 2015 Emerald cup tawny bruiser ah
from United cannabis had like all these
people around him and he was taking what
you know you know folks are bringing him
up what was otherwise like mediocre
slabs of shatter and and he was taking
you know Canada's profiled terpenes and
like painting the the dab oil and then
the folks would go in dab it they're
like oh that's the best Gorilla Glue
I've ever had
so they were they were adding terpenes
after the fact and people were going
bananas it was it was it was quite
impressive to see everyone's excitement
about taking mediocre cannabis product
and super charging it with with a
terpene profile so so you know after I
got into that I realized how
controversial it was about whether or
not you know different cannabis
companies were either a taking actual
cannabis flowers and distilling from
that to get the actual terpenes that
words in a batch of flour or be doing
research to find out what terpenes were
in safer groups say for example Gorilla
Glue and then hand blending food-grade
terpenes to to emulate what the terpene
profile would have been if you would've
taking taken them directly out of the
flower and man people will fight all day
long on social media about that so so
why don't you break it down for us
you know the differences between those
two approaches absolutely I think I
first would just start by saying my same
opinion about the GMO substance kind of
applies to this as well I think that you
know isolated terpenes we don't have the
entire catalog of 200 available to us at
this point and there's a couple of
different reasons for that some of them
are incredibly difficult to have an
isolation and that's because they might
have a they might have a
boiling-point around room temperature or
eighty degrees or so which is why when
you're in a hot row room it really just
smells something special and you're
never really going to be able to
recreate that or fully capture it with a
with a final product you know live
resins and other extractions are doing a
pretty good job of capturing as much
terpene as possible but at the end of
the day there are some of these
compounds that are not easily isolated
and so what that leads to is the
terpenes that we actually have at our
disposal so add-back are primarily the
heaviest most stable molecules the mono
and sesqui turbines so if you you know
if you were imagining you know you let's
say you started with a really glue for
just to follow your example and you took
that into the testing lab that we prefer
to use this time SC labs and they gave
you the terpene analysis back which at
this point they count 434 of them you
know you would have it would that that's
going to tell you the natural ratio that
the terpenes that they're able to test
for are found in in that plant and then
there's one other special number on that
page and it's the total content by
volume so you're going to see all these
different ratios you know and it 34 of
them you'll see alpha pining at 3% and
and beta pining a two-person yawn so
it's going to be listed out in either
percentages or by milligrams per gram
and then at the bottom it's going to say
but the total content of that entire
gram was 4% or 7% or something along
those lines it's going to vary depending
on if it was a flower sample if it was
grown indoor/outdoor or if it was a
concentrate and how it was extracted so
what's really important to look at is
you know if you're looking to emulate
cannabis naturally you're going to want
to only add back those mono and sesqui
terpenes but let's just keep it easy say
those 34 Kirkenes you're going to want
to look at what what does the plant
naturally produce at its best case
scenario fresh off the plant before any
sort of degradation has happened or miss
handling
and then try to emulate that so not just
slopping it on and you know and assuming
that more is going to be better but
really kind of precisely maybe even take
you know measuring measuring big like
that's again we'll follow your example
so we'll say a slab of concentrate
running that running atropine tests on
that and seeing where it is right now
currently as like kind of a blank canvas
without any additives to it and then
let's say you get a a plus top-shelf
concentrate that you really admire from
another source you know somebody else
did some live resin and you have some
standard vho you could look at the
terpene content of that live resin and
compare it to the terpene content of
your BHO and you could spike all of the
individual mono and sesqui torian's to
make it more like the the a plus
medicine but so I think you know that's
best case scenario what you saw Tony
doing was because he because you know
the the product he was working with is
supposedly cannabis derived terpenes
it's taking those natural ratios in the
proper dilution and adding it back so as
you know nature already did all the
heavy lifting with that I really am a
fan of those sorts of products I think
that the you know the only reason that
I'm in the business that I am right now
is because they're very cost prohibitive
they're about you know 15 to 20 times
more by the time you get to the consumer
level of somebody buying a milliliter
next to a milliliter cannabis derived
first isolated plant drive terpenes and
they're also a little bit less shelf
stable and a little bit more
inconsistent as well you know somebody
has to continue to grow that crop of
cannabis under the same conditions to
produce the same to produce the same
flower to then be distilled under this
that you know it's just it's a lot of
new kind of tech coming into play and
people haven't been isolating to
Europeans for a long time and it's a
little bit of a not as as much available
as far as like source material yeah you
know you can only grow so many plants
most places in this world and then you
have to decide what you're going to do
with those and I'm just not convinced
personally that still
Cannabis drive terpenes out of that is
maybe the necessarily the best use for
really good cannabis so I think kind of
as a compare to get back to like
comparing apples to apples you know I
think limiting from an orange and
limiting from cannabis they're
chemically identical and this is true of
all terpenes the other ones that I think
people might be familiar with our lintel
rule and lat from lavender and you're
seen from hops but what I think
ultimately it comes down to is the
importance of purity and in relation to
contaminants you know if you have five
milliliters of limiting you want that to
be as close to as possible a pure
limiting and if you're dealing with like
a distillation like what we work in you
know achieving those super high
percentage purities is one thing you
know you want to be a but we should have
everything above 96% but then the other
side of that coin is making sure that
the other 4% that's remaining is not
pesticide solvents or other degraded
organic material one thing that a lot of
people might not be familiar to hearing
is that you know things chemicals like
acetone or a couple of other like known
solvents are actually can be produced by
the degradation of plant material of
other natural organic material as it as
UV and time kind of play their course so
I think that was a little bit of a
roundabout so I apologize but really I
think as far as source comes and maybe
you could actually return to the
question yeah right on so so bringing it
back to that the cannabis strain
profiles part and you answer my question
really well explaining the difference
between the cannabis derived and the
plant food derived but you know what it
occurred to me is that when you describe
how cannabis derived is going to you
know be 15 to 20 percent more extent eat
iams more expensive what that made me
think of you know I've seen a handful of
terpene companies and I know the prices
they charge you know a lot of these
folks that kind of
right there copy to suggest that there
derived their profiles are extracted
from cannabis they just can't be doing
it for the price that they're selling it
at and it sounds to me like you know
some companies are probably you know
being a little creative with their
copywriting you know just because it's
so much cooler you know people generally
think it's cooler to take your terpenes
directly from the flower but that's so
cost prohibitive that maybe they're
writing their copy too to kind of
suggest that in an abstract way but when
when push comes to shove they're
actually pulling terpenes from from food
plans and then just doing their absolute
best to make a blend that matches the
terpene profile that they got on a test
it yeah and I mean I guess to start off
to say I we really made it our we took a
position early on because everything
that you just said was our thoughts that
I've had and that our company has had
but we took a position early on did not
try to police the industry just because
you know there's so much to focus on
within the organization that what people
are doing on the outside you know we're
good you know I just don't have a
crystal ball so what I will say is that
I think it's not it I think part of what
you said with people to copy I think
people are getting pretty creative with
their copy at least in my experience
I've bought from several of the
companies that suggests that it's
cannabis derived and what it really
appears to me is as a something along
the lines of like a cold trapped
cannabis terpene from a vacuum oven or
maybe even a you know a distill batch
combined with isolated terpenes and this
isn't a new practice by any means you
know the the essential oil and perfume
industry since I think probably its
inception or very shortly thereafter has
been plagued with companies that will
take lesser at lesser oils and cut more
expensive oils to make them stretch
further so yeah I mean it's it's a
practice that in one way or another is
happening we just like I said we never
really wanted to police the industry and
we've never been embarrassed that we
sell
plant-derived terpenes so we've just
always made it blatantly obvious that
these are from other sources and tried
to give people the tools to decide if
working with us is is within there know
what kind of within their guiding
principles for what their business is
trying to achieve right on that makes a
lot of sense you know no reason for you
to police the industry you know one of
the things about having both a free and
open market and also the Internet if
somebody is selling schlock it's the
words going to get around and they're
going to have to deal with that better
to focus on your own startup company and
your own science and go from that so you
know we're kind of late for our first
break so we're going to get to that but
anybody who's been listening to the
first set here and they're like man
they're kind of leaning on the on the
manufacturing and science part a little
heavy do not fear set 2 is going to be
all about how to use terpenes in
everyday life so please stay for that
you are listening to shaping fire i'm
Shango louse and my guest today is Ben
Cassidy co-founder of true tear pains
for anyone who is paying attention to
cannabis medicine it has become
incredibly apparent that full extract
cannabis oil known to some as Rick
Simpson oil is the cornerstone of
healing humans with medical marijuana if
you own a medical dispensary or retail
store you know that your customers are
asking for it every single day and if
you have been working with patients and
seeking out quality full extract oil in
the Pacific Northwest
you know the provider deep-green Kat
Jeter and her team at deep green have
been making full extract cannabis oil
and setting the standards for quality
and exact dosing for years in Washington
State the deep green brand is known by
patients and canvas media as a premium
quality provider for Sick Children
cancer patients and others in need at a
time when there are no national
standards for cannabis oil ensuring a
product as whole plant while the assured
and lab tested is often a matter of
knowing your sources reputable trusts
and a quality brand is essential in
choosing a cannabis medicine that is
going to be used concentrated and in
volume by any patient and especially
those with weakened immune systems
Green is looking for national brand
partners to expand the availability of
their legacy top shelf canvas oil to
emerging medical and licensed states
partners benefit from the deep green
brand recognition and credibility as
well as ongoing customer and marketing
support not only that but deep green
knows how to employ the 280e tax rule so
you can deduct it all from your taxes
working with deep green can provide the
trust and authenticity to often pushed
aside in favor of lifestyle products
your customers can assure themselves
that regardless of the state in which it
is made grande licensees adhere to the
same strict standards that patients
everywhere have come to expect from deep
green deep green licensing includes
start-up and capital planning as well as
operational and manufacturing
instruction as you'd expect for more
information on how your company co-op or
medical dispensary can benefit from
partnering with deep green to provide
full expect cannabis oil to patients go
to shaping feiyr.com
forward slash deep green to connect with
Katt Jeter and her team that's shaping
feiyr.com
forward slash deep green welcome back
you are listening to shaping fire I'm
your host Shango low so our guest this
week is Ben Cassidy co-founder of Tru
terpenes so the first set we were
talking all about how isolated terpenes
are extracted or manufactured and the
differences between terpenes that come
from from raw cannabis versus come from
plant sources well that's really
interesting for people who are nerdy
about the science part but I'm sure
there's people who are listening who are
like alright I got it I know what
terpenes are now how do I use them in my
everyday life and you know I'm going to
start with the example that is actually
how I met you then and what really
impacted me and how I knew I wanted to
have you on the show this past year in
December I was down at Emerald cup and
then was part of a group of cannabis
owners and I and we all rented this this
wine Villa so we call se together it was
really great right because all these
cannabis business owners were all
learning from each other and at one
point Ben went around the room and he
gave everybody just a live
a bit of beta-carotene in their hands
and encourage them to you know cup their
hand and inhale deeply and I've never
done that before and made it carry a
flame just smelled so good and it made
me feel so calm and it made me realize
that even though up to this point all of
my care about terpenes was really what
was in the flower I never really thought
about using the terpenes independently
from cannabis for quality of life and so
you know since that time I've gotten an
you know an ultrasonic terpene diffuser
and and you know while you showed me how
to dad it so so let's go through some of
those ways that people can use terpenes
at home without actually burning or
debating some marijuana okay yeah
definitely I think the just like you
were saying the the first and I think
maybe easiest is probably it's through
the process of what you've called hand
huffing I want to just first start by
saying what I actually had everybody try
at the Emerald cup was a was beta Kari
athlean but I had mixed it one to one
with with just an extra virgin olive oil
and I think that that's just an
important note to start off with for
anybody at home that might want to try
this just because we want to make sure
just like any other essential oil that
we're going to put it with a carrier oil
unless you're you know a Troma therapist
or an expert that's been using these for
a really long time I think you can
always assume that you should probably
cut them with something because they are
very just kind of powerful chemicals
each and every one of them many of them
act as solvents in high purities so just
want to start with that and say make
sure that you're being safe and
practicing you know good aromatherapy
practices so with hand huffing the
reason I really wanted everybody to
apply the beta Kari awfully into their
hands was kind of twofold it is one of
the most relaxing and calming you know
it's to our particular mixes derived
from a combination of black pepper and
clove and you know it very much
resembles both of those plants it's it's
spicy and earthy and so just just
when you come into contact with it it's
immediately everything I think that
you've just described it's relaxing and
it's it's really you know it's in my
opinion it's you know you people have
heard chew on black peppercorns if
you're you know if you're too high or
something of those nature and I think
that beta carry a Selene is is so
interesting for that purpose because
it's not overly stimulating it's not
in-your-face too strong and it's one of
the more benign terpenes and by that I
mean that you can be around a lot of it
before you start to kind of get to an
intoxicated level whereas there's some
terpenes like let's say terrain e all
which is the main terpene and roses and
geraniums which really can start to have
an effect on you very quickly so I like
to start with beta carry ethylene it
helps people get their hands turkey and
and then we move from there that the
second reason why it so it's very it's
just it's a good learning tool and
nobody's going to get hurt from it in
most cases the other reason being is
it's a topical anesthetic and it works
very quickly so that's that's the other
reason why I really like to introduce it
to people is because you know everybody
at one time or another in their life or
most people have had the opportunity you
know to have a sore muscle or something
along the lines where they rubbed a
cream on and we're expecting some sort
of relief and you know there's obviously
varying degrees of success with those
some of those like an icy hot pack and
like vicks vapor rub for instance
actually are containing terpenes but so
with the hand huffing i just want to
always encourage people to make sure
you're taking you're using an olive oil
or coconut oil sweet almond oil you can
get on google and look around for
aromatherapy carriers and you'll find a
list of 30 but you know the main ones
that i really like to do that with are
the primary ones from cannabis and i
think that it's just because i'm so
familiar with them and i kind of know
what to expect when working with them so
should we go down that road or would you
like to go into other methods yeah let's
go into other methods so you recommended
to me an ultrasonic diffuser which i
picked up and i love when you go ahead
and explain that in
why it's making my room smells so good
right now yeah that's actually probably
the way that I consume the most terpenes
and everybody within our company is the
ultrasonic diffuser which basically is
just using a small amount of water and a
and a vibrating sound waves to nano to
make the particles of the of the
essential oil and water into nano
particles so that they can be puffed up
into the air and naturally breathed in
in lower concentrations so whereas we're
getting a direct inhalation of the of
the extract when it's in our hands we're
kind of filling the room ambience with
terpenes when we use an ultrasonic
diffuser and that's like I said I think
I feel like it is a little bit more
natural because we're getting kind of a
diluted it's come combined with oxygen
we're breathing it over there period of
time
I personally start my day every single
day in my office I close the door and I
kick it on and I put some lemonade and
sit all in it both citrus derived
terpenes and that really just seems to
be kind of like even had a looted too in
his episode very sunny and bright and
alerted and so that's that's kind of the
way that I'll start my day if I'm sick
or thinking that I'm getting sick I use
alpha tiny alpha tiny necks as a
bronchodilator and anybody that's had
interaction with it I think we'll it
testify that that it's kind of opens the
lungs and makes it just much easier to
breathe that's that's what you had
mentioned earlier Shango and you know
it's just it's it's very it's low-impact
it's certainly there I think
therapeutically active but it's not
gonna not going to give you any sort of
chance to you know inhale something
that's too potent or too strong and it's
not going to sense your hands or you
know anything like that it's just very
easy to set in the corner of the room
and let it run in just one of my
favorite reactions to kind of take note
of is the before and after somebody
that's never used one before and you
know a lot of people you know
different differing opinions on how
aromatherapy works and what it is but to
you know I just like to let it speak for
itself so to have somebody sit down in a
room and start a conversation and let
the diffuser run for a few minutes and
then to watch the face change as they
realize that they feel different than
before you know four or five minutes
before that I just I just really love
the aromatherapy diffuser and that's
what I would generally recommend to
anybody that's starting to get into
terpenes and having interest in them
just because it's it's low-impact
it's pretty cost effective terpenes will
last a long time in it and it really
gives you the ability to start to
investigate them and then once you start
to learn more about other ways of
preparing and consuming them then you
can kind of move on to that right on
that makes a lot of sense you know one
of the things that I found really easy
too is you know while there were really
nice ones that were 200 bucks I got mine
for 50 bucks on Amazon and you know all
I did was search ultrasonic diffuser and
then there were you know all these
different ones that that I could choose
from and yeah you know they're cooler
ones that I can upgrade to but I'm up
and going for 50 bucks and and not only
that but I like that it's a way to share
terpenes with other folks too
you know I'll have people over for you
know a dinner party or loaded together
or whatever and it will fill the room
and people always comment on the smells
and that always gets me talking about
terpenes and then you know turns into a
little education thing sometimes which I
obviously am into so before we go to the
commercial let's let's talk about
dabbing terpene by themselves you gave
me a really great experience that know
we were down there in California and I'd
like you to describe it for other folks
yeah I just for for sake of everybody
else in our organization who isn't a
huge fan of me always showing that off
but I think no running into people like
yourself who are so passionate about it
and willing to to you know experience it
we had actually inhaled a very small
amount of alpha-pinene for the effect of
opening our lungs and I just want to say
that the the company that I'm with does
not really endorse that practice are we
really really
suggest that people use terpenes for
topical and oral administration at this
time but I but things I want to talk
about it if you want to talk about it
exactly basically what we had done is we
had taken a like a fait battery mod
that's what they're called the one that
I had particularly went from five to
forty watts and we put a ceramic nail on
it that had a kind of like a to go water
pipe attached to it and so we basically
had taken just deep about a third of a
drop which I usually measure out with a
toothpick or something of that nature
we had dipped down into the alpha piney
and taking the drop and put it on the
nail and I think that this is really
important to where as people when people
are dabbing cannabis concentrates they
generally already have the nail at the
temperature that they'd like it to be at
which then they go in and they inhale it
and it all vaporizes but I haven't
really found the right temperature for
that and so what's worked really well
for me is starting with a cold nail
adding the terpene and then allowing it
to come up to temperature with the nail
and then it paper eise's at exactly the
right point as soon as it as soon as
it's hit the temperature where it does
vaporize and it seems like it's a much
less violent reaction whereas as an
experiment again not a suggestion but as
an experiment if you wanted to just drop
like a drop of Turkey and on a 600
degree nail or something you would see
it dance around and then just poof off
and I think that that rapid expansion
would happen and that's what would lead
to somebody having a really poor
experience so most terpenes and not all
terpenes can be just inhaled directly I
really wouldn't suggest just going
through a whole catalogue of them but in
the case of what we did like I said it
was just a very small amount alpha
pining and you know the physical
response is so dramatic afterwards just
the you know you can definitely feel the
ease of taking oxygen into your lungs
and I think personally kind of a mental
clarity or alertness it's like you know
not necessarily the same thing as you
know after your first dab of the day
it's a little bit still
been more clear than that it's a little
bit lighter so very very positive I
really hope to develop a product around
alpha pining if we're able to you know
go through the right channels as far as
FDA approval basically for that sort of
thing because just because something is
grass rated or food safe doesn't mean
that you can put it into a product and
inhale it right on that makes sense and
you know it's funny when you mentioned
putting the putting the Terp right on a
hot email or something and having a
dance around well I definitely don't
want to hit that because the potential
terpene toxicity I do want to see that
so I might I might do that at home just
as a visual experiment and not actually
hit it and you know um you know people
are like you know how can I do this on
the go you know there's there are these
new portable dab rigs that are based on
batteries and those seem to go really
well actually the one I've got from uber
technologies I just I put a little bit
of terpene there on the nail and then I
just let it start coming up to temp and
then as it comes up to temp I can hit it
and man you know when you gave me the
pining to try for the first time I was
you know well I have asthma right and so
the idea that my my my lungs opened up
and I could breathe and I felt you know
the power that comes from being in a
forest right you know Ethan and I were
talking about that you know take going
out into the forest and taking a forest
bath because it makes you feel you know
it makes you feel like you want to throw
your shoulders back and put your chin up
and you are full power is it's amazing
just like taking a little bit of pining
will do that to you and and and so you
know slowly I've worked my way through
all that all the terpenes I have and you
know you know there's a big difference
between doing that with pining or mere
scene or little they really do each have
their own their own care caricature or
character but the thing that I would I
would say if somebody really was was
interested in you know kind of figuring
out which ones are of greater interest
for that is look at a look at a terpene
analysis and just look at the ratios
that they're found naturally in the
plant you know if you know alpha pining
is found in pretty high levels near
scene
sound in pretty high levels but other
terpenes like again I'll bring up
geranium or maybe little much smaller
quantities they're you know they're for
the amount that's in there they're very
potent but just kind of using that logic
as a rule of thumb for how much you
might want to consume if any one of them
is led me pretty well all right
fantastic so let's go and take another
short break you are listening to shaping
fire and my guest today is Ben Cassidy
co-founder of true turbines businesses
everywhere are constantly striving to
reach out to people through advertising
we all know though that trying to reach
a cannabis audience with a quality
message is pretty difficult that's why
many people choose to advertise on the
shaping fire podcast advertising on this
show allows us time to talk about your
product service or brand in a way that
really lets people know what sets your
company apart from others bold people
who own companies know that getting in a
relationship with their customers is
essential that is what we offer we will
explain your service or product and what
sets it apart as desirable and help our
audience get in contact with you it's
pretty simple really
advertising does not have to be all
whiz-bang smoke and mirrors nowadays I
find that people prefer just to be
spoken to calmly accurately and with
good intentions if you want to make your
own commercial spot you can do that too
because the podcast is young but growing
in an exceptionally fast rate if you
become an advertiser on the shaping fire
podcast now you are going to pay a
fraction of the cost we'll be asking for
in just a few months and yet everyone
listening both now and to the back
catalog of interviews later will hear
about your company again and again for
years it's a great deal for you pay a
small amount now because the show is new
but take advantage of the huge listening
audience we will have forever do
yourself a solid and contact us today
for rates on podcast and newsletter
advertising email hotspot at shaping
fire calm to find out more welcome back
you are listening to shaping fire and I
am your host Shango lows and our guest
this week has been Cassidy co-founder of
Tru terpenes so you know then it's very
common now for cannabis product
developers to spike their products with
terpenes you know they'll go ahead and
process
however they're going to but if they
want it to be relaxing maybe they'll add
some little little or mirror scene or if
they want it to pick you up they'll add
some you know commonly known as you know
sativa terpenes like like citrine or
something like that and you know I know
you have got a lot to say about that
and but why don't we want you to
synthesize that a little bit down and
and and just give us your thoughts for
product developers you know on turf
stability and degradation and homogenize
ation and things like that okay yeah
absolutely
I think just like I had said before I
think spiking with terpenes is it is an
acceptable practice I just think there
also should be you should disclose that
you've done it that's what we encourage
all of our clients to do we encourage
them artwork from our company that they
encourage them to co-brand with so that
if they have questions that those
questions can be directed to us so that
we can properly answer them so I really
think if you're getting into it it's
just all about making sure that people
know what they're consuming nobody wants
to be surprised
you know they later on so that's one of
the most important things I think the
ability to influence a product
especially like I think I've had the
greatest success with like with
tinctures and topicals we have an
incredible blend that we put into in
call an indica blend tincture in the
corrigan market same thing we have
sativa they've been great and we
wouldn't really be able to do it without
the control of isolated terpenes because
it's a standardized recipe from you know
from batch to batch to batch everything
comes out identical so I think that
that's a definite Pro if you're if
you're working with products you know
distillates or isolates isolated CBD or
you know distilled THC are two very kind
of more common cannabinoids that are
that are definitely becoming
commercially viable for people to use in
making products combining those with
terpenes so that you can control the
outcome of the product is really
rewarding and can be lucrative so what
I'll say about the stability is that
isolated terpenes
I'm told by several of the people that
we've consulted with from you know PhD
chemistry world are much more stable
because there's less chemistry basically
able to happen within within the bottle
of terpenes let's just say you had a
cannabis derive profile of terpenes from
you know from an OG Kush or something
like that you might have 70 terpenes in
there that are slowly degrading with
with UV and with time and with you know
if they're not you know kept at room
temperature verse under some sort of
colder conditions so they definitely
have the opportunity to grade where when
you have this isolated chemical you can
more readily prepare for how it's going
to degrade and you know you can put a
shelf life on it but with these unknown
solutions that are different from batch
to batch if you if you're going with
with a complex profile it's a little bit
harder to do so isolated terpenes I'm
told and you know from our experience
are much more stable but all organic
things degrades so it's just something
to take into consideration as far as
homogenous Asian you know it they
terpenes are our non-polar so they need
to MIT we need to make sure that they
are mixed into the right carriers just
about any oil or fat based carrier is
going to work great the easiest I think
healthiest that I'm aware of personally
as MCT MCT works really great with
terpenes for somebody that's first
getting into it right now I think making
like a home-based MCT tincture with or
without cannabinoids is a really good
way to start experiencing these in a
relatively safe manner as long as you're
doing your research on concentrations
and what I what I really encourage
people to do when they're starting to
get into product development with
terpenes is walk before you crawl you
know they're there's so many of them you
know they say up to 200 at this time we
offer 31 of them they're in it's about
we're going to explain that even further
but taking on so many different terpenes
it really just gives you
you know 31 more if you bought our whole
set you'd have 31 more variables so I
really encourage people to get used to
kind of the core eight the the terpenes
that are high it sound in the highest
quantities and kind of define unique
branches of the cannabis family tree and
just to briefly go through those that's
alpha piney Lynne Ahlul Bayt Akari
awfully eucalyptol lemony mere seem
Turpin Helene in Turanian they all can
be tied to common essential oils as well
that most people are familiar with and I
really encourage people to look into
aromatherapy and find the waves that
though the plants that contain these
terpenes the way that they're essential
oils are used naturally and then kind of
start to mimic those you'll find some
that are more prevalent in topical
applications and others that are used
and consumed orally or some that are
never consumed but ru zombie Otley and
inhaled through the air so I just really
you know some for somebody getting into
this it's not you know like like another
book it's not in just a new form of
cannabis extract where you can throw it
on the nail and inhale it and you're
just comparing the difference between a
co2 oil and a BHO or something these are
are definitely highly highly potent
therapeutic compounds so I just I you
know I always invite people to do their
homework you know definitely pay for a
consultation with with a company that
works with these regularly or with an
organic chemist to just get it get your
get your bearings down because you know
we for as much as everybody wants them
to be therapeutic you know with that the
other side of the coin is that they can
you know they can have dramatic effects
that you may or may not be so so
satisfied with if Houston properly so
right on well said you know one of the
things that you know I've got a lot of
respect for product developers I've
dabbled in it myself mostly enough to
realize how challenging it is it's one
thing to to put something together that
works right then and there but as soon
as you add you know degradation
homogenous Asian shelf stability and and
some kind of product liability if the
wrong kind of person get
what you've made I realize what a craft
product development is and I would and
you know adding you know spiking with
terpenes to it it adds a whole nother
level to of you know artisan to the
craft because I would say that people
are who are our adding terpenes to their
products the ones who are doing it
really well aren't just spiking the hell
out of one they're actually crafting you
know several of them together for a
desired effect and and that is
challenging just totally up and beyond
what the rest of the the soda or the
edible or the capsule is it's like a
whole nother level of expertise
absolutely and you know the other thing
with with these being highly volatile
meaning you know they evaporate easily
being being very volatile scent
molecules there also have a very strong
flavor on the palate so you know in
bringing them into a product it's not
necessarily just as easy as you know
taking your current existing recipe and
adding some terpenes to it you know you
the the entire recipe kind of needs to
be analyzed to make sure not only that
you're not going to ruin the flavor or
grossly manipulate the flavor but that
is not going to like you said kind of
like the shelf stability side of things
like three months down the road that
it's not going to separate or that you
know some sort of discoloration or
something along those lines happens so
it really is something to kind of
integrate into a product and then you
know we usually recommend that people
give it like 8 to 12 weeks shelf
stability test there are laboratories
that you can work with within the within
the food and cosmetic industries that
can do some simulated testing to kind of
help you get some more rapid feedback
they can they can do about a week's
worth of microbial testing and then
build upon that a model that could kind
of give you an idea but ultimately it's
again it's it's kind of just like with
any other new input you're going to need
to really put in your own R&amp;D we get a
lot of people that will call us and
really want the you know the Silver
Bullet and so far I haven't found it
shut right on you got to build the
Silver Bullet at home
well then thank you so much for being on
the show we also got through about half
of my questions I'm gonna have to have
you back another time but thanks for
making the time to be here today
no shouldn't go I'd really appreciate it
Ben Cassidy is co-founder of true
terpenes you can find out more at bye -
terpenes comm you can find more episodes
of the shaping fire podcast and
subscribe to the show at shaping fire
calm and on Apple iTunes stitcher and
Google Play if you enjoyed the show we'd
really appreciate it if you'd leave a
positive review of the podcast wherever
you download your review will help
others find the show so they can enjoy
it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the weekly newsletter for
insights into the latest cannabis news
and product reviews on the shaping fire
website you will also find transcripts
of today's podcast as well
for information on me and where i will
be speaking you can check out Shango
lows calm as your company want to reach
our national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hot spot at shaping
feiyr.com to find out how thanks for
listening to shaping fire I've been your
host
Shango lows
[Music]