[Music]
the stock market is a moody beast no
matter how much insight you have or how
many Fibonacci lines you draw on your
charts there are still innumerable
pitfalls that can cross your path and
ruin your trade the risks involved
skyrocket too when you invest in a
nascent industry like cannabis the
rapidly changing market lack of
historical data and of course federal
cannabis prohibition
I'll make investing in cannabis unlike
investing in any other industry if you
enjoy hearing frank discussions that
dive deep in a cannabis health business
and technique I encourage you to
subscribe to our newsletter every week
you'll receive a new podcast episode
delivered right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week and
videos - don't rely on social media to
let you know when a new episode is
published sign up for the updates to
make sure you don't miss an episode you
are listening to shaping fire and I'm
your host Shango Lohse my guest this
week is Alan Broxton Alan is a CFA
charterholders a stint in Texas he began
his career on Wall Street in 1986 and
now works as an independent research
analyst following over two decades in
research and portfolio management he is
founder of the 420 investor online
community which is the first and still
largest due diligence platform focused
on publicly traded stocks in the
cannabis industry he's a prolific writer
- with over 650 articles published since
2007 at seeking alpha where he has
70,000 followers
Owen is a frequent speaker at industry
conferences and a frequent source to the
media including the New York Times The
Wall Street Journal Fox Business and
Bloomberg TV
he's currently writing columns for both
Leafly and Forbes
welcome to the show Alan hey thanks for
having me it's always great to speak
with you and I'm looking forward to
addressing your audience fabulous well
I'm glad that you could set aside the
time for us so you know at the heart of
investing is the weighing of risk versus
reward and in an explosive industry like
ours with so many variables moving at
the same time how do you recommend
investors approached determining how
much risk they are comfortable with
yeah that's risk is what it's all about
Shingo so I'm glad you started with that
when I showed up on the scene in 2013
I saw a lot of risk in Apps
no opportunity at least in the public
markets which is where I was initially
focused and even today I like to remind
people that this is all federally
illegal so in my community at 420
investor I'm in the middle of a survey
right now that I'm about to close out
and a lot of the people have seventy
five to a hundred percent of their
portfolio invested in cannabis stocks
I think that's insane so I try to remind
people of a couple of things number one
federally legality number two most of
the publicly traded stocks are on the
over-the-counter which is a whole
different can of worms it has nothing to
do with cannabis it just has to do with
penny stock fraud which is rampant so I
do like people to keep that in mind and
at the same time I like to point people
to Canada where that federal
illegalities --nt the same issue so so
flush that out a little bit so what what
is different about the approach in
Canada versus how it is here
oh sure so yeah some people may not
realize but Canada has a federally legal
medical cannabis program and that's been
around it launched officially in 2014 it
was the second version they had one that
launched I think in 2001 and so they're
on the cusp of being totally federally
legal for adult use as well and you know
that that impacts everything and impacts
banking taxes everything all these
problems we have in the United States
they don't have to deal with in Canada
of course Canada's not as big as the
United States it's almost as big as
California I see what you're saying so
as far as unpacking one's risk goes you
know anywhere that you invest in a
licensed product market in the US your
first you know monster in the room is oh
yeah its federal illegal but at least if
you were to invest in Canadian companies
those companies they may or may not
themselves be a good company but at
least they're not federally illegal
exactly and you know it goes a little
bit deeper than that it just makes it
easier to invest in companies that you
know your audience is pie familiar with
280e
for instance
and you know it's unfortunate but even
companies that operate well they have to
pay sometimes eighty percent marginal
tax rates you just don't have to deal
with those kind of problems in Canada
yeah when when when considering
investing in companies it's amazing how
a typical looking at at profit and
margins and and P&amp;L is different because
there are line items that are there that
don't appear in traditional companies
and there are additional line on items
that you don't find in other businesses
just because cannabis is such a unique
sector right now yep yeah so so so as
far as the you know the federal
regulation aspect of it right I mean
certainly overall we have this umbrella
of investing in US companies are a
challenge because they're federally
illegal but then we've got things that
happen on a weekly scale right we've got
you know Jeff Sessions says one thing
this week and then he seems to say
something different another week and you
know we're back and forth with you know
is it gonna be schedule one schedule two
unscheduled and so there seems to be a
intentional you know media circus around
these things because it all is clickbait
on social media and so it all tends to
be kind of constantly a fervor of this
how do you what you know what do you
recommend to your investors and and
guide them to to either react or non
react to this kind of intentional you
know excitement of investors so this
whole Jeff Sessions thing is definitely
a problem I I think it's like one of
those clouds that you see lingering all
the time and will it actually rain in
last November when the election results
were pouring in I was kind of shocked
initially had to see not only that the
Senate was gonna go the other way but
more importantly that we're gonna have
changed an administration and the first
thing I thought of was we are at risk
and so I told my subscribers at
four-twenty investor that we we have a
risk factor doesn't mean anything's
gonna happen but it's something that the
markets are gonna have to deal with and
it really caused a problem because the
stock prices had run up going into the
election and then they
back so you know I I don't think Jeff
Sessions is actually going to get his
wish which is to roll back cannabis
whether it's medical or even adult use
maybe adult use will see the Cole memo
kind of ramped up a little bit so that
there's more of restrictions I could I
could see that but I don't think that
would kill the industry so yes this
remains a risk factor and something that
the media as you mentioned really over
plays and it scares people and it scares
the entrepreneurs because if you think
back to 2013 after Washington and
Colorado had voted to legalize in late
2012 everybody was sitting around around
waiting on the federal government to see
what would happen and they put in place
the Cole memo in August and then all of
a sudden all the entrepreneurs investors
were able to move forward in both states
and I think it's probably too late to
roll it back there's you have an issue
now where a lot of states are pulling in
a lot of tax money there's a lot of
employment in the sector and probably
more importantly Shango that the will of
the voters just continues to really
point to tolerance for recreational
cannabis in an actual embracement of
medical cannabis I mean we saw that in
the Florida elections very conservative
state a lot of older people yet they got
past the 60% requirement to pass medical
cannabis which was something they were
unable to do in the prior election so I
think that it's actually the state and
local governments there are more of a
problem for the cannabis industry than
the federal the federal government is
obviously not helping the industry but
it's kind of status quo it's really it's
the municipalities in the states when
we're seeing a lot of problems we saw
that in Ohio a couple weeks ago when
they handed out licenses and there's a
lot of controversy there already we've
seen delays in a lot of states we see a
lot of municipalities pushing back we
see rule changes that can really hurt
these cannabis companies when they all
of a sudden change the rules so you know
you started off time at risk there's so
many different risks and this
this industry so let's talk about a
couple other ones so on a company to
company level you know you know in a in
an industry like ours that's so
fast-paced and for you know the last 50
years has been in the shadows now that
people are able to work on these
products and these technologies and
these business solutions out in the open
more we get people who are developing
extraction technology technology x' at
this at this wicked rate and and and and
the technologies are becoming outmoded
and being surpassed by new companies at
an incredible rate how do you weigh
these these fast-paced technologies and
solutions becoming outmoded so quickly
when you're trying to decide whether or
not a company's got long term viability
ya know I'm I'm actually really excited
about this because this is one of things
I mentioned it's really one of the best
things about our industry that we we
have time in incentives for people to
make big changes and I guess you're
looking at it as a threat the reality is
most of the cannabis stocks that have
been trained over the last few years are
really not real and we haven't really
addressed that yet so it's not so much a
risk for cannabis investors is an
opportunity I'd love to see some of
these innovative companies move into the
public sector they're not really there
yet so for the most part you're talking
about in the private investment world
where we're seeing a lot of companies do
neat things we're seeing companies jump
from basically where they'll have a
product developed for let's just call it
a regular industry and then they adapt
that product and we're talking about
like POS systems for instance but it
goes a lot deeper and the thing that I
really focus on and I'm not seeing it
yet in the public markets but we're
getting close and that is technology
that will enable us to have cannabis
beverages rapid-acting it doesn't have
to be necessarily beverages but
rapid-acting cannabis edibles that
really get around one of the worst
aspects of edibles which is that you
know the onset so slow the people tend
to overdo it sometimes and really cuts
down on social nice I saw just today
shellene title has been able to pull off
in Massachusetts the ability to have
social use which is something we haven't
really seen in any market yet
certainly not in Colorado the original
legal market I think to get on parity
with the alcohol industry that's going
to be essential so that's what I'm
looking for and like I say it's more of
an opportunity than really a risk I
don't think anybody's gonna lose by the
way no markets changing I mean flower is
still very popular it runs at about 50%
in your state still and in most states
but we're seeing all these other really
neat forms of delivery and innovation
and in terms of the modes of ingestion
or consumption when an investor is
looking at a company and considering
investing you know there's so many
unproven executives in cannabis it
reminds me of the first dot-com boom
where you'd have a visionary who had
some kind of access to capital and so
they started from nothing and they may
have been you know a middle manager or
less at some company beforehand but
they're just somebody with moxie and
access to some capital and off they went
you know building building their dot-com
and the majority of them failed from
either running out of cash or just from
poor management or both you know how do
you weigh for yourself this is the fact
that there are so many inexperienced
managers who are running these companies
ya know that's a good point and so I a
few years ago I started sharing my 3p
analysis of companies and I think
investors really fall for one of the P's
the first P is the plan I don't usually
say that first of all I'm gonna say it
to you first you know what is what is it
that they're trying to do what's their
plan and then the second P is the people
and that's kind of what you're asking
about and then the third one that you
alluded to as well I called the
pecuniary because that is a P instead of
money or it could be the P P and the M
but so what I try to tell people is
don't get caught up on the plan first of
all I mean plans are pretty easy and so
then you you look at the people it's
very important because you're right I
mean even for myself I'm not the best
stock analyst in the world I was just
the only one crazy enough to show up
here in 2013 which gave me a running
head start in in the same way you know
people were either smart or stupid but
they came into this industry because
they saw an opportunity and you know
there's a lot of stigma and that keeps
people out I'm seeing huge changes on
that front over the last 6 to 12 months
where we're seeing just a rapid influx
of really qualified people and that's
that's a good thing for the industry but
it's gonna get to the point where like
you said some of these people that were
here a couple years ago they're not
really qualified to lead the industry
necessarily so and then on the money
part I think it's important because you
know people that were paying attention
in the dot-com could have seen the cash
burns and lack of tangible results and
figured out that that wasn't gonna work
one thing I run into all the time when
interviewing folks and then just doing
my own research on companies are the two
different kinds of leaders that they
tend to have on one side you've got
companies that are led by by folks who
have their life experience in
prohibition area era yeah so they are
their cannabis people first and foremost
they were in the shadows when it when it
became more normalized they've come out
of the shadows and now they're running
their company but because they were
doing black market business for all
these years they don't have a lot of the
traditional skills that you'd get at a
you know fully legal corporation now on
the flip side you've got all these new
people coming into the industry that
have little to no cannabis experience
except for maybe toking in themselves
but they have worked at you know blue
chip companies and they they know how to
read a P&amp;L and they're used to working
with venture capital and so they've got
that side but then they don't know what
ask a master grower when they go to hire
them because I don't actually they're
not from inside the industry so so how
do you see those two sets of people you
know how do you weigh between the two of
those when you're considering investing
yeah this is a great question and it's
something I point to a lot I'm flashing
back to the one and only
MJ bisque on I went to in 2014 I go to
other conferences but I don't like big
crowds and I remember kind of looking at
the it was such a divergent group of
people you had like you said the suits
and then the people that knew what they
were doing but not necessarily so
business savvy in the real world and and
thankfully I've noticed I haven't been
back to that conference but at other
conferences I've noticed it's getting
bridged and what I try to counsel
anybody he'll listen to me is look for
the management teams that they don't
necessarily have to have the Cannabis
expertise that's always I think it's
good to have somebody on the team that
really has it but you can get that on an
outsourced basis by having good
consultants you just want to make sure
that the suits running the company are
grounded in the reality of the industry
and at the same time it's very possible
that you could have people that are
emerging from the black market they'd
never have the felony or there it's
going to be hard to do but they don't
have the management savvy on their team
but they have good counselors so it's
it's you don't necessarily have to have
those people but I really like to see
management teams that have been able to
where the where the two sides have been
able to come together and appreciate
that if they want to really accomplish a
lot they're gonna have to draw from both
those wells and work together and that
they've internally resolved that and can
show that unified presence to their
investors or customers or whatever it is
I think you're really spot-on to mention
consultants because even though you know
a cannabis consultant air quotes is kind
of a running joke right yes yeah because
you know you can't go to a convention
without bumping into you know hundreds
of cannabis consultants but at the same
time you're right you can you can
third-party those types of skills
which makes the skill that the to the
suit to use your words they don't
necessarily need to know how to set up
an extraction lab but they have to be
really good with their Human Resources
approach to know how to find the right
kind of person who actually knows how to
set up a lab and in the in these early
days I would say that we're finding more
people who have hired the wrong people
and have got a fall out of that
relationship and they have more success
with their second or third person
because they're actually having to learn
from their mistakes that's for sure and
I hear about you know we're on our
fourth master grower kind of discussion
all the time and we're talking I Canada
earlier this is even up there they have
the same problem and maybe it's even
worse it's but it really hits home and I
always try to look I don't have a horse
in this race really I'm you know I'm
kind of an observer and the analyst I'm
not in the industry so I I have a lot of
sympathy and for the people who fought
the battle to get us to where we are and
it really pains me when I see like
what's going on in California a lot of
these people are going to really not be
in the industry unfortunately and you
know Oregon was a good state they've let
people even with felonies participate in
the industry but most states don't do
that but up in Canada they have the
exact same problem with the people that
have been operating the gray market
they're disenfranchised and so I've
noticed you know some of the companies
have figured this out and have tried to
bring them in and just recently the
Federal Government of Canada proposed
kind of a second tier producer called a
micro cultivator I guess like a craft
cultivator which from my understanding
this is an attempt to broaden the
industry because if it's gonna make the
industry better you you want to kill off
the black market you don't want to push
the people with all the expertise out
and make them compete with you in the
black market that's not good for society
so there's a lot we can unpack the
yeah totally well that's exactly what
happened here in Washington right yeah
instead of blessing the medical medical
yeah medical just got straight killed
and they gave the licenses to all the
newcomers so now we've got this this
highly integrated networked black market
that also happens to have incredible
technology co2 extractors and great labs
competing with the state and so it's
it's ugly so so in this in this first
section of the show we've talked a lot
about some of the unique and ugly risks
that investors have to consider when
when looking at these new companies and
and you know it's it's enough to cause
people to just say man forget investing
in cannabis it's it's it's too noisy
it's not a safe place for my money I'll
put it somewhere else that's got less of
these risks when when you hear people
who are kind of looking for a reason
because they want to invest in cannabis
but they also see these risks is there
anything that you can tell them to kind
of soothe them to like hey you know keep
looking in cannabis yeah so I've been
you know I I've been warning about these
risks for a long time and it was really
an inflection point in my cannabis
career when the local CFA or Chartered
Financial Analysts Society asked me to
speak in April and not I I wouldn't have
done it until this year and I feel like
the industry the investment set has
definitely improved the risks are still
there I think they've gone down and
they're better understood now and and
what I tell people in the 420 investor
community is mitigate the risk don't put
all your money into the industry put a
little bit don't put it all into one
stock spread it around you know I'd give
the same device to any private investors
were they to ask just in terms of you
know making sure you don't have too much
exposure to any one situation because
you just the fact that it's a new
industry you should be careful it's a
venture capital type of approach just
you know if you have make 10 investments
and one of them is a 10 bag or it
doesn't matter what happens with
with the rest really so that that's kind
of what I try to tell them to to be
diversified into not well that's mainly
it diversification shingles yeah right
on that makes a lot of sense so we're
gonna take a short break and be right
back you're listening to shaping fire
and my guest today is Alan Broxton
founder of new cannabis ventures and
4/20 investor if you own a cannabis
company you know that finding good
business partners vendors and allies is
an essential part of your role and
building your business and a new
industry like cannabis doesn't always
make that easy canna con is coming to
Seattle Boston and Detroit in the first
half of 2018 and the halls will be
filled with every kind of Ally you need
for a cannabis company technology
horticulture packaging marketing legal
Human Resources and media everything you
need for your business will be there and
your customers will be there too canna
con is a premier cannabis business and
networking event with nationally
recognized speakers and the opportunity
to have serious conversations with your
business peers and investors reserving
yourself a boot that can akan can unlock
a lot of doors for you not only do you
get to network with all the people who
pass your booth but it is not uncommon
for canna con vendors to do a million
dollars in business during the event
booths are already sold out for Seattle
February 15th 16th and 17th so reserve
your booths now for Detroit in June and
Boston in July while you still can
attendee tickets are still available for
all three events whether you reserve a
booth or a 10 for a day do not miss the
opportunity to become a serious player
in your local cannabis market visit
canikin org for tickets buthe
reservations and more information that's
canikin org while I certainly still
enjoy smoking joints I moved over to
using vaporizers about three years ago
the high was a little different than
burning the flower and in the end I
decided I preferred it for daily use
especially because I have asthma more
importantly though I could taste my
flower so much more it's hard to express
to you how significantly different
cannabis with a good terpene profile
tastes when vaped instead of burned I
have brought my vape with me to visit
growers and they are astonished by the
clarity of taste and they say they feel
like they're tasting their flower for
the very first time the air vape
vaporizer from air vape usa.com is a
great device to use on the go or at home
when you pick it up and feel satisfying
like a medical device
it isn't flimsy like many vapes are I
like how the flower is inserted in the
top instead of the bottom so travels are
shorter path to my mouth with the
cannabis at the top I get a hit that
feels more substantial even though I'm
just inhaling vapor and not full bodied
smoke since I used this vape for flower
hash and concentrates I really like that
that digital control for the temperature
is right there on the front three clicks
of the button and it fires up to the
temperature I specify really quickly and
discreetly you know vape concentrates
are a milder experience than dabbing but
you still get the potency in your hit
also the taste is great as would be
expected with a low temp tab I love that
this vape gives quick little vibrations
when it gets to the right temperature
that way if I'm chatting or distracted
while it's heating up it lets me know
when it's ready if you are ready for a
nice pocket-sized vaporizer consider the
air vape the new air vape ex has just
come out and it's gorgeous and it
includes many updates you can find more
about the air vape vaporizer at air vape
usa.com welcome back you are listening
to shaping fire I'm your host Shango
Lowe's and our guest this week is Alan
Brock Steen founder of new cannabis
ventures and 4/20 investor so during the
first set we talked a lot about the high
risks that are involved with investing
in these cannabis companies and the
importance of being diversified and you
know most everybody is getting their
information about these companies on the
internet and these you know most Lee's
canvassed companies are so obscure and a
lot of the news about them seems somehow
canned and prepared how should folks
interested in cannabis investing go
about starting their research into their
target companies yeah that's a good
question I mean this led me to start a
new business because I was running a 420
investor from late 2013 into 2015 and
just really scratching my head about the
bigger industry instead of just the
public stocks we're talking about the
whole industry and one of the things I
was known for at 420 investor was being
a really good
filter and there's so much noise and
people wanted to get information on the
good companies only not all the noise
out there and that's really what I was
trying to do a 420 investment so we
started a new cannabis ventures in
September of 2015 with that goal to kind
of focus on just the really good
companies and the really good investors
because there's a lot of fake investors
to which we can talk about so it is hard
to find news and I think your listeners
deserve to know that there's you know
that whole concept of fake news is
supreme in the cannabis industry in them
in the public stocks especially but I've
seen it even in private companies in
these press releases will know we don't
have operations today but we're gonna
have a hundred million in revenue and
next year that type of thing so there is
a lot out there you know I wish I could
tell your listeners of all the different
places there's some great content
creators out there I guess they're kind
of competitors of mine that new cameras
of interest we we definitely have an
investor audience but we get a lot of
operators as well cannabis business
times I think does a great job they have
a cultivation focus but they have real
news you know MJ business daily has
really stepped it up
they have journalists on staff they've
widened their their content so I think
that's a good place for people to get
information from cannabis industry
Journal there's some good podcasters
besides you I include you in the list
but there's some others as well we don't
have to name them all but I think it's
important to really understand kind of
what the source of the news is because
if it's just being paid for and it's not
really earned it's not really that real
and there's a lot of that going on yeah
one of those sources that I like that
that does not overly pump things up is
Alex Halperin over at weed week yeah
yeah his curation is really nice and he
doesn't add drama to things but you know
that was originally what attracted me to
to your new cannabis ventures because I
think you do a really good job curating
as well and you know your your intent
when you curate is different than a lot
of other sources a lot of other sources
they're they're curating because they
want clicks and they want right people
to comment and they want the drama and
the sharing and the arguing and all that
kind of stuff but that's not your goal
your goal you started new cannabis
ventures to be of service to the
investors in your 420 investors
community right and so so instead of
just trying to get the clicks you're
trying to create a base so that people
have got good information in the
community you run and I think that
that's a really important delineation
yeah well it's not just in that
community it's it's broader and it's
really extending from that but are you
know so we have just so people
understand our business model we're very
transparent and go to our site and see
exactly who our advertisers are and
there's no doubt we run our advertisers
and news we don't we don't share our
views like I would never say you should
invest in my advertiser but we run the
news of their competitors - it's very I
always tell our advertisers our readers
are the most important thing to us we if
we don't have our readers we don't have
a business and and we've earned the
trust of our readers for two reasons
number one that we've been very very
much a filter we we don't we will report
on like I've written some pretty
negative stories about poseurs I'm well
known for that that's really a second
point so they people can count on us if
it's important news we're gonna publish
it and that's the first thing but they
can also count on us to really call
people out and when I do go to
conferences people will come up to me
Shengo and they'll say you know I got to
tell you I love the way you're willing
to call these jokers out and so
fortunately I don't have to do that that
much but it's actually kind of enjoy it
it's it's a weird thing in our society
that you can make a lot of money saying
good things about people there's a lot
to that at the same time if you want to
say bad things about people you run a
big risk
I was sued for a hundred million dollars
back in 2013 by a company that's now
bankrupt and it literally they called
this libel I cut and pasted their SEC
filings and they didn't like that and
they sued me and anybody can sue anybody
for anything
so you know I had to absorb the expense
of getting that eliminated but it was a
big you know I was scared 100 million
dollars a lot of money but for me so you
know in cannabis cannabis is drawing out
a lot of first-time investors and we had
yes you know people who have maybe maybe
they've talked their whole life and this
is the time that they've always hoped
would happen and and they want to get
involved or or people who were around
for Google going public everybody's like
oh if I if I only would have invested in
Google a heck a lot of my friends are
doing that right now around Bitcoin you
know and so so there's a lot of new
investors and and I'd love for you to
kind of just briefly explain for folks
just to help them be aware of this kind
of news about the the habit of I guess
we'll call it fake new sources pumping
up a company or a stock to elicit
excitement and then whoever's behind the
play then dumping it could you kind of
just explain that dynamic a little bit
so that people can read with a little
more skepticism oh yeah and I love where
you're coming from and you're spot-on
there are so many people of all ages
that are showing up and you know this
started not not recently it started back
in 13 but it's still happening with
California about to legalize I'm seeing
it again and I think this is what people
don't understand about the OTC I
mentioned it earlier has nothing to do
with the cannabis industry this problem
that I'm about to tell you it's just
human nature and snake oil salesmen and
all that and so anytime something's hot
like Bitcoin right now it draws in the
scammers and the cannabis industry has
drawn in fake cannabis companies this
has been going on for years now I like
to point to the positive that there's a
lot more real companies now but it's
undoubtedly true that there's a ton of
posers out there and the people behind
these companies this is what a lot of
people don't understand the finance
seers they they get free blocks of stock
or very cheap blocks of stock and
they'll pay for news to go out there and
it sounds great and people see this and
they don't under
stand that it's not real and so it
causes a temporary blip in the price of
the stock and the volume and it allows
these scammers to unload their shares
and honestly I wish I really understood
it all the SEC is overworked I know if
they had more money and more power they
would not allow this to happen but it's
unfortunate there are companies that
don't even file with the SEC which I
can't even believe that that's legal and
they file on what's called OTC markets
and in even some of the SEC filing
companies they do things that are just
should be illegal yet it goes on and
some of these things would include like
you know we read about it after the fact
unfortunately where the SEC
enforces action and you have to wonder
how many of these do they not catch but
they'll put out a press release how they
caught these people with these illegal
offshore accounts and they were doing
this and doing that guess what this goes
on every day and that's the unfortunate
part about the cannabis market being on
what's called the over the counter or
OTC most of these stocks don't trade on
the New York Stock Exchange or the
Nasdaq there's a few exceptions and so
it's it's very unfortunate and it leaves
people with a really bad taste in their
mouth because they're excited about
investing in the cannabis industry but
they go in with their eyes wide open and
they get taken advantage of and then
they think there's something wrong with
cannabis or something you know to that
effect and it's really a structural
problem not related to the cannabis
industry but related to over-the-counter
certainly the idea of pump and dump is
is way easier to do thanks to social
media right because oh my gosh yes so
much more difficult but now if you
coordinate two or three media sources
and you put out a tasty bit of news and
suggest that everyone's buying it and
and then you buy a big chunk yourself so
that the stock goes up a little bit and
then at which somehow proves to people
that that the news that they're reading
is true so now all these the second wave
investors jump in and now it's really
going up which then really doubly proves
that
that media source is true and then as
soon as it hits the target level for for
the people behind this misinformation
they dump all of their stock the prices
crashes and then and then all of these
first-time investors and and even you
know pros they their money just
vaporizes you sound like you know what's
going on here you sure you're not a pump
and dump er yourself I'm just a nerd and
I did the doctor it was really common
then - yeah no you're right and the
social media part for sure we see all
sorts of Twitter BOTS
I mean I've my partner has actually
researched some of the names that we've
written on and we'll see we're able to
prove that there's fake BOTS out there
pushing saying good things about the
company on Twitter it's very easy to set
up an Instagram account and show pretty
pictures of Budd I mean there's if
there's all these things that can really
play to that psychology of making
something fake look real yeah that's for
sure so so let's talk about you know
informal information that happens to you
know one thing that I run into all the
time being in media and being at
conventions you know the listening to
shaping fire listening to a podcast
through your earbuds as many people do
is a pretty intimate experience right I
have access I'm in there I'm in their
ear and we're talking you know you know
usually weekly and so a lot of these
executives they take me aside at events
and they they tell me things right they
they're excited about this this merger
that's about to happen or this company
they're about to acquire this new
technology that's coming out and they're
they're bursting and they just want
somebody who they feel is going to
appreciate it with them because they're
excited and so they tell me or they are
they tell an associate of mine and now
suddenly we know information that's not
publicly available and this is happening
all the time especially with executives
who are new to playing at this level
they're used to talking you know just
talking with their friends over beers or
whatever and now they're playing with
you know seven figures or more
of valuation and so you know where is
this line between you know being a smart
investor and asking questions that other
people aren't asking so you can unearth
valuable information versus straight-up
insider trading where you could get in
some trouble yeah you know I I'm very
sensitive to that I your audience
doesn't notice I don't invest in the
cannabis industry and this is one of the
reasons why I don't because I don't want
to be in that position of of crossing
that line most of the people I speak
with they tend to be in the public
market so they're gonna be very careful
about that anyway but you know they're
very careful in general with me so I
don't really get that crossing of the
line and saying things this should be
disclosed publicly but aren't but I'm
sure it happens and III mean to me
that's a big risk we have clients as I
mentioned and you know they sometimes
want me to they want to give me
information and sign an NDA I'm like why
I don't want to know anything that's not
public
I really don't so I tried to protect
myself and them by not accepting
confidential information so but I can
see how that's a problem
yeah actually that that lack of
willingness to sign an NDA is a really
interesting aspect I'm have to chew on
that a little bit yeah I don't want
privileged information I really don't
I'm not investing and you know
especially with a public company that's
just that's a huge risk I mean you read
about this all the time these people
getting busted for insider trading I'm
not gonna be one of those people right
on so so so let's talk about companies
that are on the far side of maybe not a
pump and dub but but are on the far side
of the media's excitement about them
right so so I'm into some cannabis
companies I that I bought you know stock
in early on and and you know they got up
to a couple bucks few bucks and then and
then they're there you know maybe they
lost a CEO or or their product didn't
get adopted as fast or like we were
talking about earlier their their local
laws change
there's a moratorium or something just
mess them up right and so so so they got
up to a few bucks and now they're just
kind of languishing at you know 30 or 50
cents something like that what are the
kinds of things that you know if the
companies is going to have a rebound
these are these are stocks that are on
sale right these are these are things
that you can get at a low price so long
as they eventually go up so so from on
the Investor side what kinds of things
can happen for these companies that were
up and now they're down that actually
can revitalize and and be seen as a
value stock that's undervalued yep well
so let me warn everybody because we're I
think in the middle of our third big
rally since 2013 the first one around
Colorado the second one in advance of
the elections last year and so this
one's in advance of California it's
something I've been talking about for a
while but I always like to point out to
people and I've even been writing about
this like I think I post this with no
LinkedIn did you know that that historic
rally in 2014 when Colorado legalized
there weren't that many stocks and there
were a lot of people you were talking
about the excitement earlier so I'm you
know imagine everybody's trying to to
get into the arena right in time you
know the lines long to get in and so
that pushed prices way high so you had a
lot of some of the early stocks that
went to prices that really made no sense
and that weren't sustainable so I would
caution investors just in general to
understand that there are a lot more
stocks I tracked maybe 20 stocks at the
beginning of 2014 that were cannabis
related now I'm at 600 some of those are
Canadian so you have a lot more stocks
and just a little bit more subtle point
many of those stocks back then the
insiders held like 90 percent of the
shares and so there was just a small
amount that was in the public float and
that created an artificial mechanism
that really forced those stocks to
really unsustainable levels because if
you factor in the other 90 percent that
weren't trading the
stocks couldn't have gotten to where
they got so that that's the first thing
so look I told you the industry in my
view has really improved and we started
at new cannabis ventures tracking the
companies that have ten million dollars
a year or more in sales and this is
something that I couldn't have done last
year but we now have I think 14
companies on this page when we're
updating it as the numbers change that
are on track to ten million dollars a
year or more in revenue and in fact some
of them are pushing 30 million or 40
million in a year so I think as an
investor this is to answer your question
what's gonna make these companies that
are down work check and see if they're
generating revenue and and of course
just generating revenue isn't in the
long run gonna be the only thing because
you have to be profitable ultimately or
you're gonna just have to keep going
back to the markets and diluting and you
know forcing your price low or overtime
as there's more shares but that that
would be my first clue to take a look
and see if what kind of progress they've
make is if you go back and you look at
the companies that were trading at the
beginning of 2014 most of them haven't
really done anything Shango
unfortunately now the good news is we
have a bunch of new companies that have
come along that I think are pretty
interesting a lot of them are on that
list right on you know I had never
considered how much of the early
cannabis stock was held inside and
therefore that that 10% that was the
public float that was people were
investing not based on the
characteristics of the company they were
the price was going up based on scarcity
exactly value yes no wonder so many of
those turned around as as their their
angel investors and original owners you
know dumped some of their stock so that
they could you know eat and live and you
know RIA you know RIA
yeah it was a little bit that but just
to be clear these companies didn't have
much in the tournament operations so
just to keep the lights on they had to
but not the individuals necessarily
although that was partially the case I
mean I'm sure you remember a med box
yeah but
they also just had to like race and
capital and so you mean like fundraising
using it as a yes insider selling but
yes fundraising and a good example I
mean this is such a sad example and I
actually like this company by the way
it's called CV Sciences they they've
they've gone in a slightly different
direction because they're trying to
develop through the FDA path a
chewing-gum with CBD and nicotine but
their core business they're on my list
they're doing more than ten million
dollars a year in sales selling CBD
products they're highly regarded there
and so this is one of these stocks that
have that thin float and went to like
$200 a share and you know even today
it's at 30 cents a share so hey you know
it's kind of funny but so the stock goes
up to 200 they get on the cover of
Forbes magazine there was insider
selling but then they ended up raising a
bunch of money below $1 a share
you know they raised some at $2 after
the stock was at 200 and that that was
the reality 200 was not the reality
right now that makes sense you know
there's before we go to commercial you
know there's there's one more category
of investor that I think that a lot of
people ignore and those are the people
who are involved with sweat equity right
these are not necessarily public
companies as a matter of fact they're
either pre public or just privately held
but they're people who are who have been
told okay I'd like you to come in and
run my lab and set it up and use your
consulting expertise but we don't want
to pay you decently we want to pay you
you know 15 bucks an hour and we're
gonna give you a quit in the company and
this happened so often during the
dot-com boom even to me where I had
equity and six or seven companies that
were worth less than a rubber duck with
a hole in it right and so I think we're
seeing a lot of that now where there are
a lot of employees who they want to be
part of a company that's gonna make it
and they want to make their Green Rush
money buy by taking a lower wage and
also you know taking some sweat equity
do you have any advice for an employee
who's thinking about taking some equity
in lieu of you know immediate financial
compensation yeah well that's a good
question I have not given it thought but
the first thing that comes to mind
because I haven't really seen that I
don't really get into that granular of a
level but if you're working for a
company and they want you to take equity
take a look at what they're showing
outside investors just so you understand
exactly what you're getting I mean this
is not just the cannabis industry but
any industry and I've heard this before
a lot of times you know people can be
really smart they can be an engineer or
you know some sort of graphic design or
really smart at what they do it doesn't
mean that they understand how to value
companies or anything like that so get a
get a copy of what they're showing
investors if you don't understand it
take it to somebody who does pay them a
couple hundred bucks whatever it is to
have somebody say you know what is it or
if they're giving me 10,000 options what
does that even mean are there 10
gazillion shares are there 20 shares it
is extreme so I think that can be really
challenging for a lot of people because
not everybody has that expertise you
know so that would be my advice right on
we're gonna take another short break and
be right back you're listening to
shaping fire and my guest today is Alan
Broxton founder of new cannabis ventures
and 420 investor we humans are attracted
to plants because they offer us relief
and are a whole lot of fun sometimes
though the best parts are buried inside
the plant and we need to use specialty
extraction technology when it comes to
cannabis it is extraordinarily important
to extract its precious oils without
changing them in the process we want to
preserve the properties of the
cannabinoids terpenes and other
constituents that all work together
since 1994 Eden labs has been developing
extraction technology and processes to
do just that Eden labs was founded by a
cannabis loving engineer during the
early days of medical marijuana in
California and the expanded Eden team
has been designing and building
industry-leading solutions for cannabis
extraction ever since
Eden labs flagship product is the newly
improved High Flow co2 extractor as
other extraction companies enter the
market it is the high flow from Eden
labs that everyone chases and tries to
compare themselves with
not only that but the improved
automation software allows data to be
collected stored and studied Eden labs
can outfit your whole lab Eden's
coldfinger ethanol extractor creates
astonishing whole plant extracts working
alone or in tandem with an initial
stream distilling step to isolate
monoterpenes before extracting the rest
of the botanical constituents Eden
offers you many options including vacuum
distillation column distilling stirred
reactor units and accelerated solvent
recovery when you partner with Eden labs
your lab team is enrolled into the Eden
labs training program to boost their
understanding of Eden's best practices
to ensure that your outputs are exactly
what you require for your application
whether it be dab oil oil for pen
cartridges or edibles when you work with
Eden you're not just buying the tech you
are buying dedicated customer support to
help you attain your business goals -
you can hear Eden's CEO AC Braddock talk
about the company's values during
shaping fire episode 19 that was all
about co2 extraction so many of the new
companies in the market just smell
opportunity slap an extractor together
and hire a marketing company Eden Labs
has been listening to feedback from
extractors and consumers for about 25
years now they care about both you and
your consumer partner with Eden labs to
extract astonishing cannabis oils and
terpenes that you will be proud of go to
shaping feiyr.com
Ford / Eden to find out more
skinny-dippin humpback whales beatnik
poetry the Ottoman Empire soil
remediation interdimensional beings and
tree frogs these are just a few of the
interesting topics you can find in the
audio books library at audible.com if
you like podcasts like shaping fire
chances are that you'll dig audio books
too just like with podcasts audiobooks
speak to you telling you stories and
teaching you stuff here's the thing
audible.com has an offer I want to tell
you about right now they're offering a
trial of their audiobook service for
absolutely free you can go to shaping
feiyr.com forward slash audible and you
will get a free audiobook straight up
you can listen to it on your mobile
computer or you can download it and
listen to it like anywhere it's really
simple of course they want you to
subscribe to their service after the
free trial and enjoy their audiobooks
forever but you don't have to all you
have to do to get the free audiobook of
your choice is to check out the service
for free so that's the deal your first
book is free it's easy to sign up it's
easy to quit and their online library of
free ebooks is pretty incredible just
check it out go to shaping feiyr.com
forward slash audible to find out more
or click on the link in this week's
newsletter welcome back you are
listening to shaping fire I'm your host
Shango low sin our guest this week is
Alan Broxton founder of new cannabis
ventures and 4/20 investor so Alan in
this last section you know we've been
talking a lot about what we see now and
so often with investing people are
they've got their head down and and and
they're learning and they're looking too
much in the now what do you see out ten
years in this industry that investors
should be considering when investing in
things at this time
wow this industry changes so fast ten
years is like 50 years sure I don't know
if I have a ten year view but let me
just answer it as a longer-term view so
one of you know is a us from a us focus
one of the things obviously is you know
what's gonna happen with the federal
government and my own view there is
we're not gonna see any big changes in
the next few years maybe after the next
presidential election the problem is is
as much as people is the federal
politicians seem to be accepting of it
it's a very complex issue and you have
to deal with things like getting read a
280e
which the government makes a lot of
money off of so do they want to do that
then you're gonna get into things like
does Colorado really want it to be
federally legal there if so they they're
gonna lose tax money because California
is gonna be able to export to Colorado
we have so many different things that
are gonna have to be resolved in the
next few years then I don't think
federal legality is in the next five
years I think and that's fine I mean
that I wish they would legalize it but I
think from an investor's perspective
that's fine because it allows a lot of
companies to kind
of build-up without having to face a lot
of competition and there was a deal that
your listeners should be aware of which
took place it was announced right at the
end of October and closed early November
where a us-based liquor company or
alcohol company Constellation Brands put
190 million us into canopy growth which
is the largest Canadian you know
federally licensed producer and and that
was a game-changer in a lot of ways but
the main thing it really said was a the
alcohol industry is a little bit
concerned be hey maybe it's okay to make
an investment in cannabis but you got a
structure properly make sure it's
federally legal and I think in the next
few years we're going to see a lot more
interest from Big Pharma in the alcohol
industry it may be a little bit tobacco
I don't really personally see how
tobacco has much to do with cannabis I
know a lot of people like to say that it
does and there's some distribution
things I guess but the reality is I
think those other two industries as I
look out in the next few years that's
good from a u.s. investor that's gonna
be something to really focus on and at
the same time to watch some of the
better companies really develop their
franchises in the very complex difficult
markets to navigate right now where you
can't ship across state lines and you
have to deal with all these local rules
and state rules and things like that but
the other thing I think is going to be
really big and I've been talk about this
for a while is the globalization of
cannabis and we're seeing it in Latin
America we're seeing in Australia we're
seeing it in Europe and and of course
Canada which I mentioned before and the
u.s. is getting left behind and it's
kind of ironic to me because we have a
president who likes to be a winner and
we are a loser when it comes to the
global platform of cannabis and the
whole world is moving ahead and I think
anybody that's looking at cannabis
should really start to think long and
hard about expanding their opportunity
set and especially when you look at
things like Germany and it's a little
bit slow to play out but they have
pharmacy distribution that's covered by
insurance and it's a small program now
but it's going to get a lot bigger and
that's the way the world is headed where
medical cannabis is going to be legal
everywhere federally except apparently
the United States I think that's a
really good point that you're making in
and I talk about it a lot with my own
clients this this area of business right
like it's I think that's gonna come in
two waves you're gonna have your first
wave when eventually we'll be able to
ship interstate right and so you've got
you've got the all these these these
states where you cannot naturally grow
outdoors very easily I mean my state's
one of them here in Washington we've
only got a small part of the state that
gets enough warmth and Sun and as soon
as our market is able to be colonized by
California it's going to drastically
change the outlooks of companies here in
Washington or or anywhere on the
northern side of the country where
suddenly business plans that seem solid
if you only were doing business in your
state are suddenly going to be trashed
because the southern states with a lot
more sunshine are going to be coming in
and and similarly on the international
level oh my goodness once once Central
America and Mexico are able to grow
outdoor and process organic cannabis
oils and ship them the United States the
floor is just gonna drop out of the oil
market and I don't think a lot of
investors are thinking about how
drastically the market itself is gonna
shift hey you want me to throw another
one in that they're not quite there yet
but this whole concept of biosynthesis
where you can grow cannabinoids and not
just THC or CBD which are expressed
pretty frequently but some of the some
of the cannabinoids that are expressed
less frequently like CBD v that may be
very valuable for medical purposes you
can do this without cannabis you can do
it through this biotech process and you
know imagine putting all this money into
indoor grows all that capex and all the
sudden the infused cannabis industry
just starts buying the biosynthesized
have annoyed zai and that's something I
think people need to be aware of why the
longer term yeah that's really
interesting I can totally see the
upcoming shaping fire on that topic now
yeah we did we did 100 about three
months ago on synthetic cannabinoids and
and you know the the the general push on
that is that there's their synthetic and
and they've got attributes chemically
that are non natural and so they've got
real they can have real negative both
agonist and antagonist attributes but
but what you're describing is actually
growing the the molecule exactly as it
occurs in cannabis so yes well it's
isolate and we can argue to what degree
isolates are useful for health and
recreation that's a different
conversation but the fact that they
could just grow CBD v in a lab and have
it be molecular accurate yeah you're
right that'll that'll reshape parts of
the industry as well yep yeah well Alan
thank you so much for taking some time
with us I've really enjoyed chatting
with you and I appreciate you both both
you know kind of giving us our your
insight but then also providing some
good clean and news for us there at new
cannabis ventures oh thanks this has
been great I appreciate it
if you'd like to know more about Alan
Brock's team you can check out his
online cannabis investor community at
420 investor com that's for 2o investor
and also be sure to check out new
cannabis ventures com for daily investor
news and insight on the canvas
industry's most promising companies and
also I just checked it out they have
this great new news app that that will
push the news to you which is really
convenient you know if you're waiting at
the doctor's office around a bus or
something that's really great and their
weekly newsletter is also good if you
want to have the news push to you
instead of you having to to search it
out you can find more episodes of the
shaping fire podcast and subscribe to
the show at shaping fire calm and on
Apple iTunes stitcher and Google Play if
you enjoyed the show we'd really
appreciate it if you'd leave a positive
review of the podcast wherever you
download your review will help others
find the show so they can enjoy it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the weekly newsletter for
insights into the latest cannabis news
and product reviews on the shaping fire
web
so you will also find transcripts of
today's podcast as well for information
on me and where I will be speaking you
can check out Shango loast comm your
company want to reach our national
audience of cannabis enthusiasts email
hotspot at shaping fire calm to find out
how thanks for listening to shaping fire
I've been your host Shango lows
[Music]