[Music]
most people in the cannabis scene assume
they know how to judge good flower
subset of those people also think they
have advanced enough skills to even
judge cannabis competitions alas most
people are using their own subjective
standards and preferences while thinking
that they are being objective this gets
played out with very serious impacts
when wholesale cannabis buyers are
judging who to buy from for their retail
outlets but perhaps even more impactful
is when subjective preferences cloud the
decisions of cannabis cup judges today
we're going to talk about some of the
finer points of judging the merits of a
cannabis flower how disreputable judging
is at most cannabis competitions and the
certification called interpreting that
is - cannabis what a semi a
certification is - wine if you enjoy
hearing frank discussions that dive deep
in a cannabis health business and
technique i encourage you to subscribe
to our newsletter every week you'll
receive a new podcast episode delivered
right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple the most
important news items from the week
social media sites are becoming very
unreliable and showing folks every post
they want to see so sign up for the
newsletter and make sure you don't miss
an episode you are listening to shaping
fire and i'm your host
Shango lowe's my guest today is max
Montrose founder and current president
of the trichome Institute through the
trichome Institute max is a key
educational advisor to the government
business and public sectors he
specializes in providing a certifiable
cannabis curriculum for cannabis
professionals and serious cannabis
enthusiasts today we're going to talk
about judging the qualities of cannabis
flowers welcome to the show max always a
pleasure Shango thank you so much for
having me back so let's jump right in
max so you know cannabis enthusiasts
have a wide range of reasons they deem
cannabis to be good or bad you know like
like some stalkers it for some folks is
just the amount of THC right all they
look is that as the THC percentage and
then they buy the one that's the highest
whereas you know some more experienced
folks are you're looking for terpene
profiles but but similarly patience
right our most often judging flower
based on if it gives them relief or what
not and all these folks are looking at
the same cannabis in different ways and
you know that's that's totally happened
because there's never really been an
established standard for judging
cannabis but then you with the trichome
Institute built this interpreting
program which is kind of like a not kind
of it is a saw my a like certification
for people interpreting the standards
for cannabis so so what are the key
aspects that you've put together for
judging the quality of cannabis flowers
um well I think before I want to dive
into the aspects that we put put forth
to judging the flower is it fair to
maybe first look at all the different
types and reasons why judging and
grading cannabis is important in our
industry today yeah sure I think
everybody from a patient to to uh to a
retail buyer to the grower I mean I
think everybody is judging for their own
so-so letter let's you probably teased
out more of that than anybody so so
let's you're sure sure so you know how
in our industry everyone grows the best
weed CCI everybody does right so so
because everybody grows the best
cannabis and because there isn't a
system or a mechanism to decipher the
differences between the quality of the
units what you're seeing on a wholesale
market is the price per pound for
cannabis that should not be consumed
being sold at nearly the same price of
really really high quality product that
is extremely difficult to produce and so
there is there is a real big problem
because the high quality producers you
know they deserve to get anywhere
between three to maybe even a thousand
more per pound but they can't or on the
reverse people who are growing really
low quality cannabis stuff that's
unflushed unripe has a bunch of you know
pesticides on it what have you that
stuff should not be selling for as high
as it is and so we're the only
multi-billion dollar market in the world
that has no ability to measure the
difference of its quality and so every
head of lettuce in the grocery store and
apples and even your medicine your
pharmacy has all been quality verified
and checked for your consumer safety and
also for your for your I guess so that
it tastes good too not just being faith
but that is a high quality product and
so it's kind of silly that the cannabis
industry doesn't have anything like that
when at the same time our industry is
more serious about bragging rights
improving that our cannabis is better
than the other persons which is why
we've developed entire cannabis cups
around this and almost this black-market
process of how do you prove to your
purchaser that your your cannabis is
better than the other guys I can imagine
that would be really important at the
wholesale level too right because so
many people are are buying flour and
they are deciding whether or not to you
know put it in a bag for bag appeal or
run it into oil because it might be
strong but not very pretty they're doing
that mostly on the opinion of the
producer unless they go and they take a
look at it themselves first person which
is super time-consuming I can imagine
that you know a standard that got picked
up throughout the the industry would be
pretty much helpful to everybody well it
would and and also at the consumer level
as well and so in the state of
Washington you're not allowed to see or
smell the cannabis before you purchase
it so you basically get this grab bag
for 50 bucks and you're just praying
that is going to be decent yeah and so
what the tag
program is as trichome assurance grading
it truly is the world's first and only
cannabis quality certification process
now hold on before you go too far down
the tag thing I want to talk I want to
focus on tag more on the second set when
we're talking about you at cannabis cups
okay
let's circle back around first and
because I know that you're using these
these so my a folks these interpreters
in the cannabis cup span I first want to
set up you know why these interpreters
where they get their skills so let's
let's circle back around to like what
are your teaching interpreters as the
quality aspects in Flour which makes
your your your interpreter your saw my a
program so you know why is that the best
standard in the industry
sure so interpreting is a cannabis
someone yeh ship and in all decadent
categories of expertise which would
include wine someone yeas beer cicero
pne's cheesemongers coffee cup urge to
back with honey errs the majority of
what they're analyzing is one quality
and to you know how well does it pair
with another food and so it's about does
it taste good and what does a pair with
and interpreting does the same thing but
to go so much further way far way more
important is you know in the beer
industry when you order an IPA you get
an IPA but in the cannabis industry you
could order blue dream and not get blue
dream you know nine out of ten times in
Colorado for sure it's the most
counterfeit strain name in our state and
in Washington - and so what interpreting
does is in an industry that's as young
as it is with the strain name dilemma
and speciation dilemma is it empowers
customers and patients to know how their
cannabis will affect them physically
mentally psychotropic ly by being a
able to see and smell the psychotropic
differences within the flower types and
so you know interpreting we really start
out in cannabis elementary school where
we you know first teach you about the
very first cannabis plant ever pituitary
Mestral primordial cannabis via cannabis
ruderalis and how that easy use created
the indica sativa species and how those
species moved around the planet and how
some are drug types and some are hemp
types and we've got both of each and
this is why it gets really confusing but
then going further the program basically
gets to a point where we analyze that
cannabis is a massively hybridized
domesticated plant the way that dogs are
but in canine form and that it's not a
great wolf and it's not a coyote like
the original strains or species in the
wild so when you go to a pet store you
purchase a poodle and that's kind of the
same in the cannabis store the flowers
are more like poodles than they are like
wolves and coyotes into cousin sativa
because they're so far away from the
land race correct and so what we have is
we have to really analyze cannabis in a
much more intelligent way and
interpreting really helps people to do
that by looking at cannabis in the in
the hybridized spectrum medicine from
stimulating to sedating flower types and
then we teach you how to use your human
senses to literally use your your fifth
cranial nerve your trigeminal nerve in
your face to physically feel the
detection of the vibration of the
terpenes in different parts of your face
while simultaneously analyzing their
specific set profiles so that we can
gauge what terpenes are available in
what type of pharmacology we know they
produce and then also the shape of the
bud structure the cola itself is
dictated by the plant shape and the
plant shape is dictated by the geography
and the geography really helps us better
understand what
type of psychotropic plant types you
started out as and so we really we
dissect in class over a hundred flowers
that we bring to class visually and with
our smell with our sense of smell the
and we dissect them for their total
quality and so you know the trichome
Institute we are at cannabis education
company I believe we're the only canvas
education company that teaches people
about bad weed and you know somebody
grows and grows schools or grow books
and competitions and all these things
it's always about the best of the best
of the best but our our theory is you
don't know what good weed is until you
really understand the intricacies of
poor quality cannabis you know a moldy
weed is one of those things like you
know like like male plants right where a
lot of people who are all the way at the
end who are the consumers a lot of them
have never seen a male plant because
there's no reason generally for a male
plant to find its way into into the the
food chain for cannabis getting to the
end user and and similarly there's no
reason for moldy weed to be in there as
well it was funny when so about about
three years or so we had a plant go
moldy and you know I just took like six
seconds of video of it and threw it on
my Shango Lowe's YouTube channel and I
was shocked that it's like one of the
most popular videos that people watch
just because so many so few people have
seen moldy weed and I think that your
point is well made that you know when
you see miraculous flower I mean it kind
of stands out and you know holy crap
this looks good and it smells good I
can't wait to to toke it whereas when it
comes to you know you know be and medium
grade flour a lot of people don't they
haven't seen C D and F to know the
difference between mids and really bad
stuff that you shouldn't ingest at all
correct and you know interpreting is
it's really serious the way that wine
foam on a ship is serious
and so when I teach you how to assess
the degree of cannabis age I show you
cannabis that's three months six nine
twelve fifteen you know two years old
and we'll show you the spectrum where
we'll teach you that chlorophyll in the
bud begins to bleed at the base of the
coal of where the stem is and so you can
really see the degree of age from the
chlorophyll bleeding from the amount of
time that it takes as well as the
particular and very specific smell old
cannabis produces regardless of the
screen or terpene types that it started
out with and so we're really kind of the
only place in the world where you can
get that hands-on you know smell on
lecture expert experience but also with
the molds and unflushed cannabis and
cannabis with nutrient lock chemical
burn spider mites male flower sights
poor trim temp that was harvested early
on purpose to keep the THC levels down I
mean we really bring all of these
cannabis samples to class in Denver and
the Denver class is our level two which
is the hands-on class that also includes
a test so you know after the for our
education and a workshop we give you ten
jars of cannabis that are unlabeled and
what the test is is you have one hour to
pick five out of the ten and tell us
what's wrong with those herbs identify
the species of mold or the degree of the
un-- flush or what have you and then the
other five line them up in order from
stimulating to sedating and there's in
there's five of them and so when people
can do this when people pass more than
eighty percent of their level to test
they become a level two certified
interpreter and they get a green pin and
we have level two certified interpreters
in Canada people have flown in and have
passed from South Africa
Mexico every class we teach we have
people fly in from more than five
different states and multiple countries
last class we have people fly in from
even the Czech Republic and in Poland
yeah I know your classes are jam-packed
and I think that one of the aspects of
it is that it really is a pilgrimage
right because like I've been wanting to
take your interpreting series myself but
being out here on Vashon Island where I
live I'm a long way away from Denver and
so you know I need to make a specific
plan to come to you but really you know
even though your class would blow up if
you did it online there's simply no way
to do it because the experience of
grading cannabis you have to do it in
person because so much of it is based on
smell this I mean so yes and no so the
the yes is yes everything that you just
said because it makes perfect sense and
and that's the Denver class and it is a
pilgrimage and because people do have to
come to us because we can't take a
hundred flowers across any border right
so unfortunately it's a pilgrimage but
the the no part is is the level one that
we do and level one is simply people who
are just so excited to learn about
interpreting and they want a 3-hour
lecture and the ability to interact with
me in person and ask all the questions
that they want I do
do these level one courses out of state
and I just did one at dope magazine's
headquarters in Seattle while I was out
there judging the dope Cup and we had a
full class for sure and and because I
was judging the cup I had enough
cannabis to actually detect the enough
that were different to demonstrate and
show in class some actually poor quality
ones as well as the spectrum in and of
itself so it was kind of like a level
one and a half if you will and I will
tell you that you know our interpreting
tools are super fun and awesome they're
colorful and interactive and simple to
understand
but the guidebook I've actually started
looking at the idea of scratch and sniff
stickers so if there were people in
Australia or the UK who it would just be
a little too extreme to make the
pilgrimage that maybe we could in the
interpreting you know super kit actually
put vials of live terpenes that will go
along with the guidebook with scratch
and sniff stickers so that we can you
know if I tell you that the smell of
unflushed flower smells like this and
you scratch it and it does its better
than I guess not having a scratch it's
better than not at all yeah oops but I
think it's scratch and sniff cannabis
somali a book would just be the coolest
thing ever so do you find that there's a
lot of variability in the terpenes that
different people's noses can pick up
just like with wine different people's
palates can pick up different notes so
yes absolutely and i am i'm
unfortunately too busy to do so many
things in life but one thing that i need
to get around at doing is testing myself
as a super taster and I've ordered my
kit so I do have the super taster tester
kit which is really fun to say
and apparently there's this this
chemical way to analyze if you are a
part of a small population of humans on
earth who have an ability to taste
things much greater than other people
and I I do have lots of people tell me
that one reason why they're concerned
that they don't want to come to class is
because they have a really poor sense of
smell and you know I just asked them how
much do you care about passing your test
versus learning all of the information
about what cannabis is where it comes
from how it works and how to identify
it's qualitative features maybe that's
better than you being able to smell so
class is still important but I think the
most interesting thing the thing that's
the craziest part of interpreting and
the thing that needs more science and
more research is
where you feel the smell in the
different parts of your face and so I'm
the I still have never seen anybody in
the world publish any type of media or
content or literature or video or
anything around the idea that this is
something that is true and happens and
it's possible and I've been doing this
since I was a young kid and now I teach
this to people and it is extremely
accurate that stimulating terpene types
are felt on the atomic part of the
trigeminal nerve which is the top of the
nose in between your eyes whereas
sedating and heavier physically heavier
live hydrocarbon chains isomers terpenes
deeper richer rounder more robust
chocolates leathers tobacco's that you
really the sit in in the lower part of
your nostril and is felt there are
really sedative dominant variety types
and so it's this totally crazy thing
because whether it's cannabis or not 99%
of everybody I show this to says I've
never in my life even known that my nose
could smell at different parts of my
nose like I've never even realized that
and so when you come to class you know
not only do you see the qualitative
features the botanical elements of the
flower that are consistent with their
quote unquote sativa indica
in reality it's more like narrow leaf
drug types that are stimulating
broadleaf drug types that are sedating
do have these consistent correlations
within them and where things get complex
is the fact that these are all hybrids
and so there's a ton of crossover and so
it is unbelievably particular in
miniscule and just what we're analyzing
is the most subtle of visual differences
smell differences and taste differences
extremely extremely subtle and yes some
people are much better at seeing and
smelling these subtle features than
and most other people right on so when
we get back from the first commercial
break we are going to talk about how you
and your team of interpreters are kind
of remaking the competitive nature of
cannabis cups by bringing your mad
skills you are listening to shaping fire
my guest today is max Montrose founder
of the trichome Institute for anyone who
is paying attention to cannabis medicine
it has become incredibly apparent that
full extract cannabis oil known to some
as Rick Simpson oil is the cornerstone
of healing humans with medical marijuana
if you own a medical dispensary or
retail store you know that your
customers are asking for it every single
day and if you have been working with
patients and seeking out quality full
extract oil in the Pacific Northwest
you know the provider deep-green Kat
Jeter and her team at deep green have
been making full extract cannabis oil
and setting the standards for quality
and exact dosing for years in Washington
State the deep green brand is known by
patients and canvas media as a premium
quality provider for Sick Children
cancer patients and others in need at a
time when there are no national
standards for cannabis oil ensuring a
product as whole plant quality assured
and lab tested is often a matter of
knowing your sources reputable trust of
a quality brand is essential in choosing
a cannabis medicine that is going to be
used concentrated and in volume by any
patient and especially those with
weakened immune systems deep green is
looking for national brand partners to
expand the availability of their legacy
top shelf canvas oil to emerging medical
and licensed State's partners benefit
from a deep green brand recognition and
credibility as well as ongoing customer
and marketing support not only that but
deep green knows how to employ the 280e
tax rule so you can deduct it all from
your taxes working with deep green can
provide the trust and authenticity to
often pushed aside in favor of lifestyle
products your customers can assure
themselves that regardless of the state
in which it is made brand licensees
adhere to the same strict standards that
patients everywhere
come to expect from deep green deep
green licensing includes start-up and
capital planning as well as operational
and manufacturing instruction as you'd
expect for more information on how your
company co-op or medical dispensary can
benefit from partnering with deep green
to provide full extract cannabis oil to
patients go to shaping fire com forward
slash deep green to connect with Katt
Jeter and her team and shaping feiyr.com
forward slash deep green welcome back
you are listening to shaping fire I am
your host Shango Louis and our guest
this week is max Montrose founder and
president of the trichome Institute so
before the break we were talking about
what interpreting is and what all the
variable quality data points are when
truly looking at cannabis flower and
judging its quality so during the second
set we're going to talk about very
specifically how these skills are being
cross applied to judging cannabis cups
so you know cannabis cups have been
ridiculed since the very beginning for
you know everything from taking bribes
to influence results or simply giving
awards to their friends and it's pretty
much ruined the reputation of most
competitions in response to that you
have begun teaching cup event promoters
in alternative judging methods that are
based much more on botany and data
points instead of just the judges
personal preference why is this system
better than traditional cannabis coach
cup judging panels okay so so yeah let's
let's just let's talk about I guess
cannabis cups when describing this so if
if you put in a product in a traditional
let's just say cup they're really
expensive and the competition is serious
and the reward is really meaningful
because in this industry being able to
prove that your product is better than
the next guys is your best method of
marketing and advertising specifically
in this industry and many other
but so so it's important and so these
judges and their judgments are making or
breaking multi-million dollar businesses
and that's important too that's a big
deal and the people who deserve to win
these things it's important to celebrate
they're they're really hard efforts
because it takes more than a decade to
have the types of skills to win cups and
if people are if the way that we're
judging them isn't accurate and ensuring
that those who deserve to win win then
we're celebrating people who we
shouldn't be and promoting more poor
quality products in cannabis in the
industry so all of this is really
important stuff and so what you're
starting out with is who are these
judges and what are their qualifications
for judging and I'm not going to name
any names but I'll just say the largest
and probably oldest cannabis magazine
that we're all familiar with you can
actually pay to be a judge a thousand
bucks so if your parents have enough
money and you want to prove to your
friends that you're super cool we now
have you know people who have who don't
even know what trichomes are don't even
know what a calyx is who think that the
the male antler is called a banana on
cannabis those are the people who are
now going to determine whether your
business deserves to be rewarded or not
and put in the scene right and so and if
it's not those people then it's really
qualified industry people right and when
you ask what is really qualified mean it
mean live grown cannabis a few times and
they smoked it for five years it's like
okay do you study technical textbooks on
cannabis and and all of these
intricacies and what you find is that
most people just aren't as dorky and
nerdy as people who kind of work at the
trichome Institute and who put together
a lot of this of these data points in
these text books that we produce
ourselves and so what we've done is in
terms of starting out
with who the judges are you have to be a
really qualified judge and so you have
to be an interpreter level 3 and so you
have to be able to dissect and analyze
cannabis quality in a psychotropic
spectrum in less than five minutes
whereas the level 2 test which is the
same test is an hour and you have to
demonstrate that in multiple ways but
you also have to learn the standard
operating procedure of our grading scale
for concentrates and also things like
trichome ripeness trichome density and
then learning the the subtle spectrum
that really takes a in person teacher to
teach you what like the degree of
pungency is you know that is something
you can't learn online you have to spend
critical time with someone and we've
spent hours and hours and hours doing
this with each other and so literally at
the dope cup when there was four
sometimes five six of us in Terpening
utilizing the tag program to do these
judging's it's it's it's just it's
unbelievable how much time it takes us
we're up to like two or three in the
morning doing this but the amount of
hours that we put in checking each
other's work in cross comparing our
evaluations to make sure that they fall
within our parameters of inter-rater
reliability is intense it's really
intense
wonder what are some of the data points
that you as interpreters are looking at
versus what a normal judge would I mean
we've obviously established that you
know a sommelier level interpreter of
cannabis has got more experience and
have studied it more than the average
cannabis judge but but I also believe
that your system is going to be
different because you know I've seen
some judging packets and some of the
judging packets you know where they're
where they're doing the ratings they
seem pretty fluffy to me and you know I
know that you approach this from such a
scientific and botanical background that
I would think that some of the data
points that you are looking at are
different than tradition
judging one way couple of those be super
good question so so for those who don't
know tag it's a computer program that we
built and it's a calculator and what
it's doing is it's calculating numeric
values that level three interpreters are
giving to a variety of different visual
olfactory and consumption data points
and so you know in most traditional cups
everything is subjective
it's whatever that person thinks they
like and usually they're liking it
intoxicated right and so this program
everything is analyzed in the exact same
way double-blind twice and I guess some
of the big biggest differences of our
data points is we do the entire grading
and calculation sober until we're done
producing all the report cards and then
it comes the consumption aspect of the
judging
so we're judging all of your products
sober 90 95 percent of the judging is
done sober and that's one of the biggest
differences between the way that we
judge in other in other cups but you
know we smoke cannabis we get down we're
not just nerds we can puff tough and we
do and so you know you have to be able
to judge the consumption because it's
unbelievable
how tricky cannabis can look it can look
gorgeous it can look and actually have
ripe erect trichomes that have really
pungent terpenes and everything about
that flower just looks sexy and then you
take a hit and you're just coughing your
brains out and your chest feels like hot
spider webs and it's because this person
didn't flush the bud at all and so all
of the nutrients and chemicals of the
six months going into this plan
our is what you're smoking and so it
looks ripe because it is and it smells
good probably because it's in a
defensive mode because it's so sick
internally and you can't really see that
and so when we're like judging the
degree of the flush it's kind of like
how wine someone yeas take a sip of wine
and spit it out we don't we call it the
Clinton the only time you know anybody
would ever ingest cannabis and not
inhale it Bill Clinton so so sometimes
there's there's a Clinton effect
especially when you know we're judging
dozens and dozens and dozens of
concentrates and flowers that we can we
can look at the report and
mathematically we know they're not going
to win versus the other you know huge
lumps and groups where okay these 25 to
30 people one of these guys is going to
win we'll definitely bring that entire
hit into our lungs and feel the the
entirety of it down our throat the
intensity of the heat how much it makes
our glands swell the degree of the salt
on the side of our mouth you know how
thick is my saliva we really I mean we
look at the ash I mean we really analyze
every piece and like I said double-blind
twice and so probably that's probably
the other biggest biggest part of the
difference between the way we judge and
other people is we utilize a system that
transfers the subjective into the
objective and the system is inter-rater
reliability and essentially what that
means is I keep saying double-blind
twice you know one dope magazine gives
us all of the samples without any strain
name or grower dispensary operation so
we literally just get a bag with a
number on it so we're not allowed to
have any bias and we we don't know
you know the species or the strain name
right and then once we do our grading we
go through our process the grades the
reports are then matched against each
other's two other people and those
grades have to be within three points of
each other out of a hundred so I'm going
to tell you I'm going to tell you this
really incredible thing that happened at
the cup that we didn't expect to happen
actually there's a lot of that we can
tell you some funny stories - about some
of the cannabis we found of crazy stuff
but we had no idea that five different
cup entries were from these companies
took their best flower and divided it
into two different categories but it was
the same flower and nobody told us this
right because we're not allowed to know
anything right double-blind right and so
outside of our cannabis quality
certification there's a lab that does
the lab analysis and that's something we
should also talk about is why the tag
process is actually does do a quality
analysis overall mandated lab prophecies
in all medical states in retail that's a
big deal but the point is is this lab
did the chemo typing so the cannabinoid
terpene analysis and the reports were
identical for the five flowers that were
divided in two categories so a total of
10 buds and so when we learned that this
happened we were all like oh [__] like
this is going to be the ultimate test
how well did we did we do and
essentially the analogy for this is put
looking at a splatter painting in asking
two people to guess the the number
between 1 and 100 that they feel this
painting deserves from a quality
perspective so is it an 87 was it a 64
and so that's what we're doing we're
taking two people and we're looking at a
piece of cannabis under a microscope and
it looks like a splatter painting right
and all
I have samples that were divided twice
we got within our three points of each
other and that also says a lot about how
you are training these interpreters
right because you know you know we need
to have the human element because we
want to you know truly be able to judge
the different terpenes and how they
blend and how they impact a human but at
the same size the same at the same time
we want to make sure that everybody is
judging using the same standards and so
the fact that you've got these different
samples and different interpreters and
yet they're still coming you know within
three percent of each other
is you know it's pretty it's pretty
amazing now hey well I've got one more
question I want to ask before we go to
break here so you know you're bringing
in this whole new way of judging cups
and it's going to it's going to you know
push out people paying to be judges
which is an income stream and it's going
to push out you know friends of the
promoter who got to be a judge because
they you know they're owed a favor or
something and so you know this this will
really remake the cup scene you know to
what degree have you had you know
acceptance by a promoters and be people
who are competing because I can I bet
you that there's people on both sides
yeah oh man
I mean it's trust me it's not an easy
thing to to explain to someone that
they're going to pay you to grade their
weed and then tell the world what you
found although we don't tell the world
what we find we keep everything coded so
if we do find bad product we don't
publish that so we're never going to put
anybody's down okay
and I think that's a good thing to start
with the tag program and then you know
here's the thing
I don't really in terms of the revenue
stream of the for the companies that
have paid judges tell you what instead
of making money off of ensuring that
your cup is going to be completely
inaccurate and probably pissing off all
of the people who are paying you to have
their samples judged in the first
place and you know giving your cup
legitimacy
why don't you do education and training
programs associated with your cup to
teach the public and the consumers and
other growers what cannabis really is
where it comes from how it helps people
and develop a revenue stream based off
of producing more education for the
people who are going to these cups
no matter I get this right you and I are
both cannabis nerds and I get that but
really the heart of the question though
is our promoters digging this or not I
mean that's really where I want to take
this are they going oh yeah I want to do
this or people pushing back and saying I
don't want your science so this is
working out good for us what are you
seeing so I mean so here's what we're
seeing we're seeing that the majority of
cannabis producers don't produce that
that high quality of product there are
fewer producers that produce high
quality products right so by default
there are majority of people who would
probably prefer a system that was less
accurate because they might have higher
chances of winning right but at the same
time people who really care about the
industry and who get what the tag
program can bring to cannabis really
really love it and truly respect it and
really embrace it and so you know when I
was in Oregon and I judged the dope Cup
in October the amount of growers who
came up to me just pissed as [__] just
you know who do you think you are
grading our weed judging our weed you're
not even from our state you don't know
anything right I mean it was a lot of
people and I just sat down and I just
said look I'm going to explain you how I
do this before you start hating on me
and when I just explained to them how it
works they all just flipped the switch
instantly and said thank you for doing
this this is what our industry is needed
you know where have you been the whole
time and now I'm really good friends
with these growers and so you know dope
magazine has embraced it more than any
other companies so far but other
companies who do cannabis competitions
have started you know asking us about
the program
but you know they kind of run their
competition in their own way so I would
say that a lot of producers and
promoters really appreciate the fact
that there is a real competition and
that it's possible and people who
deserve to win are winning and that it's
fair and that it's even so even if you
lose at least it wasn't because you know
some stoner who didn't know what they
were doing about created your cannabis
and you lost because of that at least it
you know you can go back and analyze
your report and compare it to other
peoples and learn why you didn't win and
improve yourself from it that's that's
what's happening and similarly it
creates a paper trail so that people
aren't feeling like they're losing
because there was a you know special
donation made behind the scenes which
cannabis cups are constantly being
charged with so hey we're going to go to
our second break and rewrite back you
are listening to shaping fire and my
guest today is max Montrose founder of
the trichome Institute businesses
everywhere are constantly striving to
reach out to people through advertising
we all know though that trying to reach
a cannabis audience with a quality
message is pretty difficult that's why
many people choose to advertise on the
shaping fire podcast advertising on this
show allows us time to talk about your
product service or brand in a way that
really lets people know what sets your
company apart from others bold people
who own companies know that getting in a
relationship with their customers is
essential that is what we offer we will
explain your service or product and what
sets it apart as desirable and help our
audience get in contact with you it's
pretty simple really
advertising does not have to be all
whiz-bang smoke and mirrors nowadays I
find that people prefer just to be
spoken to calmly accurately and with
good intentions if you want to make your
own commercial spot you can do that too
because the podcast is young but growing
at an exceptionally fast rate if you
become an advertiser on the shaping fire
podcast now you are going to pay a
fraction of the cost we'd be asking for
in just a few months and yet everyone
listening both now and to the back
catalog of interviews later will hear
about your company again and again for
years it's a great deal for you pay a
small amount now because the show is new
but
take advantage of the huge listening
audience we will have forever do
yourself a solid and contact us today
for rates on podcast and newsletter
advertising email hotspot at shaping
fire calm to find out more
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire I'm your host Shango lows
and our guest this week is max Montrose
founder and president of the trichome
Institute so before we wrap up here max
you know you've alluded a couple times
to these unexpected stories that you
have come across while grading cannabis
at cannabis cups and you know most
probably everybody who's listening has
either been interested in attended or
which they attended a cup so why don't
you like kind of bring a lot of this
science home for us and tell us a couple
of these outlier funny stories that
you've been alluding to to kind of make
us feel like we've been sitting in your
seat sure so you know we just got back
from the Seattle dope cup you know the
edible category it's an interesting one
to judge and we don't have too much time
so I'm not going to go into how we get
into the technicalities of judging that
but it's really unbelievable how
delicious and awesome the amount of
edible products are it's just
mind-blowing how just fantastic almost
all of them are up until the point where
you get you know some companies who I'm
not going to mention the type of drink
but I'm not kidding we were literally
spitting some of the stuff out the sink
left and right and as judges trying to
get each other to like drink it as a
joke it just it's just unbelievable you
know some of those just wild cards that
that pop in there but more more than the
drink in all of those drinks from that
company was one of these flowers that
was entered in the THC category which is
generally judged for the highest THC but
not always because we're judging quality
and pH C doesn't equate to quality and
so we come across this bud and we have
we were we've literally been we've never
been so astonished by a piece of flower
in our lives and on the report which
we're going to publish on our website
soon it literally says this is the word
piece of cannabis we've ever seen ever
and it smells like a Glade plugin and
smells like just raw chemicals it's
brown and it disintegrates in a dust in
your hand and when you look at the
trichomes under the microscope they're
like really Arnon and there are looks
like bugs and fecal matter as well as a
lot of these black weird things we can't
identify and dust particles and other
things and so it was literally like I
can't even describe no analogy for how
what what the thing was but it was
really interesting because when you get
the HPLC report from the lab this is a
flower that has 47 percent THC get out
for dayavan percent 47 percent that
leaves me skeptical man hold on hold
your horses shame so we look around at
each other and we're just like what the
heck is this like how is this possible
exclusive what is this and we talked to
the lab and they just said they're like
look obviously somebody soaked this
flower in hash oil and whatever
chemically hash oil that was more you
know viscous than not has to be more
like water probably had some chemical on
it that is why it smells like a Glade
plugin but you know we're looking at the
thing and that that is what they did so
they they thought that they were going
to win first place for the highest THC
because essentially they cheated by
soaking a flower in THC oil that's like
the next level compared to people who
would roll their flowers and Keith you
know before submitting them yeah yeah
and then and tried to hide that they did
this because like it wasn't like sticky
hash oil on the bud you couldn't see the
oil just the flower but the flower was
like tan and brown and smelled horrible
and disintegrated like I said but
anyways long story short we were just
like you think you're going to win first
place annihilated it said you know we
just don't appreciate I hope you don't
sell this like to the public I hope this
isn't really a product that you make and
that this is more of like a joke and
your attempt
to try to win a cannabis cup because at
the end of the day it's not funny like
that was some of the most disgusting
[__] we've ever seen and it was
offensive it was bad but I'll tell you
but on a good note to end on a positive
note because we're aggregating data in
the way that we are we have an
opportunity where we're literally
analyzing the collectiveness of what
makes Oregon cannabis Oregon cannabis
what makes Colorado cannabis Colorado
cannabis and these are different almost
like countrywide Appalachians and then
within those there are terroir and so
this really is an interpreting someone
yay analysis but at a state level and we
were just completely blown away
fascinated and also quickly bored by the
fact that 98 percent of every flower we
smelled in the competition smelled like
a diesel every one every single one was
gorilla glue number four or Sour Diesel
these are really high in terpene alene a
gas like smell that produces a really
racy kind of high affect fuels are
really popular around here
especially since we have a hard time
getting them right because a lot of the
Northwest is indicas you know well so
the thing is is I was talking with the
gentleman who works in the area and what
he said was really intelligent which was
a lot of the diesel varietals for
whatever reason have been known to not
have to resist molds better than other
strains
and so because Seattle and in that area
is just covered in water and rain and
wetness all the time that there's really
a majority of a type of strain that has
a better chance of surviving and it
happens to be these high core pinna lean
diesel-like varietals
and so the geography in the you know the
requirement to have mold resistant
strains in that that geography
is important and if that's the case
that's what we analyzed looking at over
200 flour samples literally 98% of them
smelled almost identical they were all
just different little subtle versions of
diesel diesel these when I got bored
quick but but it was really interesting
it's really fascinating
yeah that really is interesting I had
not considered that because you know a
lot of times we don't get sativa around
here just simply because if the grown
indoor people don't want to spend the
extra light hours to finish the sativa
and good luck finishing a sativa outdoor
anywhere here in the northwest but that
makes sense because if they've got if
they're naturally resistant to mold
people will certainly keep the lights on
longer for that yeah Yeah right on cool
well I know that you could probably do
an entire show just on the same topic
again but our time is up for today
what's we're going to have you back
another time in a few weeks though to
talk about the very interesting stories
that you've got to share about beating
cannabis duis and how you're being flown
around the country to be an expert
witness so so I look forward to having
you back to get in soon max awesome well
thanks so much anger max Montrose is
founder of trichome Institute you can
find out more and register for
interpreting courses at trichome
Institute comm you can find more
episodes of the shaping fire podcast and
subscribe to the show at shaping fire
calm and on Apple iTunes stitcher and
Google Play if you enjoyed the show we'd
really appreciate it if you leave a
positive review of the podcast wherever
you download your review will help
others find the show so they can enjoy
it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the weekly newsletter for
insights into the latest cannabis news
and product reviews on the shaping fire
website you will also find transcripts
of today's podcast as well for
information on me and where I'll be
speaking you can check out Shango lows
Calm cuz your company want to reach our
national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hot spot at shaping
feiyr.com
to find out how thanks for listening to
shaping fire I've been your host
Shango lows
[Music]