[Music]
there are a few things in cannabis as
frustrating as mold it's true all of
your hard work can come crashing down by
the sudden visual signs of powdery
mildew or botrytis molds it's enough to
make you cry chastise the source of your
clones and try to strike a bargain with
God there's so much misinformation out
there about both powdery mildew and
botrytis that's been handed down from
generation to generation of cannabis
growers now though cannabis is
attracting scientists and laboratories
that can help sort out the biology of
these molding menaces to society if you
enjoy hearing frank discussions that
dive deep in a cannabis health business
and technique I encourage you to
subscribe to our newsletter every week
you'll receive a new podcast episode
delivered right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple the most
important news items from the week and
videos to recent videos have included
Kevin Jodrey of Wonderland nursery
talking about breeding cannabis for the
best terpene profiles and my keynote
address at the Imperius Expo in Phoenix
about why we choose cannabis business
even though the risks are so high don't
rely on social media to let you know
when a new podcast is published sign up
for the updates to make sure you don't
miss an episode you are listening to
shaping fire and I'm your host
Shango lows my guest today is Kevin
McKiernan chem mckernon is founder and
chief science officer of medicinal
genomics medicinal genomics made
worldwide news in 2011 when it publicly
released the first genome sequence for
cannabis sativa as a result of this work
medicinal genomics launched a suite of
tools for the detection of microbial
contamination of cannabis prior to
medicinal genomics Kevin was the team
leader of R&amp;D for the human genome
project at the Whitehead Institute for
biomedical research at MIT one piece of
vocabulary I want to point out for this
week's episode we use the term labs a
lot this week sometimes we're referring
to cannabis analytical laboratories but
most of the time we're using the word
labs as shorthand for a collection of
living probiotic bacteria originally
referring only to lactic acid bacteria
in organic growing it's often used
nowadays to refer to a wide range of
probiotic cultured micro
organisms welcome to the show Kevin
thank you for having me Django this is a
quite an exceptional podcast I'm honored
to be here right huh thank you very much
so Kevin you know this time of year
molds and mildews are being talked about
by growers everywhere because as though
as the nights are getting colder and
damp fog and rain starts to become more
common in the in the weather report mold
becomes more of a threat and you know
we'll talk about botrytis a bit later in
the show but easily the most common
scourge that everyone has to deal with
is powdery mildew biologically what is
powdery mildew okay so this is a this
evaded us for quite a bit I think the
best resources to go to are a book from
John McPartlin and Dave Watson and and
Robert Clark it has a great list of all
these hemp diseases we we we marched
through they're trying to build DNA
assays that could detect powdery mildew
and and you know why would anyone want
to try and pick up this organism well
they're from what we've learned about
what powdery mildew does and hops which
is the closest relative to cannabis is
it has an infection cycle where when it
first lands on the plant it actually
builds what's known as a historia or
like a tap root into the plant where the
spore lands and then it builds a
mycelium Network and this my city of
network is sometimes it's it's debatable
whether it's in the plan or outside of
the plant but it spreads it spreads that
network across the plant and it takes in
hops sometimes 18 to maybe 40 days
before it gets a stress event that makes
it make spores which is the powder that
you see and those spores are very Hardy
and they spread the they spread the
disease so we got brought into trying to
figure out what this thing was by trying
to build assays for it and we build we
built some of these DNA s is going after
the organisms that john was pointing us
to which was L torque and they have an
organism in there called s MACUL eres
but it's recently been renamed to a P
MACUL Eris stands for I think POTUS fara
MACUL Eris so what are these things is
your question these are obligate bio
tropes which means they you can't
culture them unless you have leaves
we tried that we tried putting them in
cultures and not didn't behave you have
to find a
grind up leaves or somehow and make it
so that there's actually some leaf cells
in there for these things to culture but
an obligate bio trove also means that
they're generally very much adapted to
their hosts so you do tend not to see
powdery mildews hopping species species
very much like you might see with
botrytis and so you'll find powdery
mildews that are very specialized like
the ones that are in grapes are known as
goal of venom Isis there's a vino in
there the ones that are on hops is P
MACUL eros and we had some debate as to
whether that was crossing over into
cannabis and it may be we've not yet
found evidence for that yet when we dug
into this we built all of these assays
hoping we'd find something that was on
grapes like golden mi C's or these um
al-tohra cos another one that's
mentioned that literature none of them
worked and so we went down a bit of a
rabbit hole trying to sequence the
genome of this thing alright and what we
have found to date is we actually
believe it's a novel species that's on
cannabis and it is something that has
about 98% identical to P Mac eulerís
which is on hops and about 98% identical
as well to go low venom Isis and bro Xia
which is another powdery mildew that's
out there so they're very interesting
organisms but they can as everyone knows
they can totally destroy your crop
however you can detect them in advance
of the sporulation stage where they make
these things known as Canadia and that's
what we're aiming to do with this
genetic test is to enable people to
screen clones or to screen their plants
at a certain period of time and remove
anything that has a positive hit and
maybe this will help people breathe
faster for resistance if you're
screening for plants that have a lot of
this on them well they're probably
susceptible to it unless you're picking
up a single spore and so we've been
trying to do some work where this test
is fairly sensitive enough to pick up
these mycelial networks but doesn't get
triggered by the spores and that's not
as hard to do as you might imagine the
spores can last a winner they're really
Hardy and they're very hard to break so
a long story is uh there are different
species pretty much in every organism
you run into and we don't see much
evidence of this hopping species to
species or host a host I should say
this is the first time I've heard the
anchor on the spore described that's
probably one of the ways that people get
confused about whether or not PN is
systemic to the plant or merely
opportunist because I can imagine that
the the spore lands and and it creates
that anchor which which is is is
probably breaking the I guess the derma
of the plant right right and so suddenly
now it's also inside so so with that
anchor idea this is what do you what is
it biologically is it systemic or is it
opportunist and topical so that's a good
point the definition of systemic is
usually reserved for something that
might be circulating through the xylem
and phloem or like in the bloodstream
but like HIV and in humans and I'd say
it might be hard to claim that it's
systemic although we should say the
experiments we have done have not
necessarily nailed that what we have
seen is that it can be present in the
plant and am I saying of network where
you can't visibly see it and the debate
right now is whether that my city of
network is internal to the leaf or
external to leaf but for practical
purposes that may not matter may be a
bit of an academic question for
screening purposes there's not much use
in a genetic test that picks up powdery
mildew after you can see it it's too
late then you really want to get
something that picks it up early and
that's the key to thwart a most
infectious disease cycles is to actually
have early detection so that you can
remove the plants that carry the
infection from the from spreading and
any further kind of a quarantine and
contain approach ultimately breeding for
resistance I think is the right thing to
do but this may be a tool that helps
accelerate that if you can find the
plants that can chronically have high
levels of powdery mildew DNA on them
well then you those are most likely to
be susceptible strands and you should
pull them pull them out of other works
there's a really good paper I'll point
people to that maybe we can put into the
show notes from a gentleman by the name
of Liebling who did a lot of work to try
and address this systemic issue and in
that paper they do mention a systemic
but I think it might be a misuse of the
term but what they demonstrate is that
this they stain this the DNA of this
working
with and you can see the network of this
mycelium it's really kind of beautiful
to look at and you can see that from a
single spore that hits the leaf it
really goes it goes millimeters away
really outside of the entire focal view
of the images that they're taking so
these networks spread very very quickly
around the plant and and I think the
unknown questions we have today are well
how early can you actually pick this up
and how quickly does that my see of
network spread and are you gonna get at
eighteen days before it outbreaks you're
gonna get it you know forty days these
are unknowns in cannabis right now we've
seen the work in hops and we're kind of
drawing parallels from hops but a lot of
the work in hops shows that PMAC your
iris will have maybe twenty to forty dpi
which is days post infection when twenty
stents tend to see the actual spores
kickoff for when they found the initial
infection of us four so that's it that's
a big gap and and stress tends to
accelerate this so if you happen to get
infected just before flowering or before
flush it that's gonna bring out some of
the the sporulation events it's a I
can't help but chuckle when you tell me
that the science is not fully decided on
whether or not it's systemic or merely
topically opportunistic because there's
so much arguing and gnashing of teeth on
line between growers who know for sure
one side or the other and everybody's
getting upset about it and you're saying
well actually the science is still out
and we're still trying to figure that
out you know what what's it doing to the
plant itself I mean we know that when
the the plant is more stressed it's more
susceptible and then when the the spore
feels has a stress event it spreads but
but what is it actually doing to the
plant itself that is damaging the plant
well there's um I think the stress
signals that go throughout the plant
probably trigger a tremendous amount of
secondary messengers signaling I think
there have there has been evidenced that
when you get these types of priming
responses with let's say another fungal
infection if right about botrytis you
can see that there's sometimes terpene
expression that changes there is a host
of other secondary message
that come out of the plants immune
system that begin to respond to
infection like this and unfortunately to
further complicate the matter you'll
find a lot of literature out there that
show co-infections of botrytis and p.m.
or through cerium and botrytis or so it
seems as if once the immune systems down
you know everybody piles on everyone
piles on and that actually was a really
complicating factor for us and trying to
sequence this genome because so many
times we were trying to scrape these
spores off you can do must do it with a
glass slide and get all types of powder
on type of slide and we try to lyse
those spores in the sequence the genome
when we always get something else we'd
always can't like Penicillium or all
these other co-infections and it's just
because they happen to lyse more readily
than the spores and they're coming along
for the ride it took us a long time of
figuring out how to wash those spores
out and then and then really you have to
really treat them with phenol to
actually crack them open to get the DNA
and the sequence it and then when you
finally do have that genome it's never a
perfectly pure genome of just powdery
mildew spores there's still some other
contaminants there and to make matters
worse these genomes tend to be about a
hundred to 180 million bases in size but
there are 90% transpose ax Bellaire it's
repetitive as all hell and it's really
hard to put the genome back together
once you do finally get the DNA so yeah
it's been a bit of a frustrating rabbit
hole be honest with you but we only
really needed one really unique stretch
of DNA in the genome that we could
anchor a PCR target for to pick this up
unfortunately we don't have to ask
people to go and do this magical spore
prep that we're talking about to pick up
the mycelium Network the mycelium
Network is really easy to crack and easy
to lyse and we just do that with a
single core like a hole punch of a leaf
and a four millimeter hole punch with
leaf we usually put two of those into
each boil and we just boil that that DNA
and it pops open the mycelium Network
when we get enough DNA to then pick it
up with one of our color metric assays
this is a PCR assay that changes color
on you so that you don't need a detector
for and you can run it in the field it's
kind of a really
idiot proof yeah yeah that's the attempt
but you know at the same time it's it's
kind of a like a pregnancy test it's
plus-minus it's not very quantitative at
the moment so you know when it changes
color on you we still don't have a good
correlation with that color change to
how intensely in fact that the plant is
what people want really one is like well
give me an estimate of the colony
forming units you might get as a
comparison with this amount of DNA and
we just don't have those because we
can't culture this thing Yeah right on
so we're just we're thinking about
making even making a quantitative
version of it just for more research
purposes but right now it's just dialed
in to be as sensitive as we can get it
with its color metric assays so it will
it will get triggered by a single cell
that much we we know because we've
targeted this at a part of the genome as
a really high copy number there's about
50 copies of this region of the genome
so a single spore or a single cell will
give us 50 targets to amplify from and
that seems to commit you know quite
about great quite amount of sensitivity
right on let's jump back to when you
were talking about how it spreads so you
describe this this stress event and I'm
sure that if there are growers I mean
they know what causes their plants to
stress but are those always going to be
the same things that causes the the
Spore to stress what specifically we can
make up the stress event that will cause
the powdery mildew spores to pop and
spread throughout the garden because
whatever those stresses are as a grower
we'd want to reduce those to as low as
possible I mean things that I've heard
about I don't have as much experience
growing as many people in your audience
but what I've would have been reading
about through my book warming efforts
here on this on this genome is that it's
usually a humidity effect or a
temperature effect that stresses it but
I've also been very fascinated in in the
microbiome in the plant so there's
there's a lot of evidence that
Trichoderma and others in other bacillus
species can knock this thing out and I
wouldn't be surprised if if your root
microbiome isn't healthy that you're
going to have a nutrient deficiency of
some sort that may not be completely
evident by a leaf color change but it
may may be deficient on the less
that can also trigger stress so some of
the best bio controls that are mentioned
in the literature are in fact using
Trichoderma which is another fungus but
it happens to make like Titan aces and
other enzymes that go and destroy this
thing and those those are probably what
are being emulated in a lot of these
products that are on the shelves that
are that are not pesticidal based but a
more enzyme and and biocontrol agents
that you see sure sure and as a matter
of fact you know people who are into
living soils and probiotics and and
producing their own labs and and using
milk instead of chemicals I mean this
really does seem the direction that
everybody's going because a lot of the
traditional you know anti molds
antifungals that people have used on
plants in in the past no one wants to
touch that stuff anymore because it's
it's gonna ding them at a pesticide test
at the state level and suddenly they're
gonna lose their crops so people seem to
be more and more moving to work in tune
with nature to to rebalance their their
leaf or to just straight-out knock out
the mold spores that way yeah and I
think it's that's it's very key right
now with all the extraction we have
going on we've seen all these wonderful
papers from many of the people have been
on your cast before whether it be Jeff
Raber or Ethan Rousseau that these
pesticides tend to hyper enrich an
extraction I mean we may get a couple
three or four fold increase in the
cannabinoids but they're seeing a
hundred to a thousand fold enrichments
for some of these pesticides so you know
if people using Michael a butyl fight
this we really really should change
practices though the one challenge and
changing those practices is that if you
do move to some probiotics you have to
be very careful of what microbial test
people are running because a lot of
those probiotics are going to trigger
your total aerobic counts or your total
yeast and mold counts are gonna are
going to go up and and we really need to
work with the regulators to not penalize
people for these organic practices
because you know Trichoderma and the
soleus shouldn't be a human threat they
shouldn't be something that elevates
your petri film counts so we do a lot of
work on that side of the fence as well
we may we make quantitative pcr assays
for microbial testing that a lot of the
labs use in many of the states and they
tend to be
dialed-in dan fairly specific in fact
our totally stand mole test we have
specifically does not hit p.m. in
botrytis and and if it did it would
probably fail you know 30% of the
samples out there that test we've we've
made sure the primers don't hit those
because they're not human pathogens
they're they're just plant pathogens and
we can have separate tests to pick them
up you probably want to pick those up at
a different time you're not interested
in whether you have botrytis or powdery
mildew after you've harvested it's too
late then you want to know about that
you know maybe six weeks to eight weeks
earlier and so we've consciously broken
apart those tests so that they they have
different sensitivities and they can be
used at different times right on we've
got a lot more to talk about powdery
mildew but it's time to take our first
short break and read right back you are
listening to shaping fire and my guest
today is Kevin a Kernan chief science
officer at medicinal genomics as a
listener of shaping fire you already
understand the importance of living soil
when growing cannabis when you have
active microbe communities in your
substrate you go way beyond simply
fertilizing with nitrogen phosphorus and
potassium having active microorganisms
in your substrate supports vigorous
plant growth throughout the plant's root
zone making for higher yields and
thriving flowers mammoth pea is the
first organically derived microbial
inoculant
that focuses on your plants nutrient
cycling processes to release soil
phosphorus and other micronutrients from
they're bound forms making them more
available to the plant increased levels
of phosphorus will also keep internode
shorter and focus your plants energy on
bud production not only that but the
microbes act as a defense shield for the
plants rhizosphere by out competing
potentially harmful pathogenic microbes
pretty cool right mammoth pee not only
unlocks the nutrients in your soil but
it also helps protect your plant from
disease mammoth Peas beneficial bacteria
act like microbial reactors
continually producing enzymes that
release nutrients mammoth pee was
developed at a u.s. University has been
extensively tested by Colorado growers
and independent laboratories mammoth pee
is proven to increase growth and enhance
blooming one of the great things about
supplementing with microorganisms is
that they won't compete with whatever
fertilizer program your or
running simply dose on top of your
fertilizer schedule for increased
benefits to learn more and to find out
where you can buy mammoth pee near you
check out their website at WWE crowd
come partner with microorganisms to
create beautiful thriving cannabis
mammoth pee as cannabis normalization
sweeps the country knowledge of how to
grow cannabis naturally and without
synthetic inputs has become more and
more available in fact probiotic growers
are experiencing large yields and
exceptional terpene profiles without
using chemicals banned in their state
move away from the risks inherent to
chemical nutrients and instead invest in
your soil use your soil again and again
reducing costs and improving the
vitality of your soil with each cycle
keep it simple organics has been a
leader in aerated compost teas for years
and now provide premium soils and
nutrients to the cannabis industry they
offer a full line of all-natural inputs
for building your soil feeding microbe
communities and brewing nutrient and
compost teas they can even help you test
your soil to spot deficiencies that may
be holding you back check out their
website at K is organics calm enter the
word Shango into the form at checkout to
receive 10% off your first order stop
pouring bottled nutrients on your soil
only to throw it out each cycle start
building living soil that will serve you
for years to come visit K is organics
calm and grow healthy thriving cannabis
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire I'm your host Shango Louis
and our guest this week is Kevin
mckernon chief science officer and
medicinal genomics so during the first
set we were talking a lot about powdery
mildew and we were talking about you
know some of the rumors about how it is
spread and versus the truth and the
science of it and I got to ask you know
a lot of us have leaf hoppers those
little those little bugs in our gardens
and you know technically if we we got
inundated with leaf hoppers they do suck
out of the plant and they would be bad
but normally
not enough to cause a problem however a
lot of growers are suspicious of leap
hoppers because they think that they are
moving the spores from leaf to leaf and
then plant to plant and therefore acting
as an agent for powdery mildew to spread
do you buy that so I have read that
Russert mites may do something similar
so I if I had a place to an educated
guess I'd say yes that they could be
spreading these things around and that
could be one mechanism for removing more
than just powdery mildew okay there
could be a host of other diseases I
wouldn't be surprised but right over on
that way as well yeah I hear that all
right so then how about the other gosh I
don't I went to say old wives tales but
but I don't that doesn't make any sense
because I know a lot of old wives and
all they say is brilliant stuff so let's
say I've got another myth and a a lot of
people remove it with their fingers
right and they're like oh I went through
the whole plan and I rubbed it with my
fingers and now I don't see any and I've
always thought that yeah you're removing
the white but you've just you've just
spread it around so you can't see it
anymore so so to what advantage does
rubbing it off with your fingers help
yeah I'll give you an anecdote about
this I don't think that would completely
purify from the plant just because these
mycelium networks get built in and and
spread pretty quickly and you can't see
them so I imagine that would stay around
and that's actually effed almost imagine
that network is like being an aspen
stand where all the roots are connected
and they you can sprout genetically
similar things out of the root zone
that's that's kind of these my city of
network stars they're creating this
fabric from which it can grow spores at
a later stress event so I be that why
that might remove a lot of the spores
it's probably a good practice just to
lower the spore count inside the garden
I definitely clean your hands and don't
touch any other plants after you do that
right I wouldn't be surprised if they
could if they could pop back out at a
later stressor event when you do that I
would probably be more inclined that
maybe these sulfur treatments or these
other milk-based treatments which I'm
assuming what the milk is doing is
putting lactobacillus in play correct
that probably does a better job eating
away that Network and in destroying it
so those are probably I bet more
party mechanisms so one story think
you've some folks a sense of sensitivity
here there was one group here that was
done there's a there's a company called
curated leaf that runs our our chemistry
here in Massachusetts and they went to
one group grow they tested 30 mothers
one of the mothers was positive for
powdery mildew they then and then went
and tested was a twenty five of the
descendants the clones off that mother
and two of those pop positive so now
they've pulled the mother and then the
two clones and then quarantined those
but that gives you a sense of the
sampling challenges we might find with
this that if it's if it's at a very low
spore count or very low frequency on the
plan it may not be all over the entire
plant it might just be in one side of
the plant that happened to get a little
bit damp or based on the corner it was
facing or something it managed to start
colonizing a plant there and when they
cut clones from that a couple of the
clones ended up with the disease so it
does travel just in the cloning process
alone and that's one thing that I think
people have to just keep an eye on right
on and similarly and in Reverse when you
mentioned that there you know there's a
mother room and one of the of the twenty
five plants tested possible positive for
powdery mildew I would think that
chances are there's powdery mildew on
all of the rest of the mothers as well
but the spore counts are so low that
they just didn't come up on the test
yeah could it could have been that or it
could they could there could be more
resistance as well I mean some of the
resistance literature and a rapid topsis
which is the model organism and that
we're looking at in hops there's six
different genetic low-side that have
been identified in hops that are
pointing towards their resistance
mechanisms and and some of the
resistance is that we think that the the
stoma or stomata are smaller and some of
the ones that a resistance was harder
for them to get that história or that
taproot into the plant another ones are
just about enzymes that the plant
happens to make that that might fight
off this infection so there's a there's
a host of different ways in which the
plant this is a hops plan of course but
if you draw some of those parallels to
cannabis you have to imagine there may
be more than one genetic resistance low
sigh in the plant and so some might
actually get infected but never actually
express the spores we don't know this
yet yeah they may just
the leaves but it's not actually
affecting them because they either have
you know some some magic chemical on the
leaves or so yes come on earth yeah yeah
right so we what we're trying to do with
the test is make sure that we we don't
crack open to many spores we want the
spores to remain Hardy and probably be
missed by the test we really want the
test to be picking up the mycelium
Network which we know is a sign of
successful infection yeah right and so
that's that's kind of what we've been
aiming for so changing gears a little
bit you know we all want to avoid
powdery mildew because it stresses out
the plan which eventually decreases
yield and might take down the plant
itself and no one likes to harvest a
plant and and have it go poof with
powdery mildew on the flowers afterwards
cuz that just that the expect experience
is gross but what actually happens to a
human if we smoke flower that has been
dried and then it's got powdery mildew
it and we and we combust it so the only
things that we've seen tied to powdery
mildew in human health is maybe an
allergenic response they're not listed
as human pathogens I mean this is the
reason why we don't have them on our
other tests or ones that are looking for
human pathogens like E coli Salmonella
and Aspergillus
you know Aspergillus there have been
cases of people inhaling those spores
and they can get a special OSIS and this
is a one patient in Toronto had this
happen to them maybe last year it was
published the patient survived but they
kind of knew more thorax and it was
really hairy scenario usually ask for
gel osis and immunocompromised patients
has like a 50% mortality rate so it can
be very serious if you get those types
of spores your lungs but it's important
about those aren't powdery mildew spores
and powdery mildew spores are probably
our bodies are probably quite used to
them because they're on a lot of other
vegetables you know not that we're
smoking those things but we're certainly
ingesting lots of other fruits and
vegetables and the powdery mildews seem
to be quite common - amongst many of
them so I've not found any literature
and I encourage anyone to forward stuff
if they can find it that's suggested
that this is actually a human health
concern it's more just I think the
cosmetics and perhaps the it might
change the the flavor and the terpene
profiles and and of course affect the
yields but
there isn't I think any evidence to be
alarmed of powdery mildew wow that's
really surprising you know the the lore
is that you know you always want to
avoid PM when producing for patients and
the idea that it is just simply because
of having a you know some sort of
allergic reaction just sounds a lot less
serious than mold spores getting into
the lungs which is how most people
normally talk about it and that it like
you know taking up residence there
yeah and that can be very serious for
Aspergillus and I agree and then in
those cases and maybe some people don't
have the eye to tell the difference
between the two of them I certainly
don't but we can tell the difference
very very evidently with DNA they're
they're very different so does most post
harvest processing remove it like
ethanol or you know using hydrocarbon
extraction well this will this just kill
the mold spores but leave the the
remaining spore material there but but
inactive I would imagine most extraction
systems would obliterate it and I've not
there's a few folks in on the field
trying to look at that question whether
the extraction systems actually destroy
the spores or whether they make it
through but if I had to place money on
it I bet ethanol extractions would would
melt most of these things away so you
know a lot of people have been talking
about that great Jorge Cervantes video
that's been going around is showing him
giving his flowers with PM a hydrogen
peroxide bath that's eight ounces of h2o
to to a five gallon bucket of water and
then he takes the flowers that and and
then and then washes them kind of
submerges them and jostles them around a
little bit and then hangs them to dry
and of course since we all try to avoid
mold generally and water on our plants
it totally looks crazy to that and you
really have to make sure that you dry
them well so that doesn't happen but so
what are your thoughts of that is that a
pretty effective way to remove PM from
your flowers if you've got an especially
higher ratio yeah and i think we saw a
lot of the grouse here resorting to that
when they when they just opened up and
had
problem with this they were starting to
resort to some of this hydrogen peroxide
treatment I think they did notice a hit
in the terpenes however which is
probably not that surprising with
hydrogen peroxide so some of the terpene
profile may change with that treatment
but it I don't know what happens with
yield either do you do you end up I
would imagine with the PM infection
you're not getting perhaps the you're
not getting the best growth the plants
busy trying to find infection as opposed
to making incredible colas and so there
may be just a yield issue as well
so since you mentioned it and I know
this is purely speculative because I
don't think there's many studies on this
but you suggested that h2o2 would likely
decrease the terpenes now regardless of
the terpene test being higher or lower
what scientifically do you think about
hydrogen peroxide would threaten terpene
I think she's oxidative I imagine some
of the the terpenes will get oxidized
with hydrogen peroxide treatment which
may change limiting and pennilyn or a
few the ones that that are that may be
more susceptible to that good I'm glad I
asked that's really interesting I would
have to look into that more myself all
right so then so then the last question
before we move on to botrytis is
prevention right like you know the best
the best cure is to not get it in the
first place and and we know that there's
probably some amount of PM on just about
every plant and the question is does do
you create an opportunity for the
powdery mildew to take over and increase
the spore accounts on any particular
plant so what can we do as a
preventative so that we keep those spore
counts negligible well this is a bit of
a self-fulfilling plug here but what
we've been pitching is just a screen for
these this stuff genetically and and use
it as a mechanism that perhaps
accelerate your breeding toward
resistant lines if you if you can screen
all your plants that the ones that are
that are starting to build up in p.m.
and now they're you're not gonna this is
before you can actually see the spores
once you can see the powder on it's too
late that their spores are there and
they're gonna spread in so by
time you're in emergency mode trying to
chop stuff down and treat things but
prior to that while these things are
potentially incubating and building the
especi of networks you could be
screening for the plants that are that
are susceptible to it and remove those
and then by default the ones that are
left over are more likely to have
resistance genetics and keep reading
those so we view it as an opportunity to
do some some selective reading based on
you know plant pathogens that are
president that you can find the being
the DNA right on and as far as so that's
how you can get rid of it long term
through selective breeding and it sounds
like our best solution in the short term
if you're if you're dealing with an
acute situation is going to labs you
know keeping a hostile environment to
those spores use your labs in advance
both you know in the soil and foliar but
I don't actually have a good answer for
how it may blow your spore tests though
that's that's something that we're gonna
have to change in the regulations so
that we can continue to use labs for
probiotic growing yeah exactly that is
the challenges if you go to a lab that's
using Petri films powdery mildew doesn't
grow on Petri films and so they're gonna
be blind to it
however Trichoderma which you might want
to consider using to get rid of it
will grow on those films and so it's a
bit of a double-edged sword there that
you might the right thing to do it's
probably probiotics but you're probably
gonna get penalized for it if the lab is
using a culture based system to to track
this right on definitely something we're
gonna have to all be active around with
both lab technique and also how the
regulations are put in place so we're
not dinging the wrong people for first
for sports they're actually healthy I
mean yeah I think California got this
right I think their most recent regs
I've seen is a very species specific on
the human pathogen front so they've got
a coli and Salmonella and we have a test
for that that's multiplexed and two
different wavelengths and then there's
four different Aspergillus species and
we have tests for all four of those as
well but there isn't anything in there
like a total aerobic count or total
yeast and mold and thank God because
those very broad
tests their their reading tea leaves
they're really not telling you what's
beneficial versus what versus what's
harmful that that's what we used to have
in Washington until just last month we
changed to moral on the line so what
California is doing so so let's move it
let's move on to botrytis you know
usually this time of year people will
first swear about powdery mildew and
then we'll follow the next person in
line will swear about botrytis and it's
such a drag to watch a gorgeous kolja
growing at the top of a plant only to
have it crumble in your hands because
it's rotted from the inside no no just
makes you cry so so so what is botrytis
so it's it's another mold in fact this
one was sequenced by the Whitehead
Institute many years ago so there's
already a genome sequence for this and
it seems to cross two different plants
so it's botrytis scenario which is
mostly found in on cannabis and that's
at least the test that we've been
building forward is toward that toward
that genome and we do find it a lot of
people have handed us botrytis samples
the tests are positive for it it is it's
it is also something that can get to the
seeds which is something where we don't
believe can happen with powdery mildew
so the the literature at least in hops
is that peat macular is unlikely to get
into the seeds botrytis however seems
like it can get into the seeds and it
can also survive the winner and so it's
um it's perhaps a little bit of a
tougher one to get rid of in that regard
so from a testing standpoint we are
still doing leaf punches to try and pick
this up and that may not we may have to
change that because it doesn't always
seem to show itself up in the leaves
like powdery mildew does but it is
believed to be systemic this is one
where there's really good literature
around botrytis scenario at getting into
the vasculature of the plant and this is
why you can see it in the center of the
buds too so when it's infected it's it's
you know it's inside out and in terms of
its its display so yeah it's a little
bit of a different beast and sometimes
you know probably harder to deal with it
anyways so for somebody who is new to
I mean just about anybody who's grown a
crop or two has has seen botrytis and
can identify it because it you know it's
a big old bear and the grow it's kind of
hard to miss once you know what it is
but for somebody who's relatively new to
working with the plants how do you
identify botrytis visually without going
into a lab well there's you know
horray has great pictures of this in his
cannabis encyclopedia of what botrytis
can look like and there's even so you
can even sometimes seen on stems as like
little gray spots and the stems I've
even gotten the DNA tests to pick it up
positive on some leaves that didn't look
like they were infected with any fungus
so we're still learning about I think
about how early this infects things I
think that what I've read is it also has
a dpi of like eighteen to thirty days is
a days post infection meaning that it
can stay unnoticed human eye for that
period of time before it begins to show
phenotypes that we can detect with maybe
a magnifying loupe or something so it's
that I've had some plants test positive
where I would have never thought it had
it had discovered leaves that were
little necrotic here and there and lo
and behold there's botrytis in there
starting to get foot and I bet when some
of those plants mature they're gonna
it's going to come out in full force so
I think this one might be a little bit
harder for people to eyeball because I
do think it has a variety of different
ways in which it can they can show
itself right on let's go ahead and take
our second short break and when we come
back we will continue talking about
botrytis you're listening to shaping
fire and my guest today is kevin
mckernon chief science officer and
medicinal genomics we humans are
attracted to plants because they offer
us relief and are a whole lot of fun
sometimes though the best parts are
buried inside the plant and we need to
use specialty extraction technology when
it comes to cannabis it is
extraordinarily important to extract its
precious oils without changing them in
the process we want to preserve the
properties of the cannabinoids terpenes
and other constituents that all work
together since 1994 Eden labs has been
developing extraction technology and
processes to do just that
Eden labs was founded by a
loving engineered during the early days
of medical marijuana in California and
the expanded Eden team has been
designing and building industry-leading
solutions for cannabis extraction ever
since
Eden labs flagship product is the newly
improved high flow co2 extractor as
other extraction companies enter the
market it is the high flow from Eden
labs that everyone chases and tries to
compare themselves with not only that
but the improved automation software
allows data to be collected stored and
studied Eden labs can outfit your whole
lab Eden's coldfinger
ethanol extractor creates astonishing
whole plant extracts working alone or in
tandem with an initial stream distilling
step to isolate monoterpenes before
extracting the rest of the botanical
constituents Eden offers you many
options including vacuum distillation
column distilling stirred reactor units
and accelerated solvent recovery when
you partner with Eden labs your lab team
is enrolled into the eeen labs training
program to boost their understanding of
Eden's best practices to ensure that
your outputs are exactly what you
require for your application whether it
be DAB oil oil for pen cartridges or
edibles when you work with Eden you're
not just buying the tech you are buying
dedicated customer support to help you
attain your business goals - you can
hear Eden's CEO AC Braddock talk about
the company's values during shaping fire
episode 19 that was all about co2
extraction so many of the new companies
in the market just smell opportunity
slap an extractor together and hire a
marketing company Eden labs has been
listening to feedback from extractors
and consumers for about 25 years now
they care about both you and your
consumer partner with Eden labs to
extract astonishing cannabis oils and
terpenes that you will be proud of go to
shaping feiyr.com
/e Dhin to find out more if you grow
cannabis with sunshine you can often
feel limited by the seasonal cycle you
want to grow sustainably and save money
so you use as little electricity as
possible but if you haven't studied or
implemented light deprivation techniques
into your greenhouse you're leaving a
lot of money on the table by and
or parading light deprivation solutions
into your greenhouse you can often add
two or three additional growing cycles
to your year when you pencil out the
financial benefit of those additional
cycles you'll realize why commercial
scale light deprivation technology is
remaking the cannabis industry what used
to be done by pulling tarps over hoop
houses has been scaled up over the last
few years in such a way that has become
mechanized easy and affordable to even
small-scale commercial cannabis
operations forever flowering greenhouses
is the industry leader in light
deprivation greenhouse design in
operation for the commercial cannabis
industry their team of greenhouse
experts have been in the fields of
Northern California for decades and
they're now building greenhouses for
commercial cannabis companies across the
country if you are new to light dep and
growing in greenhouses i encourage you
to go back to shaping fire episode 13
with guest eric Branstad of forever
flowering I talked with Eric about the
importance of intelligent greenhouse
management as well as the huge financial
benefit of incorporating light depth
techniques there are so many aspects of
utilizing a greenhouse that can go wrong
from temperature and airflow to light
depth and workflow forever flowering
will help you produce crop after crop of
well-cared-for flowers they can help you
retrofit your existing greenhouse with
light depth and other modern systems at
a level that fits your budget if you're
just starting out forever flowering can
help you plan and build your new
greenhouse so that you get started on
the right foot the cannabis business has
enough risks without trying to go it
alone with your greenhouse contact
forever flowering greenhouses to partner
with folks who have an indisputable
reputation as knowledgeable and easy to
work with go to shaping fire calm /f FG
to find out more welcome back you are
listening to shaping fire
I'm your host Shango Lowe's and our
guest this week is Kevin mckernon chief
science officer at medicinal genomics so
let's talk more about botrytis so you
know when people first see botrytis when
people are in their personal gardens a
lot of folks will just pinch off that
small amount of botrytis that they see
with the idea of oh you know I really
don't want to destroy the whole Cola or
this whole plant so I'm just gonna I'm
gonna pinch this little bit off and I'm
gonna take it away from the garden
just like hope for the best and and you
know in in personal gardens sometimes
you can get away with this but but my
question for you is are we just fooling
ourselves I mean is it all if it's
already a little bit on the plant is
there already everywhere and this plant
is doomed how bad is it so that's a
perfect question there was someone that
this happened to the summer on and there
was parts of their plant that looked
like they could salvage and other ones
that they broke off and you know threw
it into the trash and so we went in DNA
tested the stuff that was clearly just
covered in mold and also the stuff that
they thought was clean and we found we
found protaras DNA and all of it so they
opted to take the clean stuff and then
go extract it and see if they could turn
into something other than a smokeable
product but I really don't know if if
they had continued to grow that plant
for another week or two whether they
would have just shown up in the other
flowers or not and really sprouted there
we didn't really that didn't happen once
they saw it break out like this they
kind of killed the thing and started
tearing apart the parts if they thought
they could salvage but we did see DNA in
all of it so yeah I really don't have
any advice on the biocontrol of this
other than what you can probably find in
a lot of the other recommended books
about using you know Trichoderma and
other types of yeast to try and take it
down one of the things that makes me way
more suspicious of botrytis then then
powdery mildew is because it is systemic
right
I mean you are if you see a little bit
about trying to sign a flower and you
pinch it off you are mechanically
removing the spores from the flower but
at that point it's already in everywhere
yeah it's already inside of the plant so
so really you're just doing an aesthetic
thing at that point yeah well you know
there is an interesting paper a point
people - in tomatoes where they they
deploy hexanoic acid under the root ball
tomatoes and it Prime's the plant to
defend itself against botrytis and
hexanoic acid is a very interesting
compound it's actually the first
compound and cannabinoid synthesis the
hexanoic acid pathway is what is the
spread it's arguably a peak or precursor
to these things are obviously Tomatoes
don't make that but hexanoic acid I
think in other plants is a signaling
molecule the immune system
but it's an interesting paper because
they actually carbon label the hexanoic
acid they show it's not actually getting
past the root zone so it's doing some
type of cellular communication with the
plant to prime the immune system to
fight off at Rytas oh man that sounds so
interesting I will I will not only get
that paper from you folks will be able
to look on the the podcast page for this
episode and and get most of the papers
that you're referring to including a
link to that that great Rob Clark book
about oh yeah and Jesus yeah so all
right so so let's go the opposite side
right we're talking about a we were just
talking about pinching it off and you're
in your own home grow let's talk about
an indoor commercial grow now if if
you're if you find a plant that is
expressing botrytis and we know it's
systemic it would sound like you would
want to bag that plant cut it and get it
the hell out of your indoor environment
right yeah that would be my tendency
because that once these spores start to
go there they they move and they're very
they're very resistant so so you know we
talked about how powdery mildew other
than some potential allergies that it's
not really all that bad for humans even
though we all try to avoid it because
it's just kind of generally gross and
and and poor aesthetics how does it go
for botrytis I mean I mean certainly it
tastes bad and it causes you to cough
but but how does botrytis affect the
human eye the same thing I've read is
just out allergenic I've not seen
botrytis as being a health hazard and if
anyone has any papers to show us
otherwise we were all years but we have
been searching for any evidence of that
and have opted to not have it be in the
human pathogen analyst results of that
the allergy part of it is certainly
plenty for me I mean I know that when
when I come across some botrytis in a
flower when I'm trimming let's say you
know and I and I didn't know was coming
right I didn't see it and I pick it up
and it hits something and I and it's
under the lighting all sudden goes poof
right and the spores are everywhere and
of course I'm inhaling it and it's like
oh man time
take a step outside and get some fresh
air because that stuff's really gross I
think that even though you know it may
not be bad for humans it's certainly
unpleasant to my human yeah these things
are fairly ubiquitous as well in the
atmosphere and so I think it's R it's
really comes down to are they
immunocompromised or not and in those
cases maybe the out the allergenic
reaction is probably more severe of a
concern than what a healthy individual
might have from just environmental
exposure to spores so now for a light
infection of at Rytas you know in
advance botrytis infection on a flower I
mean the poor flower just melts and
there's nothing left in it but but but
some plants they'll get just a little
bit of botrytis and folks will we'll set
those aside to be processed either into
a topical or you know it is you know
maybe they'll maybe a micro filter it
and turn it into a tincture or something
though that would be arguably sketchy as
well but my point is is that you know
when you process it with ethanol or with
you know hydrocarbons does it kill the
spore but leave the spore plant material
just like it does with powdery mildew so
I don't know the answer to that it's a
good question as to whether or not you
know which extraction techniques do what
to the spores you know I would assume
the spores are the things that are
probably the hardiest and that they may
survive some of the extraction
techniques that are out there but I
don't know I have not seen any studies
done on that right on you know one of
the things that really is a drag about
about botrytis especially up here in the
in the northwest is that down in Oregon
where they have a very popular and
financially successful Riesling harvest
they actually spray it outdoors on
desert wine grapes they actually call no
noble rot because it makes it makes
dessert wines taste better and you know
then the wind blows it up here in the
northwest it's like you know as if we
don't have enough trouble with mold just
because it's so wet up here and then
we're you know it's it's they're
spraying and but try this down in Oregon
and it blows up here and suddenly we've
got there Noble
rot which we've got a lot of swear words
for yes it's true they I guess in the
wine industry this actually helps the
flavor so this is used quite often leaf
or that you know I should say I have
heard of some folks who have been
working in indoor grows where they've
been chronically exposed to high spore
counts and feel as if they've gotten
some type of allergy or or lung
infection so you know III don't want to
proclaim that this stuff is all it's all
rosy for people but there can be cases I
imagine where a year if you're stuffed
in in a room that doesn't have right the
right ventilation you're constantly
working around a high spore count that's
probably gonna aggravate the scenario so
um so similarly 2 p.m. and I and I know
that you're not big on the prevention
side I mean you believe in the
prevention side but it's not really the
focus of your research um would you say
that an approach of spraying labs Foley
early would help against botrytis in the
same ways that powdery mildew I'm
starting kiss your question and foliar
sprays whether they would help yeah yeah
so I think that's where a lot of this is
going to go is that once we have the
genome sequence of all of the pests that
that have in fact cannabis well then
it's just a question of finding the
genomic Achilles heel and hitting these
things with RNA AI or hitting these
things with other enzymes that might
actually target the weakness that you
can see in the genome and these foliar
sprays ideally would be for molecules
that are ephemeral that are like enzymes
biodegrade over time and and RNA
molecules degrade over time and so these
types of approaches I think you're
showing a lot of promise in other in
other plants and if they can work in a
rapid OPS's if you can find an economic
model club to work in $2 a pound
tomatoes you can find an economic and a
model for to work in cannabis right on I
think that is a great approach and and
while I'm at it I want to I want to plug
the the Facebook group the probiotic
farmers alliance it's a huge
yeah me too they got like 20,000 members
and if you want to learn how to make
labs and and you know lactobacillus
lactobacilli and others that will help
protect protect your plants you know you
can google it anywhere but but that
group
it's moderated really well and there's a
lot of pros on on that list so probiotic
farmers Alliance shout out there so so
Kevin I know I'm catching you off guard
with this this this last question but
you know you have got a lot of depth in
both powdery mildew and botrytis and you
know I as an interviewer I can only
really ask you questions on things that
that I've come across and and know you
know what have I what's in your head
about either or both of those that I
haven't asked you and and in your head
you're like you're like oh man this
would be this would be a good thing to
throw into the mix as well but but maybe
Shenko doesn't you know know to ask you
about it what am I not asking you and I
should about this well I would say that
so we have we've sequenced the genome of
one powdery mildew that infects cannabis
and I'm somewhat suspicious there may be
a second genome out there only because
that's what we've seen with wheat and
rye there is a two different or three
different strains of bloom area that are
powdery mildews that infect those
grasses and and the plants have evolved
different resistance to each one of them
so we're somewhat eager to see if
there's another another powdery mildew
out there that affects cannabis kind of
us having such a global spread it would
be surprise me if there were just one
right now we've tested a lot of material
from California and from the East Coast
but in a little bit in Canada but we
haven't really gotten to any
international markets with the test yet
to know whether the powdery mildew in
Europe for instance or in an Afghanistan
is is the same species what we're
dealing here dealing with here and then
the other thing is there is a tremendous
amount of confusion in literature over
the taxonomic class of these things in
fact there's a great book from Roger ta
Cooke I would point people to and the
taxonomic manual of powdery mildews and
it's a huge book and what you'll will
frustrate you about this book is if you
look at all of these species that
they're there categorizing in here they
all look the same by eye which can be a
little bit overwhelming when you realize
there's this many powdery mildews out
there and they all look the same
what am I actually dealing with so going
forward we're looking to expand the
testing menu from just botrytis
powdery mildew onto anything that
affects cannabis so if folks have ideas
and tests that we should target we have
a long list of things we're going down
and making assays for from you know
Fusarium to Pythium to downy mildew you
name it everything in these books that
were reading about we're trying to make
assays for but we always want to hear
from growers as to what they're actually
running into what what are the problems
that are really causing them economic
harm so that we can make assays that
detect them very early because we think
is the key to finding both resistance
genetics and also to just preventing
grows from getting knocked out the idea
that there may be a novel p.m. that's
specific for cannabis is really an
interesting idea it's probably really
like the other ones but has just got a
small difference that is that is unique
how would at what point would nature of
developed this this novel version of
p.m. would it would it go all the way
back to you know the land races or is
this something that probably it happened
once we all started hybridizing them so
I'll link you guys another paper to the
plumeria paper and they're they
hypothesize that this is happening
during domestication of of the plants
that when you domesticate them you tend
to take the plants out of a surrounding
where they have a lot of other species
where there might be more hopping going
on into more of a monoculture
environment and when that happens the
youth these obligate bio troves tend to
speciate at least that's their thinking
so yeah it could be just that this dates
back to when mankind decided to take
cannabis under its wing and along with
its pathogens decided to evolve
according to new cultural or new
agricultural practices yeah that makes a
lot of sense and and yet more evidence
against mono cropping mono culturing and
in favor of permaculture and companion
plants right Yeah right right on well
thanks so much for being on the show
Kevin I know your time is valuable and
I'm glad that you were willing to spend
an hour with us excellent thank you
if you'd like to know more about Kevin
mckernon you can check out the medicinal
genomics website at WWDC no genomics com
you can find more episodes of the
shaping
fire podcast and subscribe to the show
at shaping fire calm and on Apple iTunes
stitcher and Google Play if you enjoyed
the show we'd really appreciate it if
you'd leave a positive review of the
podcast wherever you download your
review will help others find the show so
they can enjoy it too
on the shaping fire web site you can
also subscribe to the weekly newsletter
for insights into the latest cannabis
news and product reviews on the shaping
fire website you will also find
transcripts of today's podcast as well
for information on me and where I will
be speaking you can check out Shango
lows calm d'Azur company want to reach
our national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hotspot at shaping
fire calm to find out how thanks for
listening to shaping fire I've been your
host
Shango lows
[Music]