we are at a very awkward time in the
relationship between the cannabis plant
and humans we've been using cannabis for
health and spirituality for millennion
yet because of the last 80 years or so
of prohibition modern generations barely
know the plan at all as a society we are
gonna have to go through a process of
relearning how to use the plan how best
to grow and hybridize her for medicine
and of course we're gonna have to undo
all of the reefer madness fed to us by
the US government and institutional
players like pharmaceutical companies
and law enforcement now that prohibition
is unraveling in the u.s. we have
stopped strong-arming other nations to
fight cannabis in their own countries -
and now their freedoms are increasing
Ukraine Mexico Colombia Costa Rica the
Czech Republic and many more countries
have varying forms of cannabis freedom
and it is spreading globally at a fast
rate now that the US has stopped
bullying everybody of course there is
Portugal - who shocked the world and
legalized all drugs in 2001 and has seen
an addiction drop by 50% in violent
crime rates dropped - not to mention
everyone is much happier what we do not
yet have in the u.s. are updated social
mores for how to talk to each other
about cannabis how to think about
cannabis as medicine and how to build a
business model for distribution that
will work to the benefit of all sure in
the cannabis activists scene we have
much of this figured out for today but
as more and more humans bringing
cannabis into their lives what is
accepted socially will all change again
and again today's guest is dr. Sunil
Agarwal he is a medical geographer and a
leading expert in cannabis medicine and
cannabinol adji he is often a panelist
and speaker at top cannabis medicine
conventions all over the world
cherry-picking his accomplishments to
describe him to you was really hard
because he's done so much right now he
is a palliative medicine physician an
associate hospice medical director at
multi care Auburn Medical Center in
Washington State he received both a PhD
and an MD from the University of
Washington where he now teaches he also
has degrees in chemistry philosophy and
studies as a National Science Foundation
graduate research fellow he wrote a PhD
dissertation entitled the medical
geography of cannabinoid botanicals in
Washington state access delivery and
distress conducted under NIH first
issued federal certificates of
confidentiality dr. Agarwal successfully
led the effort to get the American
Medical Association to call for a review
of the scheduling classification of
cannabis in 2009 their first such
statement in 72 years he serves on the
editorial advisory board of the National
Cancer Institute's pdq cancer camp
information summary on cannabis and
cannabinoids finally he is associate
member of the Humboldt Institute for
interdisciplinary marijuana research and
the New York Academy of Medicine an
honorary trustee of the medicinal
cannabis Foundation of India and vice
president of the Washington physicians
for Social Responsibility and that's not
even half of his bio it's an honor to
have dr. Sunil Agarwal on shaping fire
so for today let's look at the big
picture let's go back way back and
consider the historical roots of
cannabis and humans we will go back
30,000 years and page through the story
of the love affair between humans and a
plan named cannabis sativa
welcome to the show Sunil hey it's great
to be here Shango I'm glad I'd really
appreciate you making the time to join
us today so I want to start at the very
beginning you know at the green flower
medical cannabis summit you were
painting a really wonderful image of
perhaps how cannabinoids came into
existence like 38 million years ago
as a protective response to the
increasing UV radiation from the Sun I
really enjoyed hearing that would you go
ahead and share that perspective with us
again right now oh yeah I'd love to yeah
that this is something that I read in
some a you know a geography book that
has to come out nicely recently from a
University of New Mexico professor and
really just trying to understand the
deep history of cannabis bio
geographically we're evolved and when it
evolved and you know so it's just
because part of what we what people have
lost is a connection of cannabis to the
the natural world the biosphere like the
web of life that we're all part of and
that was kind of the context I was
giving that that history and when I
spoke at the at the summit trying to
make that illegal alien nature of
cannabis back to like hey you know this
is part of reintegrating it back into
our sense of Earth so you know the this
this advanced wind pollinated plant that
we know now as you know cannabis with
two new sexes and occasionally
hermaphrodites it evolved in a part of
the world central south southern asia
based on you know archeological evidence
based on on genetic evidence and you
know the interesting thing is that it's
evolved in a place that actually at the
same time it was evolving it was also
evolving in a place that was getting
higher and higher elevation every year
because it came at a time when the earth
itself was going through a radical
transformation whereby at that time the
indian subcontinent
actually had not joined asia and there
was a period of time about 15 million
years ago when that plate collided with
the Asian landmass and you had the
formation of the Himalayan mountain
range and that was you know one of the
you know the tallest mountain range in
the world and and there at the same time
you have this cannabis plant that's
evolving in the same time and how do you
survive in a place where you know every
year the elevation is getting higher and
higher as a plant and one theory is that
it has to create chemicals to protect
itself from the damaging effects of
ultraviolet radiation I really sorry go
ahead you know and that's that's that's
what it is and and that's just you know
does not just hurt cannabinoids about
terpenes but cannabinoids especially
have these very nice properties so
that's a that's what but probably one of
the theories and I was really attracted
that story because you know it really
respects the plant itself is having its
own life story because we always talk
about what the plant can do for us but
but really the plan
itself has its own story and you know it
eventually comes in contact with humans
and and we start to cultivate it and it
starts to influence us and then we start
to influence it but but it's got its own
storyline as well and I think that's a
great place to start if you're
absolutely right you know it has to it's
it's it evolved it has to survive and it
did a very very good job it thrived and
it adapted and that's part of I think
how why it is so Hardy and able to adapt
in so many places because it it kind of
has this cauldron of great stress under
which it it was formed so you know um
you know most people don't see cannabis
as being the long-term cure that we've
always used you know except for maybe
the last 80 years or so they don't
really think about that you know
cannabis was a central component of the
modern pharmacopoeia but also that that
we humans have been interacting with
this plant for tens of thousands of
years I know you like to talk about you
know the place that the plant has you
know in human history will you walk us
through the human relationship with
cannabis over the ages to to put the
modern prohibition in context Oh
certainly it's a it's quite a vast and
long story so anything can I say in this
short time will not do full justice but
I mean you know okay I guess the place
to start really is is that it you know
where it evolved in that part of the
world is where people started you know
first coming into contact with it and
domesticating it you know in South Asia
where my ancestors are from 18,000 years
ago you've got that's the earliest
dating of signs of domestication of
cannabis that could have been some other
records or in earlier places earlier
times in that same region but you know
that at that time you know we don't know
but the earliest writings that we get
from from that civilization that
reference cannabis it's very much in the
context of healing which is not distinct
from spiritual growth we
development and the idea that you know
you can't that the two are separate in
is it's kind of a modern fallacy I guess
you can say and in those days there's
really no distinction between the idea
of you know achieving certain states of
spiritual development meditative states
states of self-awareness states of peace
tranquility and sense of healing which
is you know pretty transformative and
fundamental to to cure I mean if you if
if disease is it comes from the word
dis-ease not to not be at ease and you
have something that's potentially part
of you know putting people at peace
that's that's kind of the fundamental
stamping out of disease is where where
it came or disease is where it came into
play but certainly also it was seen the
development of our Vedic medicine
traditional medicine systems such as
there were systems called inany and TB
which kind of came from Persia and of
other historical influences and cannabis
found homes and those traditional
Chinese medicine cannabis found a home
there's a suggestions from the Ebers
papyrus which is the one of the oldest
medical documents that we have which
comes from ancient Egypt there are
formulas for the use of cannabis and and
there it's much more you know analgesic
much dealing with relieving pressure in
the eyes or pain in the eyes so it it
still had a dual role both in this
spiritual realm and in kind of dealing
with pain dealing with problems of
inflammation and I guess over the ages
that that this is cannabis spread
through the parts of the world where
those forms of systems of medical
practice were were used Chinese medicine
UNAMI medicine Persian medicine Indian
medicine they went around the ancient
world and I think you know in there was
there was early writings of the use in
prevention of seizures from much older
times in Syria and
there's a the the first citations that
the like if you look at the government
of India it has a traditional knowledge
library digital library where they're
trying to record all the traditional
uses of plants and things in there and
their heritage so that they don't get
scooped up by big companies that say oh
we came up with that first or something
you know they're trying to establish
prior art they make reference to I
believe it's a 12th century textbook by
a guy named it Ben Minh Sinha it been
sent out he has different names
depending on which part of the world
you're in but this guy's textbook of
medicine from that time era from the
sort of the Arabic Renaissance was
widely read all over the both the east
and the west it was taught at like
Oxford and you know even in the old
monastic European traditions so this is
the citation that I think they
intentionally use to show that this this
very well-known Arabic scholar of
medicine and many other things was
citing cannabis and its medical uses and
it was being read both in the east and
the west so that that kind of was I
think a big recognition that the most
advanced forms of medicine into the
Renaissance in the medieval period
you know cannabis was part of that I
think the next big wave that you can say
where we finally get much more wider
exposure in the nineteenth it happens in
the nineteenth century and and there was
ongoing use and other throughout the you
know the centuries before between the
19th and the 12th centuries and you know
I don't want to go go into all this
there's so many different details that
we can look at with witches and and
traditional herbalists and Europe and
indigenous uses in other parts in Africa
and other places that don't get a lot of
attention but I guess it's big its big
moment in the Sun so to speak happens in
the 1840s when due to the British East
India Company's you know activities in
India they are able to import into India
leading medic
doctors from the 19th century who were
trained at the top academies of Medicine
in Europe in those days which was the
University of Edinburgh in Scotland and
that's where you got dr. William
O'Shaughnessy who trained in Edinburgh
and really this was a center of medical
training not just in Europe but also
people in the United States would go to
train in Edinburgh in those days because
there really wasn't big centers in the
US and those time so anyway this doctor
who was already kind of a genius Irish
doctor who had figured out the treatment
of cholera who nobody had ever had
figured out that oh boy we should
probably give IV fluids to cholera
victims with with electrolytes in them
so that they don't dehydrate to death
you know
from diarrhea so that was his like you
know doctoral thesis and a pretty pretty
brilliant discovery it probably saved
many lives
and he then was he got a lucrative
position in the British you see new
company they said we want you to go to
Calcutta which is our where our
headquarters are in India at that time
the prezi capital of the British India
and we want you to set up a modern
medical college and this is the oldest
modern medical college in Asia now it's
still in operation and he established it
and he was able to he was such a kind of
polygon and thoughtful man that he said
hey let's let's bring in let's try to
develop the principles where we can
teach in the native tongue to the native
Indians which is great I mean it's their
call colonialists after all so they
don't always have a high regard for
native ideas but they did and he did and
as part of that process of establishing
chemistry department and the college he
said you know I really need to learn the
local medicines so we can kind of we
don't have to import all of these from
Europe and we can kind of learn from
them and learn from Indians so he
started seeing the use of cannabis in
the marketplaces the local [ __ ] and
healers and he said well this is this is
an interesting compound and he started
experimenting with it in medical
students and animals and finally in
patients and you know he kind of made
his career at least the first half of
his career he was as a brilliant guy
that he has actually many
first to his name but he wrote a paper
that in the 1830s that that got
international currency on the use of
cannabis indica or ganja Indian hemp you
know and he covered lots of different
conditions convulsions tetanus some
conditions that infantile convulsions
and tetanus and outs of terminal rabies
again we're conditions where there
actually was no cure but because we
didn't have you know modern antibiotics
in those days antivirals or you know
inoculum but you know he was able to
bring a lot of relief to people who
otherwise would die very horrible deaths
you know and I'm unable to eat or drink
because of the convulsions from from
terminal rabies when it gets into your
nervous system or severe stiffness from
from tetanus when it gets really
advanced and he's able to relax those
muscles and allow people to eat and
drink and and of course he did have
other you know younger patients who
survived convulsions so that that kind
of thing was a was was excellent because
his discoveries really launched modern
the use of cannabis in modern medicine
and I think you know we've just had a
trajectory since that time where it's
it's come and gone and it achieved
another peak really it it started
peaking at the late 19th century early
20th century leading doctors from around
in the early 20th century doctor William
Osler who's the father of internal
medicine doctor Gower who basically did
some of the earliest studies in
Parkinson's doctor Reynolds who first
established the typology of seizures
epilepsy disorders who was Queen
Victoria's physician all of these
leading doctors you know founded founder
of Johns Hopkins University they all
knew cannabis and they all knew it was
an important part of their armamentarium
thanks to the work of O'Shaughnessy and
their own research on on it and use in
their patients so that finally that area
kind of came to an end in the 40s when
early forties when the you know federal
it got political and you know there was
a increasing now the United States was a
colonial power
this is one theory you know it was had
taken over the Philippines they had
started using you know dealing with
Mexico much more they actually you know
I think they saw cannabis in a different
light now associated with people that
they were trying to control and you know
it became much more of a political
football and the medical arts around
cannabis started falling out of favor
there was also a move to more industrial
medicine a little bit more
pharmaceutical eyes diversion of
medicine and you know even though there
had been attempts to grow cannabis in
the United States for pharmaceutical
purposes somehow it just didn't take so
only ultimately that we have to wait
until really the 70s and 80s and then
now in the peak 90s and beyond that now
we're having this next cycle of
emergence and this time we are much more
prepared and much more us you know we
can learn from the history and we now
have this endocannabinoid system science
that has developed in the late late late
part of the 20th century that really
changed everything I mean now we finally
have a deeper understanding of actually
on a molecular level
what are these cannabinoids that are in
cannabis that evolved all those thirty
eight million years ago what are they
doing in our human bodies that was an
epic answer Sunil and no wonder no
wonder you've got a dry throat that was
that was awesome I'm so glad that we got
that recorded the the picture that you
just painted from 38 million years ago
to us learning about the
endocannabinoids system in the 90s and
then what's happening with modern
medical marijuana that's an epic picture
you just painted and because your answer
was so full we need to take our first
short break right now
we'll be right back you are listening to
shaping fire using pesticides when
growing cannabis has been common for a
long time nowadays though we know better
we know that most pesticides formulated
for food crops have never been tested
for use with cannabis they've been
tested to be eaten in tiny doses they
have not been tested to be
inhaled and especially not concentrated
into a cannabis oil chemical residues
from pesticides are not healthy for
anyone but they are especially dangerous
for patients for commercial cannabis
growers this has become very impactful
cannabis enthusiasts and patients have
gotten educated enough that they avoid
growers who used pesticides not only
that but states across the country have
begun making pesticide testing mandatory
on all licensed cannabis crops the time
has come to find a better way to fight
garden pests than covering your cannabis
and chemicals and there is a better way
let some good bugs fight your bad bugs
beneficial insects and predatory mites
have come a long way since we were
buying ladybugs online and putting them
in the grow room and just hoping for the
best natural enemies biocontrol
can help you solve pest issues without
using chemicals natural enemies founder
Shane young learned best practices from
working in the ornamental plant industry
and has fine-tuned those strategies
specifically for large cannabis crops
Shane works with commercial cannabis
clients across the country to ensure
that they keep their crop safe and pest
free without the use of chemicals
natural enemies has proven solutions for
spider mites Athens thrips Russert mites
broad mites shore flies white fly and
others - you can rely on natural enemies
for expertise and excellent service for
more information go to shaping feiyr.com
forward slash natural enemies or simply
click on their banner in this week's
newsletter welcome back you are
listening to shaping fire I'm your host
Shango lows and our guest this week is
dr. Sunil Agarwal
so Sunil before the break we were
talking about how you know the medical
cannabis has come to us through the ages
and now in the modern world when we know
about the endocannabinoid system that
that we are more prepared to learn about
the influence that this beautiful plant
can have on our body well you know
animals study evidence showing
cannabinoids kill cancer
started to begin to accrue in the early
70s you know why do you think that
institutional actors like the US
government and especially major cancer
study nonprofits aren't focusing on
cannabis and talking more about it
publicly and even excitedly they just
seem to be ignoring it yes it's a sad
thing and given how much the leading
causes of death in the country now our
cancers and you know in many other parts
of the world we really have are missing
an incredible opportunity to study and
develop treatments that involve cannabis
and I think we we kind of I mean it was
starting to get in the 70s there was a
big interest in funding on cannabis
research going on there was a interest
in the National Institutes but you know
politics one over there was a sense I
think that you know the Nixon
administration was like well we don't we
don't really want to get that stuff out
there too much because we are I'm
already using this as a tool for
oppression against anti-war protesters
and you know I really I've studied the
Nixon tapes where they actually he talks
about his motivations and he tries to
fire the people who are at the world's
leading Medical Research Institute the
NIH who have argued that you know the
restrictions are too much and there
needs to you know the harms have been
exaggerated and you know we should not
be treating this like kryptonite or you
know nuclear material but unfortunately
he was not that was not part of his his
mission and I don't think that he was
and his administration was somebody that
didn't have any you know compassion for
cancer patients you can actually hear
other recordings where he talks about
hey you know it'd be it's terrible what
happens to cancer patients they should
have all the pain relief that they need
and you know I think it's just there was
just such a fundamental lack of
awareness and understanding that
cannabis could could offer anything of
value beyond getting has he talks about
it getting charged getting buzzed is
getting you know and that was that was
the view of it that it was just this
total escapist you know it didn't have
anything
any serious value to it despite the fact
that you know doctors and folks above
him or smarter than him we're telling
him otherwise so I think that's why the
initial research got really got shut
down or it didn't get renewed or
developed there was other movements
going on again it was always the idea
well can I have a noise who owns that
who's gonna make a bunch of money off of
that how do we gonna mass supply that in
that same time in the 70s is when you
started seeing the development of
chemotherapy and modern chemotherapy and
you know it was it was done in at the
NIH the first use of met was called
methotrexate to treat a certain form of
cancer that women who get pregnant can
get choriocarcinoma and I mean I think
people would just you know they just
didn't they didn't understand how could
a boyd's work they didn't understand you
know how we could produce that in a big
way because it was too much of a
political football and unfortunately you
know we dropped that thread now at the
same time there was increasing awareness
in the 70s that cannabis had a role for
palliation in cancer and that started to
start did start to spread in multiple
states Tennessee even states that today
aren't medical cannabis states like
Tennessee you know how to get cannabis
medical cannabis and cancer program
people figured out that it could help
them with the nausea and vomiting
associated with these new chemotherapy
drugs and that was going on for a while
and then you know they shut that program
down and during you know in the 90s and
and when the new war on drugs got it got
it going under Reagan and then the first
Bush and then the AIDS patient salts
that were trying to get in at that time
too and that got shut down so all of
that all the political factors got into
the way that stopped us from really
moving forward on these things and it
took it took passage of California's
medical cannabis law in 96 till to force
the federal government to start allowing
modern clinical trials research in
cancer in cancer and also in HIV thanks
to the work of Donald Abrams at UCSF I
mean he cited the passage of the
California law and his letters
to the National Institutes to get them
to do something to approve his studies
which they finally did so there was that
big long lapse so we that was kind of a
Dark Ages period of research and now
there's been a really even to this day
because of the powers that be and the
funding streams in the United States we
have not put a significant amount of
resources in in the cancer and the
cannabinoid logic approaches to cancer
area even though there was big moonshot
initiative that the vice-president just
did Joe Biden you know or we several of
us put in suggestions to the government
you know you need to fund this type of
research I mean this is there's a huge
promise in multiple types of cancer it
just didn't it didn't come up in their
latest report as a priority area they're
they're looking at more you know they're
looking at data sharing registries
they're looking at immunotherapies and
all these things again I think there's a
lot of you know economic like sort of
issues there that go into play but other
countries are developing cancer and
cannabis research you know they did a
study in Israel where they looked at the
use of cannabidiol to prevent what's
called graft-versus-host disease which
is a horrible complication of a cure for
cancer so people get what's called stem
cell transplants I'm a typo extensive
transplants and they can get cured from
blood cancers and they're looking at
other disorders too and it's a great
thing you know when you can kind of
reset your bone marrow and blood and if
you had a fatal blood cancer like
lymphoma leukemia you know and you can
treat it and cure it with it with a stem
cell transplant but then sometimes you
can get a reaction where the the graft
of your of your transplant attacks your
own body graft-versus-host disease and
it's a very severe complication you know
you get a lot of pain weakness stiffness
and it could make your life call it'd be
terrible and they did a phase two study
where you know cannabidiol had a huge
impact in prevention of that condition
in you know in patients who got these
stem cell transplants a 300 milligram
a day starting at a few days before
transplant and until 30 days after
transplant they really had a huge
reduction in the likelihood of
developing the most severe forms of GVHD
that would been in Israel in Australia
and I think New Zealand they're doing
more research on cannabis compounds and
actual treatment of cancers UCSF did a
glioblastoma study so I'm seeing a
renaissance it is happening it's gonna
be it's slow but it is it is starting in
humans and I think we are just keep we
have to keep talking about it we have to
keep we have to do much more of it we
have to fund it more and I think really
there needs to be a lot more what's
called empiric treatment trials where
people we really need to collect a lot
of primary data real good quality data
where people are using certain varieties
with certain types of cancer not all
cancer is the same the idea that one
size fits all is really you know not the
way that cancer works and I think we and
I don't believe that cannabinoids are
you know the sole treatment for things I
think that's that's really foolish
cancer is such a complex condition and
there's many things that can be done it
needs to be seen as an integrated part
of cancer treatment and I think we we
really are you know still very behind
I'm very hopeful I think the National
Cancer Institute has taken on
cannabinoids in cancer and put up a very
thorough review for the public and for
doctors health professionals and that's
a pretty bold move you know that's
government-funded and that's they go
through a lot of details of the
mechanisms by which cannabinoids kill
cancer which is by the way a very unique
mechanism you know those warned about
some of the problems that we have in
cancer treatments is that so many other
cells suffer when you're trying to kill
cancer cells and what's unique about
cannabinoids is oftentimes they are very
targeted and that's pretty nice you
leave your healthy cells alone and you
you know target the ones that are that
are causing the problems so Sunil you
know one thing I want to ask you before
we go to break that I've always you know
been curious about is that you know when
I learned to what degree cannabinoids
can
and you know start to cause apoptosis
and and you know stop this spread of
cancer cells and and that there was
something there right it astonished me
and continues to that there are so many
majorly funded cancer nonprofits that
that say up front that you know we will
find a cure for cancer and and we're
funding all this Cancer Research and yet
you know you don't hear about them
talking about cannabis or or pushing the
for cannabis or lobbying the the
government and it seems to be coming
more from patients themselves and and
skipping over these major nonprofits so
so if you can kind of give me a short
answer before we go to commercial you
know why do you think that that that
these these large cancer nonprofits are
not speaking with a louder voice to to
try to push this research yeah listen
they this is this is a Schedule one
status of cannabis marijuana really is
there are areas where that doesn't
matter and there are areas where that
really matters and I think when you when
you're talking at this level of official
cancer research these these things have
a huge impact it really does and I think
that's you know we have that's part of
the fundamentalism around around
cannabis that the government maintains
you know Schedule one is a type of
fundamentalism the idea that there is no
safety under medical supervision there
is no accepted medical use I know
they're trying to talk a big game about
research right now the DEA even but you
know the maintenance of that idea is so
far off from what we know and I think
it's still very difficult to touch for
some of these mainstream organizations
right on that makes a lot of sense well
while you while you take a drink of some
water and rest your voice for a second
we're gonna do another commercial
we'll be right back you are listening to
shaping fire look inside this crystal
ball with me for a moment I'm looking
just a couple months into the future I'm
seeing the future of the shaping fire
podcast the show sure has grown
I've continued to interview fascinating
cannabis industry luminaries and our
audience has gotten huge it has doubled
and redoubled and doubled again there
are high-fives all around the shaping
fire world headquarters new listeners
are subscribing every day and begin to
listen to the back catalogue of all the
great interviews there and that is where
the shaping fire audience learns about
your company you were incredibly smart
today to become an early adopter and
place a commercial in shaping fires
early episodes if you become an
advertiser on the shaping fire podcast
now today you are going to pay a
fraction of the cost we will be asking
in just two months
and yet all the audience that listens to
our back catalog of interviews will hear
about your company again and again it's
a great deal for you pay a small amount
now because the show is so new but take
advantage of the huge listening audience
we will have forever this crystal ball
is not a smoke dream do yourself a solid
and contact us today for rates on
podcast and newsletter advertising email
hotspot at shaping fire calm to find out
more welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire I'm your host Shango Louis
and our guest this week is dr. Sunil
Agarwal so Sunil you know the show so
far has been so educational for me you
know the first part of the show we were
talking about the the epic history of
the plant and and our interaction with
it over the centuries and then the
second part of the show we were talking
about you know the Prohibition years and
and how the marijuana fundamentalism has
still got a hold on us but we're more
prepared now to learn from the plant and
how it can work with our endocannabinoid
system than at any other time in human
existence and that's you know that's a
really great message what I'd like you
to do now is you know open your mind's
eye and imagine a future where humans
are caring for their endocannabinoid
system with supplementation through the
use of cannabis and you know maybe
eating endocannabinoid system enhancing
foods you know what does that society
look like what did that what's the human
health look like of those people what's
our best-case scenario oh sure
well you know III think the important
thing is to recognize first and foremost
that there is a aspect of health aspect
of medicine an aspect of science that is
fundamentally cannabinol aaj achill you
know there is there is an a part of our
lives a part of our health that is so
critically governed by the science of
cannabinoids say knowing the science of
interaction with you know and through
which I mean from which arised or I mean
out of which came out of the study of
cannabis so the fundamental role that
the plant cannabis and had plays but it
goes beyond cannabis too because we've
we've found cannabinoids in other plants
and we have our own internal cannabinoid
signaling system which is even older
than cannabis itself if you look at the
evolution of that so this is a this is
an area I think should be called
cannabinol adji and you know I think it
it gets us to sort of recognize that ok
well if this is a central part of
biology that helps us regulate our
homeostasis and you know it's involved
in mood appetite memory inflammation
pain perception muscle tone
you know Berlin growth tumor regulations
stress seizure activity G
gastrointestinal function I mean it's
it's everywhere it's it's playing an
important role and I think if we
recognize that then we can start to
understand our health conditions a
little bit more deeply trying to see if
there is a dysregulation or a problem in
endocannabinoid system either in Oregon
or system-wide that might explain like
clusters I mean I think dr. Ethan
Rousseau who I know you're gonna be
before you know has really done a lot of
great work to start thinking seriously
about clinical endocannabinoid
deficiency syndromes and I think there
is a there's a lot to be said for for
that when you have certain clusters
around migraines interval irritable
bowel fibromyalgia and Dmitry osis and
probably many more we'll start to see as
we start studying on a molecular level
genetic
you know endocannabinoid tone and Oh
cannabinoid deficiencies we'll get a
finer grain understanding and you know I
think we was just so that part of that
is starting to recognize looking at the
health conditions through a cannabinol
logic lens and then recognizing that
well there's a there's ways that we can
can intervene or we can you know treat
people can inhabit illogically to make a
difference to restore the problems that
are you know the funded base line issues
that are impairing their health quality
of life and their and causing symptoms
and issues and I think there's it's not
just that it's also preventative health
side too but you know we saw that
there's two different branches there's
treatment of acute issues and then
there's making sure issues don't come up
so and and you know making you know
wellness so I think I think the the
first side of it would be where you
integrate cannabinol logic approaches
thinking and treatments into all
branches of medicines that are relevant
I think I think you know we talked about
oncology
I think neurology Rheumatology I think
those these are some of them and you
know pain medicine and palliative
medicine are some of the really and I
should also mention rehabilitation which
is my one of my central specializations
I think all of those areas are really
ripe for having a cannabinol logic
approach and I think we just so excited
to think about what that would look like
if we are starting to say okay you know
we're that's one approach that we are so
patients who go to clinics or you know
they're looking on there or they you
know they see their doctors or their
whatever allied health professionals and
they start seeing that those people
recognize there's a cannabinoid problem
at the basis of your oncologic
rheumatologic etc problem so let's see
if there's a way that we can boost your
endocannabinoids activity maybe with a
some ratio of botanical cannabinoids
extra whole plant extract and let's you
know see how that does for you and
luckily we've done some research on that
with people with just your condition and
we found out that you know one to one
ratio of THC to CBD within a whole
extraction makes a big difference in
terms of restoring that problem for you
I you know we've seen there's been
research that shows in multiple
sclerosis patients if they take a
one-to-one extract over time they have
they a walk better and they have less
emergency room visits and not to mention
better you know pain and spasticity and
that's been in double-blind
placebo-controlled studies so I just you
know I think it's just a matter of
translating what research we do have and
actually starting to roll this kind of
thing out so that people who have these
conditions know their providers know and
then the patients directly know and
there's something available for people
around the corner or in their in their
healthcare system where that's provided
for I really believe that local medicine
systems are an excellent way to go
because cannabis can be produced locally
and we can we can start to quantify and
you know make varieties and preparations
that everybody can understand and share
and use and I think ultimately you you
just have a also believe this a great
therapeutic aspect on the preventative
health side and the kind of
complimentary alternative side where
you're looking at the gardens and
growing green plants and and how people
can have more interaction with that if
that you know makes their makes their
days better their pain better their mood
better and I think that's a nice aspect
to it and then that also dovetails into
the preventive health side what does it
mean to use cannabis instead of alcohol
or what does it mean to use cannabis as
a tool for yoga meditation spiritual
pursuits you know a recreational therapy
well how does that you know how does
that impact overall quality of life and
stress which we know is a big part of
heart disease so I think that's you know
some of this is so hard to to envision
because you just we're still stuck in
this fundamentalism which keeps us keeps
the relationship with cannabis really
monopolized or a better way to say all
ago lop alized and only a few people
have a legitimate access and I think
whence we recognized and actually you
know this is a Commonwealth we all have
the right to access cannabis and also
have relationships with it not just with
consumption but production and I think
health therapeutic relationships should
be a forefront of that so whatever that
looks like to you I think there's a lot
of areas I mean I didn't even mention
like infections and diabetes and you
know heart disease stroke prevention a
dementia preventing and treating
dementia there's so many exciting things
that could be with the cannabinoids to
hold promise for and I'm just I think
that future is very bright we just you
know we just gotta like collectively get
off this fundamentalism and just do it
that's awesome I love that picture and I
can imagine how you know as as Canas
becomes less stigmatized and this
research that you're talking about is
happening more and more that what we're
going to be seeing is you know a
decrease of each of these different
categories of human ailments and just
less sickness across the board and you
know and that's really exciting and I'm
really glad that that you're able to
take time to be on the show today to
kind of put it all on this long timeline
so that we can really look at how human
health and the cannabis plant are
intertwined and I think that's where
we're gonna stop for today sitting out
thank you so much for being on the show
oh it's been my real pleasure Shango I
look forward to to hearing any feedback
from your listeners and please check out
my work at cannabinol adjust org right
on fantastic and so you can find out
more about dr. Sunil Agarwal on his
website which is Kanab analogous org and
that's c-a-n-n-a be i n oh l OG i st dot
org you can find more episodes of the
shaping fire podcast and subscribe to
the show at shaping fire calm and in the
podcast section of the Apple iTunes
Store and stitcher if you enjoyed the
show we'd really appreciate it if you
would leave a positive review of the
podcast wherever you download your
review will help others find the show so
they can enjoy it too
on the shaping fire website you can
also subscribe to the weekly newsletter
for insights into the latest cannabis
news and product reviews on the shaping
fire website you will also find
transcripts of today's podcast as well
for information on me and where I will
be speaking you can check out Shango
lowes.com does your company want to
reach our national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hotspot at shaping
fire calm to find out how thanks for
listening to shaping fire I've been your
host
Shango Lowe's