[Music]
cannabis seeds are not all bred the same
some are bred for indoor growing and
have little relationship to the
geographic area that are grown in
because they never actually interact
with nature other seeds are bred for
outdoor growing and historically have
come from California but nowadays as
cannabis is being normalized in breeders
have been able to come out of the
shadows and connecting groups we are
finding that each bio region is starting
to develop seeds that work best in their
own area where I live in the Pacific
Northwest on Vashon Island
we need genetics where the flower
finishes quickly and early before the
October rains start up until now that
has usually meant growing cultivars that
bloom for eight or nine weeks ending the
mid to end of October and we just have
to go in knowing that they probably
won't fully mature before the rain and
cold set in now though breeders are
bringing seeds to market that finishin
has fused 50 days putting harvest more
towards October first or even earlier
these new genetics open up outdoor
growing to a much wider range of home
growers who live in areas of the country
with shorter summers and to these
breeders we are eternally grateful if
you want to learn about cannabis health
business and technique efficiently and
with good cheer I encourage you to
subscribe to our newsletter will send
you new podcast episodes as they come
out delivered right to your inbox along
with commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week and
videos too don't rely on social media to
let you know when a new episode is
published sign up for the updates to
make sure you don't miss an episode
also we're giving away very cool prizes
to folks who are signed up to receive
the newsletter there's nothing else you
need to do to win except receive that
newsletter so go to shaping fire com2
sign up for the newsletter and be
entered into this month's and all future
newsletter prize drawings you are
listening to shaping fire and I'm your
host
Shango lows the intro to today's show is
gonna be a little longer than usual I
have two extra topics I want to cover
with you first I want to give my sincere
thanks to Zack Badgett for saving my
crew on our way to the can Illuminati
party on Saturday night of emerald cup
he and his buddy Brennan were following
the crappy driving directions that
Google Maps was giving out to the par
along their route they came across my
crew in our car that had gotten stuck in
the mud on an unimproved road where we
should not have even been in the first
place but Google Maps took us there not
only did the guys spend a good amount of
time trying to pull our car out of the
mud but Zach even went all the way and
used his triple-a membership to get a
tow truck out there which got us out of
the mud with no problem not only did
Zach offer to let us use his triple-a
membership but it meant that his good
time at the can Illuminati party was
interrupted a few times because he first
had to call triple-a and then go back
again and meet up with the tow truck
folks so thanks to both you guys and
especially thanks to Zach who gave of
his money and time to make sure that we
were okay and able to get to the party
instead of being stuck out in a field
somewhere due to bad directions I
offered to pay for Zach's triple-a
membership for the year in thanks you
know but he wasn't having it
he just asked me to let him know if I
heard of any really good hash jobs for
an experienced professional hash maker
well this is for you Zach if you
listeners have a legal cannabis business
that produces ice hash or hash rosin and
you want a trustworthy guy who is easy
to get along with and has solid
production skills I encourage you to
reach out to Zach Badgett on his
Instagram Duet his constellation
underscore carolina zach is based in
washington state right now but he is
willing to move for the right job he is
presently on the hash production team at
constellation cannabis if you follow my
Instagram you have heard me talk before
about how great their hash and hash
rosin carts are they know zach is
looking for a role with more
responsibilities so he said it was okay
if I tried to get him a job more
publicly with one of you great listeners
so thanks again Zach you are a shining
example of the cannabis community
looking out for each other when things
go bad okay
the other thing I want to do is to thank
those of you who have left the hundreds
of positive reviews of shaping fire
online where you get your podcasts you
know I'm usually so busy doing
interviews and traveling and just you
know doing life that I never really
looked at the reviews people were
leaving about the show
those reviews are really important in
order
to be seen so I'm really grateful for
anybody that leaves a nice review
wherever they get their podcasts over
the holidays I was reading some of the
reviews left on Apple podcasts and I
want to share just two of them with you
and thank the folks that left them so
first of all I want to thank case' del
77 who says well done there are a few
good cannabis podcasts out there but
Shango is possibly the best host and
that he asks good questions and isn't
afraid to let the guest talk for a while
without interrupting tons of knowledge
while still maintaining a laid-back
atmosphere for the guests and the
listeners well done Shango and then also
CB DNA labs says the best I don't have a
far commute to work but I wish I did I
have been looking for excuses to drive
for months because of shaping fire many
thanks to Shango and his guests for an
incredible podcast I have found answers
to questions I didn't even know I had on
every episode Bravo so you know hearing
this feedback is really inspiring so
thank you to everybody who left a review
today my guest is cannabis breeder NAT
Pennington founder of Humboldt seed
company that has been providing cannabis
seeds since 2001 and has been growing
cannabis professionally since he was a
teenager net is also a world traveling
biologist and fisheries expert who has
helped to defend the environment and the
rights of indigenous people in the
Amazon as well as pret his present fight
to restore salmon habitat in Northern
California today we're gonna talk about
breeding cannabis for short bloom cycles
as well as a bit on auto Flowers tissue
culture and genetic markers such at
breeding welcome to the show nat well
thank you so glad to have you here so
you know I've been aware of you for
years but I really only zeroed in on you
after your interview with Kevin Jo Durie
during the Wunderland nursery seed
series which shaping fire sponsored I
got to watch that interview and I'm like
oh man this guy's cool and he's got
depth and oh man I want to hear him a
lot more than 20 minutes so so I then
recently was checking out your new 2020
seed catalog and I saw these cultivars
with bloom cycles under 60 days and and
then you totally got my attention
because you know most of us outside
California do not have the same perfect
cannabis growing web
that you have there and we need shorter
bloom cycles and and you've bred flowers
as short as 45 days which is a godsend
when trying to beat those October rains
so up till now if I wanted to get
something under fifty days it was
probably going to be some kind of shish
kebob cross or something what inspired
you to start to cross and sift
specifically for short blooming flowers
yeah so you know we were obviously
humble is not what people commonly think
of when they think about California in
regard to whether you know we're not out
here you know we're in shorts and tank
tops all year round we have quite quite
an or Mille you know decent winter and
really October it gets a little
touch-and-go especially towards the end
when it comes to not only just like
having to avoid molds and mildew and
things like that but even like frost
depending what your elevation is and
humbled also is this area with terrain
and mountainous terrain and so yeah
anyway we definitely do breed for
shorter season flower or shorter
flowering type cannabis but I do have to
say that really initially that was an
inadvertent thing and you know we've
been breeding here at Humboldt seed
company for over 20 years so the story
of how we started doing shorter season
varietals is is unique and interesting
and it can I really dive into it yeah
yeah we want to hear it all right so for
folks out there that have done a lot of
breeding you may have noticed how
quickly cannabis
acclimate to your environment and I I
kind of think it's one of the more
malleable crops out there as far as you
know really changing even in the course
of a generation or two or I don't know
folks have noticed but like even clones
that obviously don't aren't you know
going through when they're propagated
they're not having genetic you know
cellular meiosis or whatever so even
clones I've noticed can have kind of
epigenetic changes and adjust to their
new indoor environment let's say or or
vice versa
so cannabis malleable species and what
what I found was you know basically our
breeding practices particularly back in
the late 90s and early 2000s were a
little bit more kind of you know we
weren't as as specifically directed or
focused and I say I can't really blame
you know that was sort of just right
after cannabis was legalized medically
in California and you know there it was
okay that we weren't exactly like the
most professional but um but you know
one of the things that we would do is
like we're making crosses with a popular
clonal variety that might be going
around Humboldt or you know as much as
as often as those as the clone crosses
we're finding these wonderful genetics
that have been you know kept alive in
the hills of Humboldt and seed form and
picking the best and making crosses from
those but one of the things when
breeding you know with regular seed
doing regular male-female breeding is
essentially you're waiting to find
find out what sex this lot of plants
that you're picking from might be so
let's just say I'm gonna round off
numbers to make this easier to
understand let's just say that we're
breeding our mango tree line and we
crack two hundred seeds and we're
looking at and this is back then we're
doing bigger populations these days but
we've got two hundred seedlings
in trays we transplant them up into a
you know five inch pot or a gallon or
something like that and now they're like
fifteen inches maybe a couple feet tall
so we're starting to like look at the
sex and determine you know really what
we would do is make sure that we had the
best-looking plants out of that larger
population and set them aside as our
breeding plants and we you know as males
were showing their sex as well we'd be
you know it's rubbing those stems and
looking at the structure and doing all
the selection that we do for males but
the reason I mean we were already we
already knew that we were really really
interested in breeding and I mean it was
only a few years later that we kind of
formalized that by going and getting the
you know the business humboldt seed
company down here and eureka at the
courthouse but and that was so so far so
long before you know we have like humble
farm and humble everything you could
ever imagine but this was like I was I
just felt so funny in the courthouse is
the ladies there and I was asking was
there a Humboldt seed company and she
like ah let me check in the databases
and stuff she's like no and I'm like
okay it I'm gonna be I'd like to start a
business of that humbled she says she
looks at me and what are you doing are
you doing and I just said I'm doing
vegetable seeds and just where's your
location and I gave her my address and
you're gonna sell it farmers market and
I said yes and I think at that time we
were we've always had different kinds of
seeds you know in reality my intention
was to have a cannabis seed company but
down there that day at the courthouse it
was it was just Humboldt seeds of any
kind so back to the point I knew we
wanted to Bree I knew that that was what
really interested me and so every year
the first priority was pick your
breeders and set them aside they're not
gonna be in the main garden area so pot
him up take care of them make him happy
you know then I'd go and later on I'd do
my whole breeding set up but set him
aside and really what I found over the
years is that had a huge effect on the
flowering time of the plants because
here I was looking and choosing for the
breeding population first and without
even thinking about it I was
inadvertently dude selecting for the the
ones that had that pre flower the the
way that we determine sex on on regular
plants without you know genomics which
you know I find to be relatively easy
it's it's hard for some folks I think
but you just just experiential knowledge
you know you get it once you see enough
little male parts and yeah becomes it
becomes really familiar to you and
male female male but I get where you're
going you were you were splitting up
these plans and so because you you were
naturally choosing plants because they
were showing early which means that they
were getting a business exactly so they
were the ones that they were the ones
that were probably you know that's a
relation and and it's a relation that
I've actually seen as tangible is that
really the ones that tend to you know
identify themselves as male or female
earlier on are also a little bit you
know the earlier flower but you're still
talking about a population so if you're
selecting out of your OG population
let's say or sour tea it's kind of those
kinds of things that are later flowering
well you're probably not maybe you won't
be able to sex the plants until mid-may
but some of these earlier flowering
types you can really sex um early on and
you know with the population that
eventually led into like varieties like
our blueberry muffin other earlier
flowering varieties at a point right
around you know 2006 2005 that six I was
like realizing because I had my own
experiences and a couple other of the
farms that you know would give a lot of
reports back about how our seeds were
performing would actually say you know
hey we're having flowering is happening
way too early and we're not getting as
much yield because you know so there's
this kind of perfect balance that we end
up striving for when it comes to
flowering time and and particularly you
know for those that are growing you know
in the natural photo period you know the
just growing in in full Sun without
light deprivation and things like that
and so but back to why we have more
quicker flowers flowering types than
then you know maybe some others have to
offer I think over the years that was
something that we kind of learned to
balance and really hone in on you know
what because I think everybody does
enjoy kind of having a quicker flowering
type of cannabis because you know
sometimes especially with things like
the Haze's and certain gosh certain
landrace rivals I mean we've met a lot
of growers that have grown a lot of
different varieties have had that plant
that you're you know showing your
friends at Thanksgiving yeah it comes
thing is like fifteen feet tall it's
just starting to flower it's
Thanksgiving you know I don't know I'm
gonna be harvesting this thing next year
literally and but so some things you're
never gonna make to keep the strain true
to form you know you can't change too
much about the flowering time but you
can certainly shorten it by a few weeks
I think in my experience and you know
that could be said for for a lot of
things like the classics like Sour
Diesel that tend to be a little on the
longer side for flowering you can still
you know keep something that is
recognizably Sour Diesel with terpenes
and structure and the high and maybe cut
off a couple weeks which is you know
that's so that's a that's that's
breeding right there I mean
you know that's that's improving
something that you know without I don't
feel like you know you're not
jeopardizing too much by doing that
you're really selecting within a
population and and you know everybody's
always grateful for that too because the
shorter the bloom cycle the less time
there is for something to go wrong right
I mean like one of the challenges with
these long I mean where I live on Vashon
Island in the Pacific Northwest
anything over eight weeks is we consider
long but you know you've got somebody
who's got a 12 week er it's like oh my
gosh you've got so much time to run into
potential pest problems that you're
gonna have to solve
during flower when your options are very
limited it's you know it's if you can
knock a couple weeks off of a long bloom
cycle it's it's to everybody's benefit
so long as the flower you know still
still comes out being the haze or
whatever that you're hoping it is now
now you were talking about for your
flowers that started blooming early does
that for you pretty much equate with
ending early too because you know you
might have something that that might
start flowering early but then it still
doesn't finish until the second or third
week of October which is really at the
at the end of reasonable for most of the
country it's really nice if not only if
that if it starts flowering earlier than
it than others but then it also drags
that finishing time forward to the end
of September - do you find normally that
that when you're doing these large sips
that the ones that are starting early
are also finishing early yeah and for
the most part I'd say that that is the
case so you know you're moving the
you're really just the flower time it's
not completely static I mean it is a
little bit dynamic and certain varieties
I'm sure folks have seen it you know you
basically flip the lights so twelve
12 and next thing you know if they go
yeah it just seems like you know within
a few days you're noticing the
difference and uh and then next thing
you know you've got significant flowers
put on which is I think that's really
what the goal is is to get that you know
initial chunk to start early enough and
so when you're working in indoors it's a
little bit easier to kind of see the
difference between that because when
you're doing outdoor of course if if
you're let's say up in Washington you
know the lights changing and certain
varieties will you know trigger into
flower earlier than others and that's
just you're essentially taking the
flowering cycle and moving it up a few
weeks and then of course the end gets
moved up a few weeks as well so I mean
that and that is effective for that goal
if you really want to avoid the problems
that are associated with having you know
big beautiful flowers out in the rain or
the freezing cold then that's completely
effective for that but I think that
there's another factor that we're also
considering which is just how fast the
flowers actually grow and how you know
how much of the plants energy is
strictly just getting devoted to putting
on flower weight versus continuing to
put energy into stalk and leaf growth
and you know I think a lot of the time I
do associate those earlier flowering
ones you know they kind of go all in on
flowering too which is I know we're
gonna talk about autos in a little while
but that you know for me I see I think
of it as kind of the difference between
annual and perennial plants and where
the the plant really is putting
it's energy at the time and for me you
know I think of it being a a fish
biologist for four years while I was
also reading and running the company
when I when I couldn't be as big of a
company I got to really know and
understand salmon and steelhead and an
interesting thing about salmon and
steelhead is that steelhead can live
after they reproduce so they can spawn a
number of times
whereas salmon just kind of you know
they have to expend all of their energy
into reproduction to swimming up the
river they pretty much stop eating and
then they reproduce but from a person
that you know also likes to fish and eat
salmon and steelhead I can tell you
right now that the best I think I really
enjoy the taste of the salmon because
you're having a this is a creature that
knows that it has to put a whole bunch
of energy into this one special moment
and when you harvest it if it's at the
right moment then you're essentially you
know that energy is kind of transferring
over and I think of that with with
cannabis and some of these shorter
flowering varieties are kind of like
salmon where they're just like okay we
know that this is the the time to go for
it and we're gonna throw everything we
have into basically you know what
they're trying to do which was reproduce
and we're getting in there and
harvesting it at this moment where the
plant is just full of of every you know
all life and and vibrant and you know
big chunky beautiful buds I think that
that interpretation of it is really you
know poetic if not spiritual because you
know you're you're talking about all
life having the
particular moment when it when it gives
its full expression of who it is in the
natural system and it and it puts it all
on and you're right some of these
shorter blooming flowers when they come
on they come on like gangbusters and I
think that's one of the things that
those of us who have the opportunity to
walk through gardens with you know many
plants lets you know you can do it with
you know five or six plants but let's
let's say 25 plants when you can walk
through and all these plants are
expressing themselves fully and and
we're looking at them and we're smelling
them and we're both the plants and us
are reacting to the Sun I think that we
can feel that energy that's going
between the Sun and the plants and us
and I think that's one of the reasons
that we are so in love with this plant
is because we can we can participate in
that at an energetic level exactly and
yeah and it's it's okay I mean we're
we're all creatures and we all you know
give and take from all the different
kind of life forces on the planet and
you know I'm a I'm an omnivore I'd I
love going out and harvesting broccoli
out of the garden and fishing and all
those things and it's you do you kind of
when you are harvesting something and
especially if you've put a bunch of
energy into it whether that's you know
growing tomatoes in your garden or
growing cannabis or you know taking care
of the wild world that you live in when
you're harvesting something like that
and you have that real connection with
it it's such a thing of beauty to you
know be so proud and hold that thing in
your hand and then you know go have a
stir-fry yeah I feel like that it's a
real it is it's it's super spiritual I'd
totally agree
so before we go to commercial because
we're a little over but I want to make
sure that we hit on something because
we've certainly talked about you know
how you moved toward growing these short
blooming types and it ended up being
kind of like just systemically you just
started getting shorter ones because of
how you worked your sips which is really
interesting and then we've talked about
like the you know the the energetic
expression of these plants but there's
also people who are listening who are
like meticulous breeders who are looking
for some kind of guidance from you of
how to do the selection so before we you
know since second set we're going to be
talking more about Auto flowers I want
to make sure that we get this in here so
would you explain to us a little more
like on the brass tacks like operational
level when you are doing your sips how
are you specifically selecting for short
bloom cycles and making sure that you
concentrate on those sure well you know
so I think I explained initially there
was some inadvertent sips that happened
in the spring where we were prioritizing
breeding and so choosing first the
plants that showed out of that group
we'd choose the best ones and you know
then set them aside so that led to all
of a sudden now if we do that every
single season every every time we're
breeding then holy cow we can actually
make things almost flower too early too
quick and and that was problematic in
like 2005-2006 right around that time it
it dawned on me that look we I have a
bunch of we're controlling this and so
now let's control for exactly what
farmers want which you know maybe that's
a fuel type that normally would flower
and mid to late October let's see if we
can get it to flower and finish you know
and admit mid to early October and that
actually really was easier than I ever
thought and so basically what we were
doing was just initially seeing which
one's happened to to show first and then
of that population putting that through
the other rigorous selection that we
would normally do to make sure that it
had the you know phenotypic expressions
the type of terpenes that we're looking
for and and then eventually you know
testing for cannabinoids and all the the
more detailed stuff that we have the
capability to do now but you know gosh
this has been a 20-year process and it's
incredible what we can do now with you
know genomic stuff and and even just
simple like lab stuff that we can
utilize but back then and and something
that still no matter how fancy the
equipment that you have access to I
wholeheartedly believe that ninety
percent of of any breeders work should
be basically a phenotypic selection and
or you know and the personal experience
of smoking and and all just stuff that
you don't really need that expensive lab
equipment for and that's something that
kind of equalizes this industry which
you know now we've got folks coming in
that have all the money in the world
suspend on all that lab equipment and
it's boy thank gosh that you really need
to know the plant to be able to do
proper cannabis breeding and the more
time and energy that you've spent with
plant the more that you understand how
malleable and how to to you know form
that in in a direction that you want
like let's say a quicker flowering type
plant the more years that you've got
under your belt the the better that the
easier that'll be for you but for folks
that really want to try that I it's it's
a couple things you know early on you
can really be effective by just doing
selection and noting which ones do show
sex earliest that is more powerful than
anyone would probably expect and it was
something that dawned on us years ago we
almost did too much of that we kind of
reversed it now we've learned how to
control it and then of course the next
thing is just you know looking at
flowering if the cool thing is is you
can do it real time you can say you know
this plant is flowering now I can see
that it's gonna finish up early I can
see that it's probably gonna avoid you
know the weather I know that's coming in
late October and this is the one that
I'm going to select to pollinate but
just you know make sure that you're not
compromising what you you know the most
important thing I think is the varietal
that you're going after and those traits
the terpenes and the structure if you
like beautiful buds which I love you
know frosty trichome coated buds that's
another important factor obviously not
to ignore but um you know sometimes
those things aren't necessarily exactly
related like that frosty us buds are not
always the ones that test highest for
THC D or whatever so you know I think
those those are all important things but
essentially you can you can change
things and I think as we go into this
Auto flower discussion
next I'm holding back on a few others
that I think are relevant to that too
because that's an obviously those are
you know I don't even want to say early
but it's it's a whole different animal
but there are what we call heterozygotes
which is sort of combinations of both of
those characteristics that pop up and
there are ways to take traits that you
like and in a photo period type and
transpose them on to the auto type or or
have a heterozygote which sometimes
lands right in the middle so so then
let's let's leave that there as a nice
little tasty bit to encourage people to
come back for second set and go ahead
and take our first short break you're
listening to shaping fire and my guest
today is nat Pennington founder of
Humboldt seed company one of the reasons
why no-till cannabis growing is so
valued by farmers is because the
mycelium networks in the soil remain
established from year to year and we
know these fungal networks are essential
because they are the nutrients
superhighways that extend far and wide
in the substrate to feed your plants
the trouble with growing in new soils or
blended cocoa substrates is that it
takes most of the plant's life just to
create these mycelium highways Dino
Michael endo mycorrhizal fungi inoculant
reduces that time and gets your plant
eating a wider array of nutrients faster
and it's three times the concentration
of the current leading brand in the u.s.
at 900 propagules per gram of to fungal
species selected specifically for
cannabis cultivation this new product
called Dino my co is the result of 30
years of research and trials at the
volcanic a Greek ultra research
institute in Israel it has also been
vigorously trialed by cannabis and food
growers across the u.s. since the
product first arrived here last year you
may have already even heard about
dynamite go by its original name
dynamite
now Dino myko is available at grow shops
and online in the United States for the
first time I'd
love using dynamite go to both speed up
the growth of mycelium networks in the
soil but also as a bio stimulant to make
clone cuttings more virile you can see
side by sides showing the comparative
growth on their Instagram at Dino Maiko
if you demand reliable growing results
and appreciate the importance of an
active root zone in creating a thriving
plant I encourage you to check out Dino
Maiko at Dino Maiko calm and find out
where you can get yours
that's dy n oh my co.com whether you are
starting with new beds or pots or if you
want to add some zing to tired soil
choose dynamite go to maximize your
plants potential Dino Maiko endo
mycorrhizal inoculants living soil and
regenerative cannabis agriculture are
surging in popularity and to implement
these biological solutions real science
education is vital if you are interested
in all things probiotic growing you will
probably want to attend this year's
science of organic regenerative cannabis
cultivation conference for the third
year in a row co-founders joshua
rutherford of dutch blooms and leighton
morrison of kingdom aquaponics have
lined up an incredible array of
educators with all new content for the
traveling event they're calling it
version 2.0 going deeper down the rabbit
hole
this year's teaching staff includes
Alain Ingham on soil biology Chris Trump
and Wendy Kornberg talking Korean
natural farming Kevin Jo Durie on
cannabis genetics Kelly and Josh from
dragonfly earth medicine Susanne
Wainwright the bug lady chip Osborne on
soil chemistry and many other thought
leaders rotating in and out for
different cities so consult the website
to knows who specifically is coming for
each location there will be a breeding
panel a QA panel with the entire
teaching staff and on Saturday night
there will be a bubble hash discussion
as well joshua has built in significant
informal time for you with the teachers
the teaching staff is just as excited to
work with you as you are about attending
there is also no advertising during the
event the only vendor booths are for
cannabis seed breeders your tuition is
what's paying the staff so they'll be
present and attentive to you not a
corporate sponsor even better the
conference is not just for folks on the
west
Humboldt California is hosting one event
for sure but the show is going on the
road to Vancouver British Columbia
Portland Maine and Whitmore Lake
Michigan get out your pen now because
I'm about to give you the website this
is a fabulous opportunity for you to
hear from an array of nationally
recognized top shelf soil educators all
in one place
not only that this isn't just beginner
stuff like you get at most conventions
this is an intensive for people like us
who totally nerd out on the rhizosphere
and growing and living soil and if you
attended last year be assured that this
year is not simply a repeat of last year
every speaker will present different
material than they did last year the
website is regenerative organic cannabis
calm that's regenerative organic
cannabis calm this year tickets will be
limited in a number to preserve the
intimate experience and will only be
sold in advance online
there will be no ticket sales at the
door so don't wait and miss out on your
chance to attend this important
gathering of the regenerative cannabis
community cut through all the
misinformation out there and don't miss
this opportunity to learn real soil
science regenerative organic cannabis
calm this message is for folks who grow
cannabis I'm talking to home growers
patients and commercial growers too I'm
probably talking to you when you plan
out your next growing cycle be sure to
check out Humble CSI seeds at Humble CSI
dot-com Caleb Inspectah and his family
have lived in Humboldt County for over a
hundred years for the last 40 years
three generations of his family have
cultivated extraordinary sense of Meah
cannabis in Humboldt Mendocino and
Trinity counties because of his lineage
and the hard earned experience that
comes from growing up smoking and
sifting large populations of cannabis
plants in Northern California the seeds
you'll cop from CSI will be winning
genetics based on longtime heavy hitters
and updated and Reese if today bring out
new and exotic traits and better yields
go ahead and ask around
Caleb also known as Inspectah and
Pirates of the Emerald triangle is a
breeders breeder he reaches way back and
works with significant strains
creating them in new and interesting
ways that you'll love is a toker and a
grower as well as offering you some
surprises that will delight serious seed
traders and cultivators Humboldt CSI
goes as further step and selfs
all these chemo VARs so you know all the
seeds will be female these are not
experimental feminized seeds Humboldt
CSI releases some of the best female
seeds available anywhere and it will
show in your garden folks grew quite a
bit of CSI humble gen-x last year here
on Vashon Island and everyone was
pleased the patients had beautiful
female plants and didn't have to call
half of their garden as males the folks
growing for the fun of getting high grew
colorful flowers with exceptional bag
appeal and great highs and breeders had
seven out of seven females in a pack
which gave them a lot of phenotypic
choices take a moment right now and
visit Humboldt CSI comm you'll find an
up-to-date menu of both feminized and
regular lines along with photos and
descriptions
that's Humboldt CSI calm welcome back
you are listening to shaping fire I'm
your host Shango lows and our guest this
week is net Pennington founder of
Humboldt seed company so during the
first set we were talking about short
blooming regular of seed varieties and
for a lot of people who are interested
in short blooming cycles people are
those same folks who'd be getting more
and more interested in OTO flowers
because they meet a lot of the same
needs for you know patients and home
growers and commercial growers who all
really need to get done and out before
before the bad weather starts well today
there's the second set here we're gonna
talk about Auto flowers so sown at you
know I know that you have got two Auto
flowers in your catalog this year which
tells me you've probably been messing
with them for a few years and you know a
lot of us get a lot of flack from
growers who like big cannabis trees and
these are a lot of the people who
respect you and and have liked the
cultivars that you've brought to market
and I'm a pretty public proponent for
Auto flowers for people with certain
needs you know what
has been your motivation to go ahead and
explore Otto flowers when you're when
you're you know when you've been serving
these other folks who like big trees for
so long well I do have to say that I
love big trees and that's been sort of
the classic uh Emerald triangle or even
like the kind of the whole north glass
so yeah you know we've been growing
trees for a long time and gosh back in
the days when it was you know we had
sort of these quasi guidance from from
the you know got state or whatever the
police that you know you could do 99
plants or whatever it was we it would be
like just a personal challenge like 99
trees make them as big as possible you
like with look at Google Earth that he'd
be like now is that at almond orchard or
a cannabis I can't really even tell but
uh yeah so you know I I miss those trees
because these days it's there's not a
much motivation to do things that way
there you have these you know rules
basically you've got square footage and
you can have as many plants as you want
inside of that square footage so
sometimes production does increase when
you know you're doing things that way so
Otto's I think in a lot of respects just
completely change the whole paradigm and
why did we start breeding them well I
think you know my top answer would be
basically it was curiosity that that
drove me to start playing around with
autos and I've learned that you know
even though humbled is obviously world
renowned for growing eighth grade
cannabis that
if we just think that we're doing it
perfectly well and we don't have
anything to you know that we could be
learning from others then that's you
know not gonna do us any favors so you
know got some auto flower seeds gave him
a try wasn't initially you know thrilled
like I and I that is the general
sometimes the the preconception or the
stereotype around them and so you know
look it was a challenge to say hey let's
maybe see what we can do and see if we
can change it and and I think as I
mentioned earlier I've always been
really amazed at how malleable that
species is how you know much of our own
influence we can have on the evolution
of the plants and things like that how
how they change for us and with us so
yeah autos it's really it's unbelievable
just with our own breeding projects and
looking at quite a few different auto
cultivars making crosses and then making
selections you know it only took two or
three years before I was I think last
year was when we came out with our first
you know fully endorse taught a line
that was in our catalog and available
for folks wherever but you know maybe
the year before that I we were kind of
test running some locally with friends
in the community and things like that
but you know last year people were happy
and this year we were able to refine
that you know during last year's
breeding process and now we've got to
varietals that were really really
endorsing and you know putting out there
then we made a bunch of seeds and the
test results weren't exactly what we
were you know
we were thrilled with but those are
available for folks who might want to do
you know I think it's that's kind of
like a big field that would just be for
biomass or something like that so yeah
I think there's a ton of potential with
a lot of flour and I think that that
we're going to be able to make that we
more conducive to what people expect
from cannabis these days so you know the
the thing a lot of people go for the
Otto flowers I mean you and I have
talked a lot about October weather and
how much it sucks at this point and one
of the things people love about him is
that you can you know start them earlier
in EM you know May or June and be done
by August or the beginning of September
and they they finish when it's bright
and sunny out they've got these kick-ass
terpene profiles and you know it's
interesting to experience it from the
growers side but I'm assuming that there
have there are some breeding intricacies
that you have to be aware of when
breeding the auto flowers that you don't
have to be aware of when you're breeding
regular seeds will you shine some light
on that yeah well you know one of the
things was that uh I mean a lot of
people that don't have a ton of
experience with autos are just like
don't realize that you cannot make
clones see you like our whole breeding
process where we do phenotype hunting
and you know take clones of fout I mean
last year in 2018 we literally looked
over 10,000 plants in this collaborative
phenotype hunt effort and we're able to
take caught
it's off of every single one of them
while they were you know still in a
vegetative form preserve them and mark
them from the field to the clone tre and
it was a huge effort I'm we may do it
again this year we we actually only
ended up doing 2500 but you know that's
still really significant and I feel like
we kind of were able to focus even more
on those so we did kind of the same
result from a little bit of a smaller
batch but you can't do that with autos
so when you're breeding audit because
they'll just there's no veg there or
there is veg but there's notes taking a
clone and keeping that strain in veg so
that you can you know have it kind of
permanently you know you couldn't put an
auto flower into tissue culture for
example because it would you know flower
inside the tissue culture and to be
ridiculous so there's a whole bunch of
different breeding constraints but you
know you can also cycle through breeding
generations quick very quickly because
you know you've only got three menthe
you only have to wait three months
before you might have your next
generation and and you may have made
significant improvement in that period
of time so we look at it differently
where we're really doing more of kind of
this traditional breeding that people
have done for years with things like you
know corn and Mendel's pea plants and
it's neat because you can utilize a lot
of those methodologies and not kind of
confuse yourself with you know keeping
things clonally and breeding with them
but I do have to say there are
advantages to being able to select one
clone out of 10,000 plants and then
breed with that I mean without a doubt
that gives you a huge advantage
and allows you to progress really
quickly in developing the trait
expressions that you are looking for so
you know will we get autos that are
comparable or you know maybe even
superior to photoperiod type varieties I
think so and I think in a lot of ways
the advantages that you get of having a
quicker turn over potentially might
almost equal out with the the
disadvantages of not being able to
choose but it may take a little while
before we're able to make things that
are quite as uniform in their very
specific expression so you know if
you've got a field of a few thousand
Auto flowers and you're pollinating and
you're going out there and now you're
choosing the very best one out of that
field you're not able to take a clone of
it and keep that and then you know put
like basically cross either sell fit or
cross into it and and create like a
really stable homozygous line for those
specific traits but you know you can
actually have a big field like that and
you can hone in on one plant and then if
you are pollinating you can select the
seeds from that plant and then you've
got at least a population that you 100%
know you know is likely to display that
trait that you're you know the the
attractive trait that you were after
maybe you know at least 25% of the time
and then if you back cross it again
you're gonna get 50 and so on and so
forth so
if that makes sense yeah it does and
it's interesting to to hear you talk
about you know the traits that you're
trying to lock down because you know a
lot of folks complain about autos that
there is so much variety I mean actually
I mean people complain about a lot of
things right number one that there's
smaller plants number two that there's
you know more phenotypic variety number
three that maybe they don't have the
same quality terpene profiles as some
reg seeds and it's interesting if that
those complaints don't apply to all auto
flower seeds but they certainly apply to
many if not most because we're still in
the early days of auto flowers and
they're they're they're very useful for
particular types of patients and for
particular home growers and for
particular commercial folks but they're
not for everybody nor are they designed
that way but here's my question for you
you know one of the things I like about
you is that you don't just have all of
your staff in the front of your booth
selling seeds you are there yourself and
you're talking to your customers and you
are your you're explaining them how the
seeds are gonna work best for their life
so you've spent you know some shows now
selling these auto flower seeds what is
the response that you are seeing from
people who are looking for auto flower
solutions do you think that enough
people know about them now that as
somebody who makes seeds and puts them
out to the people that people are coming
to you and going hell yeah Auto flowers
are you seeing that yet or is this
mostly just heads still uh you know I'd
say it's a little bit of a mix basically
we're seeing folks that a lot of it is
folks that are you know looking to do it
an industrial type cannabis agriculture
in California and you know it's I think
that it's going to change things a lot
the way that that autos allow
plants eh
one of the really things I think it's
really positive about it is I think it
does have the capability of reducing the
environmental impact and don't get me
wrong I don't believe that cannabis has
very much of an environmental impact
because you know compared to the big AG
that we have in the Central Valley is
you know a lot I mean it's gotten this
kind of misplaced stereotype as in
especially here in Humboldt for some
reason and and I would have been a part
of the Humboldt environmental movement
my entire adult life and can honestly
say that there has been a major impacts
that you know pre cannabis that are
still you know not healed up but I'm
always looking for ways to lessen impact
and I think Otto flowers is a good way
to do that particularly in places like
the Central Valley where there actually
is a major shortage of water and we do
have wildlife that's suffering and
teetering on the brink of extinction so
that's like really good outcome of of
Otto flower types I think for the
hobbyist grower that people have more of
an opportunity to be able to grow
cannabis because we're bringing this
Otto flower trait into the mix because
you know you can put it in a small pot
even if you live in an apartment and if
you have a balcony and actually still
harvest your own cannabis which I love I
mean as much as we're a company that
does service you know this growing
industry which I still you know think of
as a community but there's no doubt that
that there is an industry that's
developing and you know we do service
that but what I really enjoy most about
what we do is interacting with small
farms and hobbyists and you know like
grow your own kind of people and we have
quite a few people that are that are
experimenting with autos and and having
a really good experience just in their
backyard
even in the coastal climates and humble
it it's a totally different story
because you know there actually are
there is a period of time here in
Humboldt on the coast where humble it's
famous for cannabis but that's like the
inland is where that has always come
from but we have this fog layer and in
the urban area of Humboldt which is like
really where most of the population is
it's not the greatest place to grow
cannabis because we get fog every day
that's why we have redwood trees and
things like that and but people you know
it's Humboldt so people still love
cannabis so they're here you know
growing it and we love that we can now
offer them something that they can
harvest in late July or early August
when Humboldt is actually at its
sunniest and they have a great
experience with it which is what we want
we want folks to have a good experience
and an even endure to you know you can
leave your lights on 24 hours if you
want and our Auto flowers will still
flower and you'll still get bud and so
while you know you're still kind of
using a similar amount of electricity
you know maybe you're using a little
less water and you're not taking up so
much space for so long and you're
probably kind of increasing the amount
of flower that you're getting
for that electricity that you're putting
in so yeah I think it is advantageous in
a lot of ways and yeah and using that
particular example about the the having
the lights on you know whether it be 16
18 or 24 hours one of the theses of
feedback I get back from people all the
time like oh it just turned my veg room
into a room that yields flour like like
had all this extra room in my bedroom
and and now people can actually run
autos there and certainly that helps
with resources more than more than
anything it's a huge advantage to the
grower yeah
and you know you're planting from seed
every time which you know that
alleviates the need to have you know a
whole nother space to keep moms alive or
also it alleviates the need to bring
genetics to and from - I mean you know
all people I say cannabis has been
sprayed with a lot of pesticides well I
don't necessarily think that's the case
I mean I know for a fact that the
standards that were held to here now in
California and in most legal you know
with licenses and all that stuff you
literally there's no other agricultural
crop in the world that is as clean as
what we produce because it goes through
the most rigorous testing in the world
they have baby formula that isn't as
pure as our cannabis but anyway you know
it's growing from seed not having - when
when there were problems with pests it
was just basically because you know
essentially somebody ground a good cut
they shared it with their neighbor and
their neighbors shared it with the other
person and and so on and so forth and
and undoubtedly one of those people
might have had a infestation some bugs
and
and then those bugs hitched a ride over
to the other place and so on and so
forth and so that was like how we spread
pests and pathogens historically in the
cannabis industry and you know of course
some people were willing to compromise
there maybe their morals or maybe they
didn't have the greatest one morals
they're spray these really nasty things
on it and so because autumn flowers
there's really no you're not never gonna
or you're much less likely to take a
plant from one grow to another grow
you're just more likely you're just
gonna sprout some seeds right inside
your growth and that's there's all the
much less likelihood of getting
something from another you know passing
around these pests and pathogens so I
actually really like that you know i've
been i've been talking about autos for i
know better part of a year now maybe a
little more than a year talking to
people about it push them and i had
never really considered that they're
more hygienic because we're not moving
our cuts around as much because they're
all from seed that's a really good point
yeah absolutely and you know i think we
were starting to talk about cannabis and
the specie outs of a malleable species
and you know I sometimes don't love the
terminology of plant breeding in and
biotech terminology but what you say is
that you're improving you know this is
an improved varietal over what it was
before and you know don't get me wrong
like I love landrace I think we have to
preserve seeds we can't let these
classic and original cannabis varietals
disappear that's why we keep like a
really really robust seed bank here and
humble and there should be that kind of
an effort everywhere but you know we are
basically still improving things for
what what it is that we want to see and
if a plant that just flowers no matter
what you do if and it starts flowering a
month after you sprout the seed and then
lo and behold the flowers are just about
finished after 90 days from sprout to
finish or even shorter sometimes and if
that is something that really gives
certain advantages like the ones that
you just discussed I mean they might be
good for just getting more weed they
might be good for the environment they
might save money and energy or maybe
they're cleaner I don't think there's
anything wrong with that
and particularly you know I'm not
talking about going in and splicing
genes or even editing them with CRISPR
or something like that I'm just talking
about real traditional breeding
practices where basically I mean that's
how we got all of the food just about
that we enjoy today like the things that
we grow at least and you know that's
gonna happen and I think it's it's a lot
of fun to be a part of that plant you
know and seed improvement and with autos
I've it's it's crazy how I've just been
able to see you know taking an auto
flower and crossing it with you know
like a stream we did last year we have
this vanilla frosting strain and it's a
higher THC one and it's got this
beautiful smell and you know really
attractive strain and you know we're
moving that towards being an auto flower
strain just by crossing it with similar
types of autos and it's happening
quicker than I ever expected so you know
it won't be long before we're able to
say look here's this auto flowering
version of strains that we've all come
to know and love and it shouldn't really
there's there's nothing that says that
it has to compromise the things that
we've come to love about those strains
you know it doesn't like your fur
blueberry muffin we're also working on a
blueberry muffin OTO and it has this you
know it's a strain that we created in
2008 or way back and it really smells
just like blueberry muffins and it's got
pretty purple color and you know a lot
of really nice traits about it and and I
don't think there's anything wrong with
trying to make that so that you know
someone could get some seeds and plant
them and maybe do it on their balcony
early in the year mid May and then the
next thing they've got they just you
know plant it on their balcony and they
can use the little railing as a trellis
then have their friends over and show
them the plan it's a lot of fun harvest
and and then they've got something that
they've you know created themselves and
I think everybody kind of you know who
enjoys that more like I've always had
kids around in my life and you know kids
it's hard to get them to eat their
vegetables right and so we I would
always have a garden and I always found
that if you get the kid out there and
they're the ones that planted the
cauliflower or even worse the brussel
sprouts
and you know now it's harvest time and
you get them out there and they get to
be the one that harvests it and
everything boy do they love Brussels
sprouts when they bounce and you know I
think that's it's funny because when we
first started you know really having a
decent distribution for the seed company
here you know I would be really critical
in myself and and of our genetics and we
like I've always been right here in
Humboldt County and I always felt like
oh man and of all the places too you
know if someone's gonna think you know
know that these seeds aren't good or
whatever reason it's gonna be Humboldt
ian's because they they know what to
expect and what maybe didn't work out or
whatever they're gonna tell you so so so
when breeding these auto flowers you
know one of the odd things about is that
your you need to take your your cultivar
that you that you're you know you want
to emulate if you will and and you're
more usually just crossing into a
ruderalis so that you can get that Auto
flower tendency but then a lot of people
are concerned about the the taste of the
ruderalis which is you know not usually
awesome really tamping down the flavor
of the of the you know cultivar that
you're you're trying to make auto have
you found that to be like especially
challenging or is it like add now you
just take some time and effort well I
think that that is a really good point
and I but I think that it's a little bit
outdated and there's nothing wrong with
that so if people are listening out
there they're like that's what I think
I'm like look I totally get it but and
since we were working with just like low
rider some of these original auto flower
genetics that are really clearly you
know kind of a subspecies of cannabis
because people always say there's like
ruderalis and there's Steven in to come
and I think we all know that there's a
lot more to it than just that but if
that is the defining characteristic of
ruderalis then to me that is just the
defining characteristic and I've seen
firsthand that you can completely and
totally isolate that one trait which is
I'm gonna flower literally a month after
I germinate and I'm gonna start going
towards flowering and and I'll be done
in three months rather than whenever you
know two
months after the light changes to 12:12
or the photoperiod type so I I do
believe that really that is a a trait
that you can absolutely isolate and you
don't necessarily need to bring some of
the more negative connotations to
ruderalis along with that so but that
involves a lot of selective reading and
you know essentially if you cross a
complete reader Alice with a blueberry
muffin then you're gonna have a whole
bunch of progeny and some of them are
not going to be ruderalis or auto flour
type some of them are not gonna be they
will be but they won't be blueberry
muffin at all they'll be more you know
what you started with the auto flour
look which you know stereotypic
description might be lar fear and that's
like the Humboldt word but loose loose
flowers and you know not very crystal e
and just not dank so you know you don't
necessarily know my only have 15% or
even only like 5% that really captured
they that you just carried that one
characteristic which was the three-month
start to finish and then took on and
carried the characteristics that you do
appreciate about blueberry muffin and
obviously that'll be the one that you'll
do your breeding with or you know it's
Auto far so you don't have a cool you
can't do the clone breeding so you've
hopefully that one has seeds in it
hopefully that the pollinator that you
chose had also had those characteristics
but it's it's a you know it that's
that's where you can probably get
there's a lot of advantages to molecular
marker-assisted breeding which i think
we're going to talk about a little bit
later but you know you can you can and
we do and we have done that just through
selective breeding traditional breeding
practices and and looking at the plants
phenotypic expression but i mean the
advantage is that we've essentially
devoted all of our farms to breeding and
selections and we've got these isolated
areas where we do have the pollen that
we you know us assume or best-guess
pollen is in the air and so when we're
going and doing selection and looking
through these populations that that are
have received seeds then we are able to
be you know to deem this one the best
expression the one that captured the
most ideal traits of of the set of
traits that were working with and it's
got to be such a relief to get there
after all that extra work so i want to
talk more about actually you hit on a
whole bunch of stuff the blueberry
muffin the the genetic markers and
tissue culture i want to talk about all
that more but let's do it after this
next set break you are listening to
shaping fire and my guest today is nat
Pennington founder of humboldt seed
company cultivators who grow in living
soil are very particular on what inputs
they use in their soil they educate
themselves and painstakingly create
compost and nutritive teas to create
thriving soils that will produce the
very best expression of the cannabis
plant many living soil farmers now
believe that over time seeds become
acclimated to the kind of substrate they
are grown in for example a seed that was
bred and synthetic fertilizers may not
immediately know what to do in a living
soil environment slowing their growth
and decreasing yield the regenerative
seed cooperative is a different kind of
seed bank the regenerative seed
cooperative only provide
cannabis seeds that were bred in living
soil and using probiotic growing
techniques that way when you germinate
in soil the seeds genetics will
recognize the environment and
immediately start interacting with
microbes and fungal networks these seeds
are described as bio intelligent the
number of cannabis breeders
participating in the regenerative seed
cooperative is rapidly increasing
already signed on our bamboos stalk and
bean pacific northwest roots ello s
Gardens dragonfly earth medicine ital
foundation Bob hemp pills cricket and
cicada Dutch blooms heart Rock Mountain
Farms pride of Lyon Sebring seeds and
Mount Baker highway with more being
added every month these seeds are
regulars Auto flowers and hemp varieties
a significant amount of the profits go
to cannabis seed preservation projects
available to everyone do you want to
take every advantage that you can when
growing in beautiful healthy soil then
consider buying your seeds from the
regenerative seed cooperative at
regenerative seeds calm that's
regenerative seeds calm growing cannabis
in greenhouses is taking over the
cannabis industry an efficient and
effective blend of sunshine grown
terpene profiles and the controlled
environment of indoor greenhouses can be
the best of both worlds for many
greenhouse operators though building
their green house before gaining insight
into how cannabis greenhouses differ
from ornamental crops can be the start
of a world of hurt Eric Branstad and his
team at greenhouse advisory group have
the experience and technical know-how to
help you avoid these pitfalls Eric
Branstad has been helping cannabis
growers find locations design build and
equip their greenhouses for over a
decade first starting in Northern
California but expanding over the last
five years to helping clients throughout
the world he has an impeccable
reputation for both depth of knowledge
and kindness and communication you can
hear Eric explains some of the
challenges facing cannabis greenhouses
and how to overcome them in episode
number forty one of the shaping fire
podcast no matter where I go in the
country good people with smart
backgrounds still are making the mistake
of building without knowing cannon
and it causes them to burn through
capital and time fast everyone has their
own failure point for some it is
improper ventilation planning for others
it is surface temperatures of the
building or the plants leaves or both
some folks that build their greenhouse
from scratch make really basic errors
like placement of the greenhouse on the
property or not understanding the
natural environment where the greenhouse
sits
some have even built a decent greenhouse
but are inefficient in their deployment
of light deprivation techniques and
never really hit their target yields
it's great when you learn from your
mistakes but it's even better when you
learn from the mistakes of others when
you bring on greenhouse advisory group
you will learn from the mistakes of
their many clients and you'll take
advantage of the best practices
developed by Eric Branstad over his
years of working with clients just like
you from location development to
choosing a builder and tricking out your
new greenhouse or retrofitting or
rescuing your failing greenhouse Eric
will help you through it
visit greenhouse advisory group com to
learn more and connect with Eric and his
team that's green house advisory group
did you know that shaping fire has a
fabulous YouTube channel with content
not found on the podcast when I attend
conventions or speak or moderate panels
I always record them and bring the
content home for you to watch the Shango
Losey youtube channel it has world-class
speakers including kevin Jodrey of
wonderland nursery talking about
breeding cannabis for the best terpene
profile nicholas Mamun on regenerative
and poly culture cannabis growing dr.
Sunil a girl on the history of cannabis
medicine around the world Ben Cassidy of
true terpenes on using terpenes for
health in your everyday life Reggie
Godinho of steep hill on the cannabis
genome and Jeff Lowen Fell's on the soil
food web
there are several presentations from dr.
Ethan Russo on terpenes and the
endocannabinoid system and even my own
presentation on how to approach finding
your dream job in cannabis and why we
choose cannabis business even though the
risks are so high as of today there are
over 100 videos that you can check out
for absolutely free go to youtube.com
forward slash Shango 'lose or click on
the link in this week's newsletter
welcome back you're listening to shaping
fire I'm your home
Shengo low sunnirai guest this week is
nat Pennington founder of humbled seed
company so now I'm really glad that we
finally got to this part of the show
where we can talk about the blueberry
muffin cultivar more because holy hell
man it is crazy how exactly it smells
and tastes just like that jiffy
blueberry muffin mix in the blue box
when I first smelled it at noontime
medicinals in Garberville it was like a
time machine back to my mom's kitchen as
a kid what was your reaction when you
smelled that very unique terpene profile
for the first time in your sift yeah so
the way that that happened was really
interesting because it wasn't me or
really anybody who was totally in the
company that that pointed that out it
was just a trimmer that we had and you
know it wasn't somebody that that were
really close with but we had been
working on this cross and this was
really the first year that we grew it
out with you know looking through twenty
or so different plants and one of them
did come out just amazing and we had all
kind of had our eye on that plan we were
a special one right there
but it was a you know late September
night the plant was done earlier than a
lot of the rest of them and we're up
there in the field and were harvesting
and he's right across on the other side
of the plant and he just harvests a big
old Cola and says man I can't believe
this smells exactly like a blueberry
muffin you know that blueberry muffin
mix and I said no kidding you're
absolutely right and you just named that
strain and we always had a like an
ongoing strain naming little thing
within our group where you know you get
like prizes and things like that if you
end up naming a strain so he got the
prize for the year and that was that but
you know I knew that that that you know
it was
born unfortunately we did have clones of
it because that's something we've been
doing for a long time we always started
taking clones maybe in you know early
2000 mid-2000s of every plant that we
put up in our field and we were growing
these trees so it wasn't like that much
to keep track of it was manageable and
we got to see the full expression of
them so it was worth that for but the
blueberry muffin then you know we just
back cross and back cross into it and I
think it was like 2010 that we were
finally able to you know feel confident
that the seeds should carry that
expression of the blueberry muffin kind
of jiffy mix thing and I don't always
say jiff you make but you called it and
I don't know if we've ever even talked
about it before but well it's blatant
you can't be like you can't not not like
like if you have any experience with
that and I dare call it cheap right like
that cheap blueberry muffins smell
because the boxes are only like you know
whatever a dollar a box to get this
muffin mix and and and that's the odd
thing is like yeah there are smells of
blueberry in you know across lots of
phenols right or not me more than four
you know scold cultivars but this very
particular version of the blueberry
smells just like that box and it's and
it's unlike anything else and and
everybody who smells a jar of it that's
their first response yep exactly it
people do you know note that it's that
sort of artificial blueberry muffin and
and I don't I don't mind because that
was what we were really you know that
was what we were honing in on was the
the jiffy mix so you nailed it right
there it's it's totally I'm not saying
that it smells like organic blueberries
put in whole wheat flour muffins baked
at home and no no it's totally it's it's
it's more of a a breakfast cereal
blueberry versus a organic muffin
blueberry you know
exactly right look they're pellets
they're not bluebird yeah so so that's a
good story about the trimmer fine it and
bless their hearts oh you know I have
come across two different she knows of
it there is most of them seem to be like
this purplish green color which is very
beautiful but then the one that I saw in
all of these gorgeous hugelkultur at
moon time medicinals in Garberville they
happen to have the the pur purple Fino
which I'm not sure if it was you or your
daughter who commented on my Instagram
where I posted a picture of this
this Cola that was like the size of my
forearm and the entire thing is purple
there's there's you know very little
green actually on it and and the comment
that that y'all made was it was like wow
this is this is one of the purple ones
most of them are green but they all got
the same smell how often do you come
across that that purple Phoenix I would
think that that's the one that you know
regardless of the other attributes of
the plant people probably really
freaking dig the fact that they've
they've got a fully purple plant yeah so
you know the original ones that we were
kind of the the cuts that we've
preserved and things like that they've
sort of had this purple but not the dark
dark dark purple but kind of a mottled
flecks of purple and and that is really
the target one you know one thing that
I've noticed is one of the harder things
to create complete uniformity in in
cannabis is the level of anthocyanin or
purple that you get in your flowers and
you know that's been somewhat
problematic because as we are now
breeding for folks who need to put
together a big batch of a specific type
and they do want to grow from seed you
know having strains that have different
levels of purple can be problematic
because
then you might end up with a plant
that's a little bit on the darker side
or or you know or more green and you
know I always kind of caveat with like
well that can happen too
I don't know if you've noticed but I've
seen that plants that receive more light
can be a different color than the other
side of the plant it's the same plant
but you know it has some darker buds on
one side lighter buds on the other so
there's really no way to have complete
and total uniformity in it and that's a
good thing in my opinion I like that but
um you know I think with blueberry
muffin basically we've shot for kind of
this you know purplish green kind of
look to it and that's what we've been
going for and hopefully uh most people
are finding that trait well it's it was
delightful so so let's talk a little bit
about about tech assisted breeding so
because I know that you have moved into
that direction and while you know many
of the corporate cannabis companies are
using tissue culture you're one of the
few authentic California heritage
breeders who started to experiment and
kind of judge it for its relevance what
are your impressions so far of tissue
culture and are you finding it useful or
just something to mess with you know I
don't know if I want to I don't think
that it's I mean it does take some setup
you have to buy a hood you have to kind
of have a laboratory essentially to do
tissue culture I don't know if everybody
who's doing it is you know kind of
totally corporate or anything like that
but I think that it certainly is
attractive to investors because it's
really you know kind of sounds high-tech
and you figure how that's a really good
way of must be a good way of doing
things because you know like we talked
about before you hear about pests and
you hear about pathogens in the cannabis
industry and and pesticides and pests
testing whether or not someone really
uses pesticides you know they can just
be growing on some ground that either
has a AG operation nearby and even
though most of my new amount can make
you fail a test and so it is a big deal
so I don't want to say it's not what we
found with doing tissue culture in 2015
and 2016 was you know we kind of
expected to have a lot of advantages
from it like you know okay we could
build a library of genetics that we like
working with it would be much easier to
keep those genetics kind of alive and
well happy in tissue culture and and be
able to pluck them from the shelf as we
decided we wanted to use them for
breeding and and really that is like one
of the most useful applications of
tissue culture in my mind in cannabis
because you know cannabis is an an
annual crop and it it's a fast growing
crop that in most agriculture would
immediately go to like this is a crop
that we're gonna propagate with seed and
you know we already used clone and
that's to deal with often the
male-female was I think a lot of why
that developed so much and then of
course the uniformity of the you know a
clone is always going to be as uniform
as it can be because it's genetically
identical but tissue culture you know I
I think it definitely has its place I
our experience with it was that it would
be unbelievably costly to actually use
it to propagate so you know if you're
kind of a company that's a nursery and
you're wanting to sell thousands and
thousands of individual plants that are
rooted and ready to go if you were to
to actually really pull those directly
from tissue culture and then you know
basically plants that are in tissue
culture are very small often and so you
either have to root them whether in
tissue culture or pull them out and then
root them which is really hard because
they're you know there's the tiny little
X plants and that's tricky so it's it
doesn't seem like to me like it works
for mass propagation but and I think
most folks that have gotten into doing
it I've kind of realized that but it's
wonderful for cleaning up individual
genetics and then once you've got the
genetic pathogen free and completely
pest free obviously you're then able to
maybe maintain a very clean nursery so
if you're you know I kind of tend to
think if you're doing TC and then just
bringing the plants out of TC and then
propagating them in a in a nursery that
maybe is partly outdoors or has a lot of
ventilation or whatever that you're kind
of negating all of the all of those
benefits that you're getting from tissue
culture but but if you're you know
cleaning something up there's been a lot
of talk and research done recently on
something called the hot plate and
diploid virus which is a k otherwise
known as duh ting and you know like dark
heart nursery has you know basically
developed a cure for that which I don't
we didn't really have that before but
they secure involves putting the plants
through tissue culture and and really
only taking that apical meristem which
is millimeter like even smaller piece of
plants and I can't know if I'm supposed
to say exactly but there's a little
process that that they put that piece of
meristem through and then from there you
know they've seen using pea
er which is like a genetic you can pose
a question like is this carrying this
pathogen and polymerase chain reaction
or PCR will give you an answer yes or no
and they put it you know through that
test before the process and it the
answer is yes and then go through apical
meristem tissue culture and the process
that they add to that and then the
answer is no so those are things that
are amazing that capabilities that
tissue culture has but is it a a
cost-saving way to do propagation I
would have to say probably not that's
one of the things I'm noticing
throughout our chat here today is a lot
of this stuff you get into not because
you necessarily need it for your
breeding because you've been breeding
for you know you learned breeding
old-school-style which took a lot of
time and a lot of effort and a lot of
listening to the plant and being with
the plant and the in the garden and now
we've got all these new technologies to
assist and you know some of them are
more helpful than others but it's your
curiosity that has you messing with all
of this stuff so so I'm gonna ask you
similarity are similarily are you
starting to experiment with a genetic
marker assisted breeding and like a lot
of people confuse it with like GMO right
it actually genetically modified plants
that that are you know been used with
CRISPR or something but that's incorrect
it's more like an analysis to read the
genome so how are genetic markers
helping you to do traditional breeding
more successfully yeah so we are doing
some genetic marker assisted breeding
and you know a bunch of people are
gasping but like the the distinction is
so important and and I'll just get out
ahead of that right now hopefully and
say that you know Humboldt seed company
is very work actually scared that
that there is so much biotech interests
in this precious plant that you know we
feel like has this wonderful amazing
cultural significance in humanity we've
evolved with it it's so important and I
know for a fact that folks are out there
doing both genetic engineering and
genetic modification and genetic
engineering is CRISPR which you
mentioned before where you can just you
know you just change the code of a plant
you can like knock out cannabinoids for
example you could say I don't want any
CBD in this plant I'm taking that code
out or ad code even but genetic
modification more like bringing DNA from
another species and splicing it in and
both of them essentially that's
engineered cannabis or modified cannabis
and we at Humboldt seed company a
hundred percent support or we're
actually pushing right now for
legislation in California to have
mandatory labeling for any cannabis that
is modified or engineered and we feel
like this is incredibly urgent we're
trying to get support from people and
I'll caveat that with we're not like
coming out and saying that we think that
it should be banned I mean even if we
did I don't think that that's something
that it's likely because we've seen
what's happened with food crops and
we've seen what's happened with even
animals now it it hasn't gotten a lot of
traction because there's certain things
that the genetic engineering and
modification can actually it could save
lives it could you know that's another
argument I don't want to get into it but
what we're saying is that we want
cannabis to be mandatory to have it
labeled and especially when that comes
to genetics because
what we see coming is these cultivars
getting out into the breeding community
cannabis is different than any other
plant in the world I would venture to
say people [__] love breeding
cannabis they love smoking it they're
more interested in cannabis than I mean
think about it like what other plants
are there I mean I know there's a bunch
of people that are really into breeding
dahlias I know that all kinds of species
are there's a community around them it
still pales to cannabis it pales it
totally pales so this is really
important like let's we I think we've
lost that opportunity with our food
because I don't know if you're aware
like Mendocino a few years back did get
a county ordinance through that banned
GMO and but you know there was no way to
enforce it like you go to Chevron in
Laytonsville and it's all GMI so there
it wasn't an enforceable or a realistic
thing as much as what we're trying to do
right now which is just simply say look
cannabis is something that hasn't really
been engineered or modified so before it
just gets completely you know away from
us and we couldn't ever keep track let's
just say you know we're not gonna stop
big biotech from doing what they're
doing we don't even know whether we're
opposed to it or not or maybe we'll
participate it sometimes on the road
like I'm not saying that I have either
you know I don't ever want to see it
happen I'll never participate or I I
love it I'm working on it right now I
mean we're not but but I do think that
it deserves that we deserve and that
this community deserves to know what is
and what is not genetically engineered
or modified right
back to what you asked me about so the
genomic marker assisted breeding is a
different thing entirely and that just
means so basically like I did a bunch of
studies on salmon when you know I still
a big part of these environmental groups
but in Humboldt we were battling to
remove the the Klamath Dam and save the
salmon runs and one of the things that
became really evident to me was we were
losing a specific type of salmon called
the Spring Run chinook and because there
were no there was no data on how
different those spring run fish were
from the fall run fish that they were
not protected at all so they could
actually slip into extinction without
ever receiving an endangered species
listing or any of those things no
protection no management at all so I
said look I had to change this I wrote a
grant got funded found some some
students and some you know people that
were getting their PhD at Humboldt State
and at Davis kind of tailored the grant
for that work and we started doing
genomic studies on the salmon and lo and
behold there actually were specific
differences between those fish that you
could find with something like PCR which
I mentioned before it's basically it
it's kind of like ancestry.com if you
were to say you know it is totally like
ancestry.com for plants and and you know
no one's out there like you know you
submit some you know a swab of your
cheek cell or whatever to ancestry.com
and and no one's saying all your you
know you're messing with the genome and
because you're not you're really just
looking deeper into
a organism to find out more about it
like what its history is what it's
related to
so on and so forth and you can even like
predict there's predictors like you know
is this person potentially need to worry
about a heart attack at a young age or
cancer I mean if there's enough evidence
that a certain low sire allele and the
genome does tend to have that you know
those problems like a heart attack or
something then yes it's probably
something that you should think about
and maybe you know treat your body
differently but marker-assisted breeding
is essentially the same thing you're
basically saying you're trying to find
markers like but at this allele you know
this low site which is what we did for
the salmon you know we found grab one L
which was one low side that said this
fish is either gonna swim back in the
fall or swim up in the spring and we
wanted to protect the spring run because
that as we were tearing down these dams
which is this momentous thing is like
the largest River restoration project
and in the world according to National
Geographic so I was like look we can't
lose the fish that will inherit that
space I mean historically those were the
ones that went there we put these dams
in they are now teetering on the brick
brink of extinction we got to figure out
a way to protect them before we lose
them and then we don't have anything
once these dams come out which is gonna
happen in the next year or two we won't
have anything to go repopulate up there
so we actually were able to get the
endangered species listening through
that that study and there's tons of
similarities between like that I look at
the spring run and in that fall run and
I'm like you know Otto flower photos and
so that's kind of what
No made me so comfortable with with the
marker-assisted breeding was like I had
done this before the whole purpose was
to save natural resource save like art
our beautiful environment and the
wildlife here in humble and you know now
we can apply it to like all the good
reasons that we were talking about
earlier to have Auto flower genetics and
there's I I would really argue with
someone that said that there's something
morally or ethically wrong with
marker-assisted breeding because you
know it's it doesn't even take a lot of
electricity to one like the PCR machine
is really a pretty simple piece of
equipment and the way you get the answer
is with these gels and they just one of
them glows when you put it under a
blacklight if the answer is no maybe it
glows and if the answer is yes it does
not glow and so that's exactly what we
do it's the same thing as the plant sex
tests that are available through all
these different genomics companies we've
been using leaf works a lot lately and
we've got this feminized certification
thing but that's the same concept and
and really if you have ever used one of
those then in a way if you do breed then
you've actually done marker-assisted
breeding because you've used a marker
that told you whether the plant is going
to be a male or a female and then you
know MIT maybe that made it a little
easier for you to do your breeding
project in the long run so I think that
one of the things about you know people
here that first two words right genetic
marker and then they immediately jump to
GMO when really it's it's really just
another analysis test like anything that
you'll get at any Canon I mean you know
it's more complex than then you get it
most cannabis labs my point is though
they are passive right it's it's you
trying to read the plant to understand
it it's
not invasive something like CRISPR is
where you're actually going in and
splicing and editing the genome and then
inserting genes that are not indigenous
to the plant or you know and and I think
that though it's the vocabulary that is
off-putting to a lot of people more than
the fact that you're like oh well we did
a test to find out if this part teacher
picked our particular attribute is in
the DNA which makes it sound a lot safer
yeah exactly
and I think that that is like the common
misconception and you know if people
excuse me get to understand it a little
bit more that you know it won't be quite
so scary because there is exactly that
you're basically screening a population
for this desirable trait that you're
looking for and then you're kind of it's
it's a time saver as well like you're
then saying you know all right we want
this trait so if for sprouting a bunch
of seeds if we know which the marker for
that trait we can then take tiny snips
of tissue or like little bits of leaf
and submit it or do our own PCR and then
just get a whole bunch of yes this one
has it and and no this one doesn't all
right so this this last question I'm
gonna ask slowly so you can take a sip
of your heart Giada and and take care of
that cough so I'm gonna ask it really
slowly so that you can have your sip so
you know even though you've been you
know doing this cannabis breeding for
more than twenty years and and humble
you know humble seed company has been
around for that long
you're still a pretty young guy and
you've got lots of years of creativity
left in you but you know you've you've
talked to me and and you know earlier on
this show about how you know you've
always got kids around in your life and
and and you know you've just shared with
us that you're you know a biologist and
environm
you think about generations of things so
I can imagine that you've probably had a
lot of good folks working for you and
you're probably thinking about the next
generation of people who are gonna hold
it down in cannabis and specifically
Humboldt cannabis right because you know
more than just cannabis as an industry
Humboldt cannabis is an important
American heritage so my question is is
you know how much energy do you put into
mentoring the next generation of
breeders and and and if you you know if
you're into that how do you go about
doing that the goal with this question
is I'm I'm hoping to maybe inspire folks
because you know not only do we want to
inspire folks to breed cannabis because
you know there's a lot of work to be
done but there's gonna be people who
come after us and we need to make sure
we instill them with our values before
the cannabis plant becomes totally
commoditized sure absolutely well you
know I I brought Benjamin land into the
company I don't even remember when but
that was in the early days and Ben is is
a huge part of our breeding program a
huge part of the company so shout out to
Ben he's a little bit younger than me
but uh I I probably can't say that I
exactly mentored Ben but you know within
the company definitely I don't ever
really think of it as people working for
Humboldt seed company or working for me
or anything like that it's always you
know if I'm not making them excited
about what they're doing then I'm not in
my opinion like being a good leader in
the company and so that is exactly it
you know you have to not only mentor and
teach but allow folks within the
business to develop their own ideas and
nuances even if maybe you know you've
done it before and you might say look
I don't know sometimes you have to kind
of just take an educated guess it like
sometimes it's it's important to let
people kind of try and and experience
the same failures that you've
experienced over the years but yeah I
think it is really important I mean I
started breeding at the through getting
to know people that I really really
respected and loved that were both
cannabis farmers and you know the beauty
the phenomena of humble is that it was
never just a place where people grew
wonderful cannabis it was a place where
people worked together to grow wonderful
cannabis they worked together to
embellish community they work together
to foster you know these environmental
movements they fostered social movements
social justice economic justice and that
has been a major underpinning of
Humboldt seed company ever since you
know I first walked into the courthouse
so many years ago
even before I knew it was gonna be a
seed company you know it was basically
like look how do we keep these hills
alive and one of the thing it's a very
rural place so we have to band together
and that needs to persist through this
change that we're experiencing right now
with it becoming more of kind of this
traditional economy where you've got you
know all these pressures fiscal
pressures let's just say and and then
now more obviously taxes and you know
the even the county itself as as
conducive as Humboldt I have to give it
to Humboldt like it started out a little
rocky but our county government is now
really understanding and embracing that
the
businesses the small businesses and
trying to you know help help us make
this transition and so all the way from
the County Supervisors to the the
Planning Department to our local
wildlife officials to the old growers
that you know have some of them have
come sort of out of the hills and are
now you know working in the licensed
space some of them are maybe have scaled
back their grow a little bit just so
that they can stay in that sweet spot of
of having a grow eat but not a grow
that's gonna get red-flagged by the cuz
hey you know it humbled it was it's so
much harder now to grow cannabis ennoble
than it was four years ago I mean four
years ago we were having this influx of
everybody had heard you know oh you got
the humble and it's a Green Rush and
make a bunch of money and and to be
honest like most of those people came
out here they all they wanted was to
move here because of the money and and
weed and it was cool or whatever fell
flat in their face and most of them have
now moved on to whatever they're doing
next somewhere else but you know really
it has been those people that we're here
because of the place and because and
really fell in love with this community
and and the tightness that that being in
a more of a rural environment creates
you know you and I don't want to make us
sound like you know we're a bunch of
rednecks out in the boonies
even though there's nothing wrong with
that but you know we're we we've
innovated a lot here too and coming
together has made that innovation you
know it we've changed the whole cannabis
community around the world you know
created so much stuff
we innovated we've made our mark and I'm
super proud of that Mendocino Trinity -
like I don't want to just be all
Humboldt centric because there's so many
great people and in the whole area here
Oregon um but yeah we gotta pass that
we gotta pass that community feeling
down through and my daughter I know you
probably were referring to my daughter
she's 21 years old now and literally was
on my back when I was out planting the
first cannabis you know like she's been
there since day one and and we're really
tight and she she does a lot with the
company and she's actually really did
you know how started to guide some of
the breeding a little bit and you know
she has years of experience under her
belt and you know you just can't deny
this plant loves experience it loves
people that have that are familiar with
it and and a familiar touch as they as a
cannabis breeder I think is one of the
most important traits that you can have
as a breeder is familiarity I think
that's you know a sign of some of the
best companies in any industry that
they've got not only mentorship but also
you know family companies when it gets
passed down to generation and sure you
know family companies generation to
generation they break too
but there's something about being
totally immersed in any kind of
education which really gives you much
more rounded awareness of it and and
it's funny how you mentioned how you
know the the the the humble area the
Emerald triangle in general you know it
attracts people for lots of reasons and
if their hearts not in the right place
it also spits them back out
[Laughter]
and and you know I think that's I think
that's okay
yes I thank God well you know people are
people and we try to live as harmonious
with all of them and you know it
fortunately you're exactly right
fortunately it takes a certain kind of
person to so be here and you know we've
had I you know I've been here since 1995
that was when I was 18 years old and you
know traveled around the world since
then doing the environmental stuff but I
never once thought to myself you know
I'm gonna live somewhere else it was
always this place is beautiful too but
but I miss humble and I'll be back real
soon
so well I don't think that we're gonna
top that as a place to end this
interview brother thank you so much for
sharing your time and experience and and
your good heart with us man you know I'm
glad that there are well grounded kind
people like you breeding our favorite
plant and passing it down you know
through the generations so thank you so
much
Thank You Shengo it's really been an
honor to be on with you right now it's
something I've been watching your shows
for a long time and you know this is a
little bit of an achievement for us as
well so right on man I'm glad so so you
know if you're listening and you'd like
to learn more about NAT pennington you
can or or if you want to check out his
seed catalog you can visit Humboldt seed
company calm and you can also follow the
humble seed company Instagram at the
humble seed company on Instagram you can
find more episodes of the shaping fire
podcast and subscribe to the show at
shaping fire calm and on Apple iTunes
and google play if you enjoyed the show
we'd really appreciate it if you'd leave
a positive review of the podcast
wherever you download your review will
help others find the show so they can
enjoy it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the weekly newsletter for
insights into the latest cannabis news
and product reviews on the shaping fire
website you will also find transcripts
of today's podcast as well for
information on me and where I will be
speaking you can check out Shango lows
calm your company want to reach our
national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hotspot at shaping
fire calm to find out how thanks for
listening to shaping fire I've been your
host
Shango lows
[Music]