[Music]
sometimes old things hold a lot of value
it is true that I like fancy hotel rooms
but honestly I get the best sleep
sleeping at my friend's old beach cabin
that still has quilts and Afghans that
his grandmother and probably his
great-grandmother made the cabin smells
of old wood seawater and late loud
nights of laughing playing board games
and uker and quiet early morning staring
at the crashing surf while the others
are still
asleep and it is also true I am grateful
for the prescriptions that help my
autoimmune issues but honestly I have
gotten far more lifelong Health from
Paul pitchford's book healing with Whole
Foods herbalists and traditional
nutritionists know a lot that is lost to
modern
medicine today's episode is about
slowing down and and realizing the good
to be found in the natural past so that
maybe we can embrace it in our hectic
present if you want to learn about
cannabis Health cultivation and
technique efficiently and with good
cheer I encourage you to subscribe to
our newsletter we'll send you new
podcast episodes as they come out
delivered right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week and
videos too don't rely on social media to
let you know when a new episode is
published sign up for the updates to
make sure you don't missed an episode
this month's giveaway from dinoo Michael
risal and nulan is a little bit
different than how we normally do it the
first 200 people to follow the link on
the shaping fire Instagram profile or on
the shaping fire website page for this
episode and fill out the form on the
dynamico website will receive a free 20
G package of dynamico you don't even
have to pay for shipping I have used
dynamico for Five Seasons now and a
clearly dras drastically improves root
growth young plants grow faster and more
efficiently new soil matures more
swiftly micro risal networks expand and
thicken welcome to episode 111 you are
listening to shaping fire and I am your
host Shango Los my guest today is Jeff
nordal better known on Instagram as Jade
nectar Jeff has been studying cannabis
natural medicine and psychedelics since
his teens he has a background as an
early internet R preneur but became
seriously ill in his 30s only to find
out he had contracted Lyme disease
conventional medicine held no solutions
for him Jeff turned to cannabis medicine
in his home of Santa Cruz and started
getting results he became an expert on
the acid form of canabo and cannabis
leaf juicing and started a local medical
Collective to get it in the hands of
patients Jeff nordal now holds 11
patents for using cannabis as food
though he doesn't like patents and got
them defensively so no one could ever
tell him to stop juicing cannabis leaves
for patients he is presently building
out the Jade Grove Farm in Wellness
Center deep in the Santa Cruz mountains
he also has grown more land race
varieties of cannabis than anyone I've
ever met during the first set today we
will discuss the difference between land
race wild feral Heritage and hybrid
varieties of cannabis in the second set
we will learn about the cultivation
demands of land races hot and cold at
adapted land races and hear about some
of the more exotic morphology and
turpine profiles Jeff has come across
and during the third set we will explore
breeding with land races and finish the
episode with a discussion of land race
preservation welcome to shaping fire
Jeff hey thanks thanks for having me
excit to be here yeah it's really great
to have you here you know um uh ever
since I came across your Jade nectar
profile on Instagram and started uh
watching your tours of all the land r es
in your garden um you know I I I
immediately kind of became a fanboy I
must say just watching your videos I'm
like oh look at that plant and oh look
at that plant and it was it was like um
the same reason I love going through
botanical gardens right it's just once
you fall in love with plants you know I
started with the cannabis plant but then
that love kind of got became all plants
so to be able to see lots of varieties
of a plant together it's it's really
like nerdy nature fun for people like us
who cultivate but then to see your
Instagram where it's just one after
another and they look different and the
colors and you know you you've got a bit
of teaching Vibes about it you know you
kind of tell us about the plant and
everything and so um I so I just started
as a fan and a follower and then after I
went through enough of your videos over
time I'm all like oh dude I think I
think I think this would make a really
great episode so I'm really grateful
that that you uh you accepted my
invitation to come on the show so thanks
for that well cool and uh yeah if you're
enjoying it through the
video just through the
interwebs uh yeah you should come out in
person sometime well it doesn't Full
Experience well thank you it doesn't
take much of encouragement to get me to
come to Santa Cruz it's one of my
favorite places in the world so all
right man well let's get right into it
you know um when people talk about land
races people use that word kind of like
a a bucket right because um a lot of
people don't understand the idea of land
race or or where that definition begins
or ends
and then it then it starts to get mixed
in with other words like you know like
Heritage and heirloom and and you know
varieties and and so the the definition
is is a bit muddied so so let's let's
kind of talk around this idea um and and
tease out some of the interesting
meanings especially somebody like you
who who spends their whole time you know
in the land race world I can imagine you
would have a different take on it so so
so so why don't we just go ahead and
start with like the word land race and
and why don't you get us started there
yeah yeah so uh land race and I had to
do my own research as well um and uh
yeah it it is interesting that even
different Industries and such have
different definitions for what land race
is but it it turns out that uh land race
I believe I should look this up but I
think it's a German word for land Ross I
think so that means uh and that
translates into English like country
breed so uh right off the bat land race
is domestic these are domesticated uh
varieties but you can also have land
raised dogs land raised pigs chickens
cucumbers melons um so it's nothing
specific to cannabis whatsoever it has
to do with uh just agriculture or animal
um uh
breeding and and what but what it is and
why land races are unique
is they're actually tied to a specific
region um so there's this interplay
between uh so let's say a cannabis plant
shows up in um some area let's say in I
don't know
Thailand
um so there you've got a wet tropical
environment uh and and the people who
want to grow the Cannabis there are
going to be now uh breeding with with
their cannabis uh taking cues from the
environment over time so let's say they
grow 100 plants um but 50% if it were
let's say a like an Afghan or arid
environment uh genetic that that came to
this Village in Thailand you know
hundreds if not thousands of years ago
probably half of them would mold because
they're not
adapted
for uh all that moisture and humidity uh
but the humans would start picking you
know and taking the seeds from the
plants that actually fared pretty well
um so now there's human selection going
on to find those uh seeds or those
genetics that actually thrive in their
local
environment um so once that gets
established as far as something that can
actually survive and make it to the
Finish lineon produce you know flowers
without melting down uh now the humans
might start selecting more for
effects say I like a really or like
those that culture may actually
appreciate a very energizing electric
psychedelic uh effect in their cannabis
so then they start selecting uh for that
so now you're starting to infuse
cultural values and cultural utility
into this plant while also uh uh
selecting for things that actually
Thrive um in that environment uh so
that's that's kind of the inner play
with uh for land race is it happens over
time with uh pressures from the
environment and also uh the aesthetic
and uh desire and utility of the humans
who are growing them andc and if these
were isolated from all other cannabis
plants uh you can imagine over you know
Generation generation 50 Generations 100
Generations now you're going to have a
very unique uh cannabis variety That's
Unique just to that particular let's say
Village you know you know Jee I think
I'm going to set you up for your next
definition because um you know you
already surprised me the definition of
land race already is not what I thought
it was going to be because um I was
under the impression that land races
were Untouched by humans that we had
like as soon as you said
domesticated like my my eyebrow goes up
cuzz I'm like domesticated no no no this
is this is one of the biggest biggest uh
I I don't know where the Genesis of this
am I talking about Wild versus land race
you're talking about wild or feral okay
uh yeah so so land race is
100% influenc by humans these are
domestic so so if we want to start
talking analogies here start thinking um
as far as dog breeds so uh if anyone's
familiar with let's say Anatolian
Shepherds or Kangle dogs these are uh
these big uh sheep uh protector guard
dogs that are used in in the Anatolian
mountains in turkey and they require a
very
large uh dog to fight off wolves and
bears uh they need to be very
independent uh they actually go out with
the Sheep without any humans and we'll
just watch after the Sheep but also go
and hunt and provide food for themselves
um but the Anatolian Shepherds it's not
a
specific uh standard breed that you know
has to be 16 in from tail to snout or
any of these standard breed Dimensions
uh within the Anatolian Shepherd or
Kangle uh type of dog uh you actually
get all different color types all
different uh
variations uh and such but they're but
at the same time they're similar and
they perform a utility which is guarding
sheep and being independent and also uh
being able to handle the environment so
they have a really nice double coat that
keeps them insulated in the winter but
uh cool in the summer um so so that's an
Anatolian Shepherd you also have things
like huskys uh Eskimo dogs you'll see
there are tons of variant in those
dogs uh between each one so you've got a
lot of genetic
diversity but it's also bred by humans
to pull do
slits uh but there's no uh you know like
Kennel Club sitting there going and
measuring the dogs for specific traits
it's and so th those are actually
considered landra dogs and you can apply
the same thing to carrots cucumbers
pigs uh so I I find it very interesting
that a now now in my head um a a
cultural use and uh human intention is
now part of the land race definition for
me and that's a and that's a surprise
for me so so let's let's move forward
and and and have you talk a little bit
about the the feral and wild type which
is what was in my head as land race okay
and here's another thing this is um and
by the way I have read websites cannabis
websites that just kind of become these
Echo chambers that just poach other
information just keep repeating the same
fallacy yeah over and over
and for some reason there are cannabis
websites that do Define land race as
wild Untouched by humans and that well
we all know that most of the Cannabis
websites are garbage anyway they're just
people trying to throw up content so
they can sell advertising you know well
so so right off the bat just land race
is fully domestic just do a Google
search of the definition of land race
and you'll find out the first thing it
says is it's a domestic breed also
honestly
important that like you're friends with
Rob Clark right so your definition are
bounced off Rob Clark the god of Canabis
genetics so like I'm going to go with
what you're going to say more than what
I'm going to read just about anywhere
else okay so here's here's another thing
and I don't want to get in like pissing
matches with people who say oh no it's
it's wild cannabis and such so I just
went luckily I'm very fortunate and
honored to have um uh developed a bit of
a relation with uh Rob Clark and he came
out and visited he's been out to our
farm now uh three times um just no
particular agenda we just like hanging
out you know we got 300 land race
varieties all growing in the same Garden
so it's kind of just sort of
Wonderland uh for folks it's a cannabis
amusement park is what it is it really
it's Stoner Fantasy Land um and it's
just so anyway he was kind enough to
also uh send an email with his uh takes
on these these definitions just to clear
things up and uh and yeah I'll if if
okay not to be super boring I'll just
read a few sentences from from his
actual email I hope this he said it's
okay to share this but yeah sure so long
as they're not too long well go ahead
and no no no but right off the bat land
Rises are essentially locally adapted PL
and animal varieties that in that evolve
in response to Natural environmental
selective pressures in tandem with
simple human selection for favorable
characteristics without formal
breeding so um it says all domestic
plants and animals originated from Wild
po populations evolving naturally once
humans entered the scene the first steps
towards land race Evolution began so so
there you go so it's not it's not a uh
just keeping one line of of breeding a
particular genetic for just you know
like that ultimate um seed or clone uh
it's not a narrow breeding project it's
a it's a big large wide sort of
open pollination usually type breeding
project but then selecting most likely
what would happen is then you go and
select the seeds from the plants that
finished the best out of let's say a
whole patch like a large field of
cannabis and then uh the ones that made
it to the finish line and then when you
sample them they're awesome and you go
ah I want to grow the seeds from this
plant next year so that that way the
human is
now very much influencing and selecting
for their traits so that that is the
land race and then the other part that's
really important is
uh is that they're unique to that region
because now they've been isolated in
that physical geographic region for so
long that they're now like totally
unique compared to uh you know land
races in other parts of the world right
on so so we've established land race
good let's move forward a little bit now
are are wild and feral synonymous or are
those individual ideas too uh no we're g
if as far as running the analogy the dog
analogy uh what what feral is is its
domestic cannabis that has escaped the
farm and now it's off growing wild but
it's not actually the true wild original
cannabis variety so it's like Post Farm
wild yeah so this would be like uh in
Australia if we're doing our dog analogy
here this would be the
dingo right so the dingo
were in a domestic dog that was
introduced into Australia I think like
4,000 years ago or so and then it went
totally feral now it's actually part of
the
ecosystem in Australia but it was never
actually a wild naturally occurring wolf
um it was it was actually it was never
indigenous it was brought in correct and
it was a domestic dog that then went uh
feral and now is part of that
environment so cannabis is very
adaptable and such so if it escapes the
farm and by the way in the midwest in
the US we still have uh ditch weed
that's escaped hemp from the hemp Farms
you know of the early
1900s and so that's still growing but
when when a plant goes
feral it's now doesn't have that human
uh infusion or intention going on with
it so now it's now it's just the plant
doing its thing with its only motivation
is to keep making more seed so most
likely when you have feral
populations um The Taste the potency of
THC or whatever canabo you're going for
is the you know the plant doesn't even
care about that it just wants to make
seeds so now you're going to get you
know a hardier more adaptive for
survival and
reproducing plant for the cannabis plant
but uh probably the desirable human
traits are going to start fading on
those feral
populations um right on I I identify
with feral I think I'm falling further
and further out of normative society as
well yeah so um yeah exactly so if if
you went full Off the Grid and uh went
and lived in a hut or a cave out in the
middle of night and started raising a
family and such like that yeah you that
would be the full Embrace of it you'd be
then more adapted for hunting and
Gathering and not uh sitting Compu
social media all right so let's contract
contrast then that to Wild which would
be the which would probably be a plant
that is uh indigenous to that biosphere
but has never been domesticated and
farmed exactly and the thing is is most
likely so and again this is uh from
Robert Clark who also has uh sort of
combined all of the Cannabis research uh
he's got a great book
um I think it's called ethnobotany
cannabis ethnobotany uh that yeah it
goes in actually it's very information
dense so yeah it's a heavy duty read
yeah yeah it's not just a casual sit by
the fire kind of thing uh but it is a
really really really a great re source
for going and and what they've done is
just tracked and basically agree with
all these other um botanists and
scientists and ethnobotanists who've
tracked the original origin of cannabis
seems to come from what's now
geographically in China uh and that is
where the original wild cannabis seem to
originate
from but because cannabis domestic
cannabis was cultivated and used for
10,000 plus years in that same area it's
highly
unlikely that the original wild cannabis
didn't get crossed with domestic
cannabis at some point so to
differentiate the true wild origin
cannabis from uh feral domestic can can
abis uh it it's kind of almost
impossible to do that and most likely uh
it went extinct through hybridization
with other uh domestic varieties over
the past 10,000 years so so most likely
the original wild cannabis no longer
exists all right so then the cap off
this line of definitions why don't we
finish off with poly hybrid and then
we'll start talking about morphology
okay and then one other one that's part
of is also heirloom or Heritage
varieties good so and that's more
uh those would be specific breeding
projects a lot of times sort of like uh
we've got it going on in California
especially up in Humble and mesino and
such um actually was just reading about
some of these uh the Huckleberry Hill
Farms by the way I got this sample some
of their uh White white Thorn
Rose uh which I guess is getting a lot
of attention right now and that was that
is the only like cannabis from a
dispensary uh that I've sampled in the
last few years that was like wow that's
really that took me back to like
Grateful Dead parking lot kind
bud old school really really really
beautiful cannabis so um but I looked
into their story and such and I think a
lot somewh in that lineage he calls it
uh like Mom's weed so that would be like
heirlooms where families actually have
worked and developed their own you know
strain and pass that down through the
generations to like family and friends
and such like that so that's like an
heirloom right there where it's where
it's being passed through that just
warms my heart just even thinking about
looking at the at the genetic line and
and seeing mom's weed like that is the
heart of cannabis and like the human
relationship with the plant right when
it's like it's like pre the names pre
the the you know categories for sale and
and pre competition between people it's
just yeah this was this was our family's
particular strain that we loved and we
had at our holidays yeah I think I think
that's a beautiful thing so all right so
mom's with heirloom so that's kind of
more like heirloom where it's being
passed you know just like heirloom
furniture and such you're passing it
through generations and then uh but then
Heritage strains would follow that same
uh pattern or sort of be in that same
category only that might be more widely
uh distributed so and a lot of times uh
Heritage or or heirlooms exist only in
uh clone cuting form I mean they may
back them up with seeds but a lot of
times things you know like train wreck
AK-47 uh old school even even I guess
like old school Super Silver Haze
Northern Lights and things like that
those are more like the
Heritage like original
Foundation uh strains that uh did get uh
passed passed around uh through the
Community um so done so let's let's go
back to the poly hybrid then and then
cap off with that so now poly hybrids
and there's nothing wrong or unethical
or things to be snoody about
with poly hybrids it's just now what
seems to be gone and this isn't just I
mean this is my personal opinion but a
lot of other folks um are coming to the
same
inclusion is and if we're going to do
our dog breeding analogy
again uh most of the modern cannabis
that's now on the
scene is like the
Labradoodle times 10 so now you've got
labradoodles cross to pug dooodle or
puggles back to a pitbull back to a lab
dooodle back to a Cocker span of doodle
and it's all this and and it almost
doesn't even have any um necessarily any
intention for like oh I want to create
like a really racy High
creative uh variety that tastes like
passion fruit you know what I mean it's
more okay gelato was hot last month and
wedding cake is hot right now so we're
going to cross those those two and call
this gelato cake it yeah it just just on
its face it sounds less reputable
because you're you're breeding for
marketing hype instead of breeding to go
back to your dog example breeding for
the dog that take can take care of the
sheep and feed itself in the wild right
like one has authentic human cultural
meaning and the other one is for
capitalism and it's just yeah it's like
top 40 hits like these just very
just riding hype for the next 30 60 days
and it it's almost like if people were
hanging outside uh like a dog show you
know like a breeders I don't know these
Kennel Club dog shows yeah and they're
like oh your dog won the best in Terrier
class and yours won the best in this so
how about we just cross them together
and so now we have a doberman snower or
whatever yeah exactly and it's like the
hot new dog that's going to win the next
year's Kennel Club you know and then you
just do that exponentially into and
that's where we're at now we have like
all these whoever wanton all the cups or
whatever is getting attention then you
just cross all that stuff together and
it's just become this muddled muddled
muddled uh genetics and the effects um
it's I mean it's not just me saying this
I heard this confirmed and uh there's a
lot of consensus seems to be going on in
the community at this point that you
can't really tell the difference between
smoking runs or wedding cake or Oreos or
peanut butter cookie breath or whatever
it's like it all
basically kind of tastes looks and all
kind of feels the same and unfortunately
it's not
um I mean everyone has different you
know objectives and such with with their
Stoner ISM and what they're going for
and such but a lot of
people uh like that up like a creative
uplifting inspiring clear head and such
and and feeling active and kind of
amplifying life where now a lot of the
uh cannabis varieties right now seem to
be more of like an opiate
sedative uh kind of lethargic tired well
it's that it's that it's that miring
dominance that's all through the modern
commercial strains
right and so it's just
uh yeah so and to each their own it's
not to be S I mean there's a time and
place for couch lock and such but
uh but yeah if if every cannabis variety
now that you find out just dispensary
gives you that same couch lock I forgot
my name I'm just going to sit in my
underwear and play video games and eat
pizza if that's this the same effect
you've you've now it's kind of like all
all the vast world of all these
different dog breeds with all these
different personalities and fun
characteristics have now all been sort
of hybridized and homogenized into this
just
BL same exact uniform kind of
boring effect and you know you know it's
it's not to the fault of the modern
cannabis consumer or Enthusiast either
right because you know the vast majority
like 99% of what's available is the
modern poly hybrid stuff and you know
I've been I've been a cannabis
Enthusiast for gez 30 35 40 years now
something like that and um you know and
and it wasn't until um I came across um
my buddy shared with me some cuttings of
an
authentic um aapco gold and I'm like oh
this is what all those people who were
10 years older than me were talking
about about cuz the high was so entirely
different and then and then I decided
I'm like well I can't grow that here
where I live outside and so I was I was
able to get some oh actually he's from
your area uh Eric Miner of HBK genetics
um he he used to live in the in the
Santa Cruz region um he he's got this 20
weak black Colombian land race that I
grew indoors and like those two plants
are unlike everything else that I have
smoked and and have grown just because
and and so you know when when when you
when you say that okay the you know your
your your pound cake tastes like your
cookies Tes tastes like your this you're
that right it's because the mod
commercial cannabis is pulling from this
very small pool of of of commercially
viable genetics whereas you know if
those same people were able to get
access to you know you know equatorial
plants and Thai and Colombia and all
these and then and then smoke them
against each other well suddenly their
taste pet has expanded and now they see
they that they they see that they've
been looking down right at this
particular genetic pool
but not the not the global genetic
pool exactly and um so a lot of times
when when I break out uh yeah like an
aapco or a Thai variety or uh just right
now loving some stuff from Sri Lanka and
by the way a lot of these land races
that were growing um are seeds that were
sourced back in the 70s so it's it's not
even so you're geographically traveling
and culturally traveling but you're also
time traveling I like that yeah so
there's this myth that now the weed uh
uh today is stronger and
better but once you
sample like a 1970s Pakistan or 1970s
Sri Lankan or some of these old you know
people who went on the hippie tra or
worked at the Peace Corp in some of
these areas and brought back seeds uh
you know from almost 50 years
ago and then you grow them out and smoke
them and you're like oh my God that yeah
the weed was incredibly psychedelic back
then incredibly it's like a whole
different category it's almost verging
on psilocybin like you know like a low
dose of mushrooms and a lot of the lot
lot of the modern you know enthusiasts
they haven't had that opportunity and
and so they're just all like oh but the
the percentage THC on those older
strains were so low and and now I've got
this thing that somehow is over 30 and
you know and like it's so much better
but but a lot of these smokers don't
understand the important role that um
prevalent Tes placed in those older
strains in these untouched strains that
you know they might be 12 or 18% but
their tarpine percentage is so high and
that's what sculpts the high the the
experience that you have and and and
that's where the real difference comes
from we're not it's not about the THC
it's about the whole bouquet so that's
what's going it's like the symphony
orchestra
so yeah you have the bassoons and the
tonies and you have the cellos and you
French horns going on and things they
don't play a major role but they add so
much texture and Counterpoint and
diversity within the sound that there's
this whole communication going on but
now what seems to be going on with if
there's only so much real estate on the
cannabis plant so if you're up at 30 35%
THC that's kind of like the symphony
orchestra there's only so much stage so
that means you have to kick out all the
other instruments to make way for now
you have 200 violin players all playing
the exact same note yeah that's a good
one yeah and it's just playing the exact
same Melody and it's
still you know you it's still music not
as complex yeah you've just lost all
that complexity and now it's more of a
onedimensional
buzz experience without instead of this
big
Symphony tapestry of textures and
counterpoints and poly rhythms such like
that so it's yeah that's kind
of one analogy and you could even go
like Grateful Dead Jerry Garcia style I
mean let's not let's not go that let's
not go there we only have so much show
and you and I are both dead heads and
that will be the rest of the show so so
I actually want to move forward off of
the definitions and um because we we're
coming up on a commercial not too far
from now but I want to get some of these
other ideas in here that um you know
sometimes let's let's let's take a that
black Colombian I mentioned earlier as
an example okay so um you know um we
meaning cannabis cultivators that are
growing now we will get something like a
a a a Colombian or or or a a Syrian or
you know wherever this particular um
land race has come from and and people
treat it like that is
um not just an example but that is the
type of plant that everybody
in you know um Colombia or Sri Lanka you
mentioned earlier as if one that one um
plant is the only plant that is grown
there and and um and and I just like to
to talk to that idea because I think
that that is a real common misnomer in
the cannabis world that just because
you've had one plant from you know a
growing region that you've had what they
have to offer you know and and I I just
really feel like that that's probably
not true yeah that's so that's not
reality and all you have to do is go to
mesino or go to Big Sir even go back in
in time you know 50 years ago when
things were you know more on the down
low but was every single family and
every single grower growing the exact
same genetics and the answerers no it's
and it's not in Sri Lanka or Afghanistan
there's not like
a cannabis club where they all vote on
what genetics every single cannabis
which one is going to be the official
genetic of their growing region yeah no
they're all they're all doing their own
thing but they're
also G of well one they probably you
know are sourcing their genetics from
similar Gene pools just because the
world hasn't been globalized for all
that long you know um so limited you
know genetic resources they're they're
going to pull from things they have in
the area uh but then they're also you
know going to also uh select for things
that do well in that same region so
you're going to have similarities but
are they all going to be exact carbon
copies of each other um and the answer
is absolutely not it kind of reminds me
of your huckleberry Hill example from
earlier where back in the genetic line
is mom's favorite like you know in Sri
Lanka it's not they're just producing
one kind all these different families
have got their mom's favorite and so you
know they've got just as much diversity
as as we're experiencing now um it's
just that um seeds are so hard to get
from these areas that you know one
variety makes its way out and then and
then unfortunately becomes the example
for the whole region cuz that's only
were able to get yeah but they they will
be similar though um I mean what's
happening now though in Thailand is all
the Amsterdam and Cali genetics are
coming in um and polluting their land
races uh that's that's the really scary
thing that's a whole another topic of
discussion but we may be experiencing a
global land race Extinction due to uh
hybridization it's basically like if you
know if you let labber dooodle out to
roam free and they went and basically
copulated with every dog breed on the
planet now everything's been
doodled and by the way I don't have
anything against doodle I actually have
a schnoodle a snower poodle uh mixed dog
so they're it makes your point though
what I'm saying is do we want to live in
a world where every dog breed has been
dualized yeah and uh and every can
cannabis has been cookie cake
you know um well hey I don't think I
don't think I'm going to top uh don't
doodle your cannabis um anywhere anymore
in this uh in in this first set so let's
uh let's let's end there and go for
commercial break and when we come back
we're going to start talking about uh uh
tpine profiles in land races so um let's
go ahead let's go ahead and take yeah
yeah yeah can I say one other tiny tiny
little thing about the land race and
that whole uh wild uh sort of feral
definition and such and this is a really
important thing for sort of Ethics
morals of of land races
so the definition that some folks have
worked on the wrong definition that uh
land races are just kind of wild and
feral and growing on the side of the
road also sets up a situation of
appropriation and complete erasing of
the farmer who developed the land race
variety you get what I'm saying yeah I
do so here maybe in the US if you all a
sudden have some really cool uh Thai
variety you're if you're totally
discounting that this is probably
hundreds of years of genetic work by
actual humans in Thailand in whatever
region or Village who created this like
totally Sublime variety if if you think
that it was just growing on the side of
the road wild all of a sudden there's no
credit there's no honor there's no
respect for uh those farmers and then
you're more apt to just name it
something or even call it your weed and
you've just erased uh the the human uh
work that actually got that strain to
that Sublime uh state so it's just
really important for land race to also
fully Cate at these amazing cannabis
intuitive breeders who uh develop these
like absolutely Sublime uh varieties uh
so a lot of human work went in to get
them to this point um and just because
you took a vacation to Thailand brought
back some seeds doesn't mean you created
that strain man that's a really good
point and I'm glad that I'm glad that
you held me up to put that in there so
all right thank you all right so so now
let's go to commercial uh we're going to
take that short break and be right back
you're listening to shaping fire and my
guest today is land race specialist Jeff
nordal and you know without these
advertisers shaping fire would not
happen so please support them and let
them know that you heard them on shaping
[Music]
fire one of the reasons why no till
cannabis growing is so valued by Farmers
is because the melium networks in the
soil remain established from year to
year and we know these fungal networks
are essential because they are the
nutrient super highways that extend far
and wide in the substrate to feed your
plants the trouble with growing in New
Living soils or Blended cocoa substrates
is that it takes most of the plant's
life just to create these mycelium
highways dinico endom micral fungi
inoculant reduces that time and gets
your plant eating a wider array of
nutrients faster and it's three times
the concentration of the other popular
brand in the US at 900 propagules per
gram of two fungal species selected
specifically for cannabis cultivation
dinica is the result of 30 years of
research and trials at the volcani
agriculture Research Institute in Israel
it has also been vigorously Tried by
cannabis and food Growers across the US
dynamico is now available at Grow shops
and on Amazon in the United States I
love using dyom myo to both speed up the
growth of the melium networks in the
soil but also as a bio stimulant to make
clone cuting more viral you can see side
byid showing the comparative growth on
their Instagram at
dinico if you demand reliable growing
results and appreciate the importance of
an active root Zone in creating a
thriving plant I encourage you to check
out dino.com and use the store locator
to find out where you can get yours
that's d y n o m
y.com shaping fire listeners can get 10%
off any size of dynamico on
dynamic.com by using the discount code
shaping fire onew no caps whether you
are starting with new beds or pots or if
you want to add some Zing to tired soil
choose damico to maximize your plant's
potential damico endom micro risal
[Music]
inoculant fish poop brand fertilizer is
an allnatural fish poop concentrate with
nothing added real fish poop is
extraordinarily complex not only are you
adding the nitrogen phosphorus and
potassium your plants need to build mass
transport nutrients and enhance flavor
but fish waste is also packed with
biological activity and
micronutrients when you add fish poop to
your irrigation water you are adding
life force probiotics and active
microbes these microorganisms include a
wealth of various bacteria and protozoa
which further enhance nutrient
availability for the plants because
plants are limited by the absence of any
essential micron nutrient these Trace
nutrients are the difference between
having a decent garden and having a
garden that makes you feel really proud
of your efforts fish poop is a naturally
complete solution that fills in the
cracks in your fertilizer program to
ensure you offer your garden a broad
base of nutrients not all fish poop is
created equally most products with added
fish waste don't reveal their sources or
lab results fish poop brand fish poop
however generates their own fish waste
as a b product of their organic
aquaponic cannabis farm where they raise
ornamental koi and tilapia you are even
invited to tour their Farm in person or
on their YouTube channel to look for
yourself this sort of transparency is
wildly rare in the fertilizer Market the
folks behind fish poop are also lifelong
medical cannabis producers who have deep
Connections in the community donate more
product than they sell and support
cannabis prisoner veteran and patient
collectives and charities to get your
bottle of pure fish poop go to fish
poop.com and to see their entire line of
cannabis products go to ounce of
hope.com that's fish poop brand fish
[Music]
poop you've heard me talk about the
award-winning cannabis seeds that come
from the analytical breeding program of
Seth and Eric Crawford who founded
Oregon CBD seeds in fact Seth was a
guest on shaping fire in 2020 to talk
about triploid genetics Seth and Eric
are now releasing high THC seeds for
homeg Growers and Farms as grow the
revolution seeds at GTR seeds.com their
high THC seeds are extraordinary in that
they will start to flower at 16 and 1/2
hours of daylight instead of the typical
14 1/2 hours of daylight that means in
most regions your plants will start to
flower outdoors in the middle of July
instead of the middle of August which
means these photo period plants finish
in September and not October totally
upending the photo period Seed Market
Seth and Eric took their prized early
flowering CBG line and bred it to some
of the most desired verified genetics
out there including Sour Diesel triangle
cush wedding cake chem dog Skittles and
others these crosses all Express
powerful photo period tarpine profiles
and THC giving you a great High GTR
seeds has a new thcv line with plants
like double Durban and Gigantor that
boast one:1 THC to thcv and people want
that
thcv GTR seeds are very consistent true
growing inbred f1s from stabilized
inbred parent lines these seeds are
nearly homogeneous and the plants should
all grow the same there is only one
phenotype in every pack available as
diploids and triploids sethan Eric's
company is still family-owned patient
employee Centric and partially powered
by their 2 Acres of solar panels
everyone can purchase these seeds and
the entire catalog of Oregon CBD seeds
at GTR seeds.com go to GTR seeds.com
today and choose something revolutionary
for your next indoor or outdoor run
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire I am your host Shango Los
and my guest today is land red
specialist Jeff nordle so in the first
set we talked a lot about what exactly
land races are and how to understand
them from different varieties of plants
that may have come into this modern
world in different ways so that we can
really be precise in what we're talking
about since we are talking about a
scientific term so that was really great
teasing those terms apart generally um
but now here in the second set I want to
talk about um a little bit about the
characteristics of these plants and and
and why we generally all tend to respect
them and why Jeff has you know uh Focus
so much of his life on it so so Jeff you
know in your videos on your YouTube
channel you are U constantly talking
about just being like like bowled over
by the complexities of um the tpine
profiles and and during the first set we
also talked a little trash about like
modern poly hybrids and and about how so
many of them are massively miring
dominant um but but I want to tease out
a little bit more um about uh about the
experiences that you've had in your
garden um with Unique Blends of tpine
profiles and and like you know you don't
have clearly you're not going to talk
about all 300 that you're growing but if
if I want to provide the listeners with
a snapshot of some of the experiences
you've had so so maybe just like pick
like three that were especially unique
to you and and describe them to us so
that we can smell it through you all
right as far as top three standout
turpan profiles from this year's garden
and again every year we're doing
different varieties from around the
world uh but the ones that are Super
Fresh in my mind are
uh the Cambodian two varieties of
Cambodian had the most
insane passion fruit like just that
Tangy
jippy sour super tropical loud loud loud
passion fruit and I actually uh went and
got an actual passion fruit fruit
sniffed that and then sniffed one of
these uh mandul Kiri and then also too
another region uh in Cambodia they
smelled exactly the same the actual
passion fruit and uh the Cannabis uh at
least those varieties of Cambodian so
that was pretty pretty
mindblowing um another turpine profile
that uh you rarely come across in sort
of the uh modern uh poly hybrid genetics
but uh which I'm a huge fan of are the
really
stinky skunky rotten meat burnt rubber
rotten onions just super Funk um and a
lot of times you'll find those in the
Afghan uh pack istani uh we actually
grew some
USC
um varieties this year um and and one of
those smelled like rotten decomposing
onions and
garlic really really funky it's almost
uh disgusting but at the same time
intoxicating kind of like the uh truffle
black truffle effect where it's gross
but intoxicating well I I love those
cheeses that smell and and smell like
baby diaper you know like like if if it
if that smell was coming out of a human
I'd be like but suddenly now on a on a
plate with crackers I'm like yeah this
is awesome yeah yeah oh and by the way
reminds me there's a really weird turum
profile um that actually smells like uh
like bounce dryer sheets wow like that
really gnarly fabri and and by the way
this is what's strange is I'm highly
allergic to a lot of synthetic
fragrances especially those uh laundry
detergent smells so I just absolutely am
repulsed whenever I smell that smell but
then uh and I always said there is no
smell in nature that smells like a
bounce dryer sheet but I've actually
grown some cannabis now that
smells like bounc dryer sheets and it's
kind of weird so who knows it may
actually help me uh
gets gets through my dryer sheet
aversion by uh smelling it in cannabis
form it is really strange when you smell
something in cannabis that you also
exists in the real world uh this example
isn't as great as yours but you know
there uh the blueberry muffin U variety
from humbal Seed Company it's really
startling how much it smells like the
blueberry Jiffy cake mix which is which
doesn't you know it kind of
smells like blueberries that are natural
right it it smells like itself but it
was so strange to smell that variety and
be all like oh my God like okay this
smells blueberry but it smells like the
muffin box and those muffins themselves
which you know have got a little more of
a a breakfast cereal vibe to them than
like a natural organic Berry and it's
it's a fantastic U you know variety I've
I've grown it a long time and I love it
and yet it smells like a cheap boxed
muffin mix and it's just a bizarre thing
it it is so wild the diversity of Aromas
and turpins that this cannabis plant uh
can carry and provide and that can just
sort of emerge from these plant and then
when you start Crossing plants to whole
new combinations of it's it's pretty
mindblowing I I'm not aware of other
plants that have such a diversity of
smells so I'm going to ask you one more
tpine related question I don't want to
spend too much time here because like
you know not everybody can smell it
together right so it's talking about
tpin is is kind of challenging sometimes
but the the last question I want to ask
you about this is um tell us tell us
about one plant that you smelled where
you this the the the the taring profile
of it was was a smell that you had never
smelled before
and it blew you away because you your
brain wasn't sure what to do to it it'll
probably be very hard for you to
describe it to me because of that reason
too yeah it's almost like uh seeing a
color you've never seen before yeah and
there's just yeah your your brain just
can't even process that but yeah there's
a number of uh varieties of cannabis
that uh come across in these land race
botanical gardens we do every year that
have just
it like scrambles your
brain
because you've never smelled
anything like that and so you can't even
find words to describe it because it's
such a bizarre smell um so yeah that
happens quite a bit and then you end up
just sitting there sniffing it because
it's it's intoxicating just to have that
experience yeah so it's so engaging to
have that first new experience we humans
go for
those
absolutely oh oh did want to say the
other really interesting turpine profile
that you find in land races uh
especially the African and Southeast
Asian equatorial is there's this really
interesting um carrot uh
parsnip uh turp so it's and the reason
how actually connected those dots was my
girlfriend was actually peeling
parsnips and the smell that came from
those parsnips I was like oh that's that
smell so it's that uh sort of antiseptic
astringent really earthy sweet fresh
fresh fresh carrot parsnip smell um but
you'll actually see those in a lot of
African uh varieties as well as uh Thai
Chang Rai that we grew this year
actually had that t profile uh and
that's that's always a favorite too so
while we're kind of going through your
picture album if you will of of of
plants that you love um we've just did
tpin and I want to do a very similar
thing but with morphology now right so
how the plant looks its structure
because um you know I love uh when you
go through these different plants and
I'm like wow these are all cannabis
plants but they all have got so much
different visual personality for example
you recently post a video about one from
um the island of St Vincent and and I
saw it and I'm like now this is a plant
that would work really well where I live
because it doesn't grow big and bushy it
kind of grows like it grows kind of like
straight up and down like it's a pencil
skirt or something and it's very
respectful of its neighbors right you
can walk past it without it grabbing you
like most plants do so so I guess kind
of like you did with Tarpin maybe tell
us like three of your favorite
morphologies like tell us the story of
like three plants that look
atypical um this and again I'm just
going off this year every year there's
mindblowing uh structures and uh but
this year a huge surprise was uh Brazil
Amazonia so I was you know thinking that
was going to be just a long lanky wispy
tropical equatorial sativa type this
actually turned out to
be super
short super squat bushy with big chunky
thick buds it it grew and looked almost
like an a typical indicia actually an
even bushier stockier squater uh
indicia uh but it has this wild um Pia
colada turp profile going this tropical
fruit and then uh when you finally get
around to uh sampling it and smoking it
it is super high electric almost like
Brazil uh Carnival
kind of
vibe bright colors and feathers and
electric and drum beats all in a very
squat bushy actually early finishing
these were all done uh by the end of
September as
well uh but super electric sativa Stone
so uh that was that was a big surprise
um and also like super bulletproof as
far as pest resistance and and mold it's
got all that land race Vigor still going
oh yeah yeah yeah and that's that's one
of the beautiful things too about these
land races is they're just so they're so
much heartier and designed to not be
high maintenance plants um so so anyway
they have yeah we don't even deal for
the most part with btis haven't seen
powdered Milo in 10 years wow um and Bug
pressure is pretty low the aphids are
still kind of a
menace it's probably going to be around
for quite some time they're kind of
indestructible but um yeah so that's so
anyway that that was one uh structure
that was very surprising this year
another yeah the St
Vincent as uh you noticed uh even though
we had unlimited root space so usually a
cannabis plant when it has unlimited
root space tends to
the top of the plant will then become
wide and bushy as well to mirror the
root system uh but for whatever
reason um the St Vincent just shot
straight vertical and only was maybe a 4
foot diameter plant where a lot of ours
are like 8 to 10 foot diameter plants
when grown in those conditions so uh for
whatever reason it just really wanted to
stay going vertical uh and it got
probably 12 feet tall with just really
nice uniform sort of calabra of uh
uniform flowers going um have not
sampled that one yet but
uh had all the signs that it should be
it should be a nice one yeah and and and
it's special too I just like plants that
that look different you know like like
even these mut mutants that you see
people put online like I like mutant
plants too it's like people are like oh
that should be destroyed kill it get it
out of the Jean Pool and I'm like okay
maybe all of that's true but also isn't
it cool you know yeah and it may turn
out to be a an advantageous adaption you
know um that's kind of mutants
Drive evolutionary change too so let's
let's talk a little bit about how the
morphology um responds to where these
plants are from right because a lot of
these plants that come your way these
land Races they have themselves over you
know hundreds or thousands of years have
become hot or cold adapted for the areas
that they are from and so um you know uh
I'm very willing to be wrong cuz I have
not come in a contact with as many land
races as you have but generally speaking
my impression is is that you know
equatorial plants where it is um you
know wet and hot they tend to be more
open Airy flowers so that um you know
they can uh more easily uh transpire and
you know kind of respirate and breathe
in the Heat and also so they dry out
really quickly after you know a monsoon
or something like that whereas so many
of the the you know the the Pakistani
and Afghani and you know things that are
grown um you know
near you know these these these cold
seasonal Mountain re regions they tend
to have these like like tighter flowers
and in my head it's always like oh so
they cons conserve warmth and I don't
know if that's true or not but but i'
just like to to hear your thoughts after
having interacted with so many of these
plants how do you see these morphologies
um you know uh being associated with the
different parts of the world that they
come from yeah yeah absolutely and there
definitely is um
yeah the equatorial tropical sativas for
the most part yeah share that um larier
areer uh flower structure for that exact
reason because they're in a extremely
humid moist environment and they might
even be getting rain quite often um so
yeah yeah so if if it was a super
compact dense
flower they'd all
implode you know with in the first week
of flowering um due to btis uh they'd
probably mold out very quickly so uh
yeah kind of across the board um the
equatorial sativas all have that looser
Airy uh structure a lot of times uh very
foxtail like Fox tailes upon Fox tailes
almost like a
romanesca
uh kind of you know fractals of like Fox
tales with fox tailes fox tail and uh
but you'll find those are also Crystal
coated so they may not be heavy but
every nook and cranny is coated in
Crystal so um so if you're just talking
about straight resin yield they might
actually end up being a bigger one a
better choice even though they're open
and Airy yeah yeah and um and that's
another really interesting thing about
um but yeah so that's equatorial
tropical equ tutorials you'll see that
pretty much across the board but the
amazing thing is these plants just don't
mold they just btis just does not happen
unless uh the only thing that gets the
like the Achilles heel of those tropical
sativas is uh Frost so and as things
start to get cold if you do get frost on
those buds they tend to um die very
quickly
uh so that's uh so that's the only thing
and even when they die a lot of times
you won't get btis mold you'll just get
dead spots um so they're just incredibly
mold resistant um Now with uh like
Afghan Pakistan Iranian those varieties
it's not just hot and cold but those are
also extremely Aid environments so very
low humidity where uh btis just isn't as
much of a threat in those regions so uh
the human um uh intervention with those
has has been to maximize yield so you
get more yield with a chunkier heavier
bud and if you can push it without btis
you know there there you go uh the
problem is when you
bring a super dense chunk Afghan all of
a sudden into Santa Cruz Coastal wet
foggy environment that's just a recipe
for uh btis explosions and that's and
see that quite a lot of people have that
experience um we're fortunate where
we're growing we're behind a mountain
range so that catches the Marine layer
so we're actually pretty Aid in our play
so we can actually pull off these
um uh Afghan Pakistani
yeah it's pretty obvious from your
Instagram that you live in a special
Biore region because seeing all these
different plants from all these
different regions of the world all
growing and finishing like I've I've
sworn at my phone before I'm like how
the hell is he growing this oh my God
you know because like I live at the
other end right I live Pacific Northwest
on an island you know 50 feet from
crashing water that's marine and salty
right so like I live a terrible place to
grow myself but where you are it's it's
like you know best possible combination
of attributes it's yeah and uh it's San
Lorenzo Valley in Santa Cruz mountains
has a long long uh cannabis history and
it turns out it's a real nice uh little
microclimate that uh yeah say it's it's
blocked off from the Marine layer even
though we're down in a valley uh so you
don't necessarily have to be super high
elevation uh but uh but we're behind a
mountain uh Empire Grade that actually
catches that whole Marine layer so we
just don't get that Coastal fog so uh
anyway so so yeah so the next thing I
want to talk about is the the unique
cultivation demands of land race and
that kind of fits in perfectly with the
weather conversation that we're having
because you know I'm sure lots of people
who are listening like me are being
inspired by what you're saying and we're
all like I want to grow land race and
and um
uh have you you know from from growing
so many year over a year um have you
noticed any cultivation demands or best
practices um for land races because you
know I imagine to a certain degree they
are finicky to us who are used to kind
of growing all of the same plant because
because these these these modern plants
that we've talked about earlier are very
similar to each other but but then
you're growing all these weirdo plants
which of course are land races and
they're not weirdo but like they are if
you're a cultivator who has never grown
them before so so let's let's hear a
little bit about that like I'm I'm sure
that you have run into some unexpected
growing needs that that some of these
varieties have uh well here's here's the
very good news about land R is
um they're actually developed to be low
maintenance plants we love hearing that
so so a real finicky high maintenance
like OG cush you know that
uh you know it's going to have powder
mil do and all this it not to get back
into the dog thing but um but it's kind
of like you don't have to worry about
with the land race like the hip
dysplasia and all this like kind of
inbred problems with susceptibilities to
disease and uh molds and and pathogens
uh and it turns out out actually with
the Hop blatant
vroid uh most land races I mean they can
still get it but don't seem to be
affected uh neg as negatively as some of
these poly hybrids too uh so so it's
actually yes all the land races and
we're growing them from all around the
world from totally different regions uh
but because they're such
hearty uh plants that are designed to
you know Thrive without a ton of human
uh catering and pandering to the plant
and pampering um they all do pretty they
have a they all seem to have high
tolerance to disease molds and pests um
so I I actually think they're easier to
grow than uh most of the modern poly
hybrids that tend to have sort of
genetic disease vulner yeah yeah they've
they've actually yeah they've gone for
potency and who cares about and and when
people say oh it's a challenging strain
or really finicky strain there's another
way you could say
is that's kind of crap genetics if you
have a massively disease prone
plant that might actually be kind of
crappy genetics no one wants to yeah be
growing unless you're doing some
adoptive Foster thing for sickly plants
or something why why would you want to
grow plants that you have to spray
chemicals all over all the time to fend
off diseases how about just getting
genetics that naturally fend off
diseases but do you do you find that um
it takes some time with these varieties
for you to figure out their like basic
needs like I can imagine that these
different plants from different places
have got like different water
requirements and different uh you know
uh food amendments requirements actually
not really and I and I can totally see
where you might think that but uh here's
here's how we grow
uh we we don't actually really feed
throughout the entire year so what we
focus on and we uh grow in a hugle
culture
environment uh so so
where and what we do is we build a
really super nutrient
dense Super Rich living soil in the off
season and then by the time we plop that
plant in that soil come uh uh June May
or
June we don't actually feed those plants
throughout the whole year um so it's
what we're doing is we provide an all
you can eat
buffet of compost and organic nutrient
nutrients that along with all the uh
breaking down forest debris uh sticks
leaves uh chunks of logs and everything
and so now you have all the
melium that's just thriving in there so
it's kind of like the plant um can pick
and choose what it wants it's got an all
you can eat buffet and everything's
there at its root tips uh to absorb uh
so that's that's how we actually grow we
supercharge and get really living great
powerful living soil uh in the beginning
of the season and then the plants just
kind of adapt to that so we're not at
all running around going oh this these
Brazilians need some phosphorus or this
needs some magnesium like we don't do
that at all um the only time is maybe
some of these longer flowering plants
that get super super huge uh may just
need a little bit of uh nitrogen later
in the year if they start if they've
gobbled up all the uh nitrogen a lot of
times we'll do that with just a simple
like fish Emulsion compost tea uh to
just balance them out but but no there's
these are not
um yeah they they all basically they
they're all growing in the exact same
soil with the same nutrients same
watering and they kind of and they just
kind of
adapt so when when you're new to a land
race and you don't know whether or not
it's going to be you know a 4 foot wide
or a 10 foot wide plant do you just give
all your plants the same amount of space
and let them Express themselves or yeah
yeah yeah and we're in a uh fixed we
installed these hexagon
uh shaped uh planter boxes uh in the
soil so so you're not moving your grid
every year or anything it's like yeah so
and we gave them a lot of space because
we designed the garden uh for humans to
be wandering around this is not a row
crop yielding industrial Garden by any
means it's it's actually a Living Art
Exhibit of uh cannabis genetics from
around the
world it's cool just growing but then
that make it so much it just sounds like
a pleasure Garden dude oh so so we we
started this and we started having uh
visitors out and it was just so much fun
but this was preco and then covid hit
and you know we've kind of taken a break
from having visitors out uh and then the
Hop Lon vroid had me really freaked out
until now I I I have a much better
understanding of the risk um and such
and we're not in a high risk uh of
humans visiting and like transmitting
thank goodness so um but anyway yeah the
garden's designed to actually for humans
to wander around um where each box
actually has plenty of space in between
so you can actually if you're wandering
around socializing smoking a joy and you
resonate with a particular plant you can
then walk all the way around the
perimeter of that plant see it from all
angles uh uh and and such so that's yeah
we give the plants lots of space because
we kind of see each one as like a a work
of art uh and we want to give it its its
space to do its thing good good so um
how do you find that these and and like
I I recognize that you're Outdoors so
you may not have had done a lot of this
but I bet you you still have an educated
opinion on it like how how do these land
races that have never um you know been
cultivated by
present Growers how do they respond to
things like training and scrogging and
like kind of like like human dominance
we don't well that's exactly it like um
philosophically I I don't see my
relationship with the plant as where I'm
trying to dominate and squeeze out and
maximize and exploit every molecule of
that plant to pump out more buds for me
yeah right um so we we don't top
we don't Leaf we don't train we we're
just each one of these seeds is a
mystery and we want to see what this
plant's story is so we actually step
back and just let the plant do its thing
uh so we again we don't even Leaf these
plants um and what what you'll find
though when you let a plant just go
natural you you kind of get a Christmas
tree type shape
and
then it may be like hey how do but how
does light get into the inner buds but
the answer is as as the buds get heavier
on the tips of the branches that
actually opens the plant up as the
gravity pulls down those branches so now
all of a sudden the whole length of that
branch is now sort of the entire plant
is almost blooming like a
flower and opening up and now all of a
sudden the sun can get in to those uh
inner buds as well uh but then we also
do um because some of these plants are
you know 12 feet tall 10 feet diameter I
mean they're
huge uh so we don't harvest the entire
plant all at the same time we do like a
layered Harvest so we just take the top
right Buds and then that also allows the
sun to now penetrate further into the
plant and let those under buds develop
so we'll we'll do three or four harvests
off the same
plant uh while at the same time
just watching yeah we don't we don't do
we've given up on all the human
manipulations uh the one thing we do
though I should know is as far as you do
have to support the plant um so we just
put four Redwood
posts uh creating an out Outer you know
a box of post and then we take uh
organic hemp Baker twine so it's
actually food grade hemp
twine and we just run that twine sort of
like a big spiderweb around uh the plant
to support its branches so uh but that's
that's all we do so we're going to take
a short break and be right back um when
we come back we're going to be talking a
little bit about breeding land races and
a little bit more about uh preserving
land races so you are listening to
shaping fire and my guest today is land
race special specialist Jeff
[Music]
nordal the cannabis seed Market is
filled with big name and hype breeders
fighting to get your attention and
occasionally you discover a breeder who
is breeding because it is the only thing
they care to do and they would be doing
it even if they never made a dime that's
my friend Craig hardsaw who makes seeds
as magnetic genetics Craig comes from
five generations of farmers and is
earning his master's degree in
horiculture right now he's been growing
cannabis for 15 years and been breeding
for nine he hasn't sold many seeds
because he really isn't a sales guy but
I've personally been growing his seeds
for years and I know I can always rely
on his seeds to germinate Thrive and
smell and taste great I suggested to
Craig that he should probably sell some
seeds and asked if he had enough
stockpiled to bother much to my shock he
was sitting on five full menus in Cold
Storage that he produced in the last 2
years and hadn't even tried to sell any
of them he was simply too busy breeding
well we his friends convinced him to
make his damn seeds available to the
people and now they are for the first
time anywhere you can now buy magnetic
genetic seeds at Neptune Seedbank and on
strainly.io
Neptune Seedbank has just picked up
magnetic genetics for a trial to gauge
your interest they are carrying three
strains from his Mean Mug prominence and
tpon menus which are exclusive to
Neptune it's an easy way to score his
seeds you can pick up those menus plus
his hillbilly skunk and Candy breath
crosses and more on his profile page on
strainly.io
if you want very affordable seeds that
are exceptional quality with rare tpine
profiles from a good guy go to Neptune
seed bank.com or strainly.io
sometimes it is fun to buy the hype
thing from the brand you admire but when
you're ready to buy The Strain you love
from an obscure mad scientist you're
ready for magnetic genetics magnetic
genetics. org and on Instagram magnetic
genetics as cannabis regulations become
more demanding and consumers become more
educated it is increasingly important to
avoid the use of chemical pesticides
when cultivating cannabis beneficial
insects have been used for decades by
the greenhouse vegetable and ornamental
plant industry and today many cannabis
cultivators are moving from sprays and
chemicals to beneficial insects copert
has the beneficial insect mites and
nematodes microbials sticky cards and
air distribution units you need to
partner with nature to defend your
garden whether you manage Acres of
canopy or have a simple grow tent in
your home copt is ready to help answer
your questions and help you transition
away from chemical sprays towards clean
and natural
solutions since
1967 copert has assisted growers in
identifying pests and devising reliable
Solutions while providing healthy
insects and mites that will protect your
yield since the 1990s copert has been a
leader in cannabis Pest and Disease
Control worldwide and have highly
trained Consultants to assist you in
Canada and the United States from coast
to coast with their Global Network of
grower support copert can help visit
cooper.com choose your country and get
detailed information that's copert
ker.com for the most up-to-date cannabis
related biological control information
you can also check their Instagram at
copert Canada you know getting away from
pesticides is good for health and good
for business and copert is ready to help
visit ct.com
today there are so many seed banks
nowadays that you really have options in
who to choose not only that if you pick
the wrong seed bank you could be in for
a really sketchy ride and that's only
one of the reasons I recommend Gas Lamp
seeds to my friends and listeners who
are looking for a seed bank you probably
already know Gas Lamp seeds as hembra
genetics hembra recently changed their
name to Gas Lamp seeds Gas Lamp seeds is
not just another seed bank gas lamp is a
female operated Boutique cannabis
genetics provider that only sells
thoughtfully curated seeds from the top
names in cannabis breeding with over 60
breeders and over a thousand strains to
choose from you will certainly find
something you'll love gas lamp seeds has
something for everyone with over 650
feminized strains 300 regular varieties
and over 200 autof flowers to choose
from names you know you can trust like
compound genetics humble Seed Company
Night Owl inous fast buds gnome
automatics and Ethos and we both know
that there are other seed banks who will
take your money but have no customer
service I invited Gas Lamp to advertise
on shaping fire after hearing so many
many good stories about them from my
friends they have A+ customer service
with Lightning Fast Response times in
most cases Helen and Caitlyn will get
your order out the same day you place it
most seedbanks are simply not this
organized or interested in getting your
seeds to you so fast but Gas Lamp seeds
cares you even get free seeds with every
order Helen and Caitlin get it they have
been in the Cannabis growing scene for
over a decade want some extra freebies
use the code shaping fire all one word
at checkout and they will give you an
additional set of gas lamp provided
freebies that's an extra $30 in free
seeds buy seeds from good folks who will
send you great seeds reliably every time
visit Gaslamp seeds.com today that's
Gaslamp
seeds welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire I am your host Shango Los
and my guest today is land race
specialist Jeff nordal so here we are at
the big finish and you know during the
first set we figured out what the hell
land races are and during the second set
we talked about why we have all fallen
in love with them and and why anytime
the flower is available um serious uh
weed heads are like on it like catnip
because we know that that is the special
rare rare thing that we just you know
don't have as much access to anymore and
um and and they're beloved for good
reasons so in this last set we're going
to talk a little bit about breeding with
land races and then a little bit about
preserving land races so so Jeff you
know um you know we've already touched
on breeding a little bit earlier in the
show and um it's weird it's it's like
it's a two-sided coin right like on one
side breeding with land races is
exhilarating because we like the idea of
taking whatever our favorite you know
modern strain is and then and then bre
reading it to a land race strain to
perhaps like increase its Vigor or
increase its resistance to pass or to
grab some of those like you know old
school land race tarpine profiles
whatever it is that we're trying to do
or actually the other way um try to
breed a land race to a modern plant to
like cut down on how many weeks it takes
to flower so there's there's a lot of
like reasons that we may want to breed
with a land race but the flip side of
that also
is that every time we we breed a land
race that is less of that land race that
exists in its pure form for us to
preserve for you know medicinal
applications or for just enjoying that
land race in and of its own right so so
what are your what are you know I just
like to hear you speak to that about you
know like like like are you Crossing
land races to Modern hybrids or and what
are your thoughts about that
um yeah so uh there's there's two things
going on when you're sort of deciding to
work with land race plants and uh so
there's there's there's two goals
there's uh uh preservation so backing it
up so realizing that these are possibly
at risk of going Extinction so uh do a
seed uh reup or uh just an inline breed
where you're just preserving that uh
particular line of land race for
preservation uh but then you can go off
and start playing around and
experimenting and doing all kinds of
crosses and uh uh genetic hybrid work so
those are both totally valid things but
if you just
go uh full-blown hybrid and then lose
your it's again with the with the dog
breed thing you can't really take the
doodle out of the Doberman Piner you
know once it goes in there once once
you've bred that land race all those
attributes are all mixed
together yeah it would take lots of
generations to try and back it out to
get back to the original uh variety or
at least close to that so so there's
really uh so there's preservation going
on and that right now at my stage in
where I'm at in my cannabis
Adventures is we're popping new seeds
every year total mystery seeds uh from
these different uh regions of the world
uh even sometimes going back in time to
the 80s 7s
60s and then we're observing those and
right now we're focused on preserving
those genetics and uh to do that really
well uh you can't just go skipping down
into your garden with you know if you're
trying to pollinate let's say a
Vietnamese plant uh you may have your
male Vietnamese from that same seed
batch or hopefully like three four five
males so you're getting more genetic
diversity uh oh by the way that's
another thing you're trying to do with
your land R seed backups your genetic
backups is you're not doing a lot of
selection right then you're actually
trying to get the broadest uh gene pool
so you want to use as many females and
as many males from that Pride as you can
so then when you make let's say a
thousand seeds you're trying to capture
as much genetic diversity in that uh
seed backup and those are just
uh not primary colors but these are you
know your foundation building blocks of
cannabis breeding that you want to keep
pure uh uh but then once you have those
locked in and you have those seeds where
you're saving them in a good environment
that they're going to last you know 10
years plus still be
viable then you know then you have the
freedom to go start making crosses and
hybrids uh that where you're you know
trying to improve things or adapt things
for uh like here in California um you
know I may absolutely
love uh like a the the effect the high
that you got from a plant from LA
but it's a 16we
flower you know it's very difficult to
grow that Outdoors here in California
before the storms come in and just beat
the crap out of the plant and it may
even kill it you know uh so you may say
hey I I want that Lous effect but in a
plant that finishes you know in mid
October so then you you have to start
pondering what would be the least
intrusive early finishing plant that
might carry all the LA effects with it
on top of it you get what I mean so that
that's totally cool totally fair game I
don't think that's
disrespecting any cultures I don't think
that's culturally appropriating um as
long as you're crediting the The Wider
Global cannabis
Community um and and then our
transparent with how you created that
variety like say yeah if if a taii and a
Lous plant in an Afghan went together
you know document that and let people
know that's where that plant came from
those are its lineage then I think
that's um respectful as well to uh the
origins and the farmers who created
these plants um so that's that's
totally totally cool and and fair game
but uh the sort of ethical
shortsighted blunder would be to
immediately at least this is my opinion
just immediately start making hybrid
crosses without backing up and
preserving that original land race that
may have taken hundreds if not thousands
of
years to create that unique genetic when
you say back it up would that just be a
simple open pollination like in a tent
or something that way you're not you're
not losing the pollen into other plants
but you're just you're just letting them
all make more
seeds yeah yeah yeah yeah so sorry sorry
I kind of rambled on that so the thing
is if you're dealing with a lot of
varieties of uh pure lines of land
race uh you can't be sloppy with your
pollen and uh just bring pollen down
into your garden and potentially have
that pollen drift onto other plants
right uh so so the the technique that I
use that works well but I'm open to
other ideas if other people have come up
with other uh techniques that are work
is anyway what I do is we grow the land
race plants out in our land race
Botanical Garden that's where you get
the big 10 12 15 foot tall plants but
before those plants go into flower I
label each one of those plants with its
variet
plus its pheno number so it might be
Mexico
halisco three out of four alisco plants
were're growing so this one's number
three feno right so I'll take cuting off
that number three halisco
plant take those cuting to my other
property uh root those cuting and now I
have very
small oh versions of that plant right
that are now that are now I'm keeping
them in like a 3
gallon pot so now when I need to go
isolate them for pollinating I can
easily just move them around my property
um and and then uh the males I keep in a
a separate area and then we even isolate
our males for a time to make sure some
other plants pollen is not drifting onto
that male
plant uh so so we know we're getting
that just that pure uh pollen and then
that pollen gets taken to that very
isolated cluster of let's say halisco
number three uh but but when we're doing
let's say halisco if we had four plants
I would then put helisa one 2 three and
four cuting all in one area right so
we've got the
cuting all there they're now in flower
mode and then I hopefully we'll have
three four halisco males and I'll take
all that pollen from all four of those
males and then go evenly distribute that
over all the uh
cuting you get what I mean yeah I
totally follow and I really like the
idea I really like the idea that you
take the cuting early on when the plants
in your main Garden are in veg and then
you just move them away cuz honestly
before you explained that you had the
second property I was trying to picture
you safely pollinating these plants in
your garden with all 300 land races and
I'm like that sounds like hell man that
sounds impossible to
succeed oh now yeah you you you get
pollen drift I mean you kind of have to
treat pollen like Ebola you know it's
like it just gets everywhere it will
find a way the the cool thing that most
people know though is with uh pollen
water will immediately render it
nonviable so um uh that's another way to
get a dirty hippie to shower a lot too
is is to put him in charge of the oh
yeah I'll I take 10 showers a day if not
more you know when I'm uh in the middle
of doing breeding projects um but uh
yeah so that's so we do kind of an open
pollination but we do it on just a very
small uh with small little cuttings um
and my understanding at least is that
those those cuting from those original
plants are the exact same genetic so
those those seeds will be true to that
plant it just makes it uh you have a lot
more agility and easily being able to uh
isolate and move transport plants around
for
breeding cool so I want to I want to
continue down this uh this preserving
path that we've started on you know I
think a lot more people are thinking
about um you know land races you know I
guess I'm going to talk about two levels
of magnitude generally people are very
interested in land races because
especially if they're connoisseurs
because so much of modern cannabis takes
tastes the same so the interest in land
race is increasing and they are seen as
Elite and very desirable all of that's
true but also um you know as as kind of
like Global Travel uh for cannabis
people you know continues to increase
and along with the technological ways to
tell friends about them we're getting
experiences like uh like recently A lot
of people watched on Instagram like uh
you know Kevin jodrey and Danny Montero
and um and IG land race genetics like
they put together a group of people and
all went to Pakistan right and so um
like I was I was rivited by those videos
of of like people who I know and my
friends who are like suddenly in
Pakistan places where I normally only
see represented in like war and
terrorism movies you know and suddenly
they're all there like wearing beards um
you know in Pakistan and interacting
with the locals and and checking out
their hash and checking out their plants
and I was all like wow this is great
like like I wasn't you know on this trip
but I I feel like I I got a bunch of
these experiences from the trip right
and so it just increases the meaning and
value
of of land race seeds and genetics in My
overall head and so I I think that
there's more and more people who are
just interested in land races which is
good of course because you know the the
the the land race origin areas like
Thailand specifically are starting to
get
um uh we're like bunch of our people are
bringing seeds there and and developing
them in Thailand and so and so their
natural land races getting diluted right
so all of this is to set up this
question that um you know I can see that
land races are going to become
increasingly popular and yet we already
are trying to preserve them for
medicinal reasons um I'd like to hear
you speak to the idea of preservation
and a how do you think that um land
races are effectively preserved and B do
you think there's any chance in hell
that we're not actually going to
eventually lose all the land races
because they are a set number today and
that number is likely just probably
going to T continue to decrease but
maybe maybe I've got an um you know an
especially jaded view of it so I know
that's a big question but I'm just G to
like hand you the mic and hear what your
thoughts are yeah yeah so um yeah the
extinction through hybridization is
incredibly real and it's happening um so
so yeah a lot of people are sounding the
alarm like hey we really need to start
uh backing these up uh before they all
go extinct uh as far as these land races
so
um
and yeah so so yes that is really
happening and um so so the extinction is
a real concern period full stop ABS
absolutely um and and it's not just uh
like pollen
drift it's
actually you know folks we're going to
get to a point I mean we we've romantici
here in the US we may romanticize this
little secluded fantasy Village you know
in the
Himalayas you hike up to and you think
you're going to find this like amazing
weed that's grown by monks or something
or the whole village like grows his
magical weed uh and you take this track
up there and you get up there and
they're like hey we got
cookies we got
Coca-Cola yeah exactly and they're like
yeah we're we're growing gelato and
Diesel and OG and uh oh that's the kind
of cookies that you mean ah me I I
thought you meant like Western Foods you
mean no no no no no I mean it may be
that they're like blast in I mean no
it's cool but yeah they may be actually
blasting Snoop Dog growing you know
California strains up there and and we
of course romanticize that they're
supposed to stay isolated and unique uh
when in reality they want to they want
to grow the height too they want to
integrate and they they're watching
stuff in California and Amsterdam
thinking that's that's really cool why
would they want to gr grow their
grandfather's old larhe
weed so anyway these are just like
cultural phenomenons and things that
happen and there's no judgment or
anything you just have to realize that
that's this these are things that happen
um
so uh there seems to be some value in
preserving these genetics and a lot of
these genetics
um you know could go back hundreds if
not thousands of years and they're kind
of uh in a way almost like
cultural biographies or even
autobiographies from the actual breeders
you know antique art is too yeah and
they're infusing so it's a plant but
it's
also infused with uh cultures values and
their stories and so so in a way it's
almost like their uh cultural part of
their cultural story too you know just
like their food and their seasonings and
dishes and relig dance and religion and
the and the the Cannabis is a reflection
of those values and Aesthetics that
they've chosen for um so it just be a
super bummer to have
those disappear and uh just get
hybridized or or such um and then you
know once once some of these cultures
Also may go through like you know the
hype
phase there may be in like 20 years all
of a sudden reinter in in their heritage
genetics and if if someone wasn't
backing this stuff up you know it may be
gone um and it may be that they actually
have to look outside to other people who
who happen to keep those genetics you
know in their from their trip that they
took to that region they've been keeping
them in their sock drawer for the last
20 years you know so um there just seems
it doesn't seem to be
negative in any way by uh backing up and
preserving these genetic and it just
seems like a good Long
View uh strategy that there is value in
keeping these genetics around and
preserving them if if nothing more for
just historical purpose but i' argue
there's probably tons of medicinal uh
compounds and turpine combinations and
such that may actually
have some real uh medicinal value uh it
going into the future and uh and then
just the effects and everything else so
there's there's a lot of incentive and
reason that uh these genetics really
should be backed up so um um and and and
lots of different people around the
world are are playing different parts
either by uh Gathering in and hunting uh
these seeds and actually just collecting
them and then other people are sort of
Distributing them as hubs you know for
people who are uh interested in access
to these genetics um something that
we've sort of toyed around with here in
h Santa Cruz and something that i' I'd
really like to be a part of and even
potentially work with uh a larger
organization uh who has like grant money
and such but to actually put together um
an actual cannabis uh seed bank like a
public domain seed bank to try and back
up especially uh as far as land race
genetics uh try and back up and preserve
as much of those genetics as possible
but then very important
philosophically um that would be public
domain where everyone would have access
to these there's no proprietary
ownership
uh of of any of these genetics um and
you'd be you'd be preserving them for
their own right you don't mean like a
seed bank like people use seed bank now
very often as just like a seed bank
store or a seed bank distributor where
where where that there's there's the
profit moit motive primarily you're
talking about a more classical seed bank
like like those of us who save seeds
right where you're you're making a
library preservation yeah yeah the seed
preservation that's you know going on in
Norway or wherever yeah exactly that big
building that unsurprisingly flooded
yeah yeah so that those kind of uh seed
banks and uh like here
UCSC uh University California Santa Cruz
um did something else which was the
Human Genome Project where they ma the
entire Human Genome and then put that in
the public domain so they were in a race
with some of the pharmaceutical
companies and researchers who wanted
that information to be
proprietary but uh UCS and our sort of
hippie for the community sort of Vibes
at least UCSC decided to put that all in
the public domain so it's the Human
Genome Project where anyone uh can
actually access uh that information and
we'd like to see in that spirit uh
something with a
cannabis uh seed bank or library or
archive where everyone would have equal
access uh to all those genetics for you
know there'd be a procedure to obviously
to to get them but uh where yeah where
they're available to everyone because we
kind of come from the philosophy that
humans did not create cannabis it came
from the
universe and
so who who are we to claim ownership
it's cannabis is here for the people and
the magic of it is connecting more
people in a positive way uh with with
cannabis like that that has the
potential to actually shift things in a
positive trajectory for this plant but
if we're going to start playing these uh
ownership proprietary
exclusive uh commercial dollar chasing
games with a plant that generally when
you consume
it a lot of times has the opposite
effect or opposite
message that that would be yeah that's
definitely in the spirit of just the
Cannabis experience is making things
available to to everyone equal access
share the share the love break it down
cool man well I I think that that's a
great place to stop on that message I
really I really love that and and and so
Jeff I I want to I want to first thank
you for uh I know your time is valuable
and you know this time of year is really
busy as as you know you work through you
know your plants coming down and curing
and all that and so so thank you for
making Time For Us number one and then
number two I'm I'm really grateful like
kind of like for you as as your
personality you know you're such a
chipper easy to like guy on your
Instagram and and that is exactly you
know how you showed up authentically
here today I I I can't imagine there's
anybody who's been listening to the show
who wouldn't like a like to hear you
talk more and then B wouldn't enjoy like
sitting down for like lunch and a chat
on your deck with you you know you're
just you're such an amiable dude with
like such vast experience on this very
particular topic that we all get giddy
about so so thank you for for coming on
to shaping fire and and and and sharing
with us your experience cool well it's
been been a been a pleasure thanks for
the interest and uh yeah and some point
in the future our our plan is to
actually have people come out and visit
our our property so we can just sit
there and geek out and nerd out and
stand there in a staring at these
amazing plants so so that that is the
goal and uh with Co and everything it
made it tough to have visitors so those
videos that you've watched really is is
coming from that um uh intent is
actually wanting to share share these
plants with others and Inspire others to
take a closer look and maybe delve into
uh the
unlimited infinitely fan uh amazing land
race World fantastic all right so so in
wrapping up dear listener um if you
would like to uh keep tabs on uh Jeff
and his uh land race amusement park that
he runs um uh I recommend at the top of
the list um you follow him the way I do
on Instagram and so that's really e easy
that's Jade nectar all one word now uh
that that is an absolute have to if you
want to know more about uh Jeff and um
his uh medicinal preparations he is a an
expert in the acid forms of cannabinoids
uh he even holds us patents which uh is
not something that we was on the topic
today but he's a very interesting cat so
you can find out more about that aspect
of his Goodwill at his at his website
which is Jade nectar.com and then
finally um if you want to see uh
sometimes longer forms of the videos
that are on the Instagram um you can
also search uh Jade nectar uh on YouTube
uh for for some of the longer forms of
the video videos you can find more
episodes of the shaping fire podcast And
subscribe to the show at shaping
fire.com and wherever you get your
podcasts if you enjoyed the show we'd
really appreciate it if you would leave
a positive review of the podcast
wherever you download your review will
help others find the show so they can
enjoy it too on the shaping fire website
you can also subscribe to the newsletter
for insights into the latest Cannabis
News exclusive videos and giveaways on
the shaping fire website you'll also
find transcripts of today's podcast as
well be sure to follow on Instagram for
all original content not found on the
podcast that's @ shaping fire and Shango
on Instagram be sure to check out
shaping fire YouTube channel for
exclusive interviews farm tours and
cannabis lectures does your company want
to reach our national audience of
cannabis enthusiasts email hotspot
shaping fire.com to find out how thanks
for listening to shaping fire I've been
your host Shango
Los