[Music]
cultivating cannabis Under the Sun has
been my preference during the last 10
years my first years cultivating
cannabis it was my preference because I
absolutely believe that sun grown
cannabis has wider turpine and
cannabinoid profiles thus making it
excellent medicine that said I also know
Sun grown is leafier and living where I
live on Vashon Island in the Pacific
Northwest plants rarely finish outside
so outdoor plants may be superior in
many ways philosophically but in reality
where I live anything that takes more
than 50 days to bloom doesn't have a
chance to finish for those of you who
follow shaping fire you know that this
is one of the reasons I've become such a
proponent and supporter of autof flowers
I like that I can Harvest them fully
flowered in warm dry and sunny September
so about a year ago I decided I wanted
to try my hand at growing indoors it was
a struggle for me to decide because I
identify as a regeneratively minded
cannabis cultivator and struggled with
the idea of using electricity to power
my lights in the end I decided to buy an
exceptionally environmentally friendly
bios LED light and went forward growing
a 4x4 tent inside in hopes of growing my
own cannabis medicine with fully
finished flowers and the little tent
grow would also Act as a good
demonstration to teach from on Instagram
so I could help other patients I reached
out to soil biologist Leon Morrison and
asked him to guide me in setting up a
horizon style substrate as he outlined
in shaping Fire episode 54 on geology
and biomimicry he said sure and off I
went to try and build an indoor raised
bed using all of the regenerative and
living soil techniques I use every
summer Outdoors
These Are the Voyages of the shaping
fire living soil tent its mission to
explore strange soil biology to seek out
best practices and fire flow to boldly
go where nature guides
us if you want to learn about cannabis
Health business and technique
efficiently and with good cheer I
encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter we'll send you new podcast
episodes as they come out delivered
right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most news
items from the week and videos too don't
rely on social media to let you know
when a new episode is published sign up
for the updates to make sure you don't
miss an episode also we're giving away
very cool prizes to folks who are signed
up to receive the newsletter there's
nothing else you need to do to win
except receive that newsletter so go to
shaping fire.com to sign up for the
newsletter and be entered into this
month's and all future newsletter prize
drawings you are listening to shaping
fire and I'm your host Shango Los today
my returning guest is late
Morrison Leighton is a lifelong
Enthusiast of both aquaponics and living
soil his obsession with Biosphere 2 led
him to set up an aquaculture at The
rodale Institute Leon worked with
world-renowned biologist Dr Elaine Ingam
blending his aquaculture byproducts with
compost and worm castings to prove that
natural imputs could replace synthetics
in commercial cultivation Leighton
consults widely for agriculture soil
regeneration and Commercial Land
Management projects through throughout
the United States Leon is currently
founder of Kingdom aquaponics and
invented their line of living compost
and compost tea living soil products
Leon is a sought-after speaker and
co-host of a weekly podcast on the
future cannabis project YouTube channel
one note both Leon and I lost loved ones
this week and this episode is a bit less
Jolly than most of the times that we're
together if we sound a bit off that's
why we're sad during today's episode we
will describe in detail the first cycle
of the shaping fire Horizon style indoor
raised bed during the first set we will
review how I set up the substrate
Horizons during the second set we will
discuss our soil tests the arrival of
the first pests and any risk of a
perched water table and then during the
third set we'll talk about ground covers
scrogging and growing mushrooms in the
substrate below the Canabis plants
welcome back to shaping fire
Leighton thanks Shango it's always a
pleasure to come back and and chop it up
with you right on and you know this is
kind of a different show right because
uh you know often when I have you on the
show to talk about something within your
expertise um you know I'm essentially
trying to draw out you know this this
this academic and practiced information
out of you but but today we're you know
you're here because you taught me you
know this this biomimicry style or what
people are call calling Horizon style
growing technique and um and I figured
if I was going to do a show where I kind
of did a debrief of how my first cycle
went then might as well have you here so
so thank you for both teaching me the
style and then coming back to help me
tell everybody what I did
wrong well thank you for uh being a
sacrifice sacrificial lamb today right
on all right so so you know the I want
to remind everybody before we get going
that the application of your strategy
can look a lot of different ways right
like you can plug in different soil
recipes into this model and it'll still
work great so so don't get hung up on my
own choices of specific inputs like for
example like you you can get nitrogen a
lot of different ways I personally have
had excellent success over the years
with dehydrated pigs blood that may not
be your preference though so don't get
hung up it doesn't matter like what your
inputs are to learn the substrate style
it's all about the division and the
percentages of clay silt sand organic
matter and that that's the Cornerstone
of this approach so like like during
this first set you're going to hear what
I use um but it may not be what you use
so so don't get too hung up on that um
so so let's start out by talking about
um uh how your um
biomimicry um Horizon style played out
in real terms for for my bed so I use a
grass Roots fabric pots 4x4 raised bed
in a 4x4 tent um in uh in the shaping
fire offices so so what that gives me is
an 18in soil depth with about you know 2
or three Ines of um hardwood matter on
top and we'll talk about that hardwood
matter uh later so so if you are working
in a container that's deeper than 18
Ines um your numbers are going to be a
little bit different than mine which is
why we're going to be giving you
percentages of these different areas so
so when we go through this remember
these numbers are based on my 18-in soil
depth from a Grassroots fabric pots 4x4
all right so with that said there are
there are three layers in a um Horizon
style bed the the top layer is the O
Horizon next down is the a horizon and
then under that is the E Horizon so so
if you take that 18 in the in in in in
Leighton style and by by the point L at
any point if I'm like saying this wrong
feel free to correct me well you did say
percentage and you really shouldn't you
should say fraction so basically the hor
horizonal soil system is based on a
seven-part system so your e Horizon is
17th your a horizon is 27th and your o
Horizon is 47th
so that's the easy way to break it up so
whatever your depth is divide it by
seven and and then you know use that as
a uh method to um building the the
proper depths fabulous so I took that
math and and Lon and I uh applied it to
the 18 in and so that ends up with an O
Horizon your top layer your o Horizon
for my bed is 10 in and so that's all
going to be organic matter and so um for
me I chose to use no till soil that from
pots that I've been using the last few
years and um and and and so it's it's
it's in quarters it's a quarter old soil
it's a quarter fish compost a quarter
pit moss and a quarter um Alliance soil
inoculant which which actually is a
product that um that lat makes which is
essentially a uh an incredibly living
soil would that be a fair thing to call
it well it's really just kind of um
organic matter that has been infused
with with fish biology and um soil
terrestrial biology you know it's just
basically I make this very biologically
Rich compost I strip it mechanically um
and add uh fish Brew uh bold flow um to
it as I'm stripping it so it once it
comes out of the stripping process then
I screen it out um to different um
coarseness and so the alliance is a very
coarse product so it's kind of like a
you know you fibrous compost but it's
incredibly biologically active so you
know if you want to get that from
Leighton you can and and it will
certainly help get your bed going but
theoretically if if you didn't want to
get something like that you could double
up on your
um you know your no till soil you're
bringing in from your outdoor pots and
then go with you know half soil a
quarter fish compost and a quarter pit
moss in my case because um I'm not a big
fan of using Pete Moss um because I
don't I don't I don't see it as being a
renewable resource and they destroy pit
bogs to get it so or Pete boogs rather
to get it so so I'm very happy with the
pit Moss which is made out of um uh uh
um uh organic uh paper and I find that
works really well so in my case I've got
a quarter my regen soil a quarter fish
compost a quarter pit moss and a quarter
of this uh super infused stuff from
Laton now let me ask you this um did you
get the grower grade or did you get the
cocoa
complete um of the pit Moss yeah I just
got this they have a few different
products yeah I just got this the uh I
forget actually the name of it probably
Growers but but but it's it's the strip
down stuff I got this stuff without any
added nutrition okay and so I wanted to
control that perfect great so so th
those are the major components and and
within that I also put my amendments
right um the Amendments like the
physical amount of them is so uh small
that it really doesn't um play a role in
the overall recipe as far as like like
how the soil is built the adding the
nutrition you know you could probably
hold it in you know in four hands right
so but for me I chose uh crushed oyster
shells uh Ali fish compost dehydrated
organic pigs blood of course dynamico
fungal inoculant uh pit moss and then uh
that supercharged supercharged soil
inoculant from Leighton so so so you
take that and you mix that all up and
that becomes what but what we're calling
here your organic matter um so so Leon
do you like how I describ that yeah no I
think you described it perfectly you
know it's it's basically you're building
a soiless medium or a super soil um you
know because you're adding the
Amendments we would tend to call that a
super soil over a soiless medium but
that's you know that's the bottom line
is you're you're you're still using a
traditional style of growing cannabis um
but you've also got those added benefits
of the e Horizon and the a horizon to
help mitigate moisture as well as
provide sand silt and Clay uh for the
organic or for the bio uh biology to
mine and and provide nutrient did you
intend to call this a soiless medium I
mean it's half soil um well no the top
the O Horizon is a traditional soiless
medium but isn't half of that like soil
like a quarter of it is my um my no till
soil from my pots and then another
quarter of it is the compost that you
make isn't doesn't that count as soil I
mean I always thought that soil less as
like quar and Pete and you know perlite
and all that stuff that actually isn't
soil correct and and you know I may have
misspoke because I don't really know
what your no till soil pot was like was
it Pete was it no it's none of that it
was it was like it was just um like
literally old soil that got originally
out of bags that was just like potting
soil so but then I I used it for five
years right so so it was it was like uh
bad soil gone good you know so it was
broken down yeah yeah totally so then
yes I would refer this to more as a soil
than a soil as medium although you do
have soil as medium components in it uh
yeah the pit Moss right correct and
compost because compost is not
soil eventually it'll break down to soil
but in in the beginning parts of the
composting process it's more of a
nutrient Rich uh material than it is per
se a soil but we can you know we don't
we don't need to get too crazy on the
finites all right so so that's that's
your top 10 in in when you're talking
about an 18in bed so so um so then your
next layer down is what's called your a
horizon and when using leighton's 7ths
model uh if you have an 18in bed this
next layer this a horizon is 5 in and
the a horizon is made up of uh 177% clay
133% silt 50% sand and then the last 20%
is another portion of the organic matter
mix that you made for the O Horizon so
when you're making the the organic
matter for your o Horizon you're going
to want to make you know enough to fill
up the O Horizon plus some extra to go
in the a horizon and then and then and
then at the end also I threw in a splash
of biochar I mean biochar is so potent
um you know I just like took a couple
handfuls and throw it threw it in there
so it was there but um you know it's um
it's such a small component of it one of
the crazy things about this is you know
since I was trying to make this bed as
regenerative as possible um with the
obvious uh exception of uh the fact that
it was indoors and I was using
electricity um I decided that I wanted
to Wildcraft all this stuff and um wow
depending on where you live your mileage
may vary trying to do that um the clay
was easy right as many of you know I
live on an island and then uh along the
outskirts of our Island along the
beaches um we have got all sorts of soil
erosion that is going into uh you know
the saltwater and so getting clay for me
was really easy I just I just went down
and there were big hunks of beautiful
clay that were just falling off the Clay
wall where you could see all the all the
layers of of Earth exposed from you know
the ocean water um eroding it so that
was that was great grabbing the clay was
easy heavy as hell but but easy to get
and then uh the sand was certainly easy
as well since I live on an island um I
could just collect some sand and when
you're doing only doing a 4x4 bed you're
hardly taking any you know it's like a
like 5 gallon bucket you know um the
hard part for me was this damn silt um
you know I I I understood from Leighton
that I'm I wanted to look for silt um
along uh running fresh water that was
heading towards um the salt water um
around the island and so I I looked at I
first I went to an estuary on the island
where the where the fresh water meets
the salt water and I grabbed a bunch of
that and I took it home and I gave it a
shake test in a mason jar and um and the
component of silt was very low Leon why
don't you explain how to do a uh a mason
jar Shake test for people who have never
done that sure it's it's a home or an at
home um textural test so basically you
fill a mason jar um 3/4 full of soil
then you add water till waterers just
above the top of the soil that you added
while still leaving an air space um then
you seal the lid Shake It Up set it down
and over the course of two days um
what'll happen is everything will settle
and the water will go clear and that's
the key you want that water to be clear
um and then you will see the layers the
first layer um the sand will settle out
the fastest um second the silt will
settle out and lastly the clay will
settle out and usually you'll get some
organic matter floating on the surface
of the water water or floating on just
on top of the clay layer so you
basically get sand so clay and organic
matter um ratios or percentages uh by
doing this um and so I I did this and
and and every time I took a sample it
was like almost all clay there was
hardly any silt and so so after I did
that and and was not getting a high
enough silt percentage where the the
fresh water was meeting the saltwater at
the Estuary I decided to work my way
backwards up that stream uh further up
so I'm like okay maybe instead of doing
Estuary maybe I should take it um from a
long stream right maybe maybe it'll be
more silt there and so I took another
sample there brought it home shook it up
let it sit for 2 days looked at it and
there was more silt but still not enough
where I thought that I was going to be
able to like divide it off to be able to
get 133% silt in my a horizon so I'm
like damn I still need more so then so
then I worked my way um up even further
fur um I I I was planning on going up as
far as a a freshwater Pond that was up
this stream but what I found was an
elbow in the Stream um where it was not
going straight downhill it came down and
it kind of like Jagged right and then it
continued down and in that elbow I found
silt so for whatever biomechanics re
reason that elbow held the silt better
than the other two places and when I
took it um you know it's it still wasn't
like 80% silt like I was hoping but it
was like 50% silt and that was like way
way better than anything else I had
gotten so I'm like fine we're just going
to call this good um and uh cuz it you
know it's always good to remember that
this while while we have goals we we
have we have benchmarks for we're trying
to hit um if if you can't hit the
benchmarks with what you have available
locally just freaking go for it and so I
did and um and and so that's where I
harvested um you know just a little bit
of silt because again this is only a 4x4
bed and I grabbed it and uh and then
added that as my 133% silt so I guess
technically in my math since I was using
material that was only 50% silt as my
133% silt I probably only have 7% silt
in my bed and um you know for better for
worse um and uh you know I didn't I
wasn't sure how to make up for that silt
and I don't think I did this right but I
actually tried to make up for some of
the silt by adding some volcanic aadama
clay from Japan that I had and and I'm
I'm not recommending you do that right
cuz bringing bringing clay from Japan
for this is like so environmentally a
bad idea um but I happen to already have
the stuff from when I was doing uh
aquariums back in the day and I'm all
like he this is a good use for it so um
so I put that in there so so before we
go on um is there any way that that
makes sense Leighton using aad volcanic
clay as a replacement for silt or is
that just like totally wrong no you know
there's
a technical challenge
to making a definitive difference
between silt and Clay um I try to stick
along the lines of that silt is organic
matter broken down uh about as far as it
can um without specialty um bacteria to
break it down further um Clay is more
like groundup rock um or ash from a
volcano so bottom line is though they're
the very very fine small particles that
have been pretty much broken down uh as
much as they can through natural
processes other than these really finite
special um bacteria that can continue to
break them down further um and make them
again uh plant available so that the
plant can uptake those minerals um and
then when the plant dies uh guess what
it goes back to silt so it gets
really uh complicated at that
microscopic level of what is what is a
clay playd what is a Sil particle um
traditional soil and
science has always measured these uh by
particle size and I think that's you
know again kind of archaic in this day
and age where we know that the clay
platelets are both positive and
negatively charged so that the top of
the clay platelet is is um positively
charged and the outer rim think of it as
a flying saucer the outer rim is
negatively charged so the negatively
charged Rim pulls positively charged
cations I and stores them so these are
nutrients um around the outside
perimeter so silt doesn't do that um
silt is is generally negatively charged
um does not have a positive uh aspect
though it so and sand is is has no
charge so how do we Define these as
through particle size and not through um
characteristics of perhaps both weight
um and also um the ability to hold
certain nutrients so I you know again I
think that soil science has got to kind
of come up to speed with what we know as
far as um you know some of these more
advanced understandings of these
materials so it sounds to me that even
even though I used even though I used
that volcanic aadama clay like that's
cute and that filled up the place but it
really wasn't a silt replacement it was
just something else that probably helped
the bed and let me ask you a question
when you when you did your silt test
what was the other component was it clay
or was it
sand uh it was sand okay so so here
again you know you can use that
combination
um to understanding that okay of this
material I collected in the Stream uh
50% of it was sand 50% of it was silt so
now I just use more of that and don't
add any sand you see where I'm going
with this I do so that's you know again
you you have to do a little bit of math
and and apply some common sense but you
can get pretty close to these ratios
especially if you're using um this
textual uh at home test method to
determine exactly what your inputs are
and and then just kind of play with them
a little bit and and again I use the
ratio 17 clay 13 silt based on their
properties um so if you're off on your
ratios it's not the end of the world um
but again you know your goal is to try
to get as close as you can to that um
for biological processes so that you're
allowing the specific biology that
breaks clay down that does doesn't break
silt down and vice versa so you're just
providing all of these inputs for really
getting that advanced level of of uh
living um biology to have all of the
potential um tools and uh methods to to
function at high level and again you
know we haven't even started talking
about fungi uh because they also are
really important in breaking those
things down and pulling out uh nutrients
as well as you know providing bofilm to
make Aggregates out of them but we'll
get into that in a little bit so so the
last thing that's in this a horizon is
like that splash of biochar I just I
just put in three handfuls and um is
there a reason why the biochar goes in
the a horizon instead of in the top of
the O Horizon you know you can go in
either place um generally I would
probably be more thrilled to throw it
into the O Horizon so that it's really
going to be like a little condominium
for for biology to set up shop in but in
the a horizon it's fine I mean the roots
are going to get down into the a anyway
so it's either way and and you know I
encourage people too to get real
creative with their Horizon there's no
reason why you can't put some you know
old hay or or some leaves that you've
collected or some Forest stuff in there
you know it's again diversity diversity
diversity I'm all about that and All
That Forest stuff is going to be
biologically active with local microbes
too so you know that's always an yeah
extra extra win okay so so so far we've
got the first top 10 in is the O Horizon
of organic matter and then next down is
the a horizon that is 5 in which is the
clay salt sand and a little bit more
organic matter and then on the bottom of
the bed the last 3 in is the E Horizon
which is sand and rocks and um and you
know you you could use bagged sand if
you know if you live in an urban
environment or something I'm lucky that
I just happened to live on an island and
so sand is everywhere and um and I loved
the idea that it came already living
with uh you know water-based imos that
also were oxygen tolerant since the the
the the water the tide goes up and down
right so um I grabbed a bit of sand from
the beach and then uh so so Leon why
don't you explain why you recommend the
Rocks should be
multicolored well every color um is
indicates a level of mineral um so the
different colors represent different
parts of the periodic table so the more
colors you get the more variety of those
minerals um are available for the micro
Iz to mine um and you know something
else um that you said about bag sand
just be careful not to get play sand you
don't want the white fluffy stuff you
want coarse should be taupe color or
yellowish or brownish um that's the type
of sand you want not the white powdery
stuff that's important right on yeah
that white powdery stuff that's more
like overprocessed uh like white flour
you know right yeah you you want you
want chewy stuff and and I encourage
everybody to um take a 5 gallon bucket
and fill it half full of sand and then
take measurable gallons of water and
dump it into that bucket until you see
the water just going over the top of the
sand and then look at how many jugs you
used you will be blown away at how much
water coarse sand can actually
hold right on so so so so Leighton
explaining to me why having multicolored
rocks started me on a very difficult
process because I was down on the beach
and and I was token and I was looking at
all the colors of all the different
rocks on the beach and I'm like you know
I can I can collect these rocks and I'll
have like you know 15 different colors
this is going to be the the best bed
ever and so and so I started collecting
these rocks and um and then you know
Leighton had told me that uh if you can
break the Rocks open like crack the
Rocks because if you're if you're wild
crafting rocks um they have gotten SM
smooth on the outside and they don't
leech their minerals uh very very
conveniently and so he's all like you
know if you can hit it with a hammer and
break it open um you'll have the raw
interior so that the minerals can be
extracted well I was all excited about
that so so I started collecting rocks
and then I put them in a burlap bag and
then I took my sledgehammer to it to
break them open and then oh that was
great so I poured those into a 5 gallon
bucket and then I grabbed another
bag of burlap bag full and I hit that
with a sledgehammer and I did that for
like an hour got totally exhausted all
sore and I'm like all right I got my
damn rocks and I bring them in the house
and I put them in the bed and they were
like this little dribbling in the corner
of this big ass bed and I'm like oh [__]
I have to do three in of the whole bed
of this and I'm like
no I'm like I'm I I do not have the
strength and the time and the life and
the muscle for this and so um what I
what I decided to do is um I did that
process like four more times so that
let's say like maybe an inch of the 3 in
was hand wildcrafted and hand broken up
rocks and then um then I went to the uh
the Landscaping store and and I bought
like I honestly don't know what the Rock
is anymore I forget but it was it was
just there like straight up gray
drainage rock that they use for
landscaping and I just poured bags of
that in there so um I say this a so you
can laugh at me but but but also to to
realize that you know we can only do
what we can do and uh when I realized
how much physical labor that was going
to be I just decided that you know what
having some natural rocks from the wild
environment that's great um but you know
what I'm going to have to to finish the
fill with what I can just go buy and
dump and that's what I did and I got
great results but um I just figured it
was worthwhile cuz if if you are going
to try to Wildcraft your
inputs you're bound to run into
something that's hard to find where you
live and just don't stress about it
right just just grab some stuff and move
on I agreed agreed there's no such thing
as perfection in nature so don't try to
be
perfect so it's really exciting when you
get to this next part and you um and you
get to put everything in the bed right
at this point in the process it was kind
of like um you know like uh you know if
you're if you're having you know a chef
night and you're making something
special at home you can use the the
French strategy of Mison place right
where you where you get all your
ingredients you cut everything up and
you put them in like little ramkin there
on your counter and then once all your
ingredients are set then you go and you
make your meal this is kind of Mison
place but for like soil science I went
ahead and I collected everything I got
everything ready and then the day came
that I made the bed now I want to put in
here something that I did not realize I
should have had until afterwards so I
don't have this in my bed but after I
made the bed leighton's all like oh you
should put a 4 in p 4 in PVC tube along
one of the corners so you can see how
much water's in the bottom and I'm like
what I'm not digging that corner back
out no and and so but but if I were to
do this again I would do this so so
Leighton would you explain in retrospect
why you know you recommended that I did
that because you couldn't get your hand
down between the liner and the tent so
there's no way for you to see other than
if you
overflow because you did put a liner
underneath there correct a rubber liner
yeah so the rubber liner serves as a way
to prevent
um any excess moisture from leaking out
around the bottom of your tent
unfortunately with the grassroot pots
they fit perfectly in a 4x4 tent with no
room for you to get your hand between
the liner the pot itself and the tent so
that's where I would suggest it to you
to to set that piece of pipe because and
it doesn't even have to be 4 in it can
be 1 in and you basically take two
styrofoam balls and a dowel and you drop
that styrofoam well you take a Styrofoam
ball put put the dowel into it so that
the ball stays on it and then take the
other one and slide it down till it's
about 8 or 10 inches above the bottom
one and then you just drop that whole
thing right into the tube and then as
you water that little dowel is going to
come up and you're going to be able to
determine exactly how much water is
being stored in your e Horizon and and
never flood it because you actually know
oh [__] I've added 20 gallons to this
thing um it's not leaking out where's my
level and you'll see oh wow my level's
at 2 and half inches so it gives you a
way to monitor um just how much water is
actually being stored in your e or your
aquafer because that's basically what
you created is an
aquifer and I and I do recommend that
you do that and I'll and I'll use that
next time so I'm at the point now that
the only time that I can really check
how much water is in my e Horizon is
when I go to take a soil test and I dig
in deep I just go dig in extra deep all
the way down to my e Horizon and put my
hand there and see how much water is
there and you know that is not efficient
at all that's like you know testing my
water checking my water table once at
the beginning of a run and once at the
end of a run and twice a run you know
it's worked out for me so far but I do
wish that I had that that um that
vertical tube um just stuck in one of
the corners so I could check that out
yeah it just makes it easier yeah right
on so okay so uh so here we are at the
end of set one um we have gone through a
an explanation of the O Horizon the a
horizon the E Horizon both what I did
and more how to think about it right
because this is kind of an algorithm and
you know what you choose to use will
vary and the size of your bed is going
to be different so your um uh how your
how much you need to make to fill up
your
sevenths um is going to be different but
but more we're just trying to make sure
you understand the the the idea behind
it so you can play out this algorithm
for yourself so uh Leon anything else
you want to add to this before we go to
break no I think you covered it and and
again you know it's all about diversity
so you know colors are important
textures are important um using your
local resources is very important
um if you have to buy something you have
to buy something it's not the end of the
world but again you know you're looking
for uh if you're buying sand you want
very coarse sand so like masonary sand
um you know and as far as you know the
rocks and stuff one one piece I do want
to really kind of reiterate is that when
you're when you're putting those rocks
in there you don't have to fill all 2
and 1 half to three Ines in rock it can
be you know onethird rock and the rest
can be sand but make sure you wash the
sand down into the Rocks you don't want
to have any voids whatsoever if you have
voids then organic matter is going to
get down in there and it's going to go
Anor robic so the E Horizon really
functions as a what's called sand filter
so a sand filter is uh is generally used
in you know golf courses to move
groundwater around um they can also be
used in in zoos to separate um water
that has a lot of duck manure in it um
so it's it's a it's a technique that
that prevents organic matter or fine
particulate from getting down into that
um water layer so you're basically
separating fine particulate from water
itself and that's the beauty of the E is
that it acts as a as a sand filter and
and if you're interested in sand filters
I encourage you to go back to the
shaping Fire episode with um Steven
raisner about the water food web and how
to use aquaponics with living soil
systems we talk about that a little bit
there so oh and uh Leighton I wish you
would have told me I didn't have to have
three Ines of all rocks
man I think I missed that in my notes
when we originally talked so oh that's
all right it's all a learning process it
sure is so uh so we're going to take our
first short break and be right back you
are listening to shaping fire and my
guest today is soil biologist Leighton
[Music]
Morrison there are so many seed banks
nowadays that you really have options in
who to choose not only that if you pick
the wrong seed bank you could be in for
a really sketchy ride and that's only
one of the reasons I recommend hembra
genetics collection to my friends and
listeners who are looking for a seed
bank that's hembra spelled h m b r a
hembra is not just another Seedbank
hembra is a woman operated Boutique
cannabis genetics provider that only
sells thoughtfully curated seeds from
the top names in cannabis breeding with
over 50 breeders and over 500 strains to
choose from you will certainly find
something you'll love hembra genetics
has something for everyone with over 350
feminized strains 200 regular varieties
and over a 100 Auto flowers to choose
from names you know you can trust like
Humbolt Seed Company Night Owl canado
inhouse genetics fast Buds and gnome
automatics we both know that there are
other seed banks who will take your
money but have no customer service I
invited hembra to advertise on shaping
fire after hearing so many good stories
about them from my friends they have A+
customer service with Lightning Fast
Response times in most cases Helen and
Caitlyn will get your order out the same
day you place it and you'll usually
receive your seeds in just a few days
most seed banks are simply not this
organized or interested in getting your
seeds to you this fast but Hambra cares
you even get free seeds with every order
Helen and Caitlyn get it they have been
in the Cannabis growing scene for over a
decade so save a few bucks by using this
discount code too use the code shaping
fire all one word at checkout to save
10% off your order buy seeds from good
folks who will get you great seeds
reliably every time visit hembra
genetics.com today That's hembra
[Music]
genetics cannabis folks are innovators
and problem solvers and we like to make
money have you developed a tool
technique or plant that you want to
protect and monetize you'll likely want
legal representation that is experienced
accessible and shares your values plant
and Planet law represents a wide variety
of clients who choose to respect the
environment while pursuing their
business goals have you invented a
machine or Gizmo that you're bringing to
Market did you discover a breakthrough
environmentally friendly pesticide or
fertilizer formulation that you're about
to start selling have you bred a
cannabis plant with attributes not found
anywhere else a attorney Dale Hunt and
his plant and Planet team have
established genetic patents in over 30
countries working to help entrepreneurs
scientists throughout the life sciences
plant and Planet represents
environmentally positive clients in
cannabis and other Botanicals fungi
water purification clean energy
emulsions and medical
applications plant and Planet helps
people protect what they've created if
you are an early stage company with an
established idea and are in the process
of fundraising often the investors
require intellectual property
protections happen at the same time
plant and planet can be your sole
representation or they can integrate
with your existing legal team and plug
in their Specialties plant and planet is
made of scientists lawyers with a real
passion for cannabis inventions and the
environment they have the scientific and
legal depth to help you establish patent
protections for your great idea you
don't have to go It Alone friendly
qualified and honorable legal
representation is available to you
contact plant and Planet law today to
start the conversation email
info@ pland planet.com that's plant and
Planet law our clients make the planet
[Music]
better one of the reasons why no till
cannabis growing is so valued by Farmers
is because the mycelium networks in the
soil remain established from year to
year and we know these fungal networks
are essential because they are the
nutrient super highways that extend far
and wide in the substrate to feed your
plants the trouble with growing in New
Living soils or Blended cocoa substrates
is that it takes most of the plant's
life just to create these mycelium
highways dinico endom micral fungi
inoculant reduces that time and gets
your plant eating a wider array of
nutrients faster and it's three times
the concentration of the other popular
brand in the US at 900 propagules per
gram of two fungal species selected
specifically for cannabis cultivation
dinica is the result of 30 years of
research and trials at the volani
agriculture Research Institute in Israel
it has also been vigorously Tried by
cannabis and food Growers across the US
dynamico is now available at Grow shops
and on Amazon in the United States I
love using dynamico to both speed up the
growth of the melium networks in the
soil but also as a bio stimulant to to
make clone cuting more viral you can see
side byid showing the comparative growth
on their Instagram at
dinico if you demand reliable growing
results and appreciate the importance of
an active root Zone in creating a
thriving plant I encourage you to check
out dino.com and use the store locator
to find out where you can get yours
that's d y n m
y.com shaping fire listeners can get 10%
off any size of Dynam
on Amazon or dynamic.com by using the
discount code shaping fire onew no caps
whether you are starting with new beds
or pots or if you want to add some Zing
to tired soil choose dinico to maximize
your plant's potential dynamico endom
micro risal
inoculant welcome back you are listening
to shaping fire I am your host Shango
Los and my guest today is soil biologist
Leighton Morrison so in the first set we
talked um about
um how the horizons are actually set up
and the and the uh how much of each um
in set two we're going to start talking
about um how this uh soil act the uh
some of the attributes that it showed
and um right off the bat uh the first
attribute that it showed was uh fungus
knats and so um you know it's funny
there is a u there's a Bro Science thing
that you know is is actually you know
pretty good in a lot of cases which is
don't bring your soil from Outdoors
indoors because when you bring in
outdoor soil indoors you are bringing in
a lot of variables you're bringing in
potential pests you are prob you're all
bringing in allies Predator allies as
well but you're bringing in just like a
lot of variables because um you don't
know what's in it um but I really wanted
to use my aged no till soil that I've
been have using in my pots and amending
for like the last five or six years the
soil is just absolutely freaking
fantastic so I was clear that I was
going to bring outdoor soil indoors and
uh you know when I when I told that to a
lot of my my peers they're like oh
that's so dangerous and and yeah that it
is dangerous but I was willing to go for
it because I really wanted the living
biology so um brought in the soil made
the O Horizon um put it on the uh the
bed and then turned on my uh super sexy
bios lighting LEDs and oh it took about
24 hours for there to just be a sea of
fungus gats they were everywhere and um
you know it was a concern to see them
but I also didn't freak the hell out I
didn't have cannabis plants in there yet
um I expected things to get really
excited when I took them from a cold
outdoor environment because this was um
you know during a during the fall so a
lot of the stuff had already gone to
sleep or cyst it up and when I suddenly
put it in a in a warm Full Spectrum 18
hours of light environment like
everything hatched all the all the bugs
hatched their eggs or or similar and so
I had all of these fungus snats and so
I'm like okay um breathe and and let's
call copert right um uh copert is where
I get my beneficial insects from so I I
called my uh copert rep and I said all
right um I've got fungus gnats uh and a
whole hell of a lot of them what can you
send me and so after asking me a bunch
of questions and stuff they decided on
the um uh stro lops uh cius and um for
those of you who actually know the
correct pronunciation you probably that
I butchered that but you know what I you
know generally you know what I mean and
these uh these streso lops stist um they
sent me a container of that but here's
the deal um uh because of uh how the
holidays laid by the time I asked them
that that's what I needed it was going
to take them 10 days to get it to me um
because they ship out once a week and so
I'm like all right great please send me
that stuff and in the meantime I called
my buddy Leighton to bit about this and
complain and I'm like oh dude you know
um I got I've got all of these um these
fungus knats and um and why don't why
don't you take up pick up the the
storyline here Leon what what did you
tell me to
use yeah
so it was really funny you called me and
it was like what the hell what am I
going to do and I'm like hey do you
still have that rejuvenate I sent you um
and you're like yeah I think so uh is it
any good and I'm like well did it dry
out and you're like let me go check and
he came back and said no it's still
still moist I'm like all right just whip
it up a tea and pour it across the
surface as evenly as you possibly can
and
watch what is the rejuvenate what is the
rejuvenate it's just a uh it's another
one of the products uh that I make and
it's just basically like an instant
compost tea it's it's very very fine
particulate that when you add to water
just makes the water look you know dirty
like chocolate it's got a lot of
turbidity in it so um it's just an
simple easy way to uh instantly make a
very biologically diverse tea uh for
situations like
this and then you called me back and
said what is this sorcery that you
did it is true because like I I took I
took the rejuvenate I added water I
shook it up I evenly um applied it
across the soil and and not 36 hours
later there wasn't a single fungus KN
none and I went from having like all the
fungus knats in the world to having none
of the fungus snats and I did and I
actually did say what is this sorcery
because something had changed and and at
first I thought that perhaps there was
something costic in it somehow to fungus
knats and and um and I had done
something to the fungus like some of
pesticide but why did all the fungus
Nets actually go away well you you
created a very um
aggressive uh environment that that they
became a food source very very quickly
and you know in that Ru you're going to
have all different types of nematodes um
which is probably the best way to
eradicate fungus snats not the not the
little predatory mites um although they
do help um the nematodes will work right
in the soil and and just eat the eggs as
fast as they can lay them so that's
another little trick that um if you can
get really good biocomplete or
biologically Rich compost uh and you
make a tea you're going to um create a a
much more balanced environment where one
thing can't outrun um the others uh it's
just too competitive so so Leon you know
uh I love your products no doubt um um
um but that being said you know not
everybody's not is going to want to
contact you and get your stuff so so I
asked this question if somebody is is is
the secret to it to just have really
well finished biologically active
compost and then make an
unrated uh compost tea extract will that
work in most cases even if it's not your
product oh absolutely and and it goes
back to how to make compost and so
there's a lot of recipes out there but I
like the real simple approach which is
basically collect greens and Browns off
your own property um I don't add manures
I don't hit temperature um if it goes if
it hits 115 I flip it because anytime
you get over 120 you're losing
biodiversity if you hit 130 you are in
what's called a thermophilic uh process
in other words everything is getting
cooked off and when you get to that
level it's going to take year if not two
for all that biology to naturally come
back in um so a quick way to do this is
to never let it get over 115 and you and
that's fine as long as you're just using
plants if you start playing with manur
you're going to have problems so um
basically I make vegan compost um
collecting you know 1/3 greens one uh
2/3 Browns and I make the the Browns and
greens as diverse as I possibly can
basically in the greens you're looking
for endophytic biology so bio bio uh
biology that lives inside the tissue of
the plant um we know for sure that that
biology can come out of that plant um
and into your compost pile um if you put
enough um enough of them in there and
and again you're looking for diversity
so I I'm picking little green shoots off
all the plants that I can find and all
different types and and flowers and and
shrubs and you name it um and then the
Browns is the same I'm looking for
different types of wood chips different
types of brown leaves different types of
dead stocks of plants um and and using
all of that to make this stuff and then
it's just a matter of soaking it down
like apply as much water as you possibly
can till it's just running out of the
bottom of it and then put a thermometer
in it watch and usually within 24 hours
if you've Blended the greens and Browns
appropriate within 24 48 hours you're
going to see it heat up and if you do
that and and then it goes to say 115 and
then starts to cool
off you have it all you got to do is
take that stuff put it in a compound a 5
gallon bucket with a lowspeed drill uh
like a plaster or paint mixer and just
you know throw you know a gallon of the
compost in there uh fill it fill the
rest you know half full of water and
then blend it and then pour it on you
you've just released all that biology so
there's a trick for you to make your own
inoculant at home fantastic dude thank
you so in the end um the sorcery of
getting rid of this fungus Nets was a um
a wellmade compost that was filled with
nematodes and other
microbiology and when I put it um uh
over the top of the soil suddenly there
were all these predators of fungus Gat
larvae and so you know their life cycle
is very short and so it took a very
short period of time for all of those
little hungry micro microbiologist in
the compost to go and eat the next uh
couple generations of uh fungus snats
and Zim Zam that's it
sorcery all right thanks for explaining
that so yeah yeah so moving on um uh
I I don't know that you know a lot of
times when I ask ask you questions I'm
setting you up stuff that I actually
understand you know and you know I'm
asking you the question but I'm kind of
asking it for the audience this is one
that I'm going to be asking for me too
cuz I I actually don't know your answer
um when we explained um this uh whole
process the the philosophy behind it in
um uh the biome mimicry shaping Fire
episode number 54 and then with all of
the uh companion materials that I was
posting to Instagram of my own bed um
some folks were were um commenting some
concern that this was not going to work
right that this was going to end up in a
perched water table and um and it was
interesting cuz like you know some of
the some of the angry boys were all
getting themselves all bent out of shape
about it um whereas other people were
having like you know adult conversations
and and they were all interesting and um
and and in the end when I T when I came
back to you and I said dude you know
people are arguing on Instagram about
this perched water table um you know is
this going to be a problem and you're
like no no no no no this is a this is a
misunderstanding and then you explained
it to me and and and I still do not
understand it so so I'm I'm I'm looking
forward to hearing you explain it again
so
for for for those people who were con a
either concerned about it creating a
perched water table or B people who want
to give this a try and their friends may
give them hassle about a perched water
table will you go through it uh in
simple terms so that we can all
understand why why this does not apply
to this particular Horizon style growing
system that you've shared with us yeah
absolutely Shango
so I think it was in the 60s um soil
Engineers were trying to figure out what
the best way to build a high performance
sports turf uh for both you know
football baseball golf you name it and
they actually created the perched water
table and what it was was basically they
put a liner down um and put a layer of
gravel and then on top of that compacted
sand down and then they rolled out their
sod the reason they did this was because
they wanted to have a surface like a
putting green that you could walk across
but you could still roll a ball
perfectly without having it bounce all
over the place and also you needed to be
able to walk across this um in case of a
you know a heavy rain event without it
turning to muck and
so there's very very little organic
matter and hardly any uh silt or clay in
the types of uh high performance sports
turf um so there's not a lot of of
ability to store water or to um and an
ability to get rid of it just as fast so
goes back to that filling a bucket up
with sand and and again I encourage
people to do that and notice how much
water comes in it holds um and the other
side of this if you take the bucket and
cut the bottom out and then put it
directly on soil and then fill the
bucket get you know half full of sand
and then add water come back a couple
days later and that sand is still wet so
it shows you how much um capillary
action uh wicking that the sand can do
so somewhere along the line some
horticulturist
or uh I don't know plant um
Gardener um was talking about whether to
put gravel or shards of clay in the
bottom of their pot and somehow confus
used the perched water table with with
what happens in soilless mediums or
potting mixes um in that environment and
then that goes back to why I came up
with the horizonal system for the
Cannabis industry in the first place was
because when you're using a potting mix
the bottom is going to go Anor robic and
the top is going to be hydrophobic and
because it's a low tension soil the
capillary action and the ability to Wick
is not really there so uh
that's that's the misnomer that's the
problem is that you know again somewhere
along the line somebody said oh well if
I throw gravel in the bottom of my pot
that'll help me from from getting this
anerobic environment and use the word
perched water table when perched water
table has nothing to do with potting
soil it's really talking about how to
make a high- performance sports turf and
again so when you're comparing a pot
full of potting mix to a horizonal soil
system that's like looking at a tomato
versus a cantaloupe that they're not
even close so you know again do your
homework um really read up on on where
perched soil t uh perched water tables
come from uh it was not from the
Horticultural industry or the or the
gardening industry um that's just
somewhere someone along the line got
took one term and applied it to
something that's completely different I
want to ask you about the you said that
in in when people don't use an e Horizon
at the bottom with sand and rocks um and
and they're using um top to bottom a uh
you know a soil um blend of some sort
that the bottom of the of the container
is going to go Anor robic and and is the
idea that um the reason why it's going
to go anerobic is because you've
essentially got a pot that's entirely o
Horizon there isn't O A and E Horizon
it's all just o rizon it's all organic
matter and so when you water it um you
know the water will go through and
certainly there will be some mobility of
water but really that water is going to
collect at the bottom just like it does
in any biology with a water table and
and since you've got sitting water in in
organic matter it just kind of rots
which is why since we know this is how
water
performs in in in a horizon style living
soil container we put sand and rocks at
the bottom because they can hold the
water from your watering they can hold
the water without rotting is that the
right idea correct correct and the a
horizon will help because it's not low
tension um it's actually hi tension soil
um it will help uh to pull the water out
of the Horizon and move it up into the O
Horizon
as the top dries out and pulls the water
up and so will you talk a little bit
about that would you talk a little bit
about water Mobility um we talked about
on before you do that um we talked about
this at length in the water and watering
episode we did so if the idea of how to
water your plants and how how to
understand how water uh moves around in
the container if you're like really
nerding out about this go back to the
shaping Fire episode with Leighton
called water and watering because we go
at this for like a half hour but for
those of us who are you know just
interested in indoor growing and and
hearing this debrief on this on this
regenerative tent please continue
Leon so so water does a couple things
right so you look at your um soiless
medium your your compost your um pet or
pit or um you know what whatever you're
adding in there and you're going to get
what's called fines so fines are really
small particulate that when the water
hits them the water will actually move
them down in in the pot due to
gravitational forces so as all those
fines move down to the bottom of the pot
you end up making a swamp at the bottom
of your pot um so now all of that water
is being held by those fines um because
they are high tension
um whereas the rest of the fibers are
more low tension and therefore you have
more Iration you have the ability for
roots to really push through that stuff
very e easily which is why that's used
to grow cannabis uh it was traditionally
used and still is used to grow cannabis
to this day um because it has that
ability for if you feed the plant the
roots are going to go crazy uh easily
expand and and obviously you're going to
see the effect at the top where the
plant comes out of the ground so that
being said that's why um you know these
soiless mediums or super soils will have
that issue is that as you water you
moving all the fines to the bottom where
they're going to collect and and Compact
and and store water whereas with the
horizontal system your sand filter will
prevent any fines from getting down
there um and will if your fines do move
down from your o Horizon they're just
going to naturally blend in with the a
Horizon because it too is preventing
that easy uh ability for those fines to
migrate through the soil system you know
that's that's always been an issue in in
engineering soils which I used to do
quite a bit of well I still do um was
preventing that fines from moving down
and collecting um and then creating what
would be considered uh you know an
impervious surface or or layer where the
water can no longer move down it has to
start moving laterally
um or horizontally and that's that again
is is causing all kinds of problems um
you really want everything to just move
through and again that's why this system
works so well is because it it functions
both in ability to store water prevent
it from going in Aerobic um while
preventing the overall soil system from
collapsing or or causing these um layers
to build
up fantastic thank you for that yeah so
moving right along let's um let's let's
move to start talking about soil tests
now Leon so grab your soil test there so
I got a couple things to say before we
move into this
topic so we're going to we're going to
talk about soil tests for about I don't
know the next 10 minutes or so probably
end up being 15 but but this is going to
be the last thing that we talk about
here in set two so if we start talking
about the soil tests and your eyes start
to glaze over and uh don't don't just
leave the show cuz set three is really
great uh set three we're going to be
talking about um uh cover crops um how
and how often to water scrogging and and
mushrooms and companion plants right so
third set's going to be really great but
a lot of people um just are not
interested with the details from from uh
a soil report so so if we are about to
lose you don't go anywhere just skip
ahead to set three and and start
listening again now for those of you who
are interested in the soil test this is
what we're going to do um uh if you want
to see the soil test that Leon and I are
talking about um you can find it on the
um the page for this episode uh at
shaping fire.com um that's easy uh and
and then you know you could you could
hit pause right now and go get that and
then and then play along with us at home
um or you can look at it afterwards but
but just to be clear we're not going to
go way in depth into the soil report um
uh this is not a show about soil reports
um but but Leighton is going to give his
uh overview of it and and mention what
stands out for him so we're going to
kind of do this like cursory thing the
goal of this is for us to not only
encourage you to get soil tests um I
really like Logan Labs um uh they are
who I have used they are not a sponsor
of the show and I don't get any money
from them it's just who Leighton
recommended uh back last year and I used
them and they've been great so anyway if
you're looking for a lab Logan lab is
great um uh but we're going to this is
all to inform a discussion we're going
to have about um the beginning soil test
and the ending soil test and how to
compare them all right so with that and
with the soil report in hand um late in
year you've got it in your hand now and
so we're looking at the column uh that's
labeled start so so what this is a test
of is the test of the the bed after I
built it
and after I had been watering it for 3
weeks um just by itself so that
everything the biology could start to
get accustomed to this you know being
indoors being in Horizon level um uh you
know you know being under lights and and
so uh so the why don't you explain to us
what you see in uh soil test one which
is essentially the before I grew
cannabis in it test sure so um usually
what I'll do is I'll start with ph um
you're 6'4 that's you know fine that's
not a big issue um then I'll bounce up
to um total C uh exchange capacity which
we would call
C um here you're in the high 20s or mid
20s which is
fantastic um then we bounce down to
organic matter we have a very high
organic matter content 40.
42% which is fantastic um and then I'll
start looking down at um what's called
your um Trace Elements which are very
very important um everything seems to be
pretty much in range your iron's a
little high no big deal um aluminum's a
little high but again that's not going
to be a problem unless you get into a
low PH situation I'm look at your
nitrates 356 that means there's a
tremendous amount of natural organic n
available in this soil um that the
biology can break down and release uh as
a plant food um so that was all pretty
good U then I'll bounce over to What's
called the saturated Pace test which is
probably one of the most important um
aspects of looking at the soil and its
ability to function so if you look down
under percent you'll see calcium
magnesium potassium and sodium right so
generally speaking that that ratio
should be calcium 75 magnesium 17
potassium 8 sodium zero um in this case
you have low
calcium um your magnesium is way too
high and your potassium is a little hot
um but look at your sodium 12 um so
you're losing a lot of potential because
that sodium is stuck on that cation
exchange site instead of those primary
minerals and we can talk a little bit
more about where to get some of these uh
wonderful new organic um products that
are basically 4% calcium so if you have
calcium and you add it you will bump
potassium and sodium off the exchange
site um uh calcium is is what we call a
double bond so it has two positive
charges and potassium and sodium only
have one magnesium has two as well so
you have to be careful about Cal Mag
it's so funny I was about to say I'm
like it's so funny you're telling me I
need to bump my calcium in my magnesium
I'm like oh Jesus is the actual solution
to this more cow
mag cuz we all know I mean that that the
joke right yeah right I know more
cowbell right that was that was
everybody in the Cannabis industry
laughs about that because it's it's that
was what people did was they just
pounded it with freaking cow mag um and
in this case if you put any more
magnesium on here you're going to cause
way more problems so you really just
want pure calcium and then you're going
to let the plant work through the mag
high magnesium and by the end of the Run
um you'll see that that magnesium came
down a little bit um and your calcium
actually went up in end end1 report but
anyway so that those are the those are
the things and then underneath the
percent I'm again looking at trace
minerals um Trace elements so Trace
elements and um are are really really
important for some of the finite plant
processes so you know its ability to
fight disease uh to accept sunlight um
the ability to push nitrogen and calcium
through its whole system you know
maldium is one of those really really
important ones so again you know looking
at at the the start um you know
everything looked okay uh I don't see
you know anything that really jumps out
and scares me um toward the end of the
Run um all of a sudden now we're we've
lost uh a lot of nutrients so we'll
we'll talk about that a little bit more
as things uh go forward no let's let's
let's move right to that right now so so
so you were looking at the start and so
I had a pretty good start I had I had a
nice variety of nutrients and I was
really happy with all the natural
organic matter um um that we had so so
then you know I go and I do the run
right I grew uh five plants in that t in
that uh tent which we'll talk more about
in um the next set but I grew I grew uh
five plants um they uh they vegged for
um uh like four and a half weeks or so
uh I did the flip um they and then I
grew uh varieties that were ready around
week nine took nine weeks and so uh so
here we were at the end I harvest and
then I take another soil sample because
I wanted to learn um how much nutrition
um I should expect plants to use and I
was also um planning on uh re amending
before my next cycle so Leighton let's
go through this again um what do you see
in the soil report now after I've grown
a cycle of cannabis so look at organic
matter percent it went down by four
solid points a little bit more than four
points then you bounc back up to cat
exchange capacity that too dropped um
pretty significantly you dropped by five
plus points so what that indicates to me
is that your organic matter was your
primary source of cation exchange or the
ability to store nutrients in your soil
so in that regard you know I would
encourage you to top dress with a little
bit more compost um so that you're
putting those exchange sites back into
play because there as they get broken
down from compost to silt you're losing
um the positive charges um that would
have been holding those nutrients so
that's that's one interesting thing but
but what the drops that you're seeing
though even even though you know we do
want to replenish and that's the whole
point of re amending um these are drops
that would be typical and expected after
growing a cycle of cannabis exactly
exactly but this is giving you exactly
what you're missing if you're you know
if you're paying attention to it I like
that it's also showing that the system
is functioning right oh yeah it's not
like oh I grew plants and now
everything's out of whack it's like oh
no this is what we would expect if you
grew a proper living soil plant mhm and
but it also gives you the direction on
what you need to make sure that you're
putting back into play um and again you
know people get so overwhelmed at
looking at these reports and it's like
no you don't need all of this um this
would be for someone who's you know very
very uh heavy into soil science really
all you're looking at is exchange
capacity organic matter Trace elements
and then your um your true um saturated
paste percentage like if if you look at
um like for instance the soluble cat I
right it says calcium is up at
62 magnesium at 41 potassium at 41
sodium at 25 then you drop down to
percentage they're not they don't match
up they're not even close so that's
where you have to understand that that
soluble means that it's potentially
plant available whereas
um the percent actually represents
what's being held on the cation exchange
sites which which are a better think of
it as a battery for your soil so I mean
look at your soluble cats uh calcium at
start was 62 which is great and at the
end
4.5 that means you got you gobbled up a
tremendous amount of calcium in that run
but then you drop down to percent you
look at calcium and it's
3564 and it actually went up to
39.96 so what that says is that as the
calcium that was in the soluble cation
or or plant
available um some of that fell down and
attached to the cation exchange sites so
so that's a good thing and look at your
magnesium your magnesium after at the
end was dropped all the way down to 25.6
2 which again is like the system is
functioning it's it's going in the right
direction it's balancing it out
balancing itself out um potassium went
from
12.34 all the way down to
4.24 and worse the sodium was at 12.6
went up to
3.1 uh8 so that indicates to me that
perhaps you either have high levels of
salt in your water um that you're using
to water the plant um or you used a
nutrient that had a salt base so you
know we talk about mineral salts versus
organic nutrients right there's still
going to be salts in organic nutrients
um the organic nutrients are harder to
break down which is why you need a
tremendous amount of um good biological
diversity um to make those available but
as the biology pulls things off it's
going to leave behind the salts and this
is where it goes back to oh flush
flushing is a good thing using excess
water or I used to call all I said it
originally as oh just waterboard that
[__] you hated it this is true and
forced me to rename it into a rain event
Heavy Rain event Heavy Rain event so
bottom line in this in this situation
what I'd probably recommend is that you
do a a major rain event at the end of
the cycle so that you push those salts
down uh into the into the E Horizon
where they can naturally build up down
there and and that won't cause a problem
um so that's you know that's kind of the
the the gist and the interesting things
that that have happened all right so
before before you move on on you said a
whole bunch of provocative stuff so so
let's start with um H the how much
sodium there is now what I would like to
understand is when uh when we look at
the the cation uh exchange section it
says that the sodium started at 181 and
finished at
117 so that looks like the sodium
decreased and and when we originally
talked about it you said aha this shows
that there were no added salts in your
um in your inputs and I was all happy
right cuz I'm not using you know
salt-based bottles and stuff and and and
you said yeah you're not adding any
salts but then but then when we look at
the the the soluble cat I where where
you're where you're having us look that
they excuse me the percent it went up
how come it looks like sodium went down
in the cat section but the percentage
went up they seem to be um contrasting
in their
indications well no actually they're not
see soluble means that it's mobile or
available and percentage means it's
bound to a cat exchange site so it goes
back to think of that clay platelet as a
little flying saucer and around the
outside of that Flying Saucer is 100
parking spots um that's that's your
battery you got a 100 little pieces of
these primary nutrients calcium
magnesium pottassium and sodium so when
the sodium started in in soluble cats at
25.2 three and dropped all the way to
3.91 during the cycle well they went
somewhere right they went down to
percentage those those solubles those
those salts that were released are now
stuck on your uh cat or stuck on your
clay platelet um and being stored and we
we don't want them stored there we we
want them mobile and we want them moving
we want to get rid of them or or let
them naturally break down because there
are some uh bacteria that can uh
actually start breaking salt apart so
that being said they just moved they
went from one place to another place you
follow me I do I do so all sodium is not
the same on the test um again you're
looking at what's being stored the
percent is what's being stored on the C
exchange site and the soluble cats are
the ones that are more Mobile in the
soil so they they can they can move they
either can get used up very quickly or
they can wash through the soil profile
all right fantastic so um so let's move
on to our our third soil report that
we're going to hit fast so this is this
is where things get a little iffy my
dear listener um so um I guess I'm kind
of thrown myself under the bus here um
so after seeing this uh report the
second one uh showing me how much
nutrition I used um I told Leighton that
uh I was a big fan I I continue to be a
good fan of the um the kiss Organics um
nutrient pack and uh Tad has put a lot
effort into um making a a wide ranging
Blended amendment that you can just buy
a bucket of and and add to your soil us
as Amendment and it it will just amend
like all your different categories and
it just makes things really simple also
if you're an ultra nerd for this um they
Tad at kiss Organics they will also
custom blend you a nutrient pack as well
and he actually offered that to do that
for me but I said you know dude I want
to I want to practice with what what's
bought right off the shelf I don't want
to get the custom stuff but I will let
people know that that's available so
that's why I'm telling you so so what I
did is I I followed the the directions
on the label and um I added my 18 cups
of uh of of nutrient pack uh to the top
and I watered it in and then I covered
it with some um uh from another some
more soil from uh from outside
and um watered it in and kind of walked
away from it I figured okay you know I'm
doing a fall Harvest of my outdoor um
you know I can just let this soil sit
for a while and um and just let it you
know just water it in right just just I
don't know let it do biology and so I
was about 3 days into that and I and I
called Leighton to let him know that I
had done this and he was like oh dude
you can't you can't just let the bed sit
there and I'm like well what do you mean
and he's all like well are the lights
off I'm like well yeah the lights are
off I want to save money he's like yeah
he's all like the the bed is alive
because of the light and if you turn off
the light and if there are no plants in
the bed you are just kind of like
choking all of the biology off and and
it's not going to be cycling and ready
when you transplant in plants and I'm
like whoa mind blown and and so I
realized that I needed to plant the bed
so that plants would grow so that when I
was ready to replant it you know and
focus more on it in a few weeks after we
Harvest it outdoor so the pl the the bed
would be ready to go and so I'm like oh
so I turned back on the lights um you
know not at full power but you know
enough that the bed was going to get
lights and and I put in a bunch of
flowers and onions and strawberries and
um chives
and uh you know just a whole bunch of
things and uh basil I just like bought
that living basil from the store and
threw that in there and so you know
these were all temporary plants these
weren't plants that I was going to keep
very long but they were all plants that
I was going to grow and then chop and
then cover with uh more soil and then
and then plant my Canabis in 3 weeks
when I was done with Harvest so that's
what I did and it was actually really
cool and and for those of you who follow
on the Instagram you got to see all the
pictures of these you know you know
beautiful strawberry blonde colula and
the the pink dandelions and the
strawberries I was eating out of there
and the onions it was really great to be
producing food for myself out of this
indoor tent so that was all really cool
however it was time to get a um another
soil test right cuz I wanted to see and
and and ensure that the that the
Amendments that I had used used had
brought up my numbers again and I was
ready to grow cannabis so I took my test
I sent it into Logan Labs I got it back
and I was disappointed cuz the numbers
were lower than I expected but I had
done everything right and so um I went
back to Lon and I'm all like Leighton
you know why aren't these numbers higher
you know I know this product works it ra
it's raised my numbers before but it
didn't this time and he's all like well
you were growing plants in there right
and I'm like oh yeah I got great food
and pl and he's like dude they were
taking up more of your nutrition it's
not like the beds there stopping its
uptake of nutrition just because you
didn't have cannabis plants in there and
I went oh and so I had both amended the
bed waited a while because I was busy
doing other things and then tested it
and I had used up most if not all of the
Amendments that I had put in there um 3
months earlier and so this was a life
lesson for me and so um I have to
remember that all these companion plants
I'm using are are actively pulling on
the nutrition as well and like you know
in retrospect that's like totally
obvious um so so looking at my time
frame Leon um what do you think the time
frame should be
between like you end the cycle I take
the test I get back my results I add my
nutrient pack how long should I
wait like how long should I be watering
in those amendments and let them settle
before I replant with cannabis plants
and um uh I guess that's the question
how long should I water that stuff in
before I put in the cannabis plants well
I mean again you're you're continuing to
grow plants throughout the cycle so even
though it's not cannabis now it's called
a a resting bit where you've got you
know other plants in there that are are
you know keeping the soil the living
soil system alive so you really want
to um again if you're going to plant in
three weeks you know take another soil
test and and now you again you'll know
what your companions or your foods that
you grew in there um have taken out or
or be proactive and understand that your
your numbers are going to continue to go
down I mean if you look at like
primaries nitrate and aluminum in the
beginning of the cycle you know you were
at
3656 for
nitrat uh and ammonia was at um 6.2 at
the end of the cycle you were down to
89.5 in the nitrate and
0.008 in the uh ammonium and then bounce
over to the one that you just
took um and your nitrates are at 18.2 so
they've continued to go down and your
ammonia is
AT3 so you really need uh a good source
of nitrogen in this thing bad like you
know I don't know how much pigs plugged
you tend to use
traditionally but I would say whatever
you were using you need to double it for
now to get these numbers back up to
where they need to be so and that and
that's true with the maldium um as I
pointed out before you know that's down
to less than 0.02 and that's a critical
um trace for um you know plant function
so again you know these are giving you
things that you need to know as tools um
how how best to amend next um again
you're going to need a good source of
calcium um you could use a slow release
uh you know oyster shell
flour um or you could use like a liquid
calcium Source like horta
which is an organic uh 4% calcium that's
also acts as a nitrogen now this gets
really complex so I'm not going to go
down this rabbit hole but the
interaction between calcium and nitrogen
is a really interesting one and not one
that is often talked about um if you
look back at some of Rudolph Steiner's
work in the 20s he talks about um these
in forms that don't really make sense
he's talking about ethereal and
terrestrial planes and it's really what
he's talking about is nitrogen and
calcium and the relationship they have
so those would be the the starting
points um that I would really encourage
you to uh focus on I mean uh soluble
calcium went from 62 down to 4.5 after
the end of the Run um with your most
recent test um your calcium went back up
to
37.5 H so
obviously whatever you amended had a
good source of of calcium but again
you're going to you're going to want
more I mean in the percentages stuck on
your cat exchange site remember that
that number I just gave you for calcium
was soluble so it's Mobile in the it
it's one of the nutrients that you've
added whereas if you look down on your
um your percentages your cat exchange
sites you're down to 31.947692
ability to store those store that stuff
uh on a on a a cat an exchange site so
that's why it's really important that
you get a more mobile liquid uh source
of calcium to help to to bump off the
pottassium which is 27 way too high bump
the sodium off which is
11.41 so that good calcium liquid
calcium source is really going to help
you a lot in in getting this this bed
back to a wonderful or a um a good good
place for for the next run so so I think
the the main lesson that I've learned
from this
is uh number one uh don't do your soil
test until you're ready to transplant
your cannabis plants and put them in
there because after you have done you
you you do your test and then you do
your amendments and then you add your
plants whereas what I did is I did my
test did my amendments and then I waited
a month with resting plants in there
that was eating up nutrition and
throwing me back off balance and then I
went to then I went to add my plants and
it was no longer as robust as I wanted
it to be and at that point I needed to
do another test and then re amend so I
screwed myself with that resting period
like and like certainly I Have I Lost
You Know yield per year as well and I
don't think I'll do that resting period
again yeah I would say that you know the
the interesting thing was that you you
saw what what the goal is you saw what
you started with and you saw what you
ended with and so I agree with you I
think that starting and getting that
test is critical and then once you're
ready to plant your cannabis plants like
two to three weeks three to four weeks
before you're ready to plant your
cannabis plants then do your ending test
because you had that resting period
where you those the onions and those
other um cover crops and companion
plants gobbled up more nutrients so I
think that you know I'm glad you did
this because you're really seeing what's
happening here and even though you
amended you still lost more nutrient so
again you know lesson learned start test
and just be you know three weeks to four
weeks before planting the next run
that's when you want to do your your
ending test so that you can figure out
what you need to put in play uh for the
next run and again you know even if the
nutrients are are you know like organic
form again like a an oyster meal flour
uh or you know feather meal or whatever
um that you're putting in into play you
can plant right after that you you don't
have What's called the cook down phase
which is what super soils do is they you
know they basically blend you all these
high nutrients and then they say don't
use it right away because you're going
to burn your plant if you try to plant
in it you got to let it cook off and
basically what's happening is you you're
going into a thermophilic process where
organic and nitrogen and carbon are
being eaten and broken down and you're
releasing ammonia um which is another
form of nitrogen because they've they've
broken it apart um as a gas so you're
losing you're losing nutrient value um
in that process but if you again if you
don't allow the biology to break it down
or or Bust it into uh more uh usable
pieces then it's going to kill your plan
so you have to do that but in in the
case of your situation where you're just
amending with with hard organic
nutrients um other than the pig's blood
that's a little different um these
nutrients are going to stay in play in
the soil for a longer period of time
they're not they're not soluble um but
they're not they're not mobile either
they're they're they're bound up in in
their um in their raw form which makes
him kind of slow release yes exactly
till the biology breaks him down and and
that's good because the plant will
actually say ah you know I don't need
any of that right now so I'm not going
to feed this exate for this bacteria to
break that down but I will when I come
to a point in the in my growth cycle
where I need it then I'll release exit
dates I'll grow out those bacterials and
I'll mine that source of
nutrient right on all right well thank
you for going through that that that
arduous report situation with me uh
Leighton and um so let's go ahead and
take our last break and when we come
back we're going to start talking about
um uh some a little less technical stuff
like uh like cover crops and scrogging
you are listening to shaping fire uh and
my guest today is soil biologist Leon
Morrison we'll be right
[Music]
back there are a lot of good people
launching new businesses in cannabis
psilocybin and other psychedelics and
it's very strange Time For Us in the
same moment that psilocybin mushrooms
are illegal at the federal level they
are becoming increasingly legal in
States across the country these
businesses leading the way into the
future of plant medicines require
specialized legal representation by
attorneys who have depth not only in
litigation mergers and Acquisitions but
also in psychedelic and other plant
medicines green light Law Group has been
empowering cannabis businesses since
2014 and as the market has divers ified
into siloc cybin and other plant
medicines Greenlight has been right
there evolving with their diverse
clients to provide legal expertise with
a high level of legal Acumen creative
strategy and precision that comes with
an intimate and specific understanding
of both business law and plant medicine
if you are a business owner trying to
navigate the layered local and National
Drug Laws on your own you are at risk of
fumbling these confusing and quickly
changing laws complicate everything
green light law group is ready to help
you when hit with a lawsuit or because
you were shafted by a vendor or business
partner or simply because you want to
stay legal and could use some
preventative guidance before cultivating
a controlled substance as an
entrepreneur Greenlight Law Group is a
collection of folks who care profoundly
about their work and I know this is true
because I know the folks from Greenlight
there is a huge difference between a big
legal firm who has decided to start
representing a few drug companies versus
working with a collection of high
integrity passionate lawyers who are
personally interested in new plant
medicines and firmly believe in their
power to heal contact Greenlight Law
Group today and learn more about the
services they can offer your
industry-leading cannabis or
psychedelics company that's Greenlight
Law Group at Greenlight lawgroup.com
[Music]
for years organic cultivators have been
looking for a replacement for using Pete
Moss Pete Moss has long been the go-to
soil amendment for water retention in
container growing but organic Growers
know that Pete Moss is an unsustainable
resource and the mining of Pete bogs
destroys habitat and releases
sequestered carbon but Pete Moss works
so well that many have continued to use
it but now there's finally a
revolutionary replacement for Pete Moss
that shares the same benefits while also
being sustainable pit Moss sounds and
acts like Pete Moss but instead of being
mined from fragile ecosystems it
actually is made from upcycled organic
paper and tree bark pit Moss is
excellent at retaining water in your
substrate and creating air pockets and
Tiny living environments for microbes
pit Moss instantly increases irration
nutrient absorption and Water
Conservation too carefully and locally
sourced pit Moss is the result of
decades long research into the use of
recycled paper fibers pit Moss has the
fluffy nature of Pete Moss and handles
exactly the same and like Pete Moss pit
Moss is inert so it won't change your pH
available in a range of preparations
including a nutrient enhanced blend a
cocoa quar blend and also as an organic
soil conditioner with no added nutrients
pit Moss is also available as an animal
bedding so go to pit moss.com now to
learn more that's
PT M
o.com growing healthier more sustainable
plants pit
Moss for 20 years Humbolt seed company
has been family-owned and providing
reliable High yielding seeds originating
in Northern California while the current
trend is to slap one's super male into a
line of hype strains Humbolt Seed
Company continues to breed with
precision and Care by doing large sifts
and back crosses to emphasize the
absolute best traits that a line has to
offer this kind of breeding takes time
talent and space to work no matter what
kind of Aroma you are particularly into
humbold seed will likely have something
you'll love if you love fruit you can
choose from banana mango apricot papaya
blueberry blood orange melon and lemons
across their various strains they have
all gas glue and classic Sour Diesel
lines as well of course there are the
heritage California strains like OG Kush
Jack her and headband and their
award-winning blueberry muffin is one
that Delights just about everybody's
palette especially when concentrated
Humbolt seed company is proud to bring
to market the infamous freak Show
cultivar 2 which has a great THC high
but looks so much like a fern that some
folks can't even identify it as cannabis
it's a plant that really needs to be
seen to be believed if you're looking
for well-balanced CBD seeds humble Seed
Company can turn you on to CBD strains
that actually have flavor like the dill
and pepper Turpin of Willie G's Lebanese
land race whether are you are looking
for regular feminine autof flowers
Humbolt seed company has the gear to
make this your best growing cycle ever
visit Humbolt seed company.com today to
check out their line of vigorous
genetics download their catalog and find
out where you can pick them up you can
also check out their Instagram atth
humble Seed Company to check out their
Gorgeous Flowers in the extraordinary
freak Show plant humbold seed company
let them know Shango sent you welcome
back you are listening to shaping fire I
am your host Shango Los and my guest
today is soil biologist Leighton
Morrison so Leighton here we are third
set bringing it all on home so the first
thing I want to point out is how many
plants to grow in this environment and
you know with all of the nutrition with
us being able to add more if we want to
it's not really the um the the amount of
nutrition that is going to be limiting
the number of plants we could have
what's going to end up limiting it is
the space we're going to have um and so
against all of the good opinion I got
from all of my friends um I grew five
plants in a 4x4 tent and everybody's all
like what the hell are you doing this is
just going to overgrow the tent so bad
and for me I was more interested in um
uh flavor variety than necessarily like
yield right I wanted I wanted to grow
five different tastes five different
flavors just for my own head cuz like
I'm not growing the stuff to sell I'm
just growing the stuff to smoke and so
while I while I understood that five
plants was probably going to impact my
yield because the plants are be
competing I didn't really care all that
much but I do agree five plants is too
many it was just too many they were
growing on top of each other um and so I
was growing a lot of plant matter that
never finished because it had other
plants growing over the top of it
especially because one of them was the
bot o G and the b o g the uh G GMO um um
uh cherry pie cross from Nick ryen it is
a beast it turned my tent into a
freaking cage match and it just wanted
to overgrow everything else so I had to
continually trim it down during veg and
then even after um flower it was just
trying to climb over everything so I've
kind of learned my lesson and I'm going
down to four plants um for this for this
next round which is pro still probably
too many but again I want the flavors
and I'm going to scrog it so if I fail
again so be it so let's talk about uh
cover crops so the the cover crops that
I liked uh the most is uh primarily for
cover crops I use dondra Rens which is a
a very short about 1 in ground cover
it's a green plant and it's commonly
used in between the bricks of fancy
driveways you know sometimes they have
those ornamental uh you know paav bricks
and uh and you know so you can drive
your car on your driveway but then you
know there's this beautiful pattern and
so they're very resilient they hold
their own water and you know they just
grow thousands of these individuated
plants so so that's pretty cool and I
also did everbearing alpine strawberries
because I wanted to be able to eat from
them I you you did some flowers
including pink dandelions and strawberry
blond Cula and it was just fun right the
thing and the thing though um that I was
not planning on though was when the
scrog filled up but before we start
talking trash about about how the scrog
um acted on the cover crops Leon will
you please explain the importance of
companion planting from the perspective
of number one uh the various roots of
the plants talking to each other and
then number two helping fight um the
surface from becoming
hydrophobic absolutely um so yeah the
the cover crops are are amazing in their
in the regard that they um create a
microclimate right on the surface of the
soil so the soil's not getting dried out
due to the wind that's you know the air
moving that you have in the tent um and
it's also preventing the the lights from
from cooking the the biology on the
surface of the soil um and it's it's
literally as the water evaporates it's
hitting the bottom of these little
leaves and then dripping back down onto
the soil again so in many ways you're
you're allowing a natural little um
microecosystem to occur um right at the
surface soil now now what's going on
underneath the soil is even more
important because yeah everything is
communicating especially if you have uh
micro isy fungi um the amount of work
there's some amazing things that we were
learning uh at an incredibly Fast Pace
about micro isy and some of these other
plant interactions and how they
communicate with each other through the
movement of of um different chemistry
that's that's happening in in the micro
iy uh we now know that there's certain
bacteria that will actually enter into
the micro isy and transfer from to
different plants um and also on the
outside is is a super highway of of all
kinds of you know bacteria as well as
Predators you know like amibas and
auletes so you know again there's just
like whole think of it as the internet
like a whole web um that is being
provide that's providing transportation
of both nutrient mineral and biology
back and forth between these plants um
so yeah that that interaction between
roots and um biology uh is is critical
for
for let me ask you this did you have any
pests even though you had that tent
packed with with plants no I actually
didn't have any pests um sorry
um uh none of them during the actual uh
Growing Experience right like if if if
you asked me the day that I ended I
would have said I had no pest pressure
and I tribute that in my head mostly to
the fact that um I I worked with my
consultant from uh Cobert uh beneficial
insects and I placed beneficial insects
in the tent that were preventatives and
so I assumed that that is why I got
through this run with no pests that said
when I went through and I harvested and
I went through and I um trimmed I found
two sunleaves that were face to face
with a slight slit you know like
normally where you'll see like
um uh spiders living you know like a
little Hut and I found like maybe a
hundred aphids in there and I was
startled I'm like where the hell did
these aphids come from I didn't see them
anywhere else in the tent but they had
set up a home just in in between these
two leaves and so technically there were
pests there but they but there was like
nearly No Pest pressure why I do not
understand well I would attribute that
to a healthy biological system and and
healthy plants that are are strong and
resistant um yeah they went sense too
because the a the place where they grew
it was in between two leaves from one of
the plants that was suffering by being
overgrown by the bicket OG there you go
there you go so they'll find a place
that's weakest and then try to you know
grow out in in that place and then you
know get a population big enough that
they can attack other healthier plants
but again you know if plant Health um if
the plants are healthy enough they will
deter pests and I think in many ways you
had that because of the way you grew um
the level of biology that you had in
there because because of what happened
with the uh fungus knats I mean that was
a real indicator that you put in a very
diverse inoculant that's present now and
we'll see it again in in this next run
and let me ask you another hard question
how how did your plants turn out oh they
were the best plants that I've ever
grown in my life period I mean on one
hand duh because outside in the Pacific
Northwest where I live we start to get
cold and rains the last week of
September first week of October and most
8 week plants need to go at least until
the middle of October here and so we
don't finish outdoor plants really um
you know Coastal Pacific Northwest and
so all of the plants need two more weeks
when we pull them but so so um as as my
friend Johnny told me the other day he
said oh so when you grew indoor it's the
first time that you grew finished plants
and I'm like uh yeah I guess so and so
so they were they were beautiful
colorful uh dense uh a a complex tarpine
profile um there there weren't there
wasn't much pest pressure or like
chewing of leaves or they they were they
were like an Olympic team um and they
tasted freaking incredible so um it was
a it was a wild
success I'm happy to hear that my friend
yeah I mean again it just it goes to
show that if you do the right things um
and you look at the bigger picture then
you're going to have uh a a better uh
more Rich plant because you've had the
biology and you have the diversity and
you have all the components that that
the that everything needs to function
properly so you know kudos to you I'm
glad you had such a great run can't wait
to taste it yeah right on and and and I
of course appreciate your your help on
all of this um so let's let's talk about
the cover crop and then SE SE into
talking about scrog because there's one
thing I want to say um I talk often
about um I really like pink dandelions
they're an heirloom flower that just has
become popular because Baker Creek seeds
um uh is is putting it out now and um if
if you if if you do go and you're like
oh pink dandelion that sounds great and
like you go buy a pack of seeds for
three bucks uh you know just make sure
that you don't let them go to seed when
you are in flour because uh it
absolutely sucks to have those little
white puffs of dandelion seeds floating
around in the tent and getting in your
sticky flowers that is not a win and so
what I do is I just let them grow up and
they look cool during veg and then
anything that goes to seed during veg I
like grab those seeds and I harvest them
and I share them with my friends but if
anything goes to seed during um flour I
just go ahead and pull off the the seeds
before before before they fully form
because I'm not willing to risk that
just for some um you know for for some
beautiful flowers like like I know which
flowers I'm growing you know um so so
then the second thing I want to talk
about is the experience that I had um
using the scrog and and this was
actually probably the biggest challenge
I had during the cycle so so I I had the
plants grow up um I started um uh
weaving them through the scrog
everything's great um they start
competing for space
excessively and and and and what I found
was because the plants were so strong
and because I so fully filled in the
scrog what happened was it cut off the
light to the soil down below and up
until this point you know I had the
whole bottom filled with all these green
plants the dondra and flowers and alpine
strawberries and all this great stuff
well when the light got cut off from an
effectively done scrog all those plants
below started to suffer the dichondra
started to pull back the strawberries
pulled back um it it started not looking
happy down there and so I realized that
I was I was starting to experience big
gaps of exposed um soil top and I don't
want that cuz when you have bare exposed
soil um you no longer have that little
Amazonian buffer of weather uh in the in
the inch above the soil from the dondra
Rens and strawberries and and with that
bare soil you can start getting
something hydrophobic right so I'd be
watering the top and the water just kind
of like slides off the side of the bed
and goes down the side and it doesn't go
into the soil and so I'm like [__] I I
don't know what I'm going to do and so
um after after asking around to to
Leighton and and and and some of my
other friends I realized that what I
wanted to do was to replace that green
mulch that green um tops uh cover crop
um with wood chips and and I'm like all
right because if I used wood chips then
I could grow mushrooms and I was very
excited I I I grow you know a variety of
mushrooms and I'm like oh my God how
cool would it be to be able to grow um
uh uh cooking mushrooms culinary
mushrooms below my cannabis in the in
the shady area so so what I did is I um
you know I didn't really have good
access to wood chips but because I live
on an island with lots of artists I was
able to find really nice
hardwood
um like refu from Woodworkers on the
island who make like bowls and utensils
and things like that really nice organic
Alder and and Oak and um U madone and
and other other Hardwoods um that uh
Maple and uh and and use those and that
that worked out really well and I was
able to get those and it was kind of fun
cuz they're all in curly cues as well so
they look festive and so I got a a
couple huge bags of that just gifted to
me from uh artist on the island and I
put that on top and so essentially I I I
just uh choked out the rest of the way
um all of the cover crops um and but
before I put that down I reached out to
my buddy Seth from Ready Set shroom and
um and I got some uh golden oyster um
and I got some winec cap uh inoculated
um uh you know sawdust and stuff and um
and and he shipped those up to me and I
put those down so that when I put down
these Hardwoods on top of it um
eventually those mushrooms um uh occupy
the hardwood and and I got some edible
mushrooms so that part of it was cool
but the part the part I would like you
to speak to Lon is that a lot of people
were really concerned for me that I had
put air quotes wood chips on top because
they said that the wood chips were going
to steal nitrogen from the
substrate and that concerned me and so
when I told you about it um you
explained to me that what they're
talking about what that biology is
between wood chips nitrogen and the soil
but then you also explained why this
wasn't going to happen with these cured
hardwood bits that I was using so will
you go through that for all of us oh
absolutely so in the living plant we
talked a little bit earlier about
endites um so there's all different
types of biology and what happens when
you take fresh green um trees branches
whatever um and you chip them up um
they're going to go through the
thermophilic process um they're going to
start breaking nitrogen down breaking
carbon down and heating up and that's
that's where you have a problem because
basically those
thermopyle to break down carbon so
that's where fresh new chips are
absolutely problematic um old AG chips
that are uh Punky no problem curly
Hardwoods no problem they've been cured
uh kilm dried um you know left to uh or
I should say not left but processed so
that they don't warp and twist um so
again it's not even comparable um to
what people would think of as fresh wood
chips it's it's it's old wood it's it
has gone through uh very much a um
pasteurizing process
um so that it's usable
wood this pasteurizing process removes
much of the water from it because
they're dried out and cured and so
without that water component yes they
will break down but they don't break
down in the same way so they're not
going to be stealing nitrogen perfectly
said perfectly said all right cool well
thanks for thanks for hitting that so um
so so here we are we talked about the
scrog the scrog was very effective and
when you use a scrog properly um uh it
essentially created every nug on the
plant was a cola which I was astonished
to see for the first time and I will now
scrog everything like forever and so um
and and and so um I recommend that you
consider scrogging if you have not so so
so Leon this brings us to the the the
end of third set and this is everything
we wanted to talk about today doing kind
of like this debrief from from the bed
um uh you know you have you know been
assistant quarterback on this project
from me you know you've you you've
you've taught me and you have um you
know you know caught me from making
mistakes um I'm going to I'm going to
kind of like just kind of put myself um
at your mercy I guess and and just say
from from what you have seen um is there
anything that we haven't talked about
today that that either you know
somewhere between I didn't do right or
or I could have done better that we
haven't talked about and so and so you
know don't don't be shy I I I know I'm
learning so so was there anything else
that stands out for you that we should
mention I would have loved to see um you
make a uh biological compost there um
using your plant matter your leaves
everything that you've pulled off um as
well as combining it with some stuff
outside and instead of using just all
wood hardwood shavings I'd have loved
you to mix those hardwood shavings in
with um that biologically Rich compost
that you made um that would be the only
thing that I could really complain about
because I think you know based on our
conversations um you did all of the
steps you know correctly and again you
know nothing's perfect in nature so we
don't have to try to be perfect perfect
um your combinations of of materials
your effort I mean I loved the fact that
you smashed rocks I I I I love when you
called me and said I'm just going to get
stone and bust rocks up and then day
later you called me back oh my God you
didn't warn
me yeah so you know and and I'll
reiterate why you want Jagged edges the
more Jagged edges there are there's more
surface area for the biology to grow out
its bofilm and begin to break that rock
down and when it's smooth it's basically
polished so that's the problem is the
polish doesn't really allow them to set
up in those tiny little crevices and
pores and little tiny micr cracks that
that would have been um you know a
jagged edge so th though that was pretty
much you know the only pieces of the
puzzle that I think um you know I just
want to make sure the listeners
understand the reasons why um that that
I encourage you to make your own
biological compost so this biological
compost are you what's it made out of is
it are were you did you mean like I like
the parts of the cannabis plants that
were not the flowers you would have
liked to have seen me biologically
compost the the sun leaves and the stem
and like all the other biological Parts
like after harvest is that your point
yep get after harvest every time you
should be taking anything that you're
not keeping and blend it with local
greens and Browns to the ratios we
talked about um and get it as soaking
wet as you possibly can make a nice
little pile of it um get a compost
thermometer monitor it um once you get
over the thermophilic process in other
words once it hits a temperature and
then starts going down as soon as it
goes down
to
100 throw a whole bunch of seeds on it
and let those seeds grow and put mile of
rizosphere throughout that compost pile
everyone's like oh you're you're
stealing nutrients no you're not you're
growing out biology which is what you
really want and everything that grows
there is going to die there and fall
back down and make you more compost so
that is the trick to really getting a
very biologically Rich compost that you
can use as a top dress because we lost
you lost cadine exchange sites you lost
organic matter uh between start and the
the very end results so you need to put
that back in play so chips are great as
a as a way to keep that
microclimate um in in the top of the
soil but it's also um it's not going to
give you the the kind of nutrition and
biology that a compost would have done
in the same place right on fair enough
so Leon thank you so much like let's see
I got a couple layers of thank you thank
you very much for taking your time with
me today and doing this this debrief of
what the first cycle was like and and
how we thought our way through it cuz
really we're not we're not really trying
to teach a specific recipe that you have
to use every time we're trying to share
a perspective of how these Horizons work
um indoors so that we can uh
biomimicry um as much of the natural
systems from the outdoors indoors um so
so so thank you for you know joining me
for the show today but then also brother
thank you for spending your time with me
on this project you know the hours of
phone calls and me calling you cuz I was
upset cuz something wasn't working right
and you essentially just you know making
sure that I didn't like run my ship into
an iceberg and so I I greatly appreciate
both your experience and your
willingness to play with me oh it's my
pleasure Shango it was my pleasure and
and I'm glad that there's another more
public example of this I get a lot of
thank yous and and DMS and texts and
emails about this and how it's made
people's lives um so much easier because
you're not you're not fighting the plant
you're you're letting the plant guide
you and you're just participating in its
life which is you know that's kind of
the way nature works we we don't well
humans have tried to fight nature since
you know we got started expanding but in
reality
we were just stewards of the planet
before we you know got crazy and and you
know just started expanding like you
know or breeding like you know rabbits
so um that's kind of why you know I
think so many people have thanked me is
because it's it's made their watering
practic is easier um they're they've got
healthier plants um the biological
diversity is is much greater so
therefore the Expressions that we're all
looking for those you know second and
tertiary metabolites um are are are more
potent or or more expressed and you know
that's that's it I mean it's again
biomimicry copy nature and um get those
you know get those good uh diverse
biological communities up and running
for you and let them do the work so my
pleasure dude right on excellent I got
to agree with you I get letters all the
time about that um episode 54 on
biomimicry and people are all like you
have totally changed how um I grow thank
you so much for you know doing that
episode with Leon so it it seems to be
one of the things that we talk about
here on shaping fire that really you
know hit a nerve with people uh in both
directions right there's a lot of people
who are very excited and they're using
it and they're you know it works for
them and then there's people who are all
like this is not how I learned how to do
this and I need to do some push back and
you know I appreciate that too so long
as people are being polite about it so
if you want to um hear more shaping fire
episodes with our dear and Leighton
Morrison um you can go to shap and Fire
episode 54 on geology and biomimicry and
that is the original place where we talk
about this Horizon system this Horizon
style and explain the uh the philosophy
behind it the why um that we use it in
um containers um you can also check out
shaping Fire episode 59 with Leighton
Morrison which is just simply called
water and watering and it explains the
the life of uh the hydro life of your
container and uh you know kind of gives
you an idea of exactly how much to water
um more recently episode 82 on deploying
um aerobic and anerobic soil and um that
is a a mind opening and you'll learn a
lot about the types of compost teas that
you're going to want to use on different
varieties of soil at different times of
life as well um if you want to follow
along um
um you can follow his Instagram at
Kingdom aquaponics LLC and you can find
out what he's up to and also get
announcements for his uh incredibly
popular podcast on the future cannabis
uh project YouTube channel which is on
Thursdays um but if you follow him on
Instagram um you will always know who
his upcoming guest is and then finally
if you want to find out more about this
um this you know regenerative tent that
we grow in the shaping fire offices that
we're using as this demo tent that we've
been talking about today um you can find
lots of posts about it um at shaping
fire uh Instagram uh where we post
updates and howtos and a lot of mistakes
that I made so it's always a pretty good
laugh as well and that again is at
shaping fire on Instagram you can find
more episodes of the shaping fire
podcast And subscribe to the show at
shaping fire.com and wherever you get
your podcasts if you enjoyed the show
we'd really appreciate it if you would
leave a positive review of the podcast
wherever you download your review will
help others find the show so they can
enjoy it too on the shaping fire website
you can also subscribe to the newsletter
for insights into the latest Cannabis
News exclusive videos and giveaways on
the shaping fire website you also find
transcripts of today's podcast as well
be sure to follow on Instagram for all
original content not on the podcast
that's @ shaping fire and @ Shango on
Instagram be sure to check out the
shaping fire YouTube channel for
exclusive interviews farm tours and
cannabis lectures does your company want
to reach our national audience of
cannabis enthusiasts email hotspot at
shaping fire.com to find out how thanks
for listening to shaping fire I've been
your host Shango
[Music]
Los for