[Music]
buckle up buttercup we have a
groundbreaking episode for you today
it's always my goal when planning
shaping fire episodes to offer you
insightful information on topics that
are important to you in cannabis
mushrooms and other entheogens it's rare
though to have the opportunity to
present you with a topic that is so
far-reaching that it will literally
impact every country on the globe GL
today's episode is like that today we
will discuss how to replace nearly every
chemical insecticide with a natural
farming technique that is harmless and
easy to
make if you want to learn about cannabis
Health cultivation and technique
efficiently and with good cheer I
encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter we'll send you new podcast
episodes as they come out delivered
right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week and
videos too don't rely on social media to
let you know when a new episode is
published sign up for the updates to
make sure you don't miss an episode also
we're giving away very cool prizes to
folks who are signed up to receive the
newsletter this month's sponsor is TP
Wizards plant magic Homestead and five
lucky winners will receive the three
crosses of his grape green cake seed
line and be sure to check out their
Instagram accounts at plantor magore
Homestead uncore and of course tpor
wizard to see what else they up to so go
to shaping fire.com to sign up for the
newsletter and be entered into this
month's and all future newsletter prize
drawings you are listening to shaping
fire and I'm your host Shango Los
welcome to episode
118 my guest today is Chris Trump Chris
Trump is the world-renowned master
natural farmer certified student of
Master Cho hanq the creator of Korean
natural farming he has also studied
microbial analysis under Dr Elaine Ingam
many consider Chris's YouTube videos
explaining Korean natural farming
techniques to have been the key to KN
anf's widely increasing popularity in
the United States it is especially
helpful that Chris is a certified canif
educator who actually speaks English
Chris has traveled to 10 countries to
teach and Implement these natural
farming techniques with a passion for
reading and a research oriented Approach
To Nature Chris has fostered numerous
Innovations since he began practicing
natural farming on a 750 acre organic
macademia farm he managed with his
father from 2008 to 2018 he now teaches
natural farming for a wide range of food
crops livestock and cannabis Chris is
dedicated to working with youth and
farmers in developing nations equipping
communities with a holistic approach to
Natural farming education currently
based in Hawaii he is involved in
large-scale agricultural Consulting in
the US and conducts International
educational initiatives several times a
year through his company biom Solutions
Chris Trump educates communities of
natural Farmers throughout the world
offering Financial Independence
sovereignty and hope through natural
farming Chris has been a shaping fire
guest before on episode 35 we discussed
the basics of Korean natural farming and
its sudden rise in popularity in the
United States and Chris returned for
shaping Fire episode 68 to discuss using
Korean natural farming foler and Drench
preparations today we'll be discussing
indigenous predatory microorganisms
IPO during the first set we will review
the basics of preparing IMO how to use
it and how to upgrade your IMO to become
an effective pest preventative as
IPO during the second set we dig into
the supporting science and discuss best
practices and common failure points when
preparing and using IPO and we finished
the episode looking at how IPO works
with your other farming techniques and
how to scale IPO for large scale
agriculture as well as smaller home
cultivation while Chris discovered this
Innovation 10 years ago he says IPO is
still very new simply because people
haven't heard about it enough to
encourage widespread adoption he is
stoked to be explaining it in detail for
you today on shaping fire after Chris
explained IPO to me I knew I needed to
bring you this groundbreaking technique
truly if adopted widely IPO will change
the reality of farming around the world
including cannabis welcome back to
shaping fire Chris hey Shango thanks for
having me again it's so nice to like
have you back you know um since uh you
know so much of traveling and so many of
the conventions are gone since um you
know since covid and everything and I
like I really miss some of my like
goodly cannabis friends like you I miss
seeing you all sorts all places and
being able to catch up all the time so
it's nice to have some time to like have
a reason to chat yeah it's it's great
and uh I um yeah beyond the podcast
really enjoy connecting with you it's uh
good to know good people yeah amen dude
so all right cool well let's let's Dive
Right In now um there's going to be a
lot of people who are here because
they're interested in predatory IMO but
they don't really know what IMO is and
and you and I have already done an a
shaping Fire episode um that uh you know
that talks about IMO and how to do it
and of course you have got you know very
popular
um YouTube videos that explain every
single step of of collecting IMO and
then and then you know I don't know
upconverting it through imo1 1234 so so
you know for for people who don't know
IMO this information is available to
them at at your website biomay dos
solutions that said we need to start out
with a quick run through of IMO so as we
talk about how to adapt Imo um as a
pesticide as it were um uh we need to
give people like a thumbnail so that we
can work with this so I I know that me
asking you to summarize IMO in you know
just a few paragraphs is like impossible
ask for me but but yeah will you do that
anyway will will you give us a a short
introduction to IMO indigenous
microorganisms so that we we get
everybody on the same page and then we
can push forward yeah absolutely and
um yeah the IMO is
um in its best form a snapshot of uh the
entire Community that's existing in a
wild place and when I say wild Place
ideally this is a u multiple
Generations um in in human time uh
undisturbed land so um
places that didn't get you know pushed
with a bulldozzer to make a housing
complex and now have a nice park with
some things growing in the shrubs uh a a
genuinely uh
established um old ecosystem is what
we're going for and a snapshot of that
balance that's been struck over a long
period of time between the organisms
that causes the life and the plants to
thrive or maybe the limited life in a
desert place like Mojave um to thrive
um we go there and we coax onto an augur
of rice because it is uh a great fungal
food and um many organisms can dwell
there um and we get a snapshot a bit of
the bacteria ye stara fungi Etc not so
much the macro bigger organisms um and
we put those um immediately into so Step
One is is kind of coaxing them onto that
auger step two imo2 would be immediately
putting them to borrow a Sci-Fi term
into cryofreeze we we stop their um
development we stop their replication by
um mixing them with brown sugar the
cosmotic pressure the dryness of the
sugar creates kind of a saltfish on a
long sea Voyage scenario where things go
pretty um stable and um and can last for
a long time so a farmer can have imo2
collections on their Shelf ready to go
to the next step for three plus years
without ever having to go out and
collect again um and that's that's
actually a really positive thing for a
farmer in their workflow um imo3 and
four are growing it out on substrate uh
is is three substrates uh that that I
love right now is uh rice brand and oats
mixed with wood chips um for imo3 and
then IMO 4 is that plus some soil which
brings in some
macroorganisms um that complete um
material that im4 is now shelf stable
really indefinitely if it's kept in a
dry cool place and that is used as a
farmer diverse inoculum key being
diverse um that they can use to enliven
their soil and prevent disease and pests
awesome thank you Chris the only part
that I want to expand a little bit is um
for anybody who's unfamiliar with
collecting IMO the idea of a a of
coaxing microbes onto an augur of rice
is probably a little vague and I'll tell
you a listener that essentially what
he's talking about is is taking some
cooked White rice and putting it in a in
a in a sterile uh wooden box with an
open top and then setting it out in
nature so that all of the things that
are you know in your natural habitat
land on the rice and can start to
colonize the rice thus coaxing these
microbes onto a food source is that a
good summary yeah yeah it's it's um the
the rice is falling out of the bottom
onto the ground so there's a little
stairway of Heaven of food from that you
find like a fungally rich area so that
there's literally a Stairway of rice
leading up into this box of rice and
fungi will grow up in a week time you'll
have some blooms that actually grow up
into it um you put some in on top and
and uh things can fall through the paper
towel that is the only barrier between
your rice and the outside world and yeah
it is it's uh it's that you you
clarified that wonderfully yeah sorry
for the tech term oh it's it's all good
you're used to speaking with people who
are who have some familiarity with it
and and I just want to make sure that
everybody we bring everybody along so so
what we're trying to do is we're we're
trying to capture some of the prevalent
local microbes and then through this
process of imo1 and two we essentially
incubate them to have them reproduce so
we've we've got this inoculant that we
can use on our farm or or deck patio or
even in even indoors in a in a indoor
growing situation but they are the
microbes that are popular to your
particular locality so so your IMO that
that you have on Hawaii uh is going to
be different than the IMO that I have on
Vashon Island and and so it's it very
much captures the sense of place of the
place so yeah and and why that why
that's important Shango uh just last uh
thought indigenous is important because
when you go through all this
to get these microbes from you know
across town or up in the hills uh around
your uh bio region or just your
surrounding area some healthier place
maybe than your farm is um and you get
it established in your farm because it
likes that barometric pressure that
rainfall that temperature that soil type
um that General region um it's
indigenous to there um it will
self-perpetuate meaning you could apply
once and 10 years from now find it there
thriving and serving your your crop
whereas when we buy things from a jug
that was grown in a lab um it's it's
well known that we have about 6 months
Max that that will even be
found and um you know we can't really
move these imos around because of the
the difference in environment if we took
an IMO that I made here on Bashon Island
and I took it on vacation
to my buddy's place in New Mexico well
our our environments are so different
than all my um indigenous microb species
are probably all just going to die at
his house and and and vice versa so it's
really important for you to be able to
um have both you know Lo in in each
locality yeah and and yours would
perform on that vacation trip yours
would perform much like when you buy a
jug it would have some benefit on the
short term but you're not going to get
that community that now works for you
Builds on its own and becomes actually
um a thriving soil with with very little
additional input you know other than you
know getting uh plants to grow in it
right on okay so now now we got
everybody on the same page and and if
you're you know if you're already into
Korean natural farming and you already
know all this stuff well I appreciate
your patience through this while we got
everybody along so so now let's talk
about like the the primary reason why um
we're talking today Chris which what is
is taking this IMO and and turning it
into something that that um uh I've been
calling predatory IMO um I've heard you
call it a couple different things uh
since you are the from as far as I'm
aware the inventor of it are is that the
term you're using as predatory IMO or or
have you got a different phrase that you
prefer yeah we call it IPO um so
indigenous predatory microorganism I
also love the acronym kind of playing on
the um I IPM and Imo together yeah
integrated Pest Management um so so yeah
it's uh the acronym works for me but it
is it's a um inop pathogenic fungi so
it's a it's a predatory or insect eating
fungi all right so so you know mostly in
second set but throughout the show today
we're going to talk about IPO in detail
but but just to give people a good
context with which to put all of this
information we're about to give them in
will you just give us a cursory
explanation of of um what
IPO does and then second the experience
that you had that made you realize that
the the pests and Imo could be brought
together for a beneficial
solution yeah absolutely um
IPO uh what it does for a farmer um I'm
here in Hawaii at the moment I actually
uh um was out right before this
interview placing some boxes of IPM Mo
so um because I have a client um that is
uh uh the largest uh kind of uh Kaa
coffee um producer here in in Hawaii
and they deal with a coffee bore Beetle
uh along with several other pests and
they hired me to help them overcome some
of their pest and some of their disease
problems um what our IPO has done um in
the last six months they've only been
running a program here for six months
they are pest free they're um cute
wonderful sorry I shouldn't say cute
he's a um elderly man Colombian uh
lifetime kind of coffee uh expert that
runs their coffee is tickled pink he is
so stoked because when we started I told
him he wouldn't have to buy all these
expensive products he was buying to try
and unsuccessfully manage his pests but
now with IPO application they are pest
free and they are uh tickled pink they
are very very happy clients and so when
I send them my bill they are uh happy to
pay it uh but um IPO is a fairly lowcost
uh solution to um managing uh several of
not all um well I don't know if not all
is actually accurate because a healthy
plant is also pest resistant but um IPO
is uh something that has the potential
to stay established in your
farm once
applied and give you a reoccurring um
resistance to or buffer against um
really kist insects or insects that have
some degree of exoskeleton or kiten in
their body um which is a lot of our pest
that we deal with especially since
you're on shaping fire and we're
primarily talking about cannabis like
that's the vast majority of ours yep y
yep absolutely all right so um uh you've
told me uh uh the cool story about where
the idea originally came to you so why
you know I know you've told the story
publicly before but but why why don't
you give it to people because it's a
pretty good story yeah absolutely so I
um I started natural farming um because
we needed a better way to farm or a more
profitable way to farm in one of the
most expensive places to farm in the US
which is big island of Hawaii or Hawaii
in general and uh our crop is macadamia
nuts um and um I made a scaled natural
farming uh made a lab for our 750 acre
uh Macadamia farm and uh we
were uh years into
um the um successful operation of our
natural farming uh Madame nuts and um
while running our natural farming I I
set it up uh to be by and large run by
one person so all our natural farming
operations were a one person kind of
operation
um I was doing that plus I had a lot of
responsibilities um as a manager so I
was busy all that to say and um I came
to our um natural farming lab and we
were almost out of our IMO which we're
using to make a liquid IMO a um a foler
spray of this indigenous
microorganism and
um I went to make some more in my um
material that uh the substrate I take
that imo2 and grow it out um on you know
200 lbs of uh fat-rich grains um and
wood chips had weevils in it my my seed
stock my feed stock had weevils in it
weevils are these little tiny beetles um
that get into grains and um they're
about the size they're smaller than a
grain of rice and I was like oh no uh my
grain's bad you know and because I'm on
an island with limited access to things
I knew it was going to be like 2 weeks
before I was going to be able to get it
ordered and get down you know an hour to
pick it up get back and make some and so
that was a that was going to be a huge
significant uh cost because that means
our spray program was going to be put
behind by a couple weeks and um with our
achorage and just one teab Brewer 500g
te Brewer that was a long time so I said
it was I'm I'm saying all this to say it
wasn't totally uh um just because I
didn't I was being lazy but I said you
know what whatever I'm going to make it
with uh some weevils anyway and
um went through the normal process I
have all these uh 12 IMO collections I'm
using to put in their IMO 2s and uh made
my imo3 and I'm mixing it uh daily
making sure it's going right and I saw
these like bright white puff balls
showing um on the surface of my imo3 I
can still see it in my mind's eye um
because it was really um striking I've
done this a lot and this was a total
change and
um I look at this because I'm curious by
nature and in the center of these white
puff balls is one of the
weevils and um they're scattered out
throughout so the weevils are growing
white puffballs and I'm like wow that's
really cool super interesting but I
don't have time to look into this right
now so I continued finished my IMO made
a liquid IMO and um that process of it
going out uh 20 acres at a time
continued and like a good farmer I
aspire to be I walked through my 20 acre
um plot that had just gotten sprayed the
day before or two days before whatever
it was and um just seeing how the trees
respond you know it's just something you
got to check up on periodically and
um out on the trees in our Orchard um in
the crook of a tree I saw a white
puffball very similar to what I had seen
in my
imo3 and I what is going on I look
closer and it is a um green stink bug uh
little uh Beetle creature which is one
of our primary pests in
Macadam um something that almost took
our farm under years ago um and I I was
like yes I'm still busy I don't have
time to like look into a curiosity but
now with a connection to what was
happening there and what I'm seeing in
the orchard now that it's transferred
here I'm like oh dang so I did a deep
dive of research and pursuit of what is
going on to find um that Beatles one of
their primary insects of the
whole Kingdom of Krist insects is fungi
and so I
deduced um and now we know 10 years
later more um induced accurately that we
had
wildcrafted a predatory
fungi and gotten it
to apply onto our Orchard where we were
getting now um this kill and um so I
loved it but then I was like well I
don't actually have to do anything it
just keeps happening now because I have
a whole box and we're spraying it out
and so I was like done our our pest
problem is going to decrease and um I
just kind of left it um to uh you know
benefit us passively uh forever and then
um I had a friend that needed help he
had um a locust population descending on
their Farm in Zimbabwe and he's like hey
is there anything natural farming that
will help and uh I said no but I did
discover this thing um a few years ago
and uh we've been seeing great results
and um walked them through it we did the
trials there with it and he had 100%
kill uh well the farm surrounding him
got devastated by Locust and um he had a
full crop went to all the way to Market
they were doing hemp 100 acres of hemp
there and so he had he had basically a
shield on his on his crop um that was
basically a Minefield for Locust of uh
their Predator it's like filling a
filling a tank of piranhas and you know
being the uh yeah like I I dare you to
land on my property exactly
exactly um so so let's break this out
just a little bit um for people so they
can see the application in Zimbabwe so
they had locusts so what your friend in
Zimbabwe would have done would have been
to make
IMO with the body of a couple dead
locusts set upon the rice in the IMO
collection is that
accurate yeah pretty much um you can
cook it um with the rice inside so you
can get a handful of those focus and put
it in the rice um you can also put um
insects in the um in the next stage that
imo3 stage um but it is less likely that
you're going to get what I had happen
um in unless you start with that first
step that I am a one so yeah we've kind
of we've kind of Jed it over the last uh
10 years and the best practice has been
to um to put your for your pest into
your rice and cook some I I also put
some uncooked in there so I'll cook my
rice with some in insects in there which
does smell a little bit if your insects
are smelly and then uh and then I'll
also take some uncooked insects and toss
them in as a as a topping on top before
we put them Mountain we're really just
uh putting the food source of the guys
we're trying to get to um colonize our
rice box right on you're saying you're
saying you know hey you molds that love
to eat the my target pest we've got you
we've got some of your favorite food on
top of some uh delicious rice why don't
you kind of come over here and colonize
this rice and you can eat of the pred of
the insect and also of the rice and you
can make this your house and then you're
like yeah and then and then you uh
incubate it from that point yep then I
then I have it as an inoculum
um and it isn't guaranteed that where
I'm going to put my rice box uh with
this insect in it that there is even a
predatory fungi to colonize it so that's
the that's one of the things to note
here this is um ends up being a little
bit of a numbers game where you want to
put out six boxes in various locations
um and what you can do visually is
notice when a carcass or uh some kist
insect has a unique Bloom on it or you
can really see that the fungi is chewing
on that creature in the collection box
in the collection box yeah so so
visually you can kind of verify um right
on so um I'm I'm sure that uh you know
different cannabis cultivators who are
listening are thinking about this in
regards to their own local pests right
where you are in the country you know
you've got different kinds of pests um
and I know that you do a lot of you know
General agriculture but you've been
helping those of us in cannabis for
years so um what are some of the pests
that you um you know know are are good
for this kind of process that that
affect the cannabis
plant yeah well
um I would say maybe
it is it's best if you can get a um one
of your local pests to put in the rice
box also not totally necessary so there
is um some challenge for some people to
get a pest also if you have cannabis you
don't necessarily want to produce a ton
of a pest just so you can put it in a
rice box yeah that's a good point too
yeah so one of the things you can do is
just buy insect frass um insect frass is
a product that gets sold um as a
byproduct from um insect production so
some place that produces crickets for
your local snakes or or your snake pets
or whatever um those um those places
will sell their kind of broken body
parts of their of their um Prime product
um in a bag so you can just order off
Amazon a bag of insect trash or pick it
up at your local um Garden store that
can be a substitute for using your own
um actual pest well that's interesting
so are you suggesting that um car you
know a carrus of an insect I'm just
assuming that they're all made out of
kiten and if this is true um you know I
could use some of my insect frass from
talab in my Imo
because I don't want to cause a plant to
be covered in for example mites so that
I can capture them so I'm like okay well
I might not want to breed mites for my
to make this pesticide but if I use you
know some kind of other insect's frass
that also has a carrus that it will
cross over to my target might is that
what you're saying absolutely right on
yeah that's that's really convenient I
hadn't thought about that I can imagine
that actually sourcing some of the
things especially insects that are so
small that we can't even see
them yeah yeah exactly and um and
speaking of insects that are so small
you can't see them um and um insects
that are big enough to see them um you
can also grab insects like maybe you
don't have anything on your cannabis
plant but uh you're growing some squash
outside and there's squash beetles all
over it from you know the summer and you
could grab a handful of those and put
them on your rice and you're Off to the
Races so you don't have to buy insect
Fass you don't have to have your exact
pest um it is more that that uh tasty
protein uh that we understand now there
are things I'm sure I don't understand
about how nature works and so using some
of your actual pests could be best
practice I would strongly encourage if
that's possible to do that use them if
you got them use them if you got them
right on so so those of us who have who
have followed you and your education and
learned from you for years like I have
um uh we know that you are um a student
of Master Cho and you are both educated
in and are educator of uh Korean natural
farming does this process fit neatly
into KF already or is this more like
yeah the IMO collection is is knf but as
soon as I added the the pest we moved on
to something else or or is or is this
like new ground for knf that actually
fits in that in that um educational
family
easily yeah definitely not something I
was taught in Korea nor is there really
precedent for it um in in that education
however it um it's not
um I have uh students and friends that
learned about this they grow cannabis
and uh they love the benefit of IMO and
have for years and learned about IPO and
now they just do IPO to like or not two
um they just do IMO IPO because um with
the insects in it because they're
getting the benefits still of IMO
because there's a lot of other things
that grow in the rice um in addition to
um the benefit of of some predatory
fungi so um a lot of people that have
adopted it are just um doing IPO now
because um they could kind of both and
um I am uh cautious to say that's best
practice because um when you add
something like cooked insects into the
rice it kind of changes
um the the nitrogen kind of density of
the rice it changes some things you know
depending on the insects you use or or
the stinkiness of the insect frass some
insect frass is pretty smelly um it
could really be changing um some of it
so I wouldn't uh outright say just do
IPO it's better than IMO but um I do
know that that has become standard
operating procedure for a bunch of
cannabis Farms right on so um before we
go to our first break um I want to just
confirm with you um this seems like
there there isn't any reason that we
couldn't use this indoor right like like
we prefer to be growing Outdoors Under
the Sun and under perfect situations
that's wonderful but there's lots of
people who don't have an outdoors and so
they're growing in a greenhouse or or or
home cultivating in a tent and is there
any reason why um we could not uh
cultivate a local Imo for ourselves um
you know either using you know say for
example spider mites or or or often a
big problem in indoor um and throw those
in there and then just spray it indoors
as well like it'd be great to be
outdoors but we don't have to so this is
actually a solution for indoor
cultivators too y yeah foler foler
application um weekly is kind of the SOP
for um for yeah bug free disease free
and then people cut that off depending
on your region of
um growth and whether or not you're
you're submitting for testing uh in the
legal Market um some places uh they're
you know um parts per million of
microbes is um you know more strict than
others I know like Colorado is twice as
strict as California um so there they'll
stop um that spray um um uh right before
flower you know so though you know and
then other places um you know like
Washington that they don't have quite as
strict as Colorado they're spraying
through flour with no um negative
results maybe cutting off right before
Harvest so yeah it is definitely um
great for indoor and outdoor um I
actually have a uh a fun bit um as an
alternate food source then uh there's
um there's this really cool thing that
happens in uh in seed um
germination uh a germinating seed um
that uh and I don't think I've talked
about this much uh um publicly so just
for you Shango
nice germinating seed um in its very
beginning of its germination um is um so
like malted grains if you will um that
that just beginning of germination
produces kitase protein so right when a
seed starts if you have it in the ground
in nature um it's producing A protein
that is good food for predatory fungi so
if a if a seed is uh new new to the
block um human or just make a human
analogy and they're trying to make
friends with those people that would
protect them
um they would uh you know give gifts uh
that they're new friends would like so
you know sending my 5-year-old to uh
kindergarten with a box of Oreos you
know he's going to be uh real popular at
lunch uh time as he shares with new
friends
um in a similar way um germinating seeds
will put out um nutrients to invite uh
relationships in their root Zone that
will be uh there for their whole lives
so if a seed grows in this uh wild
forest as it begins making root
relationships with fungi which is how
nature Works um it um will then maintain
a lot of those relationships as it grows
into a large tree or shrub or whatever
seed it is um so in the early stages of
its development it's putting out this
protein that it doesn't put out any
other time and that protein um then
becomes kind of a invitation for uh
relationship with something that's going
to protect it from
pests so when I go out into nature and
look for a good spot to potentially find
these predatory fungi I also will um if
I have the opportunity look for a place
where seeds are falling and
germinating um because there will be an
additional food source for these
predatory fungi um so like I was just
out today uh placing an IPO box and I
found a spot that has Ki nuts macadamia
nuts and um Ironwood trees which drop
these little Pine cones with uh seeds in
them I was seeing on the germinating
pine cone seed uh germinating pine cones
where the seeds are germinating uh fungi
blooming out of the germinating pine
cones and so I'm like oh cool and I'm
placing my boxes here one because
there's a bunch of fungi around so I'm
looking for that normal kind of mycelial
mat and health but also I'm like in
addition I know that there's a ton of
this kiten protein
um happening every time one of these
seeds starts to germinate in the ground
and so um yeah a little bit on uh how to
find also if you wanted to grow it out
sorry getting verbose but uh if you
wanted to grow it out an imo3 having
sprouted grains um could be a way to
increase the food source for these um
predatory fungi right on good and you
know it's interesting to hear you talk
about the location where these seeds
fall um you know I know that our IMO
collection is is um you know bio U
biomimicking nature but it's really
funny because when you describe it my
brain said oh that's like that's like
natural IMO collection it's like like no
dude that's just called nature you
know yeah it is it is it is I mean in
its very best all of all of this that
we're doing is just part partnering with
what with the strength and the the power
really that is already at play for the
health of plants in in nature yeah all
right so um so let's wrap up first uh
set here uh so dear listener stay with
us you know if if this is of interest to
you stick around because um I going to
totally interrogate Chris in second set
on the finer points and how to use it so
um we're going to be a quick short break
and be right back you are listening to
shaping fire and my guest today is
natural farming innovator Chris Trump
now without these advertisers shaping
fire wouldn't happen so please support
them and let them know you heard them on
shaping
fire fish poop brand fertilizer is an
allnatural fish poop concentrate with
nothing added real fish poop is
extraordinarily complex not only are you
adding the nitrogen phosphorus and
pottassium your plants need to build
mass transport nutrients and enhance
flavor but fish waste is also packed
with biological activity and
micronutrients when you add fish poop to
your irrigation water you are adding
life force probiotics and active
microbes these microorganisms include a
wealth of various bacteria and protozoa
which further enhance nutrient
availability for the plants because
plants are limited by the absence of any
essential micronutrient these Trace
nutrients are the difference between
having a decent garden and having a
garden that makes you feel really proud
out of your efforts fish poop is a
naturally complete solution that fills
in the cracks in your fertilizer program
to ensure you offer your garden a broad
base of nutrients not all fish poop is
created equally most products with added
fish waste don't reveal their sources or
lab results fish poop brand fish poop
however generates their own fish waste
as a byproduct of their organic
aquaponics cannabis farm where they
raise ornamental koi and tilapia you are
even invited to tour their Farm in
person or on their YouTube channel to
look for yourself this sort of
transparency is wildly rare in the
fertilizer Market the folks behind fish
poop are also lifelong medical cannabis
producers who have deep Connections in
the community donate more product than
they sell and support cannabis prisoner
veteran and patient collectives and
Charities to get your bottle of pure
fish poop go to fish poop.com and to see
their entire line of cannabis products
go to ounce ofh hope.com that's fish
poop brand fish
poop this message is for folks who grow
cannabis I'm talking to Hom Growers
patients and Commercial Growers too I'm
probably talking to you when you plan
out your next growing cycle be sure to
check out Humbolt CSI seeds at Humbolt
csi.com Caleb inspecta and his family
have lived in Humble County for over a
100 years for the last 40 years three
generations of his have cultivated
extraordinary sensia cannabis in Humble
mesino and Trinity counties because of
his lineage and the hard-earned
experience that comes from growing up
smoking and sifting large populations of
cannabis plants in Northern California
the seeds you'll cop from CSI will be
winning genetics based on longtime Heavy
Hitters and updated and reffed to bring
out new and exotic traits and better
yields go ahead and ask around Caleb
also known as inspecta and pirates of
the emerald triangle is a breeders
breeder he reaches way back and works
with significant strains recreating them
in new and interesting ways that you'll
love as a toker and a grower as well as
offering you some surprises that will
Delight serious seed Traders and
cultivators humble CSI goes a further
step and selfs all these kavars so you
know all the seeds will be female these
are not experimental feminized seeds
humbold CSI releases some of the best
female seeds available anywhere and if
it will show in your garden folks grew
quite a bit of CSI humble genx last year
here on Vashon Island and everyone was
pleased the patients had beautiful
female plants and didn't have to call
half of their Garden as males the folks
growing for the fun of getting high grew
colorful flowers with exceptional bag
appeal and great highs and breeders had
seven out of seven females in a pack
which gave them a lot of phenotypic
choices take a moment right now and
visit humbled CSI
you'll find an up-to-date menu of both
feminized and regular lines along with
photos and descriptions that's humble
csi.com
businesses everywhere are striving to
reach people through advertising we all
know though that trying to reach a
cannabis audience with a quality message
is pretty difficult that's why many
people choose to advertise on the
shaping fire podcast advertising on this
show allows us time to talk talk about
your product service or brand in a way
that really lets people know what sets
your company apart from others bold
people who own companies know that
getting into relationship with their
customers is essential and that is what
we offer we will explain your service or
product what sets it apart as desirable
and help our audience get in contact
with you it's pretty simple really
advertising does not have to be all
whizbang smoke and mirrors nowadays I
find that people prefer just to be
spoken to calmly accurately and with
good intentions if you want to make your
own commercial spot well you can do that
too during these pandemic days
conventions and cannabis events are
pretty poorly attended but podcast
listening is
skyrocketing with a commercial on
shaping fire you'll reach your customers
in the privacy of their headphones right
now and will continue to reach new
listeners as they explore the shaping
fire back catalog of episodes again and
again for
years a spot on shaping fire costs less
than a printed postcard per person and
the shaping fire audience is full of
smart cannabis enthusiasts cultivators
and entrepreneurs who are always curious
to learn do yourself a solid and contact
us today for rates on podcast and
Instagram
advertising email hotspot shaping
fire.com to find out more
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire I am your host Shango Los
and my guest today is natural farming
innovator Chris Trump so before the
break we talked a lot about generally
what IPO is and uh where it came from
where Chris originally got the idea and
then a little bit of how to um adapt
your IMO collection for it and and a
little bit how to use it so if you're
still here it means that you actually
care about this and and welcome and we
are about to get real specific with our
questions so um so Chris let's start
with this um you know uh does the
inclusion of pest carapaces so their
outside shell influence the microbial
diversity in IMO compared to traditional
methods you talked a little bit about
this in the first set that um perhaps
you would recommend U doing traditional
Imo
alongside
IPO because if you're going to if you're
going to do the version of IPO where you
cook the pest with the rice you're
really changing the rice it's not like
neutral rice that will take all comers
so you're not going to get a really
great
snapshot of the natural world around you
because because you've influenced the
rice whereas if you do the version where
you just put the Target pest on the rice
when you lay out the box um you've got
most of the rice is which is just
neutral rice and and you're going to
collect all comers on the rice but then
you're going to Target the molds that
are going to be on the carpas if I if
I've understood you correctly um like
like like how how do you think the the
IMO might be influenced if you only did
the
IPO yeah this is a really really good
question um I think uh one of the things
to say um and help me stay on track but
before I even answer that is how
important um some of the details of IMO
um there are lots of ways to compost
there are lots of cool things we can do
with microbial life in um you know in
farm mean um but IMO is a fairly nuanced
um think of it as a very Boutique you
know the difference between Jose quero
and uh absolute topshelf tequila like um
all the ingredients you know are similar
you know the process is similar um but
one will be painful uh when you wake up
in the morning and the other will be
smooth and might even uh you know
nourish your body um the the difference
between um you know IMO and something
where you've changed details um um is
much more impactful than uh the example
I gave there with tequila um the um the
details matter in IMO the um the
difference between producing a bunch of
bacteria and um really giving the
opportunity for fungi to grow out in a
um uh feed stock or a substrate um is um
is just a little bit of difference you
know how much water you use um you know
your how much carbon Etc so um you know
now going to adding this other um type
of uh feed stock into that first step um
really can have an effect now we want to
do it because we found we can produce a
predatory fungi and uh have effect on
our farm which affects our bottom line
gives us a healthier crop um so
definitely we're here talking about it
because it's good um and if I were to
give you maybe what I think could be a
way that you could cuz here here's the
thing yes we can say you have to do it
just like this but natural farming I'm
constantly faced with a balance between
quality of what we're producing and the
efficiency or or the time in a farmer's
life you know and and uh these are those
are important things on two sides of a
scale um you know um and so I'm uh of
the
opinion that one of the most efficient
and effective ways to do good IMO and
still do IPO is um to produce your
IPO second stage so you put out your
rice with your insect carapus in it and
you put it in
cryofreeze um uh theoretically or I mean
uh
metaphorically um with the sugar and now
it's a inoculum on your shelf when you
make imo3 that next stage you can use
some of that IPO as long as well as some
regular imo2 rice and grow that all out
together um I kind of hinted at a a feed
stock um being in your imo3 for um IPO
to grow out on and I think that that is
also um a good option having a little
bit of sprouted grains or um some insect
carrus in your imo3 can be great thing
too um yes can totally change it short
answer but um not too worried about that
being um bad um as long as you have some
regular imo2 um going into your imo3 you
know like a lot of hobbies say for
example baking you know it's really
important to follow the rules very
specifically until you don't need to
follow the the the recipe anymore um you
know right on the not yeah I'm very ADHD
man and I uh I'm a fantastic cook but
I'm I'm I'm an awful Baker because
you're supposed to follow the directions
directly and and I'm that is not my
strong point um and I ran into the same
thing with IMO the first two times I
made it you know I cut Corners I I tried
to improve on your teaching myself you
know doing it the first time and um I
got I got garbage twice and then I
realized you know what let's just do it
the way Chris says the first time and
and I and I and so I I I did it and I
struggled and I did it without making
any changes and the damn thing worked
beautifully right and and so um I think
it's the same kind of thing with this
like if if somebody is is wasn't very
interested in IMO before but now that
it's a now that it's a very healthy
pesticide if you will um now they want
to do it um I think it brings us back to
um make your
IPO as intended following the IMO recipe
and adding the predatory in or at at our
Target insect all following the
directions the first time and then as
you get familiar with it you'll have
more Fidelity with it and you know just
like a baker you know eventually you can
bake stuff without even measuring stuff
right because you just unknow it that
well well you know I just recommend that
people start by actually following the
IMO protocol specifically because
there's so many ways that seem minor
that you can totally screw up and most
of the stuff that we're working with we
can't visibly see because they're
microbes and molds and stuff yeah I I
love that whole commentary Shango I
think you're you're dead on and the um
yeah I can't I can't stress enough like
don't change anything at all um and the
reason I'm I'm definitely um particular
in uh in a lot of things I also love to
cook and if I'm going to bake something
I know like I wanted to learn how to
cook mering and I took time like studied
the recipe played with the you know the
details people put in the and uh and I
got to be great at cooking Marines
little bit gooey in the middle but if
you change anything in recipe including
like a dirty spoon you know it mering
won't won't work and so I I uh I think I
love that analogy
um I also just a little um detail if I
could uh make a request that is uh we
don't ever call IPO a
pesticide because it isn't um really it
is a a re-
enlivening of your environment to uh the
semblance of Nature and um we are
actually um uh cultivating life we're
not trying to kill anything we're
cultivating life in such a way that we
actually have the Natural Balance and
pressure that nature allows you know uh
we don't see um complete Devastation and
annihilation of all plants due to an
outbreak of spidermites in the forest
you know and it's because there's the
sufficient life that creates the
ecosystem of balance and um alternating
pressure um that causes you know
everything to perpetuate so um also
there are some things that you can run
into if you start calling things a
pesticide um and you have to talk to
somebody from the EPA and you know it's
a whole thing so yeah I follow that all
right that's that's good and you know
what when I said pesticide earlier you
may have heard me even slow down and
pause I'm like a this isn't the right
word but I'm not sure what to use so
yeah yeah it sounds like using the the
IPO phrase itself is the is the more
accurate yeah and it sorry I I'm I'm not
actually bothered by it but also we're
we're teaching this right totally we
want to do we want to set people up
right and we don't want them talking to
um people as if it's a pesticide and and
and something that I know you will get
that you and I would agree on is it
we're trying to teach a paradigm here
and it's not about pesticides and
coating stuff in chemicals and going out
there and just like kill all the things
including the target what we're in doing
is we're essentially encouraging the
enemies of our
enemy right put that on the label
yeah and so and so you know it's it's
it's not like we're not going there and
dropping a bomb we're just we're just
sending some help to to to our
teammates yeah I mean it's uh it's
that's great I love it yeah it's uh it's
it's really it's it's not an issue um
except that we have governing bodies
that uh and and the there's things with
the same name if we call it a PES
there's things of the same name that
have nothing in common to what we're
talking about you know yeah it's
strategically and like I don't know
about ethically but but strategically
totally different approach yeah all
right so let's move on you were talking
about your mering and how if you um if
you use a dirty spoon it'll destroy the
mering let's talk about that same thing
about collection collecting our Target
in insects because in in preparing for
this I was talking to my buddies while
we were uh big leafing the other day
and um and and we were talking about you
know the difficulty or the challenge
with um
uh uh contaminating IMO and we were
thinking about ways that we might
contaminate the IMO by
contaminating the target pest so let's
let's use the Locust since um we can
pick those up with our fingers and we've
already been talking about the Locust um
have you developed any practices for
collecting the Locust for example or the
spider might for
example so that um we don't in some way
contaminate the the the target insect
and thus screw up our IPM o we were
talking about like man I really think
that when I collect these bugs I'm going
to want to wear
gloves um I I think gloves gloves would
be great there's nothing wrong with
using gloves um I think that might be
unnecessary Clean
Hands um you know simply wash your hands
rinse them well make sure there's not a
bunch of soap on them or anything like
that um uh would be enough like um a
contamination one of the number one
contaminations humans spring is a
slightly less than well washed hand
after using the restroom you know and
that's you know that's enough to make
people sick and a little e ecoli to your
IMO exactly it'll liquefy your rice and
that is uh um when you see um I am a one
that's been liquefied in the middle it
is probably uh eoli or a similar uh
small fast replicating bacteria um and
so that is one IMO collection people are
like well it's so like hard to know
what's good and you know there's you
know uh detail sometimes you say you
know colors can be fine you know as long
as it's not all one color um but one
thing I say 100% of the time you never
want to use an IMO that has um gooey
middle or or liquefied rice or or slimy
in in any part of it because that will
never make good imo3 so word to the wise
you want to exclude one um I am a one
type as it finishes one way that it
looks that you're like okay I know for
sure that's wrong is gooey middle slimy
um but um another thing um to avoid uh
quote unquote
contaminating your um insects would be
not um bringing much of their
environment or um their poop
um one of the things that happens if you
harvest a bunch of living insects is um
and you leave them in a bag for a couple
days and they're alive um is they will
defecate in the bag and then you have
insects plus all their little defecation
that gets pretty funky pretty quick so
um something you can do is Clean Hands
throw them in a bag and then immediately
when you're done harvesting throw it in
the freezer
so throw them in a Ziploc throw the
Ziploc in a freezer you'll kill them
without damaging them and they won't go
through you know the process of funking
funking up their environment um so yeah
that's that's kind of how I go about it
I was out um the other day um in my I am
growing Ginger and uh I was out there
and um I was harvesting Japanese rose
beetle cuz they're devastating the
leaves and so I'm going to make an IMO
an IPO and uh foler spray them uh uh
next week and
um uh the I went in there to kind of
take off some of the bits of um leaf and
stuff that I had Harvest with because
you're grabbing this Beetle off a leaf
and then you're grabbing a piece of leaf
and I don't want to put that in the rice
and uh they're all alive so they started
flying out of the bag and so uh I threw
them in the freezer um and uh yeah that
was that um I I want to point out
another thing that you said that
deserves to be hit again and you pointed
out um you know wash your hands sure but
make sure there's no residual soap and I
want to double down on that because um
uh hand sanitizer is so much more common
too and we don't want anything that
kills microbes in the Imo box so if you
have a residual soap on your hands maybe
you use like a thick uh liquid soap in
your bathroom maybe or maybe you use
some hand sanitizer and that stuff like
that stuff leaves a lot of residue on
your fingers and then you go and you
pick up your your you know um Locust or
whatever and then you put the Locust on
top of your IMO rice you actually have
put Locust and micro
killing Agents from your fingers into
your IMO and so you know clean hands are
good clean residue residue of
cleanliness is not
good let there be no record of gaminess
yeah um so the um number one reason
where why people fail to make uh in the
Camis cannabis industry they call it
Labs lab lactic acid bacteria which a
lot of people use to to treat and
prevent powdery mildew you can totally
just use Liquid IMO cuz it already has
labs in it but um people you know will
send me pictures and they're like blah
blah blah what went wrong and I did this
I did all the things you said I cleaned
my jar I said did you make sure that you
had no soap scum left in your jar did
you double rinse it and they like oh no
probably not that that is that is the
leading reason why people's lab does not
develop is a little bit of soap and you
will not produce any lactic acid
bacteria your milk will just go funky
and so yeah it's it's um it's there's
precedent for double-checking that you
don't and so even if you have a
collection box that you've made and you
cleaned it out with some soap that can
go right into the wood and now you can
have a soap filled box that will um
inhibit microbes um baskets um that have
a bunch of shellac or like coating on
the on the Wicker um Can can uh off gas
when you get it kind of warm with um
microb development and that off gassing
can wipe out your community um and uh
and then you know people go through all
this effort um sorry I'm going down the
ways that it can go wrong here are the
ways that it can go wrong um people go
through all this effort and they get
their rice right and they got their
their bugs and then they put it in a
plastic container without any holes and
all this life that starts going in there
now starts breathing and producing um
buildup of water and uh then it rots the
edges and it'll fail every time even
though it started great because you had
all the right things just the fact that
it doesn't breathe will be enough so um
some sort of natural material um
untreated baskets or um I make little
wood boxes um that is really really
important um when you're doing your
imo1 um so you know most of us
understand that traditional IMO when
it's time to go and apply it um we will
do a folar spray um uh over the tops and
bottoms of the leaves of the plant and
um I'm going to guess that the IPO is
applied the same way as if it was
regular IMO is that
accurate absolutely um IPO can be
applied if you're making IMO 4 uh with
IPO it can be applied topically a lot of
uh pests have a ground dwelling phase or
at least a phase where they interact
with the soil so just having um that
predatory fungi in your soil around your
plants is enough um to um actually
especially if you can if you look into
their life cycle and they have a ground
dwelling phase you might not need to
ever even apply ful early to have 100%
prevention in your substrate oh my God I
I I'm going to guess that fungus gats
have got a carapace how awesome would it
be to have a resident of the soil be the
mold that loves to eat fungus s
larve this is this is accurate and you
can definitely have uh prevention from
IMO however um you can have thriving
soil in your indoor living soil bed and
overwater the top of it um and still
produce fungus Nets I I know that is
possible so beware of um surface
overwatering um because um you can still
achieve fungus nuts if you try hard
enough even with great
soil if you try hard enough you can
bring fungus Nets anywhere
man I got them in my
kitchen so um so the you know I was
trying to think of of any downsides to
IPO because it sounds awesome I want I
already wanted IMO everywhere in my life
and in the nature and everything and IPO
sounds great to have everywhere in my
garden and then it occurred to me that
um I am a beneficial insects user and um
you know we're natural farmers and and
none of us really want to be using
chemical pesticides even if they're air
quotes natural pesticides um we want to
encourage nature and so I encourage
Nature by adding the pests that eat my
pest adding the insects that eat my
pests but um it sounds like if I'm going
to use IPO it's really a one or the
other because if the
IPO kills my target mites it's also
going to kill my beneficial mites yeah
yeah it's um this is possible and uh the
cool the good news is if you're making
IPM well and it is killing your
beneficial mites um you won't have any
mites um you can you can have a great
protocol with total kill um so that's
the good news um another bit of good
news is a lot of these bigger creatures
um or some of these bigger creatures
have um like bees for example if you
take IPO and you direct apply it on a
flying bee or a bee on a on a um on a
flower you can kill that bee but if you
apply it um all over your flowers and
the bees come uh the next day they will
have it'll have no effect on them uh we
have um 140 hives here uh on the farm
and uh with I pmo applications around
their hives to prevent um Ro uh hive
beetle um there has been only positive
effect on our bees our our hives Thrive
our beekeeper loves our hives because he
comes and he um splits them or takes a
bunch of bees out of them for his other
hives other places that are struggling
um because we're always over producing
bees but however because a bee is
capable of cleaning itself right so
there are creatures that can clean
themselves and um Can can navigate uh in
really healthy soils but yeah you um and
we still have
a I don't know how or or exactly how it
works but we still have abundance of
insects um but I think that um that leaf
surface that place where our pests go to
eat um that soil um I I I I'm not
totally sure of how it all works um but
um yeah the the pests are no more and we
still have a thriving ecosystem so uh
I'm I'm P don't understand I'm going to
push even further on that and the answer
might also be that neither of us knows
the answer to this but but I'm going to
push anyway um you know that reminds me
of of you know very often especially
early in my cultivation you know we you
know I used whatever was being sold for
whatever aphids or something and you
know mostly I make my own um sauces now
but you know you you you get the sauce
and you you put it on and you know and
and it just kills everything on the
freaking plant right the good guys the
bad guys everybody which which creates
this environment where there is a um
there's a vacuum right there's no
there's no good guys or bad guys which
creates an opportunity
and I wonder if if we sprayed IPO on our
cannabis plants in veg and it kills all
of the insects good and bad that have
got a carapace is is are we creating a
weakness in our ecosystem that that
another type of nonc carapus insect
might or I guess it wouldn't be an
insect yet non nonc carapace pest might
be able to fill that
space um yeah I have not experienced uh
a downside here um so um we have there's
a a farm I helped um develop in Colorado
they're in their fourth year now they're
um uh leading the industry in in hash uh
quality um and um they have
um it's like 1,800 plants times 4 or
five no they have one B building that's
times four and one that's 1,00 plants so
five and um they have a protocol of just
uh um uh liquid IMO on the regular um
and uh they have a thriving like their
soil life um has abundance of insects um
and uh they don't have pests um I don't
know why um that is the case that theirs
can still be um and it may be plant
Health it may be oh here's something
fun
um the presence of the um the protein of
insects being processed with fungi um
that
um that IPO uh having those those
proteins in it actually triggers an
immunal response in our plants too
making them aware that they may
encounter an outbreak of their pests oh
my gosh it increases their immune
system whoa yeah so um and if you do if
you go really heavy with that you can
actually um you can actually trigger a
um extreme fruiting response or
flowering in a flowering plant where
you'll get an increase in um flour and
frutin just by um introducing them to
the proteins and their pests um and fol
early and that can um cause them to be
hey I'm going to die soon there's go
hard there's this outbreak of pest I
need to perpetuate my species by
fruiting um uh in abundance and they'll
double down on um their um yeah their
fruit production so I've seen real
extreme flowering um in my Macadam nuts
and also studied this
um um phenomenon uh because of it um and
seen it in other crops so it's it's
really uh kind of fun that there's um
more than one dimension to all of this
and those beyond our understanding so
far as well so at what point in the
process would you um uh choose to spray
the IP pmo and when do you stop so I'm
looking for when start when stop and how
often um so if your
yeah if your pest is um has a ground
dwelling phase um you're pretty safe to
just apply a solid state IPO which is a
little more expensive per application
but you don't need to apply it very
often um your plant Health's going to go
up their immune response is going to go
up um if you're um dealing with or
seeing the possibility of that
foler um um pest um maybe doesn't have a
ground ground dwelling phase then a week
application especially if it's already
showing up a weekly application is kind
of the SOP so you're applying weekly or
um by weekly if you want to go serious
go hard um if um if everything's
copasetic you know applying um every
other week or applying monthly um can be
a thing I would say that a IPO if you're
worried about killing beneficials could
be something that you do um uh as needed
or that you do uh monthly um whereas an
IMO a liquid IMO maybe where you don't
have that in um is something I wouldn't
worry about at all meaning you could
apply it every week you're going to get
the nutritive response so there's um a
nutrient quality in IMO or liquid IMO
there's a bunch of food in the water um
so you're feeding them you're giving
them their probiotics you're preventing
disease um by coding their tissue in
beneficial life which out competes or
takes up the territory preventing the
vacuum um nature doesn't tolerate a
vacuum so preventing the vacuum um which
would allow another um something like um
powdery mildew by applying IMO you have
this protected Leaf um I have not
in my opinion as a farmer that has to
pay for things and my bottom line
matters if I can make this you know
extremely
inexpensive liquid
application um pest prevention and um
plant Health uh
spray um and I get to
not pay $800 a box box for my monthly
Rove Beetle or whatever then I'm stoked
yeah that's that's kind of where I've
come to but um I also have experienced
that the living soil guys both indoor
and outdoor are still have thriving uh
bug ecosystems the pill bugs are still
going you know um well maybe not as much
the pill bugs some of those get eaten
too um but you're you're you're still
you're still seeing Abundant Life um and
uh the
um the indoor um soil in that Colorado
Farm um when I did some um uh soil
analysis uh last time I was there is the
most diverse soil samples I have ever
looked at under a microscope and I've
been looking under a microscope at soil
and and media um since
2010 and um in a lot of different places
and different places in the world
different types of crops and uh just
stuff we put together with compost and
Imo applications is the most diverse
material I've ever seen and
um it's because of diverse collections
we had every time we did IMO there was
20 plus uh different IM o2s that went
into the the batches and and really it's
self-perpetuated and and stayed living
so um yeah I mean I I uh yeah I don't
know I don't know the the bottom line is
I don't know the answer to what your
beneficial uh life is going to look like
and and uh how to find that balance but
I'm down to pursue it with the community
have ideas and yet you've been doing
this for going on a decade and you still
have plenty of life in your living soil
so it's like you might not know why why
it's happening but you know that it is
happening you're you're you're you're
not like nuking any of these pots you're
actually encouraging life in these pots
just not with
carapace um insects insects yeah yeah
and and we're we're not we're also
getting um you know we're not we're not
seeing aphids or or things that aren't
carabis mhm uh do you do you agree that
the the time or I'm just guessing since
I haven't done this but is the time to
stop week four of flower like like most
uh
folur for me um I think if you are not
doing um microbial
testing um microbial testing um you know
uh prevents us from weird stuff that uh
builds up um the dust in a dirty
environment causing um uh a funk to
happen um or due to humidity um proper
um decomposition molds happening in
flour um that can make us sick um fresh
applied liquid IMO a balanced um uh
microbial Community with lab doing the
cleanup and all this stuff that um it
just means means there will be uh Colony
forming units it doesn't mean um that
they're going to make us sick so um the
um the right before Harvest or or a
couple weeks before Harvest um is um as
far as like not having a bunch of stuff
that could affect your flavor or
anything um would be what I'd say you
don't want to apply it and then harvest
the next day because without the plant
being alive it's not working with
microbes and you know doing symbiosis
with them now the microbes are just
there without the exodites of the plant
coming out their uh Leaf tissue in the
mornings Etc you don't have a thriving
ecosystem so you don't want to take a
hanging plant and spray a bunch of
liquid IMO on it because now you're
you're pursuing composting of that plant
not symbiosis does that make sense yeah
yeah I
follow and so the the answer is is kind
of like the same way it is with
everything we spray is that when your
flowers get thick enough where you're
actually just making them wet and you
could be causing molds and other things
stop so you know as soon as as soon as
the flowers are going to grab on to
whatever you spray on it and and and
tuck it away inside its folds it's it's
the time to stop spraying well I I might
I might disagree with that it with that
uh I I I appreciate that you're bringing
in a concise answer for the listener but
I I maybe want to leave it a little more
vague because if you have good material
meaning like um a a actual healthy
liquid IMO or good lactic acid bacteria
in going in and you're watering um
that's going to actually um often act as
a cleaning agent uh uh Tiding and making
fresh you know stuff that is healthy
alive like our bigger organisms they
make fresh they keep the funk away if
you will they are the prevention to the
bad mold um and so as long as you're
doing it well you're not cutting Corners
you are in fact uh producing a material
um then it's really not going to hurt a
living plant um it's going to um enliven
and help um and I have my best friend um
uh he's no longer farming cannabis but
he did for 15 years and uh he he sprayed
right up to a couple weeks before
Harvest um on his outdoor um Four Four
Seasons or four years um and had just
amazing amazing results and the Colorado
Farm has to cut off going into flower
because Colorado is so intense with
Colony forming units that basically
they're saying you have to be producing
cannabis in a sterile manner meaning you
have to be killing all things or you
won't pass our rags and so for them yeah
cut off definitely find a way to pass
those Rags um for the outdoor Washington
farmer he he's stoked that his plants
are disease free and bug free because he
he's got a a functioning protocol and he
never had mold so yeah it's it's um it
kind of depends on your environment and
uh and really what is the material
you're producing if you're cutting
corners and you're making witches brew
and calling it Chris's liquid IMO then
yes I would say absolutely do not spray
that at all in flour and one other thing
sh go this is
important are you producing a are you
trying to feed your plants with a foler
spray or are you trying to produce
microbes with a foler spray mhm so if
you're putting a bunch of food in your
um to make tea and you're trying to
break down that food so it's planned
available that is now compostable
material unprocessed nitrogen
unprocessed nutrients and those getting
into the crevices of your flowers now
need to compost or be further broken
down that will can purify on your plant
and and so if you're so this is my big
clarification is it a food tea or is it
a microb tea if you're doing a really
great job and it's really lightweight
meaning you're not putting a bunch of
foods in it it's just for producing
microbes that's there's no buildup but
if you're putting a bunch of like food
stuff like you're adding these things
that people say are a good idea now that
goes on it's not fully processed it's
going to process on your plant material
and it's going to rot MH
wow I can't believe that that I've I
have interviewed so many people about
spraying nutrition foliarly and this has
never come up that this this this
nitrogen residue on the plant is going
to eventually compost on your plant and
and create a um funky ass
environment
huh all right well uh might as well go
to commercial I'm not going to be able
to top that one so uh let's uh let's
continue this conversation when we come
back uh you are listening to shaping
fire and my guest today is natural
farming innovator Chris
Trump one of the challenges with buying
Autoflower seeds is that often you'll
have as many different fenos as you will
have seeds in a pack that can be fun
sure but so many varieties in one pack
is a sign of an immature seedline that
hasn't been worked enough I prefer my
autof flowers to be worked enough that
each pheno in the pack really captures
the aspects that the breeder was
intending this is why I recommend gnome
automatics to my friends and listeners
who grow automatic flowering cannabis
seeds gnome automatic seeds are not just
crossed and released they are
painstakingly sifted again and again
tested in a wide range of conditions and
taken to a level of maturity that each
plant will be recognizable by its traits
traits that were hard-earned so that you
can have your best grow cycle ever over
the last 10 years gnome automatics
founder Dan Jimmy has become a trusted
breeder and he continues to pour His
passion of breeding cannabis into every
variety he releases for you to grow
check out the gnome automatics Instagram
_ automatics to see the impressive
plants folks are growing you can score
gnome automatic seeds in feminized or
regular at your favorite seed provider
listed in the vendor section of their
website commercial cannabis Farms across
the country love growing gnome
automatics because of their consistency
from seed to seed short grow times THC
percentages and colorful bag appeal
Farms interested in bulk seeds of more
than a thousand should reach out through
gnome automatics.com
while on the website be sure to check
out the gnome automatic shirts and other
merch section too if you want reliable
seeds handbuilt from effort expert
selection and experience choose gnome
automatics after you've caught up on the
latest shaping fire episodes do you
sometimes wish there was more cannabis
education available to learn well we got
you shaping fire has a fabulous YouTube
channel with content not found on the
podcast when I attend conventions to
speak or moderate panels I always record
them and bring the content home for you
to watch the Shango Los YouTube channel
has world-class speakers including Zoey
sigman's lecture understanding your
endoc canabo system Kevin jodry of
Wonderland Nursery talking about
breeding cannabis for the best turpine
profile Frenchy canoli's Lost Art of the
hashian presentation Nicholas mmud on
regenerative and polyculture cannabis
growing Dr seil Agarwal on the history
of cannabis medicine Around the World
Eric vlosi and Josh Rutherford on
solventless extraction and Jeff
lowenfels on the soil food web there are
several presentations from Dr Ethan
Russo on Tarpin and the endocan avonoid
system too while there be sure to check
out the three 10-part shaping fire
session series one with Kevin jodry one
with Dr Ethan Russo and one with Jeff
lenells and even my own presentations on
how to approach finding your dream job
in cannabis and why we choose cannabis
business even though the risks are so
high as of today there's over 200 videos
that you can check out for free so go to
youtube.com / Shango or click on the
link in the
newsletter sometimes the topics I want
to share with you are far too brief for
an entire shaping Fire episode in those
instances I post them to Instagram I
invite you to follow my two Instagram
profiles and participate online the
shaping fire Instagram has follow-up
posts to shaping fire episodes growing
and processing best practices product
trials and of course gorgeous flower
photos the Shango Los Instagram follows
my travels on cannabis garden tours my
successes and failures in my own garden
insights and best practices from
personal grows everywhere and always
gorgeous flower photos on both profiles
the emphasis is on sharing what I've
learned in a way that you can replicate
it in your own garden your own hash laab
or for your own canopic health so I
encourage you to follow @ shaping fire
and Shango and join our online community
on
Instagram welcome back you are listening
to sh iing fire I am your host Shango
Los and my guest today is natural
farming innovator Chris Trump so Chris
during the break I was thinking and you
know um I got me wondering if if we're
going to spray the IPO on our cannabis
plants and um the the the the Allied
fungus that we're working with is on the
plant and um and then it it it kills
these pests whatever ever they are and
they turn into little fungal puff balls
like they did in the IMO that we were
talking about is this going to leave
like little puffy Carr Paces all over
our
plants um I mean if you have a major
outbreak of a pest and it is all over
your plants um in some way you're going
to need to um get that off and so
hopefully you have enough time maybe
you're doing fuler watering
but um yeah I mean insect buildup in a
sticky flower is a um Bad scene man it's
a bad scene yeah I mean even even
overuse of um ladybugs is a major
problem for people as far as buildup
goes or as far
as um insect residue and and can cause
real problems so overuse of uh even
beneficials but um no the
excuse me the
um the puff ball uh is going to be a
really short-lived Bloom and then that
will fall apart and um and as far and
and the insect itself um if it has been
predated uh By A fungi um the insect
will fall apart much easier or or uh
dissolve um more likely to happen if it
has um encountered a fungi that that
attacks it so uh you're probably in a
better scenario um if they've been
killed first of all than if they're all
there um and it's going to be easier for
um uh some degree of you know uh shaking
off or or fol or wash right on it sounds
to me like there's like there's like
three layers of of use it's like number
one IPO is going to be far best used as
a preventative because then you don't
have to deal with all of the adult pests
uh fuzz balled and having to you know
clean up the evidence right so do
everything as a preventative is going to
be better and then our secondary is that
uh oh i' I've got an outbreak I'm
experiencing pest
pressure and then you you know you're
using it as a full
and and maybe even as a soil drench if
they've got a uh soil period of life and
you know hopefully they will you know
fall fall off the plant I hope it's in
veg for you or or maybe you're picking
them off by hand something like that and
but at least they're dead right um but
then your third version is you've got an
outbreak right you got spidermites that
are building tents on your plants and
that's just about being a big kid and
realizing that plant's got to be removed
right and so really you're you're trying
to save the rest of the crop by getting
rid of these um uh pests so that they
don't spread and or put down like
serious anchor roots in your cultivation
location so so you know is this spray a
Panacea um uh it is in if you if if youd
use as a preventative but if you're
using it after you know your pest has
already taken over your plants the plant
well may be done so so you know be
mature about what you expect the the IPO
to do versus how colonized your plants
are with the
Enemy yeah and and the IPO like process
takes time so if you're in like freak
out you know takeover you're you're
probably not going to want to spend a
couple weeks uh 3 weeks you know getting
all set up to be spraying I IPO if you
haven't started yet um not to mention
learning curve if you've never done it
before so this let alone if you haven't
made it yet yeah exactly yeah so this is
this is definitely something as uh you
know uh integrated Pest management
system you know uh you know you're
you're these are these are things you're
thinking about ahead of time what is my
IPM for this coming crop year you know
um that is uh um the the right way to go
about this also so yeah it does it does
work to kill things and uh don't isn't
isn't that what's all in in those Vape
carts Shango they sell the dispensary
yeah man they're all they're all they're
all filled with like spiderm and you
know dear Lord there's a place for that
come on there someone will buy
it dear Lord um that's a good point
though you said you know you you might
not be able to get a solution as fast as
you want um how What what is the
the protocol cycle if you will um if you
are using IPO for an outbreak clearly
the preventative starts at the beginning
but but if if you're coming to this
because you've got an outbreak how like
let's assume that I already have the IPO
already made and let's say that I'm
starting to uh do light foler today how
long should I expect it to take for the
fungus to take up um colony and to start
uh munching on all my
pests um yeah if you have a a total
outbreak um and irr um regardless of
what your pest is um a and this you do
in fact have um a actual IPM Mo then um
you can apply it uh every four days for
in three applications would be like a
full cycle kill you know so if you have
different there's different life cycles
on different pests but uh hitting pretty
much the across the board pests um if
you apply it every 4
days
um sorry that's not right once a day for
four days um would be uh every pest
would be hit in their adult or or in um
and then um and then you can take a
break um of 3 days
and do it again um so uh eight
applications over a period of 11 days um
would be like I H I'm really worried I
have it on my shelf I wasn't using it we
have the beginning of an outbreak we
want to make sure we get everything um
apply it every day for 4 days and then
uh give it a a three-day rest and then
do it again so that would be kind of
your whole Gam bit of pests um killed
all right um do you see any benefit in
doing like a dip um maybe or or or a
heavy foler for incoming
clones um no I I say so the the again
back to sop for natural farming using
liquid IMO provided you're making it
well is once a week so once a week
through veg um a lot of natural farmers
are um adding um the their the veg
formula would be adding in that FAA fish
amino acid or that real um Rich um
highly plant available nitrogen that
doesn't need to compost on your Leaf so
that that uh that nitrogen we talked a
little bit last segment about how these
like unprocessed nutrients have to go
through a processing phase even like
fish hydrolysate or or fish Emulsion
it's been Blended it's been chopped up
really fine but there's still a
uncomposted fish particle that will now
land on your leaf and need to process
there um and uh whereas FAA went through
the belly uh metaphorically of or or
literally of a microbe completely
processed and now is the processed
version of that same nutrient the amino
acid kind of form and that really
doesn't have any more processing it can
be taken up or pass through that um uh
tissue into the plant as
is um and so that that you do in veg so
a regular you know weekly application of
liquid IMO would be great and then maybe
every other week or every week you're
putting in the nitrogen um you don't
Brew with nitrogen in the liquid IMO
though so um also
um it may be that we're not getting a
ton of replication of IPO in the water
column so um sorry I'm rabbit trailing
Shango should we stop and clarify sure
actually I'm gonna I think that we have
made that point really well and I'm
going to ask you the follow-up question
which is um do you see any reason why we
can't Target more than one variety of
pest in um the IMO so is it possible
that we're collecting the IMO and okay
we're going to put um uh you know pest
one in there but I also have a problem
with pest two in my area and so I'm
going to put that pest on my rice as
well and so I'm going to have a a double
duty IPO or or you are you more of the
line of no no no one IPO per Pest and
then rotate them through uh great
clarifying question I really appreciate
that so
um if you put one carest insect um in
with rice and it gets colonized or um
gets chewed on um that is your
broadspectrum
IPO complete meaning there is not
another now that doesn't mean that you
can't um do um potentially better by
having your Locust and your Beetle both
in your rice and you know maybe it's a
you know that one fungi really likes
that uh that Beetle flavored you know
soft drink um you know but really it's
it's not um a lot of these uh anop
pathogenic fungi um are um broadspectrum
if you will they they they go for kind
of um whatever has that protein and
every time it when it passes them or
they blow by on the wind and land on it
um that is going to go after whatever it
finds that has that protein has their
food source I see oh yeah go ahead so so
I get so you're saying all right so you
you know if you want to add multiple
pests to your rice like you you can't
you fine but really the the the picture
the context is bigger than that it's
it's not that oh I want to Target pest
one and and Target pest two because the
IPO isn't targeting the pest it's
targeting kiten which is what the carpes
is made of so as as far as the um our
partner fungus is concerned they're the
same pest because they both are carrying
its food around on its back yeah and if
it's a seed in early germination it's
the same food
source man I'd be really tempted to
actually
spray
germinating seeds or or or even just
like just after germination to spray
them with the IPO so that it replicates
as the plant grows
absolutely or or even better you put the
seed in soil that's been treated with
IPO thriving ecosystem dude totally
which is what Nature's doing right right
yeah cuz then the the soil is already
housing um our our partner fungus plus
all of like its helper you know you know
biology and yeah and it's well
established at that point so start so
start building I pmo into your soil oh
God that's a great addition to a soil
recipe right there boy mhm yes gosh um
all right so um I you've already hit on
this but I want to make it really clear
for for anybody who still has this
question um I pmo plays nicely with all
the other forms of Korean natural
farming correct yes great I just wanted
to make that nice and clear um so um
let's see here what have I what do I
still have that I have't here
um oh yeah um so so you know this show
is about cannabis right but but um but
but most of us who grow cannabis love
cultivating plants as well and and I am
definitely one of those people that
cannabis was a gateway to food farming
right you know for most of my life I've
just been growing this one plant that I
have this special relationship with but
you know as as as we saw you know access
to food get questionable there a few
years back um I've dove into food
farming and um uh this is something that
we can use on on all of our food crops
right is there is there any crop that
you have come across where this is not a
good
idea that's a pretty broad question
about I just asked you but yeah no um
again I I um I have worked a bunch in
the Cannabis industry
but um most of my work is not most of my
work is with food Farmers um and
um I cannot um I can't see a downside um
again we're not doing anything wild uh
in as far as nature goes right we're
we're just taking something that's
already there and um and making sure it
gets on our crop that we're growing
because sometimes when we are growing
wherever it is we're growing we've
tilled it and it actually used to be
lawn or um we actually bought it in bags
and brought it indoors you know there
hasn't been the establishment of life so
really we're
um we're uh Not Afraid uh I I will say I
will bring I I think uh if I can maybe
uh take Liberty with your question and
go a little more broad sure go ahead um
I will give a caution uh that I think is
really important and I appreciate the
trigger um or the the nudge we
um we are collecting microbes without um
specifying um our collection right we're
in in natural farming we're doing
a um
uh a broad uh a broad uh invite by
putting out this food and by getting it
from different places ideally we have a
bunch of different places we've got our
microbes from and then we're uh further
cultivating it and when we finish
imo3 um it dries out and is really
almost like a powder and if I look at it
under a microscope what that powder
consists of is a bad of marbles that's
packed with fungal spores so in an ideal
you did really great great job making
imo3 under a microscope now that it's
all dried we've used up all the water um
we have desiccated fungal bodies meaning
they ran out of water so they sporulated
they pushed their nucula into a fuing
head and made a bunch of spores they're
now sitting there waiting to be
reintroduced to water so they can wake
up but all those spores um
are great for the forest but they we
have made a concentrate just like if you
have a a new cannabis smoker and you're
uh you're about to introduce them to
your dab rig you say now this is uh
concentrated maybe more than nature
would normally give you on your first to
you know take it easy um we have a super
concentrate of fungi um and fungal Spore
specifically in an IMO 3 or an IMO 4
that's dried um or a liquid IMO and so
um there though it's safe I've drank my
liquid IMO now
uh throughout the year for uh 12
years um I've bathed in IMO and eatting
imo2 any chance I get um and uh and uh I
know many people that have um IMO is um
really just a if done well a replication
of a forest floor um that said sorry
long long leadup to um it can be um uh
overly um concentrated for an immunal
compromised person you know to breathe
in to inhale a massive amount of
microbes albeit beneficial microbes um
the the reality is that good microbes
can have a negative impact on a person
um in various you know Health too much
anything isn't great you know right so
so we have a concentrate so I just I
think a general caution that you are um
producing a massive quantity your your
the the goal with imo3 is that we're
really um we're
we're uh multiplying again and again to
um produce our our microbes I have a
friend um Poncho he's on one of my
videos on my YouTube uh I haven't talked
to him in a while which is definitely my
fault not his
um and um he can't be around imo3 or
four production that dust gets in the
air he's you know he's a longtime rocker
he was Crazy Horse Neil Young Crazy
Horse and for whatever reason that has
put him in a state where starts
breathing that he itches and has a a
like a autoimmune
response you know whereas I have no
negative uh effect and so I think just
in general though I'm not so worried
about a plant um I am concerned uh that
uh we just be beware for humans
especially um elderly I have encountered
um two or three people in my whole
journey that IMO makes them itch and and
they're all you know over 50 um over 60
um humans and and so um yeah just uh
that's the that's the big caution I
guess sorry for the long-winded
explanation but well at least we at
least we understand why and I think I'll
even throw this in there is that even
though people um drink their um their
preps um to kind of like prove a point
um you know it doesn't matter who you
are you should be wearing a mask when
fol oring this things because just
because you can drink it does not mean
that it plays well in your
lungs and so you know anytime doing
foler if it's not just water It is Well
advised to wear some sort of mask yeah I
I think uh I think it goes back to what
did you actually produce did it go well
and if I'm making it I feel safe you
know to to breathe it in but uh but yeah
if you're making it for the first time
or you tried something new or whatever
yeah it's just a general you know take
care of yourself um these are
concentrates right on all right so
here's our last question uh Chris so I
want to take I want to take you a step
back from all the specificity that we
have had today and and and think about
the student who is um considering I TMO
for the first time and has just listened
to all of the details that we have given
you know move moving from different
types of science to different kinds of
like processes to make it uh maybe
they've experimented with IMO maybe they
haven't but but maybe they're they're
probably feeling you know a little bit
overwhelmed with like I really want IPO
but holy F there there's a lot of
science here I have to remember and
there's a lot of steps and yet we want
to we want to support them because this
is this could really radically improve
their cultivation or their farm and so
here here's my question for you handing
you the the mic for a nice nice Dismount
what advice would you give to someone
just starting to make an experiment with
predatory IMO in the garden to to help
like I don't know soothe their
nervousness about the complexity of it
and to kind of like assure them that
that they can freaking do it
absolutely um so in eight days from
listening to this you can
foler a um a a liquid IPO and and have
it be 100% exactly as I would do it um
it's it's it's really doable and that
would be using your imo2 to make a
liquid IMO but you basically um get a
natural M uh material container you know
like a box and cook some rice um
actually I have a fun uh uh bomb to drop
uh Shango you inviting me to do um a uh
IPO
interview um inspired me to make a IPO
howto oh that's fabulous it does not
have all this science we talked about I
kep it super truncated and short um uh
so you know is that is that on your
YouTube channel it's going to be I
literally just uh finished the last
portion of it this morning before we
jumped on the call that's why I was
maybe going to be late I got stuck in
the woods but uh but no it's uh um yeah
going to be on my YouTube channel uh it
will be uh By the time they're listening
to this so yes it is there and um yeah
it'll it'll it'll take you through just
the practical but you don't have to
watch it to uh take the interview and uh
go right into it literally rice cooked
al
dente placed um just like an IM A1 and
um if that succeeds mixing it with brown
sugar taking a handful of that putting
it in a a sock or something with an
AirStone um because these are aerobic
organisms and Brewing it for 24 hours
and sprain it on and you will have uh
your IPO foler um it's that simple so
um and uh the
um the uh
downside is um is really not there um
you know as long as you uh go through
that process um you're going to be
putting wonderful nutrients again I'm
going to return to something we said in
in um uh earlier in the interview and I
just can't say enough do
not um add lib do not uh do not uh shoot
from the hip do not come up with your
own IPO recipe um and that's where
because that's the only way you could go
wrong if you just try and hone in on
what we're talking about and um how to
do it it's really excess ible and um
what I love about natural farming I I am
a I'm super nerd in um this stuff I love
to learn about it there's a lot to learn
about it
um you don't have to know all the
science to follow a
recipe um you don't have to understand
every detail and hold all of this in
your head and heart to have the benefit
for your plans you just have to be good
at doing step one through four
and literally just experience the
benefit or experience the outcome of um
yeah the uh what nature is already doing
um nature um I love that it is more
complex than uh we understand or than
our understanding and at the same time
you don't have to know a darn thing
about the complexity of nature to walk
up to an apple tree pick an apple and
eat it and say this is good it feeds me
so that's what we're doing here right on
Chris thank you so much I really
appreciate that that summation it's like
it's like you don't you don't need to
know everything in order to to to
participate in this you just need enough
to do the recipe very similarly like you
know I don't know how my everything
functions in my car but I can totally
Drive um and you know I can I can learn
how to fix different parts of my car as
I go so so Chris thank you so much you
know uh you you educate people all
around the world and you've been doing
this a long time now and you're
certainly an ally to the Cannabis
industry and um and just thank you for
for the time that you spend with those
of us in cannabis and then most
specifically thanks for spending your
very valuable time with us here today so
that we can learn more about IPO when I
when I stumbled across it three weeks
ago I was like holy crap I can't believe
Chris and I haven't talked about this
already and so uh thanks for freeing up
your schedule to be here with us thanks
a lot dude yeah absolutely Shango and uh
yeah thanks listeners for uh for the
time you put in if you got this far uh I
think you deserve a round of applause
yeah right on dude right on all right
dear listener so if you would like to uh
know more about uh Chris Trump and more
maybe even more importantly his videos
um I'm going to give you uh three places
for you to go the first is his website
for his business biom which is uh uh
www. biomay dos Solutions and and biomay
is B IO
Mei dos Solutions and if that sounds
weird to you like it's his his his URL
is different it's not a.com it's a Dos
Solutions right so it's
www. biomay dos Solutions and and your
browser will get you there so so on the
biomay website you can find out about
Chris you can can get access to all
sorts of resources you can get the free
classes you can find about upcoming free
and paid classes and there are resources
for how to make the various natural
fermentations that uh Chris has been
teaching about all these years plus
there are links to the YouTube videos so
so like big win there at at at www.
biomay dos Solutions now if if if you um
want something like you know on the
regular you can also follow his
Instagram at biomas Solutions and that's
uh B IO Mei dos Solutions is his um
profile there on IG and then and then if
you're interested in following Chris for
for you know Chris himself as a human as
he travels around the world and teaches
different farmers and and and you know
learns some of these new uh innovations
that he's coming up with like first
before they even become classes then you
want his personal Instagram which is
soil Steward s o i l s t w a r d soil
stward and um you can uh Follow Chris
you can comment Chris reads that stuff
and also there's an entire Community
there's like a you know 35,000 followers
or something on his on his Instagram and
it's a really nice place um to to learn
and also to to interact with other
people in our community um uh who have
who have got the best of intentions this
very well well behaved uh place so great
place to learn and that's @ soil stward
on Instagram you can find more episodes
of the shaping fire podcast And
subscribe to the show at shaping
fire.com and wherever you get your
podcasts if you enjoyed the show we'd
really appreciate it if you would leave
a positive review of the podcast
wherever you download your review will
help others find the show so they can
enjoy it too on the shaping fire website
you can also subscribe to the newsletter
for insights into the latest Cannabis
News exclusive videos and giveaways on
the shaping fire website you'll also
find transcripts of today's podcast as
well be sure to follow on Instagram for
all original content not found on the
podcast that's @ shaping fire and @
Shango on Instagram be sure to check out
shaping fire YouTube channel for
exclusive interviews farm tours and
cannabis lectures does your company want
to reach our national audience of
cannabis enthusiasts email hotspot
shaping fire.com to find out how thanks
for listening to shaping fire I've been
your host Shango
[Music]