[Music]
to folks on the outside who are not
familiar with cannabis the medicinal
qualities of the plant can appear
overblown in a pipe dream
quite literally and they are right that
most of us talk about cannabis as a
panacea
because it does offer relief from so
many bodily ailments
and those folks say how can one herb fix
so many things in a human
that simply cannot be true but the thing
is that cannabis really only does
one thing it balances and strengthens
and interacts with the body's
endocannabinoid system
balancing and activating that one system
is a very big deal though
because the endocannabinoid system
touches all the other mission critical
systems in the human body
at the same time though not all humans
react to cannabis in the same way
by now most cannabis users understand
how completely the terpene profile
controls the quality of euphoria
that cannabis gives us when smoked or
vaped and terpenes themselves influence
humans in differing ways
which is why some folks can smoke any
and all equatorial cultivars
while i have to be really picky with
mine or i get a racing heart that i find
dysphoric
we all have our very own personal and
individual relationship with cannabis
all this is to say that cannabis helps
the endocannabinoid system of all humans
but which cannabis cultivar used in
which way and at which dose are all
variable from human to human
it really makes me cringe to see
cannabis folks arguing on social media
about some patients dosing protocol
because to really understand how best to
administer cannabis to a patient
really takes a pretty in-depth patient
intake
or some advanced self-awareness and
self-diagnosing
folks are usually arguing as if dosing
is the same for everyone and it very
much isn't whole plant cannabis medicine
is a great tool and we need to recognize
how to use it is dictated to a large
degree by the physical health
nutrition expectations mental health
and experience with cannabis that the
patient has
every cannabis patient is different and
deserves to be treated uniquely
if you want to learn about cannabis
health business and technique
efficiently and with good cheer
i encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter we'll send you new
podcast episodes as they come out
delivered right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week
and videos too don't rely on social
media to let you know when a new episode
is published
sign up for the updates to make sure you
don't miss an episode
you are listening to shaping fire and
i'm your host shango los
my guest today is dr chris spooner dr
spooner is a naturopathic doctor with 20
years clinical experience
with specialties in gastrointestinal and
integrative medicine among others
he has been a board member and vice
chair of the college of naturopathic
physicians of british columbia since
2008.
dr spooner is presently on the medical
advisory boards
of several integrative care and cannabis
companies
even with all of that chris still keeps
an active private clinical practice at
paradigm integrative medicine helping
real people
every day today we're going to discuss
the wide range of variables at play in
the human body to consider
when making cannabis recommendations
during the first set
we talk about those body variables and
how unique each human is when it comes
to cannabis medicine
during the second set we review the
analytical tools and tests we can use
when performing a patient intake
or serious self-diagnosis and in the
third set
we talk about easy to access whole foods
that you can eat
to support a thriving endocannabinoid
system
welcome to the show chris hey shango
great to be here thanks
thank you so let's start by giving
everybody a really good idea of the
variables
at play when discussing the use of
cannabis medicine you know
humans are not at all the same even
though textbooks
about the human body and the discussion
of the endocannabinoid system
may suggest that they are so so let's
start would you
please give us a sense of the variety of
health
variables that could potentially impact
the use of cannabis medicine and should
be considered when choosing how best to
use cannabis
to relieve ailments
sure super interesting question you know
and this definitely
falls within kind of you know my my
integrative medicine
functional medicine naturopathic
medicine approach and
i don't uh you know this is an approach
that i use pretty much with all my
patients whether it be
cannabis medicine or not you know and
essentially
you know what we're really trying to do
is is recognize that you know you've got
individual patients and i think one of
the challenges that we have with
medicine
right now is that you know we're using
evidence-based medicine
we're trying to protocols and
standardization part of it
and and what we've forgotten is that
we're kind of creating medicine by
average
you know i was just having this
conversation with a patient yesterday i
was showing them some
a data set you know and some slides
saying okay well you know and there's
this nice graph
line down the middle of it you know but
you know when you take a look at the
number of points
data points that are actually on the the
best fit line there's only four
and the other 150 or above or below so
and that starts to become something
that's become a real sort of foundation
on how i work
you know with with patients on this
which is you know we need to recognize
and we've got to really dig
into these unique aspects of patience
you know and so
you know when i start off there's a
couple things that i take a look at
first and foremost and and you know sort
of a base of a pyramid and which ones
you know each one sort of successively
builds on the next and so
you know to me you know optimizing
nutrition is has got to be key in this
right you know and so
you know i think that well you know when
you start looking at the cannabinoids
and the endocannabinoids in particular
you know all of these things are are
basically you know built off fats
you know in our body and so you know our
you know the macronutrient part of it
you know the omega-3s omega-6 you know
saturated fat status
of our diets becomes really really
important you know because i think we
need to remember the endocannabinoid
system is a
homeostatic regulatory system
right which means that you know you can
only push it so far versus the other
it's actually a balancing thing so if
we're trying to create
a super intense therapeutic effect on it
i think we're going to cap that out
at both you know both ends of that along
the continuum of
you know one extreme versus the other so
we need to look at ways to build
capacity um within that and try to
unload it so that we allow the
endocannabinoid system to balance as
opposed to
push before before you move on um
you've all we're not even three minutes
into the show and you've already blown
my mind
did you did you just say that if our
nutrition is lacking the
the cannabinoid therapy will only be
able to do
so much because our body won't have the
capacity to properly use the cannabis
we're introducing
absolutely wow yeah all right please
continue
yeah well and that you know and so
that's you know you can carry that three
theme through a whole a whole the whole
range of things that i'm suggesting here
so i mean if we start off like i said
with optimizing the nutrition
you know and and again i mean you can
talk about things like fats and protein
status and amino acids and such
you know if we talk about micronutrients
you know i mean there's you know the
area that i do a lot of work with with
my patients is nutrigenomics
you know so we'll use like the the
23andme platforms one we tend to use the
most it's
it's you know some people have concerns
about that
um for a number of different reasons
mostly about where their health data and
things like that's going in but it
certainly is accessible and
and you know that's a whole other
conversation we could have but i mean
certainly within that you see
variability within patient populations
on you know again how they
build different parts of things that
intersect with the endocannabinoid
system and and
those are things that can be modulated
again macronutrient and micronutrients
so you know that's probably you know
again that's a fairly
deep dive into okay what's the diet that
you're looking at you know let's take a
look at some of the physical signs and
symptoms
you look at various different nutrient
deficiencies
you know and and that starts to become
part of the the conversation and basic
you know
history building you know that that's
i do um next thing you know we take a
look at is hormones and hormones build
off of your nutritional status as well
too and and
again you know what we're talking
estrogen progesterone testosterone
you know we can move into some of the
neurotransmitter part of that as well
too
you know what they're talking dopamine
you know serotonin
you know epinephrine norepinephrine
cortisol levels
all of those have huge interplays you
know with regards to
you know effects on metabolism and blood
glucose and so again you know you need
to have
you know if your carbohydrate metabolism
blood sugars off
you know is that you know an impact on
cortisol or a response to altered
cortisol status and adrenal function and
so
again you know that's your dietary
habits start to build in on that as well
too and so
that starts to become the next part of
that you know we also take a look and if
we look at the the nutrigenomics part of
this
you know things like um you know
catechol like dopamine for example is a
catechol i mean
you know and it's you know it's impacted
by
a whole host of a network of of
different
um you know estrogen metabolism
cortisol epinephrine norepinephrine and
those build on again various different
micronutrients like b vitamins and
methylation status on neurotransmitter
production
so suddenly now you're seeing this
intersection here and then you know how
those hormones and neurotransmitters are
cleared out of the system
uh particularly through something called
catechol o methyltransferase which is an
enzyme that's the warrior versus the
warrior phenotype if anybody's
been following that aspect of it and
that has in my experience
has significant implications for
endocannabinoid tone
and response you know and and
furthermore it probably explains to a
large extent
what's going on you know with for
example the gender differences that we
see you know how women versus males
respond differently and largely that has
a significant
you know interplay with um you know
estrogen metabolism
and impacts on dopamine so you know that
starts to become something that's super
super interesting
so there's that element of it you know
the next
phase that i started taking a look at is
is the gastrointestinal tract
i do tons of work i mean it's it's one
of the areas that i work up outside of
cannabis
medicine with several other companies
with which is on microbiome
and um you know so that suddenly ties in
hugely with our
you know endocannabinoid there's some
really interesting research
that takes a look at the endocannabinoid
system as kind of the intersection
between the gut microbiome
you know and and the gut brain access
and the implications of that on
endocannabinoid system functioning are
fascinating as well too you know so
this becomes something that again when
you base it on our nutrition i mean the
types of fibers that we start to make
like for example
if we wanted to dig down into this a
little bit more and again we can
obviously we've got some some wine times
to talk about this so you'll probably
find a
skitter round over places but you know
let's take a look at something like
gaba you know the endocannabinoid system
you know the cb1 receptors are
you know i mean they have significant
impacts on gaba and glutamate
you know those are the excitatory
inhibitory neurotransmitters
and one of the interesting things is if
we take a look at the gut microbiome
you know butyrate is a short chain fatty
acid
anybody who's ever smelled rancid butter
you know
that's you know that's butter or that's
butyrate
and um but it's produced by um
you know the microbiome in the large
intestine right you know
the bacteroides species of bacteria that
colonize the large intestine
and it gets it by fermenting different
types of fibers particularly things like
psyllium powder
and um an old bran are two big sources
of it as well too there's several others
as well but that's what i use
predominantly
and butyrate is actually the building
block for
gaba all right gamma aminobutyric acid
so butyrate butyric so suddenly now
you're taking a look at one of the
major you know sort of regulatory
neurotransmitters within the
endocannabinoid system
you know the significant component of it
is being
generated in our gastrointestinal tract
by our microbiome and the type of fiber
that we eat
so suddenly that you know has huge
implications on this as well too so that
becomes a really significant element and
you know i do seminars for um
for continuing medical education for
patients on on gut ecology and
gut microbiome and how that works and
intersects with
immune function and t cell polarization
and this type of thing as well too so
there's some
some really interesting intersections
and again you know when we start talking
about endocannabinoids
you only start thinking about
anti-inflammatory effects
logic effects you know how much of that
is this intersection with gut microbiome
and
and t cell polarization through you know
mucus associated in
uh lymphoid tissue and this type of
thing
so that's that's that part of it um
my past work was in environmental
medicine i spent a i did a post
doctorate down at uh
in phoenix at the southwest college of
naturopathic medicine we created a
environmental medicine center center of
excellence uh dr walter kranian who you
guys actually probably up in the
washington state area would know him he
was quite highly regarded for
environmental medicine had a
very large clinic up there and so i had
the opportunity to spend a lot of time
and learn from him so you know we got to
spend
you know things like working with the
phoenix fire department and setting up a
wellness center and working at sort of
you know getting heavy metals out of
guys that went to hurricane katrina and
you know 911 and stuff and trying to get
rid of you know various different toxins
and the implications on that but that
part became part of these detoxification
pathways and certainly in that work i
mean that's probably where i ended up
getting a lot of my
my interest in in genomics because we're
taking a look at
genetic variation in cytochrome p450
enzymes which are the enzymes that clear
out a large you know the significant
amount of what we call xenobiotics or
you know chemicals within the
environment how those things get out of
our system is
run through the liver which is this big
filter you know and and so
that has implications on drug metabolism
and how that clears out
you know and again when we took a look
at environmental pollutants
you know things like solvent exposures
and pesticides and heavy metals
you know what we looked at is that had
you know three sort of areas that they
affected neurological
immune function and endocrine and so you
know suddenly when we start taking a
look at the impacts of
you know environmental compounds and
these xenobiotics
you know and how that starts to impact
you know hepatic function and clearance
and you know
you know how genetic polymorphisms and
variations
start to impact that then suddenly again
you know i mean suddenly there's all
sorts of you know
connections and intersections happening
with the endocannabinoid system
you know and certainly you know i mean
you know ethan you know
dr russo and i were just doing that work
on
you know the genetics of uh cannabis
hyperemesis syndrome
you know and and what we were seeing in
there was you know some genetic variants
on some of these drug clearance pathways
you know which again intersects with
pharmacogenomics and potentially
you know this environmental medicine
type thing you know and certainly you
know one of the things that i look at in
the work that i've done with some of the
license producers up here in canada
you know as we've really tried to
emphasize hey look pesticides are a
problem
you know but even especially with hemp
for example i mean one of the things i
think that gets
you know missed a little bit is that
hemp is a bio accumulator of cadmium
right
you know and so now you're going to have
to start taking a look and paying
attention and those those heavy metals
need to be looked at and
especially when we're doing concentrates
you know is that starting to be
something and cadmium's a fairly
nasty metal that has some significant
implications particularly on estrogen
metabolism
so there's your detoxification pathways
right on so so for those who are
are keeping score at home um i'm seeing
uh four variables so far that you've
delineated
that you talk to your patients about as
you are
moving towards your diagnosis and
figuring out cannabis protocols number
one being
what is the state of their nutrition
because they have to have the capacity
to be able to
um to intake the the cannabinoids
uh two uh was hormones um
three was the the con the status of
their gi
tract and four would be environmental
influences that might be acting on the
endocannabinoid system
um before we go into those any more
depth is there is there more on that
list
that's it all right so so i a couple
things that i want to focus on
which just um glowed in your answers
but i didn't want to interrupt you so so
the first thing is is
um you mentioned with you know
some amount of of coarseness to it
that there are gender differences um
when it comes to using
cannabis and um there is just not a lot
being talked about on that would you go
into that a little bit
oh sure yeah um
let's see where do we start on this one
well how about um um how do the health
how do the health benefits of using
cannabinoid medicine
differ between men and women and others
yeah i there's a couple different areas
that i would look at this and i
i guess what i was trying to think is
there's is how do we put this into a
logical framework that makes sense
so i think where i'd probably start with
this
we we see different responses uh like
women in general have different
responses to dopamine and that's
that's a large factor because dopamine
and estrogen get
cleared out through this this calm tea
enzyme right and and so what tends to
happen is
is that the system can be overloaded
um you know it becomes you know has to
clear out i usually use the analogy of
we've got a
kitchen sink and what's what's the size
of the drain in the kitchen sink and
within that sink we're pouring in these
various different hormones and
neurotransmitters
and so obviously for women as estrogen
levels you know start to
to rise you know you're going to have a
more significant capacity
consumed by the clearance of those you
know that particular hormone
and so what are the implications on that
for other neurotransmitters and things
like dopamine for example
so that's i think that that by you know
it has some significant implications on
you know how women respond to it you
know
how they utilize it and dosing
strategies and that and it's it's not
i mean i couldn't say definitively i'd
have to spend time with each particular
patient to kind of identify
you know what's going on so for example
you know some women
um either through nutritional
deficiencies or genetic variants don't
clear out estrogen
as well you know they either have a
smaller drain or what have you and so
that has implications on mood which you
know i mean i don't think i'm speaking
out of turn here but anybody who's
in a relationship will have noticed that
sometimes you know moods
change a little bit throughout cycles
and
again that has a lot in my experience to
do with again you know how these
estrogen metabolites
are either accumulating because there's
multiple different you know
metabolites of estrogen based on the the
molecular structure what we call
two hydroxy four hydroxy and 16 hydroxy
alpha
estrogens and each one has a slightly
different effect and pathway
and so as those are kind of consuming up
different capacity of
calm tea then that starts to shift
around you know the the dopamine
metabolism and can lead to you know
again
mood anxiety you know headaches you know
pain cramping and this type of thing so
so i think that that's
you know just just from a standpoint of
of how you deal
you know with women's health and
gynecological health
you know that's you know those estrogen
metabolites in that pathway so when we
start taking a look at the
endocannabinoid system well
we see intersection there through you
know serotonin pathways and dopamine
pathways in particular
and then furthermore you know things
like you know the menstrual cycle is
regulated through prostaglandins and
prostaglandins are again you know
built out of the types of fats that we
have are omega-3 six and nine saturated
fats arachidonic acid and this type of
thing
and those prostaglandins have a singing
a significant impact on the lining of
the uterus of the endometrium
and again so you know they help you know
shut off and open the small blood
blood vessels that are involved in
menses and so
you know again one of the things that we
work a lot with women is taking a look
at your essential fatty acid status and
so
you know i think the logical extension
of that is well let's take a look at
what happens with the endocannabinoid
system and certainly you know we see
that you know
you know various different
endocannabinoids like pea and
and this type of thing have an impact on
on uterine proliferation endometriosis
ovarian cysts and such
so so i think that's you know probably
uh
yeah yeah that's a good snapshot and you
know listening to you describe this
you know on on one hand um the detail in
your answer is remarkable because
i swear i talk to cannabis researchers
all the time
and i do not get this level of detailed
answer
from most anybody which you know is
impressive but then also at the same
time as somebody who works with patients
you know daily um it also
is kind of frustrating because i'm like
oh my god
you know this is the more the more
sentences you say chris the more complex
the the diagnosis seems to become
about what cannabinoids we're going to
use
to offer relief and strengthening to
which
part of the human so they can even use
the other cannabinoids
with the ailment that we're actually
targeting
it's like there's so many there's so
many layers and it makes sense right i
mean so many people
pooh-pooh the idea of how much good
cannabis does you're like oh people
think it solves
everything well it's like you know right
it doesn't solve everything
it solves one thing the endocannabinoid
system and the thing is is that's
the body's um thermostat and so
it touches all of the mission critical
systems in the body so yeah
cannabis does really well with this one
system but it's the master regulator so
in a way
yeah it actually does help everything
and while that makes it
such a beneficial herb at the same time
as a caregiver who's listening to this
show
i can imagine it can feel kind of
i don't know defeating in a way where
who's got the amount of information
about their about their patient
and the time to talk with them about all
this and and we're going to talk more in
the second set
about the analytics you use but but just
speaking to the bigger idea of
the complexity of this really suggests
to me that we have
just scratched the surface of
endocannabinoid medicine
yeah and i i i think this is the
i mean this speaks to such a larger
issue you know which is
is what is health care and what is
disease care
right you know and and like i said i
mean i'm integrative you know i mean a
lot of my
my naturopathic doctor friends streak
and [__]
you know when i prescribe stuff and and
things like that
a lot of my medical doctor friends
shriek and horror when i start talking
about you know
holistic approaches and things like that
um so i i look at myself as a bridge
you know i try very much to be very
grounded in science
you know um but i also recognize that
you know i mean
there's a role you have to use the right
tool
you know you have to but you have to
also have enough information in our
healthcare system at this time
you know struggles and especially up
here in canada i've talked with many
many of my
medical doctor friends you know and we
have you know we have medicine where
doctors are you know paid by the
government and things like that but you
know
to a large extent and again i practice
in the u.s you know medicine
is is determined you know on this sort
of fee-for-service model right which
means that okay well if you see more
patients you make more revenue out of
this
and so you know and and the efforts
around evidence-based medicine and to do
these things are to try and create a
a structured framework to do that which
is again it's really helpful when
you know you're in an emergency room and
you're crashing and you're having a
heart attack or
you've been in a motor vehicle accident
or you've crashed or something like that
as well too i mean these are things
where
you know are super important to have
these things that can be acted on
quickly and rapidly and be very very
effective
but the model starts to break down as we
get more and more into these individual
you know into individual care and and i
think you know what i i
struggle with and what i i try and you
know my one
small voice in the wilderness here is to
say like hey everybody
it can't just be about cannabis it
actually needs to be about the patient
and and like i said cannabis is an
incredible tool it's it's very helpline
and as we you know we've talked in our
previous conversations
is that you know i kind of come from
that as saying like you know
cannabis is remarkably easy to to do
something with because it actually works
you can see it happening i mean
try dealing with you know the sort of
poking and prodding of some of the other
herbal medicines
and and so that becomes you know uh it's
more difficult it's
more nuanced on this as well too so
you know but what i struggle with here a
little bit is that i see
cannabis kind of being moved into sort
of like well thc and cbd
what's the dose what's the prescribing
and all there is that we move into what
i call sort of you know and i'm not the
only one i certainly didn't coin this
term but
green allopathy which is well let's just
find a green alternative for the
medication
so we'll use willow bark or curcumin for
aspirin there's an anti-inflammatory or
will
you choose whatever one sort of goes
there and again you know i think you
know trying to bring this
patient-centered focus back into it and
i think that's you know that's what sort
of drew me to
the you know endocannabinoids and
cannabis system was we started
to see patients responding quickly
and and you know being able to work
fairly
on their own to be able to sort of
manage their own health care through
accessing cannabis and now it's sort of
like you know
my job that i kind of look at is well
let's bring in some of these other stuff
that's been
you know i mean you know what i'm
talking about here isn't new within sort
of the integrative medicine naturopathic
community it's just nobody's ever
overrelated on the endocannabinoid
system
in this particular way and and so you
know it's just like i said my role as a
bridge is to try and sort of bring that
up but again you know i mean for
patients that have itself i think most
people have a good sense of
you know how do i optimize nutrition i
think if we sat down and said okay
what's a healthy diet
look like you know most people could
tell us and so i would say like well
just recognize how important that is and
not and not only just in using that in
cannabis but again also trying to make
your cannabis work better for you
you know and and you know again are we
do we as as clinicians and people do we
want to keep someone on a medication
forever whether it be cannabis
or a pharmaceutical or a herbal medicine
or do we want to try and build
the capacity where patients can take
control of their health
things okay i'm out there exercising i'm
getting blood pumping i'm
you know doing my exercise routine i'm
eating healthy i've got my diet cleared
up as well too
and does that start to say i use my
cannabis to kind of help me get to a
certain space and now i can use
it either less frequently or at certain
situations because i have the resiliency
because i built on these other aspects
so so another thing that you mentioned
that i
found very engaging is this phrase that
i'm going to start using all the time
of medicine by average and
you know i know that there are doctors
and caregivers who are listening who run
into this every day
because you know first off just because
we work with cannabis
at least up until normalization has
begun
the vast majority of patients that we
come in contact with
they are already not the average they
are the fringe because
by the time that people get to cannabis
medicine they've usually already tried
everything else right
the idea of like you know everybody's
parents and grandparents now using you
know topicals and
and you know edibles for their aches and
pains this is really something that has
just come into acceptance again
you know more recently as there are more
recreational stores around but
but you know in the in the transition
years that we're in and certainly in the
heritage market
by the time people got to cannabis
western medicine had already given up on
them
and so so by its very you know
nature of the prohibition years everyone
we got was generally
not average they were on the fringe
because regular medicine didn't work for
them
so then we've got that set of patients
but then also we've got all these new
patients which
uh you know since since cannabis
medicine can help just about everybody
um you know there's there's all these
people who are served by western
medicine who are now
also being served by cannabinopathic
care
and um i find it both
you know informative and troubling
that the medicine by
average really is to the advantage
of the the
health industry and the and the
patient care industry and not the
the health care industry is you made
that delineation earlier about
about medicine for health versus
medicine to keep you alive to sell you
more medicine right
and um this idea of medicine by average
is so frustrating to so many caregivers
i'm not expecting you to have an
answer for it because it's it's it's a
it's a difficult paradoxical thing
but but what kind of advice would you
give to caregivers
who are dealing with this trying to
provide
individualized medicine in a system that
does
medicine by average
yeah i mean and again you know i'm so
steeped in it i had
you know again i had this conversation
with a patient the other day and
and they're like oh my god this is so
frustrating and it's like
well this is just the ocean that we kind
of swim in as naturopathic physicians
it's something that you know
is why people come and seek us out um
i i think that this is the amazing about
you know podcasts like this in the world
that we live in now is that people
are starting to you know learn more and
i mean just just
like i think about my own experience and
figuring out cannabis and
you know the the people that i've worked
with and just the giants that i've
i've had the opportunity to to learn
from right you know but my
my own learning was accelerated that way
but i think at the end of the day you
know being
you know your own advocate um and
starting to sort of say like hey wait a
second
you know i have some questions about
this and about that
you know that that's that's key i mean
that's the most important part of it you
know and
i think the hardest part is yeah how do
you find a clinician that works
you know that's saying like well that's
really interesting and i don't i
certainly can't answer you i mean i'm
always surprised that
some of the doctors that are super open
to this and
some of that aren't you know i mean i
just had a super interesting
conversation with a rheumatologist down
there your way in seattle
uh doing really cool stuff with a heart
rate variability and and autoimmune
illnesses and
we were coming at this from two
different ways but the intersection was
remarkable and i'm like okay
i've met some rheumatologists and can be
pretty conservative right you know and
so suddenly you know to have them
move outside of this is really exciting
so i
you know again i i couldn't tell you how
but i think certainly i think
i think most doctors are seeking you
know that relationship i think the
the um the epidemic of physician
burnout that we have has a lot to do
with the loss of sort of the
doctor-patient relationship
you know doctors are seeing that as much
as anyone else and so you know i mean
you you have to you're gonna have to
sort through a bunch of different
physicians perhaps until you find one
that
that has that and and i but i do
sympathize with a lot of those doctors
and certainly
you know the ones that i know socially
versus i know professionally sometimes
there's a bit of a
uh incongruity between the people i know
them to be and how they're working in
their space and
they're all humans and so i try and
approach that with some compassion and
and and and sympathy of how they're
doing and
and go from there so again i don't i
don't know if i necessarily have an
answer on them say to be the advocate
you understand your patient your doctor
is
is probably struggling in a lot of
different ways around that and
and reach out and try and engage in
conversation and you'll find some that
do and some that don't which is
you know maybe horribly naive but that's
what i'll put out there right on thank
you chris
so um we're going to take a short break
and be right back
and make sure you do come back because
after the break
we are going to be talking about some of
the analytics
that are available to take a good
snapshot of your body or your patient's
body
so that you can start to thread the
needle of individualized cannabis
medicine
you are listening to shaping fire and my
guest today is naturopathic physician
chris spooner
as cannabis regulations become more
demanding and consumers become more
educated it is increasingly important to
avoid the use of chemical pesticides
when cultivating cannabis
beneficial insects have been used for
decades by the greenhouse vegetable and
ornamental plant industry
and today many cannabis cultivators are
moving from sprays and chemicals
to beneficial insects covert biological
systems has the beneficial insects
mites and nematodes microbials sticky
cards and air distribution units
you need to partner with nature to
defend your garden
whether you manage acres of canopy or
have a simple grow tent in your home
cobrad is ready to help answer your
questions and help you transition away
from chemical sprays towards clean and
natural solutions
since 1967 cobra has assisted growers in
identifying pests
and devising reliable solutions while
providing healthy insects and mites that
will protect your yield
since the 1990s cobot has been a leader
in cannabis pest and disease control
worldwide
and have highly trained consultants to
assist you in canada and the u.s
from coast to coast no matter where you
live
covert biological systems can help visit
cobert.com
choose your country and get detailed
information
that's cobert
dot k-o-p-p-e-r-t.com for the most
up-to-date cannabis related biological
control information
you can also check out their instagram
at covert canada
you know getting away from pesticides is
good for health and good for business
and culprit is ready to help visit
cobert.com today
if you're an autoflowering cannabis
enthusiast this event's for you
announcing the 2021 autoflower cup
august 6th 7th and 8th in a little of
washington
just outside of seattle presented by
camp ruderalis
this gathering has something for
everyone there's the autoflower cup
competition of course
but it's so much more than that there'll
be a stunned-in glass hookah lounge
a pop-up magical butter chocolate shop
and waterfront marketplace with an array
of vendors
there will be an old school autoflower
seed swap joint rolling competition
cannabis cooking demos solventless
squishing demos
and late night documentary screenings of
both dosed
and fantastic fungi the food will be lit
too including chef sebastian carosi's
award-winning classics like elk chili
kobe beef kimchi dogs oyster po boys and
razor clam chowder
enjoy the campfire chili and oyster
chowder cook-off
wild oyster harvesting mushroom foraging
and s'mores around the campfires each
night
each day there dan jimmy of mandalorian
will teach about autoflowers
and there will be presentations on
closet cultivation and hunting for
psilocybin mushrooms
the competition is open to everyone
commercial and home growers
there is a category for photoperiod
plants too so check out
the autoflower cup 2021.com for those
details
clearly there will be plenty of cannabis
around but due to state law it won't be
supplied by the event
but there will be easy public talking
which is why this is a strictly over 21
event
you can camp rent a cabin or stay at a
local airbnb
glamping and rv packages are available
too
i'm happy to say that shaping fire is a
sponsor of the event and i'll be there
too
i look forward to connecting with other
autoflower fans like me
so get all the details at the autoflower
cup
2021.com and follow the instagram at
the autoflower cup 2021 and i'll see you
in august at autoflower cup when we
bring the autoflower family together to
celebrate
while i love growing under the sun
there's a lot of good reasons to grow
indoors and if you're like most folks
you want a lighting source that grows
high yielding healthy plants without
using excessive amounts of electricity
bios lighting creates biological
lighting solutions
that brings the natural brilliance of
the outdoors into your grow room
bios lighting has the attributes that i
look for in a horticultural lighting
solution
i've bought those cheap lights online
and they're difficult to work with and
fail in no time in contrast my bios led
light is industrial grade to last a long
time
it is ip66 wet rated so little foliar
overspray won't harm it
it is easy to clean without taking it
down and of course the most important
aspect
it is built for the exact light spectrum
i want for great yielding healthy
cannabis plants
and it doesn't hurt that their lighting
rigs look badass too
many horticultural led lighting systems
are based on irrelevant performance
metrics and people love to argue online
about these numbers
i prefer to judge on par photon
efficiency and how happy my plants are
and the bios lights exceed my
expectations in these categories
bios lights have an optimized broad
spectrum that
maximizes photosynthesis and plant
growth while also providing the ideal
conditions
for superior par efficacy and a
comfortable visual experience
i also love their attentive and
over-educated customer service folks
bios starts with a team of biologists
before getting the electrical engineers
involved
they have studied how light impacts
cannabis plants and devised an overall
strategy that works
i encourage you to check out their
website at bioslighting.com
to learn more about how this strategy
can work for you
and shaping fire listeners can get a
special deal use the discount code
shaping fire all one word no caps for 10
off your entire purchase that's
biosliding.com
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire i'm your host
shangolos and our guest this week is
naturopathic physician
chris spooner so during the first set we
focused on the different variables that
can significantly
impact the patient's use of
cannabinoids and during the second set
we're going to try to figure out how we
suss out which of these variables we
need to be able to
pay the most attention to when either
doing
a self-assessment as a patient who is
trying to self-heal
or as a doctor or caregiver who is
working with a patient
and you want to give them the best
individualized medicine as possible
so so chris i guess take us from the top
you know you you've got a new patient
and you've got their you know
questionnaire in front of you
and and and you know from our our prior
talks i know that there is
um you know i'll call it a battery of
tests i don't know if it's that many but
there are some tests that
you rely on um
to give you your basic information and
you know we've all had blood tests so
why don't we start
there's something that people have got a
frame of reference with and then
and then continue on through the other
analytics that that you
give your patients yeah sure yeah and it
again you know it's
this is gonna fluctuate a little bit you
know so i mean you know i'll give that
caveat before we get started here and
certainly if
you know i may segue into one or two of
those if we need to but
but yeah i mean i think you know we're
starting off i mean you
there's a number of things to factor
here you know so first of all you know
what type of testing does a
clinician or a patient have access to
you know i think probably what i try and
do is start off with the very basics you
know basic blood work blood chemistry
uh you know cbc like compete complete
blood counts
you know liver function tests you know
thyroid these these sort of
standard things that you can get from
any of your your medical doctors
you know or naturopathic physicians or
or you know
these are pretty straightforward so i
mean that's that's a nice easy one to do
it's it's relatively inexpensive it's
you know so
i think this is a good place to start um
generally what i do is i kind of break
this down and if we starting with the
the model or the framework that i
suggested about you know taking a look
at sort of
optimizing nutrition here a little bit
you know there's a couple of markers
that you can take a look at
within a basic blood work that can give
you a general sense of things so for
example you know we could start off with
is someone anemic or not you know so a
lot of patients may come in with fatigue
and
you know exhaustion and you know and and
fatigue is a pretty you know it's a
pretty broad-based indicator but you
know i mean we can sort of see is like
you know what your iron status looking
like
you know because i mean sometimes you
just need to make sure that you're
checking off some of the basics because
sometimes there's a tendency to
you know to rush off into more exotic
you know the the analysis is you know
when we hear hooves think of horses not
zebras
right you know and then the qualifiers
unless you're in africa but
you know so there's some contextual
component to that as well too
you know so so certainly just taking a
look at you know what your your
red blood cell counts hematocrit
hemoglobin is
um and just making sure you're not
running anemic but within that you know
one of the ones that i like to pay
attention to is a
fairly it's a decent indicator of things
like vitamin b12 and folic acid status
is is what's called the mcv it's the
mean corpuscular volume so this is
basically
you know the the size of your red blood
cells
you know and and usually i mean the old
term for it was a pernicious anemia
which
you know then we'd give people b12 shots
to try and bring it around a little bit
if this
mcv was a little bit elevated um
up here in canada i think we're using
the same unit some of these will vary a
little bit but usually it's above 97.
i forget what the number is you just you
forget the the units um
but uh you know that usually suggests
that these blood cells are a little bit
bigger and and
the reason that this one's important
from an endocannabinoid status is
if we go back to this sort of you know
calm tea pathway that i was you know
sort of
speaking to a little bit earlier you
know the b
vitamins particularly you know folic
acid b12
b6 and that are involved in this thing
called a methylation pathway
and and this methylation pathway is one
of these things that creates
a compound that that you know supports
uh
com t uh s adenosine methionine in
particular is the one it is but
um but those your b your folic acid and
your b12 have to be
you have this little methyl group it's a
little carbon with three hydrogens onto
it
added to it so you get these methylated
b vitamins and you know for for people
that are
in the know about nutritional
supplementation we
most people tend to use methylated forms
of folic acid and b12
uh because they're active and we know
that these genetic
variants aren't there but certainly if
we see the mcv starting to be up there a
little bit it starts to become something
like well maybe we need to take a look
at the b12 status
or or take a look at um
you know uh supplementing someone with
that you know the other part of this is
that pernicious anemia often had
something to do with gastric
inflammation
b12s absorbed there's a cofactor for it
in the lining of the gut that helps get
it absorbed so if there's irritation to
the lining of the stomach you know
certainly that can compromise absorption
as well too so things like acid blocker
medications and that can have impacts on
that
so so that's the one of the you know a
nice place to start it's nice and easy
so if you're seeing that mcd being a
little bit elevated well
maybe we need to take a look at that
sort of the absorption of b12 and its
various parameters of that
as we start working down a little bit
more a couple of the other markers that
i start to take a look in there
um you know i take two i like to take a
look at the white blood cell counts
um and this speaks to a larger element
that's that's
um we need to have a quick
conversation about which is about what
are reference ranges
because this very much speaks to our
last thing of you know medicine by
average
you know so i think people need to
understand that reference ranges so when
you
when you get a lab test it gives you the
number like for example
tv is uh 91
and with it you're given a reference
range that is 88 through
97 right and and you look at that and
you're like oh well that must mean that
i'm
healthy within the space well you could
be or you couldn't but you need to
understand that that reference range
refers to a population norm so basically
what you're looking at is sort of a
you know kind of a 95 percent of the
tests fall within
value a and value b of which there's an
upper and lower range right and so
that really speaks to this sort of
medicine by average and i've always sort
of been like well if you're one of these
people
that tends to be up at the upper end of
a value
you know and you drop 10 points you know
do you feel as bad as a person who's at
the lower end of the value and drops 10
points
you know and uh you know but one of
those falls within the
the reference range and one of them
doesn't and so that's where this
individualized medicine goes where you
need to kind of start to ask some
you know patients some questions about
this and and thyroid testing is
notorious for this right you know you
can see some patients
you know they just have a range that
they feel much better and that
sometimes is inside the reference range
and sometimes outside of that
you know hold on before you continue on
another thing that you just said about
the reference range that just surprised
me
um unless i misunderstood you said that
the reference
range comes from the averages of the
tests
that are um taking place well that means
that if a population is getting
increasingly
unhealthy that the reference
range will change as well say for
example in my country you know
obesity is a scourge here and so
the our reference ranges that are
attached to obesity would be
theoretically moving in the wrong
directions
but then also since it's happening to so
many people our reference range is
actually drifting with
the population's lack of health yeah
potentially you know and
i think you know and for some of these
tests you know there's a long history of
what we know like you know blood lipids
and things like
that you know that it's like okay well
we know that these issues
you know i mean there's a fairly long
history of what this looks like so i
think they're a little bit more
resistant to that trending
in that respect um so as i
so yeah i don't disagree with you and i
think for
like for example again let's go back to
thyroid a little bit you know because
again there's a lot of interpretation on
that there's other factors that start to
come into this you know
the thyroid the it's interesting up here
in canada
you know the the depending on the lab
the upper limit limit of that is is 5.5
and i believe that if you cross the
border down and
into washington state there i believe
the american
college for endocrinology has kind of
said it is like under 2.5 so there's a
significant difference on where you're
classified
as you know hypothyroid or thyroid and
it may not necessarily be the test so
much as what the impact is on your
clinician's mindset
as to whether this is an issue or not so
someone that's looking at a reference
range of up to five
you know i would say like whoa okay your
thyroid your tsh level sitting at 4.5
that's a problem
whereas a physician may not you know
who's used to seeing it at five whereas
someone who's trained
you know or in a different jurisdiction
where it's slightly different may look
at that and be like oh yeah i know i
agree
you know that you know you need to be
under 2.5 so i think you've got two
things there one is certainly the issue
that you're speaking to but the other
one is also the clinician's mindset
and how they start to prioritize what to
look like which i think it's probably a
little bit more
i don't know if insidious is the word
but that's the one that comes to mind
right now
[Laughter]
so so so far we've been talking about
the blood test because that's something
that we're all kind of familiar with
we've all seen our ranges
and we could probably do an entire show
just talking about
a blood test and how to go through each
aspect of it and how it could
impact the endocannabinoid system and
maybe we'll do that
but for today let's let's move on
because i think that i think that both
patients and caregivers have gotten a
good taste of
of what there could be to unearth
in a blood test i mean i know that i'm
gonna go back and look at my recent
blood work with whole new eyes now
but let's move on to the next one so so
what other analytics
do you um do look at to help get that
snapshot
so that you know in what ways to
diagnose and
give protocol to a patient sure yeah so
i i think the next one is that's the
biggest one that's and we touched on
this is healthy hormones right so
what what and i tend to use a lot of
um questionnaires around this and again
we could
probably go quite some time on this but
certainly like i said i think when i'm
taking a look at this where i've been
spending a lot of time with patients i
don't know whether it's just the patient
population that's
coming in right at this moment but but
certainly
obviously in the the world that we live
in now stress levels are through the
roof
with people right you know and so
super key indicators you know that i
think really impact endocannabinoid
function are things like
you know that that stress hormone
cortisol
epinephrine norepinephrine you know
dopamine
type parts of that and so that leads me
down sort of taking a good hard look at
at where these stress hormones comes in
and questionnaires are usually
you know the most straightforward way i
mean when i start taking a look at
adrenal stress
you know and and sort of these elevated
cortisol you know adrenaline nor
adrenaline pathways
you know sleep is always a big indicator
you know i i really
i try and get patients to tell me okay a
little bit what's your sleep looking
like
you know and if people are coming in
because again there's different ways
that people don't sleep well and
certainly i think you know
if i take a look at where a vast
majority of my patients are using
you know cannabinoid therapies it's
certainly in the area of sleep
all right so but i think that for some
patients it works and for some patients
it doesn't and
and again that goes into sort of that
regulatory effect of
you know are you sort of winding someone
down by having more gaba in their system
you know or you know are they starting
to be stressed out and is this cortisol
and so there's that interplay between
the stress response and these
neurotransmitters
so what's this question you know so
sleep so i ask patients for example if
i'm trying to root out
okay is there a stress response and this
is usually something like cortisol is a
big one right
you can get a good indicator about okay
first of all are you difficult having
difficulty falling asleep at night and
what does that look like
so a patient for example that you know
they need to get to bed by a certain
time frame if they're not in bed and
asleep between nine and ten
you know suddenly they get a second win
and they're up and about
again um you know that's almost always a
pretty good indicator that they're
getting a little bit of a second
cortisol spike which is unusual
your cortisol should be sort of winding
down
towards the end of the day you know it
peaks in the morning and then it tapers
off throughout the day
but if it starts to come up a little bit
at the end of the day you're going to
see this this sleep issue
you know and so that becomes something
that will will probably
impact your response to cannabinoids
like you may find that the cannabinoids
knock you out and certainly depending on
the the the form that you're using right
you know i mean
and i'm sure you've had this
conversation many times you know orally
you know cannabinoids take longer to set
in but you get that six day window
effect and you get a little bit more of
those psychoactive compounds because of
that sort of
first pass liver function there a little
bit as well too so
you know but if some people are vaping
or something like that
you know they may not are using you know
different forms of it that have a little
bit more rapid onset that might clear
out a little bit more quickly so
you know a patient that's vaping i
usually recommend vaping as opposed to
smoking just because of my environmental
medicine
background and smoking is not something
that i try to i try to discourage as
much as possible
um you know an hour and a half two hours
in suddenly they'll be up again so you
really need to take a look at that
cortisol response and again there's
different ways you can deal with that
you know whether that's
meditation winding down taking a look at
your use of electronics beforehand what
does your stress sleep hydra
gene look like you know there's some
herbs that i use that are quite helpful
in there that kind of synergize nicely
with cannabinoids there
as well too so that's there's that's
that's a really interesting point about
um the the lights in the evenings and
that second potential cortisol spike
because
you know clearly i talk with patients
about you know
sleeping in cannabis all the time and
the number one thing that comes up with
people is i ask them do you drink coffee
right
because because people are like oh i've
got such insomnia but like i know that
coffee's got a half-life of 14 hours
and so that means that by the time
they're drinking their coffee tomorrow
they still have this morning's coffee
still in them
and so i encourage them to you know cut
down on or get rid of the coffee or
caffeine and you know their their
insomnia will probably go away and
you know after they look at me with
utter shock um
you know they're all like listen i'd
rather keep the caffeine
and just use more thc to get to sleep
right i mean that's that's not uncommon
but this idea of the blue lights and
using electronics at night of which i am
absolutely guilty of it's an interesting
idea that
if poor sleep is uh decreasing
our cannabinoid uptake and effectiveness
and poor sleep comes from using
my phone in bed at night and getting a
second wind and hanging out for two
hours
on bed reading stuff what this
you know if we backtrack that all the
way back my
using my devices at night is hurting my
endocannabinoid system
and that is not something i think is
immediately
apparent to most folks it certainly
wasn't to me until now
yeah and certainly you know again if we
you think about it in the context of
of a thermostat right you know i mean
you know my thermostat goes and tries to
heat the house without
all the windows and doors open well
that's gonna be a little bit more good
example
yeah right there's there's only there's
only so much capacity that you can and i
think that you know i mean
this touches on you know some of the
genetics that we talked about it talks
about sort of the nutritional
capacity it talks about the hormonal
environment
you know so you know all those things so
again you know it's sort of like
okay how do i optimize this system and
you know and this is the interesting
thing right is i think
i think that the thing that's become
most apparent to me here is is that your
your body
it seems to me and there's probably
people that are much smarter than me
that could expect you know they could
explain this or maybe poke holes in this
argument so
please feel free to i'd love to learn
about this but but what i find is
for example like let's take a look at
the stress response
and talk about inflammation and what i
want to use this
example to demonstrate is it isn't turn
one on
turn one off it's turn both on
and then turn one off so what ends up
happening is you get a faster response
if you have the sort of you know the the
the driver and the inhibitor going at
the same time so there's a
tension created in the system right and
what happens is that so for example
when we take a look at cortisol response
cortisol
is a immunosuppressant right it it's an
anti-inflammatory anybody that's taken
prednisone or
you know will will appreciate that so
it's a very powerful anti-inflammatory
at the same time cortotrophic releasing
hormone which is the hormone that
stimulates the response of that
also has an impact on vagal nerve tone
which drives a pro-inflammatory response
so you've got the same mechanism
like different branches of the cortisol
result being anti-inflammatory
but then pro-inflammatory at the same
time
and if you think about it it's like okay
well i'm going to run away from
i'll use a distinctly canadian response
you know the the grizzly bear
you don't want to wait for your system
to come online if they've you know given
you a club or two and you're running
away like crazy so you want your system
to come online so basically as your
stress response
drops suddenly it unleashes the
anti-inflammatory effect
you know on your nervous system which is
wired to get you the hell out of dodge
you know suddenly shuts down and calms
down now the other one can basically
cascade in on it
so i think the endocannabinoid system
probably has that same type of tension
in there and then you've got all these
other modifiers around it as well too
and when we talk about
the lack of sleep or the dietary issues
on top of that suddenly
you're you're taking away you you're
limiting the resiliency of it you're
kind of sort of cornering it in a little
bit so that you limit that
response a bit that way wow
all right so so so far we have talked
about
um the analytics that are helpful that
come from blood tests and hormone tests
and you've alluded a couple times to
genetic screens
and especially the 23andme and again
you already mentioned this but we're
going to set aside the
concerns that many people have about
whether or not there are identifying um
aspects of their health that are going
into
these large data sets and and and
whether or not people want to
participate we're just going to set that
aside for this conversation because
again that's a whole nother show what
we're going to focus on though is the
usefulness of this kind of a test for
the patient
so so what what do these
this these variety of tests show us that
is worth
noting sure yeah so
again you know you can break this out
into the endocannabinoid genetics
you know and then the nutritional stuff
you know
and and sort of hormone metabolism
things like that and and so where i
start to take a look at here is
you know some of the things you can
start to see is you know the cannabinoid
receptor and
and you know dopamine receptors and such
you know you see
you see some genetic variants where you
know these receptors are
are more responsive or less responsive
and that starts to set up you know are
some patients
you're more likely to to you know become
a little bit more hooked on you know
habitual cannabis use you know they get
the
the reward seeking response from that a
little bit and they tend to go down that
pathway so certainly that's something to
be aware of
you know when you're taking a look and
and that what you're going to provide
from a formulation standpoint
you know so there's there's that aspect
of it you know we can also start to dig
into
you know some of these um
[Music]
enzymes that you know drive the
different aspects of
the the cannabinoid system right so you
can take a look at
you know pha you know fatty acid amide
hydrolase
you know magl another one as well too
and degrade that and you know those
enzymes kind of give a sense of how
quickly you know these endocannabinoids
hang around
inside your your your synapse the gap
between your nerves on that as well too
so again it just gives you a sense of
what's the
the resiliency of that system so you can
start to build out some sense of
of that you know certainly where i start
to take a look at it is things like you
know
because most patients come in here and
again i think your your comment a bit
earlier on about how we tend to have a
patient population that have exhausted
other options
we tend to have a little bit more of the
canaries and the coal mines so
certainly i tend to see some of the
stuff that i also saw in my multiply
chemically sensitive patients which is
that
you know which is very similar
population in some respects
is that they have genetic variants and
things like their ability to clear out
these enzymes for example if we are
these compounds like let's talk about
your caffeine example that you use
some people genetically um don't clear
out caffeine well some do just fine
you know and so you know these are you
know and again i suspect that the people
that are a little bit more sensitive to
caffeine
um you know are are again sort of these
people that have some of these genetic
variants about clearance of cytochrome
enzymes and stat and that may
impact clearance of other medications
and other substances
it's um you know again a whole other
conversation we can talk about
google's you know i think it's called
alpha one is their new
artificial intelligence that looks at
protein folding
uh on it and it came up with some really
interesting stuff which is that you know
sort of
genes appear to organize
in biochemical pathways you know so that
you know they kind of support each other
so
um like for example i did 23andme
and it turns out that i'm genetically
pre-programmed to have to have
cod liver oil my swedish and swiss
background
pretty much uh means that i don't do
vitamin d terribly well my vitamin a
i don't convert it from plants terribly
well and my oils the
the hemp the plant-based oils i can't
really convert them into the sort of the
omega-3 stuff that we find in fish oils
you know but that that
group of them i've seen that repeatedly
in patient populations that
you know people of northern european
descent and things like that and some of
the first nations populations
you know seem to have these things where
their vitamin d
and their their essential fatty acids
and fat soluble vitamins seem to be tied
together
and you know we see this in other
different elements as well too
so that's that's a really cool element
of it and then
we go down the pathway of things like
again depending on what our patients are
looking at
so you know anxiety stress mood
depression you know chronic pain i
really start taking a look at a lot of
the tryptophan stuff around this as well
too there's some really
interesting aspects because that ties in
both of the b vitamins that we talked a
little bit earlier about folic acid b12
and b6 support
and then also the ability to convert you
know the amino acid tryptophan into 5
hydroxy tryptophan and so there's some
genetic variation on that too
so these are the types of things that
you know as you start to take a look
they show up and
different platforms have different
elements of it i just use the 23andme
raw data and load that into a multiple
of different you know genomic platforms
to start to identify those and
you know as several of them that i use
i'm working on one right now with
another company to try and
make a little bit more specific sort of
functional cannabinoid medicine platform
and so hopefully we'll have that out in
the next year so that's going to be
popular
i hope so yeah i think it'd be
interesting i mean the challenge is
trying to simplify this stuff down
because
you know again it's i realize i'm
probably just you know people are kind
of getting a fire hose effect right now
and
giving little snippets of it as well but
um but hopefully we can make it much
more practical and patient-friendly so
and i that that idea of being
overwhelmed by the details
like that's not lost on me you know like
you're right we are kind of moving
around
and there's a lot of vocabulary in this
episode
but it's also true to life right i mean
like this is
what it's like to be a patient like
anybody who is still with us
on the episode you know you know people
have got to decide that they're going to
care enough to learn the vocabulary
if they are going to become captains of
their own health
um we cannot have optimum health
let alone individualized cannabis
medicine
in a western healthcare system
that is designed more to keep us on
pharmaceuticals than it is to
heal us and move us on our way and so
you know while while at certain times
the vocabulary
that you've used even you know um washed
me in new ideas like oh i've got i've
got a long list of things that i'm gonna
google when we're done here
but that's what it's like to be a
patient that that is what it's like
and so um i think that
cannabis patients probably more than
most
are used to this because
we we we've already talked about how
cannabis patients are generally outliers
because the rest of the medical system
has
given up on them and then they've so
they've had to take their research
into their own hands and so those are
probably the people that this
episode is is most targeted for
because what we're giving i mean like
you know
from helping enough of my friends like
i've got rheumatoid arthritis friends
and
um and hypothyroid friends and all these
folks
we there are little snippets throughout
the episode where people are like ooh
there's a new search term for me that i
had not considered
on whatever topic and i think that's how
self-empowered patients have to go about
their medical education so so anyway i
agree with you
and i think it's par for the course yeah
well and i i
i would say again you know i mean this
is interesting because again you know
when i take a look i mean i've been a
naturopathic doctor now for
graduated in 1998 and so you know i had
you know undergraduate and naturopathic
college
as well with that for five years you
know five years of naturopathic college
four years of
undergraduate you know so i've kind of
been steeped in this for a really long
time in terms of this integrative
alternative medicine
what we're talking about in in cannabis
medicine isn't
new i mean this is something that sort
of the holistic
integrative medicine i mean you know
when i started off in in this area i
mean i remember going down and i
grew up in victoria on vancouver island
and i remember going down to uh the the
chinatown and getting chinese herbal
medicines and walking into this
and it was like it was just you know the
the
smells and and this you know you're just
like oh my god this is just so
fascinating you know but
you know this little chinese fellow you
know giving me all these herbs these
wonderful herbs and it was just you know
and now we take a look and go into any
you know sort of you know choices
you know integrative pharmacy whatever
and you see what the evolutions look
like and
and cannabis is is you know has the
potential
and just following that same course but
just in a very
magnified effect simply because the the
population behind that that's driving it
is
is i think there's just pent up demand
and suddenly it released and so now it's
moving
but i mean the what you're talking about
with cannabis patients is exactly what i
find in my patient population that's
non-cannabis
they're all very engaged they're doing
the research i have these conversations
with them i mean i
i never underestimate the capacity of my
patients you know to understand the
concepts that i'm giving them it's if
they're not getting it's because i'm not
doing a good enough job explaining it
right you know so i need to come back
around and find out that language that's
going there and so i know that we've
slipped into some jargon around that but
you know again
certainly you know we can you can you
can sort of dial that back in a lot of
different ways but
it's it's it's patients being empowered
it's patients starting to look into this
saying look you know
i don't i don't the current model is not
serving us well the symptom-oriented
thing we're just dealing with a symptom
is kind of the equivalent of of you know
pulling the batteries out of my smoke
alarm while there's toast burning in my
toaster
right you know it gets rid of the
irritation on it but there's still this
underlying issue that's kind of
happening here a little bit that needs
to be addressed
and i think that's what patients are
just struggling to find and i again
i don't there's just a medical system
that that they're trained to look at
that and it's like okay well i need to
you know i always joke with my patients
a little bit it's like your doctor is
concerned with you not
dying they don't really care about how
you feel about it
right and and and i don't mean that to
be overly critical i mean it's like look
they've got more pressing things just
make sure you're not dead the fact that
you've got a little bit of body aches
and pains because you're taking your
stat and they're like well
this is what it is at least you're not
going to die of a heart attack right so
the intention behind that is
is caring and genuine and all the rest
of that it's just that you know what are
they going to do about it like what's
the tool that they're going to have i
mean the option for them is to put them
on the medication switch it around a
little bit or stop it
you know but you know again all of us i
mean even in this conversation i mean
there's a deluge i mean this has been
20 years of experience that i've got
locked up into my brain i think that it
would be unfair to expect someone else
to try and
have that same type of experience and be
able to bring that to bear
you know and so you do what you do and
just like i don't know i mean
there's a billion different topics you
could bring up that i'm like
i don't know who i held a lot about that
one i'm gonna need to go do some work on
that and talk to some people so
i think at the end of the day you build
a healthcare team of people you become
your best
advocate you know you do your homework
on this you you be inquisitive and
curious and you know you persist
uh here on uh vashon where uh where i
live
ashon island um about i don't know gosh
has it been six years now
um we formed a patient and cannabis
enthusiast community
social group here called vimeo and
you know we we continually use this term
um scrappy street medicine because
so many of the people who have come to
endocannabinopathic
medicine because they were
fringe and black swans and outside of
the medicine
by average they have had to self-teach
and certainly before google it was
you know nearly impossible to do this
kind of research but it's becoming
easier and easier and we all have kind
of embraced this idea
that um
we work together to bring our
pre-existing scrappy street medicine
out of the bro science and into
an understanding that you're talking
about
of integrative medicine that's been
around for a while
but also has had the difficulty of
not being incredibly popular or
accessible to most people and
and is not taught in regular school
right and so
you know even though to you you know
you've been studying this for over 20
years
for most of us you know just simple
stuff like including
environmental medicine what what in your
house is off-gassing something
can be mind-blowing because a lot of
people are taught that
you know all the all the industrial
manufacturing is fine you know
and so and so that's that's how i you
know that's how a lot of
a lot of folks come up right as as you
know scrappy street medicine folks who
then
get access to professionals like you who
are now more accessible to us in
cannabis
because you know you're not shamed and
it's not as taboo to come on
on a podcast like this and and we get to
hear
some you know hints and best practices
from somebody who's
who's inside the specialty so
before before we wrap up and go to um
our next commercial break uh chris
were there any other tests that you
wanted to make sure that you pointed out
for caregivers or or
patients that they'll want to take a
look at for clues
we've you've mentioned uh the blood
tests uh hormone
tests and the genetic screens so far
sure
i think probably the last ones would be
that what kind of touched on was the
fats part of it right you know i mean i
there's there's some questionnaires that
i use you know things like you know do
you have dry
skin you know uh you know what's with
inflammation you know
there's some different conditions that
you can use to get a sense of
um you know what what the fatty acid
status is i mean and
for the most part if you've got dry
scaly skin that's always dry you
probably are pretty much deficient in
fats so there you go um
you know you might take a look at things
like vitamin d status that's an easy
test to run
you know has significant impacts
especially for for those of us you know
up near the border and above the border
here you know above the wall so to speak
yeah um you know uh so so those are
important things that i think are our
elements of it there's there's one last
blood work
test that i that i like there's one
called ggt
it's a liver enzyme it's usually used to
test for
alcohol most doctors will look at if
it's elevated so you need to stop
drinking and
but what it is actually is it's a really
uh it's a decent marker for something
called glutathione which is a super
important antioxidant
it's it's built out of an amino acid
called an acetyl cysteine that actually
is
showing some real promise and things
like helping with addiction
and and you know neurotransmitters
certain neuroplasticity brain health
parkinson's you know antioxidant status
you know this type of thing and i think
that's that's one that i tend to check a
lot
and you know and i take a look at those
numbers and it's one of those ones that
even though the upper level of it is
is fairly high there's been some
interesting papers published that showed
it's actually based on
insurance actuarial tables that show
that you know some
optimal levels occur at much lower
levels within the normal range of that
as well too
so that's a big one that i like to take
a look at as well too
awesome thank you so we're going to go
ahead and take that second
short break and be right back after the
break
we are going to go into talking about
whole foods your diet and how you can
support your endocannabinoid system
through your food choices you are
listening to shaping fire and my guest
today is naturopathic physician
chris spooner
[Music]
one of the reasons why no-till cannabis
growing is so valued by farmers
is because the mycelium networks in the
soil remain established from year to
year
and we know these fungal networks are
essential because they are the nutrient
super highways that extend
far and wide in the substrate to feed
your plants
the trouble with growing in new living
soils or blended cocoa substrates
is that it takes most of the plant's
life just to create these mycelium
highways
dinomyco endomycorrhizal fungi inoculant
reduces that time and gets your plant
eating a wider array of nutrients faster
and it's three times the concentration
of the other popular brand in the u.s
at 900 propagules per gram of two fungal
species selected specifically
for cannabis cultivation dynomica is the
result of 30 years of research and
trials at the volcani
agriculture research institute in israel
it has also been vigorously trialled by
cannabis and food growers across the u.s
dynamico is now available at grow shops
and on amazon in the united states
i love using dynamico to both speed up
the growth of the mycelium
networks in the soil but also as a
biostimulant to make clone cuttings more
virile you can see side by side showing
the comparative growth on their
instagram at dinomyco
if you demand reliable growing results
and appreciate the importance of an
active root zone in creating a thriving
plant
i encourage you to check out
dynomico.com and use the store locator
to find out where you can get yours
that's d-y-n-o-m-y-c-o-d
shaping fire listeners can get 10
percent off any size of dynamico
on amazon or dynamico.com by using the
discount code
shaping fire one word no cabs
whether you are starting with new beds
or pots or if you want to add some zing
to tired soil
choose dinomyco to maximize your plant's
potential
dynamico endomycorrhizal inoculant
with the national hemp program in flux
due to stringent thc testing
requirements
brother seth and eric crawford continue
to release seeds to hemp farmers that
will be legal
no matter how you grow them or when you
test them these new varieties from
oregon cbd seeds have substantial
amounts of
cbdv cbgv cbcv and thcv
while always staying below the point
three percent thc
limit and guaranteeing compliant crops
for farmers every time
also these new varieties cannot be
pollinated by your neighbor's
uncontrolled pollen
or a rogue male in your own crop either
oregon cbd seeds are non-gmo certified
too
oregon cbd seeds was founded and funded
in 2015 by seth and eric
maxing out their personal credit cards
without outside investment
they continue to refuse outside
investment that would change their
company culture
oregon cbd grows tons of fresh food on
their research farms for local food
banks
literally tons of food they also give
away tens of thousands of pounds of r d
flour to patients as their company began
to succeed
seth and eric started donating money to
the cannabis medicine and hemp fiber
cause too
by giving millions of dollars to oregon
state university
in order to establish the world's
leading cannabis genomics research
program
and they treat their employees right
oregon cbd pays for full health and
dental coverage for their employees
a 401k program and their minimum
starting wage is 20 bucks an hour
plus everyone shares food from the farms
seth
has been on shaping fire a few times to
talk about novel cannabinoids
you can check out episodes 25 and 37 on
cbd cultivars in the hemp market
episode 66 on triploid cannabis genetics
and the very first shaping fire live
episode 47
with seth and soil expert jeff lowenfels
talking about autoflowers
if you are a hemp farmer and you want to
grow reliable seeds that are sure to
thrive in past testing
check out oregoncbdseeds.com to learn
more about buying seeds for the 2021
season
that's oregoncbdseeds.com
this message is for folks who grow
cannabis i'm talking to home growers
patients and commercial growers too i'm
probably talking to you
when you plan out your next growing
cycle be sure to check out
humboldt seeds at humboldtcsi.com
caleb and specta and his family have
lived in humboldt county for over a
hundred years
for the last 40 years three generations
of his family have cultivated
extraordinary sense of meat cannabis in
humboldt
mendocino and trinity counties because
of his lineage and the hard-earned
experience that comes from growing up
smoking and sifting large populations of
cannabis plants in northern california
the seeds you'll cop from csi will be
winning genetics
based on long-time heavy hitters and
updated and resifted to bring out new
and exotic traits and better yields go
ahead and ask around
caleb also known as inspector and
pirates of the emerald triangle is a
breeder's breeder
he reaches way back and works with
significant strains
recreating them in new and interesting
ways that you'll love as a toker
and a grower as well as offering you
some surprises that will delight
serious seed traders and cultivators
humboldt csi goes a further step
and selfs all these quinovars so you
know all the seeds will be female
these are not experimental feminized
seeds
humboldt csi releases some of the best
female seeds available anywhere
and it will show in your garden folks
grew quite a bit of csi humble genetics
last year here on vashon island
and everyone was pleased the patients
had beautiful female plants
and didn't have to cull half of their
garden as males
the folks growing for the fun of getting
high grew colorful flowers with
exceptional bag appeal and great highs
and breeders had seven out of seven
females in a pack
which gave them a lot of phenotypic
choices
take a moment right now and visit
humboldtcsi.com
you'll find an up-to-date menu of both
feminized and regular lines
along with photos and descriptions
that's humboldtcsi.com
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire i am your host shango los
and our guest this week is naturopathic
physician
chris spooner so um in the first two
sets we talked primarily about figuring
out
um what might be the problem and
how best and what kinds of cannabinoids
that we want to introduce into your body
for optimum benefit from your
cannabinopathic care
and as we have sussed out that it can
get really complex
fast and the context for every single
patient is slightly different and so
today's episode has so far has not been
the same solutions for everybody it's
essentially
here are a bunch of things to consider
and then now you have to
go on your own individualized path well
set 3 is going to be a little different
because we're going to be talking about
the
foods that you can eat that generally
strengthen your endocannabinoid system
and this is especially great especially
for folks who either want to round
out their cannabis use with food that's
going to
support their endocannabinoid system or
folks who just can't really afford all
the cannabinoids that they
that they need but they do have access
to
clean food so um you know we've we've
talked in the past with dr
russo on an earlier episode about um his
seminal paper about um uh you know
particular foods that strengthen the
endocannabinoid system but that has not
been
updated in a long time and chris i know
that
you work with patients all the time
both as a naturopath but also in your in
your species
specificity of of the gut right and so
you're talking about foods about the
foods that they're eating
all the time so why don't we start with
the recommendations that you give
your patient base on foods that they
should
eat for endocannabinoid health sure
yeah i know i mean it's um it's pretty
straightforward i mean i think we've
touched on a lot of these things you
know i think you probably get won't be
too surprising giving our previous
conversation but
um i try you know patients
sometimes prefer supplements i prefer to
try and get patients to do as much as
food wise as they can uh to start off
with and
and so i mean i'd probably say for those
of you that have been listening
you know the first one i'd be going with
is something like cod liver oil i mean
most people it's
it's they're looking at it going like
well that just sounds downright
disgusting
but one of the things i really like
about it is that it's got a couple
things it's got
vitamin a and vitamin d in it
okay which is is fantastic you know and
so for those people that genetically
aren't able to do it it kind of bypasses
you know that issue and then you've got
it converted has a fair amount of what's
called dha in it which is one of these
essential fatty acids that's really
helpful for brain health uh
and its partner sort of epa um
is is a bit of an anti-inflammatory so i
find that you know
for those patients that are coming in
with inflammatory illnesses or
neurological stuff
or you know inflammatory conditions like
fibromyalgia and this type of thing i
mean this is a good place to start you
know arthritis pain
you know this type of thing you know so
you know a tablespoon a cod liver oil
gets your a's and your d's your fat
soluble vitamins and those important
essential fatty acids you know and it's
again we could certainly dig down deeper
into the science behind
why that is and whatever but you know i
mean we we do see
that you know omega-3 deficiencies
definitely really
impact you know sort of endocannabinoid
you know particularly the neuronal
functions as well too but also
synergizes quite nicely through the
anti-inflammatory effects so it
synergizes really nicely with things
like
cbd so that that would be probably one
of the first ones i'd be taking a look
at there as well too
the next one that i'm super fascinated
by
is this whole concept of the microbiome
right
you know and uh and so what i think that
you start taking a look at here is this
whole
i forget what the paper was here i'm
just gonna pull it up here real quick it
was um
yeah endocannabinoids the crossroad
between the gut microbiota and host
metabolism it was actually published in
nature i think in 2016.
a super fascinating article about this
that talks about the role
of the microbiome and actually how it
impacts a lot of liver pathology um i
don't know i suspect this isn't
something that shows up on everybody's
radar but
is it an epidemic proportions here right
and we always attributed that with
alcohol use well it turns out
it actually has a pretty significant
component of you know
disruptions in the gut microbiome and
that seems to be impacted by
endocannabinoids
interestingly enough so uh
taking a look at what's happening within
that that you know gut bacteria within
the digestive tract
i think is hugely important and you know
again i could go on and on about
the trials and tribulations and the
disrespect shown to our hepatic
liver system um but but i i won't i
won't stand up for them on that soapbox
right now
but i certainly think you know uh
anything that supports
the bacteria in your gut and that would
be something like you know a probiotic
if you want to go down you know the
foods that you would be looking at you'd
be taking a look at fermented foods
you know um you know your sauerkrauts
your yogurts
you know these types of things that that
really
they do two things one they supply
bacteria and
again it's there's a lot of subtleties
in the quality of probiotics and that
that
certainly again we could go on long
enough but suffice it to say
a lot of the fiber and a lot of the like
the the fermented
by-products so for example in yogurt and
milk products uh
the sugar lactose is composed of
galactose and
glucose well you can get what's called
the galacto-oligosaccharide which turns
out to be very helpful for the gut
microbiome and that's
produced in yogurt you know along with
sort of the the fermentation products
and the sort of ph
altering effects of that the lactic acid
so i think fermented foods you know if
you're dairy sensitive or things like
that you could take a look at other
different fermented foods
in there but i think that's a super
important thing and also a lot of people
who are sensitive to dairy foods like i
am
actually are okay with the fermented
ones so like you know you won't see me
drinking a glass of milk
but i can totally handle uh quality
yogurt
absolutely yeah and especially if you
get like a grass-fed yogurt
and why is that well it actually
dovetails with the types of fats
grass-fed animals have different omega-3
uh you know fatty acid profiles in their
milk that are skewed to the more
beneficial ones too so there's
a double whammy with stuff like that so
if you could certainly tolerate a
grass-fed yogurt
great fantastic you know goats yogurt is
probably another one that you could look
at if you're
if you're not too averse to goatee
flavors but uh
you know you go from there so so that
would be something that i think there
are definitely things you can involve in
there um
fiber is super important you know
especially for large bacteria this
is again i'm not going to go too far
down this rabbit hole but let's just
suffice it to say that
your gut bacteria is not the same below
the stomach as it is in the large
intestine
it varies significantly in the types of
bacteria
you know what they do and what they
produce and what they eat
and the ones that we really want to
emphasize going back to that
conversation about
butyrate that's you know again adding
things like
oat bran and psyllium husks and things
like that those are the two big ones
that i recommend on a regular basis
but anything that you know you could add
you know healthy fibers into it
again some people have sensitivities
around gluten and this type of thing so
you know this is where you'll get a
gluten-free oat or something along those
lines might be something considered
there
you know rice brands can be part of that
that start to bypass that as well too
but getting in those
those fibers that the bacteria can start
to work on and produce some of these
really important compounds
i think is really really important and
again you know we could spend hours
talking about that but
i think if i were to make those three
recommendations to patients
that would be at as a dietary strategy
overall
i tend to encourage patients to move
more towards that
paleo keto type end of things and this
is recognizing that
not all diets there's a lot of caveats
that go in this
and certainly i'm not of the view of you
know paleo means eat red meat and bacon
and cream
it means you know mediterranean type
diets you know
olive oils healthy oils fish avocado
you know coconut oils you know organic
safflower sunflower oils flax oils those
types of things healthy nuts and seeds
you know and again i think most people
would be like yeah it sounds like a
healthy diet i should probably do some
more of that so if you're really trying
to
improve your endocannabinoid tone that's
where i'd be leading and that's where i
said most of my patients
and then so like let's look at the
opposite right you mentioned earlier
um the idea of you know to having the
heating on in your house but then having
the window open so yeah you might be
heating your house
but all the good it's doing this is
going right out the window and i see
that
so often when i go to conventions
and you know people are all you know
talking about
you know cannabis medicine and patience
and then we break for lunch
and i watch these people eating like the
crackiest
you know fast food and i'm like oh you
know essentially they're leaving their
window open right
they they know about health but then
they're actually putting you know
tinder into their um into their body
instead of
like nice long burning logs right um
so so will you speak a little bit to
um the harm that processed foods do to
the endocannabinoid system because yeah
we want to increase
the quality of the foods we are eating
but at the same time we really
should be getting rid of these other
foods that are actually causing damage
the endocannabinoid system at the same
time
yeah you know and again most people when
they see naturopathic physician they're
pretty much being well he's going to
take me off sugar
dairy and wheat so myself
might as well fit the stereotype and
don't do that um
but but no definitely i think when you
take a look at particularly your
processed foods
you know i mean there's there's a number
of different things that come into it i
mean
um and there's maybe there's a couple
reasons that might surprise people if
anybody wants an interesting read on it
there's a book
sugar salt fat that talks about you know
sort of the fast
food industry and the processed food
industry
you know and it was essentially an
investigative journalist that had heard
that a lot of the foods
you know big companies general mills
nabisco and rs i got together and one of
them was kind of saying like one of the
individuals was being like look
we may be kind of moving into cigarette
territory here where suddenly it's going
to become apparent that there were some
real health benefits that we kind of
knew about that we kind of pushed
and so it's a fascinating read but aside
from the fact that something like you
know your hydrogenated fats and your
trans fats the
the problem is that these fats are odd
lengths like when you're taking a look
at essential fatty acids
you know they're you know 16 18 20 22
carbon molecules strung together with
different
bends you know the omega-3 for example
talks about you have a bend in the fat
if you think of it as a pipe cleaner
there's a bend
at you know the third carbon in you know
where's an omega-6 it's the six carbon
and so these hydrogenated fats
have have these bends and these lengths
that are just
odd your system doesn't quite know what
to do with it so i kind of liken it to
gumming up the works
so when you're putting these fats into
your body suddenly you're getting this
odd kind of you know your body's like
what do i do with this and what do i
make with it and so when we
you know extend this to the thing of
like hey omega-3 deficiencies have
impacts on your endocannabinoid tone
because
some of the important endocannabinoids
are associated with those
well if you start throwing more of these
fats and they start to predominate in
your system
then that starts to become problematic
you know
sugars and things like that it's not so
much i mean you know heaven forbid i you
know i can be a bit of a chocoholic
myself at times as well too you know so
i think there's an important balance you
know i kind of use the 80 20 rule you
know 80 percent of the time
20 percent of the time i enjoy stuff you
know and you know i like a nice
something tasty every once in a while so
i try not to be too obsessive about it
but you know as your health
challenges mount up that becomes less
and less over time
but i think arguably you know some of
the larger issues that we see
in the context of health you know
inflammation
insulin blood glucose issues are there
so carbohydrates start to become
super important and really trying to
making sure that we're getting our
our carbohydrates that have a lot of
fiber and the analogy that you use like
a quick burning piece of newspaper and
your fireplace burning a log
you know there's a difference between a
steel cut oat versus oat flour which i
equate to
similar type of burn times you know so i
think trying to get your carbs as
unrefined as
unprocessed as whole as possible is
where i would be suggesting that way as
well too to help
limit those blood sugar swings and those
insulin response and thereby
you know probably being at the base of
the pyramid
i think you're 80 20 you know it fits
for so many things but in this
case i think that most folks are
probably 80 percent eating questionable
food and
20 eating healthy food but really
remembering the 20
that was good and so you know most folks
seem to be
kind of out of touch it's amazing the
power
of a food journal to really get to the
bottom of what you're eating
every single time in my life that i have
done a food journal
i have been shocked and disappointed in
myself for what i'm actually eating in
real life
versus what i think i'm eating yeah and
that's something i do with patients all
the time i give a minimum of a two week
diet diary with all of my patients and
it's not so much you know
and i i can do all sorts of different
things i do like interventional pain
management i can stick
needles in people's backs and joints and
things like that and they'd be like yeah
and
ask them to stop you know do a diet diet
you'd think i was you know
trying to remove one of their limbs or
something yeah so i mean it's it's
challenging but i
tell them it's like look this isn't
really for me most patients usually
after about a week or so start getting
the general gist and they start
modifying their diet all by themselves
and really a sneaky little trick i do is
i just keep on giving them
all by themselves you dropped out there
right there what was the thing
what was the very last thing you said
yeah usually i just give them
diet diaries for three four weeks and
they just start making changes all by
themselves
oh good you know i i don't even need to
tell them anything they're like they
know what they become so apparent
themselves yeah
yeah so corollary to the sugar of course
is
alcohol so um how will
using alcohol like processed food
degrade
our endocannabinoid system yeah
i think again alcohol there's a context
to it i mean it depends on the type of
alcohol and how much you're drinking i
mean we've got the french paradox where
you know a glass of red wine and things
like that's not really too much of an
issue and in fact
you know there may be some health
benefits because it helps you relax and
unwind and
and things like that as well too but
some people again genetically have
problems uh metabolizing alcohol
and so that can be an issue and and
certainly we know
i mean my general experience and this
comes from my environmental medicine
stuff is that
things like alcoholism and that there's
there's some really interesting stuff
that we saw around
serotonin tryptophan metabolism and that
in there so again there's that
intersection so i don't i don't know
exactly where it all in there and and
but i do tell patients like look you
know let's take a look at your alcohol
consumption because again you could
potentially
you know limiting your resiliency
resilient because you're starting to
consume
bandwidth in your endocannabinoid tone
through these
these disruptions and serotonin pathways
and then there's also
little metabolites that your body has to
uh to clear out as well too
i think that the next issue that starts
to become problematic in that is that i
find that a lot of stuff some a lot of
patients have
going to the gut microbiome like yeast
issues
and it's not uncommon to see patients
have sort of sensitivity to yeasts
uh in because of you know like you know
particularly
and no no disrespect to the craft beer
industry but they tend to have a little
bit more
yeasty type stuff in there as well too
so i see sometimes that's a problem so i
tend to watch tell patients
you know with a lot of gi issues to to
watch out for for
stuff with high yeast contents and
whether that's craft beers or homemade
wines or things like that so
that's that's another option of it as
well to get them to consider
right um so so let's do a little summary
here before we wrap up there chris so
you know as we've already recognized we
were a little
i don't know we were kind of like
shooting like shotgun pellets right kind
of a little bit scattered
but but we covered a wide
breadth of so that hopefully we are able
to provide
new search terms and new i don't know
paradigms new ideas new approaches
mentally
for both caregivers who are in taking a
new patient and want to help them
with their endocannabinoid system as
well as self-directed
uh you know cannabis enthusiasts who are
trying to do it better
and so you know there's kind of
something for everybody in this show but
to kind of summarize it what are your
i'm going to ask you for recommendations
for two different kinds of listeners
what would what is would be kind of your
summary recommendation
for someone coming to use cannabis
medicine or
food for health for the first time and
then what are their
recommendations for long-term cannabis
users who
already you know are using cannabinoids
but they want to be more effective
right so i as a clinician the thing that
i as you probably
got i like lots of information right and
i think the
the more we understand about you know
what we're using and what we're dealing
with that helps inform our decision
making process and helps us make better
decisions so
you know for someone who's new to
cannabis you know
who's um you know where would i start
you know again obviously
you know we're taking a look at what's
your overall health you know
what is it that we're dealing with are
you looking at inflammatory conditions
are you looking at gut injuries
so so get get your medical records get
you know review what's going on here a
little bit try and get a sense of
okay you know what's my overall health
looking like
um and then dietary wise you know spend
some time and and just do
the basic nutritional stuff you know
take a look at that you know clean up
the diet
you know get some exercise going
optimize your potential these are these
are really
basic things you know and there's lots
of different tools that are out there
there's apps and fitness bits and things
like that so
i certainly encourage patients to do
that um
when it comes down to the cannabis
itself which we
we haven't really touched on yet but i
think this is this answer just kind of
goes into where i suggest
both my more experienced cannabis
patients which i would give the same
recommendations to as the new patients
but one from a cannabis standpoint
is know what you're getting like
i think the biggest issue that i see
here
is formulations and we don't know what's
in it we don't know the ratios of your
cbd
your thc the terpene profiles you don't
know how it's being extracted what's
there with it as well too
so you know know what's going into your
bodies and if i were to summarize
everything that we're talking about
whether it's diet or whether it's
cannabis it's like
you know what you're doing get your
information understand what it is that
you're eating what you're doing with the
food what's in your food
understand what's in your cannabis and
and get that and
be thorough about it be you have to be
your own advocate and
you know knowledge is power fantastic
well chris thank you so much for
spending your time and your expertise
with us you know when uh dr
russo uh recommended uh you to me after
after i initiated a conversation with
individualized cannabis medicine
he's all you know you really need to
check out my friend chris up in canada
and
and you know i saw who you were on the
internet but then when we started
talking i'm like holy hell this guy has
got
really unique information that i haven't
seen elsewhere and
that has been my experience today so i
really appreciate both your expertise
and um and your good cheer
thank you so much it's uh it's been a
real pleasure i've really enjoyed this
so thank you so much
excellent i hope you uh will come back
another time so absolutely
so if you want to connect with chris or
just find out more about his practice
you can reach out to him at
paradigmnaturopathic.com
you can find more episodes of the
shaping fire podcast and subscribe to
the show at shapingfire.com and wherever
you get your podcasts
if you enjoyed the show we'd really
appreciate it if you leave a positive
review of the podcast wherever you
download
your review will help others find the
show so they can enjoy it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the newsletter for insights
into the latest cannabis news exclusive
videos and giveaways
on the shaping fire website you also
find transcripts of today's podcast as
well
be sure to follow on instagram for all
original content not found on the
podcast
that's at shaping fire and at changolos
on instagram
be sure to check out shaping fire
youtube channel for exclusive interviews
farm tours and cannabis lectures
does your company want to reach our
national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts
email hotspot at shippingfire.com to
find out how
thanks for listening to shaping fire
i've been your host shango los
you