[Music]
we all love our plants and our cannabis
plants play an important role in our
lives
when we as humans love something give it
importance and strive to understand it
we call that sacred
if you want to learn about cannabis
health cultivation and technique
efficiently and with good cheer i
encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter we'll send you new podcast
episodes as they come out delivered
right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week and
videos too
don't rely on social media to let you
know when a new episode is published
sign up for the updates to make sure you
don't miss an episode also we're giving
away very cool prizes to folks who are
signed up to receive the newsletter
there's nothing else you need to do to
win except receive that newsletter so go
to shapingfire.com to sign up for the
newsletter and be entered into this
month's and all future newsletter prize
drawings
you are listening to shaping fire and
i'm your host shango los
my guests today are blair and daniel
auclair
blair and daniel auclair are farmers of
cannabis and food at radical herbs farm
in kovalev california i'll point out
that radical is spelled radical like the
taproot
r-a-d-i-c-l-e
blair trained on biodynamic farms first
on maui and then at rafael gardens in
sacramento located at what was then
rudolf steiner college daniel also
started farming in hawaii before
starting an apprenticeship at live power
community farm a horse-powered
biodynamic vegetable csa located in
kovalev
their paths came together when they met
at the farmers market in kovalev and
from there they embarked on an
agricultural endeavor together getting
married and starting a family in fact
blair is expected to go into labor any
day now which explains why she sounds a
little out of breath in the interview
they are now stewards for 60 acres
consisting of hay fields and about two
acres under cultivation of vegetables
and cannabis production
in 2018 they won the regenerative farm
award at the emerald cup with two other
farms
radical herbs is both dragonfly earth
medicine and sun and earth certified
blair and daniel practice biodynamics on
their farm radical herbs and this year
will be featured in a documentary
alongside green source gardens and bryce
land forest farm the film titled tending
the garden is a journey through a year
in the life of these three family farms
cultivating cannabis food and community
in the pursuit of a regenerative future
blair and daniel practice a sort of
farming that embraces both science and
mysticism today we are going to discuss
biodynamics
special note that the internet isn't
very robust out in kovalev there are a
few minor audio drops in today's show
welcome to the show blair welcome to the
show daniel hey right on shanghai thank
you for having us thanks so much for
having us happy to be here right on so
so let's start by creating a bit of
context for folk because i bet there's a
bunch of folks like me who generally
think that like biodynamic growing is
essentially like organic growing plus
magic and like you know that's a little
vague but it's also not that far off
from what i'm gathering so so please
like like set the table for our
discussion today by walking us through
the philosophy behind biodynamics and a
bit about rudolph steiner the father of
the practice
sure so um that's a really great
description of it and um
steiner was known uh as the scientist of
the invisible
and so
he had been working his whole life
to establish a a
science that would be taken as
legitimately as the natural sciences
but one that studied spiritual phenomena
as opposed to
or or as it relates to
the natural sciences he wanted there to
be a science of the spirit to go
alongside the science of matter the
natural sciences
and he devoted his life to that he was a
part of the theosophical society back in
the day with h.p blavatsky
he wrote books he lectured extensively
he established
areas of research that changed medicine
pedagogy economics architecture the arts
he had his hands in everything
uh and was a very controversial figure
actually um
and in his time
um but before he left us he
was asked by farmers uh in austria to
give indications for a spiritual renewal
of agriculture and that's actually what
the ag lectures were originally titled
it's the spiritual renewal of
agriculture because these farmers a lot
of them
the lectures were given on a sugar beet
estate
they were noticing
uh with the onset of chemical
agriculture they were seeing a decline
in soil health a decline in seed
germination and they really were
concerned about this and wanted to know
what they could do to combat that and so
he gave a series of lectures uh to that
end and that's where biodynamics has
come from
and
um
there was an experimental circle that
was formed very soon after and that's
what we
have been working with today there's a
series of preparations that are were
given to
um using the compost pile there's field
sprays
and just ideas of working with the
rhythms of
moon cycles
and
what could blair say
uh yeah i think that's a really good
like beginning introduction and that was
those lectures were given in in 1924
and so this was kind of some people see
it as like sort of the first
uh kind of
written organic guidelines in a way uh
predating sort of what we know but we do
know that two
uh you know
hundreds and centuries before that
people have been practicing agriculture
and been doing regenerative practices um
it and it was just sort of in this time
that
uh chemical agriculture started to make
its way in that there was really
beginning to see a degradation in land
um but one of the things that steiner
really looked at
in looking at a farm was looking at it
as sort of this this living organism
that strives to be self-sustaining
and so when you're looking at that
you're looking at
you know one of the biggest things is
how do we reduce the off-farm inputs
that we're bringing on
into the farm and how do we create
fertility on the farm and how do we
create this organism that can function
and be able to sustain itself without
having to bring a lot in
and so you know we're looking at not
only like
growing cannabis growing vegetables but
how do we incorporate
different parts into the farm as far as
like
bringing the animal elements in you know
we have we have different types of
livestock but a way that you can bring
the animal element into the farm if
you're just even in a backyard gardener
is to plant some flowers um to grow some
perennials uh grow some annuals and in
that way you're bringing in you know
you're bringing in bees you're bringing
in pollinators those bring in birds and
all of a sudden you have this uh
vibrant thriving
animal aspect to the farm
also um part of bringing in biodiversity
and creating a living organism is
building fertility and there's different
ways of doing that we build fertility by
um you know making making compost and we
definitely still are
lacking in our closed loop system and
still bringing compost bringing potting
soil but it's always sort of like a
it's a constant goal that we're striving
to get better at as is is closing those
loops and you don't always have to it's
not always about having that
animal aspect of making compost and
for fertility cover crops are like an
amazing excellent way to bring in
fertility to the farm
a great way to keep your soil covered in
the winter time and kind of closing the
loop in that respect and also
it just
it
it's a great way to also just bring in
more plant diversity to your farms
you're not only just growing like in a
cannabis bed if you're you know
has a tendency to just they you know
people will grow cannabis and then in
the winter time it'll just
sit there um but if you're bringing a
cover crop in and planting that on your
cannabis beds
then you're bringing in more diversity
and
soil
different soil roots and stuff too
to that farm
also as far as diversity like wild
places are really important too
in creating this farm organism in that
even in the demeter certification you're
required to have 10 of your farm at
least dedicated to wild areas
and we know in those kinds of areas
you're you're
bringing in a whole
dynamic array of different animals and
organisms and
i think the way that we try to
treat our farm in even the places that
we cultivate we're trying to mimic wild
places as much as possible by
having as much diversity of crops you
know making sure we have flowering
plants and
annuals
annuals for flowers and perennials for
flowers and ensuring that there's sort
of this
constant uh
amount of vegetative growth all the time
to encourage a diversity of
beneficial insects and pollinators and
birds and putting bird houses up and
that sort of thing
and then
let's see as far as uh
the biodynamic preparations daniel
touched on a little bit
and it will go into more detail later in
the show
um
it's kind of one of the more well-known
parts of biodynamics is the biodynamic
preparation the horn manure and it does
one a little bit less known its
counterpart is horn silica and those two
work together
in sort of relation to the cycle of the
year whereas like horn manure is made
from
uh putting a manure and a cow horn
buried in the winter months and that's
sprayed
on the soil or as horn silica
is also put in the
in a horn but buried in the summer time
and used as a foliar spray as the plants
are ripening and kind of trying to
enforce the
amplify the cosmic forces that are
influencing the plants
and so um in a lot of biodynamics you're
kind of looking at that duality of
aspects not only in the type of
fertilization that we're doing as far as
like the horn manure and the horn silica
but looking at the rhythm rhythms of the
year
how the plants and the earth are
affected by those rhythms and then also
kind of like the the
the cosmic aspects
of
of the earth and and the influences of
the cosmos on the earth and the plants
and so the the plants are really you
know creatures that are
much more
influenced by the cosmos than than we
are
and so
there uh there's a whole um planting
calendar that people are familiar with
that we'll kind of go into a bit later
in more detail
but the you know the
plants are very influenced by
mainly by the moon and well mainly by
the sun first and then by the moon and
then there's
constellations and
uh planets and all those things
uh too
um
let's see and then there's also there's
the biodynamic compost preps and so
the compost preps are
sort of um
were indications that were given by
steiner in his lectures and they really
look at kind of they're
really seen as sort of like homeopathic
preparations that are used to bring a
heightened vitality to the compost pile
and
those are created and made in order to
bring different elements and to really
create a potentized compost that then
can be used on on the land one of the
things that i noticed right away is that
this really does sound like um
like more of a family farm environment
right where where people are going to
i don't know grow humans along the
alongside growing their crops like when
when you're describing like you know 10
of a wild zone and lots of these flowers
and you know um you know uh piles of
sticks for birds to live in and hedge
rows and like it sounds like a very um
biologically complex and abundant area
um which which is what i picture when i
visit regenerative farms
you know in northern california
whereas
i don't picture this when i when i see
some of the multi-acreage farms that are
very
i don't know more sterile right they've
got very long rows and you can see the
high fences
um for protection and and you can see
the the the heavier tilling equipment
and
um it's
like like that seems like it would be
the antithesis of what you are
describing which is kind of like
building an agricultural area or a homes
home place on the farm where you can
grow
flowers and food
and humans and animals and cannabis
and um it just seems a lot more like a a
traditional abundant environment instead
of more of a mechanized
sterile growing environment yeah
definitely and i would say you know like
as looking at growing cannabis too that
you know and and plants in general
they're there absorbing their
environment they can't go to other
places to get things and so you know
looking at like what's the type of
cannabis you want to smoke what's the
kind of food you want to eat
where that
plant being is located and what it's
absorbing
has a lot of influence on that and so
are you getting something that's
absorbing salt fertilizers and that's
what you're smoking or are you having
something that's growing in in living
soil surrounded by other plants and the
communication of other plants under the
soil and the mycelium and that's what
the plant is absorbing and that's what
you're ingesting and and experiencing
and so i think that that was like a
really nice a really beautiful picture
um that you painted and i think so much
why we love living where we live and the
communities that we live in and the
other farmers that we're surrounded by
is really you know
i think
you know not just the community that
we're able to create on the farm with
diversity but also you know so important
to have a
community in general with with who we're
uh
relating with and and who were you know
in this whole process with too listening
to you and daniel describe the um you
know the the uh
embracing of nature and the the coaxing
the most out of nature inviting it to
participate with you on your farm
um it actually sounds a lot like the
messages that we're all sharing now in
the regenerative cannabis
scene
but um it's interesting to note that
that this
agriculture and life philosophy you know
came from the 1920s where they were
about to
run into agriculture like industrial
agriculture and petroleum fertilizers
and
and you know the mechanization of of the
um of the farm
and and these folks were having an early
reaction
to being very unsure and unsettled about
that just like we are feeling you know
we've got evidence now why
they were right to be unsure and
unsettled because now we're at the we're
at the far side of industrialized
farming feeling like okay we've seen
enough and we need to we need to circle
back to some of the important aspects um
that that we've lost
um does that is like does that fit in
for you with your picture because i i
think that there's something more to it
like obviously there's the preps that
we're gonna talk about in set two or
three
but um but i really feel like um
i mean not not to sound too woo but it
actually sounds like you're you're
farming and the ways that you go about
it are kind of as much of um ritual and
prayer as it is
you know just trying to grow good crops
yeah i would say you know i think what
modern agriculture has done is
taken things apart and separated and
tried to create and compartmentalize
things and that's not what nature does
you know nature works in in rhythms and
cycles and like you know taking the
animal away from the grass and then
growing the feed over here and then all
of a sudden you're having this complete
imbalance where you're having to put
these chemical fertilizers on
on a field to grow something and then
you have this over abundance of
of waste from the animals and it's just
like completely out of balance where
we're trying to bring as many things
together in one place to have them
benefit each other and and work together
and then i think where biodynamics takes
it another step
is trying to create ways to
create pictures and imaginations for
things that we can't necessarily see
or that
regular science can't um
be able to quantitatively measure and in
that respect steiner really was able to
create some pictures and imaginations
for
a whole level of
spiritual
elemental um things that happen on the
farm and in nature
that we can maybe intuitively feel
or
try to imagine and so in and that way he
kind of like took agriculture
um
to a different to a different level of
you know how are the planets influencing
the plants um how are the elemental
beings working like
what are the gnomes and doing to
doing on the land and different things
like that where we can really um
not even i feel like in a certain sense
begin to
imagine the different
microscopic spiritual things that are
happening in the plant world in the
natural world
and just try to begin to
imagine
how all those things are happening like
like uh daniel was saying only recently
we've been able to
um
talk
at some point saying only recently being
able to understand what mycelium is
doing and how that's able to
create a communication with with plants
and i think that's one thing we try to
do in our cannabis beds too and why we
do so much companion plantings i think
really that there's this whole
conversation happening underground
between
the roots that is really important to
have as much diversity as possible
and
i don't personally know that and i think
that scientists are just being able to
somehow with their measurements like be
able to
have an idea that there is something
going on
but i think that like also
back in the day
in 1924 steiner was able to understand
that there is this and uh elaborate
communication happening with with plants
that we
um you know can't really grasp but
weren't able to grasp at that time
there's an image that he shares of the
farm
uh
being an image of a human standing on
its head right where
the the nerve sense and the
the thoughts of the plants are happening
under the ground
and then above ground is the belly and
the reproductive organs so there's like
an inversion so
to make sure that the
the nerve sense in the soil is active
and alive is allowing for
more um
communication to be happening through
the plants and it's a very fun image to
work with as you're walking around the
belly
of the farm and the soil being the
diaphragm separating the two
you were making me think of uh um
of a thing where
we want it science wants us to have way
measure and count to be able to tell if
something exists and it's real whereas
anthroposophy and biodynamics wants to
replace weigh measure and count with
levity rhythm and quality oh man that
that's heavy duty actually because and
actually to to the i was like sitting
here struggling right because i'm like
okay
so is by dot is biodynamics more
um you know a strategy for
for farm upkeep or is it a
philosophy of living
and i and i realized that
it's kind of it's kind of both those
plus because
so many of us me included um you know
we're feeling more disconnected from our
communities and from um you know nature
and from
uh you know our families everybody's so
spread out and especially during these
quarantine days it's harder to see each
other and everything
and and this entire
way of thinking about agriculture
continually comes back to
interconnectedness
and um
you know kind of like a um
a spiritual intent like like i'm i'm
going to do my i'm going to do these
things on the farm that i know that are
good for the farm because in the end i
need to produce food in cannabis so that
i can you know feed my family but at the
same time i'm going to do it with a
ritualistic intention that somehow makes
it more meaningful it's like it's like
taking regular
regener regenerative or natural farming
and and turning it way up
with um with ritual practices to give it
spiritual meaning do you think do you
think that's a fair assessment i mean
i'm new to this so i don't know what i'm
talking about but but you hear listening
to you talk about it it makes me feel
like it's it's all of our bases of
natural farming turned up
with spiritual practices i think you hit
the nail right on the head that's like a
perfect summary and um steiner even has
you know also like a lecture on
festivals like he knew that like this
community sort of festival spirit
celebration
is also extremely important
for us i think for nature for the world
and being able to you know it's not it's
not just about
making money on the farm it's so much
more than that and how can we connect
with with different parts of of of being
and be more
spiritual creatures there's an element
like a trend to want to say that nature
will be fine if we just leave it alone
like humans need to remove themselves
from the equation but anthroposophy is
kind of
a way of balancing that out to say like
you cannot remove the human element from
from nature we are
a part of it and he goes on to say that
like in the future
the seasons will
will happen less and less unless until
humans recognize their role in it like
we need to be a part and
be co-creators with
nature because nature needs us as much
as we need it and
that puts us in a very delicate place of
what is our motive
is it ego driven to dominate or are we
wanting to
be fair and equitable and and um with
each other and to you know it's a
there's a moral element that comes that
comes out of this too it really
illustrates how this variety of farming
and i dare say the two of you then as
practitioners of this type of farming
you really have to
you really have to lead with your heart
and with vulnerability right because
because i can imagine even though you
get great results on your farm and even
though the preparations that we're going
to talk about in the next two sets are
very real and they're about managing
nutrients and such um i can imagine that
a lot of this really strikes people as
woo
and you have to be a little choosy about
who you're gonna be vulnerable with
about like how you actually see your
your farm because you've you've really
described um you know
um
you use this term imaginations right and
i'm sure that that's like a term of art
from rudolph steiner but but the way
that i take it myself is like you are
you are intentionally using your mind
and your heart and storytelling and
imagining and
daydreaming and all of this stuff to
connect you with the animals and the
foods and the
and the natures of your farm and
you know that
that's not this it's not entirely
popular right now right where everyone's
trying to sterilize everything and get
everything down to
that that great quote that daniel just
said about like weights and measures and
and scales right
where everybody is approaching not
everybody i don't want to be unfair so
much of farming is about bean counting
now and it's spreadsheet farming
where where your kind of farming may you
know still gets the the bountiful
results but somehow it has more
um more human meaning
and daydreaming in it and that's that's
a pretty that's some radical stuff it
feels vitadymix feels so good because it
is so unintellectual
right like there's a very like science
is like dominating our culture right now
with this intellectuality biodynamics is
dirty it's unacademic i feel and you're
right the uh when we say the
imaginations um
steiner had the three
capital letter eyes imagination
intuition and inspiration
are
our three components to
developing oneself i think bob marley
was tuned into it also he had the i3s
were his backup singers but um
it's yeah it's very much um
i love i've
i went got into the weeds there it is
um very much
unintellectual and um
i think it just like creating a mat like
we talk about creating imaginations it's
like a steiner did give like quite
specific indications of types of
meditations to do and actually at night
um kind of as uh sort of a meditate
imagination and meditation
to go through your look at your day
going backwards
um
like start just
laying in bed you just start to think
about like what you did that day and
step by step go backwards and then kind
of bring it forwards and you take that
into your into your dream world and to
steiner too the dream world is also a
very important place where we're able to
communicate
with
spiritual beings and
the cosmos in a way that we can't
necessarily do during the day it
sometimes seems like there is a turn off
with biodynamics because there's a new
language that needs to be learned like
etheric bodies and astral bodies and
living warmth and
dead warmth and
all these kind of things but i would
just push back against that and say that
the language that we're using is one
that we had to learn at the beginning
also and so when
you take the time to to
to get into why these words were chosen
and and what not like it it does
bring a living quality to
farming that
for us i guess is um continually
inspiring and allow puts us in a place
of curiosity
um and always
it it makes us take the broadest
view of what's happening as opposed to
focusing on
what's directly in f we have to see
what's directly in front of us but then
use
as much of our
surroundings and open
open one's perspective or um
perspective to to gain clarity as to
like what's happening because everything
is connected and so
biodynamics for us
is a
really broad and it's a very broad
way of
uh
seeing the world
right on i really get that idea of the
inspiring hearing your describe it you
know my my head goes two places with it
the farm that as you describe it it
sounds like like a like a beautiful
beautiful place that is that is rich
with smells and animals and and like a
very highly expressive
um soil food web right and it just it
just it sounds beautiful it sounds like
a beautiful like hobbiton kind of place
to go and it sounds like a great place
and yet the other side of me is is all
like oh it also sounds very inefficient
and like that is your whole damn point
right is that those efficiencies
is what kills human connection and you
are intentionally reaching out to these
imaginations
and um
and intent when you're making these
preparations
so that it builds connections because
like that's that's kind of at the core
of the whole biodynamic thing right is
these connections yeah i mean i mean in
many ways i would say that we're all i
i wouldn't categorize as us as
inefficient too i mean as we talk about
biodynamics and kind of you know talk
about why we're into it so much we also
like utilize a lot of different other
agricultural practices too and don't see
biodynamics as like the only way like um
you know as far as our vegetable farming
we're really into
um
no-till
uh bio-intensive market gardening which
is really like an amazing practice and
like all really focused on efficiency
and you know trying to grow vegetables
with the least amount of
uh disturbance to the soil and
uh and least amount of weeds and all
this and but we feel like that there
then is you know and and regenerative
agriculture and and different things but
um i think that biodynamics just kind of
to me a lot of times dynamics is sort of
just kind of also the icing on the cake
and like we're able to
do all these other things and then
biodynamics were able to just take it
that much further into
another realm of relating to and
understanding nature and the natural
systems around us i like that idea of
infusing meaning into farming by adding
these extra aspects like you you mean
you are just farmers right you've got
your you got your you know your these
techniques and those techniques but you
do it in a way
that um
allows room for for spiritual connection
as well
and um and you're right like even even i
you know some of the vocabulary i
struggle with a little bit
because i'm like i don't i don't know
what these words mean
and that doesn't mean that you know i
should
you know reject the ideas just because
some of them feel foreign to me
um you know this is this is merely an
introduction to biodynamics so just
because i don't know the vocabulary
um you know it inspires me to learn more
instead of to you know reject it as as
the other
um one more question before we go to
break where where um
when you're when when you consider your
planning of your farm for the season
um and we'll talk more about the
calendar later but that's not really
what i'm talking about i'm talking like
like do you have um like like multiple
layers of planning for your farm where
your plant you you're planting one layer
which is
the the the germinating the planting and
and
and harvesting of the plants and then
you have a second layer
which is the ritualistic spiritual
practices that you do in in
um in tandem with that um how do you how
do you plan a biodynamic farm when
you're when you
when you also want to make sure
that you have intention because like
like i forget to do important spiritual
practices in my life just because like i
get busy
or maybe i have too much caffeine and
then and then i'm just like i'm i'm just
doing my day it takes it takes effort to
be reminded to do
these these actual extra spiritual
practices that make us feel connected so
so i guess my question to you which i've
kind of backed into
is is how do you go about reminding
yourself to to incorporate the
biodynamics more spiritual practices
when you're also trying to just do the
day-to-day of a farm yeah that's a great
question i think i think that's also why
i feel like you could i kind of see
biodynamics as the icing on the cake of
the farm because you know we do have to
you we have to continue running the farm
and managing the farm and making sure
things are functioning um
i'd say also in a certain sense
those practices and kind of learning
about it
is done in a biodynamic way in that
it often it's it can be a bit
things are kind of structured in a
seasonal way like the preps are made at
different different times of the season
uh different times of the year but then
also like the winter time is a much more
inward slow time where we can kind of
like slow down and be able to do some
reading and do kind of more of that
inward inward work
as opposed to just
this
you know being outside trying to get
everything done
and um
i also just wanted to to touch on what
you were saying about you know kind of
the accessibility of
of the vocabulary and and learning about
biodynamics i wouldn't necessarily
recommend somebody who
knows nothing about
steiner and
anthroposophy to like pick up the
agriculture lectures
uh because it can it's it's not an easy
thing to read and he did give the
lectures to a group of people who
already had kind of like understood
a lot of his other um
uh practices and things so there was a
certain level of like
who he was delivering that to but there
is a really great book
um called culture and horticulture
that's by um
wolf stole is that her story
um it's called culture and agriculture a
philosophy of gardening and
culture and horticulture sorry culture
and horticulture
and it really does an excellent job of
like making the concepts
really simple and understandable to
uh to understand and a really great
introductory book to to biodynamics
fantastic well then uh i will look that
up myself and um and that is that is a
good point that the uh
you know some of these terms of art in
any
advanced discipline is kind of like a
secret language and not to let that be
off-putting so
all right so i think that i and you and
everybody listening is very excited
about learning more about these
spiritually enriched farming practices
so so let's go ahead and go to our first
commercial and we will be right back you
are listening to shaping fire and my
guests today are regenerative cannabis
farmers blair and daniel eau claire
once you've discovered the benefits of
using cannabis it's a very small step to
start making your own edibles gummies
lotions tinctures and concentrated oils
at home
magical butter has been helping cannabis
consumers become self-sufficient for
over a decade with the easy to use
magical butter countertop botanical
extractor you can create high quality
cannabis products to your exact
specifications at a fraction of the cost
of store-bought edibles
i talk a lot on this show about the
importance of home growing so you don't
have to rely on others to feel healthy
well the magical butter machine can
empower your personal health by putting
you in control of how you use cannabis
in your daily life
i've been making my own butters and oils
on the stove for years and i much prefer
the ease of using the magical butter
machine i just set it and walk away
with the simple touch of a button the
magical butter machine grinds heats
stirs and steeps your herbal extract all
at the correct time interval and
temperature for the perfect infusion
every time
as a result you achieve your desired
infusion easily safely and consistently
check out the magical butter instagram
to see the machine in action and don't
feel like you have to go it alone there
is a huge community on facebook called
magical butter users united sharing
recipes and best practices so you can
learn at your own pace from others who
are already doing it successfully
now is the time to get your own magical
butter machine and save money while
enjoying cannabis
use the discount code shaping fire one
word no caps to get 10 off visit
magicalbutter.com today
one of the challenges with buying
autoflower seeds is that often you'll
have as many different phenos as you
will have seeds in a pack
that can be fun sure but so many
varieties in one pack is a sign of an
immature seed line that hasn't been
worked enough
i prefer my autoflowers to be worked
enough that each pheno in the pack
really captures the aspects that the
breeder was intending
this is why i recommend gnome automatics
to my friends and listeners who grow
automatic flowering cannabis seeds
gnome automatic seeds are not just
crossed and released they are
painstakingly sifted again and again
tested in a wide range of conditions and
taken to a level of maturity that each
plant will be recognizable by its traits
traits that were hard earned so that you
can have your best grow cycle ever
gnome automatics became a trusted and
loved brand in cannabis over the last 10
years as mandalorian genetics and
recently changed their name to gnome
automatics
the only thing that has changed is the
name founder dan jimmy continues to pour
his passion of breeding cannabis into
every variety he releases for you to
grow
check out the gnome automatics instagram
at gnome underscore automatics to see
the impressive plants folks are growing
you can score gnome automatic seeds in
feminized or regular at your favorite
seed provider listed in the vendors
section of their website
farms interested in bulk seeds of more
than a thousand should reach out through
the website too
while on the website be sure to check
out the gnome automatics shirts and
other merch section
if you want reliable seeds hand built
from effort expert selection and
experience choose gnome automatics
for decades americans have enjoyed
cannabis flowers and joints and bongs
and bowls
and now with the normalization of
cannabis use increasing across the
country
we have the opportunity to enjoy smoking
cannabis luxuries that simply were not
attainable before
north coast hand rolls blunts cannons
rosin infused donuts and canagars
available in the state of michigan
north coast focuses on flavor over
everything else
instead of growing their own flower
north coast goes out into the
cultivation community and creates
relationships with the best growers
working with the best new cannabis
varieties available
surely heavy thc is a factor but north
coast focuses on aroma complex terpene
profiles and taste that continues
throughout the entire smoking experience
the north coast team curates flowers
like others curate art they seek out the
best talent build relationships helps
them take their product to the highest
levels and then buys their well-cured
flowers in order to hand roll them just
for you
i really like their hand blown glass
tips
and north coast has branched out beyond
canagars into rosin solventless thca
diamonds and exceptional hash rosin
carts for on-the-go cannabis
connoisseurs ii
north coast provides you with attainable
luxury offering you an ultra premium
smoking experience at a price that seems
reasonable and repeatable
to find out more about north coast line
of cannabis products visit their
instagram at northcoast.rolling
that's north coast dot rolling and when
in michigan ask for north coast at your
favorite shop
north coast
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire i am your host shanko los
and my guests today are regenerative
cannabis farmers blair and daniel eau
claire so so let's segue into the
biodynamics calendar because for me this
is this is how i first got turned on to
biodynamics and i gotta admit i didn't
have the most positive response to it
right away i'm like why am i you know
germinating seeds with the moon cycle
and stuff it like you know how i was
brought up um was much more mechanical
farming and um and you know now of
course i understand um the interplay
between nature and and um you know
friends have explained to me small parts
of why we um germinate you know at
certain times of the year which i'm not
going to try to explain because you're
about to um but uh but i'm excited to
get to know more so um you know normally
when we think about you know farming
with the calendar we're thinking about
weather right just like is it you know
when's the last frost and and when does
it get
like the hottest time of the year and
when do we have to be prepared for
drought and and that's all true
but in this idea that you presented
during the first set of of kind of going
beyond the basics of farming to this
embracing of nature being alive there's
this entire biodynamics calendar that
exists that is supposed to guide us um
for for most of the attributes or most
of the actions that we take during
farming so so please dive right into
that and give us an example of working
through a calendar year of of the
biodynamics calendar when it comes to
cannabis
yeah sure so um i think one of the you
know one of the biggest things i think
you really brought up just comparing
like the biodynamic calendar to like
farming with weather like
we can you know we can make those
decisions of how we farm according to
weather because we have legs and we can
walk outside or come inside but you know
plants are very much like weather is
weather all year round they are kind of
like subject to to whatever is going on
and and the same with um
as sort of uh
and beings who are in the ground
um constantly having the world and
the
the earth move
around it and being affected by the
by the planets and the the cosmic beings
in
in our solar system and so the
biodynamic calendar um it originally
wasn't something that steiner did it was
actually created by um a woman maria
tune
and so
um it wasn't indications given by
steiner but she was definitely she was a
a german biodynamic farmer
and she did many experiments and trying
to see sort of like the qualities of
of what the elements of the earth and
how that affects and and the
constellations and the moon and the
planets and how that affects
um plants um so the one of the things
that it does the way that it's sort of
organized in many ways
is by the the constellations
by the zodiac and not in the way that we
kind of look at it in traditional um
sort of astrology where the
constellations are divided evenly into
like 30 degrees
the
the constellations in the biodynamic
calendar are divided by
um kind of their
width and distance that they have
um in the
um
in the year and so they take up
different amounts
of time so
it's not like uh
um
like aries takes up uh
you know a different amount of space
than
than taurus and gemini and so
the basis of how
those things are
are indicated is more
by the lunar cycle
as the moon
is passing through these constellations
within a month
it passes through these constellations
for different amounts of time
and then each of those constellations
are related to an
element fire earth air water
and each of those elements are then
related to
uh different aspects of of the plant and
sort of which part of the plant you are
looking
to cultivate or looking to grow so like
the fire element
is related to
fruit so if you're trying to grow
a tomato you would be looking at the
calendar and seeing
how
or where the moon
is in an element of
of a fire planet or a fire constellation
which would be
aries
leo
and sat and
sagittarius and so
um the same would be so if you're trying
to cultivate a root plant that would be
the earth element and that would be
something like
a radish or a potato or something that
you're trying to cultivate for root and
so you would be looking at like where
the moon is in those constellations
and you know there's not like something
you have to
go in and figure out and discover
there's calendars that are made that you
can purchase
our favorite one is the stella natura
calendar
but you can also get there is a maria
tune
calendar as well
and then the same so for cannabis we
would be looking more at the air
elements
and so that would be because that's
related to flour
and then if you're say growing
lettuce or something or
kale or leafy greens that would be
related to the to the water element
and so
um if you're looking at the calendar
you it would it would tell you
at different times of like the moon it's
usually around like
three two three to four days
um
depending on
the length of and the size of the
constellation as the moon is passing
through it uh would be like okay um you
know on these days
the moon
is passing through
um
let's say so
so for cannabis the moon is passing
through an air sign like gemini
uh
for a couple days you may want to like
that would be the time
that hopefully it would also relate to
that would be the time that you would
start you know that you would want to do
something with the cannabis
that being said that would be i feel
like on the more like strict side of
things that you're constantly trying to
do things
when a certain
uh when the moon is in a certain
constellation reflecting that that
energy
for us as we as we
have practiced things
um
we have found that it's more
in
we look at more of the larger cycles
um as far as like the moon
full moon and
new moon and waxing and waning as far as
how we relate to
to planting and growing
we find that it has it can have a
tendency it was just like
trying to run a farm and trying to do
the daily work of like
managing things and doing stuff that
like
we don't recommend really like trying to
live your life by these planting
calendars i think it um
more than anything it also just like
we've talked about creating
imaginations and visualizations of
things and kind of like looking at
you know the constellations and the
moons and the planets like they do have
an effect on the plants and it kind of
gives a a picture and a guidance to like
that that can have an effect but you're
not gonna like
damage something or
you know or do something like really
uh
really poorly if you're not gonna be
like following the calendar strictly and
so i think it's important always to have
that um
context that
i think that it can feel a little bit
like uh
sometimes i feel like like you're
following a textbook in a way like you
said like it kind of can be a turn off
because it's like oh i got to do this
then or that then and it's kind of like
a bit a bit restrictive and
in my experience and
um
and i think daniel will talk about it
too i feel like it really helps to just
create pictures for this like whole
other level of connection that the that
the plants have to
its environment and to the cosmos that
we can
maybe only
begin
and to imagine or understand and so
um i think for me that's kind of like
the
the planting calendar and
i uh daniel i have both you know
apprenticed on a few different
biodynamic farms and
as far as like rt at least for me my
teachers um one teacher like to say that
there's the tunes and the untunes like
the people who are into maria tunes and
her and her planting calendar and the
ones who don't really uh abide by it and
so
i think as far as like that is usually
the first thing that people are
introduced to in biodynamics and
it's actually not even part of the
demeter certification to plant by the
calendar
um
so yeah that's kind of my summary of it
daniel you have anything to add that was
really awesome um like you were saying
the new moon and full moon cycle is kind
of more what uh we kind of go by i will
say though if there is a day
where everything is just kind of like oh
my god i need some direction like what
should we do it is helpful to say all
right where's the moon right now and
like oh it's a root crop let's go weed
the carrots let's go cultivate like and
it does provide some kind of framework
to work with but um
it seems like the for us the you know
sowing seeds as close to the new moon
as possible um
especially coming into the new moon
definitely not like after the first
quarter like after
when it's waxing but around that time is
great for
seed germination
because it gives the seeds time to get
their radical out get established in the
soil and then by the time the moon is up
and bright the first cotyledons are are
able to absorb that light
and um and that seems to work really
well and then we also use the full moon
as a time
to if if weather permitting to spray the
horn manure preparation because at that
point the full moon
as we know it affects all the water
watery element of the earth and so it's
a
really good time to get that spray
happening in onto the soil so that it
can be utilized at that at that time
and same with transplanting
when the moon is dark it's better for
the seeds to
get put the transplants to get put into
the ground so they can establish their
roots and not be too overstimulated
at night
so at first you know when you were
describing it i was thinking oh
this is this is really much more about
um of the above the ritual of the farm
and to creating a context to give
farming more meaning but then you just
flip the script on me again and you're
like oh well actually
you know when when you germinate is is
related to
um you know the the additional
brightness of the moon and and the i
don't know the swelling of the water
being pulled up you know and then and
then with transplanting you want darker
so it sounds to me like there's actually
a combination of both there is this
there is this kind of like um um
belief framework um
that is connected to the constellations
which for
some farmers it will give the entire
dance of the season more meaning but
also
um
there are very real reasons behind much
of it um
where the the planetary bodies which we
know have effects on earth are actually
going to be influencing our crops
yeah definitely and i think you know
the the
biggest influence the biggest planetary
body that is that the plants are
influenced by is the sun right that's
like the larger kind of like everybody
knows the sun is influencing the plants
and their growth cycle
and then i would say the secondary one
is the moon and that one often i feel
like if you are sort of like really
paying attention and really in tune you
can you can um
you can definitely see
what like a full moon and spring and
you're like all those weeds were like an
inch big and holy moly there how are
they five inches now and we got to get
them out of here something like that
and so those i think those we can also
we can definitely also visually see um
really when you're really paying
attention and then also just
incorporating into like those examples
that that daniel was giving um
and then
um
as far as like as far as like harvest
goes to with cannabis i think it's a bit
more challenging often especially for an
outdoor operation because you're kind of
a bit more subject i feel like at least
where we are to weather
and sort of timing
just trying to to get things in
because it takes such a long time to
harvest and kind of getting everything
in on time and making sure there's not a
frost or a rain we're kind of a bit more
like can't necessarily really follow the
calendar uh in that respect
but then you know the the sort of
the the planetary kind of like
constellation influences
are those much more
imaginative and you could say kind of
clairvoyant aspects that
steiner was really um
you know he didn't develop this but just
in general that kind of philosophy of
those ideas that we can't really yet see
but
but a picture to help understand and
grasp them a little bit more
for folks who are not familiar with the
clairvoyant aspect would you just
explain that a little bit what is what
is this experience of clairvoyance and
how does it relate to biodynamics
clairvoyant i guess is a seer right
someone who
um
can read the script so to speak um
i don't we weren't saying we're
clairvoyant uh but steiner um
certainly was and i guess he
would maybe describe that as like
reading the akashic record um
kind of like the big the big movie reel
in the sky so to speak um but he was
able to
um
that's where all these indications came
from
um
the the speaking of elements as carriers
of spirit or that there's this uh
interaction from the cosmos to the
earthly realm that
um
that permeates all of biodynamics so
am i
what more could like what do we say
about clairvoyance so is that a good
description yeah that works that works
just fine
i like this idea that you said of the uh
you know reading the big movie script in
the sky right it's the idea of of being
aware that there is a storyline to life
and a storyline to the seasons
and be being aware of that instead of
just um
uh being counting and running the farm
as a business so uh yeah i think that
sounds uh like a great description so
let's move on to the individual compost
preparations and um i know that a lot of
the the natural farming people who are
here for the preparations less so much
the the philosophy are probably glad
that we're moving on to this um and and
um you know a lot of people claim to
have fantastic results with both these
individual compost preparations and the
spray preparations that we're going to
be talking about in the third set so um
so
my my general understanding of how these
work is that um
biodynamics believes that you should be
treating your compost piles with
particular preparations of a very um
specific
group of of herbs and and they do they
do it they do a certain job on nutrients
in the pile so so i'm not going to try
to explain it myself since this is not
my specialty
but but why don't you take us down um
the path of these individual compost
preparations um how to make them and and
and what their roles are on the
biodynamic farm yeah so i'll start with
the caveat first instead of going into
details and ending with a caveat at the
end but i just wanted to say that you
know we've been both been practicing
biodynamics for quite a while and this
past year was the first year that we
actually made all the preps on our farm
and we've always done it in in community
in community groups and it's not it's
not an easy thing to do and it's not
like uh
it's not something that's like easily
achievable and um
you know a big reason that we
are at least for me like that i kind of
also
fell in love with this area of northern
california and stuff was uh because of
the
b dank the biodynamic association of
northern california and
the quarterly meetings that would happen
winter spring
summer fall where we would make the
biodynamic preparations together
and then those would be um
kind of uh
taken care of by one of the
practitioners
one of my tea my teacher harold hovind
and then you could buy the biodynamic
preparations from the organization
and there's other places to buy them
also there's a really
strong biodynamic group in oregon
and um i believe there's a strong one in
colorado and there's also
a few on the east coast and so like
in us describing these like i just don't
want to feel like people have to feel
like oh that's too crazy that's too hard
i can't do that i think they're really
made supposed to be done in community
and
and also that you know they they can be
purchased from the pfeiffer center and
and different organizations too that you
don't have to make them on your own
so that's just my first little thing i
wanted to say and then daniel can go
ahead and explain the preps
all right that was really good yeah jpi
josephine porter institute is another
one yeah say that
um
so
the the preps are
discussed in the third lecture
and
in that he
starts off by wanting to talk about
nitrogen and nitrogen's role in farming
and he brings up the what he calls the
four siblings of nitrogen which is
carbon oxygen hydrogen and sulfur
which is what makes up proteins
and
so
like we had said early on wanting to
work with living chemistry like being
able to bring living uh
elements into the farm as opposed to
working with uh synthetically derived
elements
he brings up uh different plants that
have certain relationships to certain
elements
and so starting from a place of
recognizing an active interplay of
spirit and form
uh
spirit manifesting in the earthly realm
on a carbon framework
there's
the elements attach themselves to this
carbon framework in different ways and
so
start wanting to make compost which is a
great thing that can be done on farm
which alleviates a lot of issues with uh
with plant diseases and whatnot by
providing the soil in the in the biome
within the soil food the compost being
food for the microbiome
we want to make certain elements
available to the plants as best we can
and there are people who are creating
more preparations still out of their own
observations but the ones that he
uh starts off with is um
the the preps are the plants that are
used in the preparations are yarrow
chamomile nettle
oak bark
valerian and dandelion
and like blair said this being the first
this past year the first year that we
were able to make the element
the preparations on our farm that's not
to say that we weren't growing all the
prep plants on our farm and i think that
that has been a really good
uh teacher for us and a way of getting
a real good authentic connection to
these plants like we have yarrow growing
everywhere
there's dandelion popping up all over uh
chamomile we continue to make more beds
of chamomile even though they volunteer
every every year um so
growing the plants and living amongst
them and using them for teas and whatnot
to just gain a accustom
to them is a great way to start
but what he's saying here is that by
harvesting these plants and putting them
in a
vessel
and putting them in the earth to uh
to absorb forces and to potentize them
then become medicines that we can put
into our compost pile to enliven the
compost
um and so let we can start with yaro and
these were given numbers when they came
to the new world like i the story that i
am familiar with is that
uh it was said that
the americas would not take these things
seriously if they didn't have a number
attached to them
so i forgive me if i don't know the
numbers off the top of my head um
but to speak about yarrow he says that
the you know the nature spirits reach
the highest the the height of perfection
in their use of sulfur
with with yarrow
and
so
there's the carbon framework
that
the plants are composed of and then you
have these elements that attach to them
in different degrees
so
the yarrow being put into the bladder of
a deer
you enhance its inherent ability to
combine sulfur with other substances and
sulfur being a a really important part
of plant health
um
chamomile
is uh also has homeopathic amounts of
sulfur uh but it works on calcium
in addition to potash so that that is
also a way of keeping plants healthy
chamomile goes into intestines um
so the way the vessels were chosen
uh is very interesting um
antlers are different than horns
uh when we talk about the horns of a cow
which the um
i'm getting off topic a little bit but
the horn manure preparation we see the
manure going into a horn because the
horns are a way of reflecting energy
back into the animal whereas antlers on
a deer
have more of an outstreaming force and
there's a relate relationship to
nitrogen there and surrounding
areas
that has a relationship to the bladder
the nitrogen being a very present uh
component of urine
he even says that a bladder is the is a
perfect
uh
description or an image of the cosmos
but yarrow being put into a bladder uh
gets hung
in a sunny spot all summer
before getting buried into the
uh the earth over the winter
uh camomile has a relationship to
intestines and we know this from just
how chamomile tea is great for
um digestion
nettle is one that does not have a
uh
nettle does not have a vessel although
some
people
are experimenting with
um putting it in the
um what's the sheath of the heart um
the pericardium
so nettle being the greatest benefactor
of plant growth it it too contains
sulfur uh assimilates and incorporates
um
a sulfur which assimilates and
incorporates the spirit but currents of
potash and calcium are also present in
uh nettle iron
is the one that we're after with uh the
nettle preparation
this one gets buried a whole year and it
is
infusing intelligence for the soil
now
in order to
for wanting health on the farm
we need to
have a very broad view of
interrelationships
and calcium is a great medium
for
making those relationships
you can almost never have too much
calcium
in your soils
the oak bark is one that
is put into
the
skull of a domestic animal
and
again this is like very important that
we are choosing
um in a situation like this we wouldn't
want to use lime we want to use calcium
from
a living
source
um
oak bark being
a a material very high in calcium
moving on to
the the
the dandelion preparation
this is like the language that he uses
is is really beautiful um i would
encourage people to
to
try to read the lectures
um dandelion is said to be a messenger
from heaven
that mediates the homeopathic
distribution of silica and the cosmos
the dandelion goes into the mesentery
which is the
um
what the intestines are encased in in
the animal
and
you know i don't really claim to
understand all of this stuff i guess let
me just say here that
working with the preparations
is a great practice of keeping your mind
in a in a question like having more
questions than answers
and
and i've said this before but like when
you think you know all the answers to
something that's a very dangerous place
to be in um because there's a lot of
different elements involved so when we
work with these things
i'm constantly wondering what we're
doing
but that's a really great place to be as
you can receive kind of insights that
you wouldn't expect
silica
is a very important
element
in
in our practice
and dandelion has a great relation to
silicic acid
and
is
said to be able to attract silicic acid
from the atmosphere and make available
to the plants
lastly valerian is one that
doesn't does not get a vessel does not
get buried but his crush is pressed
valerian flowers which has a
a great way of stimulating phosphorus
and so
once these preparations are made and
they've gone through the proper
um burial and process they get added to
the compost pile and
the
if we the more we work with compost and
the layering of plant materials from our
farm manures straw bedding leaves
gathering uh seaweeds putting all these
things together you're creating a raised
um
you're you're creating a almost a living
being so to speak
and you're forming chaos
within that compost pile there's gonna
it's going to heat up things break down
it becomes
micro biologically alive
adding these preparations is said to
help to
almost act as antenna
to help bring form
to the chaos
chaos is
a word for potential it you know it's
not a bad word
when things are in a state of chaos they
are open to influence especially cosmic
influence and adding these preparations
is a way of helping to guide the prep
the compost pile to a healthy
decomposition
and bringing
the different elements that we need for
healthy plant growth and soil biology
to interact with each other
so um each of these preparations sound
like they take quite a long time um uh
even even the unvesseled ones sound like
it can be time consuming is is the idea
generally that you would make
these compost preparations this year to
apply to next year's compost piles or or
is it not does it not really take as
much time as it sounds and you can
actually use them same year
no that is correct the it's the work
that you do one year is for the benefit
of next year
and some of them take longer than
than others like um some take a whole a
full year
whereas others are just buried over the
the winter
and so it is said
that the earth is the most alive in the
winter time
and that can seem backwards but
it's an in-breath
that's happening
um the crystal crystalline forces are
are happening inside the earth at that
time and it is kind of said that in the
summertime the earth is dreaming
in plants like the sun is actually
putting the earth to sleep and it is
dreaming in plant life it is
like it it has to like the seeds have to
germinate they have to
um whereas in the winter time the earth
is within itself and it gets a little
complex with northern hemisphere
southern hemisphere that is discussed in
some lecture other lectures from the
agriculture course but
um
and it should be said too that the
amounts that are used in the compost
pile is very minute it almost can
sometimes seem like it's you're not even
like how can this little bit of
preparation make a difference in this
compost pile so you it is possible
for the if you make
um you can make more than one year's
worth
uh in the fall does that make sense for
sure so you're gonna you're gonna make
them for this year but you're gonna make
enough not only for yourself for the
next few years but also to share because
i get that whole community vibe trying
to do all let's see one two three four
five six of those
um
all by yourself on your same farm with
like that sounds like very time
consuming but if you've got a bunch of
farms that are doing this um everybody
can make them one season and then and
then share them um at the grange hall or
wherever and then um then everybody's
got enough to last them a few years so
that that makes sense both on a um you
know a nutrition stabilization uh level
for the compost pile but also for the i
don't know the spiritual everything that
was alive in our community connecting of
humans and families also
for sure it's it also happens like very
close to harvest time so it can be like
very inconvenient to make to have to
make the preparations and you need a cow
so not very many people have a cow to
butcher an expendable cow
oh yeah i can i can imagine the um the
the the biodynamic supply store it gets
pretty weird sometimes
so so let's go ahead and take our uh
let's go ahead and take our second
commercial and we'll be right back you
are listening to shaping fire and my
guests today are regenerative cannabis
farmers blair and daniel el claire we'll
be right back
for years organic cultivators have been
looking for a peat moss replacement peat
moss has long been the go-to soil
amendment for water retention and
container growing but organic growers
are recognizing now that peat moss is an
unsustainable resource and the mining of
peat bogs destroys wetland habitats and
releases sequestered carbon but peat
moss works so well that many have
continued to use it
now there is finally a revolutionary
replacement for peat moss that provides
better benefits while being a
sustainable choice
pit moss sounds and axe like peat moss
but instead of being mined from fragile
ecosystems is actually made from
upcycled organic paper and cardboard
headed for landfills
pit moss is excellent at retaining water
in your substrate and creating air
pockets and tiny living environments for
microbes pit moss instantly increases
aeration nutrient absorption and water
conservation too
carefully and locally sourced pit moss
is the result of decades-long research
into the use of recycled paper fibers
pit moss is lightweight and easy to use
and pin moss is inert so it won't change
your ph
available in a range of preparations
including a nutrient enhanced blend and
an organic soil conditioner with no
added nutrients
pitt moss is also available as an animal
bedding for horses chickens and small
animals
you can save 15 percent with the
discount code shaping fire one word no
caps when shopping on pitmoss.com so go
to pittmoss.com now to learn more that's
p i t t
m o s s
com
growing healthier stronger more
sustainable plants
pitt moss
as cannabis regulations become more
demanding and consumers become more
educated it is increasingly important to
avoid the use of chemical pesticides
when cultivating cannabis
beneficial insects have been used for
decades by the greenhouse vegetable and
ornamental plant industry and today many
cannabis cultivators are moving from
sprays and chemicals to beneficial
insects
covert has the beneficial insects mites
and nematodes microbials sticky cards
and air distribution units you need to
partner with nature to defend your
garden
whether you manage acres of canopy or
have a simple grow tent in your home
cobra is ready to help answer your
questions and help you transition away
from chemical sprays towards clean and
natural solutions
since 1967 culprit has assisted growers
in identifying pests and devising
reliable solutions while providing
healthy insects and mites that will
protect your yield
since the 1990s cobot has been a leader
in cannabis pest and disease control
worldwide and have highly trained
consultants to assist you in canada and
the united states from coast to coast
with their global network of grower
support covert can help
visit copert.com choose your country and
get detailed information that's covert
k-o-p-p-e-r-t
dot com
for the most up-to-date cannabis related
biological control information you can
also check their instagram at covert
canada
you know getting away from pesticides is
good for health and good for business
and culprit is ready to help visit
cobert.com today
one of the reasons why no-till cannabis
growing is so valued by farmers is
because the mycelium networks in the
soil remain established from year to
year
and we know these fungal networks are
essential because they are the nutrient
super highways that extend far and wide
in the substrate to feed your plants
the trouble with growing in new living
soils or blended cocoa substrates is
that it takes most of the plant's life
just to create these mycelium highways
dinomyco endomycorrhizal fungi inoculant
reduces that time and gets your plant
eating a wider array of nutrients faster
and it's three times the concentration
of the other popular brand in the us at
900 propagules per gram of two fungal
species selected specifically for
cannabis cultivation dynomica is the
result of 30 years of research and
trials at the volcani agriculture
research institute in israel it has also
been vigorously trialled by cannabis and
food growers across the u.s
dinomyco is now available at grow shops
and on amazon in the united states i
love using dynamico to both speed up the
growth of the mycelium networks in the
soil but also as a biostimulant to make
clone cuttings more virile you can see
side by side showing the comparative
growth on their instagram at dinomyco
if you demand reliable growing results
and appreciate the importance of an
active root zone in creating a thriving
plant i encourage you to check out
dinomyco.com and use the store locator
to find out where you can get yours
that's d-y-n-o-m-y-c-o
dot com
shaping fire listeners can get ten
percent off any size of dynamico on
amazon or
dynamico.com by using the discount code
shaping fire one word no cabs
whether you are starting with new beds
or pots or if you want to add some zing
to tired soil choose dinomyco to
maximize your plant's potential
dinomyco endomycorrhizal inoculant
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire i am your host shango los
and my guests today are regenerative
cannabis farmers blair and daniel eau
claire all right so the big finish here
with set three we're getting to the part
um that is probably uh almost as popular
as the biodynamics calendar when people
talk about biodynamics and that is these
uh these spray preparations and we're
gonna start specifically the one that
people talk about the most which is the
the horn manure and the horn silica
spray preparations and um you know this
was the number one thing that i heard
people talking about about um at uh
emerald cup two i guess it's probably
three years ago now um in the
regenerative area the horn manure
preparation demonstration is like i
probably heard about that for like an
entire year afterwards people talking
about how interesting and engaged and
how like they're like oh my god there's
so many more aspects to learn and so i'm
excited about learning this myself
because i actually missed that
presentation so let's start with that if
you would please explain the the horn uh
preparations um and and and how to do
them sure thing well that's very
interesting to hear i think that would
have been um us that was there given
that presentation
and um
the
the horn manure preparation is really
one of the most fun
uh aspects of
of biodynamics for me i feel like and
it's a really great way of engaging with
your land
um
in
in this thought uh in the way
biodynamics is presented and the way we
start to visualize
the farm like
it's um
we have to understand that the
um
the plants that we see on the earth are
said to originate in the farthest
reaches of the cosmos
the plants only exist because of the
earthly realm
and they are
a mirror so to speak like plants
the archetype of the plant is radiating
out from this from the distant cosmos
and manifesting on the earth being
reflected back
and so if you think of the
that gives us a periphery
and center
image
and we want the plants to be able to
fully express themselves and
and engage with the earth and be
earthbound as best they can
so
a way of doing that
and of enlivening the soil to allow for
that connection to take place
there is a field spray that is done
throughout the spring and in the
uh wet part of the year where there can
be a
the water allowing for
the soil to receive the spray
but you're taking the manure from
a cow
and putting it into the horn of a cow
and that image
if your imagination will allow you
paints a picture of
opposite ends
coming together
you have form
on the on the one side of the with the
horn
and you have formlessness
the manure from the other end being
brought together
then that is put into the earth
over the winter time
to absorb the the forces streaming down
into the earth from the cosmos
throughout the winter
and all the activity that's happening
under the ground
so that way of taking
two opposing ends and bringing them
together
is a reflection of
the opposing
periphery and center
of the archetype of the plant and the
earth at the at the center
so
this preparation then
being unearthed
from the ground
is you'll see it teeming with um with
michael reizel
and
it's it comes out uh if done long enough
or you know buried at the right depth it
comes out smelling delicious and is a
very
um
earthy smell crumbly uh
you know
you can tell that it's potentized that
it was it's gone on it's gone through a
change
uh this also being used in a homeopathic
dose
is then put into water
it's like a tablespoon
for like five gallons or so it's it's
not very much
um we tend to put a little bit more in
ours because we feel like the land
needed it
needs it
but this this then goes through a
stirring process
um
and this this is something that will
become individual for each person but it
feels like an hour is a good amount of
time
you add this
preparation into preferably rain water
and it is stirred in one direction
to form a a
um an organized vortex
for a minute and then that is
thrust back on itself and stirred in the
opposite direction also for a minute
and then this process is repeated like i
said for about an hour
and in this process you will find
a change in the water
um one of more like organization at
first
it
it splashes a lot you're gonna get
splashed in the face and
um
and it's it's not as organized as you
begin to do it the water seems to take
on
a more
um organized component it's sometimes
referred to as the fifth phase of water
this is then sprayed over the fields
like over your cultivated areas and even
beyond
uh in very minute doses i like to refer
to it as micro dosing
your your land
uh this is done in the early mornings
you want to be out there i'm sorry this
is done in the evening
so that it is given time
to
uh you you don't want it to evaporate
you want to get it onto the land and
then be have time to be absorbed
uh and this is something that should be
done on uh repeated
um intervals and and that kind of that
process is somewhat i would say up to
you
yeah but stick with it if you're
you want to do it um
after a rain uh like i said before when
it's wet
um you can you want to utilize the full
moon
because the full moon like we said
before has a uh obvious effect on all
the watery elements of the earth and it
is it it can also help to propel
what you are doing further
uh like you're spraying minute doses on
the land but then that full moon
activating the water is being able to
penetrate more deeply and with repeat
sprays um you you know the benefits are
what steiner says is
and it seemed to suggest that he was
aware of what mycelium was doing before
mycelium was as
um studied as it was but he says this
will help bring in elements from beyond
the cultivated space it brings in
elements
being that everything is connected under
the ground you're bringing in elements
from your your woods from your fields
from
um
where the animals are grazing so
it's the horn manure preparation is
helping bring the periphery down to the
earth and allowing the plants to be
to receive that
radiation that's coming to them from the
archetype in the cosmos
the cosmos not just being a place of
stars and comets but the the home of
spiritual beings
so that is a gravitational pull that you
are providing the plant with the horn
manure the horn silica
is the
counterpart to
the
the gravitational pull and it would be
the levitational pole
so this is finely ground quartz crystal
that is made in the spring
and is buried throughout the summer
and winter
dug up in the fall
so this spray is then
what you
use to help the plant achieve its its
ripening to allow it to
uh go through its fruit-forming process
it's flower-forming process that you
want it's helping to allow
what you are growing
ripen in time and
achieve
the the health that it is
uh capable of getting so you are as well
spraying uh using minute doses
of finely ground quartz crystal in water
going through the same stirring process
as you did for the horn manure
and then
spraying this onto your plants in the
early morning before sunrise or just at
sunrise in that dawn time
and it is helpful to use a backpack
sprayer
for this one when you apply the horn
manure
we use a combination of different things
like little uh handheld brooms or
cedar branches tied together and you're
kind of just flinging the water all over
the place i don't really like
putting that mixture through a sprayer
just because of the the pressure that
the
water goes through through the handle
and through the whole process
that doesn't feel as natural as just
kind of flinging it from a bucket with a
with some cedar branches
but the the quartz
spray the
the horn silica
is much more conducive to being sprayed
through a backpack sprayer and you're
trying to
cover you want to
kind of feel like fill in the aura of
the plant you're spraying above it
you're and you can see it you're just
kind of misting and then falling and
mixing with the dew that's on the plants
um
and as the sun's coming it's a really
beautiful fun
uh process to to go through and so the
horn manure you're spraying at the time
in the spring to help get the roots
established the quartz the horn silica
you're spraying in the early summer
whenever
whatever you're growing once you start
to see the ripening fruits of what
you're doing you want to start spraying
the quartz the horn silica then so
we often start our spray for the
cannabis at the end of july beginning of
august that's what we have found is when
anthesis begins on the plants and so
from that point on we're spraying
uh you know every other week or like
three to four times throughout the the
ripening season
um what have i missed i was just gonna
mention a little bit like why the cow
horn
and i think in general in biodynamics
cow horns are really important like um
in certification you're not allowed to
have cows without horns and
unfortunately it's uh you know it's a
common practice to remove horns from
cows
and the cows horns are extremely
important for the cows their sinuses
actually go up into the horns
and um
in there is part of
the cow just in general is this very
sort of meditative
very focused on digestive animal when
you see it it ruminates you know that's
where that whole word comes from it eats
its food but then after it does that
it'll then sit down and start ruminating
and it'll actually has four you know the
cow has four chambers a four chamber
stomach and that
food that it eats gets moved around into
these four chambers actually comes back
into the mouth
after it's been eaten they continue to
chew it and then goes back down
and all this process that happens within
the stomach
and uh
that sort of like the flavors and the
taste and the digestion gets circulated
within the horns too and it's kind of
said that the horns have
a bit
of like the cow is kind of like the guru
of the meditative guru of the
of the animal world and it has sort of
this connection the horns to to the
cosmos the the horns and the
hooves kind of contain
are kind of the two ends of the of the
animal that kind of contains this
digestive process and has much more of
that um
solid sort of formative process
and you know like uh
pyramids and cones and that sort of
thing kind of have this very
uh
kind of formative condensing
shape as far as
um they're
what they look like and so putting
manure into the into this vessel
really creates that sort of um kind of
what we're talking about when you're
stirring kind of going from this chaos
this like very
loose substance manure and putting it
into this highly highly formed
uh
very
uh complex thing that is that is the cow
horn
and then you're also
on top of a layer that goes on top of
that is as you're stirring
you are able to imbue
your own forces into the mixture like
it's very important to be aware of your
thoughts
as you're doing that um
and it's amazing to see how your
thoughts can travel
within that hour but having an intention
that you bring into what you're doing uh
is
i i we feel is definitely felt
and i think that like two these
preparations can be purchased um from
different biodynamic groups and um
or the josephine porter institute
and um i think that that's almost
in a way more important than making them
is super important but it's not
something you have to do but it i think
i'm so glad daniel brought that up
because it really is this
meditative process that happens within
the stirring and
i think just in general in biodynamics
your intention and your footprints and
your presence on the land is so
important and i think that that that
spraying these preparations give you
gives you a moment to pause and to
focus more
on our sort of like mental intentional
ways that we are uh working with the
land and part of me as we're as we're
talking about this i'm trying to think
about what people might be thinking
about this and i will bring up and and
just be honest that
it was difficult
to and still somewhat is it's something
that i think about a lot like
how is it that we are taking
this crystal from the earth and smashing
it up smashing it to pieces
and then spraying it on our fields like
there's an extractive element to that
and uh steiner
says that by doing this we are freeing
up
elemental beings
that
the crystals are home of elemental
beings they're an impression that the
earth has felt over time
that we are then able to release and
this takes us down a really
long
rabbit hole of how
what is going on with the mineralization
of the earth and how we're transforming
the mineral element of the earth
the mineral realm is being transformed
and
not always with the best of intentions
um
but it is one to meditate on like how
this fits into to that
and i will just say that it feels
i i have come to peace with it a bit
when this process is done
in a way that we hope is serving
nature and the ecology that surrounds us
because there is a
destructive element it feels like that
you're taking a quartz crystal really
beautiful
uh symmetrical divinely shaped thing and
then
smashing it into pieces where the
surface area is larger than
the
the whole of the plant we there's a
mentor that we
um
uh
engaged with uh who gave an imp uh
demonstration of the
of quartz crystal showing how he held
the courts and dropped it into his hand
there's the gravity pull and then he
crushed this thing up to a point it was
in his hand he just blew on it and it
just
lifted up into the air in this uh way of
demonstrating levity and so i just want
to say that there is a um
tension
that kind of exists in in the horn uh
silica prep
because manure is very available you
know uh feed your cow and you'll get
something out of it but the harvesting
of quartz crystal is something that is a
bit more
uh of a of a stretch so i just wanted to
to bring that up right on
so um you know
so much of this
preparation i mean i recognize parts of
it
um
as foliar prep right just like things
that i i have done many times
in different recipes
but then there is then there are these
additions that are you know
stir it
you know
in in in clockwise for
um you know x amount of time and then
and then and then immediately just stir
it the other way and so so that you're
getting some of that chaos and then it
and then it reorganizes itself and
and it's interesting because there
really is a blending of
organic practices that i recognize that
i'm like oh i've done something that
like that before
and then there and then and then
suddenly you're talking about how
the the horn manure prep
is is an illustration of the beginning
and the ending and completion of nature
because since the horn is on the head of
the cow and the
and the manure comes out the back end
and i'm like oh my gosh i thought i was
in the i was you know for a second there
i thought i was in the realm of of
scientific preparations that i know and
then now now suddenly i'm in the
dreaming you know and i'm and i'm and
i'm and i'm i'm doing a
an imaginative energetic preparation
that is causing me to
sit down and reflect and get manure on
me and think about how it's not dirty
like suddenly it gets like really big
a a prep that sounds like something that
i want to do
to have my cannabis plants um grow and
my farm to be abundant and healthy has
suddenly turned into
you know personal mysticism and personal
growth and i'm like oh my god there's so
much here
and it kind of makes biodynamics like i
don't know i i guess um i'll say a bit
slippery and not in any disrespectful
way it's kind of like biodynamics is
is kind of different for everybody where
where
you learn biodynamics
and and it's in this this it's
collection of philosophies and
preparations
and then after that it's given to you
and then each farmer will make it their
own based on their
personal life experience and like i dare
say what the farm tells them and if i
would you know if i would to say that to
most groups of cannabis people
i think that um i would get some eye
rolls but hearing you talk about it
um
you know it sounds it sounds less like
an eye roll and more
like a
like a spiritual practice that has
meaning to each individual people but
maybe not in the same way to a group
and um and
and that's i you know i find that to be
a rare thing in cannabis right and um
and what so so what are your thoughts on
that being as much of a spiritual
practice as it is you know fertilizer uh
well
we ask a lot of our of the land
um
it's i it doesn't feel comfortable for
me to
to expect the land to continue to
provide
without any sort of
uh recapitulation
and ever since learning about these
ideas and these practices it hasn't felt
right for me to not do them
um
the land
provides it's abundant and it um
but
it needs to be have something given back
and if this in this is a small part of
that but it does feel very important and
it is very much a spiritual um
practice
um
one that helps to connect us to the land
us to the plants
um
dare i say the cosmos
and
um
and i think uh i
kind of somewhat of a famous quote from
steiner is that
you can never have a spirit without
matter or matter without spirit and so i
think that kind of sums up where where
he's coming from and that
we can't ignore the
the unseen but
i think try to recognize and and embrace
things that we can feel
yeah i like that idea things that we can
feel you
something that i just wanted to tag onto
that when we were talking about the
preparations um i failed to to bring
nitrogen back into the the situ
the equation we talked about the other
siblings carbon oxygen hydrogen and
sulfur but nitrogen never came back up
and i was just reminded of it because
he says that
farmers should meditate
and it's very important for them to do
so
but when
but be aware of actually what we are
doing when we meditate and he says that
we're we are growing into an experience
of the nitrogen that surrounds you
because we think of nitrogen as
something that you need to feed to your
plants in order for them to grow but the
nitrogen is there what he says
as a way of
of
allowing the other elements to work
through the plant
and so when we sit down and meditate we
are growing into
the nitrogen in the atmosphere which
there is a lot of
and then that is where we are able to
get impressions from the farm and from
the land that we might not have had we
not taken the time to to do that and
stirring 500 is a great uh meditation
meditative practice
um
and so
yep that's that's what i wanted to bring
to that right on so you know i'm sure
there are people that are listening
who are considering the the spiritual
aspects but then they they also actually
want to do these preps and
um so much of what we're doing in in
regenerative and natural farming right
now are you know you know variety of
preps and fermentations you know a lot
of them coming from
korean natural farming how how does
how do these preps play with the others
you know from what i'm hearing from them
it actually sounds like they're all in
the same gang and and all these
different preps can work together with
the the other um natural farming preps
that that we might be more familiar with
but but i bet i better ask because there
might be some part of the the spiritual
structure that makes that um not as
applicable so so how do these preps
interact you know and play nice with
other natural farming techniques i i
think they play great with each other um
i think that it's you know it's all i i
feel like um we don't practice very much
korean natural farming but we do we do
do some other fermentations
um with plants and stuff and so
i i don't think you should like i would
never say you should do one or the other
i don't believe that at all and i think
that
it's important to grasp on all different
kinds of
of of agriculture and i think it's
it i think things go wrong when you
start to
think you should only be farming a
certain way and that i think it's
important to gather from
all different types of of practices and
and utilize the ones that feel good good
to you and you know that's you're you're
creating your farm individual
individuality and
and creating the systems that work
best for you
right on so the horn manure is a way of
um it's almost like a
imo collecting collection oh yeah this
is it is kind of like an imo for sure
yeah
yeah so so there a lot of them are are
sharing a lot of the same you know
overall strategies even though the form
and certainly in this case the the
spiritual
intent
is is certainly more involved and so to
kind of you know finish up this show
with that you know i guess spiritual
intent vibe um you know when i when i
when i talked to y'all before
our recording and and
and and read some of the steiner stuff
everything seems to be very
future focused there seems to be a real
awareness of
of inertia and that you know we we know
we're going to end up in the future and
so let's try to do something now so the
future is better so um would you both
take us out with a couple words on this
idea of biodynamics as a vehicle towards
the future because honestly we just
don't we don't get a lot of that in a
lot of the other um
farming traditions for sure and
thank you for asking it
what really attracted me to biodynamics
is that it does speak to us in a way
that i had not found in other literature
and other
philosophies
and
when when we speak of the earth as a as
a living being uh that
that's something that can just kind of
get said and then we move on to the next
thing
but um
through
familiarizing ourselves with steiner's
work
he is
very much
wanting to drive home that we are living
on a
highly developed spiritual being
and
the we are
locked into this
um
direction towards the future
of which we need
we're here to learn lessons of how to
make that future happen
and the plants are one of our first
teachers in doing so
and so
when we work with the land when we work
with these imaginations that we find
the imaginations that give us the ideas
of making these preparations of putting
these herbs into these vessels when we
work with these ideas at first they can
seem far out
and they are
but they start to bring up feelings
that
that teach us lessons of of of where
we're going um
the
and what is that what is the lessons
that the plants are trying to teach us
and what is being said is
that when we learn to
to um
when we learn to coexist with each other
the way plants coexist with each other
we will be in a place
receptive to feel the love that we can
freely give
back to the creator
and so
when we observe the way plants of
different species grow next to each
other and seem to
be good companions for each other we
think of what's happening under the soil
with the roots we think of the
communication that's going on
we feel
we see that there is this
idea that one cannot be happy if the
other is not happy
and we learn how plants are able to
help bring in
uh nutrients from afar if if someone if
a different plant needs it we see this
communication that is done out of the
um
freely given like a
a gift economy so to speak right like we
do this as a way as an offering
and um i believe that very
wholeheartedly that
when we engage with the land when we're
farming we are not just farming to
um create like substance for us to eat
we are
beautifying the surroundings that our
senses will gain nourishment just as
much as we gain fuel
uh
to to exist um we need to eat but we
also need to absorb beauty and kindness
and biodynamics
is what awoke me to these ideas
in these imaginations
and it goes on from there then once we
uh
exit the um the plant realm we attain
the animal
consciousness where we learn to feel
into the other being
and then we move on to only will we be
truly human when we are able to
understand the ego of another
um as we understand our own and it gets
uh it goes on from there but um i do
believe what biodynamics has to offer
beyond
other philosophies is this
larger picture that we're dealing with
things more than just elements more than
just nutrients we're dealing with
transformation
metamorphosis
and growth
uh that will bring us into the next
stages of of spiritual
um
spiritual development and the next
evolution of the earth that we are all
caught up in well certainly um i think
that all of us who are regenerative
farmers and and i don't know probably
the
the all of us who who participate in the
very soul of the cannabis plant
would share this idea of um
you know
embracing
the interaction with spirit and with
nature now and expressing our love in
ways that
i don't know nurture and bless the
future
and
whether no matter the words that we use
to express that idea
um it can only be good and and i'm
grateful that that biodynamics as uh you
know as a as a farming philosophy and
and as i'm learning is more of a
more of a life philosophy as much as a
farming philosophy um
you know it's nice to have some of that
importance
injected into our
farming
in a day and age where there are so many
pressures to encourage
farmers to look at their farm as
commodities
and uh and as and as purely as a
food dispensing device so
so with that i think that uh we will
wrap up for today um thank you so much
to both of you for sharing um your time
and
your experience but but in this
particular show
thank you very much for
i don't know um
letting the you know pulling aside the
veil and sharing some of the aspects of
of this you know biodynamic spirituality
in your farming which as you said
is not necessarily invited everywhere
all the time that you talk about farming
so so thank you for
for being vulnerable that's that's
that's the feeling i'm going for thank
you for your vulnerability and sharing
with us um that your heart behind um
your farm uh processes thanks so much
for having us it's a pleasure to talk to
you and uh
really appreciate what you're able to
share on your show and
and uh yeah i really appreciate what you
do yeah thank you shango um it's been a
pleasure speaking with you and i really
uh felt comfortable and
it seems i feel like you're a very
important voice in the regenerative
cannabis community so i appreciate all
you do
and uh appreciate you taking the time to
invite us on here today right on thank
you both so much
so dear listener if um if you want to
learn more about um biodynamic growing
but
even more so
how these ideals can be expressed um in
your own cannabis cultivation i
encourage you to follow the radical
herbs
uh instagram and as i mentioned in the
introduction that's radical with a with
not necessarily the spelling that you
would uh expect so it's radical like uh
like the tap root radical so it's r a d
i c
l e
herbs h e r b s so it's radical herbs on
instagram and you can follow along with
uh blair and daniel uh on their farm and
um and and and see examples and also see
their fantastic herb that comes out of
the farm um if you want to find out more
about the farm itself
their website is also delightful and has
got information and that is also at
radicalerbs.com
you can find more episodes of the
shaping fire podcast and subscribe to
the show at shapingfire.com and wherever
you get your podcasts if you enjoyed the
show we'd really appreciate it if you
leave a positive review of the podcast
wherever you download your review will
help others find the show so they can
enjoy it too on the shaping fire website
you can also subscribe to the newsletter
for insights into the latest cannabis
news exclusive videos and giveaways on
the shaping fire website you also find
transcripts of today's podcast as well
be sure to follow on instagram for all
original content not found on the
podcast that's at shaping fire and at
changolos on instagram be sure to check
out shaping fire youtube channel for
exclusive interviews farm tours and
cannabis lectures
does your company want to reach our
national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hotspot at
shippingfire.com to find out how thanks
for listening to shaping fire i've been
your host shango los
[Music]
you