[Music]
know your dealer has been a drug culture
safety standard forever
as cannabis migrates towards whatever
potential legalization the future holds
one of the few but important advantages
of the licensed cannabis market is the
availability of analytics
it is very helpful to know which
cannabinoids are dominant in cannabis
products how potent they are what
terpenes are present and that they are
devoid of dangerous pesticides molds and
heavy metals
this is a modern equivalent of know your
dealer
we could do a whole episode on gaming
cannabis analytics to cheat but on the
whole having cannabis analytics
available to us is an important modern
win for cannabis patients and
enthusiasts alike
psychedelic mushrooms are following in
the footsteps of cannabis in so many
ways and because cannabis has already
laid the groundwork for mushroom
legalization many states are rushing to
develop legal frameworks healthcare
standards and manufacturing rules
similarly we have begun to recognize the
importance of analytical labs for
mushrooms too
all mushrooms are not created equal and
as patients enthusiasts and product
developers all have increased access to
psilocybin mushrooms the importance of
knowing what we are ingesting becomes
hugely important
if you want to learn about cannabis
health cultivation and technique
efficiently and with good cheer i
encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter we'll send you new podcast
episodes as they come out delivered
right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week and
videos too don't rely on social media to
let you know when a new episode is
published sign up for the updates to
make sure you don't miss an episode also
we're giving away very cool prizes to
folks who are signed up to receive the
newsletter there's nothing else you need
to do to win except receive that
newsletter so go to shapingfire.com to
sign up for the newsletter and be
entered into this month's and all future
newsletter prize drawings
you are listening to shaping fire and
i'm your host shango lowes
my guest today is dr george selhorn
george selhorn ph.d is founder and
principal scientist at flourish labs in
portland oregon flourish is one of the
first labs in the u.s to provide
analysis of psilocybin mushrooms
he has also been lab director at rose
city labs a cannabis and environmental
analytics lab
george has 22 years of experience with
liquid chromatography both preparative
and analytical
he's worked in hiv vaccine development
as well as cancer and autoimmune
disorder drug development his phd in
molecular plant sciences with an
emphasis in biochemistry is from
washington state university
on today's episode we're going to get up
to speed on psilocybin analytical labs
because they are about to become
incredibly relevant just like cannabis
labs have
during set one we will look closely at
the components of mushrooms and get a
better understanding of what we are
looking for specifically during the
second set we will talk about prevention
of bad actors gaming the system and
trying to cheat like folks do in
cannabis labs along with some of the
mechanics of mushroom sampling and
during this third set we're going to
talk about mushroom storage at home and
specific varieties of potent mushrooms
welcome to shaping fire george
thank you very much shango i'm super
excited to be here right on well thank
you for bringing your um your rare skill
set to us because we're excited to talk
about it so
you know by now most of us understand
that with cannabis analytics we are
looking for potency of a range of
cannabinoids and terpenes to help us
understand the potency of our flower
and what we're curious to start with is
what are the constituents
of psilocybin mushrooms that we want to
measure
uh yeah there it is very similar we are
looking at a potency measure when we're
looking at the biomass of mushrooms or
an extract for example
there are alkaloids in mushrooms in the
psilocybin mushrooms that are our target
as opposed to cannabinoids and
terpenoids in cannabis and there are
five primary ones there's two that most
people know about which are silicen and
psilocybin
and then there's three additional ones
norcilisin baocystein and norbiocysteine
these are the five primary ones that
people look for there's also an
additional sixth analyte called
arginasine which can also be found in
the psilocybin mushrooms and that's
actually
so six total but five that people mostly
look at and then i have a feeling people
are going to be more interested in
organizing going forward i've heard a
couple people talk about
a hypothesis that they think that might
be
responsible for some of the the
wood lover mushroom issues like there's
uh you know toxins from wood lover
mushrooms that can make people sick so
and that's actually a pretty good segue
into why
we're doing this you know the main
reason is safety that's why i'm
interested in doing this is these
molecules are quite powerful and have
the ability to influence the way people
think quite substantially so
with this being introduced to a whole
new group of people with the
legalization of psilocybin in oregon
we want to make sure people are safe
so these other metabolites um you know i
feel actually quite rookie about this
because you know i'm familiar with
salosine and psilocybin but the other uh
what four that you mentioned like i've
never heard of any of them um you
mentioned one of them that um you know
it can be toxic so i'm guessing that
said that
i don't know for sure but i've heard a
couple people
you know mention that they think that
might be involved so yeah i don't know
for sure okay cool thank you for the
question
i don't want to put words in your mouth
for sure there's a lot of unknowns here
in this industry and in this in this
topic you know it's been in the dark for
so long being a schedule one substance
that people weren't allowed to do this
research for a fair a very long time but
thanks to you know organizations like
maps and people like rick doblin they've
opened up the ability for us to start
looking at these things again which
actually happened way back in the 60s so
so these these other constituents are
other than uh
soloson and psilocybin are those for all
things that you that that we are trying
to analyze and get potency for because
we want to encourage them because we
think that they are you know like
perhaps helper molecules for psilocybin
or something or are the are the other
other four really more things that we
want to track for potential negative
reasons
well for the north silicon bay cysteine
and north bay of cysteine i know that
people are definitely interested in them
as psychedelic molecules i do not
believe there's major toxicity
associated with those in larger doses
they're more minor alkaloids in the
mushroom compared to psilocybin and
silicon and
you know they're not found in every
species either i've definitely seen
um bail cysteine and norbiocysteine in
some uh samples from customers but i
have yet to see
norcillusin show up so um and some of
these molecules you know convert into
each other you know psilocybin converts
into silicon uh and all of these
molecules are very similarly related
structurally
it you know it reminds me right away of
the entourage effect in cannabis and
indeed you know um so oh good so that's
that's what i'm curious about do you
think that and again i know we're very
early in this research but do you think
we're gonna find that these um these
different constituents are working
together or do you think that they just
happen to sometimes co-occur
yeah i'd be hard-pressed to believe that
they don't have some sort of
synergy or interaction with each other
because you can make the analogy to
cannabis where you look at cbd and thc
for example they don't bind to the same
receptors that's why they have different
effects in the body and you know where
we know the
target for silicon and psilocybin
we may not know all the target receptors
for the other constituents and we might
not even know if silicon and psilocybin
touch other receptors either you know
there's uh
the experiments that are done in order
to figure this stuff out are pretty
complicated and involve like you know
binding kinetics with the analyte and
the receptor and it takes a great deal
of work to uh
to figure out and then you also when you
have lower affinity or what i mean by
that is like the interaction between the
receptor and the molecule is not very
high
it's like really low those can be
actually hard to discover that they're
binding to in cell or on the cells so it
takes even more
extensive work to discover the minor
receptors that they might interact with
wow that's really interesting all right
so
i know for me the four that you
mentioned other than silicon and
psilocybin were all new to me but to
people who are studying at your level
and understand these mushrooms
intimately
are you expecting there to be some or
many more constituents of the mushrooms
that that we discover and find out are
things that we do want to analyze like
like the so this is an ex the the number
of things we were going to be looking
for in these assays is expanding as we
learn more
exactly yeah there is some work going on
in israel where they have a very
advanced lab where
pardon me where they use a different
technique than we use and flourish to
look at these
analytes they're using a
mass spectrometry
and with a liquid chromatography coupled
with a mass spectrometer you can
identify molecules that are
super low abundance
and maybe a thousand fold more sensitive
than the hplc uv that i'm using to do
these quantitative analytics and i know
that they've discovered a host of new
molecules
in psilocybin mushrooms that
is in the literature and just really
isn't well known at all and then what
you need to do then is single out these
molecules and then do experiments with
each of them and this is a very massive
effort and you know um
one of the biggest deficiencies i have
right now
is uh
in this field is the time
to
dive really deep into the literature of
basic research most of my work right now
is involved with researching method
development because i'm setting up
additional tests outside of psilocybin
mushrooms which we can talk about later
if you're interested or maybe next time
but most of my time is spent developing
new tests for the lab so i'm a little
bit deficient on the newest
alkaloids coming out of
these mushrooms but that's actually
something we could probably talk about
in a single episode if you're ever
interested in the future
it's really interesting to uh experience
how much opportunity that there is in
mushrooms right now you know for for
somebody who sees themselves as an you
know a an organic chemist or you know
naturalist scientist to the idea that
there's you know all these species to
discover and then there's all these
species to then do um you know
experimentation within the lab
and then you know of course how they're
interacting with the human like what
what a time to be somebody early career
who is interested in this
yeah actually i have two answers to that
question first of all you said
additional species so right now i've
been talking mostly about the philosophy
mushrooms and one thing that i thought
was really interesting too is i've even
seen a reference where people have found
buffetinin
in the mushrooms that's the same ones
found in the toad right that's a really
powerful dmt molecule uh that's another
reference i'd need to follow up and
verify but i thought that was super
interesting but for other species there
are like gymnopolis and
foliota there are these molecules called
bisnor agonin
hispidin and then in ammonita there's
muscomol ibotanic acid and muscasone so
there's
there's a host of other molecules that
can be looked into as well you know
so just narrowing down on the philosophy
mushrooms
is super interesting but there's also a
lot more out there and to be honest when
we're talking about the fungal kingdom
there is so much we don't know i mean
unbelievable amount of information out
there to be mined by people to
figure out what's going on with these
absolutely incredible
organisms so i know that you know the
the few
labs that there are for for mushrooms in
the united states they you know they
they look different and they're run
different but i'm going to ask you like
a real general question from your
experience just kind of about all labs
in general which is
do you think that mostly labs are are
being set up at this point just for
philosophy or do you think that you know
both part of their business model to be
able to have a more variety of customers
but also the direction that interest is
going would you say that most labs are
are setting themselves up for the
amanita and all these you know these
other mushrooms that are coming
into popularity again
yeah well first of all most people are
going to be handcuffed by their laws so
it's only legal to mess with any of
these in very
few places in the country the state of
oregon
denver oakland
and
maybe i've heard of a lab in michigan
but i don't know if they're just doing
it without having the laws changed yet
so and there's a couple levels of of
this answer here so um to set up the
testing for psilocybin and silicon it's
not that difficult there's information
out there in the literature you don't
need a tremendous amount of equipment
you know you know 20 30 000 investment
and and you could get going
now
having the ability to do
you know analytical
method development and develop methods
for things that there might not be a lot
of information out there is going to be
a real challenge for anyone that doesn't
have a massive amount of experience in
chromatography method development with
hplc or lcms
so
what i've noticed is several of the labs
that are up and running well several
there's only a few
most of the people doing it are very
young scientists and by young i don't
mean their physiological age but the
amount of experience they have
with this type of work and the less
experience you have doing this the more
difficult it is to expand into different
um you know species or different tests
and me i've been doing chromatography
method development for 20 years you know
um it's kind of funny i i just recently
announced that i can test for cordyceps
and i got some cordyceps mushrooms from
a guy on instagram you know collaborated
with he gave me some material to help
develop my method and uh
i had this guy's uh mushroom and an
extract for gosh it must have been two
months and i've just been so busy in my
day job and all the other things
involved i'm a parent i'm a father uh
i'm a husband and uh
i just didn't have time to get to it and
then just last weekend you know i
developed a method for cordyceps in two
days
and um you know a lot of people are not
going to have
the base knowledge to do something like
that so quickly and then you know
validating the method and making sure
it's correct you know it takes a lot
more work after you develop it to make
sure that it's correct and you know we
can have
um really challenging issues where two
different molecules
have what's called the same retention
time
and what that means is when you have a
complex molecule say i do an extraction
of a mushroom and then i put it through
my machine we use a column that is
packed with a bed of what's called resin
which is basically a bed of
a bead that has a chemical functional
group or a chemistry
uh interactive group on the surface of a
molecule we take our complex
mixture of mushrooms and we pass it
through that mole through that
column and all the molecules in the
mixture interact with the surface of
that column resin in a different way
this is how they start to separate out
and resolve from each other
and so when you put a sample on a column
you can have stuff come out within a
couple minutes 5 10 15 maybe even 20
minutes to be even longer depending on
how fast the flow is and how uh how much
interaction occurs between the molecule
of interest and the resin bed of the
column so these retention times is how
you distinguish which molecule is which
because if you do everything the exact
same way every time they should come out
to the same retention time within 0.05
minutes of each other you know within
seconds they should be very reproducible
now if we have two molecules that are
almost identical for example silicon
then psilocybin is a very subtle change
where psilocybin loses a phosphate group
which is a phosphorus and four oxygens
and when you do that you actually get a
pretty big change in the physiological
uh behavior or the the chemical behavior
of the molecule and then you get these
to separate very easily
and then with cordyceps you're actually
looking at molecules where it's a subtle
of a change of a hydrogen
and an oh group so a hydroxyl to a
hydrogen and everything else on the on
the molecule is identical
so separating those when there's such a
subtle change
is critical right because you don't want
to tell people you're testing cortisone
but
it's actually that peak also has either
adenosine or two deoxy adenosine right
you'll be giving them the wrong
information so you have to make sure
that with your method development that
you have all your controls in place and
all your standards
separating at what is called a baseline
resolution so that you can actually
quantitate or give people the
concentration of these analytes in their
mushrooms right on that was a very clear
uh explanation and you know i i've
talked about this before when i was
talking to dr miyabi shields on this
show but i really like
um
uh i don't know the artisan approach
where by
by creating these lab processes right
kind of you're kind of inventing your
own tools um my you know all my my my
gran my grandpa and my uncles they were
all uh carpenters and i remember when i
was a kid the first time that i realized
that you know they needed to do
something in carpentry and so they
actually developed and made a tool
because that tool didn't exist and the
idea that you could like invent tools
was like fascinating to me as a kid it
still is cool to me yeah and that's
essentially you know what you're
describing is that all right we've got
we've got this new box of information
called mushrooms and you know we need to
come up with tools to be able to open
this box uniquely and um
i get pretty jazzed by that
um let's talk about uh terpenes um i've
only really understood that word that
there have been terpenes in mushrooms
for about three years after it came up
uh uh unexpectedly uh during an
interview
and so you know since that time i have
been trying to learn everything i can
about um mushroom terpenes um they all
they seem to be incredibly subtle they
certainly don't play as big of a role to
to humans as as an aroma attractant as
they do in our our favorite plant
cannabis um but but you know all of the
mushroom research i'm talking about
saying they're like you know
these terpenes are going to be a bigger
deal than we take them for now
and so i i would like to hear what you
have to say about
um you know the terpene like like you
know are you testing for mushroom
terpenes are there a few that are
particularly common
and uh in your conversations with your
customers um uh you know do you have any
you know status quo of where we're at as
far as understanding the role that
terpenes play in these mushrooms
your last question is the easiest one to
answer and the role that these terpenes
are playing for the most part we have no
clue this is a brand new area of
research i mean there might be a couple
labs around the world that would
disagree with me and say they know more
and they probably do but these are kind
of obscure and i don't really know too
much about them
i'm definitely not an expert in mushroom
terpenes
because
they're so new and one thing i'd like to
say is they're very different from the
cannabinoid terpenes as you said
cannabinoid terpenes are typically
associated with
uh odor and providing us with that
beautiful profile that we get from all
the diversity in the cannabis plants
the mush sorry the terpenes found in
mushrooms are generally called
triterpenes so they're much larger and
they're more complex often than the ones
we know about in cannabis and they do
not have odors associated with them
because they're not as volatile if
they're volatile at all
and
they're found in some species and not
others for example the rishi mushroom
has a large group of tri-terpenes that
are
people are very interested in and they
are much more complicated to test for
right now like first of all getting
standards for them uh can be a challenge
most people that are going to be looking
at terpenes are going to be using mass
spectrometry which uh these machines are
very expensive and
flourish is definitely planning on
buying one in the near future so that i
can expand into these more
lower abundant molecules and ones that
you might not be able to find uh you
know authentic reference standards for
because
using a mass spectrometer you don't
always need a reference standard well
you don't need a reference standard to
identify things there's these databases
that you can pay enormous amounts of
money to have access to and you can
basically find just about any molecule
that we know exists that way if you want
to use a mass spectrometer to quantitate
then you definitely need reference
standards so
but i have a feeling that these terpenes
these tri terpenes from mushrooms are
going to be
really important i have a feeling that
they're going to be critical
in the bioactivity and the medicinal
properties of these mushrooms i believe
there's also some found in turkey tail
and definitely in lion's mane as well
and some of these other
mushrooms they also have these unique
compounds associated with them that
aren't found in other species like uh
you know these arinasines and uh
oh what's the name of the other group of
the compound eranasines and hersinones
from lion's mane they're these
incredibly unique
uh
dye terpenoids from the mycelium of
lion's mane uh and also one's in the
mycelium i believe
that's the
uh iron acing and i believe the hersinos
are more abundant in the fruiting body
and paul stamets has talked about these
quite a bit on various podcasts he's
been on and and you know
these are responsible for neurogenesis
and well the hypo i don't know that i
should say that i know there's a very
strong hypothesis
that uh these things are helping you
know in vivo in humans there's
definitely in vitro work showing that
these lions main compounds actually
initiate neurogenesis and if
paul stamets is also referring to other
work that shows when you combine
psilocybin
and lion's
neurogenesis and also another thing that
he's sorry i just hit the mic um
another thing that he led on to on one
of the joe rogan podcast years ago is
the combination of these two molecules
and then you add in uh niacin or vitamin
b3 and what niacin is a vasodilator and
it can dilate the very
um
well it dilates all blood vessels right
but if you think about where you need
these molecules to work
if someone is dealing with neuropathy
from diabetes or from some uh you know
traumatic injury
and we want to get the psilocybin and
the lion's mane molecules to the
absolute depths of the periphery of our
of our uh
of our circulatory system these are the
capillaries all the the deep parts of
our brain you know like where the
neurogenesis is needed where the
neurodegradation has occurred
and by combining all these together
you're going to get a stronger response
by the combination of the iron acines
and herzenones with the psilocybin and
then using something like niacin to push
these molecules to the absolute end of
the circulatory system where they're
most needed and so i think that's just
absolutely fascinating and i was
actually
what actually precipitated the beginning
of flourish labs was i was thinking
about making a supplement with lion's
mane
and uh
niacin and then you know letting people
get their own psilocybin but then all
these laws changed and i thought about
you know making this as a product
and then i had a couple of friends say
oh i think you should make a testing lab
which i need to shout out both of those
people a couple of really good friends
one's been my friend since uh college
uh jeffrey thank you so much for
pushing me towards this lab and then
another guy that he's worked with and
i've become friends with
a guy named drew and i want to thank
both of those guys a lot because without
them i probably wouldn't be here right
now i would have missed the boat
um so let's let's come at the mushroom
from a different um direction oh before
before we do that i wanted to uh just uh
jump on the niacin bit um you know we've
talked about niacin and microdosing on
the show here a couple times and you're
the first person to explain why niacin
is in the stack so right so thank you
for uh explaining that that's really a
valuable um
insight so there's actually something
really interesting about that as well um
niacin if you take too much you can get
what's called a niacin flush i have done
this yeah it's not fun not super
dangerous but not fun and so one of the
cool things about using niacin in this
context is you can prevent people from
taking a whole bunch of not that you
right you don't want to be the
psilocybin police but you know by
putting niacin in the microdose you're
not going to take too many because
you're going to get a nice and flush way
before you start tripping if you want to
have a macrodose just you know grab five
grams of some good mushrooms and go for
it i see what you're saying yeah so that
so that once they are on store shelves
it decreases
the likelihood that people are going to
take their whole bottle of
dose at the same time yeah for
jurisdictions that are worried about
this you know that are more conservative
it might be a really good thing because
there are molecules you could add in
there that will dilate your blood
vessels without the nice and flush
there's some peptides and some other
molecules small molecules that'll do
that
so let's talk about adulterants right so
you know
again most of us have got cannabis
analytics as our framework in our head
and in addition to like the cannabinoids
and the terpenes that that were that we
want um we're also especially in the
licensed system uh looking at at molds
and heavy metals and um and like just
you know chemicals from like eagle 20
and things like this
um
you know
mushrooms are not grown the same way as
plants of course
so from your perspective um
what
substances might we be
searching for in mushrooms in the lab
that would suggest that they were
perhaps
grown incorrectly or in in an unclean
environment which would cause us to
reject batches of mushrooms i don't know
what that would be but i'm assuming
there are
there's yeah i'm i'm not a mushroom
grower i never have grown mushrooms so
i'm
a little bit
uneducated here the cool thing about
mushrooms if you screw it up my
understanding is a lot of times you
don't get anything like if you get a
contamination
a lot of times the contamination will
outrun the mushrooms that you're growing
so you basically just have to throw it
out
i'm i'm sure there are situations where
people are growing with
maybe substrates that might have heavy
metals in them or substrates that might
be contaminated with a
some sort of organism that would be
unhealthy for us and so i absolutely
plan on instituting this type of testing
at flourish labs
as well i believe when
it comes time for the regulated legal
testing under 109 you will be looking
for contaminants like heavy metals and
uh you know bacteria or other fungi that
could be dangerous to humans that might
be slow growing and we'll use a pcr
genetic test to determine these things
which is really pretty straightforward
not difficult to do
and going to be critical again because
you're taking you're basically making a
food
right or a medicine for somebody that
they're going to ingest in their body
and it has to be clean
right on so let's let's get back to the
analytics so
i understand that you know one of the
things that are interesting about
mushrooms is that not only do they have
um you know common
uh um
common constituents that are just used
in and applied in novel ways in fungus
but also there are some um constituents
that that um uh don't occur very often
except in mushrooms and the type of uh
labs that we're almost familiar with
they're they're using uh chemical
standards for
um for these constituents and then um
you know using the technology compare
against the standard um to then figure
out how much of it is in any particular
mushroom i'm i'm guessing that since um
you know the philosophy mushroom is
still a schedule one at the federal
level that some of these standards uh
might actually be challenging to get
your hands on but i'm willing to be open
to the path to the fact that maybe they
all already exist and it's just been
access to them for years and years so so
tell us a little bit about how difficult
standards are to be able to obtain to do
the work
yes this is one of the most common
questions i get from people and you'd be
surprised how easy it is
um so there's a philosophy here that is
pretty um
straightforward so
these molecules you you have to take a
certain dose right and so in order to
get the standards you contact these
chemical companies and they basically
have one milligram per milliliter
solutions that you can buy they're dea
exempt
because you're paying anywhere from 70
to a few hundred dollars for a single
milligram nobody's gonna be abusing
these things you're you're gonna you can
go down the street and find them for way
cheaper
right so they're dea exempt when it's a
milligram or less and they're often in
solvents you would never put in your
body so
it's too much of a hassle to try to get
these and abuse them it's super
expensive and no one would ever do it
that's why their dea exam now if you go
trying to buy five grams or you try
grand more than or you're drying up
trying to dry buy a powder then you need
a dea license but just for single
milligram
uh one mig per ml reference standards
all you need is a legitimate laboratory
and
uh
by legitimate laboratory
when you start a company like this or
you have a laboratory you're starting in
a non-profit or in a university you know
the companies vet your location like you
can't have a mail service you can't have
you need a legitimate commercial
laboratory location for them to even
send them to you so that's the that's
where the level of of uh sort of uh
regulation comes in by the actual
chemical companies they won't just sell
them to anybody also right on cool all
right so let's talk about um sampling um
as we all know
um people game the system all the time
in cannabis
by um by which flowers they choose to
send to the lab maybe they're just
sending colas or maybe they'll roll the
flower in keith first or you know
whatever they're going to do it's it's
not a representative sample which
scientifically is is actually quite
a process of having and having and
having um
a large lot all the way down to a small
lot but but when you're done
mathematically it's it's representative
of the entire lot um when it comes to
mushrooms though
um uh
i don't know what a sampling uh process
is like and so does it matter which
mushrooms you pick like can you game the
system
by sending like a larger or a smaller
one tell us a little bit about that
yes so uh one of the most interesting
things about these mushrooms to me is
the variability
of the alkaloid content from
flush to flush
from mushroom to mushroom and also
within the mushrooms themselves
so
i believe it's going to be a lot harder
to adulter them than with cannabis for a
couple reasons we can get to that in a
moment but i had a customer interested
in looking at the various uh structural
aspects of the mushroom and
so when the mushrooms are growing you
know the way that they grow
the the cap and the stem appear fused
for a really long time and some
mushrooms have a veil which is like a
little skirt around the uh the cap that
attaches to the
the stock and then when that opens then
the uh the spores are able to drop from
the mushroom cap now i've been told by
growers that and also seeing research in
the literature where
most likely the most potent time to
harvest is just before
the caps open and the veils open like so
everything is closed up
however
if you look even more carefully i had a
customer like section the mushroom
uh from the step the the bottom of the
stem up to the tip of the cap when we
looked at the lower part of the stem
and we looked at the the stem and
the junction of the stem and the cap
right there so it like
he took about i don't know a few
a half a centimeter to the right
of the stock side and about a half a
centimeter to the right of the left of
the
of the cap and he sliced that and then
he took the top of the cap and when we
looked at that that center piece where
the veil connected to the stalk and the
cap was by far the most potent part of
the mushroom oh that's interesting yeah
yeah like like twofold more potent than
the cap and maybe like two and a half to
three times more potent than the stem
that's a really funny answer because
everybody argues about whether or not
stems or caps are are the most potent
but actually it's it's where they join
well in that instance definitely because
i've also seen
uh
just recently a guy on instagram showed
that the stock was more potent than the
cap
and so this opens up a whole host of
questions around
mushroom cultivation right so we've
learned a ton about steering plants to
produce molecules cannabis with thc or
cbd
other plants you know that like
to produce
compounds of interest for pharmaceutical
or or industrial purposes
i'm really interested to see if we can
do this with fungi
and once these growers get out of the
basements and closets and start making
these commercial facilities and they're
able to control their environments with
really high level um
uh
man i'm missing a lot of words today i
totally apologize
high fidelity control of their
environment you know they can tune it up
or down a couple degrees a couple
percent humidity they control co2 oxygen
levels light dark
when the when the mushroom growers get
these tools are they going to be able to
produce highly consistent batches they
might
well they might not also because maybe
the mushrooms control this in a way we
don't understand
i did briefly read an abstract of a
paper last night where they claimed that
they could influence the alkaloids in
the mushrooms by
growth conditions
so it's definitely possible it's just
going to take a massive effort
of research and development on the on
the mushroom grower part growers parts
to
you know normalize cultivation so that
people that are producing products
can grab a batch from the same grower
every time and know more or less that
their product is going to uh
come out the way they expect
now if this is not the case it's really
good news for labs like myself because
if they have a consistent batch every
time you don't necessarily have to touch
test every batch of raw material before
you make a product right but if you're
varying more than 10
of your raw material batches they're
going to have to test every batch so
they know how to make
their products so then i would be able
to be testing pre-product formation and
then i would be testing their products
as well so
for the growers and the product
and the producers and people making
product i hope that they can
normalize to grow
and get consistent batches
it will just help them save a lot of
money you know and the testing we're
going to be there we're going to be
required to test everything before it
hits the shelves if there ever is retail
or before it hits the clinic before it's
given to patients so you know our niche
is there
but we're definitely available to help
if that is the case where they need pre
and post testing right on so let's go
ahead and take a short break and when we
come back we're going to continue down
the same um
the same vein and and talk about uh
testing mushrooms that have been dried
or fresh um you are listening to shaping
fire and my guest today is biochemist
george selhorn and you know without
these advertisers shaping fire would not
happen so please support them and let
them know you heard them on shaping fire
[Music]
there are a lot of good people launching
new businesses in cannabis psilocybin
and other psychedelics and it's very
strange time for us in the same moment
that psilocybin mushrooms are illegal at
the federal level they are becoming
increasingly legal in states across the
country
these businesses leading the way into
the future of plant medicines require
specialized legal representation by
attorneys who have depth not only in
litigation mergers and acquisitions but
also in psychedelic and other plant
medicines
green light law group has been
empowering cannabis businesses since
2014 and as the market has diversified
into psilocybin and other plant
medicines green light has been right
there evolving with their diverse
clients to provide legal expertise with
a high level of legal acumen creative
strategy and precision that comes with
an intimate and specific understanding
of both business law and plant medicine
if you are a business owner trying to
navigate the layered local and national
drug laws on your own you are at risk of
fumbling
these confusing and quickly changing
laws complicate everything
green light law group is ready to help
you when hit with a lawsuit or because
you are shafted by a vendor or business
partner or simply because you want to
stay legal and could use some
preventative guidance before cultivating
a controlled substance as an
entrepreneur
green light law group is a collection of
folks who care profoundly about their
work and i know this is true because i
know the folks from greenlight
there is a huge difference between a big
legal firm who has decided to start
representing a few drug companies versus
working with a collection of high
integrity passionate lawyers who are
personally interested in new plant
medicines and firmly believe in their
power to heal
contact green light law group today and
learn more about the services they can
offer your industry leading cannabis or
psychedelics company
that's green light law group at
greenlightlawgroup.com
[Music]
once you've discovered the benefits of
using cannabis it's a very small step to
start making your own edibles gummies
lotions tinctures and concentrated oils
at home
magical butter has been helping cannabis
consumers become self-sufficient for
over a decade
with the easy to use magical butter
countertop botanical extractor you can
create high quality cannabis products to
your exact specifications at a fraction
of the cost of store-bought edibles
i talk a lot on this show about the
importance of home growing so you don't
have to rely on others to feel healthy
well the magical butter machine can
empower your personal health by putting
you in control of how you use cannabis
in your daily life
i've been making my own butters and oils
on the stove for years and i much prefer
the ease of using the magical butter
machine i just set it and walk away
with the simple touch of a button the
magical butter machine grinds heats
stirs and steeps your herbal extract all
at the correct time interval and
temperature for the perfect infusion
every time
as a result you achieve your desired
infusion easily safely and consistently
check out the magical butter instagram
to see the machine in action and don't
feel like you have to go it alone there
is a huge community on facebook called
magical butter users united sharing
recipes and best practices so you can
learn at your own pace from others who
are already doing it successfully
now is the time to get your own magical
butter machine and save money while
enjoying cannabis
use the discount code shaping fire one
word no caps to get ten percent off
visit
magicalbutter.com today
[Music]
there are so many seed banks nowadays
that you really have options in who to
choose not only that if you pick the
wrong seed bank you could be in for a
really sketchy ride and that's only one
of the reasons i recommend hembra
genetics collection to my friends and
listeners who are looking for a seed
bank that's hembra spelled h-e-m-b-r-a
hembra is not just another seed bank
hembra is a woman-operated boutique
cannabis genetics provider that only
sells thoughtfully curated seeds from
the top names in cannabis breeding
with over 50 breeders and over 500
strains to choose from you will
certainly find something you'll love
hembra genetics has something for
everyone with over 350 feminized strains
200 regular varieties and over 100 auto
flowers to choose from
names you know you can trust like
humboldt seed company night owl
cannerado in-house genetics fast buds
and gnome automatics
we both know that there are other seed
banks who will take your money but have
no customer service
i invited hembra to advertise on shaping
fire after hearing so many good stories
about them from my friends
they have a plus customer service with
lightning fast response times
in most cases helene and caitlin will
get your order out the same day you
place it and you'll usually receive your
seeds in just a few days
most seed banks are simply not this
organized or interested in getting your
seeds to you this fast but hembra cares
you even get free seeds with every order
helene and caitlyn get it they have been
in the cannabis growing scene for over a
decade so save a few bucks by using this
discount code too use the code shaping
fire all one word at checkout to save
ten percent off your order
buy seeds from good folks who will get
you great seeds reliably every time
visit
hembragenetics.com today that's hembra
genetics
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire i am your host shango los
and my guest today is biochemist george
selhorn
so during the first set we talked a lot
about uh what is actually in mushrooms
in general but specific philosophy that
we want to test for and then we talked a
bunch about the things that might be in
mushrooms that we don't that mean that
we want to test for that that we don't
want to have in there
um let's talk a little bit more about
the mushroom
itself and getting getting it prepped
for the analytics um
do mushrooms always have to be dried
first to test or can we test them fresh
and and do can we can we only
compare fresh tests against fresh tests
or can we
compare fresh tests against dry tests
because because the water aspect doesn't
matter
yes we can absolutely test wet or dry
mushrooms
dry mushrooms are a little easier to
homogenize than a wet mushroom but it's
totally possible and
we control for moisture you know we do
dry weights
dry weight measurements in the end so
basically if i were to get a dried
mushroom from
a batch and a wet mushroom from a batch
what i would do is
homogenize both individually
and then you weigh out a sample
and then you extract it and you do the
hplc and you get your numbers
and then i always ask for a little bit
extra
you know you need a portion of mushroom
to do the analytics on and you need a
portion of the mushroom to dehydrate so
you can get the true dry weight so
even when i get a dried mushroom from a
customer i will take a small bit of it
and you know i basically have a little
dehydrating oven
that will uh
completely dry it out at i use 104
degrees so it's not too hot and it
doesn't matter right because i'm not
actually testing the part that you
dehydrate you pull out a sample first to
do the testing so it doesn't get any
heat treatment light or
oxidative degradation
and just at the end all you do is a math
adjustment to adjust for the loss of
water just like in cannabis so it
doesn't matter what the water content is
you can compare any mushroom as long as
you fully dehydrate a sample and
calculate the dry weight percentage
typically um how much of a sample
in in dry weight because i'm figuring
dry is is almost 100 of what everybody's
using yeah but um uh how big of a sample
do you think a lab is going to request
most of the time
um because uh you know same thing in
cannabis having a little bit extra is
helpful especially if something comes up
and goes wrong yeah you have tests yeah
exactly so what do sample
samples volumes or sizes look like for
mushrooms
uh so for me i prefer two grams uh two
grams is plenty for me
i've seen other labs ask for three four
and five grams which in my humble
opinion is a little bit excessive uh but
for for the way i do it is i get two
grams from a customer and typically
uh most people are fully dehydrating
these things themselves
uh i would say an average like
you know air dried mushroom has about 10
percent moisture but most of the ones
that i'm getting for from people only
have about one percent moisture so
they're fully dehydrating before i get
them so i usually make a very small dry
weight adjustment but yeah two grams is
plenty for me i keep one gram for the
dehydration step and i keep one gram for
analytics because for the analytics i
use about 250 to 350 milligrams so that
gives me at least two tests two
extractions that if i had to extract
their sample twice then i have plenty
for the extractions and plenty for the
dehydration
one of the challenges that was very
common with labs at the beginning of a
licensed cannabis
was
testing edibles because um
it's so much it's so much more difficult
to target in on the cannabinoids when
you've got you know god knows what else
is in this brownie
um
is it uniquely more difficult to find
mushroom metabolites in chocolate or
other edibles because you know
chocolates and honey and gummies seem to
be the the three
ways that um
mushroom edibles are first coming to
market
right
so there's an interesting chemistry
problem here and it's both in cannabis
and
in uh mushroom stuff so real quickly on
cannabis we know that the cannabinoids
are fat soluble they're they're
hydrophobic molecules which is why it's
really easy to make a chocolate bar with
cannabis because it has a bunch of fat
in it whereas it's way more difficult to
make a consistent gummy
because you're putting a hydrophobic
molecule into a water-based product a
gummy now we flip this when we go to the
mushrooms it's super easy to make really
consistent gummies all the gummies that
i've tested from people
have been
really consistent and then flip that the
chocolate bar and now you're trying to
put a water soluble molecule into a fat
soluble product so the consistency in
the chocolate bar is more challenging
with an alkaloid than a terpene from
cannabis and i test for both i have
methods for edibles extracts and
fruiting bodies so i can do all of those
things
i
think
this is the only lab in the country
doing edibles but i'm not positive i
haven't seen advertisements for anybody
else doing edibles well that certainly
explains why i'm seeing the growth in
mushroom
uh
um you know gummies and gelatin based
stuff uh you know traditionally
chocolates have been incredibly popular
but if the if the if the homogenization
is a problem that's a that's a big deal
breaker as far as consistency and and as
we all know especially with a
psychedelic yeah right yeah exactly um
and and as we know like during the
transition from um you know the the
heritage market to the medicinal market
you know the semi-legal medicinal market
and then a licensed market in cannabis
that you know the biggest reason
uh to go in that direction is for
consistency for patients right right and
we're ju we're we're climbing that same
mountain now with mushrooms trying to
figure out what is that absolutely
what's the best way to create repeatable
results for patients um
because you know that that's the that's
the only reason for legalization in in
my or not legalization but licensing
because i don't i don't really believe
that the state should be involved with
licensing or taxing this at all but i do
like the idea of there being consistency
in the products uh because in the end my
number one priority is is patience so
yeah so that makes some sense here's why
the gummies are kind of everywhere now
yeah yeah and you know there's a
downside to these edible things too like
sugar is such a huge problem in this
western culture and
you know everybody wants to put it in
this sweet candy it's just it's not the
best route for medicine in my opinion
yeah i'm with i'm with you on that
that's why i've pushed um tinctures as a
great primary thing because
you know okay with capsules you're kind
of uh well for cannabis anyway with
cannabis uh capsules you're gonna have a
whole bunch that are exactly the same
and there's no variability from day to
day and then you know all these people
are eating all these 10 milligram
cookies and you know that's not
necessarily great for patients either
yeah right so with mushrooms it's great
right because it's water-soluble we
could make teas and beverages without
sugar you could even make a concentrate
into a few milliliters like in it you
could make like a shot size and just
boom right there you know because it's
so easy to get these alkaloids into
water they're water soluble and there's
actually a really interesting thing i'd
like to add here something that i've
discovered
over the last six months since i started
this company
a one milligram dose in a gummy is not
the same as a one milligram dose in a
fruiting body and my hypothesis
which is
supported by the types of molecules that
make up the fungal
biomass
mushrooms are essentially a time release
pill
we do not have enzymes in our gut to
digest chitin which is the cell wall of
fungal biomass
so
all of the degradation that takes place
in the stomach and the gut is through
the acidity of our stomach
so the acid in our gut is going to break
the mushroom down slowly and slowly
release the alkaloid content of the
mushroom over a period of time
whereas you take a gummy and it has one
milligram in it because it's been tested
and we know it has one milligram of
silicon in it
or say 1.3 milligrams of psilocybin
because there's a conversion factor
there
you can feel one milligram in a gummy
you will not feel one milligram in an
average potent mushroom
so
it comes down a lot faster too yes
you're basically getting all of the
alkaloid dissolving immediately you get
this full milligram going into your
bloodstream all at the same time it's
going to hit your receptors and cause an
effect so what i'm saying excuse me what
i'm saying is for people out there they
start getting a hold of gummies
you know go easy first your mileage may
vary
yeah your mileage may vary take less
than more
initially and if it's been lab tested
that'll give you a really good metric
for your you know dosing yourself you
know and i i think with cannabis that's
been one of the coolest things is people
like okay i know what one milligram five
milligrams 10 milligrams is going to do
to me now
so let let's talk about what's in that
gummy right not not the actual gummy and
the sugar itself but
you know
if if what's in the gummy is not
um
pulverized and powdered mushroom it
means that there is an extraction
happening first and then the result of
that extraction is what's going into the
gelatin process what is that extraction
it can vary um so a lot of people are
using 100 ethanol or grain alcohol
because for one it's uh you know you're
allowed to consume it and for number two
it's easy to evaporate off
so um
this is something i've actually been
helping a lot of people uh with their
product development i've been kind of
doing consulting for people which i'm
definitely open to doing if anybody's
interested but because i have tons of
extraction experience both in cannabis
and in mushrooms and in plant material
in general because i've done that my
whole life in the lab and as a as a
recreational cannabis user
you can extract with water you can
extract with
acidified water
you know add citrus juice or something
you can extract with methanol ethanol
acetic acid
however you want to be able to
obviously people don't use methanol when
they're doing products like you're
making anything to be consumed i use
methanol in the lab because it's the
best one for extraction for
uh quantitation
um
my biggest i would
say the best solvent to use for
extracting mushrooms is 100 ethanol so
grain alcohol you don't want to use lab
100 ethanol because these are
uh cut with really nasty adulterants to
remove the last bit of water so
everclear is the best
if you're at home and you're not sure
what to use and the great thing about
alcohol especially 100 alcohol
is with very mild heat you can boil that
off so say you have an ounce of uh of
mushroom material that you want to
extract as much as the psilocybin out as
silicon and psilocybinators alkaloids so
you will do a mechanical extraction
either with you grind it up you can put
it in a vessel you can just shake it
with a shaker you can use a vortex you
can use a more powerful method or like
ultrasonication or some way to get the
alkaloids out of the mushroom
then you filter your biomass out and you
have this liquid with your mushroom
extract
now fortunately
the the alkaloids are pretty good well
resistant to mild heat so you can add
you know
80 90 100 degree fahrenheit heat to this
to this alcohol extract and boil it off
until it's reduced to whatever volume
you want
and then you would add a little bit of
water
and then you boil off the rest of the
ethanol and you have all of your
alkaloids in distilled water
and then you have a clean extract no
harmful compounds unless there's
something in the mushrooms you didn't
know about unless there's something in
your solvent you didn't know about but
that's the cleanest way to produce a uh
psilocybin extract and that also gives
you control over concentration as well
you know most uh sorry go ahead i was
just gonna say and if that's how they
are doing it um often when they're
making these uh
these edibles that's great but also that
is a pretty simple process that is
something that a citizen scientist or a
home user would be able to do as well
100 and that's kind of why i said it
because
mostly what i think people are doing is
they're kind of afraid to work with
solvents which you know very
understandable
but just pure grain alcohol is totally
safe and
a lot of people i believe are trying to
extract in water
and they're unable to reach these higher
concentrations and there's other tricks
you can do too right i said you have an
ounce of mushrooms you extract into i
don't know 100 milliliters of a solution
you can filter that biomass out take
that
sample that you have your extract in and
use a fresh mushroom batch to re-extract
right because the the solvent has a
certain capacity to hold alkaloids and
you're never going to saturate that
solution with one extraction so that's
another way you can increase the
concentration of your extraction by
using the same solvent or water on fresh
batches of biomass
right and you combine that with the
alcohol thing then you can achieve
really high concentrations and and you
know be able to make gummies or
any kind of product by just diluting a
little bit of it out
that's the same way that i get my um
cannabis tinctures for myself for
treating my brain injury up to the
numbers that i want them to be so i
don't have to take like freaking five
six eight squirts right um i'll do a you
know not a single and not a double but a
triple maceration so introduce the same
ethanol to fresh plant material three
times yes
so and what did you call it it's
carrying capacity
um
uh what
uh the uh whatever it wasn't supposed to
be a quiz but but the the the total
amount of cannabinoids the ethanol can
hold because that that's where i want it
to be right i want it to be at the
highest so yeah the saturation point
essentially yeah so so i don't have to
take in any more everclear or you know
whatever the ethanol is that i'm that
i'm using for it right and some people
you know especially
uh you know recovered alcoholics or
people that don't consume alcohol they
don't want that yeah so you need to have
an alternative and luckily we can boil
off
uh the
uh solvent pretty easy
and one thing i want to add to that real
quick is uh
i've seen studies where people
treat the psybin alkaloids up to 60
degrees celsius which is 140 degrees
fahrenheit
and even with you know relatively short
treatments 5 10 15 20 minutes you don't
get much degradation so that's why you
can heat these up to 100 degrees
fahrenheit and get almost no degradation
if it's for a short time you could also
institute a rotovap which is a rotating
evaporator we use in the lab with mild
heat and that you know if you've got the
money to buy a road of app for example
that will go even faster so there's
tools out there to be able to do this
i know that you've already said that
you're not a mushroom cultivator so you
may not have anything to say about this
question but
people will indeed be curious if if you
have come across any ways um that
cultivators can increase their potency
um in you know in their growing bins
perhaps from a conversation with you
know a client of yours or something you
know because people are always looking
to increase potency and clearly you know
getting good uh you know genetics is is
you know probably the number one thing
but do you have anything else to add
i
the one thing that comes to mind is i've
heard people talk about co2 levels i
believe co2 levels are important for
triggering
fruiting body formation
and so i would imagine
that um the air composition oxygen to
co2 ratio and temperature are probably
super important i saw this really
interesting post last night on instagram
that paul stamets put out and he was
saying that
the temperature of the mushroom is
cooler than its surroundings
and so
it has like this
endothermic behavior when the fruiting
body is is forming and by endothermic i
mean it actually absorbs is able to
absorb heat because it's like a heat
sink it's like a heat sink yeah so an
exothermic chemical reaction produces
heat and an endothermic
reaction sucks heat out away from the
reaction so for example
um
when you mix like acetonitrile and water
together which is the solvents i use in
the lab for analytics it gets cold and
you have to let it warm up to room
temperature before you use it that's an
endothermic reaction so this chemical
reaction occurs and then this mass now
absorbs heat from the environment
because the reaction like costs that
biomass heat or that mass not biomass um
but yeah so you know temperature
uh co2 oxygen are probably the first
metrics i would look at but again that's
that's a hypothesis based on very
limited information good enough we'll
take that
um so um
this is i guess this is a little bit of
a fanboy question but um you know what
what varieties are you seeing
consistently getting high potency
results i mean online just from based on
people's talking um i i think that most
people would put uh you know whatever
version of a penis envy at the top of
that list but but you're you know you're
in a unique place because you're
interacting with people who are growing
a wide variety and you're seeing the
test results um and uh
um
yeah i think i'll just stop there what
are you seeing yeah uh the most potent
mushroom i've seen so far is an ape
which i believe is a penis envy variety
albino penis envy yep yep and uh
i've actually seen some variability in
different apes but uh the highest
potency i've seen so far is 1.8 percent
dry weight and uh
um
these beautiful apes that are just
bluish and fat and beautiful so that's
one thing i i i almost said something
earlier about people's
visual appeal to mushrooms and comparing
it to how people just freak out about
cannabis flowers but i know there's some
mushroom geeks out there that totally
love just looking at the different
morphologies of these fungi and i find
it super interesting as well
but uh you know you can definitely see
some people thinking oh
yeah cannabis flower is way more
beautiful than a mushroom but now i
think that's uh to the in the eye of the
beholder so to speak but what i see when
i look at these uh
these amazing natural organisms that we
have
i see
um
uh chemistry factories right like these
this unbelievable ability to produce
these chemicals that
nature is providing and and it's so
interesting too if you think about
why plants are chemical factories and
it's a pretty simple
answer they can't run away they can't
run away from their predators so they
have to defend themselves chemically and
then plants have been plant and fungi
have been on this planet for so long
they've had plenty of time to
evolve mechanisms for defense which are
super broad they've also had time to
evolve
uh
molecules that
affect organisms in other ways which is
what we get to benefit from which is i
find absolutely fascinating that these
completely different organisms produce
molecules that affect our brain
chemistry that is
just blows my mind
right on so um let's go ahead and take
uh our second commercial break and when
we come back we're gonna talk about how
the
the new existence of
mushroom analytics is actually changing
mushroom pricing
in the underground
so
we're going to take this short break
we'll be right back you're listening to
shaping fire and my guest today is
biochemist george selhorn
[Music]
one of the reasons why no-till cannabis
growing is so valued by farmers is
because the mycelium networks in the
soil remain established from year to
year
and we know these fungal networks are
essential because they are the nutrient
super highways that extend far and wide
in the substrate to feed your plants the
trouble with growing in new living soils
or blended cocoa substrates is that it
takes most of the plant's life just to
create these mycelium highways
dinomyco endomycorrhizal fungi inoculant
reduces that time and gets your plant
eating a wider array of nutrients faster
and it's three times the concentration
of the other popular brand in the u.s at
900 propagules per gram of two fungal
species selected specifically for
cannabis cultivation
dynomica is the result of 30 years of
research and trials at the volcani
agriculture research institute in israel
it has also been vigorously trialed by
cannabis and food growers across the u.s
dynamico is now available at grow shops
and on amazon in the united states i
love using dynamico to both speed up the
growth of the mycelium networks in the
soil but also as a biostimulant to make
clone cuttings more virile you can see
side by side showing the comparative
growth on their instagram at dinomyco
if you demand reliable growing results
and appreciate the importance of an
active root zone in creating a thriving
plant i encourage you to check out
dynomico.com and use the store locator
to find out where you can get yours
that's d-y-n-o-m-y-c-o
dot com
shaping fire listeners can get ten
percent off any size of dynamico on
amazon or dynamico.com by using the
discount code shaping fire one word no
cabs
whether you are starting with new beds
or pots or if you want to add some zing
to tired soil choose dinomyco to
maximize your plants potential
dynamico endomycorrhizal inoculant
[Music]
for decades americans have enjoyed
cannabis flowers and joints and bongs
and bowls
and now with the normalization of
cannabis use increasing across the
country we have the opportunity to enjoy
smoking cannabis luxuries that simply
were not attainable before
north coast hand rolls blunts cannons
rosin infused donuts and canagars
available in the state of michigan
north coast focuses on flavor over
everything else
instead of growing their own flower
north coast goes out into the
cultivation community and creates
relationships with the best growers
working with the best new cannabis
varieties available
surely heavy thc is a factor but north
coast focuses on aroma complex terpene
profiles and taste that continues
throughout the entire smoking experience
the north coast team curates flowers
like others curate art they seek out the
best talent build relationships helps
them take their product to the highest
levels and then buys their well-cured
flowers in order to hand roll them just
for you
i really like their hand blown glass
tips
and north coast has branched out beyond
canagars into rosin solventless thca
diamonds and exceptional hash rosin
carts for on-the-go cannabis
connoisseurs too
north coast provides you with attainable
luxury offering you an ultra premium
smoking experience at a price that seems
reasonable and repeatable
to find out more about north coast line
of cannabis products visit their
instagram at northcoast.rolling
that's
northcoast.rolling and when in michigan
ask for north coast at your favorite
shop
north coast
[Music]
after you've caught up on the latest
shaping fire episodes do you sometimes
wish there was more cannabis education
available to learn well we got you
shaping fire has a fabulous youtube
channel with content not found on the
podcast when i attend conventions to
speak or moderate panels i always record
them and bring the content home for you
to watch the shango los youtube channel
has world-class speakers including zoe
sigmund's lecture understanding your
endocannabinoid system kevin jodrey of
wonderland nursery talking about
breeding cannabis for the best terpene
profile frenchie cannoli's lost art of
the hashishin presentation nicholas
mahmoud on regenerative and polyculture
cannabis growing dr sunil agarwal on the
history of cannabis medicine around the
world erik vlosky and josh rutherford on
solvent-less extraction and jeff
lonefels on the soil food web there are
several presentations from dr ethan
russo on terpenes and the
endocannabinoid system too while there
be sure to check out the three 10-part
shaping fire sessions series one with
kevin jodrey one with dr ethan russo and
one with jeff lowenfels and even my own
presentations on how to approach finding
your dream job in cannabis and why we
choose cannabis business even though the
risks are so high as of today there's
over 200 videos that you can check out
for free so go to youtube.com forward
slash shango lose or click on the link
in the newsletter
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire i'm your host shango los
and my guest today is biochemist george
salhorn
so one of the interesting um
i guess impacts from the the recent
existence of mushroom labs
is how it is impacting price
in the
i guess both the the underground
mushroom market and also in the
just blossoming
um soon to be licensed market
because up until
labs existed a psilocybin mushroom was a
psilocybin mushroom they were generally
the same some had their you know people
had their preferences because maybe they
had a good trip on it one time or they
liked how they looked more
um and then uh and then and then people
would be like oh these tend to be
stronger than these other ones but it
was really just conjecture and very
anecdotal on uh uh and i first
you know each person had their own
opinion and there was no way to compare
and contrast
aha enter mushroom labs now
and so
now we actually know what's in them and
so there's this new variety you know up
until now it was you know people's
preference and maybe maybe the mushroom
had something desirable about it like it
was albino or leucistic or or oh cool it
looks like penises you know which is you
know kind of kind of a a novel thing too
so people were making decisions on you
know aesthetic choices but now
we you know you can you can put them in
a lab and say all right this this you
know black cap albino penis envy is the
most potent thing
that you know we've gotten tested versus
you know this brazilian
which is beautiful and easy to grow and
has these other attributes that we're
attracted to
but you know it's only point you know
seven percent not point seven percent
it's it's only seventy percent as potent
as the eight for example i just made
that number up so but but just for the
example and so that is now impacting uh
pricing at the at the street and
manufacturing level because people are
starting to charge
more
for ultra potent mushrooms like these
apes and that's very interesting
what is your experience like behind the
scenes with your customers because you
know
it's getting to be a bit like cannabis
where
the higher the thc the more likely it is
to be sold
well
the potency of mushrooms is now um
becoming related to the price as well
from both people who are taking it for a
spiritual experience
and for people who are planning on doing
an extraction and putting them into a
bunch of gummies or something
right yeah i didn't even know that was
happening to be honest because i don't
you're in the lab yeah right yeah you
know people
pay me to take their mushrooms and test
them so that's actually fascinating and
you know it makes sense actually
um because at least with mushrooms that
we can touch on the cannabis stuff i
have a pretty strong opinion about that
one if
if you want to hear it but with
mushrooms
i've tested stuff as low as 0.2 percent
all the way to 1.8 percent
so that's you know nine-fold difference
in potency and you know if you go
to
a
a bar
and you want to buy a budweiser that's
whatever i don't know one 1.5 whatever
the percent of a budweiser is you're
gonna pay a low amount of money and then
say there's like some eight and a half
percent belgium you're probably going to
pay more for that beer right because
alcohol
is
like we know what it does it has a
linear effect you drink more you get
more drunk right with mushroom alkaloids
you take more you have a more
interesting experience
this is like linear the more you take
the higher you get
so it makes sense in the mushroom world
and the only problem there is are people
going to be saying oh this is an ape
when it's really like a way less potent
mushroom so you know ask for the lab
test if they're if they're charging you
based on on potency
it's interesting how suddenly coas are
very relevant in mushrooms now too yeah
i've had people requesting them being
made yep and and you know it's
interesting there are arbitrage
opportunities as well in this because um
if you are manufacturing um you may not
necessarily choose an ape mushroom
because they are at the the you know
even though the potency is the highest
100 percent it is also the highest price
and so
uh there would be good arguments to be
made that you know you're looking for in
a manufacturing environment you may be
looking for a balance between
um you know what mushroom has got the
right balance of potency availability
easiness to cultivate
and then easiness to
um you know uh break down and use right
um yeah you're 100 right so so you know
most potent mushroom is not necessarily
going to be best mushroom for
for manufacturing
and and these realizations are just
coming to the industry and it's really
interesting to watch them
sort themselves out
yeah no i totally agree because if
you're running a business
it's all about efficiency like how much
does it cost me to do this and how much
do i get back and how much product can i
make from it
so i could very easily see a scenario
where there's a one percent mushroom it
grows fast
it's really easy to grow like you say
it's it you know it's
maybe it grows twice as fast as a
mushroom that's 1.5 percent you know
what i mean so it would be better to
grow the one percent you get more
biomass you and then your extraction
efficiency is better with the slightly
lower potent mushroom it you know it's
going to be everybody's process is going
to have to be worked out
in that manner and that's what i would
suggest people do is just don't go right
off the bat and buy the most expensive
potent mushroom you know get a couple
different potency batches see how much
it costs you to make your product and
then you know make correct decision
so um earlier in the in this uh second
set we were talking about um
uh what part of the mushroom tends to be
the most potent and you told me about
the the single uh
test case you have done where it was
actually the junction of the stem to the
cap that tested highest which was a
really interesting um insight
um and then and then you know as we as
we worked our way out of the question
you know i just mentioned that people
argue quite a bit online about whether
or not it's the cap or the stem
and you said yeah there's a lot of
variability and we moved on but i want
to come back to that because
um uh you know you are the chemist and
you are the person who is um you know
doing these tests and granted most of
your tests are on homogenized mushroom
right so the the calf and the stem are
all mixed together
but um i i'm thinking that you have
something to say even if it is there's
no there's no hard and fast rule i just
want to get your thoughts on
uh stem versus cap potency generally
across all philosophy mushrooms
that's such a difficult question to
answer um
you know i would feel comfortable if i
tested at least 10 different
mushrooms and looked at caps and stems
and stuff but i've only done it once you
know like an n of one is a classic
example of not enough data
decision
um
but you know there's
over the years people have looked at
this in in different
academic groups or different parts of
the world where they're allowed to do
this work and in general the theme is
that the caps are more potent so i would
probably lean to that being true
there's always exceptions to rules like
where we saw the guy have a more potent
stem the other day but in general i
would say the caps probably do have more
alkaloid than the stem
so
if there was a fully mature mushroom
right on that makes sense so so the rule
of your rule of thumb would be cap but
um but we know the variability between
varieties is so significant that um you
know don't put too much weight on the
rule of thumb yeah very good the best
thing to do is just grind it all up in
my opinion you know grind everything you
have into a single
powder and then it's going to be is
pretty consistent because i've had a
another customer where he took like a
pound and ground the whole thing up and
then he sampled it three different areas
and called that a b and c
and then um he did that for four months
every month he did a sampling like abc
right and so he was looking for
degradation over time and consistency of
sampling
and uh
he found some really cool stuff like the
the
the sampling
and the consistency was highly
quality everything's was really close
like every test i did
um was
right around six milligrams per gram so
0.6 percent and uh over time
he barely lost anything so he had a
really uh
good storage conditions so
if you're looking for consistency
homogenize
i think that the time when it comes up
most of the time is when um there is a
sales a sale taking place
because um you know so often um a
purchaser whether or not it is you know
somebody who is trying to establish a
business in oregon or if it's in like
the traditional neighborhood market um
you know there's always people want the
caps because they look cool and they're
kind of like ceremonially dope um but
but so often you know if if you're the
last person to buy mushrooms from your
connection um there might be a lot of
stems in the bottom and so you might end
up with mostly stems and a few caps
and um
you know the fact that we don't really
know um does help the position of the
seller um
so that's when i think that's when it
usually comes up because anybody who's
growing their own and it's not it's not
changing hands
we're just going to homogenize it like
you said so it's so it seems to be
either either in a in a licensed market
uh or or about to be licensed to market
where there is a professional cultivator
selling to a professional manufacturer
or when you're just getting mushrooms
from your homie you know right right
um
let's hit on uh the storage of mushrooms
next because there is uh there there's
the answer to how best to store your
mushrooms has really evolved over the
years and and um
very much so over the last three years
and so
you know when when i was in college back
in the early 90s uh we were told to um
you know to you know put it in a ziplock
and put it in the freezer and um you
know that seemed to work but i'm
understanding now that there's a lot
more people doing this research now and
it's evolved so so why don't you tell us
a little bit about the varieties of
storing our mushrooms
and uh how we can get the most longevity
about them and and probably in your
answer include a little bit about uh
what causes mushrooms to degrade too
sure
yeah so
remarkably the best way to store
mushrooms is in the dark sealed in a bag
uh at about 60 to 65 degrees and you
know moderate humidity
i've seen people
uh do freeze thaw studies like you said
in the freezer and put them in the
refrigerator
and store them just at room temperature
would be a little bit warmer than 60 65
70 75 degrees
and pretty much the best uh
way to do it to
to maintain alkaloid levels is uh
cooling in the dark
right so
um
do we want to
do we want to remove as much oxygen as
possible like like if i was just going
all right so so we're using like a um
a vacuum seal that's what i'm trying to
get to yeah that's that's a good move
then
yeah absolutely absolutely so the
primary
um
uh
issue is oxidation so
if you take away the oxygen
then you're gonna have way less
opportunity for your mushrooms to
degrade light and heat
and oxygen are your enemies when it
comes to this so
oxygen is the molecule that does the
damage but light and heat will speed it
up
so and the reason why the freezer
doesn't work all that great is um
when you freeze thaw
biomass whether it be tissue from an
animal
plant bacteria fungi
you when you freeze thaw something you
cause some of the cells to lyse or burst
and when you do that you're going to
expose the contents to oxygen
so that freeze thaw in and out of the
freezer your every time you do it you're
going to burst some of the cells and
then that's going to lead to the
degradation in the refrigerator it's
probably a moisture thing as well
so moisture also could be a problem so
if you don't fully dry your mushroom you
put it in the fridge the change in
temperature is going to cause
condensation
if the biomass absorbs any of that water
it will facilitate degradation as well
whereas you keep them in a nice
consistent dry dark environment and it's
cool
that seems to be the best way to
preserve your mushroom potency over time
so you suggested keeping them in a you
know low 60s dark spot in a bag let's
talk about that bag
because you may have just kind of said
that generally
there's a difference of an opinion
between
a paper bag because some people say they
need to breathe but i think that's just
the opposite because of the oxidation
aspect and then there's people that
don't dry you don't need to breathe
right on and then and then there's other
people who talk about either using
plastic or
or because most plastic
uh that's not a vacuum sealed breeze
some people are suggesting
glass jars are the way to go so so what
is the vessel that you recommend
actually if you want to be really anal
about it and give yourself little to no
you know the best opportunity to
preserve your your material a glass jar
that seals would be great yeah
and also if you want to go even a step
further you can take an inert gas like
nitrogen or argon and
blanket the vessel with that and it
pushes out all the oxygen now that's
going a little far and beyond most home
people aren't going to do that but in
the laboratory or in a business you
absolutely would want to do that because
you'll get much longer shelf life if you
purge the oxygen from the storage vessel
um a way to do that cheap at home
without um
adding the inert
excuse me without adding an inert gas is
um you know for these these um these you
know food fresh uh
vacuum packs right um
they've got these uh mason jar lid uh
adapters which is what i use for my
cannabis
and so you know i know i know the stuff
that i'm gonna smoke soon and then i
know the stuff that i've just taken out
of cure that's probably gonna sit there
until i get to it in two or three months
right and so i put it in a large mouth
mason jar and i think i paid like 20
bucks for this adapter and it sucks the
the all the air about it
out of it and so i would think that that
would also be a win for when i have
mushrooms 100 and filling up the vessel
with as much material as possible so
there's no room for air
right yep nope that's exactly uh the way
you would do it if you're
covering all your bases all right so
let's talk about time for degradation
for um the you know the most common way
of keeping mushrooms versus
the the the crazy way that we just
described for like you know perfection
so you know most people they're going to
get their mushrooms in a ziploc and then
they're gonna
bring them home and let's let's not use
freezer or refrigerator because we've
already suggested that that is no one
should be doing that so they want to
keep it in a cool dark place so so fine
it's good let's just put it under the
bed
so so it's dark it's cool and it's in a
ziploc bag
and let's say that the mushrooms when
you receive them let's say that
they were they were harvested two weeks
ago
and they were dried properly and um
you've got a very
short supply chain between the
cultivator and and and me as the
as the mushroom enthusiast all right so
so in that in in that scenario
um how quickly are my mushrooms under
the bed gonna degrade
are we talking we have a nice cool it's
like a 60 65 degrees yeah yeah let's say
the template let's say the temperature's
right and it's dark um it's slow i can
give you a an example that was not
perfectly stored but when i first
started setting up uh the lab here and
doing my r d and getting my method
started i had a grower friend give me a
nice bag of homogenized material so that
i had a good amount of material to go
back
and check
like so i could work on consistency
right trying to make sure i was getting
accurate results over time now i had
that material and i did all my initial
development about last september
uh or i mean uh sorry last
december january is when i did that work
and then i tested that stuff about a
month ago so it was about six months
where it sat
um
probably closer to 70 degrees
it's just in a plastic bag in my closet
in my bedroom right
and it went from about
seven percent
to about point five six percent so let
me really quick what is that
that is a
yeah that's about eighty percent so it's
like a twenty percent loss in six months
and um
that's not too bad because it's actually
way better than i thought it was going
to be it was elevated temperature so if
you keep it at 60 degrees and that
probably could have warmed up in there
above that if it got warm you know like
a couple few weeks it's been warm
recently so it could have accelerated a
little bit towards the end there but
that guy that i did the study with
you know over four months i think the
the potency changed by like two percent
so very little yeah very insignificant
the one of my friends who's a cultivator
he was very concerned about this last
year during the pacific northwest heat
dome when it got to like 114 where he
lives in eastern washington
and um you know he said you know other
people he knew were going to get ice
uh in order to you know keep food or
their pets or whatever cool and um you
know he kind of you know how a double
boiler you've got the the heat source on
the bottom and then a secondary thing he
he was actually taking all his storage
of dried mushrooms and putting him in a
in a vacuum packed bag and then put it
in a cooler that had all ice in the
bottom but then was sealed and then was
on top and that's how he's all like he's
like i don't know what the science says
about how quickly these are going to
um
uh lessen potency he says but i want it
to be zero and so he's like i may be
sweating my ass off during the heat dome
he says but my mushrooms won't and i
thought that was a pretty novel approach
this is a pretty clever approach yeah
because
what he did was smart because
it allows him to put his mushrooms in
the air
above the cold
whereas if he would like laid it
directly on the ice that super cold
temperature probably would have caused
some condensation to form inside there
so it's almost like he just made a
little bit of air conditioning for his
mushrooms you know yeah and he like he
describes it as a double boiler and like
it's weird like like even though it's a
radically different application of that
idea i totally got what he meant i'm
like oh yeah absolutely yeah he's
letting the the ice at the bottom cool
the chamber above
and it's not going to drop it down to
the ice temperature but it's going to
keep it much cooler than ambient so
that's pretty pretty clever like i said
i like it right now
so so let's talk about um you know since
we're talking uh about mushroom
analytics labs and you know primarily
shaping fire talks about entheogens um
and you know evolution of mind and all
um but there are um other mushrooms that
people are all hot about now um you know
generally put in a you know chinese
medici medicinal groups like you know
reishi and turkey tail and lion's mane
and all and all these other mushrooms
that sometimes we use in cooperation
with philosophy mushrooms for for this
ailment or that um uh
but also just just taking them for
general health seems to be pretty
appropriate um right uh
can you talk a little bit about the
awarenesses that you have um uh testing
these other mushrooms as well i'm
assuming that you you you don't just
test philosophy since you've talked
about you know these other mushrooms and
you have such intimate details with them
i'm assuming that there's people who are
are formulating you know a lion's mane
extract or something who's coming to you
as well
and um uh you know what are you seeing
as far as like variability in the
potency of these mushrooms because you
know unless they're really degraded they
all look the same and and and there's no
real way for us as a consumer to know
whether or not
this particular lion's main product is
is is as strong as this other one as a
consumer
right
yeah this is uh the direction that we're
going um i'm in the process i just got
the cordyceps testing set up
however the testing for a lot of these
other mushrooms is a lot more
complicated
sometimes you can use the hplc uv but
for most of these you're going to need a
mass spectrometer and you know those are
exceedingly expensive over a hundred
thousand dollars for the right machine
to do that testing and i plan on going
there that's
uh
i want to turn this business into a
fully functional mushroom lab not just a
psychedelic lab
and i'm actually i've been approached by
customers for things like mescaline dmt
uh ayahuasca alkaloids like people are
asking me about testing for all these
things so in the long run i would like
to be able to test for all of that and
the coolest thing about being in oregon
is with the decriminalization laws
we we can test these as long as we have
small amounts you know so it's it's
really cool it actually gives you an
advantage of being in oregon that the
other jurisdictions had only legalized
psilocybin they're not going to be able
to touch yeah right on that makes a lot
of sense and there's so much demand i
mean like um
even though cannabis is not normalized
yet especially at the federal level um
all these other entheogens that we love
and humans have been using forever um
they're coming in the door right behind
cannabis in the same way um still gonna
be politically and you know
legally messy for a while but everybody
everybody knows that the doors are open
and and it's cracked open pandora's
snowball's rolling downhill yeah yeah
so um so i want to ask you a question
about fruiting body versus mycelium
potency because this is probably one of
the the most asked questions i'm asked
um when talking to folks about um
uh chinese mushrooms and and such um
you know there are people who fall on
the the it's okay to put mycelium in the
caps um in the way that uh stamets does
for his products and then there are
people who believe that
mycelium-based
medicine is is um
you know snake oil and it's actually
only the fruiting bodies that should be
used um in kind of more of a you know
real mushrooms uh company kind of way
and um it you know
someone's opinion really tends to fall
on the fact of whether or not they what
their personal preference is um but
you're an analyst and and so um i wanted
to hear what your thoughts are about um
whether or not we should be buying
products that are made from a fruiting
body or from mycelium when we're talking
about non-philosophy medicinal mushrooms
yeah this is uh super interesting and
this is the point where opinions don't
count
science counts
when you have data showing that there's
molecules present in a certain part of
the biomass
i don't care what someone's opinion is
if if we know that lion's mane mycelium
makes hersinone a
or our iron acine a
and the fruiting body doesn't
then you can go eating the fruiting body
all day and you're not going to be
getting the iron acids you'll get the
hersinose which i i believe that's
correct that the ironaciens are
typically found in the mycelium and the
hersinones in the fruit if i have that
switched i apologize to everybody who
knows that off the top of their head but
it you know this is where the science
rules
you have a good lab
a good scientist that that knows how to
do all the stuff properly and has the
proper controls and the proper
identification of these molecules
and you can even start looking at this
on a genetic level too you could start
looking for gene expression
in the mycelium versus the fruiting body
and that's another layer of evidence
that it's being produced right so
you can find the gene
in both the fruiting body and the
mycelium because the gene the dna is
consistent from
doesn't matter the structure of the
mushroom or the mycelium but the turning
on of that gene does matter so there's
ways that we can look at that and then
obviously if the molecule is present
in so for example we grow some lion's
main mycelium
and we have a boatload of biomass and we
pull that out we extract it and we
identify hersenone a using mass
spectrometry it's there
right so and then you go and you have
the fruiting body of lion's mane you
grind that up you do your analytics
maybe the maybe erin acing isn't there
so
all i'm saying is there's different
molecules made in mycelium and fruiting
bodies for different species and i've
heard paul stamets say this ad nauseam
but some people just don't want to
listen you know if if you don't want to
follow the data and the science that's
your
right
but it's not going to be correct in
terms of what the contents are of those
extractions or those biomasses i think
it's also one of the reasons why we need
to make this information more available
to people right because i don't think
that anybody well or very few people are
intentionally making decisions that are
anti-science i think that most people
just would never know where to find the
data that you're talking about of people
testing mycelium versus fruiting body
this information is just hard to get
you need to be a scientist you need to
be able to go on to pubmed and not just
find articles that fit what you're
looking for but be able to go into the
article
and read it from a critic's perspective
and you know because every time a
scientist reads a scientific paper
you're putting that data to the test
you're saying does the data that people
have presented in this paper convince me
of what they're trying to convince me
and a lot of times you'll have a
scientist read a paper and be like i
don't buy it that data's not convincing
look at what they did here they're
trying to they're changing their axes to
get you to think there's a bigger effect
you know there's a lot of subtle things
scientists can do to trick a
non-expert
so that's why it's dangerous for like
your average person to go into pubmed
read a science paper and be like oh this
is what this means you know it's like
it's dangerous to do that because a lot
of times
unfortunately
there are plenty of scientists out there
that have an agenda and they're being
paid by a company to get a certain
answer and they'll do everything they
can to support it you know look at the
food industry for goodness gracious i
mean
well we run into that in cannabis all
the time because
people are people are reading these
tests and even though and certainly
people are fudging with their graphs but
at the most basic level you know you
really have to study whether or not they
used and they used isolate or a whole
plant resin in the patient's study
because they they act differently you
can't just say you know oh we use 200
milligrams of cbd for this
lupus patient because 200 milligrams of
isolate is different than 200 milligrams
of cbd
in you know a whole plant residue oil
yeah totally and there's there's reasons
for there's there's reasons to use
either right so so you know even though
i'm a whole plant guy i'm not trying to
diss the isolate you just have to know
what your goal is and understand um
what was done in the study
100 and there's a really good example
for that too you know with exam cbd
isolate versus a cbd
extract you know children with dravet
syndrome
they need cbd isolate you know like the
cbd is what actually helps
the the seizures you know you don't need
that other stuff and plus when you have
all that other stuff in there you might
have to give the kid a little bit of thc
which you might not want to do to a
five-year-old or something you know so
there's absolutely applications for
isolates versus croods you know if
you're going at something like a cancer
or multiple sclerosis or some
inflammatory thing you don't want
isolate because all those other things
in there are going to have different
effects and synergize and attack the
broad
symptoms that someone that has cancer ms
or something like that as opposed to
something very specific like a dravet
syndrome which is a very specific kind
of epilepsy so
and we transfer this to the mushroom
world and i guarantee there's going to
be
ailments that uh well for example
depression
psilocybin
pure psilocybin isolated in the lab even
maybe synthesized and used as a
medicine for
um
uh depression that works a hundred
percent you know like you don't need
like a whole mushroom extract to pull
that off so but there's definitely going
to be
something out there where we talked
about earlier with the five or six
different alkaloids we're finding in in
philosophy that are you know measurable
by uv
hpl cuv
maybe a different proportion of those
might have a better effect on ptsd than
depression or a better effect on
any of these other ailments that we're
seeing psychedelic mushrooms being uh
effective on can we get an even better
result by changing the ratio of bail
cysteine to silicon
i'm really looking forward to us
you know actually having the research
behind these other
uh components of the mushrooms so that
we can start even having this whole
plant a whole mushroom conversation
because at this point um
you know anybody who says that they know
is is is you know blowing smoke because
the research isn't there like like
i respect smart people's hunches
but we're only in the early days of of
learning
what's in the mushroom and so to say
that we know all the ramifications is
just unrealistic
yep the hunches and hypotheses put us on
the road to discovery right yeah exactly
well it's kind of like the same thing
we're going through with cannabis right
uh we all started with bro science and
now we have to uh individually like
replace what we think we know
with new things um as the as the
research you know it gets established so
of course yes well let's wrap up here so
george thank you so much for uh sharing
your unique expertise you know um with
there only being three you know
municipalities or not municipalities but
three three jurisdictions in the country
that um you know it's it's it's legalish
to do what you do at the you know at the
state level but it you know it's still a
schedule one drug um
you have got perspective and experience
that is you know just exceedingly
difficult to find and and it took me a
while to find you and then it took you a
while to be comfortable to you know um
you know be a little more public so so i
appreciate you choosing to share your
knowledge with us and um i wish you the
best of luck on on on this research and
the um
and your applications uh however you use
it so thank you so much for being on
shaping fire
yeah thank you so much for having me
this has been super incredible and it's
the first time i've ever done anything
like this so it was uh
it was great i had some closing thoughts
there for a second but they may have
just escaped me um
uh other than oh yeah i remember so uh
real briefly i could just kind of give a
brief history of of my interest in this
you know i started my psychedelic
journey pretty young i took lsd for the
first time at 15 years old
and got very heavily into it for a
couple years which had an enormous
impact on my life for the better
actually
my my my younger days were pretty wild
you know i grew up a skateboarder uh
with a single parent that was a business
owner so there was a lot of freedom and
i got into a lot of things young and
i was going down a track that probably
wouldn't have been really beneficial to
my longevity and after experiencing
psychedelics mostly lsd and then a
little bit of mushrooms towards the end
there by the time i was finishing high
school
it completely changed me and put me on
the academic track you know i i found
some better people to be friends with i
got this amazing
young lady that i started dating and we
were together for 10 years that she
helped steer me in the right direction i
ended up going to college going to
graduate school getting a phd and all
this stuff so
i really strongly believe that the
combination of
cannabis and psychedelics
helped put me where i am today and uh so
i've been involved with this counter
culture
for my whole life since i was about 15
and i'm 45 now so for 30 years i've been
involved at the edge of counter culture
as a skateboarder as a you know cannabis
person and um
very very
bullish on the ability of psychedelics
to do positive things to people and now
we're finally here all these years later
where we're given the tools i happened
to get the education and now i can be
put in the position to help a bunch of
people
um
you know overcome challenges that might
provide them with a better life down the
road so that's kind of
why i'm here how i got here and i just
really appreciate the opportunity to
share uh what i know about the mushrooms
and the analytics and the science behind
it and i'm really excited to see where
all this goes in the future well thank
you so much george so if you want to
follow along with george
and his research there is but one place
to go and that is the flourish lab's uh
instagram account
and so that's at
flourish
f l o u r i s h and then underscore
labs labs
underscore
oregon so if you happen to live in
oregon and you are looking for analytics
you can reach out to george that way but
if like me you've got no need for
analytics but you're very interested in
in keeping up with uh the science and
his research there there's the place to
go
you can find more episodes of the
shaping fire podcast and subscribe to
the show at shapingfire.com and wherever
you get your podcasts if you enjoyed the
show we'd really appreciate it if you
leave a positive review of the podcast
wherever you download your review will
help others find the show so they can
enjoy it too on the shaping fire website
you can also subscribe to the newsletter
for insights into the latest cannabis
news exclusive videos and giveaways on
the shaping fire website you also find
transcripts of today's podcast as well
be sure to follow on instagram for all
original content not found on the
podcast that's at shaping fire and at
changolos on instagram be sure to check
out shaping fire youtube channel for
exclusive interviews farm tours and
cannabis lectures
does your company want to reach our
national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hotspot
shippingfire.com to find out how thanks
for listening to shaping fire i've been
your host shango los
[Music]
you