[Music]
there are lots of folks in the
regenerative cannabis Community who will
say that they have been into natural
farming their whole life and that is not
me it isn't that I was against Natural
farming it's just that I had never
really considered it I was a Midwest
City boy with a great deadhead weed
dealer and I just didn't have a need to
grow my own so I never really gave it
much thought but after I moved to San
Francisco in 1994 all of that changed
when I visited Dennis perrone's cannabis
Buyers Club I came in contact with epic
varieties of kind bud that totally
changed what I thought weed could be but
I really couldn't afford them in the
amounts that I wanted to smoke top shelf
weed is expensive I knew that if I
wanted to smoke those flavors that I was
going to have to learn how to grow them
myself
so I started learning about basic NPK
growing focused on the mineral and
chemical content of the soil and really
wasn't all that passionate about it and
I didn't really follow through
so instead of growing the fancy flowers
I now knew I wanted I decided to just
get a better job in the virtual reality
industry that allowed me a Ford to buy
that top shelf cannabis
everything changed though when I learned
about Elaine Ingham and her model for
cultivation called the soil food web
instead of being focused solely on the
nutrient composition of the soil Elaine
focused more on the life of the soil
growing cannabis went from boring
nutrient math to suddenly having a
relationship with microbes and other
life forms in the root Zone it was like
having friends in the soil who I was
getting into a relationship with and
unlike the Tamagotchi that I kept alive
at the time when I kept the microbes in
the soil alive they grew me amazing
thriving cannabis that was my kind of
relationship my new friends were
nematodes worms arthropods and fungi and
we shared the same goals
if you want to learn about cannabis
Health cultivation and technique
efficiently and with good cheer I
encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter we'll send you new podcast
episodes as they come out delivered
right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week and
videos too don't rely on social media to
let you know when a new episode is
published sign up for the updates to
make sure you don't miss an episode also
we're giving away very cool prizes to
folks who are signed up to receive the
newsletter January's giveaway sponsor is
Gaslamp seeds you've heard me talk about
them before by their old name of hemora
genetics hembra genetics is now Gas Lamp
seeds Gaslamp will award seed packs to
five lucky winners who are subscribed to
the shaping fire newsletter there's
nothing else you need to do to win
except receive that newsletter so go to
shapingfire.com to sign up for the
newsletter and be entered into this
month's and all future newsletter prize
drawings
you are listening to shaping fire and I
am your host shangolos
my guest today is soil biologist Andy
Marsh Andy is a soil Health practitioner
and focuses her efforts on soil
restoration through her business rhizos
LLC based in Texas
she studied bio-environmental science at
Texas A M focusing largely on
agricultural microbiology and
bioremediation
Andy has studied the soil food web with
Elaine Ingham and is a certified soil
food web lab technician that means that
Andy has completed all of Elaine's
foundational soil food web courses and
has gone further to earn a soil food web
certification in microscopy soon she
will also have her soil food web
consultant certification
Andy has been practicing soil
microbiology for over 12 years
during the first set we will talk about
seasonal impacts on soil and biological
activity focusing on the metabolism of
the soil changing food sources and
differences between container soil and
ground soil
the second set is the big one today as
we look in detail at the sorts of
nutrition available during winter and
discuss preparing soil with specific
compost tea Brews biological inoculants
like protozoa infusions and fungal Foods
as well as the effective use of mulches
and crop covers finally we finished the
episode in set three with a discussion
of best practices to revive your soil in
the spring in order to shorten its
transition from Winter dormancy to
actively growing your thriving cannabis
plants
today's episode comes from the
perspective of living soil and the soil
food web today we are most interested in
microbial life and the prey and Predator
relationship in the soil and how that
changes seasonally
certainly there are soil chemistry
aspects to be considered after having a
yearly soil test done but that's not the
focus today today we set aside mineral
and other amendments and focus squarely
on the preservation of biological
activity in the soil so that you can
preserve your gains from year to year
welcome to shaping fire Andy thank you
so much for having me so at the end of
the season temperatures obviously
decrease and at the lower temps life
slows down both above and below the soil
if the soil food web is cycling life all
summer so our cannabis plants can grow
I'd like to understand which aspects
slow down into the fall and winter in
the soil which causes everything to kind
of go to sleep so I guess I'd like you
to start off with a description of an
active soil food web a summertime soil
food web and then describe the
mechanisms that change and slow as we go
into winter so that as we talk about how
to interact with that
um we know we know the mechanisms that
we're talking about
sure so yeah you know with the food web
we're talking about these Predator prey
relationships
um below ground for the most part so
who's eating who and in the summer time
in a vegetative growth cycle flowering
cycle it's a very active partnership
between the plants and the microbes
below ground they're constantly
communicating they're feeding one
another and so in theory if you ha if
you've done a great job of inoculating
your soils in the spring and you've
established these relationships or
really introduced these relationships
between the plants and the microbes
there's a lot of predators eating prey
which is cycling nutrients so when I say
Predators I'm referring to things like
nematodes that's nematodes that feed
them bacteria nematodes that feed on
fungi
um and then the protozoa which are
primarily bacterial feeders things like
flagellates and amoeba ciliates as well
although and we can come back to this
ciliates are more of an an indicator
species that we use to um
provide as a sign of anaerobic
conditions in the soil and so we don't
want to see too many ciliates among the
protozoa in that ecosystem but this
brings me to the point of another
feature that's happening in a thriving
root zone is the element of diversity so
you'll have a lot of these different
types of organisms you're not just going
to see fungi are just going to see
bacteria you're going to see a little
bit of everything in your soil at that
time and so as things kind of get
colder and are going into a more dormant
state
the the main
element that is changing there is as the
plant dies back it's no longer providing
the root oxidates to kind of
be a source of fuel and energy for us
its microbial Partners below ground and
so their Dynamics change the the
microbial Partners below ground are
going to start feeding on other things
and finding other food sources and so
that's really important for us to know
as stewards is what are those food
sources do they have enough food because
in theory we actually want them to stay
as active as possible throughout the
winter and there's some reasons there's
some really important reasons for that
but in terms of what that that root Zone
could look like in the winter if we
don't consider the the microbes needs
through that period where they don't
have their plant photosynthesizing above
ground
things tend to go really dormant below
and that means you have protozoa that
are insisting and they're no longer
feeding on bacteria in general bacteria
are kind of the hardiest group so you're
always going to have your your cold
loving bacteria your heat loving
bacteria and you'll always have some
kind of bacteria activity happening in
the root Zone but it's really a matter
of losing some of those larger organisms
like your your fungal activity your
nematode activity and protozoa that we
we want to really try to keep those
organism groups active rather than
allowing them to go into dormant States
so um that's interesting because I I
thought that you were going to say that
things slowed down because of the
temperature primarily but I'm getting
I'm getting the idea that
um while yes temperature probably plays
a role that really it's about the the
abundance of summertime
food sources that are decreasing and
that is actually what causes the I don't
know metabolism of the soil to slow down
right so like in nature if you think
about a really mature forest ecosystem
one way that the trees uh in that
ecosystem continue providing for the
microbes underground that they're going
to rely on more so in spring and summer
is many of the deciduous trees are going
to drop their leaves and actually feed
that soil in a different way so it's no
longer through root oxidates but it's
through this Leaf litter on top of the
soil and that's doing two things that's
insulating the soil from those harsh
temperatures that you've referred to and
it's also providing some kind of organic
matter to feed into that system to keep
the the metabolism going below ground so
it can actually be quite busy if the
ecosystem is providing some kind of food
source and protection to the
microorganisms in the root Zone
I would think that if the food source is
changing during the winter from being
our cannabis roots and potential
companion plants to now not being
cannabis Roots perhaps still the
companion plantings but now
um you know Leaf litter and potentially
a top mulch or whatever whatever we're
going to put on the pot to help it
overwinter that that's actually going to
change the varieties of life forms that
are actually going to be active in the
soil too
it will it will certainly and a lot of
times that leaf litter or mulch that
you're topping off a container with or
the the soil itself with those are
carbon Rich
materials and so that is going to
provide more
um benefit to your your fungal uh types
of organisms so your fungi are breaking
down carbon Rich materials more so than
bacteria but they're all linked so as
one
organism starts feeding on a particular
material it inevitably creates a
byproduct that another organism can feed
on thus the soil food web everything's
dependent on everything else when when
when the pots I guess this question is
specifically container oriented but when
a container gets cold during the winter
um you know it gets it gets truly cold
in a way that
um the ground won't since the ground is
enjoying some geothermal benefits are
there some parts of the root Zone some
inhabitants that we just know we're
going to lose during the winter because
they'll cyst up because uh just simply
the the cold is enough to knock them
um knock them back into a dormant State
instead of just the losing of a their
food source
yes I kind of think of this on a good
better best scale so best case scenario
you're able to provide the root Zone
enough
fuel to and protection to actually
maintain some level of activity that's
not always possible but the second best
option would be to protect it enough
that those organisms that you do quote
unquote lose are at least insisting and
they're not actually dying which is you
know the the worst case scenario is that
the the
extreme temps or conditions that that
soil is exposed to is so severe that
you're actually killing the organisms
and you're essentially starting from
square one come springtime when you're
trying to rejuvenate that soil
interesting so
um so often we treat our containers and
sometimes even our Fields as okay we're
done with it and we just like people
just walk away from it and and you know
they get into trimming or or start
focusing on the holidays or you know
just doing anything other than farming
um because they've had a long summer but
I'm actually getting this idea now that
um you know the the that you want to
make sure that you button up your soil
properly before you walk away from it
and not to be too hasty about it because
we we want to kind of turn it from like
the the high you know the high very
active setting down to like a low simmer
for the winter because we we don't want
it to go entirely to sleep we just want
it to turn down so it it it it it eats
through the nutrition that we're setting
it up with slowly throughout the winter
so that so that when we when we when we
reapproach it in the spring we're not
we're not having to start it from a cold
start if you will there's already a low
warmth going on mm-hmm
yeah I think what you observed there
about how Hasty we can be once our
growing season is over it's really
an invitation to reflect a little bit
like I would I always encourage people
to consider
what's your relationship with that soil
that soil that you discarded or the soil
that you're no longer tending to just
because your cash crop isn't growing in
it right now and asking the question you
know are are we going to need that soil
to support our goals later or did we
rely on it this past season to produce
something meaningful for us and you know
just because the cash crop isn't
actively growing doesn't mean that our
stewardship responsibilities for that
crop are uh over
um we do have responsibilities and
there's
the biodiversity of the partners below
ground are part of what makes our crop
successful and so just you know building
a relationship and considering that when
you don't have your your crop in season
what are you doing to ensure that you're
caring for that soil system so that you
are introducing your plant to a very
hospitable new home come spring I really
like that emphasis on the stewardship I
remember a couple years back I visited
uh Nicholas over at a green um
the green Gardens in in Wolf Oregon and
and he was walking me through and and I
like it because they do a lot of food
planting underneath their cannabis
plants so they'll have cannabis growing
up top and and on potatoes growing
underneath and um uh green Source
Gardens that's it and so uh and I asked
him I said oh I bet you I said I bet
you're really going to be happy to like
walk away from the garden and and be
done with it and he says you know I I've
never really done with it he's all like
the the soil is a family member you know
and and just because
um it's we're going into winter I don't
I can't just turn my back on it
um I I need to do what I can to make
sure that it's taken care of and fed and
loved through the winter so that we're
not strangers in the spring and and like
the first part of that I may have
paraphrased poorly from him but the so
that so that we're not strangers with
the soil in the spring is the part that
really
um held on for for me me and uh and I
thought I thought that was beautiful and
and it sounds very similar to the this
idea of stewardship that you're putting
forth oh definitely I love that phrase
too to to be strangers in the spring
feels so uncomfortable and you almost
start feeling guilty at that point you
know because I've been there even even
as someone who considers themselves very
um enamored with soil more so than the
plant itself sometimes when that
planting season's over you just are
eager to get comfortable and and kind of
step away from that work for a while and
I think that's okay I think there's room
for both like we all deserve rest and we
should snatch rest when we can when we
can get it
um but there's you know finding a
balance like what does it mean to you to
stay connected to that soil throughout
the winter and finding ways to do it uh
that that makes sense to you and given
that season of of the year in life
um I think also to take it into a
non-soil example I feel the same way
when I Rush taking the plastic off of my
greenhouses in the fall and if I don't
put them away properly you know if I
don't if I don't wash them down let them
dry fold them up and like lovingly put
them back you know if it's a season
where I pull them down wet I roll them
into a ball and I shove them in the back
of the barn which you know it's not
something that I I'm ever proud of but
it happens sometimes and when I come
back in the spring I see that you know
now the the it's it the plastic is moldy
and it's and it's and it's crunchy and
it's it's all like oh you did me bad
Shango you know and um I that same thing
happens with our soil if if we if we
want to have a good start in our spring
we need to end the fall properly as well
um so let's let's talk about the some of
the differences that um that there is in
the The Changing from a a container
versus the ground and so um you know
during during set two we're gonna go
into more detail about the things we
want to do
um for our soil what whatever whether
it's in the ground or whether it's in a
container but as far as the the coming
of winter I would think that the
containers are at a much higher risk of
getting true seasonal damage than the
soil is because we have a a smaller
diverse diversity of life forms because
it's just contained in the container and
things aren't generally coming in and
out unless it's being like delivered by
you know birds or frogs or uh people
people and life forms that are going by
right
versus the the actual ground soil which
has got a huge amount of biodiversity
and also is being somewhat kept warm
just from the nature of Earth
would you agree that that those of us
who are growing in containers really
have to pay more attention because the
ground some more often than not will
cover your mistakes whereas a container
won't
yeah the ground is much more forgiving
in that way certainly and you know not
to say that we we can't also find a way
to mess that up but right by poor
practices but in general more forgiving
in ground planting and in ground
you know stewardship of the of the micro
world I think
it's like anything in controlled
agriculture or uh when we're trying to
emulate nature it's it's always
imperfect but we just do our best and so
when we have these containers
um I think definitely the two points
that you brought up are the are the most
um obvious ones you know like you have
more of that service is exposed and what
the service I'm talking about is like
the actual root zone is exposed where
that's just not the case in ground and
the the observation you made about
migration of organisms is kind of a less
obvious one to people so that really is
a limiting factor if you think about it
like even during the growing season you
don't have migration between one root
Zone and another and sometimes that can
be helpful if you have really strong
plants with great microbial Partnerships
that are thriving and then maybe some
plants that have some kind of disease
and could benefit from
um you know the migration of those
organisms from one one side of your
planting to the other and some people
would actually view that in the opposite
way it's kind of like a is this glass
half full or half empty and some people
would be concerned like oh well when you
share a root zone now you have the risk
of pathogens tearing through and that
that is also true but if you're if
you're actually growing from a
biological perspective
your decisions and your amendments are
all about focusing on beneficial
organisms and kind of taking up real
estate uh on on the root surfaces and
Plant Services as well because they
migrate below ground and above ground
all these organisms and you're taking up
real estate so that Pest and pathogens
don't even have a chance to come in so
that's really what we're doing with our
amendments whether it's in pots or in
ground but I do find that you have to be
much more diligent in any kind of
container because each each plant now is
has its own root Zone that you have to
tend to rather than one single root Zone
that has shared resources and shared
communication between the plants as well
I think that's one of the first things
that we have to give up when we start
practicing natural Farming versus
some of the more sterile kinds like like
you know certain types of Hydroponics
and such is that
um we are we don't have
sterile soil there are pathogens in
every one of our pots and and it's not
about like making sure my containers
don't have any pathogens it's about
um uh feeding the beneficials and making
sure the environment for the beneficials
are positive so that they are always out
competing the pathogens but we know the
pathogens are there it's a it's a hard
truth that's like really creeps a lot of
people out when they when they come to
regenerative style farming at first but
but you know technically the pathogens
are part of of the the food web as well
and we just want them to play a very
small role yes I agree and I feel like
there might even be an analogy here
somewhere like with our human societies
like you're always going to have a bad
egg on a team but in general that team's
much more resilient when you have a lot
of you know good healthy communicative
partners that are helping move the ball
forward you know and they might even uh
band together and say enough is enough
and we're getting rid of this parasite
that is in you know messing with our our
goals so I if you can kind of sometimes
that helps to just relate to the soil in
some ways like thinking about it their
communities similar to ours in general
you know their the systems in place are
are moving towards beneficial
Partnerships and it's only when there's
an imbalance in the ecosystem that
there's a specific set of organisms that
take advantage of that and let me just
take a moment too shingo if you don't
mind kind of explaining some of my
perspective on pathogens
um because I think it might be of
interest here please the when I think of
pathogens this is you know this is me
trying to Reef frame pathogens so I'm
I'm not perfect at you know not getting
angry when I see when I see something
that is destroying the garden but I
think of pathogens as filling a role in
the ecosystem what a pathogens
essentially doing and and why it's
evolved is that that soil is sick in
some way and it's destroying the above
ground organic matter to feed that soil
and you know in time that process of
pests and pathogens destroying the above
ground parts of the plants and we're
turning those nutrients to the soil
would set the stage for a stronger more
resilient environment that would
actually support more and more
beneficial
microorganisms and kind of do themselves
the pathogens out of their job so when
you see a pathogen it's really telling
to say oh well something's amiss here
the plant isn't actually getting
everything that it needs for me so this
is that's one way that the ecosystem is
communicating with you and instead of
trying to stamp it out with pesticides
and whatever else we can get our hands
on that is more of like a sterilizing
effect just consider what can we do to
add to the system to give that plant
what it needs in order to fight that
pathogen or eliminate it so that it's no
longer needed in that ecosystem I think
that's a really healthy way of looking
at it that that even though I mean
because our goal is to have beautiful
high terpene profile High cannabinoid
flowers that's that's the end goal
and so the if the pathogen is
challenging us from getting to our goal
it makes us want to be pissed off at the
pathogen right when actually it is
playing its role just like just like if
I get sick and I get a uh I get a a high
temperature myself and I'm like oh I'm
so tired from having this this high
temperature but but my body is
intentionally increasing the temperature
so that I can heal it's trying to heal
me and and I think that if we embrace
the pathogens as being a partner but a
partner that we really don't want to
have to do their role very often that's
probably a more holistic approach to
thinking about our soil instead of like
good guys and bad guys exactly exactly I
appreciate that analogy that you
provided as well right on so all right
great well um I think that set two where
we talk about the what to do and why is
going to be the fattest of the three
sets so why don't we go ahead and wrap
up and go to our commercial break and
then we'll get right to set at two which
is probably what most people are here
for anyway so we're going to go ahead
and take a short break and be right back
you are listening to shaping fire and my
guest today is soil biologist Andy Marsh
so without these advertisers shaping
fire wouldn't happen so please support
them and let them know you heard them on
shaping fire
there are so many seed banks nowadays
that you really have options and who to
choose not only that if you pick the
wrong seed bank you could be in for a
really sketchy ride and that's only one
of the reasons I recommend Gas Lamp
seeds to my friends and listeners who
are looking for a seed bank you probably
already know Gas Lamp seeds as hembra
genetics hemra recently changed their
name to Gaslamp seeds Gas Lamp seeds is
not just another seed bank Gaslamp is a
female operated Boutique cannabis
genetics provider that only sells
thoughtfully curated seeds from the top
names in cannabis breeding with over 60
breeders and over a thousand strains to
choose from you will certainly find
something you'll love Gas Lamp seeds has
something for everyone with over 650
feminized strains 300 regular varieties
and over 200 autoflowers to choose from
names you know you can trust like
compound genetics Humboldt Seed Company
Night Owl in house fast buds gnome
automatics and ethos
and we both know that there are other
seed banks who will take your money but
have no customer service
I invited Gaslamp to advertise on
shaping fire after hearing so many good
stories about them from my friends they
have a Plus customer service with
Lightning Fast Response times
in most cases Helene and Caitlin will
get your order out the same day you
place it most seed banks are simply not
this organized or interested in getting
your seeds to you so fast but Gaslamp
seeds cares you even get free seeds with
every order
Helene and Caitlin get it they have been
in the Cannabis growing scene for over a
decade want some extra freebies use the
code shaping fire all one word at
checkout and they will give you an
additional set of Gaslamp provided
freebies that's an extra thirty dollars
in free seeds
buy seeds from good folks who will send
you great seeds reliably every time
visit
gaslampseeds.com today that's Gaslamp
seeds
[Music]
there are a lot of good people launching
new businesses in cannabis psilocybin
and other psychedelics and it's very
strange Time For Us in the same moment
that psilocybin mushrooms are illegal at
the federal level they are becoming
increasingly legal in States across the
country these businesses leading the way
into the future of plant medicines
require specialized legal representation
by attorneys who have depth not only in
litigation mergers and Acquisitions but
also in psychedelic and other plant
medicines
green light Law Group has been
empowering cannabis businesses since
2014 and as the market has Diversified
into psilocybin and other plant
medicines green light has been right
there evolving with their diverse
clients to provide legal expertise with
a high level of legal Acumen creative
strategy and precision that comes with
an intimate and specific understanding
of both business law and plant medicine
if you are a business owner trying to
navigate the layered local and National
Drug Laws on your own you are at risk of
fumbling these confusing and quickly
changing laws complicate everything
green light law group is ready to help
you when hit with a lawsuit or because
you were shafted by a vendor or business
partner or simply because you want to
stay legal and could use some
preventative guidance before cultivating
a controlled substance as an
entrepreneur
green light law group is a collection of
folks who care profoundly about their
work and I know this is true because I
know the folks from Green Light there is
a huge difference between a big legal
firm who has decided to start
representing a few drug companies versus
working with a collection of high
integrity passionate lawyers who are
personally interested in new plant
medicines and firmly believe in their
power to heal
contact Greenlight Law Group today and
learn more about the services they can
offer your industry-leading cannabis or
psychedelics company that's green light
Law Group at greenlightlawgroup.com
as cannabis regulations become more
demanding and consumers become more
educated it is increasingly important to
avoid the use of chemical pesticides
when cultivating cannabis beneficial
insects have been used for decades by
the greenhouse vegetable and ornamental
plant industry and today many cannabis
cultivators are moving from sprays and
chemicals to beneficial insects
copert has the beneficial insects mites
and nematodes microbials sticky cards
and air distribution units you need to
partner with nature to defend your
garden
whether you manage Acres of canopy or
have a simple grow tent in your home
culprit is ready to help answer your
questions and help you transition away
from chemical sprays towards clean and
natural solutions
since 1967 culprit has assisted growers
in identifying pests and devising
reliable Solutions while providing
healthy insects and mites that will
protect your yield
since the 1990s covert has been a leader
in cannabis Pest and Disease Control
worldwide and have highly trained
Consultants to assist you in Canada and
the United States from coast to coast
with their Global Network of grower
support covert can help visit copper.com
choose your country and get detailed
information that's covert
k-o-p-p-e-r-t.com for the most
up-to-date cannabis related biological
control information you can also check
their Instagram at covert Canada
you know getting away from pesticides is
good for health and good for business
and culprit is ready to help visit
covert.com today
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire I am your host shangolos
and my guest today is soil biologist
Andy Marsh so before the break we were
talking about you know getting us all on
the same page as far as an understanding
of the soil food web what is happening
like systemically uh in the soil as
temperatures cool and kind of making
sure that we all understand that we're
not
the winter does not make the system stop
the winter makes the system slow and so
um set two is going to all be about what
can we do for our soil in what ways so
that we can turn our soil down to this
slow simmer so we don't become strangers
with it in the spring so
um what do you think about this Andy I I
was trying to figure out what our goals
are for containers and and soil going
into the winter and I and I I made this
list that we wanted the soil to be fed
warm watered drained and then undamaged
during the winter does that sound like a
pretty good list to you yeah I really
like the last one undamaged I would I
would have used the word undisturbed but
I think we're getting at the same thing
it's like basically just not trying to
disrupt that all of those organisms that
are doing their their work during the
winter
so let's start by getting rid of
something that I see all the time on
um like not not huge farms but just like
scaled regenerative Farms it is not
uncommon for me to go to a farm tour and
to see that cultivators have stacked
their large containers during the off
season and you know
just looking at it it looks like an
obviously bad practice because at the
very least we are compacting the soil by
stacking the the pots and and every time
you go up a level it's more and more
weight that's compacting the soil
um but I bet that you have
even other very more specific uh reasons
why we should not be stacking our
especially fabric pots
um uh over the winter so would we start
with that because I want to I want to
remove that as an option for folks no
sure yeah I think there's a lot of
a lot of evidence for not wanting to to
do that um I'm sure let me just first
start by kind of empathizing with why
you might find yourself doing that and I
suspect it's one kind of what we're
talking about earlier about you're done
with the growing season you're just
trying to pack things up and get things
put put away and kind of out of sight
and in a space where they're not going
to be completely drenched in snow or
whatever else so I can empathize with
wanting to stack your
pots of soil you know in a corner and
you might even think that you're doing a
good thing by removing them from the
elements in some regard
um I but the more you kind of consider
what's going on in those pots the less
of a good idea this this becomes because
you're right you are certainly
compacting the soil and that's
problematic for
a lot of reasons
um reason number one though a soil
structure is something that I get really
excited about because it's it's where
like biology chemistry and the physics
of the soil meat is like creating great
soil structure and it's something that
we're attempting to create throughout
the growing season and we whether we
realize it or not are contributing to or
or taking away from throughout the
growing season and then come winter time
if we don't realize what kind of gains
we made in terms of the improving the
soil structure and then we go and stock
these soils like that we're really
setting our we're really kind of
regressing in terms of whatever progress
we might have made
in improving that soil's structure so
yeah compaction is like a Surefire way
to kind of
um you're you're not only physically
putting pressure to the soil surface
office and creating compaction from the
top down but you're also kind of sealing
off the top of that soil so there's
limited air exchange and and limited
moisture exchange and this is what
happens in in-ground systems when we
um
compact them through any number of means
that's called soil sealing when you do
that and and whether you're doing it by
stocking pots or you know mowing a space
to too often and creating compaction
that way the at the end of the day
you're really reducing that soil's
ability to bring oxygen in which all of
these microbes that we're talking about
all these beneficial microbes really
need oxygen and the ones that thrive in
oxygen poor environments are are
pathogens
right on so so we want to make sure that
we our topsoil can get air exchange it
can get some uh you know rain and snow
and you know interact with with uh
nature as it will and
um I like what you said where you know
if we spend all summer treating our soil
fantastically why on Earth would we want
to suddenly give those advances back by
by stacking them and then crushing the
soil uh structure that we've and our
worms have spent all summer working on
exactly and that makes our job a lot
harder come springtime when we're
dealing with soil if you plan to reuse
that soil which
you know you might not you might find
that you actually need to purchase new
soil or make new soil which can be very
labor intensive and I feel like if you
the more you can do taking care of the
soil you got uh the less labor and
inputs and expenses you'll have come
springtime in dealing with that soil I'm
really grateful that the the Cannabis
growing scene as a whole has
um embraced reusing soil
um it wasn't it wasn't too long ago that
people thought that they needed to
re-buy soil for every cycle both indoors
and Out and because they wanted to keep
it as sterile as possible but sure but
but now we're realizing that that aged
older soil has with has got so much more
uh personality if you will and and it's
that biodiversity which actually makes
your cannabis taste good
um
yeah I like that
I'm like sipping on my coffee here but
yes yes I I'm glad to hear that about
about cannabis cultures that you're able
to see this shift towards uh reusing
soil and rejuvenating it rather than
yeah creating more and more sterile
environments that's a good thing all
right so if our goals for our soil is to
have it fed warm watered and drained
let's start with the FED part so
um uh many folks have got their favorite
uh amendments that they you know they've
harvested their cannabis plant and then
they will they will amend or inoculate
or add something
um before they walk away for the winter
so let's let's talk about a couple of
those and specifically you know as I was
saying in the introduction we're not
approaching today's episode
um dryly chemically like okay I did my
soil test and now I need to add this
kind of NPK kind of action we're talking
about what kinds of amendments we're
going to be doing to keep the the life
force of the living soil intact and so
by all means you know do your do your
soil tests and and react to those but we
also want to make sure that our soil
just stays alive so so let's start with
nutrition so um so taking what you said
during the first set that there are
um the food sources are changing from
the uh from the rhizosphere getting
exudates from my cannabis plant roots
and having that back and forth
relationship but now the cannabis plant
is gone and so I want to add some
nutrition so that
um Everybody stays alive in the root
Zone when the root zones are not feeding
them so what types of um nutrition as a
soil biologist do you find are are going
to be most beneficial for the folks that
we want to keep going
yeah so so one way to think about this
is to take it take an approach where
you're providing a variety of foods
because again the theme Here of the day
is going to be biodiversity so if you're
trying to cultivate nurture and maintain
a biodiverse microbial Community then
you the more different types of foods
you can provide to your soils often the
better and so one way to do that is to
take a multi-prong approach by feeding
the soils through maybe a cover crop so
that that you know something that would
survive your conditions when you're not
growing your cannabis plant anymore but
you instead come and plant a cover crop
that will feed the soil root oxidates in
lieu of your cash crop and then compost
tea is another great
option I and I would just want to take a
moment to kind of explain the difference
between an extract and a tea and an
extract is you're generally just trying
to knock the microbes off the surfaces
of solid compost so that you end up with
a liquid that has just kind of
free-floating organisms and those are
really great for soil drenches
also in containers of course to kind of
infiltrate those organisms through the
soil profile and teas are a little bit
different in that you have that Brewing
step so you so you do the same thing
where you're knocking off the microbes
from the surfaces of the solid compost
but this time you'll have a brewing
cycle where you're adding microbial
foods and you're effectively increasing
the population sizes of those organisms
and you're kind of providing them this
packed lunch so to speak whenever you
distribute that liquid onto your your
soils
and so
um I like teas as a method to feed the
root Zone in the winter time because it
has more microbial Foods in it and I'm
not so focused on inoculating because it
it is a challenging time and
um we in theory if we've done a lot of
great inoculating throughout the season
um our main goal is just providing a
food source and not so much on
inoculating of course inoculating is
always happening so it comes Springtime
I just kind of want to differentiate
that you're you'd be more focused on
introducing new organisms into that soil
but not so much in the fall and winter
and then lastly there's you know compost
and and mulch are also ways to feed the
soil nutrition and those are those are
going to be a different set of food as
well than what you might have
Incorporated through a tea and of course
course the the cover crop is kind of the
unique food source that we can't
necessarily replicate because it's
coming directly from a photosynthesizing
plant oh gosh there's so much in this in
that answer I'm excited to tear this
apart with you all right so let's go
step by step so
um so the first thing we that you were
talking about was the variety of
nutrition so so
um uh uh I'm going to ask my next
question about compost tea but right now
I'm talking about what
um like natural amendments so so are you
are you talking about adding the for
example like uh like like crab shell and
feather meal and alfalfa meal and like
things like that uh like making a blend
of that like we would when we are making
soil and then and then putting that onto
the soil as a top dress or or that maybe
will then cover with a mulch or are you
talking about specifically adding that
type those types of nutrition and and if
so
um what what varieties of that nutrition
do you think work well in Winter
um
the ones that you mentioned feel more
like they they lean towards mineral
amendments which you know do eventually
end up interacting with Biology I mean
most everything does but
um I that's where I would again kind of
take this approach to your soil Health
not strictly from this dogmatic biology
is the only thing that matters mode but
more more from an interdisciplinary
approach and and really doing those soil
chemistry reports a saturated Pace tests
and maybe even considering some of the
leaf tissue analysis that you might have
done during the growing season and those
are the things that are going to inform
your mineral amendments that you might
want to make and I do think this is a
good time to be making those mineral
amendments going into the winter and all
this this is an experiment too right
you'll you'll find that maybe you
amended the soil going into your dormant
period and then I would recommend
testing it again once you're it comes
planting time and just see like did it
move the needle and on in some areas
maybe it did in some areas it didn't and
record that stuff you know really be
diligent about
um what's functioning and what's not and
getting curious about why that might be
um so I hope that kind of answers part
of your question it does I actually
think that I just learned something
because the very nature of my question I
think is wrong so I I asked that
question with the Assumption or belief
that
um I like this term mineral amendments
that these these types of mineral
amendments that are the same ones that
we use when we're responding to a soil
test and we need to we need to round out
our soil I was under the impression
question that the microbe life also ate
these these mineral amendments and so in
my head
I was I was going to feed my microbe
life both by adding compost tea which
we'll talk more about in a minute but
also with these
um with these other mineral amendments
but but I guess it's it's probably true
that that microbe life may not even eat
minerals I mean I make if I could be
really wrong on this and and but I'm
always I'm always learning and
embarrassing myself publicly yeah on the
show anyway so so so do does the life
the the living parts of the rhizosphere
do they eat that stuff or not
yeah and and to be clear I'm always
learning too so you know just keep that
in mind but my expectation is that those
mineral amendments are really useful
during the growing season when we
recognize that there's a mineral
deficiency the because the plant is in
relationship with the microbes there's
communication happening and in
incentives being offered to those
microbes to provide the particular
minerals that that plant is deficient in
and so it's pulling it is providing that
from the minerals that we're adding but
maybe that Dynamic Isn't So relevant
come at winter time because you don't
have that same crop in you know as part
of that ecosystem this is a breakthrough
moment for me I get this so the mineral
amendments are not really for feeding
the microbes the mineral amendments are
what the plant wants and the microbes
will bring them to the plant in exchange
for exudates and other types of food
from the plant but during the winter
when the plant isn't there we don't
really need the mineral amendments
because there's no bartering going on
between the microbe life and the plant
and so
we're just trying to replace what the
microblife normally gets from the plant
right and I would say I would say more
we're not necessarily trying to
replicate exudates in any way we're
we're trying to provide foods that we
know
microorganisms feed on when there are no
living plant roots and that's in general
organic matter so like your humic acids
fulvic acids when you're brewing a tea
maybe you consider fish hydrolyzate and
you want to do these things mindfully so
I'm not going to
get in to any specific ratios or
anything here but just you know kind of
stay high level in terms of how to think
through it but when you're when you're
brewing a tea
you want to consider what what is living
in your soil and you can do this through
a microscopy assessment that's the most
a Surefire way to know what's living in
there and what's not
but you can also kind of do this through
Maybe
maybe to other indirect observations so
for instance if your mulch isn't really
breaking down like you've had Mulch on
your pots all through the summer time
and it it still looks pretty good at the
end of that season and it's not being
broken down odds are you could benefit
from more fungal activity so maybe when
you go to brew dot compost tea you're
adding more fungal Foods rather than
bacterial Foods so bacteria foods are
simple sugars things like molasses and
and honey
where the the fungal foods are going to
be more complex sugars
all right so let's let's talk more about
um the compost tea as the nutrition for
the rhizosphere
um uh and and less of it as
um using mineral amendments so if we
want if we're if we're going to be
putting the compost tea into the soil at
the beginning like let's call it late
fall
um is the idea that we want to we're
essentially trying to add
um
microbe life
to the soil via the compost tea that
um that then the
larger microbe life that's in the
container will then be eating so
essentially we're we're pouring compost
tea filled with smaller life that the
Predators that would be normally getting
its food from the plant will then be
eating
all the life forms that are in the
compost tea is is is that what we're
doing we're trying to
um sustain this predator-prey
relationship
um throughout the winter yeah yeah
that's a good way to look at it it's
like you're providing you're providing
prey organisms to nematodes and protozoa
the predators in the soil and you're
also providing that packed lunch so
um like the the foods that you're adding
to your compost tea are going to end up
in the soil once you apply it and not
just feeding the organisms that were in
the tea Brewer but now they're available
to the organisms that are existing in
the container
and and at this time of year I know
we're we're both fans of brewed tea and
also extracts but this time of year we
actually want to do a brewed tea because
we want to
um we want to increase the density of
the microbe life because we you want to
offer lots of options of of varieties of
microbe life that's going to be in the
compost tea but we also want it to be
very dense because we want it to last
throughout the winter right
yes I think I think teas are the way to
go in the winter and look you it's not
that you're doing anything wrong if you
do an extract so
the extract just doesn't have the added
benefit of the increase in microbial
activity nor does it have the microbial
Foods both of which can be of benefit
going into this more dormant period so
obviously if we if we've got a
microscope or or if we have the access
to Someone Like You who does microscopy
for other folks you know for a living
um that is one great way to know how we
want to build our fall brewed compost
because you can like literally look and
see who's in the soil and see who's
there that you want to feed and then and
then who you might want to add to the
soil to kind of round out the the
Predator prey relationship but honestly
most folks who don't have a cannabis
growing business or just home Growers
um they're they're probably not going to
do that and so can you can you give some
advice or or uh some mental structure to
what the rest of us should do to like
what would you recommend to have in our
brewed tea at for for fall
um when we don't exactly know what's in
our soil but we we want to give it kind
of a a general Buffet so that so that
um we can do the best we can without
exact knowledge
yeah I think the the biggest thing to be
aware of is that what we don't want to
do is be brewing a bunch of bacteria and
putting that on our soils and I say that
because a really common characteristic
of a disturbed ecosoil ecosystem is that
it's very bacteria dominant and when it
comes to cannabis
we want a little more balance between
our bacteria and fungi ratio instead of
it being entirely bacteria dominant so
in general fungi is more sensitive to
Mechanical disturbance certainly so
anytime we dump our containers or turn
them in any kind of way or they're
exposed for long periods of time we'll
expect to lose some kind of fungal
biomass but not but will actually see an
increase in bacterial biomass and the
reason for that is that bacteria start
feeding on the fungi that are dying off
and they kind of have a little party all
to themselves to increase their numbers
and so that that's one balance that we
want to be really careful about when
we're making our own amendments and and
we don't have the tools to really look
at a drop of that tea under the
microscope and see
whether or not we've just got a bunch of
bacteria and no predators that would be
the worst case scenario
um or if we're if we're Brewing
something that's a little more balanced
so one thing that I'd encourage people
to do
is create a what I would call a
protozoan infusion this is a method that
I've learned from the soil food web by
Dr Elaine Ingham and you you take a
healthy leaves and a different kind of
vegetation and put them down in a bucket
with uh kind of something to weight them
on top like a rock
and you can add just the tiniest bit
like a drop of honey and that's actually
going to encourage some bacterial growth
but what occurs in tandem with that is a
produce the the Predators will respond
to that increase in the bacteria
population and so
um there I if I was doing this without a
microscope I would I would go online and
do some research and see if you can find
the best time to use that kind of Brew
because there's going to be a a peak
period after you've encouraged the
bacterial growth that the protozoa will
have had a chance to respond to that and
then you can use that as a useful way to
introduce Predators into your ecosystem
um that's one thing that comes to mind a
couple others are to just focus more
heavily on your fungal foods and go
really light little to no bacterial
Foods as you're preparing your compost
teas so again you can find some guidance
online but in general humic and fulvic
acids are really useful for feeding
fungi as our fish hydrolyzate and
there's there's some others online that
I've I've yet to try but I'm sure are
just as viable
I really like this
um protozoa incubation technique that
you just described I've not I've not
come across that
um and and I like the idea that
I don't have to just make food available
and hope for the best but that I can
actually incubate protozoa and make more
of them and then pour them into the
Container this sounds like something
that I would want to do like any time
I'd want to do it in the spring I'd want
to do it like before flower when when
the plants are working the hardest and
then and then again at fall to keep
every it seems like it's a good thing
for all through the season yeah
certainly and I think any time that you
really need a nutrient boost that's when
I'd Focus the most on your Predators
because that that's who's doing that job
for you by feeding on the bacteria
they're cycling nutrients to your plant
so I think the the times and the growth
cycle that you pointed out are are dead
on interesting okay so um another thing
that you mentioned when we started
talking about like you know best
amendments for pre pre-winter
um you were talking about inoculants so
would you consider this an inoculant or
or how were you using that word what do
you think of as an inoculant because in
my head this may be inoculating my soil
with protozoa but I may not be using
that um word in the proper scientific
way
yes I think in the case of the protozoa
infusion that's certainly an inoculation
technique you're trying to introduce a
specific organism or group of organisms
into the soil that's how I would Define
inoculation
and when I mentioned earlier that I
wouldn't be so focused on that again
it's not that inoculation isn't
happening with your compost tea it's
more that your focus and intention and
again relationship with what you're
doing is thinking more critically about
the foods you're putting into that tea
rather than what you're necessarily
growing and and um
growing in population in that tea so in
the springtime I'd be much more focused
on looking at the samples from my
compost tea and making sure I know how
much fungi is in there because if I and
how much protozoa and
Etc are in there because that would
matter more to me come springtime due to
all the nutrient cycling that I'm going
to rely on for my plant growth but in
the winter time I'm more concerned about
feeding the microorganisms below ground
and less concerned about what they're
going to do for my plant because my
plant's no longer there right on
um right all right so then
so we've talked about the the mineral
type amendments we've talked about
adding uh complex uh brood compost teas
so that or there's a an array a buffet
of foods for our life forms in the soil
since they're not going to be getting it
from the plant and then and then this
delightful protozoa infusion which I
like want to make one immediately
um and so so the last category that I
want to talk about are
um uh what kind of a role at this point
would you think that natural farming
fermentations like you know everybody's
talking about Korean natural farming and
you know fermented plant juices things
like this that that we are making which
are in a way
um kind of like incubated
um nutrition and in some of them even
incubated like hormones if we're if
we're going to be using
um
you know like a fresh grown tips from
that we that we harvested in the spring
or something like part of me thinks oh I
should add some of that stuff in the
fall to to keep some of that zesty life
force in the soil but some of it is also
me thinking
it that's adding the wrong kind of
encouragement at the wrong time of the
Season that that's more of a spring
thing and and I might not want to be
using those types of ferments as a
um going into fall root drench or
something like that at this time of year
so is there is there any role for that
kind of a incubated fermentation
I think you're you're on the right track
with that like I wouldn't
again I don't think that there's
anything that would go wrong necessarily
by adding uh those fermented plant is it
fermented plant juice that they call
that yeah yeah
um and and just to be clear I'm not
fully up to speed on knf methodologies
I'm fascinated by them and I think
there's a lot of
um things in common in terms of what
what we're interested in doing uh from a
biological perspective whether you come
from the the k f side the soil food
website or you know there's there's any
number
um even if you're like really focused on
mycorrhizae like we're all kind of
generally interested in in similar
things and so
um I think with the what what I know
about the fermented plant juice approach
being more focused on those plant
boosting signals that that would make
the most sense to me in the context of
the growth cycle when you need that kind
of activity so it again it's it's not
that you're doing you'd be doing much
harm it's more like are you spending
your time and energy producing a thing
that's going to actually
help the soil at this current state that
it's in and I don't know that that would
be the best use of your time is focusing
on on those types of amendments right on
that well said and that also discourages
me because
um I I have been hanging out with other
folks and we've been talking about it
and it's not uncommon for me to hear
people say well
I had some extra fpj in the fall and so
I just put it on the pots and and
that might actually it might be better
to waste it or hold it for the spring
instead of throwing it on the pots and
kind of confusing the system at that
point yeah because it could I I don't
know I imagine that it could confuse the
system if the microorganisms are
receiving these
um you know chemical signals from that
were derived from a plant that was
actively growing but they're not
actually that they're not actually
supporting an actively growing plant
then it might kind of uh be unnecessary
and
um you know it's hard to know what's
really going on you know without digging
into some academic research if it's even
been done on this kind of stuff but I
think if you can preserve that Amendment
and save it for spring that would be a
much better use of that Amendment
um this is totally conjecture but it
could totally be the case that um the
microbe life become aware of those
chemical signals and then they think
that oh there must be a plant around
sure and so then they start looking for
exudates and when when we don't want
them looking for exudates we want them
focusing on eating other other you know
Predator prey relationship life forms
it's like it's like when you go past
somewhere and you smell somebody's
barbecue but it's like you're not it's
not your barbecue so you're not getting
barbecue and now you're like just hungry
and annoyed yeah right now now you have
to go out of your way to go find
barbecue yeah all right so so let's
let's move on to uh top dress mulches so
um uh
there are different mulches with
different goals and to my best
understanding
um the the two big reasons we use them
are number one to uh create some kind of
warmth at the top of the container or on
our field
um over the winter and then and then
also that as it breaks down it is uh
biologically active and kind of like a
slow drip of interesting nutrition into
the soil
um would you agree with both of those
and would you add anything to that list
I I think I would use the word
insulation like I I you know it's it's
really creating a barrier between the
environment like the ambient
temperatures and the soil Atmos or soil
sphere in the root Zone
um and then yeah it's creating
biologically active I'm
I feel like
um we might get into it but to answer
your question directly I wouldn't add
anything to that list at this time
um
we're going to talk about cover crops
you know when we when we segue to the
next topic so this time I'm talking more
about
um I guess I'll say not actively living
plants and so
um what are some of your favorite over
winter mulches
one word and that's aged I just want
aged Mulch and if I can find much that
is from my region as locally as possible
that's ideal because in theory
they those
um
yeah indigenous microorganisms thank you
yeah they'll they'll have the the
organisms that can survive your your
local environment
um just colonized on their surfaces and
I say aged because the younger The Mulch
the more resistant it actually is to
microbial activity which is not what we
want so like in the Landscaping industry
it's really common to use very young
mulch to use cedar mulches or other
mulches that have a lot of secondary
metabolites that deter breakdown and
that's for aesthetic reasons but of
course here in cannabis we want to
actually be eating the soil with our
mulch so the more aged generally the
better I'd say the minimum you'd want
that mulch to have been kind of sitting
somewhere as wood chips for a minimum a
year ideally longer
all right so I like that you know you
kind of just systemically over the top
said whatever your mulch is we want it
to be old which I like because we all
have access to different things
depending on our bio region right and so
so you want to use wood chips fine we
want them to be old though you want to
use Forest Duff fine we want it to be
aged for stuff you want to use old grass
clippings fine but we want them to be
old so the the idea is what whatever
that you've got
um is usable just make sure that it's
matured enough so that it breaks down
properly
yeah and I think in the case of things
that might break down faster than wood
derived or or lignin
based materials so as you mentioned the
grass clippings like that you wouldn't
want those to be aged a year at all
um I think you could you could uh
with something like grasses or any kind
of like vegetative biomass that you chop
down and kind of I've seen people do
this with like flail mowers the chop and
drop method I think that's viable to
just set it and leave it it's it's
better than removing a lot of that
material if it's already if it's already
in place like if it's in C2 and you are
chopping and dropping I think that's
totally appropriate rather than the
disturbance that would be caused if you
were to remove that material and try to
age it somewhere else now you you might
decide to actually compost that material
and that's a whole other thing but as
far as a mulch purpose goes I think a
chop and drop method is just as well
when I have heard people talk about them
using mulch to keep their containers uh
warm over the over the winter
um it's funny you mentioned earlier that
it's it's it's used like kind of as an
insulator and I'm like oh that makes
sense too but I always thought that the
reason we were using it to air quotes
keep our pots warm is because the mulch
as it rots it's
um it's warm right you know like a warm
compost pile and I actually thought that
it was that as it broke down it was
creating a warmth like a heat Source at
the top of the pot and now I'm
understanding that it's really more
about like being a like a a Band-Aid if
you will on the on the wound where you
removed the plant and you're kind of
like sealing it up
um what at what point is it too much of
a good thing because in the in the first
set you were talking about
um we we don't want to over seal our uh
the tops of our pots right and so we
wanted to be able to engage with the the
atmosphere and the rain and the air to
some degree but but we also want there
to be like a nice thick layer so will
you will you speak to I guess uh the
thickness of the layer and what kind of
attributes we want our mulch to have so
that things like water and air can go
through it kind of talk to us about what
what the attributes of a good mulch are
so that when we look at what we have
available to us where we live we can
judge our mulches
okay great okay so the first thing that
comes to mind is the size of that
material so if it's too large
it it doesn't provide as much protection
you might have large gaps for instance
um I'm thinking of like maybe something
that's like really thick straw but you
it's it's not very finely chopped and
you you'd have
um you'd have to put a little bit more
of that material layered in order to
really effectively mulch a space
um and then there's also
um the the fact that you want this
breaking down so like the thicker that
material is
um if it's really chunky wood chips for
example even if they've been aged
um that might not be optimal you might
want them to be I'm just kind of
eyeballing things around the room right
now but maybe uh two inches long by half
an inch wide would be like the North
Star and you know give or take an inch
on either side but the the point is you
don't want bark essentially like four
four inches long by three inches wide
would probably be getting too too large
for the kind of mulch that we're
interested in here
um also avoiding the hydrophobic
conditions so this still applies even
when you're mulching so we it's kind of
ironic because you mulch a soil surface
to try to avoid evaporation loss as well
maybe that's one that we can add to the
the reasons for mulching is to avoid
evaporation loss from the soil surface
um among the other two which was
insulation and keeping things
biologically active but uh the The Mulch
layer itself can actually go hydrophobic
if you really neglect it so making sure
that it it is getting some amount of
moisture so if there aren't any rains or
any precipitation that they're actually
getting watered in some way because they
really mulch layers really can compact
similar to soil
and provide a hydrophobic surface which
can become problematic
and then
um let's see other features in mulch
those are those are the two that are
coming to mind a shingo so I'll kind of
turn it over to you and see if you have
any questions about that I do um I'm
getting this picture hearing you
describe how
um we we don't want it too chunky but we
don't want it too fine it kind of
reminds me of of that uh that old
example where where the the college
professor holds up a jar with marbles
and it says is this is this full and
everybody goes yeah it's full and then
and then and then he adds uh something
smaller than Marbles and yeah and it
fits in between he goes is it full now
they're like yeah and then he adds water
and you're like oh so so I'm kind of
thinking that a blended mulch is is
probably going to be our best practice
where perhaps you have
um some semi-chunky things that are age
wood chips and then some and then some
smaller things that maybe is Forest Duff
and leaflet Twitter and then maybe
um you know something else like like a
powdered biomass and so that when you
put when you put it all together
um in a ratio that that looks good to
you you have you you have some of each
you can kind of blend those in a way
where there is enough room for airflow
and for water to get in and it's not a
sealed thing but
um but it's by blending two or three
mulch things together that you actually
come up with the optimum mulch for where
you live I like that I like that because
it Harkens back to variability you know
supporting biodiversity so I think
that's definitely again I think of these
things as either good better best or
having a North star and just aiming for
that don't beat yourself up if you can't
get your hands on you know four
different feedstocks for your magical
mulch concoction but but the more more
variability the the better in general
and that that does apply to this the
size and the source of the mulch yeah
all right so before we go on to cover
crop let's let's talk about what I did
this year
um uh get a little get a little free
Consulting out of you
um so I I did something I thought about
it a little but I didn't think of it a
lot and I probably should have waited
until after
um we recorded this episode but I had
access to a whole lot of
um
a CBD hemp biomass this year where where
they just take the whole plant and they
um they essentially wood shipped the
whole thing together I don't know why
they did this exactly but um they had it
and they they offered it to me for free
and I said great so so I'll take it and
and I'll figure out some kind of
fertilizer for it or something but then
I noticed that
um you know I didn't have anything set
aside to mulch the top of my pots going
into fall and so I put about an inch
layer of this uh pretty finely powdered
essentially chewed up cannabis like amp
plants and I just put like an inch layer
on there because in my thoughts were
um it would it would insulate it it
would let the water through
um if there's any snow that we get this
year it'll protect the soil from that
cold shock and then as it rotted oh and
this was this was aged this is this this
material was probably about three years
old and so and so at as it breaks down
since I already know it's a hemp plant
it's probably going to be packed with
the nutrition that my plants want next
year and so so great
um except for the fact that it wasn't
you know from my Island and so the the
imos won't be accurate I thought that it
was going to be pretty good but now I'm
starting to think that because it was I
put a an inch of fine granular powder on
top that it might actually get wet and
kind of like push to together and
actually create an oxygen seal and I
might actually want to like remove that
what are your thoughts well there's so
much there okay I'm like writing down
notes as you're talking about that so
the first thing that comes to mind and I
just want to mention it in case it
applies to anyone listening is that this
material
um it's on but until you said that it
had been aged my original concern was
that it would still have a lot of
nitrogen in it and that that's just of
concern because it would start actively
decomposing or composting really on top
of this soil and generating heat so when
you were talking about earlier your
perception of mulch actually creating
heat the only time that that I would
expect to see that happening is if the
the material that you're mulching with
has a high nitrogen content and it and
effectively what's happening is it's
being broken down by a lot of bacteria
and so you're having a bacterial Bloom
and not so it's generating the Heat and
going back to what we talked about
earlier that's not necessarily in the
best interest of our plants right and in
fact in a really worst case scenario if
you had if you use a high nitrogen mulch
uh product too thick you could actually
create a little anaerobic environment
and have again very worst case scenario
you could have like a combustion issue a
crop up because what happens in an
anaerobic environment is a lot of those
those microbes are generating alcohols
and compounds that it will once oxygen
does get back into that system can
become flammable at certain temperatures
so
um so again just like kind of using a
North star and a South Star if you will
um that that would be like just a word
of caution I don't I wouldn't use high
nitrogen materials as a mulch with the
exception of that chop and drop method
now when I say chop and drop I'm
thinking of it in terms of
green vegetative biomass that you're
dropping on top of a mulched an already
wood chipped type of mulch so it's kind
of a layered effect so you have a carbon
it's not in direct contact with the soil
and I think that I just want to clarify
that that would probably be
um
not the best case of a mulch situation
if you had like a high nitrogen
vegetative plant decomposing directly on
top of the soil got it and that that
Harkens back to the the one guide rule
you said which was aged you know so yes
yeah yes if I follow yeah and so so yeah
there's some instances where maybe
um maybe you can get away with it yeah
not being aged but just be mindful that
it's not actively
composting on top of your soil and so in
this case you've dealt with all in
theory you know I don't know what
happened during those three years but
you've dealt with a lot of the nitrogen
in that case and I imagine any kind of
resins or things that would create a
hydrophobic
um
you know seal from a a chemical
perspective but now the concern is the
fineness of this Mulch and just like in
clay in clay soils that become compacted
it's all those platelets that line up
really snugly together and create this
seal
um in in the soil and create compaction
layers and so that might be happening
with a really finely chopped source of
mulch and in that case I think if you've
put you said you put it on about one
inch yeah
I think you could maybe gently mix in a
chunkier mulch Source instead of
I mean and you know you're you're there
with all the context in person so you
you know how bad it is or isn't but if
it's
um able to kind of be moved around and
judged a bit if you will then I would
just I would just add in some chunkier
Mulch and maybe something a little more
carbon rich but just as aged and uh just
to add some of that variability right on
good uh thank you for that um as far as
how things age
um do things have to be interacting with
the environment to age or does it simply
need time to go by so the contrast I'm
making is somebody who's got a pile of
wood chips in the in the you know corner
of their yard and they're getting rained
on and uh you know warmed up by the Sun
and you know they are they are aging and
breaking down versus
um for example this this biomass that I
was referring to that um it had just
been sitting in plastic bins in a
shipping container at this hemp farm for
three years and they're like we need
space will you just take this stuff and
get rid of it and so I did
can something air quotes age in a
plastic bin not exposed to the elements
time is passing but biology may not be
happening
this would be a matter of moisture
mostly and then also when was that
material harvested before being mulch so
I'll kind of walk you through my thought
process on that the first thing is
whenever it's harvested if it's if it's
a green if it's in a green vegetative
state as opposed to you know and and
field AG you have a lot of crops that
send all their sugars down out through
the roots and then the above ground
parts of the plants become this like you
know Brown like dormant state and it's
no longer photosynthesizing it's really
no longer living above ground
so that is a carbon-rich source and if
you were to harvest that material I mean
I assume this would happen with a
cannabis plant right you could just
leave it in the I don't think people
really often do this but if you left it
in the ground you left it in your
container and let it die back and then
you come and chop it and mulch it that
is that is going to be more carbon rich
and far less of concern from the
nitrogen perspective that we were
talking about but if you harvested it
when it was green and then chopped it up
you'd really have to dry that material
this is where moisture comes in you'd
have to dry it before storing it in
plastic bins so that because if you were
to just uh you know chop it when it's
green and then mulch it while it's green
and then put it in a plastic bin even if
it had a lid on or lid off of it whether
it had a lid on or off it would probably
be too moist in that volume and start
getting funky and you'd start losing the
night the nitrogen
um in that material because it's
actively breaking down and it'd probably
be doing it in a pretty stinky way which
is often anaerobic so
um you'd really want to dry that
material on a tarp or something and then
you can put it in your your bins and
save it but it's not it's no longer
Aging in terms of decomposing anymore
and sometimes that's desired like I do
this whenever I want to save a high
nitrogen
material for a future compost pile that
I'm not yet ready to build but I want to
make sure that it actually maintains its
high nitrogen value and the only way to
do that is to dry that material before
storing it and if you don't you just
lose all that nitrogen and then it would
it would uh become anaerobic and
problematic in that way so I know that
was a lot of information so I'm going to
check in right on
um uh this is really interesting I've
never actually thought about mulches as
as much as we have really dug into them
today and I just I just looked at our
timer we've done almost almost an hour
second set like essentially on mulches
and yeah and so um I'm glad that like
you know we really the goal of this was
really to get people to understand
um how to think about mulches so that
people can use whatever they have near
them right
um because we don't we certainly don't
want people to like purchase stuff and
ship in their mulch like there's mulch
all around us unless you're living in a
city and then and then maybe still then
um but I I think that
um
we have effectively gone through mulches
that so people can think about what do
they want in it how am I going to age it
how am I going to apply it and so this
kind of like system of thinking through
it can be applied to wherever folks are
so so I think I think that uh even
though it went longer than I thought we
were going to we definitely hit the mark
so that's a win yeah okay good all right
so um what I think I'm gonna do though
let's uh let's move um talking about
cover crop to the third set and and wrap
up this set right now and go to
Commercial and then and then we'll pick
up with uh cover crop
um uh when we come back so
um uh you are listening to shaping fire
and my guest today is soil biologist
Andy Marsh
for years organic cultivators have been
looking for a peat moss replacement peat
moss has long been the go-to soil
amendment for water retention and
container growing but organic Growers
are recognizing now that peat moss is an
unsustainable resource and the mining of
peat bogs destroys Wetland habitats and
releases sequestered carbon but peat
moss works so well that many have
continued to use it now there is finally
a revolutionary replacement for peat
moss that provides better benefits while
being a sustainable choice
pit Moss sounds and acts like peat moss
but instead of being mined from fragile
ecosystems is actually made from
upcycled organic paper and cardboard
headed for landfills
pit Moss is excellent at retaining water
in your substrate and creating air
pockets and Tiny living environments for
microbes pit Moss instantly increases
aeration nutrient absorption and Water
Conservation too
carefully and locally sourced pittmoss
is the result of decades-long research
into the use of recycled paper fibers
pittmoss is lightweight and easy to use
and pit Moss is an earth so it won't
change your pH
available in a range of preparations
including a nutrient enhanced blend and
an organic soil conditioner with no
added nutrients pit Moss is also
available as an animal bedding for
horses chickens and small animals
you can save 15 percent with the
discount code shaping fire one word no
caps when shopping on pitmoss.com so go
to pittmoss.com now to learn more that's
p-i-t-t-m-o-s-s.com growing healthier
stronger more sustainable plants pit
Moss
one of the reasons why no-till cannabis
growing is so valued by Farmers is
because the mycelium networks in the
soil remain established from year to
year and we know these fungal networks
are essential because they are the
nutrient super highways that extend far
and wide in the substrate to feed your
plants the trouble with growing in New
Living soils or Blended cocoa substrates
is that it takes most of the plant's
life just to create these mycelium
highways
dynomico endomycorrhizal fungi inoculant
reduces that time and gets your plant
eating a wider array of nutrients faster
and it's three times the concentration
of the other popular brand in the U.S at
900 propagules per gram of two fungal
species selected specifically for
cannabis cultivation dynomica is the
result of 30 years of research and
trials at the volcani agriculture
Research Institute in Israel it has also
been vigorously trialed by cannabis and
food Growers across the U.S
dynamico is now available at Grow shops
and on Amazon in the United States I
love using dynamico to both speed up the
growth of the mycelium networks in the
soil but also as a biostimulant to make
clone cuttings more viral you can see
side by side showing the comparative
growth on their Instagram at dynomico if
you demand reliable growing results and
appreciate the importance of an active
root Zone in creating a thriving plant I
encourage you to check out dynomico.com
and use the store locator to find out
where you can get yours that's
d-y-n-o-m-y-c-o.com
shaping fire listeners can get 10 off
any size of dynomico on Amazon or
dynamico.com by using the discount code
shapingfire one word no caps
whether you are starting with new beds
or pots or if you want to add some Zing
to tired soil choose dynamico to
maximize your plant's potential
dynamico endomycorrhizal inoculant
online cannabis seed Distributors often
seem to be all the same but Multiverse
beans constantly Works to provide you
with cannabis seeds and a buying
experience that you won't find elsewhere
Multiverse beans Works directly with the
Breeders to secure as many packs of your
favorites as possible so that they have
your favorite beans long after others
have sold out some shops simply buy
breeder minimums but I get messages all
the time from breeders saying some
version of Multiverse has to buy my
entire run
at multiversebeans.com you can find rare
cannabis seeds from Night Owl seeds
including the dark owl sub label
Mephisto genetics Square One genetics
Robin Hood seeds and Ethos and so many
others
Multiverse also initiates projects with
breeders to secure exclusive packs that
you simply won't find elsewhere
Multiverse founder Paul lall sees
himself not only as a curator of the
best cannabis seeds available but also
as a collaborator with breeders trying
to bring novel crosses to the market
that his customers are asking for
Multiverse beans also creates exclusive
stickers for their popular seed
varieties that are available free only
when you order those seeds from
Multiverse
check out their stickers like the badass
recent slap for Mothman by gnome
automatics on Instagram at Multiverse
beans and finally the freebies as you'd
expect Paul sends quality freebies with
every order and when you spend at least
150 dollars Multiverse allows you to
choose your freebies from their special
selections
you can get a 10 discount off regularly
priced items when you use the discount
code shaping fire all one word at
checkout
sign up for their mailing list to be
eligible for their monthly seed giveaway
worth 250 dollars so go to
multiversebeans.com now for a buying
experience you won't get anywhere else
welcome back you are listening to
shapingfire I am your host shangelos and
my guest today is soil biologist Andy
Marsh so here we are with the big finish
we're going to start off by talking
about cover crops that we bumped from
set to and then we're going to talk
about
um uh good strategies for for waking up
your pots in the spring
so that you can preserve all your gains
from the prior year so so Andy when it
comes to cover crops it seems that there
we kind of need to make a choice about
whether or not we want to do a mulch or
a cover crop because the mulch would
then be on top of the cover crop and if
we have the mulch on top We're Not
Really Gonna I don't think going to
plant the cover crop into the mulch so
it really is a you got to pick one right
I think it kind of depends it kind of
depends on your cover crop and how it
like its morphology because something
really delicate and low growing I agree
with you you probably wouldn't want to
double up on those two or really I just
encourage like a light mulching in that
case
um but I think you can I think I think
mulching in general even if you're
light-handed about it is always a good
practice and that you can you can do so
effectively with your cover crop so so
if you're doing something that's really
really short
um you'd have to use a lighter hand but
if you did something that was like a
bigger Plant say for example like a
while it's not my favorite a lot of
people really like red clover
um you could potentially start your red
clover and once it has grown above the
tops of your containers then go and add
a mulch
um beneath the red clover and so then
that way you're having both
yeah that way you're having both and in
some cases depending on your mulch you
could get away with mulching lightly
before that cover crop germinates as
long as it's light enough and they're
they're able to get the microclimate
they need to germinate
um you might find that you can get away
with that so the way that the way that I
think about cover crops is that it's a
really intimate exercise with your
cultivation it's a it's a very
um specific practice for you within the
context of your particular cultivation
practice okay so it it's an exercise and
understanding like critically thinking
and then researching plants that might
make sense for your specific context
I like that idea that it's that it's
something intimate and and it's very
much to your your kind of growing style
and your growing preferences for example
one of the reasons that I don't
personally like red clover
um is because it grows up into the lower
branches of my cannabis plants and so um
so I personally don't use it but but
people who aren't growing in you know
smallish containers like I am where I've
traditionally been in in seven gallon
containers but moved up to 20 versus
some of the regenerative farms in
California that are using 300 gallon
um
grow bags well they've got they've got
lots of room for red clover in a big bag
that size whereas for me I need more of
a a petite uh cover crop because there's
there's just not a lot of surface area
in a in a 7 to 20 gallon bag exactly
yeah I agree with you so let's talk
about the the things that we're hoping
the cover crop
um uh is going to do for us so the one
that you've you one that you mentioned
earlier in the set is that
um it helps keep the rhizosphere alive
because uh it is a plant and it is
feeding the microbes through its root
structure so I would put that probably
at the top of the list of of the good
thing we're wanting for it to do
um the second a second thing is
something we talk about on the show a
lot which is it helps the the top of the
soil from going hydrophobic because each
one of those little
um stems that are going into the soil
are providing a way for water to get
into the soil and create these like
little Tunnels for them to get down into
the rhizosphere and then the third one
that we talk a lot about the show is
that if if you if it happens to be a
cover crop with a canopy there's a
there's a space between the top of the
soil and the and the canopy of the cover
crop which creates its own kind of Bio
region and can trap moisture and be a
home for uh uh you know insects and
others that live on top of the soil so
they you know you can have a more active
food web over the winter
um so those are the three things that I
most think about but I bet you've got
some more so what what are other good
reasons to have a cover crop yeah I love
that last one I think of it as like a
habitat just like you described
I would add that the cover crop can also
provide additional nutrients into the
rhizosphere and not just through the
exudates that are feeding the microbes
but in other ways so like your legumes
for example anything that's able to fix
nitrogen is a really strong example of
this but there's other plants that will
be able to bring about
more calcium or maybe maybe taking up
something that you're you actually have
too too much nutrient and you actually
want to remove that excess through a
cover crop that would kind of fall under
phytoremediation and cover crops can be
really useful for that so that would be
the only thing that I'd add to your list
there you had a great list
um would you just explain for folks who
are are like you know they're listening
to this episode because this is all new
to them would you just explain nitrogen
fixing what that goal is
short oh gosh I love this topic so much
so you're gonna have to keep me
keep me concise okay all right but but
in general uh nitrogen fixing plants are
a miracle to us because nitrogen the
only way to get nitrogen
into even just into biology in general
including you and me so first of all
nitrogen is the backbone of amino acids
and proteins we all every living thing
requires nitrogen and
the only way that nitrogen gets into
life forms is from from the atmospheric
nitrogen going through some kind of
process in the soil and getting into our
food web okay so
um nitrogen it has a triple bond it's an
N2 molecule atmospheric nitrogen is so
that means one nitrogen atom is
connected to another through a triple
bond and it's really really difficult to
separate the two to then allow it to
become something like a a nitrate and be
taken up into plants and so what's
really cool is that these nitrogen
fixing plants like legumes as well as
some free living
organisms that do nitrogen fixing
outside of plants entirely is that
they've found a way to break that Bond
and start this the cycling of nitrogen
into the system
and so by using these plans it's
essentially capturing wild nitrogen and
and packing it into your soil so that
your plants can use it next summer yes
exactly fabulous so um all right so so
that's probably enough on cover crops
there
um so let's let's move on to what was
going to be the start of set three
before we we bumped cover crops over
which was I was going to start with this
very dramatic question
um let's talk about worst case scenarios
that um that we want to avoid with our
containers and
um I could really only think of two
which would be number one your container
freezing solid
um because I don't know this for sure
but I would think that
um you know unlike the the ground which
will probably not freeze solid because
of the ambient warmth that that the
Earth has as a container could actually
freeze solid to the point where I'm
guessing it could it could wipe out huge
swaths of of the microbes
um is that true
yeah definitely I mean the microbes have
water in them and under freezing
conditions they would crit you know
those water molecules would freeze and
effectively kill them so
um that that would be bad news to have
to have all the water in your pot that
essentially freeze
and then the second thing I I considered
was that
um you kind of want to be aware of the
containers to make sure nothing gets
deposited in the on the top of the
container that might cause uh the
biology be thrown out of balance
um and I'm not like entirely certain
what that would be like I was I was
trying to think of like you know you
know passing animals feces like you know
a dog or something like that but you
know I I would I would tend to think
that the pot would be able to to deal
with that very likely but then I was
thinking about like you know one of the
farm hands laying there you know a can
of soda that's partially Rank and then
it gets knocked over by the wind and now
suddenly you've got half of a Diet Coke
in your soil and so so you probably just
want to like like just be aware and you
know occasionally walk your field and
just make sure that that
you know chaos has not arrived on the
top of your containers yeah when you
mentioned that just now I was thinking
of somebody tossing out the last little
bit of coffee onto their plants thinking
like oh here's some nitrogen and it's
like okay that's that might be fine here
and there in really small quantities but
if you if it's always the same plant
that's closest to wherever you're
standing in the field at the time that
you finish your coffee like if it can
become a problem so just you know being
mindful yeah
um what do you think about the idea of
Home Growers because like this is this
isn't something that scales well
probably
um but I've got a neighbor who actually
uh has got a hole dug in there on their
yard and they do uh five twenties every
year
um and they they put their 20 gallon
pots like they bury them and so
um in their in their thought the
geothermal temperature will keep the
rhizosphere in the pot like safe and it
also allows the migration into the pot
of other diverse life forms that are
already in the soil because the the oil
the hoil the hole that he dug is deep
enough that
um he's got about I don't know maybe
eight or ten inches of soil that he puts
on top of them and so he by his theory
it's actually he says he says it's
inviting
all of these
um soil inhabitants from his yard to
like come on in come on into the
Container for the the winter there's all
sorts of like interesting Foods here
that you don't normally get and so he
attracts all these things and then when
he pulls them out in the spring
um they don't have to wake up they're
they've kind of been awake all winter
and they've got more biodiversity what
do you think of that that's cool I I
like I like the idea of that for sure I
think it all it all is sound to me and
just hearing about it and I think
there's yeah the the only reason that
that would work is because he's taken
good care of his pots and created a
habitat for organisms to be interested
in enough in uh joining right so right
the invitation is good yes yes I think
that's really neat and the fact that
um it's buried and able to
stay warm and much warmer than if it
were exposed above ground is um I mean
it sounds labor intensive to dig such a
large hole but you know if you have the
means and
um I say go for it yeah he's he he's a
retired person with a lot of time on his
hands and he loves he loves to Tinker
and experiment so I like going over
there all sorts of odd odd
labor-intensive things so good neighbor
to have yeah totally
um so earlier in the show we talked
quite a bit about
um how to devise a fall compost tea
um
once it gets really cold and things are
you know things are frosting over and
maybe we're starting to get you know
nights in the 30s and stuff
um I'm guessing we want to stop adding
compost teas because we don't want to be
packing our containers with water once
they start getting cold because that
extra water will expand and could
actually cause damage to the pot so I'm
thinking we we want to do what you know
the the big compost tea before the frost
and then don't add any more water or is
the position like actually making sure
they get watered over the winter is good
because they're less likely to cyst up
what are your thoughts on that
I think you want to be mindful of
moisture levels because if they get too
low you will have some loss in your your
microbial populations but
um you know I'm holding space for the
idea of it freezing through which is
hard for a Texan like me to really
empathize with because I I've never
experienced it firsthand but I I'm sure
that happens up north
um and it's probably when you least
expect it so I I'd say trying to find
some kind of middle ground and if that
means keeping things pretty moist on the
front end but as those temps get colder
and colder and there's a greater risk of
freezing then yeah that you back off and
you make sure that priority number one
is that you're not
complicating any of your equipment
um by freezing and also not killing off
any of the organisms that are freezing
it's kind of like are you going to lose
them to freezing or are you going to
lose them to them not getting enough
water and it's your job to be in tune
enough with when you choose to pull
which lever and that's probably a big
bio region question as you pointed out
in my head
um you know pots never run out of water
because I live in the Pacific Northwest
and my winter is all rain but if you
happen to live in the part of the
country where your Winters are cold and
dry well then you know you actually
might have dehydration issues so it's
good to it's good to make sure that you
are cultivating for where you live
certainly and you could just as another
option you could consider
uh removing the soil from your pots I
don't know if you tell me if this is a
feasible idea but having that in contact
with soil whether you're slightly
burying it or just kind of mounding it
somewhere in a really thoughtful space
Maybe behind a wind break or an area
that's like pretty well protected but
you'd you'd be able to
again have migration occurring in that
scenario and have a better chance of the
the microbes surviving in in some
capacity and less concerns about
freezing the only downside to this is
the amount of disturbance so then when
you come in in the spring you're
disturbing that soil in order to put the
soil into the pots and and that's not
ideal but it's also again comparing that
reality to what happens when you leave
that pot exposed all winter long and I'd
say that that disturbance might actually
be the lesser of 2 two evils there yeah
that's interesting when you when you
first suggested that my thought was oh
my gosh it's just going to wreck the
mycelium networks but if let's say you
live somewhere that gets really cold
like um
like I imagine Montana to be okay right
like I've seen enough movies where you
know nature just seems to freeze solid
and and so if you've got extreme
situations like that a a 10 gallon
container on your deck it probably
doesn't have a chance right and so and
so if you were to make a pile of all you
know 10 gallon containers of this just
the soil yeah you'll beat up the
mycelium networks but at least they'll
all they'll all essentially be huddled
together for the cold season yeah I
agree it's it's again just kind of
thinking critically about these things
and comparing one option to another and
not getting too dogmatic about it just
because you saw someone on Tick Tock
swearing by their method of
overwintering their pots doesn't mean
it's the best method for you yeah right
on um all right so uh let's go into this
uh last area which is let's talk about
waking up the pots uh in the spring so
let's assume that we we did all the
things right
um we did a a late C season fungally
dominant
compost tea and then we also did a
protozoa infusion in the fall and then
we had a really nicely Blended top Mulch
and then we were growing a cover crop
that was helping keep the microbes fed
over winter and so now we find ourselves
in the spring and
um
we want to transition our pot back to a
position where it's ready for us to
bring in our clones or our seed starts
and and we want them to just like
immediately get into this wonderful
relationship uh and reform a rhizosphere
and take off so what what hints would
you give us to ease that transition for
the microbes from where they're getting
their food and the plant to be warmly
embraced by the soil
um yeah so so it's important at this
point that you're not providing too many
synthetic nutrients I mean
really we if we're thinking biologically
we don't really want to be using many
synthetic nutrients at all
um because they can kill microbes but
especially during this early
establishment phase it can be tempting
and so I just want to note that
when we when we provide those nutrients
directly to the plant it's disrupting
that engagement between the microbes and
the root oxidates the the plant is only
going to generate those root oxidates if
it has needs that need to be met by the
microbes and so that's why I just want
to caution against getting too attempted
by providing some kind of synthetic
nutrient boost and instead focusing on
yeah maximizing the inoculation and your
job is to make introductions you're
bringing in the microbes so that they
can start responding to those exudates
so similarly you don't necessarily need
to be all that focused I'm providing a
lot of microbial Foods because we want
them to be getting their Foods now from
the plant and start creating that
relationship
so would that make a suggestion that we
we don't want to do a heavy spring
compost tea
I think I think you can do you
definitely want to do a compost tea but
this time be more focused on the
inoculation and so this is where
extracts might actually be become of
Greater interest to you
doing more frequent extracts rather than
big batches of like
nutrient-rich tea and and I say this in
terms of
maybe you know you can certainly do a t
but don't go don't go too heavy-handed
on it because your goal is if you find
yourself tempted to be adding tea
um super regularly in the spring maybe
start alternating with an extract and
again an extract is just the microbes
you're not adding Foods you're not
having a brewing cycle
um it's just less dense yeah
um uh Jeff lowenfell's uh says that
early in the season you you want your
microbes to be you don't want to make
them lazy you don't want to make it too
easy for them you want them to get to
work and that sounds like what we're
describing here
um same with the plants yeah we want
them building
um not not laying around because there's
all this easy free food exactly yeah
that's that's the right on right on
um is is there anything that we need to
do or is there anything that we can do
that can support them changing the food
source uh from the compost tees to back
to the the roots exudates and such or or
does that just they probably prefer the
exudates and so as soon as we put a
plant in there
um it will they will naturally just
switch on their own you know because
we're just trying to decrease as much
transition time as possible right right
and and there is a level of patience
that's always required here because
you're taking a very young plant that's
not yet pumping out lots and lots of
exudates and so
um because of its limited capacity to
photosynthesize it has a small surface
area to do so
um so I think just tapering off and
knowing that like leading up to planting
day
um to go really light-handed like little
to no microbial foods are being added
during that time you did that work in
the winter to get your microbes through
winter and have food to sustain them but
but now as you're transitioning into
planting you're you're going to back off
in terms of feeding the the micro Foods
again so that when that plant gets in
there they can start creating their
relationship and once it gets to a
certain stage
um
there shouldn't be a limiting factor
anymore so you know you might in in
terms of using my microscope to look at
these things of what's really going on
in the root Zone you might see like a
drop in your biomass during a phase
where you've put a young plant in into
the Container but it it kind of turns a
corner at some point once it's really
photosynthesizing and pumping out those
sugars to feed the microbes it's funny
because it's um it's fall and I am not
thinking about you know growing right
now right now I'm feeling tired from the
summer and I'm glad I'm not like you
know farming right now however you know
you talking about these like healthy
thriving pots and these young plants I'm
like ooh like start the season start I
love I love thinking about and I'm like
whoa whoa whoa whoa we got we got five
months man like chill out like we've got
a while but um you know there is
something inherently exciting about
thinking ahead to the a fresh season
every year you'll you'll look like you
have imaginary plant friends if you're
out there attending to your pots with no
plants in them but I think that's just
as well right on
um well Andy thank you so much for being
a guest on shaping fire this is um I
I've always been interested on things
that I can do to get a a jump start on
the on you know next year but I I'm
usually I'm thinking about well let's
let's make an fpj let's make a
fertilizer let's make sure that the
compost is going and um the idea that I
can pay attention and use intention with
the soil that is in my containers and
the Earth so that
um I don't have to put in as much work
every spring to get the micro machine
pumping along
um I'm glad to have you know a better
understanding of how to do that as well
yeah I think all of these things too the
the cover crops the mulching the adding
of the microbial foods and the
inoculation the biology itself they're
all contributing to so many different
areas that benefit us so it's not just
about plant nutrients it's also about
that soil structure we talked about
earlier and I I think that's really
undervalued or it kind of goes
unrecognized a lot of times come
springtime just how valuable that it can
be to have a pot that's been nurtured
and has a really healthy structure
that's prepared to become home to that
young plant it's kind of like moving
into a neighborhood that has a good vibe
and lots of friendly neighbors as
opposed to something that's you know
neighborhood that's been really
neglected and and desolate wow that's a
great example excellent right on well
let's let's let's all get to making good
neighborhoods for our uh for our plants
to move into in the spring so thank you
so much Andy I really enjoyed our
conversation
me too thanks for having me if you want
to find out more information about Andy
Marsh
um there are two great places to go
um first uh you can go to her Instagram
which is at soil is sexy and uh her
Instagram's a lot of fun not only do
will you learn lots of
um you know good best practices for
taking care of your soil
um but there's all sorts of interesting
uh microscopy posts and uh great like
pictures of of slides and such and so if
you are either interested in microscope
science or
um actually don't know much about it
like me it's a great place to start
where you can you can pick up
interesting things without it
um you know necessarily like you having
to read a whole book you can get get
little bits here and there and it's it's
fun to follow along
um now if you are more serious than that
um you definitely want to check out
Andy's subject stack which is uh
rhizos.substack.com so that's rhizos r h
i z o s where you're gonna find more of
her uh writings and scientific thought
than the kind of you know Instagram
which is a little bit sometimes science
light sub stack is is where you're going
to want to go when you decide you want
to you want to read something serious
that's rhizos.substack.com
you can find more episodes of the
shaping fire podcast And subscribe to
the show at shapingfire.com and wherever
you get your podcasts if you enjoyed the
show we'd really appreciate it if you
would leave a positive review of the
podcast wherever you download your
review will help others find the show so
they can enjoy it too on the shaping
Fair website you can also subscribe to
the newsletter for insights into the
latest Cannabis News exclusive videos
and giveaways on the shipping fire
website you also find transcripts of
today's podcast as well be sure to
follow on Instagram for all original
content not found on the podcast that's
at shapingfire and at changolos on
Instagram be sure to check out
shapingfire YouTube channel for
exclusive interviews farm tours and
cannabis lectures does your company want
to reach our national audience of
cannabis enthusiasts email hotspot
shippingfire.com to find out how thanks
for listening to shapingfire I've been
your host shangolos
thank you