[Music]
without a doubt the most important group
of folks in the cannabis scene are the
cannabis patients of course I am happy
for everyone to have better access to
cannabis but for me helping defend
patient access to clean and legal
cannabis and making sure they are
educated in how to use it is my driving
force even though I'm not a doctor
because I interview so many doctors and
I bother to read the scientific papers
that come out about cannabis medicine
lots of folks approached me at cannabis
conventions at the grocery or even on
the ferry back home to Vashon on Island
to ask for suggestions and relieving
their symptoms of this or that in most
cases I have read something or done an
interview on a particular topic and have
something helpful to say some topics I'm
particularly deep on and I'll teach
those to small groups one of the most
asked about topics is Parkinson's
disease Parkinson's has become
incredibly common and there are a lot of
good people getting bad information
about how best to use cannabis for
Parkinson's relief today we're gonna fix
that if you want to learn about cannabis
health business and technique
efficiently and with good cheer I
encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter will send you new podcast
episodes as they come out delivered
right to your inbox along with
commentary and a couple of the most
important news items from the week and
videos - don't rely on social media to
let you know when new episode is
published sign up for the updates - make
sure you don't miss an episode
also we're giving away very cool prizes
to folks who are signed up to receive
the newsletter there's nothing else you
need to do to win except receive that
newsletter so go to shaping fire com2
sign up for the newsletter and be
entered in this month's and all future
newsletter prize drawings we have an
extra giveaway this episode because we
are moving into home gardening season
our friends at Dinah myko asked me to
help them give away several hundred
retail sized bags of their end of my car
I saw one occupant you'll hear more
about their great product during the
first commercial break but for now I
just want to give you the URL of Dino my
co.com forward slash shaping fire that
is a link to a page on their website
where they are collecting addresses to
mail out these samples for absolutely
free they have
committed to sending out at least 300
packages to the shaping fire audience
this is a very popular soil starter so
do not delay in filling out the form at
dyno my co.com Ford / shaping fire you
are listening to shaping fire and I'm
your host Shango Lowe's today my guess
is canvas researcher and educator Zoe
Sigmund Zoe travels the us teaching
groups and writing articles on
cannabinol Pathak medicine she is the
former program director at project CBD
org and is presently science editor at
broccoli Magazine she has built out
educational content focusing on
scientific information about cannabis
for organizations like Pharma and
groundworks industries Oregon Health and
Sciences University and Hudson hemp
Sigmund has also testified about CBD and
canvas regulation to the FDA and
regularly speaks about cannabis and
cannabis science to patients medical
professionals and consumers today we're
going to talk all about Parkinson's
disease the first set explains what
Parkinson's is the second set explains
how cannabis works in the human body to
relieve Parkinson's and the last set is
about proper dosing protocols and best
practices for using cannabis in
real-life applications our goal is to
provide actionable information for
Parkinson's patients and those who love
them welcome to the show Zoe hey Shango
how are you doing great thank you so
much for giving us some of your valuable
time I know you're on the road and I
appreciate you being with us thank you
so much for having me on
so Parkinson's disease and a handful of
similar afflictions are often put in a
basket together because they share many
of the same causes and symptoms so so
let's start there to make sure that
we're all on the same page about what
we're gonna be talking about today one
of the most prevalent visible symptoms
of advanced Parkinson's disease is the
vit is the tremors usually starting in
one hand and then and then unfortunately
spreading from there what are some of
the signs of Parkinson's that people
commonly become aware of first yeah I
mean the tremor really is the first sort
of noticeable physical sign of
Parkinson's
unfortunately at that point the disease
is pretty far progressed really early
signs that I have come across our
constipation and a loss of spell so
they're very subtle symptoms early on so
it really is sort of when the tremors
start that people start to think oh
maybe this is Parkinson's disease that's
interesting I had not heard about the
the loss of sense of smell and and you
know for a lot of people I think that
they go you know maybe that's a stuff
nose or maybe it's allergies or
something or age you know yeah yeah yeah
and and as we know what by the time the
tremors have arrived you're all you've
already lost so many dopamine creating
brain cells that we're already far down
the path so yes that point you've lost
60 percent of the dope name
dopamine-producing neurons so it's it's
a lot yeah it is a lot and and usually
by the time people get to cannabis they
are they have already you know
Parkinson's is already part of their
life they've already been going to
doctors for it
they've been they've got a diagnosis and
they are they are weighing treatment at
this point and but I know I don't want
to give symptoms short shrift because
we're gonna be talking about the
symptoms a lot more later on when we're
going to be talking about how cannabis
can help relieve some of those symptoms
so so why don't we do a little more of a
review of what those symptoms are likely
and let's let's talk about them in two
categories would you first talk about
the the early maybe less recognizable
symptoms like a sense of smell and then
and then and then talk a bit more about
the the ones that were more familiar
with like the shuffling of the feet and
and and and bending over a little bit
and as for people who maybe are not the
Parkinson's patient themselves who are
listening but maybe have a loved one
let's let's let's dig into that a bit so
some of the early symptoms and these are
also secondary symptoms later in the
disease program
our digestive issues so not just
constipation but oftentimes like nausea
or loss of appetite mood disorders are
also common anxiety and depression this
is both it could be an early symptom
it's also we're adults
and people who are getting older often
have a little bit more anxiety about
getting older and so again it's not like
a concrete way to determine whether or
not you have Parkinson's pain sleeping
issues these are all things that can be
indicative of Parkinson's disease early
on but they're also just common ailments
as we age with other conditions so it's
difficult to say if they're directly
connected to Parkinson's but they are
common in people with Parkinson's
disease as the disease progresses into
the motor symptoms you of course get the
tremors there is something called
Braddock hadisha which is a slowed
movement so it's this inability to
consciously move quickly
there's rigid muscles impaired posture
loss of the ability to control your
movements completely and so it's like
you have muscle spasticity you have
tremors all of these like different
involuntary movements are in slightly
different categories but they are they
can look pretty similar to people who
are not experiencing them and that's one
of the challenges right because I want
one of the things that everyone
recommends for Parkinson's is to start
treating early but so many of the early
symptoms could be so many different
things you know swallowing problems and
chewing and eating problems and sleeping
problems and you know constipation so
many different things can be causing
these including like other medications
that you may be on because all this
stuff is side effects from other
pharmaceuticals and more often than not
the patients that I have worked with it
is when the tremors start to arrive and
and you really have the difficulty with
motor function tremors the slight
hunching over the shuffling of the feet
you can't get in a good step it's it's
somewhere in there that either they or
their spouse or a good friend points out
hey do you know that you're like you're
doing this and that's when people start
going oh man maybe this maybe this isn't
just something from the pharmaceuticals
maybe this as a package is is something
more serious right right and that's a
really hard realization for a lot of
people and you know it's sort of at that
point you could go in and the doctor can
test for some like biomarkers of the
disease but if you're already if you're
already there
it's sort of like okay here we go yeah
so all right so so let's talk about more
the the underlying what Parkinson's is B
and I know that it gets gray real fast
because yeah real fast because you know
we don't we don't really know however it
is common to be around you know with
Parkinson's groups and have people say
that it's it's difficult for them to
figure out sometimes which of their
symptoms are causing the Parkinson's and
which of their symptoms are coming from
the Parkinson's and and I often offer a
delineation to patients that it is not
really as effective to try to determine
which is causing which it's it's almost
like these things are a package that
start to show up at the same time and
and and the same attributes that that we
use to diagnose Parkinson's also cause
these other symptoms and it's very often
difficult to figure out you know which
came first the chicken or the egg right
which came first the symptoms or the
Parkinson's so right so will you kind of
get to the heart of the matter and let
us have a better understanding of what
the state of the science is about what
Parkinson's is and its cause to the best
that we know and so that we can start
teasing out symptoms from cause totally
so I mean you are
to say that it gets gray really quickly
so there's a couple of underlying causes
for Parkinson's disease Parkinson's
disease neurologically so it's
characterized by the loss of neurons
that produce dopamine in a particular
part of the brain and therefore a loss
of dopamine in other parts of the brain
later on it's also marked by an
accumulation of these protein clusters
called Lewy bodies now that really is
sort of like a dead end there's not a
lot about Lewy bodies out there it's
just sort of like here's a biomarker of
Parkinson's disease if you see an
accumulation of this kind of protein
this is associated with this disease for
the most part people and researchers are
focused on the dopamine aspect of the
disease the loss of dopamine how to
prevent the loss of the neurons that
produce dopamine how to preserve
dopamine that's hanging out in your
brain and other than that the
pathophysiology is very grey we don't
really know what factors play into the
development of Parkinson's disease it
could be genetic it could be
environmental we know that there are a
couple of symptoms neurologically that
are associated with Parkinson's but only
Parkinson's what you were talking about
earlier where Parkinson's disease is
included in a lot of other
neurodegenerative diseases those
diseases are often associated with neuro
inflammation oxidative stress
excitotoxin a calcium channel
dysregulation a bunch of things in the
brain that show that something is not
functioning properly and so Parkinson's
exhibits all of those things as well
and so that actually brings us back to
this idea that that Parkinson's and it's
kind of related ailments you know you
know parkinsonian syndrome and you know
the things that are all kind of often
put in this basket they're very often
diagnosed by symptoms instead of what's
going on in
the body which which is always strange
right when you like other diseases like
like lupus is another one of those right
there like yeah we don't know what it is
but if you've got this basket of
symptoms we're gonna we're gonna call it
lupus so that we can talk about it right
and but but to distill what you just
said down to what I think is the
essential kernel the essential kernel
seems to be that that for the for the
for our conversation today Parkinson's
is the the loss of neurons that caught
that that create dopamine and it is the
lack of the dopamine in the dopamine
serotonin cycle that starts to cause the
the more serious aspects that we are
more familiar with with with you know
motor and mobile what skills all right
exactly
so oddly enough when we in during next
set and when we start talking more about
how cannabis acts on Parkinson's
explaining to patients that that in
essence the this bigger picture that is
threatening their life it comes down to
these these dopamine creating neurons in
my experience patients feel a certain
amount of I don't know they're glad for
the clarity of purpose right because
Parkinson's is kind of is this big
amorphous thing that that there are many
opinions on but when you bring it down
to this one thing that that you're
losing these neurons and that's what is
inhibiting your life patients tend to
give me the you know they get this look
of ah this like an aha moment and
they're like oh now I can now I can kind
of focus on understanding this because
I've named my monster and I know what it
is
right yeah and in those terms that can
be much easier for someone to approach
it to because you know most of us have
heard of dopamine and so if you say hey
this is what's going on people have
something to grab onto and then you know
sometimes I have found peep
who have chronic illnesses like
Parkinson's disease become huge nerds
about their own condition and so it's
just it's an incredibly useful tool to
say like hey here's one of the causes
this is what we think is one of the
causes of Parkinson's disease so if
we're using Parkinson's disease as the
primary let's say the flagship ailment
in this basket
can you elucidate a little bit what the
other ailments in this basket might be
like I've already mentioned parkinsonian
syndrome but honestly that's the only
one I other one I know there often
I mean Parkinson's disease research is
often done in conjunction or sort of
lumped together with things like
Huntington's disease or multiple
sclerosis or Alzheimer's disease so
there they all have different
pathophysiology is there all you can
definitely tell in the body in the brain
that these are different conditions but
as far as treatment and the underlying
causes they're often discussed in the
same sort of way there's specific
research in each of those areas of
course but especially when you get into
how cannabis interacts with these
diseases it's they're frequently
presented together so I know that you
are very hardcore about keeping up on
the up to the date research on a wide
range of diseases that you're very
focused on is there a lot of research
going on with Parkinson's and cannabis
right now I mean clearly there's more
science going on now with cannabis and
there there has been ever in in human
experience before but still technically
since cannabis is a Schedule one drug
and illegal at the federal level it's
difficult to get cannabis studies
approved at all and so clearly there's
Parkinson's research going on but how
about Parkinson's in cannabis research
yeah actually I'm pretty impressed with
the amount of cane
research that focuses on Parkinson's
disease and it largely focuses on CBD
and I think that as CBD has become more
and more legal researchers are really
latching onto it as a compound that
could be beneficial for a number of
diseases including Parkinson's that said
the evidence that cannabis could be
useful for Parkinson's has been around
for a really long time out like since
the late 19th century before Parkins
dizzy Parkinson's disease was called
Parkinson's disease there was evidence
that cannabis at that point canvassed
indica could help relieve some of the
spasticity and shaking of the condition
that is now known as Parkinson's disease
and so there are older pieces of
research that focus on cannabis without
being specific about the cannabinoid
content or THC there's also evidence
coming out about endocannabinoids minor
cannabinoids like THC bcbg all of these
things are areas that researchers are
starting to look at and from the
perspective of Parkinson's I think it is
because Parkinson's is one of the most
common neurodegenerative diseases in our
older population
and so there's a in addition to that
there isn't really a good treatment for
it there's there aren't medications at
this point that slow the progression of
Parkinson's disease there are there's
really one or a very small handful of
medications that can treat the symptoms
but the disease will continue to
progress and so researchers are really
dead set on trying to find compounds
that can slow the progression and I
think that that's why there's been so
much interest in cannabis and
cannabinoids yeah absolutely and you
know it's interesting that you mentioned
that that cannabis has been used for
Parkinson's before it was recognized as
Parkinson's you know going back a
hundred years
because you know when you see these old
antique bottles of cannabis you're
reminded that you know historically
cannabis has been you know some 70% of
the pharmacopoeia of what we humans used
for everything right and and the idea
you know that the fact that cannabis
being taboo is only really something of
the last you know 70 years or so and
though I must admit there is it is crazy
to see some of the concoctions that are
in these bottles you know though oh my
god you'll they'll throw you know
cannabis and morphine and cocaine in the
same bottle and they'll say this is
medicine and alcohol right you're like
oh you know that that will definitely
cure what ails you so but this brings us
up to where we where we are right and
I'm sure most folks are most curious
about how can they actually use cannabis
to treat their Parkinson's and maybe
roll back its progression and we're
gonna start that in a moment for the
second set so let's go ahead and take
our first short break and rebuy be right
back you are listening to shaping fire
and my guest today is canvas researcher
and educator
Zoi Sigmund one of the reasons why
no-till cannabis growing is so valued by
farmers is because the mycelium networks
in the soil remain established from year
to year and we know these fungal
networks are essential because they are
the nutrient super highways that extend
far and wide in the substrate to feed
your plants
the trouble with growing in new soils or
blended cocoa substrates is that it
takes most of the plant's life just to
create these mycelium highways Dino
Michael endo mycorrhizal fungi inoculant
reduces that time and gets your plant
eating a wider array of nutrients faster
and it's three times the concentration
of the current leading brand in the u.s.
at 900 propagules per gram of to fungal
species selected specifically for
cannabis cultivation this new product
called Dino my co is the result of 30
years of research and trials at the
volcanic a Greek ultra research
institute in Israel it has also been
vigorously trialed by cannabis and food
growers across the US since the product
first arrived here last year
may have already even heard about
dynamite go by its original name
dynamite now Dino Maiko is available at
grow shops and online in the United
States for the first time I love using
dynamite go to both speed up the growth
of mycelium networks in the soil but
also as a bio stimulant to make clone
cuttings more virile you can see side by
sides showing the comparative growth on
their Instagram at Dino Maiko if you
demand reliable growing results and
appreciate the importance of an active
root zone in creating a thriving plant I
encourage you to check out Dino Maiko at
Dino Maiko comm and find out where you
can get yours that's dy n oh my co.com
whether you are starting with new beds
or pots or if you want to add some zing
to tired soil choose dynamite go to
maximize your plants potential Dino my
co endo mycorrhizal inoculants did you
know that shaping fire has a fabulous
youtube channel with content not found
on the podcast when i attend conventions
or speak or moderate panels i always
record them and bring the content home
for you to watch the Shango lo c youtube
channel it has world-class speakers
including kevin Jodrey of wonderland
nursery talking about breeding cannabis
for the best terpene profile nicholas
Mahmud on regenerative and polyculture
cannabis growing dr. Sunil a girl on the
history of cannabis medicine around the
world Ben Cassidy of true terpenes on
using terpenes for health in your
everyday life Reggie Godinho of steep
hill on the cannabis genome and Jeff
Lowen Fell's on the soil food web
there are several presentations from dr.
Ethan Russo on terpenes and the
endocannabinoid system and even my own
presentation on how to approach finding
your dream job in cannabis and why we
choose cannabis business even though the
risks are so high as of today there are
over 100 videos that you can check out
for absolutely free go to youtube.com
forward slash Shango 'lose or click on
the link in this week's newsletter this
message is for folks who grow cannabis
I'm talking to home growers patients and
commercial growers - I'm probably
talking to you when you plan out your
next growing cycle be sure to check out
Humboldt see
sighs seeds at Humboldt see si.com Caleb
Inspectah and his family have lived in
Humboldt County for over a hundred years
for the last 40 years
three generations of his family have
cultivated extraordinary since amia
cannabis in Humble Mendocino and Trinity
counties because of his lineage and the
hard-earned experience that comes from
growing up smoking and sifting large
populations of cannabis plants in
Northern California
the seeds you'll cop from CSI will be
winning genetics based on long time
heavy hitters and updated Andrus if
today bring out new and exotic traits
and better yields go ahead and ask
around
Caleb also known as Inspectah and
Pirates of the Emerald triangle is a
breeders breeder he reaches way back and
works with significant strains
recreating them in new and interesting
ways that you'll love is a toker
and a grower as well as offering you
some surprises that will delight serious
seed traders and cultivators Humboldt
CSI goes as further step and selfs all
these chemo VARs so you know all the
seeds will be female these are not
experimental feminized seeds Humboldt
CSI releases some of the best female
seeds available anywhere and it will
show in your garden folks grew quite a
bit of CSI humble gen-x last year here
on Vashon Island and everyone was
pleased the patients had beautiful
female plants and didn't have to call
half of their garden as males the folks
growing for the fun of getting high grew
colorful flowers with exceptional bag
appeal and great highs and breeders had
seven out of seven females in a pack
which gave them a lot of phenotypic
choices take a moment right now and
visit Humboldt CSI dot-com you'll find
an up-to-date menu of both feminized and
regular lines along with photos and
descriptions
that's Humboldt CSI comm welcome back
you are listening to shaping fire I'm
your host
Shango Louis and our guest this week is
cannabis researcher and educator is Zoe
Sigmund so cannabis is a long history of
being used not only to relieve the
symptoms of Parkinson's but also rolling
it back because of the cannabis plants
ability to cause neurogenesis the
creation of new brain cells at
dopamine so before we talk about how
cannabis can help in the short term with
symptoms abatement how about we start
with your explanation of how cannabis
can help combat Parkinson's long-term by
revitalizing the endocannabinoid system
and making more of these neurons that
are so important totally and there's a
couple of parts of that question so as
far as cannabis and neurogenesis this is
an area that is of great interest to
researchers we start seeing how neuro
degeneration is can be caused by things
like neuro inflammation oxidative stress
so these are like basically little
compounds that float around wreaking
havoc and cannabinoids have been shown
to combat those underlying causes of
neuro degeneration and so by being
anti-inflammatory by being an
antioxidant cannabinoids are able to
help preserve your brain's ability to
create new neurons which is incredibly
important as we grow and change it's not
like our brains suddenly completely stop
creating new neurons it's part of being
alive but in people with Parkinson's
disease you see that neurogenesis take a
nosedive and so if you can do anything
to prevent the underlying causes of a
neuro degeneration you're doing
something good and so there's been all
these individual studies in rodents and
in cell cultures that show that THC and
CBD and CBD can help retain neuronal
health in a number of ways so this is
both preserving or protecting from
oxidative oxidative factors and also
preserving things like synaptic
plasticity cells have life cycles it's
really important that they complete the
entire life cycle and Parkinson's
disease and other neurodegenerative
diseases interrupt that life cycle in
one way or another
and cannabinoids and the
endocannabinoids system are responsible
for regulating
life cycles and so manipulating the
endocannabinoid system can help
reestablish or preserve some of the
ability for cells to have a more normal
life cycle the endocannabinoid system is
a promising therapeutic target at a
number of ways for Parkinson's disease
that has to do with its relationship to
the dopaminergic system so the system
that produces dopamine and this is sort
of like a cutting edge of research it's
super interesting it seems like unmanned
amide which is one of the cannabinoids
that our bodies produce an
endocannabinoid is vital in the cycle of
creating dopamine and it's integral in
healthy adults and then in Parkinson's
people who have Parkinson's disease we
see a number of impacts on the
endocannabinoid system depending on the
stage of the disease
so in people who are sort of
pre-symptomatic before they have the
motor issues associated with Parkinson's
disease we see a depression of the
endocannabinoid system so these are
lower levels of endocannabinoids and
endocannabinoid receptors which makes
researchers think like huh something is
going on potentially like this system
could be a target for therapy and then
as the disease progresses to the
intermediate and advanced stages let's
start to see those motor symptoms you
get an overexpression of
endocannabinoids and endocannabinoid
receptors and the thought is it could be
a compensatory reaction something has
happened in the early stages of the
disease that causes the endocannabinoid
system to under express which allows
things like oxidative factors and
inflammatory factors to proliferate in
the brain and that makes the disease
progress more quickly and then as it
progresses the endocannabinoid system
sort of like snaps back up and starts
over expressing all of these things
which is actually kind of good
because an and amide has been it's been
shown that when you do things chemically
that make an and amides stay around
longer you're also making dopamine and
stay around longer and so you kind of
want more an and amide hanging out so
you're preserving whatever dopamine your
brain is still producing if you're a
Parkinson's patient so it gets a little
technical but yeah it's there's there
are many reasons why the endocannabinoid
system is a target for therapeutic
promis in parkinson's cannabis and the
endocannabinoids system are obviously
deeply interrelated and what's
interesting is in a lot of therapeutic
settings and in Parkinson's disease
there's evidence basically suggesting
like the endocannabinoid system is much
larger than we currently accept it as
being so most people will characterize
the endocannabinoid system as consisting
of these two receptors cb1 and cb2 the
endocannabinoids our bodies produce and
the enzymes that synthesize and break
down those endocannabinoids but we see
that plant cannabinoids and
endocannabinoids interact with a bunch
of different receptors in our body and
these receptors could be very important
in helping to mitigate some of the
effects of Parkinson's disease and some
of them are orphan receptors recently
actually very recently CBD was sort of
in the parkinsonian research news as
being beneficial because it interacted
with an orphan receptor receptor called
G pr6 and it was an inverse agonist
which means it makes the receptor do the
opposite of what it usually does which
is good because activating the receptor
causes an increase in parkinsonian
symptoms and CBD by making it do the
opposite caused a decrease in those
symptoms and so you start to see like
very specifically like all of the
effects that different cannabinoids
could have on all these different
receptor
that could be beneficial or not
beneficial for Parkinson's disease all
right so let's unpack a little bit of
this because it is it is complicated but
your your your explanation is is on
point but I also know that that when I
when I publish episodes that are about
specific diseases or ailments we attract
new listeners who have come just for
this one episode right and so first
thing I want to do is I want to address
the endocannabinoid system and the way
that I usually explain it to non
cannabis crowds it's is that the
endocannabinoid system is what keeps the
human body in homeostasis it keeps
everything in balance it's it's kind of
like the second grade teacher in a
classroom and when the second grade
teacher is in the classroom the kids are
generally well-behaved and doing what
they're supposed to do but as the
teacher goes outside of the room into
the hallway eventually one kids gonna
crack up and then another kids gonna
crack up and then and then different
kids crack up first and then eventually
though you know the the it's it's
chaotic and and that's kind of what
happens with the endocannabinoid system
as well where the endocannabinoid system
once it becomes weakened perhaps this
particular body system starts working
less well and then another one Purdue is
is less well and so then we start
getting oxidation or or or inflammation
because our body is not doing its its
general housecleaning that keeps the
body in homeostasis and so since these
cannabinoids that we're talking about
which which naturally occur inside the
human body as endogenous cannabinoids
meaning produced inside the body we turn
to cannabis for Fito cannabinoids
because we can get them from a plant and
they do the same thing which is signal
right these these cannabinoids are being
used to signal to turn switches on and
off in different parts of the body which
is
essentially doing this homeostasis were
so so if we have a dearth of these
cannabinoids and our body is not
producing them the switches cannot get
turned on and off and it's as if the
second grade teacher is leaving the room
and the kids start to act up and it is
when these this particular set of kids
if you will that you have just described
when when it's these kids that stopped
working in the brain the ones that cause
Parkinson's symptoms this is why we want
to treat Parkinson's with cannabis
because we want to give the body the the
communication tools to turn these
switches on and off and essentially act
like the second grade teacher in the
room how do you buy you like that you'll
buy that yeah all right all right I
think I mean like it makes a lot of
sense is it this is how a lot of
researchers look at finding compounds to
treat conditions
what's wrong with the cells what can we
do to make the cells do what they
normally do and like this is true of
Parkinson's you know the primary
treatment for Parkinson's disease is
leave a levodopa which is a precursor to
dopamine and so basically researchers
were like okay people aren't producing
it up dopamine they get these symptoms
that are related to Parkinson's disease
this medicine can help brains produce
more dopamine and it's very similar with
cannabinoids you know if the
endocannabinoid system is not
functioning property properly not
producing endocannabinoids or receptors
how do you make it do that will you
introduce a compound that interacts
directly with it and what's interesting
about THC which is the primary plant
compound that interacts v1 and cb2 the
sort of best-known receptors in the
endocannabinoid system is it it could
actually jumpstart the endocannabinoid
system if it is underperforming this was
a theory put forward by dr. McPartland
and guy I don't know five years ago
which is sort of like there might be
a clinical endocannabinoid deficiency
that's responsible for a number of
conditions and taking THC could sort of
snap everything into place on the other
side of it
chronic use of THC down regulates the
cb1 receptor and which doesn't really
seem to be much of an issue for chronic
cannabis users and and this is
completely theoretical at this point so
please this is just from me reading
research everyone listening if if
Parkinson's disease in its later stages
is character an overproduction of cb1
receptors perhaps finding a way to down
regulate those receptors could help to
restore some balance I don't know that's
an interesting and novel approach I have
not heard but they have - that's an
interesting idea yeah you know one of
the things that I think it would be
worth teasing out here a little bit is
so far you and I've been talking kind of
generally about this basket of
cannabinoids that we're going to take
from the cannabis plant and and and
somehow these cannabinoids support this
endocannabinoid system but I think it's
important to to make sure people
understand that these these various
cannabinoids each have their own job
which is one of the reasons why it's so
important to take whole plant
preparations you don't you know you
don't want to just take a cannabinoid
isolate like pure CBD crystal or
something like that because that that is
not treating the whole endocannabinoid
system which is what our goal is and and
you'll you'll know these the specifics
on these better than me but to get us
going on at for example THC is an
anti-inflammatory CBD increases the
number of signaling molecules to to turn
on and off these these switches a CBG
you know while it decreases the
experience of neuromuscular pain it also
offers patients the confidence to feel
that they can overcome
the stresses that their body's under so
you know each one of these cannabinoids
you know taking one on its own doesn't
get us where we want to go it's the fact
that all of these different cannabinoids
including the ones that we have not even
figured out exist yet these different
cannabinoids when they work together in
concert they are rehabbing our body's
basic synth systems bringing them into
homeostasis which by definition will be
decreasing the underlying lack of
dopamine that would that we call
Parkinson's mmhmm yeah totally I mean
it's really important it's really
interesting to look at it bringing this
back to Parkinson's too because we're
still really figuring out what causes
Parkinson's disease we're also still
figuring out what we can do to make it
better and so sometimes it's like you
have to do three things at once to make
the symptoms of Parkinson's disease
decrease a good example of that is in a
rodent model they had a cb-one
antagonist so something that blocked the
effects of cb1 and they also had a Fon
hitter so they had a compound that
basically made an and amide the
endocannabinoid that our body produces
stay around for longer so they black cb1
Maydan and amides to stick around
bloggers and saw a decrease in symptoms
associated with Parkinson's disease in
rodents and it's like you know you're
looking at at least three different
targets in that model P par gamma C b1
and then the fine habitue
it was only when all those things were
together that you saw the results you
know so it's just combining these things
can be very very powerful and it's not
what Western medicine is used to doing
and on top of it each one of those
compounds have many able
ocular targets in the body it's not just
THC will do this one thing because it
interacts here it's like THC does lots
of things because it interacts
everywhere so does CBD yeah it's
exciting but it also really pisses off a
lot of patients and their families when
you're trying to explain right because
Western medicine is so reductionist
people want to hear that you know the
disease is caused by a and we take B
which undoes a and of story put it in a
pill you know yeah and really not only
is that not really how nature or our
bodies work it is definitely not how
cannabis medicine works and cannabis
medicine is is is more about here is a
broad range of you know naturally
occurring chemical compounds that our
body normally makes but it's not making
and so we're gonna get it from a plant
and once we put them in our body you
know dozens of little chemical reactions
happen which when you put them together
becomes a melody that decreases the
experience of disease and potentially
the disease itself and and most people
do not want to hear that kind of an
explanation totally well and I mean
we've all been trained to not accept
that sort of explanation we're looking
for like you know how often have you
worked with someone who's like oh I'm
having trouble sleeping but I don't want
to feel high and I don't want to feel
altered and like you know what's good
for sleeping what's good for pain and
it's kind of like well let's walk you
through like you can't really tease
apart symptom management but based on
cannabinoids alone like you're not
necessarily going to get the same pain
relieving qualities from CBD as you do
from THC and if you take THC it could be
really good for pain but you might feel
high like it's it's not this completely
custom formed pharmaceutical oh so it's
a plant it's a plant
a lot of really interesting compounds
and it does a lot of things all at once
and sometimes that's good and sometimes
it's bad like parking in Parkinson's so
much of the research about THC has been
incredibly contradictory because cb1
while it's apparent that it plays a role
activating it has had like very
contradictory results so activating cb1
can cause an increase in symptoms or a
decrease in symptoms sort of depending
on the model blocking cb1 same thing
it's obvious that manipulating cb1 has
an impact on this disease but we're not
entirely sure what and it has an impact
on both the disease and the side effects
of the most common medication so tremors
are a hallmark of Parkinson's disease
and they're also a hallmark of the side
effect of levodopa which is you know
this shaking involuntary muscle movement
that develops in like 30 to 50 percent
of people who take this medication and
so cb1 activation seems to help the
shaking associated with taking levodopa
but it might not help the shaking
associated with the disease itself so it
gets really complicated it's really hard
to win it's usually not the patient it's
usually somebody in the patient's family
who will send me an article usually not
a scientific paper but just some article
that they saw in the internet talking
about how THC in you know lab rat
studies sometimes can increase some of
the markers for Parkinson's and they're
all like my family members should
absolutely not be taking something that
increases the markers and at the same
time you say you know you got to tell me
like okay you are my optically looking
at this one study which we don't really
understand its meaning
yet and it wasn't done in humans but
perhaps that study is going to be
outweighed by the fact that that you
know cannabinoids cause neurogenesis and
the creation of more dopamine creating
neurons and the the anti-inflammatory
aspects of THC makes the body feel
better and the muscle relaxation aspects
of it decrease the tremors and the CBG
increases the patient's confidence and
decreases the neuromuscular pain so
you're alive you're like ok you know
plant medicines are complex and you
really need to look at at how you are
gonna treat the human in a much more
broad holistic way and I always feel bad
for for these families because this is
not the best time of their life to be
learning detailed medicine that they're
totally unfamiliar with and so you got
out you got to walk them through this
stuff very slowly and lovingly so that
they can feel empowered to make
decisions for themselves or their family
members at the same time that they are
being incredibly frustrated yep exactly
exactly and you know it's totally
understandable that they're frustrated
they want an easy solution and it this
isn't an easy solution it's a really
interesting one it could be a very
powerful one but it's definitely not
easy and it's not straightforward and
it's it is asking a lot to to sort of
introduce people to this concept that it
it's gonna take time to figure out
whether or not something works or not
and in general I mean in the human
studies that have been conducted on THC
and CBD and people with Parkinson's
they're it's by and large there have
been no worsening of symptoms you know
at worst usually it's like nothing
happens so if that's the worst-case
scenario why not try it because the best
case scenario can be incredible
it could help cease some of the
involuntary muscle movements it can make
people happier I mean
you know quality of life is huge and
that's a stunning effect of cannabinoid
therapy sort of across the board even if
people don't observe any sort of
metaphysical manifestations of cannabis
therapy they feel better and that's
really important yeah that's a very good
point and I also like your point that
you know nothing may happen at all but
you're really only risking good you know
most of the time not most the time every
Parkinson's patient that I've ever you
know become familiar with and taught a
dosing protocol to if they fall into one
of three categories either category one
for whatever reason it doesn't seem to
have any effect and they're frustrated
by that and and that sucks but you know
that's the that's the nature of the be
so sometimes that's Basket one basket
two are people who are able to relieve
their daily symptoms to some degree and
maybe all the way which can be like a
huge win but the the Parkinson's
continues to progress over time and and
you know they're not able to turn the
tide on the Parkinson's and then there's
the third category which is always
delightful to run into where they
they're very responsive to cannabinol
Pathak medicine their their daily
symptoms decrease right away and that
their treatment of the endocannabinoid
system causes their body to start
creating more neurons that create
dopamine on on the body's own and then
the the body's endocannabinoids system
fires up and the Parkinson's rolls back
and they're their tests numbers become
better and and and everybody is
astonished for the miracle cure and
right you know and of course we hope
that everybody's in that category but
really I haven't come across a patient
yet who experimented with cannabis and
it made them worse except for it's it's
worth mentioning people who start taking
th
without following a specific dosing
protocol can accidentally over medicate
themselves and get more high than
they're comfortable with and yeah and
that can be you know an hour - of
displeasure or you know more often than
not people who are the age that people
generally get Parkinson's I find that
those people more go to sleep than then
have a paranoid experience but you know
it is it is like because you know once
you once you're high one of the classic
hallmarks of you know cannabis
intoxication is a loss of the ability to
balance in the same way and since people
with Parkinson's already have are sort
of compromised in their ability to
balance that could be definitely I've
experienced patients who got really
scared because they lost their balance
when they were high and so that's like
yeah totally understandable but again it
has to do with you know that's too much
you know you could take less definitely
and I've run into actually actually many
Parkinson's patients who are very
sensitive to THC and it could have to do
with the expression of cb1 in their
cerebrospinal fluid they just have more
targets for that THC to hit and so maybe
they're getting high faster it's funny I
had a I had one patient that I was
working with and that was her primary
complaint was that when she would take
some purple flower THC in the evening
before bed as a tincture so that she
could get a good night's sleep and then
and then you know maybe two two and a
half hours she would normally get up to
use the restroom and the THC was in her
body and and she felt a little unstable
going to the restroom and and I told her
I said I said you know that that is a
thing for some people and so you know
let's decrease your dosage and she was
like uh-uh and I said oh and she said I
just put a like a bar on the wall and I
and I like a railing and she said I
added a railing between my bed and the
bathroom and I hold on to that she says
because it's so important for her to
take THC at night at that dosage so that
she wakes up in the morning hungry and
I'm all like my gosh
see this is this is the next this is
next level patient self care where they
have learned how the cannabis medicine
works for them uniquely and and she was
causing you know she was getting
individualized medicine after she
learned how to properly use the tincture
for her and and people just need to be
patient through those first couple weeks
of learning how the how to use the
medicine best for you and then you can
take the advice from you know your
doctor or somebody like you or I and
adapt it for you and now you've got like
best practices for you and rec that is
the you know gold standard for using
cannabis totally and it is I mean it's
it's a lot of experimentation and it can
take a little bit of time and you know
having patience can really turn out well
yes alright so before we go to
commercial I want to talk about the the
use of cannabis to relieve short-term
symptoms and we've already touched on a
bunch of this but you know generally up
to the now we've been talking about you
know fighting Parkinson's as the disease
to try to get rid of it you know to get
rid of the underlying lack of dopamine
issues but you know for many folks the
initial cessation or lessening of
physical symptoms that gives them their
first confirmation of hope in cannabis
is just taking a little bit that a
friend gives them and you know many of
us have seen the the internet video of a
Parkinson's patient with significant
tremors being given just a tiny bit of
cannabis oil on their tongue and then
like within four or five minutes those
tremors are gone and they're chatting
and you know their friends they're
crying and it's like powerful you know
videos yeah and and you know there's
there's plenty of these on YouTube that
people can check out seeing that happen
in person with the patient it really
is breathtaking and so let's talk about
like the short-term what symptoms have
you seen abated with cannabis in the
short-term
and when I say short-term I mean like
you take some tincture you know
consistently let's say every three or
four hours and the symptoms go away you
know to some degree within a day and
then more so day two so very very Swift
response
totally tremors pain sleeplessness
appetite all of those things I've seen
return in Parkinson's patients and it
really improves their quality of life
not only that when when patients are
eating properly because they've got
their hunger back and they're getting a
proper night's sleep it's helping the
underlying systemic issues that are
going on for them because none of us are
gonna thrive with crappy food and crappy
sleep and also the quality of life
shoots up okay mark yeah the anxiety and
depression is such a big issue for
everyone who lives with chronic disease
and so if you can manage that with
cannabis it's huge yeah so okay so when
we get back from the commercial we're
gonna get right down to specific
cannabis dosing protocols and methods
but right now we're gonna take our
second short break and be right back you
are listening to shaping fire and my
guest today is cannabis researcher and
educator Zoe Sigmund growing cannabis in
greenhouses is taking over the cannabis
industry an efficient and effective
blend of sunshine grown terpene profiles
and the controlled environment of indoor
greenhouses can be the best of both
worlds for many greenhouse operators
though building their greenhouse before
gaining insight into how cannabis
greenhouses differ from ornamental crops
can be the start of a world of hurt erik
Branstad and his team at greenhouse
advisory group have the experience and
technical know-how to help you avoid
these pitfalls erik Branstad has been
helping cannabis growers find locations
design build and equip their greenhouses
for over a decade first starting in
Northern California but expanding over
the last five years to helping clients
throughout the world he has an
impeccable
computation for both depth of knowledge
and kindness and communication you can
hear Eric explains some of the
challenges facing cannabis greenhouses
and how to overcome them in episode
number 41 of the shaping fire podcast no
matter where I go in the country good
people with smart backgrounds still are
making the mistake of building without
knowing cannabis and it causes them to
burn through capital and time fast
everyone has their film failure point
for some it is improper ventilation
planning for others it is surface
temperatures of the building or the
plants leaves or both some folks that
build their greenhouse from scratch make
really basic errors like placement of
the greenhouse on the property or not
understanding the natural environment
where the greenhouse sits
some have even built a decent greenhouse
but are inefficient in their deployment
of light deprivation techniques and
never really hit their target yields
it's great when you learn from your
mistakes but it's even better when you
learn from the mistakes of others when
you bring on greenhouse advisory group
you will learn from the mistakes of
their many clients and you'll take
advantage of the best practices
developed by Erik Branstad over his
years of working with clients just like
you from location development to
choosing a builder and tricking out your
new greenhouse or retrofitting or
rescuing your failing greenhouse Erik
will help you through it
visit greenhouse advisory group com
to learn more and connect with Eric and
his team that's green house advisory
group as a business owner you are
incredibly busy in reality you are
responsible for everything your company
does you've got so many responsibilities
every single day and often you just
don't have the time to really dig into
your marketing as deeply as you'd like
you know there's more that you could do
to reach out to new customers and
encourage loyalty and the customers you
already have but you certainly don't
have the time for it and you're not
ready to hire somebody full-time for
that role either for you I recommend
blunt branding at blunt branding Kirsten
Nelson and her team are focused on
improving your bottom line you know most
marketing firms are excited to make your
logo packaging and website very pretty
but they leave responsibility for
improving your bottom line up to you
they don't want that kind of
responsibility but that's
pretty much the most important part of
marketing right Kirsten and her team
will help you engage new customers
funnel them to your point of sale
whether it be online or a storefront and
keep them coming back to you and telling
their friends now if you happen to be a
new cannabis company or an established
company moving from medical to adult use
in your state
Kirsten especially can help you not only
is she well versed in marketing and
finance but she totally gets cannabis
whole plant medicine terpenes heritage
farmers and the particular needs of
startups check out what she did recently
for moon time medicinals and humbled at
moon time medicinals dot-com Kirsten and
her team put together a whole brand
package for them built their website and
wrote their sales materials no doubt
this is a paid commercial spot but that
does not mean they bought my opinion
I've worked with blunt branding on five
projects now for various of their
clients and every single time they have
done more than they have promised and
over delivered on results I love how
they generate new revenue and focus on
that as the goal instead of just making
a pretty logo similarly every single
friend I have referred them to has come
back to thank me
and that just does not happen every day
grab a pen and paper because the website
address is coming up if you want someone
to implement marketing programs that
feed your bottom line give blunt
branding a call they will share proven
techniques to increase your audience and
generate sales while using cutting-edge
technology solutions in the background
that make all of this easy automatic and
trackable go to shaping feiyr.com
forward slash blunt branding to find out
more you can also click the link in our
newsletter Blount branding marketing
that makes you money
cannabis is fun medicine and we love to
celebrate it cannabis connects people
and creates opportunities for new
friendships at the joke shop we create
custom cannabis themed jewelry money
clips rolling trays and home furnishings
that I love and they also make great
gifts too i'm ashley Villafranca owner
of the toke shop I came to cannabis as a
patient seeking an alternative to the
pharmaceuticals being pushed at me for
chronic pain and fibromyalgia I realized
that not only was cannabis a huge help
in controlling my symptoms but I found
cannabis to be wonderfully social -
cannabis makes friends
so I took my love of jewelry design and
blended it with my newfound passion for
cannabis and began hand crafting
bracelets earrings and friendship
necklaces and then expanded to many
clips rollin chase and other home
furnishings all made in sterling silver
14-karat gold
and aluminum so there's something for
everyone's budget I consider it all to
be New Age cannabis fashion and cannabis
couture I invite you to stop by my
website at the Tokyo at the toke shop Co
you'll find a wide array of attractive
and fun cannabis items starting at only
10 bucks and if you're fancy there are
very fine luxury pieces as well and I'm
always happy to do custom orders with
your name or a particular theme come
check out my array of items hand stamped
with terpenes cannabinoids and other
cannabis themes that's the toke shop see
oh thanks welcome back you are listening
to shaping fire I'm your host Shango
Louis and our guest this week is
cannabis researcher and educator Zoe
Sigmund so here we are at the part of
the show that a lot of people have been
waiting for I am sure we are going to go
through specific dosing protocols to get
you started with using cannabis to help
treat your Parkinson's disease you know
historically Parkinson's patients have
been recommended to start with a air
quotes 2 to 1 of 10 milligrams of CBD
and 5 milligrams of THC every 3 to 4
hours which is about the amount of time
that the cannabinoids stay active in the
bloodstream while a reasonable place to
start
even this basic dosage protocol though
has definitely has room for
customization especially if the patient
has never tried cannabis before I
wouldn't want to start them out at 5
milligrams so Zoe when you are
consulting a new patient where do you
like to suggest that they start with
their cannabis dosing yeah I don't
really suggest that they start lower
than 5 grams so two and a half
milligrams is a is a pretty good place
to start even then I have had people
with Parkinson's disease say that that
was pretty significantly altering and so
if people are nervous about the feeling
of being high start with one
of THC I'd still say at least 10
milligrams of CBD you can basically take
as much CBD as you're comfortable with
taking CP there's a lot of information
about CBD for Parkinson's patients
clinical studies and observations that
show dosage dosages really up to the 600
milligrams of CBD have been shown to
have benefit in various aspects of the
disease as far as the THC is concerned
we really want to avoid people feeling
uncomfortable and so two-and-a-half
milligrams one milligram if you're
really nervous the first time you take
cannabis medicine we really hope that
you don't feel anything because that
means you can increase your dose and it
also means that they you know there are
very very rare people I have had
canvassed researchers suggest me that
maybe it's 1 in 10,000 people who have a
severe reaction to THC where they'll
take a very small amount of it you know
of two and a half milligrams and they
will have an outside response to it and
get really high for a few hours and it
is is incredibly rare and I've only come
across one person in all of my years
talking with cannabis patients who is
that sensitive but if it's you or if
it's a family member or if you're a
caregiver you don't want to be the one
that finds that rare patient and so if
if the if the patient does not have an
experience with THC starting at
incredibly small what what regular
cannabis patients would consider
laughable starting with those laughable
amounts really is the best way to go and
and we'll talk more about method later
but this is one of the reasons why I
really like tinctures for patients
because if if you're if you're smoking
you can't control your dosage at all and
if you're taking a concentrated oil it's
really hard to get low doses and if
you're taking capsules you're stuck with
whatever's in that capsule but if you
are taking a tincture
you can take a full dropper you can take
a half a dropper or you can just take
three little drops whatever is
convenient for you and that is how we
would get to as you suggested a 2.5
milligram THC dosage or if the person
hasn't had any at all maybe maybe just
give them you know ten drops which is
gonna make her you know you'd have to do
the math based on what's on the bottom
what it says on the bottle right but
let's just say that ten drops is going
to be one milligram perhaps well let's
let's start there because you can always
increase your dosage and once it's in
your body it's much harder coming back
and saying exactly doing a healthy self
titration of moving up until you find
your sweet spot is is really a way to go
so so Zoey how do you recommend people
find their sweet spot and how do they
know when they've hit their sweet spot
of the right amount of THC to take yeah
I mean it's it it varies from person to
person and I think that a really good
metric that I've used for a long time is
basically you want to feel relief of
your symptoms without any unwanted side
effects so that could mean different
things for different people for some
people you know maybe you're looking for
a lessening of pain but you don't want
to feel high and so you would continue
to slowly titrate up to the place where
maybe you've been feeling pain relief or
in some way for a little bit of time and
then finally you hit a dose where you're
like ooh I feel high so move back down
so it's always a really good idea to
keep track of exactly how much of any
cannabis medicine you're taking and then
sort of recording what your experiences
are on that medication or at that dosage
level so that if you hit a point at
which you're uncomfortable you can back
it down to the last step and it's good
to point out that it isn't like if you
add one more drop you go from not
feeling it to being like super stoned
right you know there's there's a
progression of not feeling anything not
feeling anything maybe you had a couple
sips of wine um
and then maybe you had a glass amount
and then oh maybe it would maybe you
actually had a martini intoxication and
then oh maybe now you're kind of
slapping at light switches or grasping
at the doorknob and then you're really
high right you know like so yeah so
there's this range that so long as you
start on the low end you can tiptoe your
way up and and what I have found is that
there are there are many many
Parkinson's patients who tell me that
they don't want to feel high and they're
afraid of feeling high and so they'll
titrate in one milligram two milligram
three milligram and then someone around
four milligram when they start to
actually feel anything at all they're
all like oh I really like the warm
sensation that I get from it
and then at five you know or six they're
all like they're like oh you know I have
I really enjoy this it really makes my
TV much more interesting we had laughs
last night right and like you know and
generally speaking unless somebody is
you know very familiar with cannabis
medicine there really isn't any reason
for a novice to really go much beyond
five or six milligrams unless they are
experienced and unless there is either
they've got some kind of resistance that
they've built up over time or if they're
dealing with a contain component and
they want to take a lot more THC to deal
with that but but you know if you're if
you're just getting your legs under you
and learning about using cannabis for
your Parkinson's you know generally
speaking you don't really have much
business going above five until you know
what you're doing because anyway
anywhere above five you could have a
surprised overmedication experience once
you're a an established cannabis patient
though you know pretty much anything
under 10 is going to be pretty safe and
then and then it's okay to play with
even more than that - it's it's
absolutely sort of what you feel and if
it's effective and you know people do
balloons THC and so if you're using it
every day you might need to increase
your dose in it if you go above ten
that's that's fine it's not scary it
just depends on your body and what you
need
yeah I think that's the kicker right
it's it's not scary so long as you have
built up the experience to get to that
point I mean there's there's plenty of
cannabis patients that are taking a
hundred milligrams of THC in an edible
at once but you know it's it's not their
first time taking cannabis right these
are these are patients that have been
that they have learned how cannabis
works with their body and they learned
how to do it and when to do it and
they're very experienced but but for the
vast majority of people who are coming
to cannabis everything all of our work
on THC is going to be done under five
milligrams and you know generally
speaking as much CV whole plant CBD as
you can afford and it's it's a it's a
shame that it has to be that way because
you know the cheap stuff that the
affordable CVD is is very often
questionably made isolate from other
countries and such which are not going
to give you the benefits of entourage
effect and and really working with the
whole system of the body the the whole
plant preparations they're more arduous
to make and you know their prices
generally reflect that but thankfully
they seek to be more effective or as
effective at lower doses as CBD isolates
higher doses and so you can play around
I mean I think that it is beneficial for
almost everyone to take a pretty large
amount of CBD at some point in their
life as long as you're not on
medications that stress your liver and
see what it's like and then sort of
start to understand what different
amounts of CBD can give you as far as
benefits and it's you know in
Parkinson's patients there's been a ton
of human observations about like CBD
improving quality of life spasms sleep
quality like all these issues and it's
like you it's anywhere from 40
milligrams per day up to 600 milligrams
per day and usually like a lot of the
studies are at around 150 milligrams
which is kind of a lot when you're
about how CBD is usually sold how much
CBD is usually in a tincture bottle but
it's just to say like if you can afford
it if you can find like a high quality
preparation go for it and and also it's
unfortunate too because so many of the
products on the shelves in license
stores they will they will make a an
extraction of a THC plant and then they
will spike it with CBD isolate so that
they can get like huge CBD numbers but
it's not really a whole CBD plant and so
so often people you know I will often
recommend that a you know it taking
taking the cost off the table for a
minute if they can afford it go ahead
and start with their two point five
milligrams of THC but plan on five
milligrams a dosage to be your target
and then if you can take 10 to 20
milligrams of whole plant CBD with that
3 to 4 times a day so that you end up
with you know between 60 and 100
milligrams of whole plant CBD and you
know 15 to 20 milligrams of THC spread
out over the whole day you're gonna very
likely see a significant benefit right
because you're giving you're giving a
healthy dose consistently throughout the
day and you are rebuilding your
endocannabinoid system and so just
because some of the studies that we've
seen are you know 200 milligrams and up
and day many of these studies are still
being done on rats and the the dosing
does not always actually the CBD studies
in Parkinson's it's in humans that's
what's really impressive about
Parkinson's disease like there's a bunch
of preclinical stuff in rats like really
interesting stuff with CBD but the the
dosages I was talking about those are
all based on humans all right so then my
follow up to that would have been since
since you're more familiar with these
studies are they always using whole
plant are they using isolate yeah
excellent question
that information is almost never
provided yeah yeah and so so it's
interesting you know people people will
often get you know poor or no results on
a few hundred milligrams of CBD isolate
but you give that same patient twenty
five milligrams of whole plant and oh my
gosh suddenly it works because the body
knows how to deal with that instead of
just quality questions I think I feel
like in CBD isolate in the world of CBD
isolate you're a little bit more
susceptible to fraud honestly you know
people just miss labeling what's in the
bottle and misrepresenting was in the
bottle and you do need to be careful
about who you buy your products from for
that reason no one's regulating this and
so you need to trust the person who
makes the oil the person who grows the
flower in the flower that goes into the
oil it's a it's a bit more of an
involved process than other medications
definitely and another place that
patients get super frustrated right
because you know there's so many places
for for things to go wrong on the path
from the plant being in the ground to
being in your hands at home you know
there's there's potential pesticides
that are being used at the grower step
and then you've got you know some
extraction methods are better than other
like I'm a big fan of ethanol extraction
because it really pulls out the whole
plant but if you can't get ethanol you
know I would probably go and try some
you know co2 extraction though that is
not my personal preference I'd always go
to the ethanol first but then you can
come all the way down to people using
distillates and isolates and and spiking
a THC cultivar and and so most patients
are not going to be sophisticated enough
to be able to unravel that and so then
they go to a store and they ask a
budtender
and there are some epic bud tenders who
you know it's more than a job for them
they are doing their research at home
and they're going to convention
and they're learning stuff but that is
the minority and very often than not the
budtender will give you what they have a
lot of in stock or what other people
tend to buy neither of those are based
on medical efficacy really right right
which is it's just it's a problem it's
one of the main problems of cannabis
medicine you know getting a consistent
product that you can trust contains what
you think it contains and making sure
that that product works for you so I hit
on it a little bit earlier about the
different methods and it's so common for
me to come across patients who are first
trying to get familiar with cannabis
medicine and so somebody gives them some
joints to smoke and and certainly there
are you know some ailments that smoking
is very appropriate you know depression
glaucoma pain loss of appetite you know
these types of things you know certainly
you know smoking a joint it will work
but but for Parkinson's we really want
to be in more control of the dosing and
being able to fine-tune it and know
exactly how much we took and write it in
our patient journal so that we can
control our doses better over time so
when when folks are asking you what your
preferred methods are for actually
ingesting it what do you like to tell
them usually sublingually so sublingual
administration involves holding a
tincture or spray under your tongue for
a minute to allow some of the active
compounds in this case cannabinoids to
pass through into your bloodstream more
readily this is in contrast to just
swallowing a tincture which then needs
to pass through your entire digestive
system first and you actually lose a lot
of the potency of the cannabinoids well
it's passing through your digestive
system and so the sublingual
administration allows for a faster onset
and maybe a little bit more better
absorption of the cannabinoids
I have also and this is a bit
controversial but especially with people
who are very concerned about cannabis
use I have suggested maybe starting or
trying a transdermal patch first
transdermal patches have a lot of issues
in terms of consistency people's skin
are different thicknesses it's difficult
to tell
really how bioavailable the compounds
are but the benefit is you could put it
on and feel the effects really quickly
within 15 minutes and then if you don't
like the effects you can take it off and
then the effects will go away just as
quickly and so it's sort of a good way
to see if if this is something that
works for you they are very expensive so
not like the best may be a long-term
solution which is where you can start to
move into the land of sublingual
administration and I'm still looking for
a transdermal patch that I really like
what's in it - because yeah transdermal
preparation that is a lot of heavy
processing of the cannabinoids and and
and to get to that point we're often you
know we're often way beyond whole plant
where we're in this kind of over
processed version which at that point if
somebody's gonna go transdermal I
actually like taking cannabis oil and
mix it with a little bit of hand lotion
and actually using it as a topical and
letting it sum through the skin rather
than going transdermal but but I think
that I don't think that the transdermal
[Music]
technology has come into its own yet I
still think that as as more investment
money comes into the cannabis world and
we get more cross over for the
scientists that that you know are really
good at making them we're going to see
more of them come to the market and who
knows that transdermal may actually
already exist in you know one of the
medical states and I just haven't come
across that product yet yeah yeah I mean
the transdermal technology has advanced
a law in the past several years and
really outside of cannabis it's a very
interesting administration method for
very small molecules like nicotine and
or estrogen for nicotine patches or
birth control patches which is where
this sort of technology really evolved
and so I have seen you know promising
suggestions for the transdermal
technologies but yeah you're right like
we still have a lot to learn as far as
that administration method and tinctures
just really are very easy as far as
dosage control which is awesome that
said Parkinson's is one of the diseases
where maybe because of the length of
time that cannabis has been used to
treat Parkinson's there have been some
studies that have shown benefits for
from smoked cannabis especially as far
as mood and fatigue and pain and so if
you're King if those are the symptoms
that you're really looking to help
mitigate in Parkinson's disease like
smoking could be a really good option
for you if you're open to it actually
that's a really good point to make too
because when I was kind of dissing from
the smoking aspect I was thinking to get
the cannabinoids unchanged into the body
where it can cause neurogenesis of these
dopamine creating neurons right and so
for specifically that sure a sublingual
tincture or oil is going to be optimum
but you're right the symptoms that come
with Parkinson's can very well be
treated with a joint and especially the
quality of life aspect I yeah I know a
lot of Parkinson's patients that they
have found that their favorite part of
their day is sitting on their porch and
smoking a joint and just feeling not
crappy for a while right totally it's
really important I think another thing
to note about anything that you ingest
through your mouth is if you take your
cannabinoid medication with fad
something fatty a fatty meal a fatty
snack your body will absorb those
cannabinoids like significantly better
like two to three times better and so
it's always worth noting that if you are
taking a tincture or an edible eat a
spoonful of peanut butter or ice cream
or an avocado or whatever to help
really help your body absorb those
cannabinoids and this is not an excuse
to eat cracky calories either right I
mean like we're talking about a very
small amount of fat to the point that
you know a lot of good capsules are made
with a little bit of oil and a little
bit of coconut as the fat and a capsule
and that's it
so this is this is not your ex you know
this is not the reason to take a little
bit of cannabinoids and then a pint of
Ben &amp; Jerry's right your fat maybe a
couple spoonfuls yeah there you go so um
you know another thing I think we should
hit on before we wrap up our
conversation is that you know while you
and I have both seen huge successes for
Parkinson's patients using cannabis and
the vast majority of patients that I've
come across who have you who have used
cannabis have gotten some good results
to the point that that Parkinson's is
kind of low-hanging fruit for cannabis
it's not it's it's it's one of the more
easily accessible and treatable diseases
with cannabis it doesn't work for
everybody and and and and and it's
important to be clear about that that
sometimes folks will take cannabis and
they just won't see the changes that
they want and they'll be like I don't
know why but it doesn't work for me and
and I don't have an explanation why it
doesn't work for everybody but to know
that that is a possibility and sometimes
you also have to play around with the
dosage and sometimes it's weird
sometimes
I jest that people like after they've
tried for a few weeks and they're like
it's just not working for me I'm like
well put put the rest of the cannabis
medicine you have aside and like just
take a break for a few weeks and then
come back to it and approach it again
and sometimes it works if the second
time and sometimes it doesn't but I
think that it's just I think it's
important for people to know that if
they are going to give this a try
there are people that that they don't
get the benefit that they are looking
for while there are people who get
incredible benefits so be gentle with
yourself and and and take notes in your
journal so you are sure
you're taking enough because honestly
when people say they're not that the
cannabis did not help their Parkinson's
it's it's almost always the fact that
they misunderstood the dosage and
they're taking such a small amount that
that it wouldn't help anybody right
right yeah and I think a big an
important part of the jobs that both you
and I do at helping patients is
modulating expectations and trying to
help people approach cannabis medicine
as realistically as possible and it is
really important I mean many of the
Parkinson's patients that I've worked
with have not had benefit from cannabis
therapy and that's okay and they were
okay with it and part of the reason they
were okay with it was you know walking
into it knowing that it doesn't work for
everyone and there's a bunch of things
that you can try and it's okay if it
doesn't you know it might and that's
where it's like modulate expectations
and keep hope high you know and and and
usually the by the time the people get
to cannabis they've already tried
everything else anyway you know and you
know certainly there are some you know
more nature medicine type folks who will
start with cannabis and you know those
are those are our kind of people but but
that's that's not usually the case
normally they've gone through all the
Pharma first and it either has got
really bad side effects or it doesn't
work for them and they're like okay what
do you got what do you hippies got you
know and and so we we educate them and
and hopefully they find some advantage
there but even people who don't find
that the cannabis medicine is actually
helping reverse or rollback their
Parkinson's at the root core their
quality of lives is are almost always
increased just because taking a little
bit of cannabis and the muscle
relaxation aspects of it and getting
your your you know getting the munchies
getting your appetite back and being a
little stoned and for the vast majority
of patients that in and of itself makes
life better totally and it has been in
some of the human studies on Parkinson's
disease both THC and CBD have helped
people get off of pharmacy
chuckle painkillers which is another
huge benefit lucky if it's not helping
with Parkinson's directly you know
helping you get off of opiates which
might not make you feel very good I mean
like I have only taken opiates once and
it made me puke for days you know and
it's like but if that's your only option
for pain relief having it another option
is really nice and so it's like there's
all these things to take into
consideration when you're considering
whether or not cannabis medicine is
effective yeah absolutely all right so
let's wrap this up because you know
patients and families and educators who
are still with us in the show they are
probably just lit with interest at this
point and and they're probably gonna
want to take this and learn more so so
before I ask you for where you would
recommend people to go I want to start
by recommending your video that is on
the shaping fire YouTube channel at
youtube.com forward slash Angello's you
just gave a great talk at Vimeo on
Vashon Island about getting to know your
endocannabinoid system and it's great
you you expand for about an hour what we
did in about 10 minutes today and not
only is it is it playful and you know
you're a humorous person but also you
use you know Star Wars metaphors to
explain the endocannabinoid system and
so it makes it pretty delightful so so
you so folks can check that out on on
the shaping fire YouTube channel where
else do you like to send people Zoe to
learn more yeah project CBD which is the
nonprofit I worked for for a year and a
half before I worked there I recommended
people go there and now after I work
there I recommend people go there I
think that's an incredible resource and
will continue to be so and I think that
as far as putting out information that's
accessible to people who are not
necessarily scientists it's still one of
the best I'm gonna go ahead and double
down on on your suggestion of project
CBD org which my listeners are certainly
familiar with because it is the it's the
only web resource
that I plug consistently because as far
as I'm concerned it is it is the only
you know always trustworthy source for
information that's been vetted plus you
can get both kinds of articles you can
get articles that translate cannabis
medicine and research into you know
regular person vocabulary but also
there's a section on the site called
conditions that you can click on I think
there's like 50 different conditions
there including Parkinson's and when you
click on it you will get links to all of
the original scientific research on
PubMed gov so if you're the kind of
person where you know an article is not
going to give you the level of
specificity that you need to make health
decisions for you and your family going
to the project CBD org site under
conditions and clicking Parkinson's and
getting access to the science firsthand
oh you'll feel so much more satisfied
with the with the path that you take
knowing that you have read the science
yourself firsthand oh yeah it's
wonderful and I mean like if people
really want to get into it pull up
PubMed and search Parkinson's in
cannabis and PubMed is a database that
collates all of the scientific research
that's being done I'm pretty sure gone
everything but if you open it and search
for a specific specific condition and
cannabis there's thousands of articles
and it could be a really useful resource
fantastic so Zoe thank you so much for
taking the time out of your schedule to
hang out for a little bit and to share
your vast experience on this topic and
and you know thank you for sharing your
experience working with patients
directly because you know often there is
a gap between the the scientific papers
and how patients find relief and I
appreciate you that you have got both
bodies of information and your
willingness to share it with us ah thank
you so much thanks for having me on
Shango if you want to find out more
about Zoe
and and and keep up with her posts you
can find her on Instagram and that's at
Zowie underscore Sigmund so that's zero
e
underscore s IG ma n you can find more
episodes of the shaping fire podcast and
subscribe to the show at shaping fire
calm and on Apple iTunes stitcher and
Google Play if you enjoyed the show we'd
really appreciate it if you'd leave a
positive review of the podcast wherever
you download your review will help
others find the show so they can enjoy
it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the weekly newsletter for
insights into the latest cannabis news
and product reviews on the shaping fire
website you will also find transcripts
of today's podcast as well for
information on me and where I'll be
speaking you can check out Shango loast
calm your company want to reach our
national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hotspot at shaping
fire calm to find out how thanks for
listening to shaping fire I've been your
host Shango lows
[Music]