[Music]
making cannabis products for yourself or
your arthritic grandmother is one thing
but making cannabis products for the
public is a whole different world not
only are you way more likely to get sued
if you make a mistake but selling
cannabis products commercially means
that you need to adhere to a wide range
of standards these standards are
generally manifested in a hodgepodge way
through state experimentation product
failures and everyone's fear of
violating the Cole memo
none of those methods will necessarily
derive scientifically accurate
manufacturing standards for cannabis
products though it's a mess if you enjoy
hearing frank discussions that dive deep
in a cannabis health business and
technique i encourage you to subscribe
to our newsletter every week you'll
receive a new podcast episode delivered
right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week and
videos to don't rely on social media to
let you know when a new episode is
published sign up for the updates to
make sure you don't miss an episode you
are listening to shaping fire and I am
your host
Shango lows today my guest is Jhon Marku
Jhon Marku is chief scientific officer
and chief auditor for Americans for safe
access and the patient-focused
certification program he's also on the
board of directors of the International
Association for cannabinoids as medicine
he received his PhD for significant
contributions to the study of the
structure and function of the cb1
receptor and the role of the
endocannabinoid system in bone before
earning his PhD dr. Marku worked at the
California Pacific Medical Center
Research Institute studying the
anti-cancer properties of compounds from
the cannabis plant he serves on multiple
government and trade association
committees and scientific organization J
Hans work has appeared in a wide range
of media including Forbes The Washington
Post
and vice he's also also an author of the
American Armour copia cannabis monograph
Jahan Marku was the first recipient of
the Billy Martin research award from the
International cannabinoid Research
Society and he is a court qualified
synthetic cannabinoid and cannabis
expert welcome to show Jhon thank you
I'm happy to be here so you know in the
early days of medical care
in Colorado and Washington in Oregon and
California there were pretty much zero
production standards and and few best
practices everything was being made in
you know kitchens and spare rooms in
people's homes and and most of it was
made with care but still most of the
products were not potency tested and I
even toured one production facility that
that had a chicken as a pet indoors
which was crazy and and part of the push
for more full legalization was because
everyone wanted to increase quality
standards and make products more uniform
you know what do you see as the early
motivators for cannabis folks to
standardize and improve quality there
were a number of things that were
putting pressure on cannabis providers
at the time you know one was doctor's
confidence in the products you know and
when we first saw California and other
states come online with our medical
programs between 1996 and then starting
in 2002 when Americans for safe access
first helped create the distribution and
access centers in Oakland California
bypassing those early regulations you're
right there was no there was no required
testing and things like that but it
became quickly evident that physicians
which there were only a handful at the
time writing recommendations weren't
really that comfortable with
recommending a product that they did
have an unknown consistency or safety
and an unclear about what education
their patients were receiving before
consuming these products and at the time
while physicians were recommending this
and in a very small number of them they
were also concerned about their own
education and so we kind of approached
it from that way the second thing that
happened was the de A's denial of a
rescheduling hearing happened around the
turn of the century one of the several
at this point and we read that as a road
map most people probably didn't read
full few hundred page reports but I've
read all of them and you know what they
said is there's these seven factors
there's these eight factors that
cannabis has to fulfill to be
rescheduled and one of them was there
are no standards of production
distribution safety there aren't studies
or you know ons a lot of the products
that people are accessing there is an
education or training and things like
this we're like oh well why don't we
address those things Thank You DEA for
telling us what we need to do and so
steps here the executive director of ASA
engaged in this really amazing campaign
more than ten years ago
to bring in standards groups and these
were years long conversation with the
American welfare McAfee and the American
Herbal Products Association and we began
working on the American herbal
pharmacopoeia cannabis monograph and at
the time there were no standards and so
we created this monograph with people
like Ethan Russo and Momma del Sol e
Rafael McCullum was a reviewer of the
document as well and many many other
people I think about thirty people in
total reviewed the monograph that myself
and several of the people drafted and
that readily got adopted across the
states you know there's so there's so
much catch-22 in that right the DEA is
all like you know we don't want to take
it off schedule one which would allow
people to use it for research until that
there are standards and the standards
they'd have to come from research so
you're you're put in this position where
you need to start really small and kind
of back into it yeah and the great thing
is is that the University of Mississippi
has been producing cannabis for decades
that people with compromised immune
systems have been using without ever
having a recall of their product you
know there are occasional adverse events
report and I'll say what you want about
the specifications of the products not
everyone's a big fan of there being
stems and seeds and pulverized material
but it's still met standards for use in
vulnerable populations and we've seen
decades
some people to this day through the old
federal IND program are receiving 300
pre-world cannabis cigarettes a month
and you know Irv Rosenfeld who's one of
them has never you know his doctor has
not as yet to report you know him
getting lung infections or having any
serious illnesses so in some sense we
know that the the cultivation of
production can be standardized and
what's standardized really means is that
the variability is known now you have
arranged a target you're trying to hit
and if you don't know what your range or
your variability is in your product you
probably don't know what you're doing if
you don't have product specifications
how do you know that's your product and
simple things like that can really make
a huge difference in the confidence that
physicians might have and patients might
have because you don't just have to win
over the patients they're grasping at
whatever is available to treat their
symptoms to to improve their conditions
but their caregivers are often the ones
who are accessing those products
administering those products and in
making critical thinking decisions about
whether or not that product is safe and
appropriate for their loved ones and so
by increasing confidence in these
products is by adhering to voluntary
consensus standards now every industry
has pretty much created its own
standards the people who are involved
the stakeholders the interested parties
get together and create standards and
that's what we did with the American
Herbal Products Association which is a
really amazing organization our
standards are also public and so we
mentioned the monograph which creates if
you want to call this a botanical
medicine or herbal supplement or
something like that follow these
standards to meet you meet these
specifications meet these guidelines and
you're you're making a product that fits
that definition likewise you also have
the operations your operations need
trained staff they need to be clean it's
Americans for safe access right so
making sure that you're ensuring that
for patients is really important and so
with the American herbal products
Association
we decided to form these committees with
them for cultivation manufacturing
laboratory tents testing and dispensing
and over eight years with involvement of
over a hundred cannabis companies we
created standards and when these were
published they were readily adopted by
over 20 states and for the first time we
saw recall plans adverse events
reporting lab testing and mandatory
employee training and and this has also
been a I think a game changer for a lot
of folks so let's let's talk for a
moment about the the the people involved
with making the standards obviously
Americans for safe access was was
driving this pursuit but you were
talking about lots of different people
coming in from different parts of the
industry to create this voluntary
consensus standard and you know when
there are so many different players with
a wide variety of approaches and
opinions how does a nascent
industry like ours derive a set of
standards that somehow incorporates the
body of knowledge of all the people
involved I mean you you get together a
bunch of cannabis people and there's
usually as many opinions as there are
people in the room so you know without
going too much into the methodology well
how did you find that the that the group
opinion somehow melded together to come
up with a singular best practice that
that's a great question and I think
first I'd like to illustrate it with
what the herbal products and botanical
medicine industry has done in the US and
how they have come together because even
within existing botanical medicines and
herbal supplements they're not all those
companies adhere to the same standards
some are some are less robust and the
health and safety practices they take
than others you know they're I think
there was a recent expose for example at
a major shopping outlet like a Target or
something like that
the herbal supplements had very little
to no active ingredients you know we see
the same thing with some of these CBD
products that people are selling on the
internet that they have 0.00% CBD in
them sometimes and this is something
that a lot of independent groups
looked at and so what I'd like to use as
an example of how the industry can get
galvanized is oftentimes for survival
and in the 1990s when appa really became
a prominent player the the standards
holding group for the patient-focused
certification program you know Larry
Kessler the then head of the FDA made an
announcement without a strategic plan
for it that he was going to make all
vitamins of illegal and supplements that
didn't have a letter or number in their
name so like vitamin E would be okay b12
would be okay but say goodbye to your
ginkgo biloba extract or potentially
essential oils things like that and as
you can imagine this galvanized an
industry in a way that had never been
seen before and so the FDA through a
decades-long process of gaining power
made a huge power play here and what
ended up happening was is that the
Herbal Products Manufacturers and
Industry they launched the most
successful grassroots campaign in the
history of the United States all health
food stores across the country stores
that sold herbal supplements vitamins
botanical medicines put caution tape and
tarps and things over the supplements
those sections and said you know if you
want to have this is what the FDA wants
to do is take away your ability to
choose your medicines to choose your
durable supplements and things like that
and in between 1993 to 1994 Congress
received more letters about the right to
choose your own botanical medicines and
herbal supplements than any other issue
the piece the federal deficit war you
name it
that was issue and the FDA called Appa
and said we give up let's write a bill
and they wrote the dietary health and
supplement Education Act or de chelly
now this created standards for labeling
of herbal products shortly thereafter
there was also the Good Manufacturing
Practices laws that passed as well and
this gave the industry a group of
standards and not still to this day many
many there are many great players in the
botanical medicine and herbal products
base but there's also a lot of
characters who decide not to engage in
that or create their own standards
grouping or you know what have you but
the idea is it gives a path forward for
those people who are thinking ahead and
I think that for the cannabis world it
was well there are no standards my
regulations in my state haven't caught
up but I immediately you know a lot of
companies see the validity and value of
taking on national standards or
voluntary standards even if they're not
required in their state you know give
you an example you know medical cannabis
is not required to be tested in Colorado
but there are many companies that engage
in product safety testing for their for
their patients yeah becomes a market
differentiator they're able to use it in
marketing to say hey we we adhere to a
higher level of quality assurance yeah
and those are the places I think that
will stay open them you know one of my
mentors uh said to me you know you
you're like the world's luckiest
paleontologist and I said well what do
you mean and she said well you get to
walk with the dinosaurs you know you in
ten twenty years no one's gonna believe
you that there were these huge big
lumbering companies and much like the
dinosaurs the environment was very
different then than it is now and so I
think when we think about changes in
regulations you know what is gonna
survive these changes in development of
regulations I mean on the East Coast
what I'm seeing with my work there you
know changes gears a little bit is with
doing regulatory inspection trainings in
writing checklists for regulators and
working with our contracts we have with
the program administrators you know they
are getting very serious about
compliance not just with the Cannabis
ready
relations but workers safety issues too
and we were seeing you know cannabis
operations around the country getting
now getting inspected even though
they're federally illegal getting
expected by state agencies and even
though state agencies having nothing to
do with cannabis are issuing fines
especially for workers safety violations
and dangerous environments which could
simply be that you don't have a fire
evacuation map on the wall and little
things like that that you would expect
from any other employer you went to work
with now there are a lot of good players
out there and we cannot sit around and
highlight and point out the bad guys but
I think what we can do with standards
and third-party certification is easily
highlight the people who are doing
things right we're doing a good job and
I think that's the power of this like
you said it differentiates people and I
think the key to acceptance of cannabis
and getting over these walls that are
that are that are keep popping up it is
the standardization of products is
applying these standards is
appropriately testing your products you
know I sometimes think that someday
there's going to be a cultivator or
manufacturer that's going to get really
upset when someone brings them an
inflated THC reading from a lab and
they're paying for thousands of dollars
of milligrams of THC that simply aren't
there in the product and I think that as
things move forward and get more
regulated the accuracy of lab testing
the reliability of labs the reliability
of sample collection representative
sampling of products of standardization
of processes is not just going to become
an issue of quality it'll be a very
serious economic issue we're already
seeing that in extraction vessels which
again a lot of seen a lot of groups that
don't that can't predict their yields
from doing an extraction process you
know they just say oh I got a lot this
time well as far as I know a lot isn't
really a quantifiable number a lot
compared to what and so I think you know
people are always surprised and one of
the things that I've done in my own
independent research field as I look at
a lot of
Cannabis waste and there's so much
valuable stuff that simply isn't
extracted fully that is thrown away and
sometimes regulations do do interfere
with some of these processes like I'd
like to see more people looking at
cannabis routes but some states make you
throw that away
so I think there's a lot of
opportunities in innovation and
increasing efficiency and overall
product safety as well and again a lot
of this hinges on a couple of things is
access to those educational materials
you know we Americans for safe access
helped design a study on dispensary
staff training which was published in a
2016 in December by ryan van jury and
marcel von miller and what they showed
was that a lot of dispensary staff don't
have science or medicine you know
incorporated into their training and let
me illustrate something for you you know
to set the stage you know the thing that
I worry about you know is imagine if
this was for example I had you know so
aggressive cancer and I had to was new
to cannabis and I went into a dispensary
and I really have just three things to
guide my choice about a medicine for my
treatment
one is a strain or variety name another
one is a potency level right how much
THC or CBD is in the product and the
third thing is something that says you
know keep out of reach of children or do
not consume while driving that's really
you know all the information that you
might have when making a very important
decision so the quality of training of
the dispensary staff were the
ambassadors of these products right
they're not producing the products
they're not cultivating the products
mostly the dispensary staff has probably
never been inside a manufacturing
facility for cannabis and so it becomes
really important that they understand
from seed to production what is
important in these products and we found
that you know most something like thirty
to forty percent had no science and
medical background we had them over a
phone interview make recommendation
like okay you have a patient coming with
high anxiety what would you recommend in
this instance knowing that you know
you're not supposed to make
recommendations you know strictly like
you got to be careful about that but
this was again a survey and kind of
testing their knowledge about the
products and you know there were some
you know interesting findings and one
was that when we had the statements
anonymous from the dispensary agents
reviewed by physicians by a panel of
physicians and about half the
recommendations the physicians thought
would have exacerbated a patient's
symptoms instead of improved them and
that was concerning for example someone
comes in with saying their have appetite
wasting or anorexia or hiv/aids and they
need to improve their appetite and
someone recommends a CBD rich product
which does not stimulate cannabinoid
receptors so it will not make you hungry
and so that would not have improved
someone's symptoms you know in CBD can
also be alerting and so if someone's
looking for something that's gonna put
them help them sleep better it's
debatable whether or not something rich
and can have a diol alone would be the
best choice just to give you some
conceptual examples to work with sure I
actually run into that all the time with
with patients who are taking CBD for
pain and they want to take it at night
for the pain but but then it causes them
to you know to feel a little stimulated
and have a hard time going to sleep and
so you know we move we move their CBD to
the front part of the day and and give
them you know something with light THC
from dare I call it an indica you know
strain and and you know helps them with
their insomnia but hey we're a little
late for our first break so let's go
ahead and take our short break it's also
very funny to listen to the background I
know that you're in your at your place
in there in Brooklyn and it's a you can
really get a sense of place it sounds
like kids outside playing hopscotch or
whatever they're doing yeah I live in
Crown Heights
and there's actually a rabbi down the
road for me as a big family but he's
also one of the medical cannabis
physicians in New York right okay so
let's go ahead and take that short break
and be right back you're listening to
shaping fire and my guest today is Jhon
Marku a chief science officer at
Americans for safe access
we humans are attracted to plants
because they offer us relief and are a
whole lot of fun sometimes though the
best parts are buried inside the plant
and we need to use specialty extraction
technology when it comes to cannabis it
is extraordinarily important to extract
its precious oils without changing them
in the process we want to preserve the
properties of the cannabinoids terpenes
and other constituents that all work
together since 1994
Eden labs has been developing extraction
technology and processes to do just that
Eden labs was founded by a cannabis
loving engineer during the early days of
medical marijuana in California and the
expanded Eden team has been designing
and building industry-leading solutions
for cannabis extraction ever since
Eden labs flagship product is the newly
improved High Flow co2 extractor as
other extraction companies enter the
market it is the high flow from Eden
labs that everyone chases and tries to
compare themselves with not only that
but the improved automation software
allows data to be collected stored and
studied Eden labs can outfit your whole
lab Eden's coldfinger ethanol extractor
creates astonishing whole plant extracts
working alone or in tandem with an
initial stream distilling step to
isolate monoterpenes before extracting
the rest of the botanical constituents
Eden offers you many options including
vacuum distillation column distilling
stirred reactor units and accelerated
solvent recovery when you partner with
Eden labs your lab team is enrolled into
the Eden labs training program to boost
their understanding of Eden's best
practices to ensure that your outputs
are exactly what you require for your
application whether it be dab oil oil
for pen cartridges or edibles when you
work with Eden you're not just buying
the tech you are buying dedicated
customer support to help you attain your
business goals - you can hear Eden's CEO
AC Braddock talk about the company's
values during shaping fire episode 9
tene that was all about co2 extraction
so many of the new companies in the
market just smell opportunity slap an
extractor together and hire a marketing
company Eden labs has been listening to
feedback from extractors and consumers
for about 25 years now they care about
both you and your consumer partner with
Eden labs to extract astonishing
cannabis oils and terpenes that you will
be proud of go to shaping feiyr.com /e
Dhin to find out more did you know that
shaping fire has a fabulous youtube
channel when i attend conventions to
speak or moderate panels i always record
them and bring the content home for you
to watch the Shango Losey youtube
channel has world-class speakers
including kevin Jodrey of wonderland
nursery talking about breeding cannabis
for the best terpene profile dr. Sunil
Agarwal on the history of cannabis
medicine around the world
tad Hussey of keep it simple organics on
living soil microbes and mycelium and
Ben Cassidy of true terpenes on using
terpenes for health in your everyday
life and Reggie Godinho of steep hill on
the cannabis genome there are several
presentations from dr. Ethan Russo on
terpenes the endocannabinoid system and
holistic orchard Inge and even my own
presentations on how to approach finding
your dream job in cannabis and why we
choose cannabis business even though the
risks are so high as of today there are
over 50 videos you can check out for
free go to youtube.com forward slash
Angello's or click on the link in this
week's newsletter welcome back you are
listening to shaping fire I'm your host
Shengo Lowe's and our guest this week is
Jhon Marku chief science officer at
Americans for safe access
so we talked during the first set about
some of the best practices that have
started to become industry standards and
where those standards are even coming
from and one of the things I think a lot
about is the contrast between processing
enough for the uniformity of the product
so it meets a standard versus the
importance of whole plant medicine and
and and by whole plant medicine of
course I mean preserving all the the
cannabis constituents as a whole group
in the final product so the patient can
take advantage of the
taraji effect for you know both human
healing and equality buzz - the more we
process the more we seem to break up the
plant into its discrete parts thus
moving away from whole plant and I'm
sure that you've had to give you this a
lot of thought in developing being
standard so so where do you kind of
think through this for yourself to find
a happy medium between repeatable
results of a product but also being
whole plants since that's where all the
really good cannabis studies are based
on yeah I mean um well so I've been
injecting cannabis into various
instruments and applying it to cells for
purl for a fair amount of time and I
quickly realized this issue just within
my own hands because you know I was
having to generate data and you know in
just a simple student level and present
it to other people and I was working
with an internship with Arno has
accomplished seems like a lifetime ago
where I had to like ride a bicycle and
pick up samples from a coffee shop as
part of a product safety study and
analyze those in the lab at the
University of Leiden in Holland and I
quickly found out that Wow you know
ethanol versus other solvents like ether
or sodium hydroxide really could change
what you were looking at like you could
use solvents in a setup where you could
actually remove the acids from the
extraction or you could favor the
extraction of some other terpenes and
this is like something we're seeing now
I think is affecting testing is like
people are like oh the labs are getting
it wrong I'm like well sometimes it's
the user error there but also when we do
a targeted analysis like saying we just
want to look at cannabinoids and you
extract for those nothing comes out
entirely unscathed you're gonna have an
efficiency there and some research that
we've done over in the Czech Republic
comparing different very recently
comparing different solvents and
extraction processes to be found like
holy cow like oh wow if you use meth
all over ethanol you're gonna favor
certain terpenes and so what I think
people need to start thinking about is
what they're testing for and so you have
a targeted approach which is like I want
to test for THC and then you can have
non-targeted which is I just want to see
everything that's there before I begin
the targeted approach and you know when
we talk about losing compounds and
changing things it's absolutely possible
you could start with one set of powdered
flower like a standardized batch of
flower its uniform just say imagine a 50
gallon drum of powdered cannabis and
everyone takes a handful out for a
different extraction process e2 makes a
in oil you could end up with as many
oils as samples you took with different
specifications because someone uses a
different ratio of methanol and ether or
whatever it is that they're extracting
in methanol chloroform what have you
versus ethanol or co2 yeah you could end
up with different products and then you
think about the lab well what are they
using to prepare their sample for
analysis cuz the lab just doesn't take a
cookie and like oh this looks good I'm
gonna shove this into my 250,000 dollar
piece of equipment that's a great way to
like destroy a workhorse in your lab
like just clog it and shut down the
system call it a day so they have to
extract what they want to test out of
that and I think that you know as we
think about manufacturing we shouldn't
think so much about focusing on you know
accuracy is important but also what are
you making what are your specifications
you people are very efficiently using
co2 which i think is one of can be one
of the safest extraction methods but use
often times if you're not super savvy
and have 20 years of experience by by
terpenes and you have to kind of collect
those but when you add them back to the
product are you adding them back in the
same ratio that's in the plant and so my
very first research poster was entitled
plant wisdom cannabidiol enhances the
anti-cancer effects of THC it was the
first thing I ever presented at a
research conference and I develop that
idea of
from talking with amazing people reading
other people's work but doing my own
analysis and I had at the time gotten
the permission I think enough time has
passed I can talk about this but at San
Francisco State University I got this
very special permission to do a very
short-term project studying cannabis
through the legal market that had
developed there I was a patient at the
time which made things less complicated
but essentially it was you know I got
permission for this one-year project and
what I found in my own very small
sampling was when I use different
extraction methods I did see slightly
different ratios of compounds but when I
use the same extraction method against
different samples I saw there were
varying ratios of terpenes and
cannabinoids now I didn't quantify
everything I was just doing a non
targeted approach seeing well what is
the fingerprint look like and can we
repeatedly make these fingerprints and
after a while is like wow there is a
difference I mean even 10-15 years ago
you could find a mouse of CBD that were
1 to 5 percent in the cannabis material
being distributed in California but no
one was looking for it at the time and
so I brought that data to a lab where I
was working and said hey you know I have
this chromatography data that looks at
ratios maybe there's something here
maybe some of these ratios might be good
for treating you know a certain disease
what do we got they said well we have
these really aggressive brain cancer
cells and petri dishes that don't seem
to have anything that affects them why
don't we throw some cannabinoids in
there and see what happens and so rather
than start with the the data that we had
from analyzing samples we started with
math and we started well let's just add
THC and an increasing amount see what
happens let's add CBD let's at CBN let's
that CBG
and then we took amounts of those
compounds that really did nothing on the
cancer cells and started combining them
together and through mathematics and
what's called a bunch of other nerdy
statistical stuff I won't go into the
paper has already been published so if
you want to look that up but we found
basically that you know you could
enhance activity with combinations of
cannabinoids and one of the things that
came out of
was a four to one ratio of THC to CBD in
a petri dish to to inhibit brain cancer
cells and so you know if you say we
wanted to turn that into a product
saying wow that looks like something
that can effect a very particular type
of brain cancer a very particular
molecular pathways could be triggered
you know that might inform what type of
product you want from your specification
if the other cannabinoids are not
important and the other terpenoids are
not important then you're going to
extract and process for those purposes
and so I think you know like my
roundabout way of talking about that is
is you know there there can be what's in
the plant and there can be what you
determine scientifically might be needed
for a condition and those two things are
not diametrically opposed through proper
extraction through knowing what you want
to get in the end product you can then
choose an appropriate extraction method
right now I feel like it's a little bit
of like a ready fire aim approach like
let's put everything into the extractor
I have this you know it's you know some
sort of magical filter that separates
things out and so I think when we think
about manufacturing people should have
an idea in mind about what they're doing
and I think GW Pharmaceuticals is sort
of the great conceptual example is they
wanted a one-to-one ratio of THC to CBD
and their product as well as a high
level of certain terpenes that have
strong anti-anxiety properties and so
they took their CBD rich material made a
hash oil extract took their THC rich
material made a hash oil extract and
then combine those and ratios and that
sort of thinking I think needs to start
creeping over into the cannabis industry
you know you people patients are taking
different strains and combining them to
explore their effects
I would encourage more operators to be
more open about what they're making and
what they're combining you know don't
just take all the refuse and throw it in
there keep track of where that extra
material is coming from well these are
two different strains and things like
that
I think it's interesting that excuse me
that you know you kind of approach the
question differ from the opposite
direction that I normally do and in a
lot of the whole plant evangelists that
I talk with where you know we we
generally look at it as that okay you
know either you know your best would be
either smoking or eating the flower
itself there's there's perfect right and
then and then a step down from that
would be you know an ethanol soak which
gets you know a good amount of
everything that's there and then as you
go down you know you know through the
hydrocarbons and co2 you're getting less
and less of the whole plant nosov it and
and and i like your idea that too
instead of continually going back to the
the plant or the flower as being the
goal and to have all the extraction
methods and processing methods have to
compare themselves to the whole plant
instead go the other direction and say
okay what is this that you what's the
end goal of the product is this a an
intense dab oil for an extreme pain
patient is this is this somebody who
needs to get you know just a little bit
of you know THC but a whole lot of THC a
because they're working with Lyme's
disease or rheumatoid arthritis or
something and I think that that approach
is actually far more forgiving for
designers than the way most of us go
about it and and I think that that opens
up some some new possibilities so so let
me take this one this one more step
further then so some product designers
break the cannabis plant into all of its
individual constituents and then rebloom
as they wish customly and in other folks
you use isolates of components and just
sell them as is like the the popularity
of CBD isolate right now but but some
use the full extract cannabis oil
there will be variability in the in the
components from run to run but they're
going to be true to the strain behind it
so my question for you is do you think
that there's a
for that variability that's necessary
when using whole plant extracts because
you know let's say that I let's say that
I run ten plants of the same strain and
I make you know ethanol hash oil out of
it and their own syringes there's gonna
be some drift between syringe but they
really are the pure plant how do you
like resolve that for yourself when
doing standards between staying true to
the plant versus having repeatable
results so that labeling on the package
is accurate well first of all we have
two things one companies have already
created standardized products right with
whole plant flower bed jerk an
international fantastic example of what
you can do with standardized cultivation
procedures and creating sort of a
standardized plant material so you can
make cannabis plant material that will
meet pharmaceutical standards there are
some eyebrow-raising things that they do
like gamma radiate the material which
you know some people don't have a
problem with some people do you know the
banana 8:00 this morning was probably
gamma-irradiated from the grocery store
so so you know there are ability to do
it Connecticut is a state I like to use
too because they have to meet
pharmaceutical standards so when we talk
about this drift it's absolutely
possible but this drift that we talked
about happens with all natural products
no I don't like to often invoke talking
about the alcohol industry but it can be
illuminating and informative and we talk
about its most close you know hops --is
most closely related relative of the
cannabis plant
so breweries deal with this similar
issues too and there's a thing called
heads hearts and tails when you make a
batch huge batch of beer and you know
and that's one of the differences
between some types of beer and others
you know I went to graduate school in
Pennsylvania it's a very rich and
vibrant beer community there of you know
of Vicki's various breweries that people
travel from all over to visit
they deal with the same issue and but
they've done it so much they've put
science in there saying you know when we
are some stuff is coming out of the
vessel and we're bottling it we're
paying attention to those different
things because there's certain parts of
it you don't want where the sediment has
settled or near the top where it might
be different or then maybe it needs to
be continuously mixed while you're
allotting it and so there are lots of
other products that have that are
natural that we see around us every day
and I hate to use you know company names
but you know one of my favorite things
to ask people is why is Budweiser the
king of beers is it because it's
delicious and refreshing
well you know that's questionable but
it's really because it's the same
anywhere you open it you open it in
Japan or Paris or you know in Tennessee
it's going to be the same product within
a certain level of acceptable variation
and I think you know thinking about it
in broader terms yeah if you are
capsulated or packaging a batch there
might be certain things you can do to
reduce the standards but that's also why
you keep track of batches and also know
what part you might want to use I've
seen you know extracts that have been
sitting for years and in storage you
know I used to work under a DEA license
in the past and I did some really just
super fun stuff collaborating with my
food also the university Sippy used to
characterize new cannabinoids so you
would discover and things like that and
visiting Ole Miss and you know you can
see that even extracts that were
homogenized after they've been sitting
for a while they will start to separate
and you will see this sort of head
hearts and Tails sort of thing happen or
even a biphasic thing where some of the
you know fats and stuff go to the top
even just sitting on a shelf over time
right on so as far as the drift you know
with some of the cannabinoids it's more
serious than others right if there's if
there's a drift in CBG unless that's the
part of the medicine that you need you
know the CBG may or may not matter but
with THC obviously it
serious really fast and one of the most
serious challenges that edibles makers
have is to ensure that each piece has
the same dosage for example eating the
first of ten cookies in a package
expecting it to be ten milligrams when
it's actually 17 milligrams can be a big
deal to many users
so imagine ization is a real problem you
know what best practices do you see the
industry adopting so each edible of a
particular package is reliably dosed
I think that that comes down to
developing a method for properly
extracting the cannabinoids from your
edibles one thing that has always struck
me is weird is that you know I visit a
lot of cannabis labs and almost no
manufacturer provides a blank of their
product for the labs to calibrate to
like they might provide them the soda or
the cookie or the Lawson's
but they don't provide them just that
matrix like oh here is what we use so
you can create a sample prep method and
you and and so that's part of it too and
that was an issue and we were doing at a
small team and we were traveling between
different labs with our equipment to to
look at edibles and what we published
and throughout into the the Internet's
was a if you freeze these products and
pulverize them you can create a powder
of almost anything and then do a more
efficient extraction but still you know
we ran into the issue where companies
could not supply a blank of their
product so that we could spike it with
cannabinoids and make sure that we were
validating that collection process so I
think that there is one that's aspect of
it which says that you know I think
every every single cannabis manufacturer
needs an in-house lab you can't label
your own supply but it can be extremely
helpful to check along the production
line if you're doing things correctly so
as you go from Step a to step B to step
C to set D your two
measurements of one type or another
maybe there are gal elliptic maybe it's
the smell and feel thing maybe it's a
decarboxylation step and then for the
final testing you send it out to the lab
that is what's now you know versus the
old reactionary method which is we're
going to make something and get a
pass/fail at the end which leads to a
lot of waste a lot of questions about
standardization and then you know thin
layer chromatography using the silica
plates and other devices can provide a
wealth of information to help guide you
in that production process and so I
think for your if you're trying to
develop a better brownie or lozenge or
delivery of any product you're gonna
need the in-house lab it just isn't
going to be feasible usually unless you
have a very good relationship and
they're nearby working with a lab to get
those instantaneous results that can
feed rnd and give you sort of real-time
so you can make adjustments in the
process see to make sure you're getting
that standardized product and you also
have to determine what makes a batch
right and I think what you see you know
people always talk about the oh the dog
food industry uses like fifty pounds of
dog food per batch to do their sampling
for quality control and you tell you
know yeah we're gonna do fifty pounds of
cannabis extract and you're like no way
that life is like the price per gold per
ounce there's no way we're giving you
that it's way too expensive but
sometimes something like that and I'm
not you know those numbers are conflated
but you know what needs to be understood
is that when you first start a product
the amount that you have to sacrifice
for quality control to establish those
limits is vast it's large it's a big
wide sampling area and as you say okay
look these products are being consistent
these products have these specifications
you can start to narrow that testing
window and make it tighter and tighter
and tighter until there's issues and
then you have to kind of expand it again
and so it's kind of like our universe
which expands and contracts
as should the sampling window to ensure
that your you know product safety and
consistency and so I think you know if
you're say making edible products you
might be sacrificing a batch or two for
lab to make sure you have a validated
method for that particular edible right
on so we're gonna take our second short
break and rev be right back you are
listening to shaping fire and my guest
today is Jan Marku chief science officer
of Americans for safe access
skinny-dipping humpback whales beatnik
poetry the Ottoman Empire soil
remediation interdimensional beings and
tree frogs these are just a few of the
interesting topics you can find in the
audio books library at audible.com if
you like podcasts like shaping fire
chances are that you will like
audiobooks too just like with podcasts
audiobooks speak to you telling you
stories and teaching you stuff here's
the thing audible.com has an offer I
want to tell you about right now they
are offering a trial of their audiobook
service for absolutely free you can go
to shaping feiyr.com
forward slash audible and you will get a
free audiobook straight up listen on
your mobile device computer or you can
download it and listen to it like
anywhere it's really simple of course
they want you to subscribe to their
service after the free trial and enjoy
audiobooks forever but you don't have to
all you have to do to get the free
audiobook of your choice is to check out
the service for free so that's the deal
your first book is free it's easy to
sign up it's easy to quit and their
online library of books is pretty
incredible so just check it out go to
shape and feiyr.com forward slash
audible to find out more or click on the
link in this week's newsletter as a
business owner you are incredibly busy
in reality you are responsible for
everything your company does you have so
many responsibilities every single day
that often you just don't have the time
to really dig into something as deeply
as you'd like you know there is more
that you could do to reach out to new
customers and to encourage loyalty and
the customers you already have but you
certainly don't have the time and you're
not ready to hire someone full-time for
that role either for you I recommend
blunt branding blunt branding principles
Kirsten
Nelson and Anthony Garcia are focused on
improving your bottom line
you know most marketing firms are
excited to make your logo packaging and
website very pretty but they leave
responsibility for improving your bottom
line up to you they don't want that kind
of responsibility but that is pretty
much the most important part of
marketing right Kirsten and Anthony will
help you engage new customers funnel
them to your point of sale and keep them
coming back to you and telling their
friends no doubt this is a paid
commercial spot but that does not mean
they bought my opinion I've worked with
blunt branding on three projects now for
various clients and every single time
they have done more than they have
promised and over delivered on results I
love how they generate new revenue and
focus on that as the goal instead of
just making me a pretty logo
similarly every friend I've referred
them to has come back to thank me and
that just does not happen every day so
grab a pen and paper because the website
address is coming if you want someone to
implement marketing programs that feed
your bottom line give blunt branding a
call they will share proven techniques
to increase your audience and generate
sales while using cutting-edge
technology in the background that make
all of this easy automatic and trackable
go to shaping feiyr.com forward slash
blunt branding to find out more you can
also click the link in our weekly
newsletter Blount branding marketing
that makes you money welcome back you
are listening to shaping fire I'm your
host Shango Louis and I guess this week
is Jhon Markku chief science officer at
Americans for safe access so you know
the the obvious end game for all these
standards outside of just simple patient
and consumer safety is that eventually
the United States will be able to
participate in the the brand-new
international trade of cannabis and
cannabinoids you know it's already
starting and the United States is is
quickly falling behind because we're
still schedule one but I know that you
work with international groups too to
help develop these standards
Androids and so I'm curious you know at
this point from the the countries that
are just now starting to trade like you
know Canada's exporting and such who is
setting the international standards for
cannabis now is there a an international
governing body that people are deferring
to or is it simply country a and Country
B they're adopting their own standards
and they're trading based on that uh the
answer is yes and no largely who
determines the standards and
international regulations are the people
who show up to those meetings and a lot
of standards are done through a
voluntary consensus process which means
that volunteers people are giving their
time to international standards groups
to work on these committees so for
example I am a chairman of the d 37
cannabis subcommittee under training
credentialing and assessment that's the
standards I'm working on wow they really
they really gave it a sexy title didn't
they I know I know it almost fits on a
business card but they were working on
an acronym but you know they were they
have a dozen other subcommittees are
addressing everything from security to
cultivation standards and they're it's
all run by volunteers at ASTM and now
there that's the international level and
in order to get to the international
level the individual players like the
country a country B has to develop
monographs right so the US has a
monograph we've reintroduced cannabis
into the pharmacopoeia the Holland has a
monograph Germany has a monograph and a
couple other countries do which has led
Europe to say okay well these countries
have standards for their products now we
can start to come together and harmonize
those across jurisdictional boundaries
and and what we really want to avoid is
you know politicians who have no may
have no experience and well there are
variable there's like two politicians in
our entire country that have a science
background but you know most do not have
experience with medicine or product
safety it's it's there
kind of doing what sounds good often and
so we end up with these really
incongruent standards and we're
international standards come in as if a
group like ASTM which if you don't
aren't familiar I'd consider a quick
internet search save us some time here
but they're international standards body
create tons of standards we've submitted
our best practices that we've worked on
to help guide this but as soon as ASTM
post something countries that don't have
any regulations established which is
pretty much a lot of them will adopt
that immediately and that will probably
supplant what's going on and so when we
talk about walking with dinosaurs if
you're not paying attention to what's
happening with the voluntary consensus
standards process you're gonna be
hitting us a wall it's just a matter of
time and developing your own standards
at the local level you know whether or
not that will be even considered by
international standards group that all
governments look to for guiding their
industry is dependent on you finishing
those standards and showing up to the
meeting where people have been doing
this for like a hundred years developing
standards for products and so I think
you know I used to say I think
erroneously or maybe miss speaking say
you know I was encouraging people like I
actually stopped creating new cannabis
groups we have so many resources here
but now I feel more like okay maybe it's
a good thing that we see all these sort
of independent groups that aren't
talking to each other but they should be
bringing their standards up for peer
review and one dangerous trend for me
that I see as groups that cell standards
to people standards are not some secret
thing that should be behind paywalls you
should be accessible to everyone so that
everyone can understand product safety
so they can effectively protect public
health you know in these issues and I
think that participation is essential
right now and looking if even if you're
your only option is locally but put
pressure on your representatives of the
local industry association to
participate in ASTM to participate in
opera or these other groups that are
working nationally and internationally
oh go ahead when you when you go when
you attend these international meetings
where the where the standards are being
discussed and and and brought to
fruition
are there US government representatives
there because you know the US has a
tendency to just poopoo anything that we
were not involved with and I can imagine
a world where you know we're all we're
all still scheduled wanting over here
and and this this international body is
making these standards and then if if
the US government isn't involved when we
finally get around to be scheduling
suddenly you know we'll be like oh well
we weren't involved with those we're
gonna have to start all over again and
so my question for you is is is is is
the US government involved in some ways
so that when we eventually do schedule
we can slide right in and the second
part of that question is what do you
think that we would need to do to bring
our industry in line with those
standards so that we could start
participating in international trade
well I think that government
representatives will always have a
arms-length approach to something like
this but it's not to mean that people
who don't have experience or are showing
up as individuals not representing
government issue there we do encounter
people who work or have worked with the
EPA for example FDA people and you know
the FDA has rotational advisors you know
you're not just like oh and we're at the
FDA I want to work with them for 20
years yeah people say that but
oftentimes they're rotated in and out
like they work for a year then they're
off for a year and so you know that
allows some interesting dynamics there
but I think whether or not the US
government participates and I think it's
also worth pointing out that groups like
the United States pharmacopoeia the USP
a lot of people talk about this that's
not a government agency that's a
non-governmental agency almost a lot of
standards groups are non governmental
agencies they're they're independent and
things like that
but let's just say you know standards
process with a steams gonna take years
to develop and release it took us eight
years to develop the standards have been
adopted in over 20 states for best
practices and we could see something
similar with HTM but it's best to start
early because even if it remains
Schedule one I would make a significant
bet I'll give you a two to one on it
that if ASTM was a releases standard
tomorrow it would be rapidly adopted in
all the states as saying you must follow
standards equivalent to this ASTM
standard because it is the international
body and that would supplant a lot of
perhaps what they're referencing now in
the literature or compliment what
they're you know you can give you an
example maybe on you know must train
employees according to standards by ASTM
or must you know have security practices
in line or equal to the standards that
ASTM and I think that you know whether
or not the US is ready for international
trade in some ways it's already
happening GW sativex Epidaurus
you think they need it rescheduled to
get their products in the country it's
their market advantage you know the
University of Mississippi with their
cannabis production their market
advantage right now is the schedule one
and their single license and so I think
we have to think about a little
skeptically is that some groups like
pharmaceutical companies may not need it
rescheduled to do what they want to do
with international trade you know
cannabis products can't be made here
really but they can be shipped here such
as like again Sativex and licensed
pharmaceuticals so i think that whether
or not it gets rescheduled people need
to be ready for the next wave of
standards because even if cannabis got
rescheduled and let's just say for sake
of argument what's a schedule to what
would change for all the dispensaries in
California probably nothing because
they'd all still be federal illegal
non-fda-approved products but what we
would see is an increasing ability of
our
government to issue guidance the EPA
might be able to start to say oh it's on
Schedule one substance anymore maybe we
can issue some pesticide guidance
officially right because right now all
pesticide use of cannabis even if it's
appropriate safe is illegal because it's
a Schedule one substance a mandatory
minimums criminal penalties access to
banking some of these issues might
loosen up if you know the where their
wheels will grease by a change of
scheduling status but we still have a
lot of work to do to harmonize that
federal and state law and so it's this
weird area where we're on track to
harmonize federal and state law we have
a couple of milestones to reach but just
because that's happening doesn't mean
that international standards aren't
going to be becoming mandated in those
states that have cannabis programs
well since the standardization process
is so long I'm actually quite relieved
that there's already an international
body who's getting started now so that
by the time that we reschedule or D
schedule there are standards that are
already in place instead of starting
that 20 year process whenever we get
scheduled you know so well thank you for
being on the show John I know you're up
your your time is very valuable and I
appreciate you coming on and sharing
with us these these insider thoughts
about how standardization is coming
along and where it's headed
well thank you it is really great to be
able to to share this information and
you know if if your listeners have a lot
of questions I'd be happy to answer them
and a follow up or written response to
if if people are interested in learning
more right on and and and folks who want
to learn more but they they don't want
to wait around for another episode you
can find out more about the
patient-focused certification at
creatively enough patient-focused
certification org also if you want to
find out more about the events and going
ons full of safe access for the
Americans for safe access you can go to
their website at safe access now dot org
forward slash events
and and jaylen is very active on Twitter
and so you know if you've got a question
in a 140 characters or less you can feel
free to reach out to Jaylin on twitter
at je han Markku and so that's @j aah
a n ma r CU you can find more episodes
of the shaping fire podcast and
subscribe to the show at shaping fire
calm and on Apple iTunes stitcher and
Google Play if you enjoyed the show we'd
really appreciate it if you'd leave a
positive review of the podcast wherever
you download your review will help
others find the show so they can enjoy
it too on the shaping fire website you
can also subscribe to the weekly
newsletter for insights into the latest
cannabis news and product reviews on the
shaping fire website you will also find
transcripts of today's podcast as well
for information on me and where I'll be
speaking you can check out Shango lows
calm your company want to reach our
national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hotspot at shaping
fire calm to find out how thanks for
listening to shaping fire I've been your
host Shango lows
[Music]