[Music]
I think it is fair to say that most
people who enjoy cannabis do so because
of the THC in cannabis. That said, I
know plenty of people who are focused on
the other canabonoids for either health
or commerce reasons. Plenty of people
obtain their relief through CBD or CBG
or CBN or the other novel canabonoids
and next generation products like
beverages infused with these canabonoids
have become a huge hit in the market.
But many of these companies are held
back because those other canabonoids are
associated too directly with the wrongly
persecuted THC molecule. Hemp has been
one way to try and take a half step away
from full THC plants in order to gain
access to the other canabonoids. But now
many states, including California, have
made canabonoids from hemp even
disallowed. For example, I used to love
Creek River Botanical Hops and
canabonoid beverages, but I can't find
their products anywhere now due to the
change in California law interpretation.
While it was foolish from the beginning
to prohibit the cannabis plant at all,
prohibiting access to the non-THC
canabonoids is even worse. It's like
dumb stacked upon ignorance. It sure
would be great if we could get
canabonoids from a secondary plant that
doesn't have THC in it at all, wouldn't
it? If you want to learn about cannabis
health, cultivation, and technique
efficiently and with good cheer, I
encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter. We'll send you new podcast
episodes as they come out, delivered
right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week and
videos, too. Don't rely on social media
to let you know when a new episode is
published. Sign up for the updates to
make sure you don't miss an episode.
Also, we're giving away very cool prizes
to folks who are signed up to receive
the newsletter. So, go to
shapingfire.com to sign up for the
newsletter and be entered into this
month's and all future newsletter prize
drawings. If you like what we do and
want to put something in the chip jar,
you can Venmo at
Shangolos. You are listening to Shaping
Fire and I am your host Shangolos.
Welcome to episode 121. My guest today
is Dr. Paula Berman. Dr. Berman earned
her bachelor's in biotechnology
engineering and her master's and PhD in
environmental engineering from Bengurian
University. Throughout her studies, she
worked in the plant lipid biotechnology
lab under Professor Za Vman, focusing on
the chemistry of vegetable oils and
their applications in biodeiesel
production. She completed her first
postdoctoral fellowship in the cancer
biology and canabonoid research lab at
the Technon's faculty of biology led by
professor Diddy Mary. As the lab's lead
analytical chemist, she developed mass
spectrometry methods to identify over a
100 canabonoids in cannabis as well as
endockinabonoids and related
compounds. Paula then joined the lab of
professor Esaf Aheroni at the plant
science department at the vitzman
institute where she completed a second
posttock and now serves as a research
associate. Her research focuses on the
biosynthetic pathways of canabonoids and
psychedelics with therapeutic potential.
This coming summer, Paula will establish
her own research lab at the Volcani
Agricultural Center, where she will
continue investigating medicinal plants
and their specialized metabolites. This
is truly impressive work. Today, we're
going to learn about the woolly umbrella
plant, uh, better known in the lab as
the heli. We conducted today's interview
halfway around the world from each
other. So there are a few echoes and
minor drops today, but nothing annoying.
During the first set, we will discuss
the botanical attributes, distribution,
and uses for the heli plant. In the
second set, we dig into the various
canabonoids, extraction methods, and
applications. And we finish the episode
with a short discussion about the future
of this amazing plant, both commercially
and scientifically. Welcome to Shaping
Fire, Dr. Berman. Hello, Shango. It's a
pleasure to be here. Thank you so much
for taking time uh especially since we
are so far separated in the world today
to be up uh late uh talking to me and
early here. I I appreciate you making a
special time for us. It's my pleasure.
Thank you for this invitation. So let's
start off with the simple basics with uh
the woolly umbrella plant. It has a
complex to me scientific name. I tried
to say it a bunch of times in
preparation for our interview today and
and each time I said it different. So
instead of me embarrassing myself, let
us please start. Would you say the
scientific name for us so that we can
all learn it together? Uh so the name is
Elryum Umbraum.
Thank you. That is a mouthful.
It's also tough for us. Yeah, I believe
it. Um so Woolly Umbrella is the common
name that I have most come across. Is
that your preferred common name as well?
Uh, so actually in the lab we call the
plant Heli as a nickname. Oh, that's
cool. Heli from the from the from the
from its proper Latin name. Great. Um,
and so great. So I'll probably go back
and forth between heli and woolly just
so I can feel scientific. Um, so so let
let's start with um the distribution of
the heli. where where is the heli plant
found and what are its basic
characteristics?
Uh so it's the the origin is in South
Africa in the eastern part of South
Africa. H it's a it's a a perennial
herb. H it grows all year round. H it
flowers around January to April. Um it's
an ornamental plant in South Africa. It
grows wild. H it has um um silver hairy
leaves and with beautiful um bright
yellow flowers that look like umbrellas
and that's where the name of the plant
comes from.
The um you said that it's used for
ornamental purposes primarily. Does it
have a reputation as a medicinal plant
at all or or was this um a surprise to
find medicinal properties in this plant?
H so a lot of helicry plants h from
South Africa have a medicinal
um erh purposes um it's known to be
burnt in rituals in cleansing rituals to
h connect to ancestors to provide
spiritual guidance and induce
transes the zulu tribes use a lot of
elicryome species as part of their
traditional medicine h but to be honest
We couldn't find exact proof whether
this specific helicryome plant helip
plant has medicinal purposes. I mean I
we know now about many of the molecules
that the plant biosynthesize the plant
the molecules that the plant
accumulates. But we cannot say for sure
what are the exact medicinal purposes.
We found a study for example that found
that extracts from the ryzen
plant have a gaba receptor binding
effect which h possibly have anxolytic
effects anti-epileptic or can be used
for insomnia and there are also a lot of
other molecules that have many different
bioactivities. Um, but the really
interesting thing about this plant is
that it's really
been overlooked over the years. It's not
been studied and there's there is very
little information about it. Well, uh,
that's fun cuz that way you get to
explore all the parts of it that you
want to. You don't have to go just for
the pockets of lacking research. That's
great to be the the first to a plant.
Where where on the plant do the
canabonoids
um uh appear? Are they expressed? Um, as
you know, our, you know, the show that
we're on shaping fire, we are mostly
focused on the cannabis plant, but
really canabonoid medicine in general,
which is how I found my way to you. And
in cannabis, the the canabonoids are
grown in the reinous flowers. Where are
they grown? Um, in the heli plant. So,
in the heli plant, we found canabonoids
in all the aerial parts of the plant h
besides roots. Um so basically any type
of tissue that contained a glandular
tricom. So similar in cannabis in
cannabis you have so in fluorosences of
cannabis are the most abundant in
glandular tricoms and this is where
these the canopinoids are biosynthesized
and where they accumulate. So similarly
we found it also in the helip plant h
they are biosynthesized and they
accumulate to these glandular tricoms
and these are most abundant in leaves
actually h we found them also very
abundant in flowers but h most
interesting and the highest potential
for us is h the fact that they
accumulate the most in leaves since they
are in tricoms uh glandular tricoms in
the heli plant just like they are in
cannabis this when you rub the plant
with your finger will you burst tricoms
and get the smell of the aroma of the
plant? Uh so you do I mean it's it's
quite different than in
cannabis. You have a very light aroma
very nice aroma like a perfume h from
the leaves and when you rub them you
have this reinous material on your
fingers. Definitely. Oh cool. So, so you
spearheaded this comprehensive study
that unveiled the plant's rather unique
ability to produce canabonoids. I'm I'm
really interested in what I guess I'll
call the ignition point of this idea.
So, you know, finding canabonoids in
plants is so atypical, I think, that it
wouldn't be the first thing that I would
look for. Um, it begs the question,
which came first? Did you did you go to
this plant looking for canabonoids or
somehow did you come across them
accidentally in the lab and then you
explored what you found? Which which
came first when deciding to go into um
working with this heli plant? So
actually we were not the first ones that
found that the plant produces
cannabonoids. H there is a German paper
from
1979 H that found that the plant
produces large amounts of CBGA
um um along with other
molecules a more protein types molecules
and some other types um but
um despite the fact that h the plant
that that it was shown that the plant
produces canabonoids this plant was very
largely overlooked
There were no additional studies looking
into the
phytochemistry, no genome, no
transcriptto, no biological information
whatsoever on the plant. Um, there was
another study from 2018 led by professor
Totes Capati and Professor Giovanni
Aendino which is a very known expert in
natural product chemistry group from
Italy. And they were also trying to
confirm that the the plant that hel
produces h cannabonoids and to find what
other cannabonoids it produces. And to
their surprise and to our surprise h
they couldn't find any ail canabonoids.
H only cannabonoid like molecules
molecules that have a very similar um
chemical structure like cannabonoids but
instead of alkal chains which we find in
cannabonoids h they have an aromatic
moty. So in this other study from 2018
they also couldn't find any canabinoids.
So when we started this study
h basically our first question was does
the plant produce cannaboids or not? It
wasn't uh we it wasn't confirmed and so
this was our starting point. Um so what
methods did you use to analyze the plant
for canabonoids? What did you do
differently that um caused you to find
them? So I I don't think that h I mean
we used the same methods as the
other group did and I will just talk
about them very briefly. I think that
the difference was that perhaps they
were using a different chemovar that in
their chemovar so like you have in
cannabis high THC high CBD high CBG and
so on types of chemovar. So perhaps they
were analyzing a chemov that doesn't
have cannabonoids. Um but actually it
was for us it was the quite immediate uh
that we identified that the plant has a
very large amounts of CBGA and the way
that we did it is using a
LCMS HLC which is connected to a mass
spectrometer it's so it's a method it's
an analytical chemistry method that
allows us to take very complex um
samples and to be able to identify the
specific compounds that are present in
our samples. Um so this was the the
basic uh um method or instrument that we
use for the identification. Uh but we
also use some other techniques. So for
example um uh we use the fact that we
were growing the plant. So we we h use a
feeding of isotopically labeled
molecules. So these are molecules that
have isotopic labeled specific carbons
or hydrogens that are labeled in the
molecule that are more that are heavier
than than the other atoms that are in
the molecule. And then um we dip leaves
into solutions that contain these um um
these molecules, these labeled molecules
and we basically feed the leaves h with
the labelled compounds and then
following several days of feeding h we
can see whether the plant uses these
molecules they incorporate them in the
biosynthesis using LCMS. So basically we
can
um test whether a a specific molecule a
precursor is taken by a the specific
enzymes in the plant to produce the
molecules cannabonoids in in this
instance. So, so we also used this
feeding of isotopically labeled
molecules and using LCMS uh we could
identify which of the molecules were
labeled by um
specific specific atoms. Um we also
purified specific molecules and then
structural lucidated them using
NMR. And we use a really cool technique
uh to do localization of molecules to
find where these molecules are
specifically localized in the tissues.
It's a it's a a method that is called
multi imaging mass spectrometry imaging
where we do masspec h we acquire a
spectrum for each h pixel in our sample.
So we can show specifically what is the
location the localization of specific
canabonoids or any other molecule that
is in the sample. That's like what a
helpful tool. I can I can imagine um the
the cheer that went through the lab on
the on the day that you found
canabonoids in your first attempt. you
know there there there are the you know
these rumors and and perhaps CBGA and
and and and suddenly your lab uh you
know digs into it and suddenly boom
there they are. I can imagine that that
was a huge encouragement for everybody
on the team. Yes, you are correct.
So So these canabonoids that we're
finding in the heli plant are are these
identical to those found in cannabis? I
I I'm assuming that they are the same
molecule just occurring in a different
place. Is that accurate? H So some of
them are similar and others were
different. So um we found around 40
identified around 40 cannabonoids in the
heli
plant. No THCA, no CBDA. We found
different types of CBGA canabonoids with
different alkal chains. We found small
amounts of
CBCA and
the m most of the other types of
cannabonoids were completely new novel
cannabonoids that are not present or
have not been identified in cannabis. Oh
my gosh, how exciting. Uh do do I I know
I'm jumping ahead a little bit, but do
we know if those new canabonoids
interact with the human endockinabonoid
system yet or we is it too early to
know?
So, unfortunately, we haven't tested
them yet. I think that this is one of
the first things that uh we would really
really like to do. I bet it's so
exciting.
Um but uh we are pretty sure that they
also have other bioactivities and they
that they bind to different receptors.
So in this paper by um
professor Tetellas Kafati and professor
Giovanni Pendino H they tested some of
the molecules that they found in uh the
helip uh for binding affinities to h TRP
channels and to h CB-1 CB2 and and some
other ones. So even um some of more
fruin types can carabinoids that they
found the ones that have the aromatic
mighty instead of the alkal chain h some
of them also show the h
potential so we are pretty sure that
these will be
um expanding the repertoire of
modulators of the endocanabinoid system
but unfortunately they still await
testing. Sure. Sure, I understand. Um,
so I I assume that you are able to
isolate these canabonoids in the lab.
Um, as somebody who studies uh plant
medicine preparations in the home by
citizen scientists, if you will, um, uh,
other than extracting the canabonoids
from the plant in the lab, can this
plant be smoked whole as it is as well
or um, are there other uh, chemicals in
the plant that make it unattractive to
be smoked in in other traditional ways?
You mentioned, you know, some of the
heli plants were were burnt into smudge
pots and such traditionally, but I we I
don't know about this particular plant.
Um, so um I I don't know. I can't give
you like I I don't know exactly because
we've never tested it. Um there is since
there is so little information about it,
I would say that first someone needs to
test the toxicity. H we found that there
that there is no mutagenicity. H we
found a paper that looked into the
mutagenicity and there is none for this
extract. But I I think that it should be
tested for safety before I can recommend
people to start smoking it. Um
sure. And and even if you said that um
we we would never recommend that anybody
smoke it here. So I'm we we don't
definitely don't recommend that. But um
I figured if there was any reason that
you were like, "Oh yeah, like like this
plant also has got a natural biotoxin in
it." I figured I'd want to get that out
right away. So
um also the plant doesn't have THCA, so
you would probably don't will not have
the same effect as in cannabis. Sure.
But the, you know, the the the CBGA
certainly got a lot of attention be
because so many people in the states
have a hard time finding um CBG other
than in isolate, which I recognize
isolate is more popular for um you know,
the the pharmaceutical pursuit, but um
folks look for cannabis that is high in
CBG, at least here in the States, for
its you know, for its other medicinal
uses. And so that's that's the direction
I was coming from. Does the plant have
um a how do I want to say this? Are
there a lot of canabonoids in each plant
like the the potency if you will of each
plant? Is it very high or or is the is
the amount of u the volume of
canabonoids in the plant uh lower where
where um compared to say cannabis? Uh so
when we measured uh concentrations
absolute concentrations of cannabonoids
um we found that the leaves that are the
most abundant as I mentioned before h it
has around 4% of uh CBGA per dry weight
which is a lot much more than you can
find in most cannabis chemovers that are
not high CBG. So I know that now there
are these high CBG uh strains uh that
for sure have a much higher
concentrations uh but for CBGAS uh quite
a lot. Yeah, for sure. That's
impressive. It's good. That's exactly
what I was hoping to find out. That's
that's a good news source. Um, so you
know, for cannabis and canabonoid
enthusiasts like we here at Shaping
Fire, your discovery is very important
and exciting, but I'm curious what the
response was from the scientific
community and separately the
pharmaceutical product community to your
research. um you know uh we want to hear
that you were celebrated and you have
attracted all of this new research
grants and and and that and that you
know this plant has become a celebrity
but that's not always the case and and
and I don't know the answer so so what
was the response from the science
community and the and the pharmaceutical
community h so actually the responses
were very enthusiastic good we got very
amazing responses Um I think that the
the biggest achievements that we made
the biggest advance advancements uh to
the field in this uh study h was first
of all the very comprehensive chemistry
that
we elucidated h the fact that we
provided another genome and transcryto
of a plant that produces cannabonoids.
um the enzymes that we identified uh
that you can use in etrology systems to
produce cannabonoids outside of the
plant. uh which by until this point were
only known from uh cannabis and now we
contributed to new enzymes that h can
contribute both to the to um the the
same types of cannabonoids but also to
produce h new types of cannabonoids h um
that were never been tested or are not
known h including new nature types of
cannabonoids
Um also it was very
[Music]
um the fact that we shed light uh to the
um evolution or we suggest about the
evolution of the biosynthetic pathway of
canaboninoids to have another plant that
produces the same types of molecules as
plant scientists. H it was very excited
and we got really good responses. H we
think that uh and we heard that it opens
uh new frontiers or avenues for
uh new as new modulators, new molecules
that can modulate the endocanabinoid
system and I believe that it has a whole
new type of entry effect.
This is great.
So we've mentioned the fact that the
plant produces cannabonoids but besides
cannabonoids h there are also other
types of meurpoids or tarpenols that are
also produced in very high quantities
along with h the canabonoids and h these
also have some of them have already
bioactivities that are known h ones that
h we elucidated which are completely new
Um so I think that overall uh this was
very exciting and the response from uh
uh all around was very exciting very
encouraging. Oh well congratulations and
and and I know that um you know this is
a pretty obscure topic for a lot of
people. I'm sure that when you go to you
know a cocktail party or something this
is lost on a lot of people but talking
with us we we're we are your supporters.
we're we're your fan base and and I and
and you know for us this feels like you
know a high five big celebration.
There's so much new potential you know
healing potential and science potential
and an entourage effect potential. Um I
mean there's there are lifetimes of
research here. So so we're we're all
excited with you. So congratulations.
So, so this plant, does does finding
this plant suggest that there might be
other plants um within the the heli um
um family isn't accurate, but um a genus
that um that might also be providing um
canabonoids or do we feel like we we
found the one within the genus?
Um
so as a plant scientist I think h that
or I expect that there
are hidden treasures that we haven't
elucidated yet. I think that nature is
amazing and h it's the the diversity is
so large that we there are still so many
plants that remain unexplored. Um I
would like to also mention that there
are also other plants that uh produce
cannabonoids or canominoid like
molecules. There's a rodendum doricum h
a plant it's not helicryome genus. It's
a different plant but it produces the
canabinoids. I mean it's also alkal
types canabonoids but they are quite
different. They are um CBCA type
cannaboninoid h but also produces them
in very large amounts. H also some other
um cannaboninoid like molecules h that
are called the
morphins. So I am if if these have all
been identified I am pretty sure that we
will hear also about some other uh new
plants. Fantastic. We're going to take a
short break and be right back. You are
listening to Shaping Fire and my guest
today is plant biochemist Dr. Paula
Berman. Fish Poop brand fertilizer is an
all-natural Omry certified fish poop
concentrate with nothing added. Real
fish poop is extraordinarily complex.
Not only are you adding the nitrogen,
phosphorus, and potassium your plants
need to build mass, transport nutrients,
and enhance flavor, but fish waste is
also packed with probiotics and
micronutrients. When you add fish poop
to your irrigation water, you are adding
fertilizer in a form that strengthens
the soil food web in your garden.
Because plants are limited by the
absence of any essential micronutrient,
these trace nutrients are the difference
between having a decent garden and
having a garden that makes you feel
really proud of your efforts. Fish poop
is a naturally complete solution that
fills in the cracks in your fertilizer
program to ensure that you offer your
garden a broad base of
nutrients. Not all fish poop is created
equally. Most products with added fish
waste don't reveal their sources or lab
results. Fish Poop brand Fish Poop,
however, generates their own fish waste
as a byproduct of their organic
aquaponics cannabis farm where they
raise ornamental koi and tilapia. You
are even invited to tour their farm in
person or on their YouTube channel to
look for yourself. This sort of
transparency is wildly rare in the
fertilizer market. The folks behind Fish
Poop are also lifelong medical cannabis
producers who have deep connections in
the community, donate more product than
they sell, and support cannabis
prisoners, veteran, and patient
collectives and charities. To get your
bottle of pure fish poop, go to
fishp.com or search for fish poop on
Amazon or walmart.com. And to see their
entire line of cannabis products, go to
ounceofhope.com. That's fish poop brand
fish
poop. You've heard me talk about the
award-winning cannabis seeds that come
from the analytical breeding program of
Seth and Eric Crawford, who founded
Oregon CBD Seeds. In fact, Seth was a
guest on Shaping Fire in 2020 to talk
about triploid genetics. Seth and Eric
are now releasing high THC seeds for
home growers and farms as
Growtherevolution Seeds at gtr
seeds.com. Their high THC seeds are
extraordinary in that they will start to
flower at 16 1/2 hours of daylight
instead of the typical 14 1/2 hours of
daylight. That means in most regions
your plants will start to flower
outdoors in the middle of July instead
of the middle of August. which means
these photo period plants finish in
September and not October, totally
upending the photo period seed market.
Seth and Eric took their prized early
flowering CBG line and bred it to some
of the most desired verified genetics
out there, including Sour Diesel,
Triangle Kush, Wedding Cake, Chem Dog,
Skittles, and others. These crosses all
express powerful photo period tarpine
profiles and THC, giving you a great
high. GTR Seeds has a new THCV line with
plants like double Durban and Gigantor
that boasts 1:1 THC to THCV and people
want that
THCV. GTR seeds are very consistent true
growing inbred F1s from stabilized
inbred parent lines. These seeds are
nearly homogeneous and the plants should
all grow the same. There is only one
phenotype in every pack available as
diploids and triploids. Seth and Eric's
company is still familyowned, patient
and employee centric and partially
powered by their 2 acres of solar
panels. Everyone can purchase these
seeds and the entire catalog of Oregon
CBD seeds at gtr seeds.com. Go to gtr
seeds.com today and choose something
revolutionary for your next indoor or
outdoor run.
One of the challenges with buying
autoflower seeds is that often you'll
have as many different fenos as you will
have seeds in a pack. That can be fun,
sure, but so many varieties in one pack
is a sign of an immature seed line that
hasn't been worked enough. I prefer my
autoflowers to be worked enough that
each pheno in the pack really captures
the aspects that the breeder was
intending.
This is why I recommend Gnome Automatics
to my friends and listeners who grow
automatic flowering cannabis seeds.
Gnome automatic seeds are not just
crossed and released. They are
painstakingly sifted again and again,
tested in a wide range of conditions,
and taken to a level of maturity that
each plant will be recognizable by its
traits. Traits that were hard-earned so
that you can have your best growth cycle
ever. Over the last 10 years, Gnome
Automatics founder Dan Jimmy has become
a trusted breeder, and he continues to
pour his passion of breeding cannabis
into every variety he releases for you
to grow. Check out the Gnome Automatics
Instagram at
Gnome_automatics to see the impressive
plants folks are growing. You can score
Gnome Automatic seeds in feminized or
regular at your favorite seed provider
listed in the vendor section of their
website. Commercial cannabis farms
across the country love growing Gnome
automatics because of their consistency
from seed to seed, short grow times, THC
percentages, and colorful bag appeal.
Farms interested in bulk seeds of more
than a thousand should reach out through
gnomematics.com. While on the website,
be sure to check out the Gnome
Automatics shirts and other merch
section, too. If you want reliable
seeds, handbuilt from effort, expert
selection and experience, choose Gnome
Automatics. Welcome back. You are
listening to Shaping Fire and I am your
host Shangol Los. And my guest today is
plant biochemist Dr. Paula Berman. So
Dr. Berman, in the first set we talked a
lot about um the heli plant and where it
lives and and how it expresses itself. I
would like to talk a little bit more
generally about canabonoids. We've
certainly done plenty of episodes of
shaping fire on canabonoids for folks
who really want to get into them, but
for for folks that this is their um you
know early uh understanding of
canabonoids, would you explain why
plants produce canabonoids or or why we
think that they produce canabonoids?
H okay. So first of all I would like to
say that h why
are the type of question that is the
hardest to answer in biology. Um and
let's talk a bit about any type of
specialized metabolites. So plants
produce specialized metabolites. So
canabonoids are type of specialized
metabolites. These are small molecules
secondary metabolites unlike primary
metabolites. These are molecules that h
the plant h doesn't have to have them to
survive but it helps them flourish in
their environment. So these are
molecules that the plant produces. They
can be very very different between
plants from different families even from
the same family from different genuses
they can be ex they can have completely
different types of molecules. And the
reason that a plant produces a specific
type of molecule is because um it helps
them um flourish. So for example, it
gives them h protection
um to cope with different types of
stresses like for
um fighting with herbivores or pathogens
that come to try to h damage the plant.
uh they provide protection from abiotic
stresses like uh UV radiation. Uh they
have antioxidant
uh effects um uh and they also attract
different types of pollinators or seed
dispers. So h basically um it is not
known for sure what is the actual role
of canabonoids in the plant. It's
believed that is possibly one of these
that I mentioned now.
Um um but uh for sure it uh the plant
produces cannabonoids. It invests a lot
of energy to produce these cannaboids h
because it gives them some kind of an
evolutionary advantage. That makes
sense. Does does this discovery change
or evolve our understanding of the
evolution of canabonoids? Um I can
imagine that um like while while we were
surprised and excited to find
canabonoids in this plant, there may be
other plants that are also expressing in
similar ways. But but h have us f have
we finding canabonoids in this plant um
you know kind of changed our
understanding of canabonoids.
H so I think it it for sure helps the
trying to answer the reason why h the
plant evolved to produce cannabonoids. H
but we are not there yet. Um we have
several suggestions of how or what might
have
happened or how did the
evolution encourage the plant to or push
the plant h to start producing these
types of molecules. So h the the basis
comes from the from from the enzymes
from the biology of the plant. So a
plant will not start to produce h
molecules um
um that are very very different. it will
not make up an
enzyme. H it's probably a an enzyme that
is already there, a type of protein that
was already in the plant that will
mutate h slowly until it makes some
change that the plant h feels that h is
advantageous and then this is maintained
for next generations. So we believe that
h by looking into other members of the
families from other types of elicomes,
other types of plants from the astro
family because el chrysome is a astro
plant h which is very distant
than cannabis which is an a cannabis
plant. H and by looking into uh other um
family members that don't produce
cannabonoids but when we are looking
into what other chemicals they do
produce h we found some uh
commonalities. So for example um we
think that in order for a plant to
produce can carabonoids h it will start
by having probably a analactivating
enzyme that will use fatty acids h to
produce h this alkal chain that we have
h for canabonoids or that is also found
for fluoroglyucenoids which are also
found in hopes for example we will have
a polyatase that H erh will do
the will probably do a specific type of
of cizization for example uh for making
fluoroglucenoids or chalons which are
more available in nature and this will
possibly mutate into h making the
backbones the chemical structure for the
canabonoids or the a more protein types
of cannabonoids. So um they will start
to do a different type of tilization
which we see in both these plants. And
then we also have a prenal transfer that
we found in our study that was very uh
specific that would work only on the
types of molecules that have this h it's
a resource
backbone which is found in carbonids
versus the one from fluoroglucenoids or
the other types of compounds. So we
think that we have some clues about what
types of plants would also perhaps uh
produce or can be good candidates to
produce cannabonoids. But of course
there are also a lot of questions that
we didn't look
at still that have to do with for
example localization of enzymes
transport
toxicity availability of intermediates
for the uh for this pathway to evolve.
Um
that that is so exciting. You know,
listening to your
answer, there are so many different
opportunities for medical research, for
botanical research, for for healing
opportunities in so many of the
different
um I don't know research opportunities
that you just went through. I mean a as
some as as somebody who has studied the
endockinabonoid system, it's it is just
so wildly exciting to have another way
in to start to compare and contrast to
with the other plants that we've already
that we're already familiar with. And
and this is before you add all the
additional um uh uh other tarpen and
other aromatic compounds that are also
interacting with all these canabonoids
to create new ways. Oh,
fantastic. So, so the plant itself is is
it hard to grow the heli plant or is it
pretty easy?
Um so we started growing it from seeds
and actually it wasn't that easy to
germinate the the seeds.
Um but since once we we managed to
germinate we propagated dur using
cutings h and this h grow very well. H
unfortunately up to this uh point we
haven't uh uh been able to uh produce
seeds out of the plants our m mature
plants. I mean they produce seeds but
they don't germinate. So interesting. Up
until now we've only propagated them via
cutings. Oh that's interesting. So
that's a whole but it it grows very
well. We grow them in a greenhouse
and they flourish. Even though that uh
even though you're not
producing viable seeds yet, is the plant
itself and seeds for it very easy to get
in South Africa or is it a rare plant
there? I think that in South Africa it
it grows wild in
nature. I I don't think that it's very
easy to get h seeds.
Um but uh yeah but the the plant I I
it's it's a plant that grows wild when
you uh from what I understood I've never
been there but when you uh walk around
you can see uh these plants everywhere.
Very good. Um, so in the lab,
um, I'm curious to know what extraction
methods you use to remove the
canabonoids, um, to isolate them. And is
the extraction or uh, isolation process
with this plant any easier or more
difficult than than cannabis, or or is
it about the same because you're just
trying to get canabonoids out of plant
material? So it's it's pretty
straightforward. It's the same as what
we do for cannabis h to extract
canabonoids from
cannabis. So there are many ways that
you can extract this, but what we
usually do in the lab is just a simple
ethanolic extraction.
Mhm. So, um you may not know this next
question because it's it's very cannabis
um user centric, but um are are you
familiar at all with how um traditional
uh cannabis enthusiasts will use ice
water and ice to make the tricoms on a
cannabis plant uh cold and then and then
mix them. So the tricoms break off and
settle into the bottom and then are
concentrated that way to make hashish.
Is that would that be possible with this
plant? Are the tricoms brittle and
removable like that on this plant? So
the tricoms on this plant have although
there are also tricoms but they they're
um they have quite a different uh
structure. They have a much stocker a
shorter stock compared to the ones from
cannabis. And we did try to um purify
tricoms because we were interested in
doing anal analysis of single tricoms
and it was much harder to do than uh in
cannabis. Very good. Thank you. That's
of course we're curious to know can we
make hash out of
it? Do the do the canabonoid levels vary
depending on the growing conditions? I'm
not sure if you've gotten to that part
of the research yet, but uh it's worth
asking. So, we didn't go we didn't get
to that part yet. I'm sure that they
will change just like any other type of
plant that will be affect. So, any type
of specialized metabolites in plants
will change h in response to any type to
to specific types of stress or growing
conditions uh for the good or for the
bad. H um does the plant contain
canabonoids throughout its entire life
cycle or only at certain stages? Uh we
found them in all the
[Music]
stages and in all the tissues besides
the roots as I mentioned and since it's
an all all year round growing plant h
you have them all year round as well.
That's great. So it's not like in
cannabis where you need you start
growing and then you need to wait until
you get the plant h to flower and then
you have a limited amount of time that
the plant is flowering and then after
that you need to have another cycle here
the plant h just grows h all the time
and you can use the biomass. It sounds
It sounds also that since it's um since
the tricoms have got canamonoids in it
year round that it might be possible to
treat this as an ever growing plant too
where where maybe you're growing a a
larger shrub of it and you harvest half
of it and then you let the rest of it go
and then you harvest it again later.
Does that seem reasonable for this
plant? Yes, definitely. Wonderful. Um,
uh, let's see here. Um, so from what
you've seen so far, and I I understand
this research may not have been done
yet, have have you found any potential
benefits that might make it superior to
cannabis for certain canabonoid um,
applications.
Um, so h first of all, the fact that it
has high CBG like we mentioned before
versus other types of cannabonoids. H
also the fact that it has no THC, it's
it makes its legal status uh much
easier. I mean it doesn't it's not
illegal like uh cannabis. Even cannabis
that is high CBD with very low amounts
of THC. H it's still not it's not in the
same uh status as the helipant. H like
we mentioned we have a all year round
supply of cannabonoids h and the leaves
that are the most abundant ones uh so
you don't need to wait for flowering of
course the fact that you have
canabonoids that are not present in
cannabis h it's also another advantage
that might have h different types of h
bioactivities as well as also
non-cannabinoid molecules h in cannabis
you have these h canoflavs for example h
But these are very very much much much
lower concentrations compared
to to cannabonoids. In the helip plant
you have a lot of flavonoids amorphins
and other types of compounds that are
very abundant and in look like similar
concentrations like the canabonoids.
What is the what is the aroma of the
plant itself when you're just in when
you're in the greenhouse? What do you
smell? It's a beautiful aroma. It's like
a very light perfume smell. Nothing like
cannabis. Is it Is it more floral and
pleasant or is it is it more like like
like stanky beautiful? No. No. It's like
a floral. Very floral. Yeah. Like a
perfume. Mhm.
Um uh so when
you when you started publishing your
results and people started um noticing
it um have you gotten um the support
that you would hope to have gotten in
order to continue with this research and
and increase our familiarity with the
plant. It sounds like the the the
reaction to your research itself was
positive. Uh I'm asking this question
more about the going concern like going
into the future like do you have the
support that you need now to continue
this research to get us more familiar
with this plant? Um so um yes I mean we
have no um barriers at the moment h to
continue this uh type of research. Of
course the the biggest barrier is time.
Yeah, because we are
also studying other plants and
other we have other goals that we want
to achieve. But this is s is definitely
something that uh we are planning to
continue. We have some more questions
that we are planning to
answer and we yes we we don't have any
problems continuing working on it.
That's fantastic. So, in set three,
we're going to talk more about uh the
future and and what some of the
strategies of interacting with this
plant look like. But for right now,
we're going to take our second
commercial break. Um you are listening
to Shaping Fire. And my guest today is
plant biochemist Dr. Paula Berman. And
you know, without these advertisers,
Shaping Fire would not be able to
continue. So, please support them and
let them know that you heard of them on
Shaping Fire.
Revenue is tight for cannabis businesses
right now. There is no question about
it. And when revenue tightens,
businesses need to spend smarter on
advertising. Instead of throwing obscene
money at hanging your company's logo
from the rafters at your next
convention, perhaps consider placing
commercials on Shaping Fire. And if you
are a very small business, there is
simply no better bang for your buck than
commercials on shaping fire, especially
if your products are for regeneratively
minded
cultivators. Advertising on this show
allows us time to talk about your
product, service, or brand in a way that
really lets people know what sets your
company apart from the others. Bold
people who own companies know that
getting into relationship with their
customers is essential. That is what we
offer. We will explain your service or
product, what sets it apart as
desirable, and help our audience get in
contact with you. It's pretty simple
really. Advertising does not have to be
all whisbang smoke and mirrors.
Nowadays, I find that people prefer just
to be spoken to calmly, accurately, and
with good intentions. If you want to
make your own commercial spot, you can
do that, too. With a commercial on
Shaping Fire, you'll reach your
customers in the privacy of their
headphones right now and will continue
to reach new listeners as they explore
the Shaping Fire back catalog of
episodes again and again for years. A
spot-on Shaping Fire costs less than a
postcard per person. And the Shaping
Fire audience is full of smart cannabis
enthusiasts, cultivators, and
entrepreneurs who are always curious to
learn. And right now in the new year, we
are booking the few open spots we have
for the rest of 2024. I'd love for you
to be one of our new
advertisers. Do yourself a solid and
contact us today for rates on podcast
and Instagram advertising. Email
hotspotshapingfire.com to find out
more. This message is for folks who grow
cannabis. I'm talking to home growers,
patients, and commercial growers, too.
I'm probably talking to you. When you
plan out your next growing cycle, be
sure to check out
Humbultcsi Seeds at
humbultcsi.com. Caleb Inspecta and his
family have lived in Humbult County for
over 100 years. For the last 40 years,
three generations of his family have
cultivated extraordinary senseia
cannabis in Humbult, Mendescino, and
Trinity counties. Because of his lineage
and the hard-earned experience that
comes from growing up smoking and
sifting large populations of cannabis
plants in Northern California, the seeds
you'll cop from CSI will be winning
genetics based on longtime heavy hitters
and updated and reifted to bring out new
and exotic traits and better yields. Go
ahead and ask around. Caleb, also known
as Inspecta and Pirates of the Emerald
Triangle, is a breeders breeder. He
reaches way back and works with
significant strains, recreating them in
new and interesting ways that you'll
love as a toker and a grower, as well as
offering you some surprises that will
delight serious seed traders and
cultivators. Humboldt CSI goes a further
step and selfs all these kovars so you
know all the seeds will be female. These
are not experimental feminiz seeds.
Humboldt CSI releases some of the best
female seeds available anywhere and it
will show in your garden.
Folks grew quite a bit of CSI Humble Gen
X last year here on Vashon Island, and
everyone was pleased. The patients had
beautiful female plants and didn't have
to callull half of their garden as
males. The folks growing for the fun of
getting high grew colorful flowers with
exceptional bag appeal and great highs.
And breeders had seven out of seven
females in a pack, which gave them a lot
of phenotypic choices. Take a moment
right now and visit humbultcsi.com.
You'll find an up-to-date menu of both
feminized and regular lines along with
photos and descriptions. That's humbult
cssi.com. After you've caught up on the
latest Shaping Fire episodes, do you
sometimes wish there was more cannabis
education available to learn? Well, we
got you. Shaping Fire has a fabulous
YouTube channel with content not found
on the podcast. When I attend
conventions to speak or moderate panels,
I always record them and bring the
content home for you to watch. The
Shangolos YouTube channel has
world-class speakers including Zoe
Sigman's lecture, understanding your
endockinabonoid system. Kevin Jodri of
Wonderland Nursery talking about
breeding cannabis for the best tarpine
profile. Frenchie Canoli's lost art of
the hashishin presentation. Nicholas
Mammud on regenerative and polyulture
cannabis growing. Dr. Sunil Agarwal on
the history of cannabis medicine around
the world. Eric Vloski and Josh
Rutherford on solventless extraction.
And Jeff Loenfelds on the soil food web.
There are several presentations from Dr.
Ethan Russo on tarpen and the
endockinabonoid system too. While there,
be sure to check out the three 10-p part
shaping fire sessions series. One with
Kevin Jodri, one with Dr. Ethan Russo,
and one with Jeff Loenfelds. And even my
own presentations on how to approach
finding your dream job in cannabis, and
why we choose cannabis business even
though the risks are so high. As of
today, there's over 200 videos that you
can check out for free. So go to
youtube.com/shangolos or click on the
link in the
newsletter. Welcome back. You are
listening to ShapingFire. I am your host
Shangolos and my guest today is plant
biochemist Dr. Paula Berman. And um we
we've been talking Dr. Burman and I were
talking during the break about how much
I feel like a you know a cheerleader for
this plant because you know all of us
who have been studying canabonoids and
have been caring about you know
endockinabonoid medicine for years and
and have worked with the plant you know
we've we've all got this very close
relationship with cannabis and and we're
always trying to find the plant and
learn about the plant to find out that
there is another plant that produces
canabonoids in these volumes that is
doesn't have the same legal structures
around it. It it's it just creates it
just feels like this huge opportunity
where we can practice healing in a way
that um might not be
um so inaccessible due to the laws and
and um and and and I
just it's fun to I I I'm probably going
to embarrass you a little bit, Paula,
but you're kind of like a hero to us,
right? like the research that you're
doing is is something that we all are
looking for and you're at at the at the
front of it. So, so uh I know I'm
fanboying about it, but I have a feeling
that you don't get enough of that and so
I'm just I'm just letting my freak flag
fly so so that you understand how much
we appreciate this research that you're
doing.
So, thank you very much. I would just
like to mention that uh this project has
been like a dream project to me. Um I've
I've worked with the cannabis uh for uh
for almost 5 years before I came to the
Wiseman Institute and
um and so cannabis cannab is kind of my
uh true passion. Uh but uh having this
uh uh
so having the opportunity to work on
this uh um uh study that was so uh
preliminary the the information that was
known about it was so preliminary and
everything that we found was new and uh
thinking about how the prospects of
working on this uh topic and what can
come out out of this uh study h is truly
exciting. for us as well. So, thank you
for the support. Absolutely. And and and
I and I don't don't go away listener yet
because we still have more to talk
about, but this seems like a really good
time for me to ask you. You you you have
mentioned a couple times how important
the other people involved have been in
this research and you asked for an
opportunity to acknowledge them. Let's
it seems like it's just fitting to go
ahead and put that in here and then
we'll then we'll continue with our
conversation on pharmaceutical
companies. So, so who are those those
other folks that you wanted to make sure
to acknowledge? So, I just wanted to
mention that I was part of a team. So,
we work with Professor Asafar on his lab
in the Wiseman Institute and he is of
course the the principal investigator of
true inspiration really he's like such
an enthusiast about plant science and uh
uh everything related to small molecules
and biochemistry and I learned so much
from him. I wanted also to acknowledge
uh Luis Adam Prashant three other
postocs uh that also worked on this uh
project. Luis is a
bioinformatician and he did all the
genome and the
transcriptto in this study. Adam Adam
and Prashan that did a lot of the
molecular biology and taught me how to
do a lot of the things that we did here
in this work. H Dong H was also a do
postoc h that helped me with the maldi
imaging and uh feeding of plants. H we
have Tally from the NMR unit and Sadaran
Deal from the electronic microscopic
unit microscope unit in the Wiseman
Institute that helped me um really have
the most amazing uh images of tricoms
and many other people that I will not
mention although they contributed a lot
other people from uh the lab. So thank
you for the opportunity to mention them.
Absolutely. And and thank you to
everyone on your team for this very
important research that you're doing.
All right. So, let's let's continue to
look a little bit more forward. So, so
we're at this interesting time with this
plant where, you know, we're still doing
the fundamental research to figure out
how this plant expresses itself. We also
know that um you know, pharmaceutical
companies are always looking for uh
early stage new drugs. Have we gotten to
the part that pharmaceutical companies
are starting to become engaged with this
research or are we still a little early
yet? Uh so I think for us it's still an
early stage. I mean we have not been
uh doing uh any active uh research on
the with pharmaceutical
companies but I am sure that it will
also come.
What do you think will be the long-term
um uh how do I want to say this? What
extraction method seems to work best on
this plant as far as um moving towards
scaled solutions? You know, for example,
you mentioned in the lab you like to use
ethanol um which is what a lot of uh
home cannabis preparation um preparers
use. Um but when it's scaled up um they
use different um extraction styles uh
for large volumes. Will they be will
they likely be the same extraction um
varieties at at scale as as we see with
cannabis or are there any intricacies in
the plant that would um uh make that not
as uh elegant? Uh no I I believe that
the same types of extraction methods
that apply to cannabis h will also be
applied here. H in the past uh we also
used to do a lot of uh ethanol
extraction in in when we were studying
cannabis ethanol extractions h also when
we were scaling up I know that uh at
least here in Israel it's considered
like uh the standard method to make
extracts h and it works pretty well with
uh also with helip especially because h
when it's intended for patients you
don't want to use organic uh salt vents
or other methods that might be
hazardous to to patients. Yeah. Um is
your team working on uh breeding
programs at all to increase the
canabonoid production or are are we at
the point where we're just trying to
figure out how that's taking place to
begin with? So we in the wisman
institute don't work on h breeding. uh
we we are trying to do some uh um
genetic engineering transformation uh
for the heli
plant but uh we have not succeeded yet
but it's definitely one of the things
that we want to do to have the potential
to um be able to uh knock out genes or
to add genes for example imagine the the
possibility of adding a CB CDA synthes
into the heli uh plant that will allow
you to make CBDA in the in the plant. We
are talking about basically it's one
gene that will take CBGA to produce
CBDA. H of course there there might be
also some other uh uh genes or some uh
other proteins that are involved but to
have this ability is h of course with
very high potential and very interesting
h overall also to have the ability to
knock out genes to even for hel even for
us to study what's the role of
cannabonoids. So you asked me before h
what is the role of cannabonoids to the
plant. So one of the best ways that one
would be able to test this is um if you
have the ability if you have a a system
to do transformation of a plant h to
knock out specific genes and then you
will have your mutant and you will have
a the wild type plant. Um and then you
can take both and and test them with
different types of stresses with uh to
see interaction with uh pollinators uh
uh interaction with bacteria and so on.
It will help you answer these type of
questions. H another thing is another
thing that we study in the lab a lot is
the by synthetic pathway. So one of the
aims of this study h besides the
chemistry and uh all the work that we
did was also to identify the
biosynthetic pathway how the plant
produces car cannaboids and once we
found the specific enzymes then we have
the ability we show how we can trans
um take these um enzymes outside of the
plant and express them in hetrology
system. So being either other plants or
in bacteria or in yeast and then to have
a production of cannabonoids h without
having the limitations of the plant or
even to test this
h question h if you take for example a
just as a a tomato or you take a a
tobacco or some other model plant that
people use biologist plant scientists
use h that you know how to transform.
And then you take the whole pathway of
canabonoids and you put it inside these
plants. And then again you have the
tomato, the white type tomato and you
have the mutant tomato and you can use
these systems to try to understand um
what these canabonoids do to the plant
whether it helps them survive in which
conditions h cope with which stresses
and so on. there. You you describe so
much different research all taking place
on the plant at the same time. How many
people do you have working on in in the
lab on on these projects? I mean, it
sounds like a huge number of people. So,
so this specific project um brought
together several
um different people and not all of them
working full-time only on this. several
helped according to their um h
specialty. Um yeah, but this is one
advantage of working in this lab. The
fact that you have such a
multid-disiplinary team of analytical
chemists and then molecular biologists
and bioinformaticians
and it again it's a really it's a big
blessing and the type of lab where you
can do this type of work where you can
ask these questions and having all the
tools that you need to to answer them.
Sure. Can you can you just let us know
is it more or less than 50 people? No,
it's less than 50 people. So this is
this is a this is a lot of passionate
people cross crossworking on each
other's projects so that so that um uh
every everyone's project is lifted up at
the same time. I like this there there
must be a lot of excitement um moving
around the different cells of of the lab
for yourself. What what are we um likely
to see as the next published research
coming out of your lab?
Oh, so first of all we do in the lab a
lot of things also not related to
cannabonoids. Actually this was the only
sorry not true we are also working on
cannabis and we have a study that will
be published I hope in the coming months
h which I cannot uh too early say too
much about it yes because I don't want
to scoop us but h we are having some
really cool uh results also on this
other cannabis project but most of the
other people in the lab don't work on
cannabis We have a lot of um researchers
on very different types of we ask
different types of questions questions
related to uh plant science. H me
specifically h in the lab in the last
years I've been working on um
psychoactive plants. So last year we
also published a a paper on the
biosynthetic pathway of measculine in
pot in alucogenic cacti h where we
elucidated the bio synthetic pathway and
I am working on another pathway that
hopefully will be published in the
coming months h which is also not
carbonid
but
psychedelic chemistry. I I which is
really cool. I enjoyed reading that
research last night actually. I uh in in
in preparating preparing for our other
aspects, I I stumbled ac across the
peyote paper and I'm like, my gosh, Dr.
Burman is doing the most interesting
research.
Thank you. Uh so um so uh I've got two
two questions for you kind of is is in
moving us to wrapping up. So, so we
understand that
um the the genie is out of the bottle,
if you will, as faring as far as this
plant goes. We we know the canabonoids
are there. We know that they there are a
lot of them and that the plant is easier
to use because of the of the legal
reasons. Uh I'm curious though because
we're still in the early stages when
we're we're trying to find the basics
about the plant. What do you foresee say
10 years down the line being the status
of this plant? You're see you see faster
than anybody how quickly this research
is taking place and the areas that are
more likely to blossom to allow the pun.
Um where where do you see our
relationship with this plant in 10
years?
So I I can tell you what I would like to
see. Sure, let's do that. I would really
like to see
um a lot more
research done on the bioactivities of
the molecules that the plant produces. H
I would really like to see that there is
a transformation platform to do
transformation of the plants. uh to be
able to answer all these really amazing
interesting questions that I mentioned
before and to have basically to have a
a new uh even new types of molecules
that we can produce and to learn much
more about the
plant and to have available products
from the plant or inspired by the
molecules in in the helicry plant. So
even if it's not from hel once we learn
about the bioactivities of these
molecules. So to have h the opportunity
of having h having them produce even
outside of the plant h in other
platforms or other h systems and
hopefully that they will help also um
patients or people that uh h that need
it. Excellent. So when we do research
shows, I try to end with this question
because I always want to encourage
uh young new scienceminded
uh folks who are in college or just out
to inspire them that there is still so
much research to be done uh in
canabonoids that that this this area is
just starting to blossom and it's a
great time to get into this research.
What kind of an advice would you give of
the types of things to perhaps study and
to uh bone up on for for canabonoid
researchers who are still in college and
but but would like to start moving into
researching with this plant? What kinds
of backgrounds and preparations should
they be making? Um first of all I would
tell them to go for it to go for
studying cannabis cannabinoids h I think
that h it's a it's a platform that can
combine so many different uh disciplines
uh starting from uh plant science
chemistry uh
biology of course uh medicine
pharmacology uh there are so many
questions that can be answered and there
there is such a big huge potential to
help other people uh by combining these
disciplines. So I I would even advise
people not to stick to only one part of
the research but to actually combine. So
look into the plant, see how the plant
does what it does and then try to go
outside of the plant h and also to test
h to understand what it does uh to
humans or we can uh uh push uh or use
the plant uh for new uh drugs or new
treatments or new medications. H and I
would also would would suggest to that
it's important to keep in mind that uh
this is still in the in the scientific
com community it's still considered a
bit of a controversial subject. So
people that go into studying canabonoids
need to be aware that
h sometimes we find people researchers
that work in this h field uh that that
it has kind of a bad reputation and it
it's sometimes hard to raise money for
grants or convince researchers that what
you're doing is serious research and
that uh also when you want to submit or
to publish there are sometimes
journals that don't look into cannabis
or canaboninoid
research h the the best way. So just to
be patient and
um the potential is huge. H so good
luck. Very good. Well, thank you Dr.
Burman. you know, um, we really
appreciate when a scientist like
yourself who is in deeply and on the
front lines and and not usually
available to, you know, just regular
folks like us. um that you make the time
to, you know, come out of the lab and
into the daylight and talk to us so that
we can um you know, encourage you and to
and learn what you're doing and to
encourage, you know, uh uh those who um
to who fund your research to fund more
of it. So, so thank you for sharing your
time and your insight and your good
cheer uh with us so that we could um
learn more about this absolutely
beautiful plant. Thank you so much.
Thank you for uh the questions. Thank
you for the encouragement and
uh it's been a pleasure. Excellent. So,
dear listener, if you would like to uh
uh keep up with Dr. Burman, there are uh
two ways to do that. Um you can follow
her on uh
LinkedIn and um I believe that is as uh
Paula Berman. And then um if you have um
a
sciencespecific question you can reach
Dr. Burman through her email address for
the lab which is
bur. So
bangmail.com very simple like that. You
can find more episodes of the Shaping
Fire podcast and subscribe to the show
at shapingfire.com and wherever you get
your podcasts. If you enjoyed the show,
we'd really appreciate it if you would
leave a positive review of the podcast
wherever you download. Your review will
help others find the show so they can
enjoy it, too. On the Shaping Fire
website, you can also subscribe to the
newsletter for insights into the latest
cannabis news, exclusive videos, and
giveaways. On the Shaping Fire website,
you'll also find transcripts of today's
podcast as well. Be sure to follow on
Instagram for all original content not
found on the podcast. That's
@shapingfire and shangolos on Instagram.
Be sure to check out the ShapingFire
YouTube channel for exclusive
interviews, farm tours, and cannabis
lectures. Does your company want to
reach our national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts? Email
hotspot@shapingfire.com to find out how.
Thanks for listening to ShapingFire.
I've been your host, Shangol Los.
[Music]