[Music]
working in any part of the cannabis
industry is arduous no matter your role
you're gonna be working hard because
every single cannabis company is a
start-up this applies especially to
cannabis breeders quality breeding of
stable cannabis cultivars is a huge
amount of work it doesn't take much to
simply introduce a female plant to a
male plan and make seeds but a serious
breeder has a wealth of experience in
cannabis bonnie terpenes the weather
grower needs customer expectations and
marketing they also have to put in long
hours and many seasons to sift through
seeds to find the best Fino possible and
the damn thing is they are the ones
easiest to rip off because cannabis
genetics is a wild place with
insufficient regulation nearly no case
law and at its most basic it is
incredibly easy to pop a seed of someone
else's life work cross it with some bag
seed your already own and boom you have
something to market you know some folks
don't even bother making that cross some
folks just make seed of someone else's
strain rename it and sell it right
through as if it's their own and this is
the shady stuff that happens before you
even get into corporate cannabis big AG
and everyone's attorneys get involved
cannabis genetics is like its own high
drama TV series that's gonna play itself
out brutally over the next 15 years
until some best practices get
established if you want to learn about
cannabis health business and technique
efficiently and with good cheer I
encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter every week you'll receive a
new podcast episode delivered right to
your inbox along with commentary on a
couple of the most important news items
from the week and videos too don't rely
on social media to let you know when a
new episode is published sign up for the
updates and make sure you don't miss an
episode you are listening to shaping
fire and I'm your host
Shango 'lose my guest this week is
Reggie Godinho Reggie Godinho is chief
science officer at steep hill labs
Reggie's a rare one in that he has
expertise in science law argumentation
and cannabis all at the same time he is
a published genetic researcher with 18
years of intellectual property
experience in writing prosecuting and
managing patents and patent portfolios
in fields as diverse as software and
telecom - biotechnology and molecular
genetics
regi received his BS and molecular
biology and PhD in molecular genetics
from the State University of New York at
Buffalo and he conducted four years of
postdoc research at the Washington
University in st. Louis
studying transcriptional regulation of
ribosomal RNA today we're going to be
talking about cannabis patents and other
intellectual property
welcome to the show Reggie thanks Jango
thanks for having me here again you're
taking a big chance of having me back so
I think well one of the reasons I like
having you on this show Reggie's because
you're a firebrand and I know you're
gonna tell me the truth regardless of
its political implications so I'm glad
that you are willing to come back and
and talk some truth so you know I want
to start off very at the top with
patents because the number one question
or concern that I get from growers
cannabis enthusiasts and breeders all
over the country is that how can people
be patenting cannabis when you can't
patent nature and they say it's just
impossible our cannabis is safe and yet
you know there's a lot of smart people
who are saying that there are things to
be concerned about so let's start there
what's actually happening that's
allowing people to patent plants so it's
it's a little confusing right so so it's
not that you can't plant patent plants
you can't patent a naturally-occurring
plant that you just find in nature okay
however cannabis has stopped being a
naturally-occurring plant that you just
find in nature since we stopped just
growing landraces right so as soon as we
started breeding and specifically
selecting for higher THC contents
something happened right which is known
and patent speak as but for the hand of
man right so so what ends up happening
is that you can take a naturally
occurring plant and then you do some
selective breeding and you push it in a
direction that didn't occur naturally
and now it's not a naturally occurring
plant anymore it's actually a plant that
has been read specifically and once you
get to that point it's no longer a
naturally occurring plant it may be
based on that unnhhh Eicher but but you
know what you find in nature and what
you create by a directed breeding
program are not the same so that that's
the difference
so where's the threshold on that because
you know what was the first time someone
took an Effie plant an Afghani plant and
crossed it with a Thai plant and we got
a feet I was that first cross of two
landraces
technically patentable because it didn't
happen in nature or is there a threshold
to how much you need to change the land
races before it is passed and patentable
so there is no well-defined threshold
typically you know if you were to take a
bunch of land races that let's say
existed on you know you have two
different land races that say ones in
Texas and so it's technically a u.s.
land race and ones in Mexico a couple
hundred miles away and it's technically
a Mexican land race and they can
pollinate each other and if you were to
go into that field where let's say some
Texas pollen landed in a Mexican field
and you were to find one plant that
looked different from all of those
plants in that field you would be able
to take that plant and patent it because
it's not the same as what was growing
naturally around it so the short answer
to your question is yes
that very first cross would have been a
patentable cross and the only reason why
nobody has patented cannabis going back
is because not because it's been illegal
but because the patent off has hid
behind the fact that it was an an
illegal planet and an illegal activity
to do anything with it and so therefore
they were like oh well if nobody's going
to ask we're just not going to say right
so but as soon as anybody called the
Patent Office and asked the question can
you patent cannabis the answer was yes
right so so now we get to the question
that you're asking which is you know so
where does it stop being a naturally
occurring let you know plant it stops
being a naturally occurring plant when
you can find one difference in a field
of everything else being the same so and
that it's weird that it occurs that way
but in the patent law especially for
plant patents if you were to go through
a field and found like a thousand of a
certain strain and there's only one of
some other strain that would technically
be patentable because it's it's it's
novel from all the other ones that occur
by nature right so it's kind of a gray
area or it's kind of a ill-defined area
but yes anything that would not
naturally occur by you know in nature
would technically be patentable so
taking a ruderalis or taking a an Afghan
tie and mating it with a Southeast Asian
because those things would probably not
happen because of the geographical
distance yes that is a patentable to
cross that threshold sounds awfully low
man I got to tell you and and I'm gonna
ask you to kind of flip positions
because I know that you are a you know
you are a keep the the cannabis plant
free person and you want that IP to stay
in the hands of development but I'm
going to ask you for a second to
advocate the the opposing position so so
the people you don't as a longtime
cannabis guy and you know advocate I
don't like the idea of patenting
happening and yet I know good people who
are moving in that direction so will you
just explain what the what the argument
is from the patent makers side on why
they believe that patenting these
genetics are good for the industry and
then and then after you make that case
well we'll take it apart okay okay so
let's start from the perspective of the
the investment that's required to create
new strains right so think about it you
have to take you know you get to find a
suitable germ plasm and if you in if
it's not in your own germ plasm right
you have to go buy it or license it from
somebody it's going to be a cost
associated with that you have to grow it
up then you have to take and find a good
strong male or okay let's just say so
you have to find a good strong female on
a good strong male okay and and and
whether or and there's a cost associated
with finding those right then you have
to do the cross and as we know right the
reason why the cannabis industry is is
essentially promulgated on the whole
idea of clones is because getting a
phenotype and then and then breeding so
that phenotype is pure is a very
difficult thing and it almost never
happens in cannabis right right so so
in order to get to that point where you
can have let's say something that is
patentable in a way that you that really
make sense the patent right so and what
do I mean by that so a utility patent
gives you the strength of being able to
patent everything associated with that
plant from the seed to extracts to
edibles anything associated with that
strain if it has if it represents that
that chemical profile or whatever the
claims work for that particular strain
is covered and everything that's derived
from that plant a plant patent doesn't
give you that a plant patent only gives
you that thing right it gives you that
what I say it gives you that you know
one claim and it's for the plant as
shown as described you can't get any
chemical information into it you can't
get any of these other things and
because of that you can't protect the
seed you can't protect the extracts you
can't protect any of that thing you all
you get is the vegetative plant right so
so if you are interested in preserving
the entire product line around a
particular new strain you have to go
after utility so what does that mean
that means that you have to have more
than just plant that ax you have to have
some chemical analyte data you have to
be able to describe why it's novel so
now you can see that there's a whole
bunch of investigation that goes into
this and a whole bunch of money that
goes behind that if you take an example
of Monsanto which is you know obviously
we all consider that the the Dark Lord
evil empire but but but the reality is
is that you know they are have a very
same business plan they spend a billion
dollars a year in plant research in
order to be able to protect that
investment in research you have to have
some assurance that you're going to be
able to have the right to be the only
one to sell that product because you
spent all the money to make it right so
when you look at it from that point of
view it's not necessarily an evil thing
right and they're not going out there
and patenting corn right they're
patenting corn that they have put a lot
of time and effort and resources into
making
very special right unique different from
everybody else's the same thing applies
in cannabis right so here we are we have
a bunch of guys who are trying to go and
build a better turf but better
cannabinoid but this that the other
thing well that requires a lot of time
and energy phenotype hunting breeding
right so if you want to protect the
whole entire thing you have to get the
plant to the point where you can have
the information and the genetics in the
chemistry to be able to pack those
things and protect them right and you
know they're the only way to do that
after you've put all that money and time
into it is through a patent right so and
and and I know it sounds like a horrible
thing because you know we want the plant
to remain free right but if I'm given a
choice between do I want the plant to
remain open source and free or do I want
the people who spent all their time and
energy building this industry having a
future revenue stream when the likes of
the Dow and Monsanto's come to town and
can do everything for free because it's
all open source I'd rather have our guys
patent it and have a future right so so
yes you know it depending on how you
look at it it could be a bad thing but
it's also the way businesses play it's
the way agricultural you know industries
have been built and for us to think that
in the patent industry we're not going
to have to play by those rules is I
think foolish on our cards right so all
right so so let me go let me do a quick
summary here so so essentially a like
like most agriculture the the reason the
patent people are who are coming in want
to patent their novel versions of
strains is because they put a hell of a
lot of money doing huge sorts for
genetics and using all this technology
assisted not necessarily GMO but just
like laboratory testing try to to bring
these novel strains that are like listen
we've put you know six figures into
developing this we need to be able to
recoup so that we can pay off our
investors and so they want to patent it
so that they can preserve some value so
but but then you know
kind of shifted a little bit so it's not
necessarily for when I getting from you
the patents that are bad it's actually
who's gonna hold them because it sounds
to me like you're also saying that
patenting by the Heritage farmers to
keep it open source is actually probably
a good thing the question is who is
making the patents the the green rushers
who are coming to take advantage of
these you know 40 years of hybridization
in my is am i picking up what you're
putting down yeah absolutely yeah i
think you know we need to touch base on
a few other you know pieces that you
know make it the more the the more
directed argument and that more directed
argument is is that you know what's out
there right now and this is you know
patents peak right so there's a one-year
bar right so once something is offered
for sale commercial sale and it doesn't
even have to actually be sold right if
there's a contract offering for sale
that's made public and that contract is
then not signed but the contract but the
offer was made in a public way right
that's it the clock starts ticking so if
that is not filed within one year in the
united states you can't file it it
becomes open source right further if you
have any expectations to be able to
patent that strain anywhere else in the
world you can't even do that as soon as
you offer for sale you lose the right to
file anywhere else in the world other
than the united states the united sates
the only one that has that one year
window right so so when you look at it
from that perspective right so what
should be happening is is that these
people who have all this open source
stuff should be trying to develop their
next next greatest thing and then that's
where you start putting your fences in
the ground right because anything that's
already been sold is available for
everyone right
that means monsanto and I said it's the
last time we talked right yeah
Monsanto Dow those guys can go to the
dispensaries and just buy one of
everything often to dispensary shelves
and they don't have to pay it
thing because it's open source it's been
sold they can't protect it all they have
to do is go pay that $15 or $20 for
that's that cut off of the dispensary
shelf they can take that back to
Monsanto and do all their stuff with it
do all their breeding with everything
else that they buy from every other
dispensary right so how do you avoid
that becoming the paradigm you avoid
that becoming the paradigm by those same
people who have developed these 40 years
of hybridization now they do it the way
everyone else do it does it their next
set of crosses they do it in a way that
they can track it they can document it
and then they get some chemical data and
maybe some genetic data under their belt
and file before they release it changes
the way we do business in the cannabis
industry right but it's the way that we
help litter the ground with patents that
are held by the people inside the
industry to keep the green rushers from
coming in and taking everything away so
it sounds like the way that you know
people continue to look back like oh I
made these strains that I'm in love with
over the last 10 or 20 years that that
looking back and trying to preserve
those is not the successful path forward
what is the successful path forward is
to look into the future and either
create new crosses that are based on
your old-school genetics or just move
forward with new genetics but the idea
is to what what you know what have you
done for me lately you know what what
are you doing that's new and novel and
that's where breeders should be putting
their attention yes however I wanna I
want to say in order to make this really
a rock-solid kind of industry for us
those same people who are going to be
working on the new genetics and working
off of their own their old strains so
this is where kind of somebody has to
absorb the cost right and this is gonna
sound horrible
but a lot of this is only partially
successful unless somebody anybody
everybody okay chips in and we can
identify the genetics that are already
exist and tried
put a name on them or a sequence to them
or something so that we can say look
this is the database that we started
with so anything that exists in this
database Monsanto or Dow or whatever
they can't just come in and say oh look
this is a new strain that we made
ourselves because we'll have the
information that says ah sorry that
existed already right so so it's a
two-fold approach cataloging what exists
so that we know where we started and
then moving forward in a way that allows
us to protect the new stuff and do it in
a way that allows us to get there before
the likes of the big AG people come
that's how we protect you know the
industry from the patent perspective and
keep it kind of you know within the
industry right because if we don't do
that and I know it sounds gloom and doom
right and I say the same thing last time
it sounds gloom and doom but without
this you know it really becomes a
free-for-all
right and we don't need a free-for-all
what we want is to be able to protect
what we've built and then have a stake
in this industry as it grows and moves
forward right if if it's a free-for-all
I can guarantee the likes of Monsanto
and Dow and all instant jente and all
those people who'd like to come in they
do it better faster and more accurately
than we do it's it's if that's what they
do right so for so we have to protect it
because we know what will happen when
they come right so time to take get the
head out of the sand
and and play this game like any big
business would play this game
that sounds so expensive to to you know
determine the code of the genome of each
strain that everybody has developed that
they want to preserve I mean how much
how much does it cost to do that kind of
analysis per strain nowadays well so
there are different levels of genetic
analysis and and you can some of it is
targeted sequencing some of it is is
short read you know whole genome some of
this long stuff right well so that's a
great question because I'm going to give
you the the here's where the other shoe
drops all right what I'm talking about
is what I would call responsible
patenting in the cannabis industry we
haven't had to do this in any other
agricultural industry and the reason is
is that because there's no other plant
on the planet that is as complex and has
as many active compounds as cannabis
right so normally when you you take like
say let's say corn and you you know you
don't emit junky GMO but you do directed
breeding to increase the sugar content
or to make it you know so it has you
know when you pop it it has bigger
kernels or whatever some of those things
can be achieved by just you know
directed breeding programs right so but
but in at the end of the day you're
changing one component or you're you're
looking at one component you know you're
change looking have a change in the
sugar content or a change in the size of
the kernel right but now we are faced
with a cut with a plant that has 500
active compounds and we are only looking
at a couple CBD THC right maybe you know
right so so when you have 500 active
compounds and you're only looking at 2
or 3 compounds how do you get any
granularity in five or six or seven
hundred or a thousand strains right
because at the end of the day if you
don't look at it enough compounds they
all overlap which is exactly what we see
right now in the patent record of those
strains that have already been you know
filed on and and issued right so they
all have kind of because they're only
looking at a couple things they kind of
overlap right so you know so what has to
happen is and then actually it's funny
that we're having this conversation
because on Friday this week I'm actually
talking in front of the American
intellectual property lawyers
Association exactly on the pitfalls to
successful patenting in cannabis right
so and one of the points that I make is
that you know when you can take a strain
you take you know the same genetics and
you grow it in five different places
with your five different conditions you
get five different you know answers that
that tells you that you need to go
deeper than just you know what does the
genetics
look like because now because of the the
paradigm or the you know the only
equation that really that biologists
ever use is genotype plus environment
equals phenotype right so right so
that's that's the basic you know biology
math for us because I always think about
it as nature versus nurture right you've
got it exactly yeah yeah right so it's
exactly it so so now but the problem is
is that so we already know that even the
genetics cannot define a specific
chemical analyte output I have data on
it like I have the same genetics grown
in four different places
gave me four different responses right
so that means that responsible patenting
so that you can protect a strain and a
particular set of genetics and a
particular chemical outcome that means
you have to include in that claim the
way you grew it because if you don't
grow it that way it comes out with a
different output right so so now we're
looking at a plant that is unique unto
itself in terms of how you have to go
about patenting it and this is where we
are in the dark ages right now because
patent examiner's and the Patent Office
don't understand cannabis they don't see
these problems because they've never had
to deal with these problems because no
other commercial agricultural plant has
been the same right it's been let's
change this thing let's change that
thing and we'll get a patent on it right
now we're not really trying to change
things or we kind of are trying to
change things but we don't know where we
started and we don't have it defined
endpoint because any given genetics can
do any different thing depending on how
you grow it right so so the only way to
get successful and you know
forward-looking patents that allow us to
have people going after specific strains
that do specific things is to have a
level of detail that has never been
asked for in plant patents which is so
so that's what we're looking at trying
to force a change on the patent office
and why I'm going to go speak to the AI
pla on fridays because you know this is
this is a huge thing that people in the
patent office who are issuing these
hands don't understand they they clearly
don't understand
they also not understand that when we
call something a strain we have not done
the stable the stabilization that is
almost always part of the process these
are ethnic exactly right so so so we're
trying to put cannabis into plant
patents and utility plant patents you
know that have been crafted around a
certain paradigm and cannabis does not
fit at all right so so we have we we got
a lot of work to do and and it would be
very good if the people on the cannabis
side understood and helped educate by
going the extra mile providing the data
to the Patent Office that I'm talking
about so that it's already there right
and it helps create the way things have
to be done because otherwise we're going
to end up with the kind of patents we
already have have you know issued that
came out of the biotech institute LLC
right so and I know that's another topic
so I don't want to jump into our next
topic but you know but a direct result
you know of not understanding how to do
this correctly is what we see with those
paths that were already issued right on
so we're gonna talk about biotech
Institute after the break but before we
go to the first break I just want to get
a number out of you because I know that
there's people who are listening who see
themselves as wanting to protect the
genetics that they've worked hard on of
now and going forward and you're
referring to the the kind and amount of
data that you want to be able to send to
the Patent Office what is the price tag
to get that research done for one
cultivar so for one cultivar and you
know and again I said there's different
levels of analysis and that's a ballpark
figure yeah yeah so anywhere between I'd
say 500 to 5,000 dollars right and and
and let me let me say why it's so wide
depending on the type of strain you're
dealing with you may be able to do
something which is called target
sequencing because you oh no why it's
different and you just have to look
there and say look all these other
strains have this this strain has this
this is why it's different okay
when you do however a regular let's take
what which is what most of the cannabis
injury does let's take that female on
this male and or maybe that female in
three or four males and throw them into
a room together and see what we get
right so now you're looking at a
situation where in order to get the
information you have to go much deeper
you have the sequence much deeper the
deeper the level of sequencing the more
it costs okay and then you add to that
whether or not you're doing it for
private commercial use or for public
domain use right so a lot of at least in
the programs that we offer it's depo we
have a commercial price and in a
research price so we've been able to
secure through our partner that if the
data that we generate is donated to the
public domain so that we can use it in a
publication after you file the patent
right so so you you know we let you do
what you're going to do first and we use
it and accumulated data and then we
publish publish it later after it's not
an issue for you right we can offer a
much cheaper price because it goes into
the research domain right and so that's
typically half price that gets you in
between 1,500 and 2,000 dollars for a
whole genome sequencing of a long read
right 5,000 would be the single the
single cultivar price where you keep it
for yourself and nobody else has it but
you and your patents right so so that's
the prices that I've been given to work
with through the university that I
partner with right so but that's for
long read you don't always need long
read if you are using strains that are
already decently characterized and now
you just need to find in a couple of
regions where the differences might lie
because you've taken strain and strain
but you put them together and you want
to see what unique parts of a and B they
got together you can do short read
sequencing which is comes in at you know
around 800 to a thousand and then
there's targeted sequencing which is
good just looks at specific genes and
comes in around 300 to 500 right so so
that's why there's that wide range but
it's based on what you need and and what
you're trying to get
so right on that's fantastic analysis
I'm gonna be parroting those words from
you a lot over the next six months I can
be assure you of that
so we're gonna take our first short
break and be right back you're listening
to shaping fire and my guest today is
Reggie Godinho chief science officer and
director of genetics and intellectual
property at steep hill
now that the health benefits of terpenes
have become well-known in the cannabis
industry people everywhere are looking
for the purest terpenes without
adulterants the problem with most
terpene providers is that they're not
sourced naturally and instead are made
as a byproduct of refining petroleum and
that's so sketchy the terpenes sold by
true terpenes are entirely different
they are certified organic non-gmo and
food grade that means they are extracted
from real plant sources there are no
solvents of any kind used during the
extraction process they are distilled
only with steam that's right only steam
in fact terpenes from true terpenes are
so pure that you can eat them not only
that but you can stack them with better
results - what I mean is
other companies terpenes have got a few
percent of impurities and when you stack
those terpenes to make a blend you're
adding a variety of impurities that
degrade your final product true terpenes
also has strain-specific terpenes for a
wide range of cannabis strains like
Durbin poison sunset sherbet and
granddaddy purple true terpenes has
robust and supportive customer service
so your questions will get answered fast
and efficiently if you shop for turps
before you know how rare that is so
whether you want to cup your hands to
smell some beta-carotene to calm down
after getting too high or if you want to
dab some alpha pining so your lungs feel
fabulous and your mind feels liberated
true terpenes will provide you with a
truly natural experience if you are a
cannabis product developer these are the
trips you want to add to your oil or
edible or a capsule or whatever true
terpenes are simply the best your money
can buy don't try and make a premium
product with substandard terms choose
true terpenes for a top-shelf experience
go to shaping feiyr.com forward slash
true tour peens to find out more or
click on the link in this week's
newsletter as a listener of shaping fire
you all
ready understand the importance of
living soil when growing cannabis when
you have active microbe communities in
your substrate you go way beyond simply
fertilizing with nitrogen phosphorus and
potassium having active microorganisms
in your substrate supports vigorous
plant growth throughout the plant's root
zone making for higher yields and
thriving flowers mammoth pea is the
first organically derived microbial
inoculant that focuses on your plants
nutrient cycling processes to release
soil phosphorus and other micronutrients
from they're bound forms making them
more available to the plant increased
levels of phosphorus will also keep
inner nodes shorter and focus your
plants energy on bud production not only
that but the microbes act as a defense
shield for the plants rhizosphere
by out competing potentially harmful
pathogenic microbes pretty cool right
mammoth pee not only unlocks the
nutrients in your soil but it also helps
protect your plant from disease mammoth
Peas beneficial bacteria act like
microbial reactors continually producing
enzymes that release nutrients mammoth
pee was developed at a u.s. University
has been extensively tested by Colorado
growers and independent laboratories
mammoth pee is proven to increase growth
and enhance blooming one of the great
things about supplementing with
microorganisms is that they won't
compete with whatever fertilizer program
you're already running simply dose on
top of your fertilizer schedule for
increased benefits to learn more and to
find out where you can buy mammoth pee
near you check out their website at
www.opm.gov/tribalprograms
but let's let's really hit that hard and
then the first time I heard you talk
about this was in that article that came
out last fall in September of 2017 in GQ
magazine titled the great pot monopoly
mystery written by a man to Chicago
Louis and it blew everybody away and you
know you and I had talked about patents
generally earlier on on the podcast but
suddenly this article that kind of went
down a rabbit hole of he-said she-said
about patents that were starting to
place take place freaked out everybody
but nearly nobody had any actual
information so it was all like rumor
mill and gossip upon gossip and I hate
that stuff but but in that GQ article
you an email that you wrote is mentioned
that you wrote to some of the other
heavy players in the industry waving
your hand and raising a red flag to
these new patents that you saw coming
out and why this needed to be addressed
immediately to keep an open market so
will you take us back to that time and
explain what was in the email and why
you felt so motivated to get the word
out yeah so okay so I have besides being
you know a scientist the reason women
actually vote in directive intellectual
property is because for the last 22
years that's what I have done right in
the biotech sector written and/or
managed portfolios and before I came to
steep hill I was the senior patent agent
at sequin home right so and so you know
the first thing I did when I came to the
industry was like okay you know let's
see with a patent landscape looks like
because I'm about to embark on some
research as the director of genetics and
I don't want to know what's out there
what I'm up against right what pitfalls
to avoid so you know I did what any
decent patent practitioner would do and
you do you know your your patent arena
searches patentability searches you know
what just general landscaping to see
what the industry looks like and in that
initial analysis I found you know at the
time it was only three applications that
had been submitted by the
tech Institute LLC you know and my you
know and was interesting because they
were they were hidden patents right so
it was you know a method pet under
breeding and I forget the title and we
can look it up afterwards but you know
but it was essentially it was breeding
cultivation so on and so forth you know
forward you know Pat you know for
cannabis right when I went through the
claims and this is this is a a protip
okay so don't ever pay attention to what
the title of a patent says because
they're purposely written to be vague
and and misleading okay so you can't
ever tell what's gonna be in a patent
from looking at the title you have to
look at the claim structure right so
when I did my my search I actually was
looking for things that had cannabis or
marijuana in the claims and then I
filtered it down from there and and in
that filtering process I found these
three patent applications and when I
looked at the claims my jaw hit the
floor because the first one I looked at
was a hybrid cannabis plant having a BT
/ BD phenotype what does that mean right
so there was a few other things attached
to it but B TBD just means that it can
make both you know it's the genetic you
know nomenclature that we use for
specific genotype / phenotypes in
cannabis so bt is THC dominant BD is CBD
dominant b TBD mean it's a heterozygous
means that it can make both THC and CBD
so that claim structure the way it was
written was basically claiming anything
that could make THC and CBD well holy
crap that's like it that's the entire
medicinal cannabis industry right right
so so that was a bit on the alarming
side and and so I I you know looked at
them I talked to some other people in
the industry and and and none of them
think knew that they were existent right
so
like literally everybody talked to had
no clue they were there right and as I
said they were still application at the
time that had not been issued so while
they were still applications I started
to contact people like Steve DeAngelo
and some other people and I think what
really happened in the very beginning
was is that you know we were so
concerned about rescheduling that people
weren't really paying attention to this
even though I was making I was talking
to some people about it it was in the
height of the whole rescheduling thing
right so like two years ago and so
people just didn't understand or just
didn't care and because of that nothing
was done and then the first patent
issued and that was the one where there
was the B team so BD phenotype that and
and the limitations were where it had to
have at least three percent THC a or THC
and at least three percent CBD and at
least one percent terpenes right well
I'm sorry but if you're a cannabis
grower and you can't hit three percent
THC and three percent CBD or one percent
terpenes you shouldn't be a cannabis
grower right like like honestly right so
so the limitations ended up not being
limitations right and so this is where
I'm going with this whole thing right so
because the patents themselves were
actually written quite well they look
just like any other good plant utility
patent which means that it was done by a
reputable firm with a good patent lawyer
right if I had written these claims
myself or these patents myself I would
have done it exactly the same way so the
paths are well written and therefore
that means that the claims that were
issued are bonafide claims that will be
hard to challenge right so so that's
part number one it's a it's a well
written patent and if I had done it I
would have done it the same way right so
now how did they get over on the patent
office they got over on the patent
office because it looks like a patent a
good plant patent it has limitations
that if you don't know the industry look
like limitation so when you say 1%
terpenes where beta mercy and is not the
dominant terpene right well anybody
who's a cannabis grower knows that you
can manipulate
terpene profile by the growing regime
right right so so now we have
limitations and claims that are not
limitations and they were not caught by
the Patent Office because the Patent
Office doesn't understand cannabis right
and they experience they don't have the
experience to realize it's over broad
they're like all it reads okay but they
don't have any sense of context right
and this is exactly what happens anytime
a new arena is opened up in the Patent
Office this is not unique to this when
we went to molecular data based
Diagnostics a lot of crappy patents were
issued then too and when we went to you
know different types of engineering
though you know when we opened up
business method patents every time a new
arena of patents is opened because
there's nobody who knows how to examine
them the same exact thing happens so the
fact that this happened in the cannabis
industry is not the issue right because
it happens in all industries where there
is not enough expertise for the patent
examiner's right I remember during the
dot-com boom you know there was a patent
for it clicking on an image that took
you to a advertisers website you know
they're like patting that it was like
well that's that's the entirety of the
internet you know yep exactly right so
so and it's because you have a weakness
in the examiner force that doesn't
understand the incoming new technology
right that's exactly what happened here
so they saw a plant patent that looked
like a bonafide plant patent but it was
applied to F once well in any other
agricultural you know domain
you don't patent an f-1 you patent a
stabilized true breeding strain because
that's how you get your ROI right so
Monsanto doesn't sell F once Monsanto
sells stabilized true breeding strains
that have gone to the point where you
may not even be able to get you know
fertile seeds from the cross right so so
that's how how deep they go into these
things right and so because they don't
do that in the cannabis industry right
but the Patent Office doesn't understand
they don't do that well what happened
they issue patents that look right but
can't possibly be right because
f1s and we don't do any of that other
stabilization right so so this is where
one of those things where a patent
practitioner saw and I'm not trying to
call the guy out but I guess I kinda am
right so when I saw it I was actually
really offended that a patent
practitioner would pull the wool over
the patent offices eyes like that but
then again it's because I didn't do it
and I wasn't first right so he somebody
beat me to the punch and so I can't say
that it's not sour grapes right so
because as I said it's a well written
patent and I would have probably done
the same thing and you know even though
all of us who haven't done it are all
you know bent out of shape about it you
know you kind of have to give the person
like ball or credit I mean that's a
freaking hustle you know Ted wait to
have your ear I mean I don't like it and
I'm you know I work against it but you
also got to be impressed like dang yo
that's some game yeah absolutely and and
and to have the balls dude it was like
and what balls he has to pull that one
off and you know it's like putting your
arms around the whole cake and saying
this is all mine exactly dude exactly so
so but you know so and I guess you know
two things though right so as of right
now the patents are really teeth 'less
right so so in any good regime right
enforcement has to have teeth right so
you can't really enforce anything
because it's still Schedule one so it's
federally illegal right so they have
these patents and until it gets switched
to they can't enforce it the patents
really may not mean much right but we
know it's coming it's not gonna take
twenty years so the patents will still
be enforced when that time comes and
then we have an issue right so then we
have to see whether or not it can be
challenged because they're invalid so
the question then becomes is who's gonna
put the money up for that and that's
kind of where everything fell apart
because we started this part of the talk
about my letter right so I wrote the
letter where I did this analysis and I
looked at all the claims when I said
well this is the potential impact and
the potential impact is large right
because if you're looking at all THC CBD
producing strains right and that's the
focus of most
additional cannabis now one-to-one
ratios you know two to one one to two is
what but it's you know always THC CBD
hybrids tend to be the most interesting
for the medicinal aspect of cannabis
you know you now have a situation where
a good 50 to 75 percent of potentially
all medicinal cannabis moving forward is
claimed right but it gets worse because
that was just the first one that came
out down the pipeline pipeline right
they now have three actually that they
have for now so since then three other
members of this portfolio have issue
they now have four issued pens which
means that it's even a harder job to
invalidate them and the patents have
become even broader so now they have one
that's a medicinal cannabis patent it
doesn't even claim the phenotype right
there's no BT bead B sub T sub D in it
it's just a hybrid cannabis plant making
at least one point five percent THC a
and 2 percent or 3 4 whatever the
numbers were right so they even took out
the requirement for that genetic you
know limitation so is it possible under
certain growing conditions together
Tate's a dominant plant to produce CBD
well yeah it's probably possible to do
that right would it fall under the B sub
T B sub D genotype technically it might
but it doesn't have to if if it's a
trick of you know for instance you know
let's look up the other way high CBD
plants right you get to a point with
high CBD plants where it doesn't matter
you know how hard you try you will get
some THC produced right so you know I
could imagine that there are probably
THC dominant plants that do the same
thing right so so now think about this
that means that somebody with completely
unrelated genetics to the genetics that
went into the patent could infringe
because they happen to grow their their
own genetics the wrong way so in my mind
that's not what the patent office meant
to do right that's that's just it
possibly be possible right that some guy
inadvertently
not even you know using the same
starting genetics is is um you know it's
going to be you know on the hook for
this you know it can't be right and and
the way things are written out it that's
exactly the way it works and that and so
we got to do something about it
absolutely have to do something about it
and I would think that after they got
their first patent and it was over broad
and after everybody was done drinking
this champagne they're like well what
can we do now and so they come with
three more that are increasingly even
more broad and they're probably
expecting some pushback but my goodness
they've they've taken so much real
estate of the industry at the beginning
everyone who wants to play defense has
to push them that much farther back now
and there's probably some amount of
their patents being reinforcing right
like once you have one if you have four
it makes your first one look better yeah
absolutely
there is that so and you get the kind of
backdoor into protection well we didn't
get it there but we have this other one
that has this and it's not there but now
they have to invalidate - right so and
the more patents in suit the more
expensive it becomes right so you know
and then think about it this way right
so he's got these things in hand right
if somebody is going to start to
challenge him what do you do you go get
a deep pocket partner like Monsanto hey
help me help me fight these things off
and I'll you know let you use the
patents or you or you can buy them cheap
or you know whatever so you know there's
all sorts of possible scenarios right
and the only reason I bring up those
scenarios is because if at any point the
idea was for them to get these things to
protect the industry from the likes of
those big AG companies you'd think that
not therefore they would have donated it
to the public domain already which they
have not done which tells me that
they're in this for their own personal
gain right so yeah that's an interesting
point - right like you know these overly
broad patents if if we had them and they
were in the public domain we'd be like
ah these are really good patents they're
very broad and they protect you know
medical marijuana now and into the
future that's great but since somebody
else has got the
and looks like they're motivated by
profit and could potentially flip it to
a you know mega aggron core that that
that suddenly it looks way less way less
attractive well and and and and way less
like it was done for the correct you
know philanthropic reasons right so this
is definitely this wasn't done in the
best interest of the industry at least
yeah right on so so that's good let's go
back to your original email before we go
to the second break here oh yeah your
your original email was looking to like
like sound the alarm
raise the flag bang the dome that this
was going on and from what I know about
you I'm assuming that your kind of point
of your email that you sent out to to
these big industry players where hey we
need to pull together right now and do
some fundraising and stand up to this
because we're either gonna a need a
whole bunch of money to do do the the
the long read on the present cultivars
to protect them or be and more likely
somebody's gonna have to stage you know
a lawsuit to to quash these patents when
they become enforceable and and with
that assumption that's what you were
trying to get people to consider did
anybody consider I mean is there anybody
working on that it seems like a level of
participation and cooperation that our
industry hasn't quite pulled off yet so
you know me very well Shango because
it's exactly what I did so yeah so I put
together the letter I sent it around I
went to the people like you know Steve
DeAngelo Stevie Angelo pulled some
people together I ended up speaking to
somebody at one point who was campaign
adviser to Hillary Clinton we tried to
put it on into that domain to get it to
be publicized that way they were an
interesting because it was too
controversial a topic I put together a
seminar at the new West summit I don't
know if he you know they're they hold
that it's you know kind of the
all kind of you know that big data kind
of meeting for the cannabis industry
it's held every year and so to two years
ago I did exactly that I did a a seminar
on the patents and then by invitation
only right we had gathered using new
frontier the data company we had get and
we had gathered a number of people for a
private seminar that occurred afterwards
it was another two-hour session and in
that session I had actually brought in
an outside law firm I brought in Marcin
Koster because we have dealings with
them and and I had them give a
perspective of what it would take the
challenge depends the kind of money the
the approach because you know
challenging you know validity of a
patent in the court of law is expensive
right so there are lesser expensive ways
called in to portage of view or export
interview they're there that are
available through the patent office that
come in way cheaper but at the end of
the day was still gonna cost between 300
to 700 thousand dollars right and they
were asking that a war chest be put
together or at least like half a million
dollars so they could go through and do
the whole entire thing and and as soon
as they came to the number part the
entire meeting broke down and it became
a discussion of well who's going to
contribute and what about the people who
don't contribute because they're gonna
get benefit anyway so they're good what
do we do about the Free Riders and and
literally it became more about how to
you know who's gonna put in what and and
how how the people who put in what they
put in were gonna benefit more than the
people who didn't put anything else who
were the Free Riders I like and I
couldn't believe it I like looked at the
room as it devolved into this side
conversation and I was like holy [__]
dude what's going on here
right III sorry about that I thought I'd
turn that off III I literally was
floored right and how far do you write
because the position that you're
bringing to them is is you know
somebody's trying to take the whole pie
we want to make
pi available to everybody do we want to
do this and then alike yeah but if we
pay for it we want the whole pie right
right so and so what ended up happening
was nothing absolutely nothing so I so
and there was instant because you know
the GQ article talks about Mowgli and
and how Mowgli went to you know Amanda
well I had actually talked to Amanda
about this previously and I was actually
the one who actually told its told
Mowgli about it and Mowgli and I were
kind of at opposite ends of this thing
for a while even publicly when we
finally realized I'm like dude you know
we're saying the same thing you want
them to protect stuff now to keep them
away I'm telling them that they should
protect stuff now the way to do with is
to patent it before other people patent
you're against patents but at the end of
the day we want the same thing we want
the industry protected you know you seem
to think it can be done a certain way
I know patents a little bit better and
I'm telling you we should do it this way
that's and - I mean knowing both you and
Mowgli homes from Philo's Biosciences I
can see how you guys probably approach
this differently you're all like let's
defensively patent it and he's all like
patent suck and so I see and and I agree
with both of those right and so I can
see how it probably took you guys a
little bit of you know mental jostling
to find out you're actually on the same
page right and I and just for the record
I love Mowgli dude Mowgli it's an
awesome dude and I love talking to him
and and he and I you know have you know
a deep respect for each other right so
and so you know it was important for me
to me to make him understand what I was
trying to say right I'm like dude I'm
not trying to tell people to patent
stuff to keep it from being open-source
I'm trying to tell them the patent stuff
because if they don't they won't have
anything left right so you know so and
at the end of the day I said by the way
if we all patent stuff and we say that
you know and we can let anybody you want
to use those patents for free right so
once we own a patent we can give anybody
the right to do anything we want with it
right but by having that pen you keep
the people you don't want from do
it from doing it right so so this way at
least we have some control right and
that's all I was trying to do is like
make sure that we in the industry
maintained control of what we spent so
long building because dude these guys
are gonna come in and with their fancy
labs and whatever they're gonna like
like like literally out-compete us in
the matter of years right the amount of
money that these big companies can dump
in with their you know thousands of
scientists on their payroll there's no
way the industry can compete if they get
into it right the only way to slow them
down is to put up all these picket
fences and say it and make a feel full
of land mines that they have to
negotiate around right that's how you
slow them down we're gonna take a short
break and be right back you are
listening to shaping fire and my guest
today is Reggie Godinho chief science
officer and director of genetics and
intellectual property at Steve Hill
if you own a cannabis company you know
that finding good business partners
vendors and allies is an essential part
of your role and building your business
in a new industry like cannabis doesn't
always make that easy
Canha Khan is coming to Boston in
Detroit this summer and the halls will
be filled with every kind of ally you
need for a cannabis company technology
horticulture packaging marketing legal
Human Resources and media everything you
need for your business will be there and
your customers will be there too because
canna Khan is a premier cannabis
business and networking event with
nationally recognized speakers and the
opportunity to have serious
conversations with your business peers
and investors reserving yourself a boot
that can akan can unlock a lot of doors
for you not only do you get to network
with all the people who pass your booth
but it is not uncommon for canna con
vendors to do a million dollars in
business during the event canna con
Seattle E event in February sold out
well in advance so reserve your booths
now for Detroit June 1st and 2nd and
Boston July 27th and 28th attending
tickets are still available for both
events whether you reserve a booth or
attend just for a day do not miss the
opportunity to become a serious player
in your market visit canikin org for
tickets booth reservations and more
information that's canikin org while I
certainly still enjoy smoking joy
I moved over to using vaporizers about
three years ago the high was a little
different than burning the flower and in
the end I decided I preferred it for
daily use especially because I have
asthma
more importantly though I could taste my
flower so much more it's hard to express
to you how significantly different
cannabis with a good terpene profile
tastes when vaped instead of burned i
have brought my vape with me to visit
growers and they are astonished by the
clarity of taste and they say they feel
like they're tasting their flower for
the very first time the air vape
vaporizer from air vape usa.com is a
great device to use on the go or at home
when you pick it up and feel satisfying
like a medical device
it isn't flimsy like many vape Tsar I
like how the flower is inserted in the
top instead of the bottom so travels are
shorter path to my mouth with the
cannabis at the top I get a hit that
feels more substantial even though I'm
just inhaling vapor and not full-bodied
smoke since I used this vape for flower
hash and concentrates I really liked it
that digital control for the temperature
is right there on the front three clicks
of the button and it fires up to the
temperature I specify really quickly and
discreetly you know vape concentrates
are milder experience than dabbing but
you still get the potency in your hit
also the taste is great as would be
expected with a low temp tab I love that
this vape gives quick little vibrations
when it gets to the right temperature
that way if I'm chatting or distracted
while it's heating up it lets me know
when it's ready if you are ready for a
nice pocket-sized vaporizer consider the
air vape the new air vape ex has just
come out and it's gorgeous and it
includes many updates you can find more
about the air vape vaporizer at air vape
usa.com welcome back you are listening
to shaping fire I'm your host Shango
Louis and our guest this week is Reggie
Godinho chief science officer and
director of genetics and intellectual
property at steep hill so Wow
we have shaken a lot of trees so far so
we talked about why you know patenting
people don't understand it and even the
Patent Office is and yet there's still
some patents that are coming out and
they're not going to likely be held in
the open sector so that's all a drag but
you know some people have successfully
licensed their strains because they're
trying to
you know advance and make some money off
of their life's work some folks more
successful than others and I know that
when I was at Emerald cup this year
everybody was talking about this
particular company in April research
because several of the winning strains
were licensed from them and so you know
as you know cannabis people are
everybody was was uninformed Lee talking
crap about nei Pro research with without
actually knowing what they do and so
let's talk a little bit about the
licensing of strains Reggie you know
where where are we at now I have people
successfully proven that you know that
they own the strains that they have
developed them themselves and then are
successfully getting fees from company
for using those genetics so there you've
got a lot of questions there some of
which I can't answer but what I can
answer is that yeah you can actually use
the same you know we were talking about
DNA sequencing earlier and and what you
need to get a patent well it's the same
information that you would use for
licensing right so and this gets back to
being able to prove what's out there and
was not out there right so if you as
let's say a company want to have you
know a business where you build new
strains and then license them as your
own you know as your business model what
you end up doing is you you get your
germ plasm you do genetic analysis on
your germ plasm right and you can and
and it's probably a good idea to do
genetic analysis on other you know
related or non related germ plasm just
to be able to establish a baseline right
and by genetic analysis I don't know
semi Nall ways sequencing although
sequencing is the epitome of genetic
analysis right so but you know once you
have this Basel information the same
information we talked about you know
what the cannabis industry needs you
then start your breeding program right
and so now because you have the starting
material and now you have your your f1
zaroor your even you know your later
hybrids right so you can now do an
analysis where you say okay this is what
my offspring look like this is what the
parents look like here's what some other
random things
look like look at my differences those
differences are gonna boil down to what
I call the single nucleotide
polymorphism or variants right so at any
given nucleotide position there's a
possibility you will have a change there
a polymorphism or a variant right so so
when you develop a new strain even a few
sets that you take let's say you take
you know you know Afghani and you cross
it with you know you know a lambsbread
so you again you end up an Afghani bred
right so whatever something like that
well you can see what the snip calls
will be in the in the Afghani you'll see
what the snip calls will be in the you
know Jamaican lambsbread you'll see the
where they overlap where they have the
same snip calls you'll see where they
have the different snip calls right and
in that population will then be a unique
snip table that's unique to that new
germ plasm which is the offspring of you
know a plus B right and every time you
build a new strain you will end up with
a new variant call table right and that
variant call table is the proof behind
which you can say look this is unique to
this nothing else has it here's what I
started with the mom had this the dad
had this that a la right and so now that
is a very defensible position and this
is what I'm talking about in terms of
what we need for responsible patenting
as well right it's the same information
that would be the basis of a strong
contract for a license right so that
because now you have the markers you can
show that this is unique to me
I made this nobody else has it and now
if somebody you know illegally trades
that ourselves that and you're not a
part of that License Agreement or
whatever
you can go in enforcement and enforce it
because you have this unique thing it
you only gave it to this person under
contract if it gets out from that person
that means that he has breached that
contract so we are seeing a lot more
companies ask exactly for this kind of
analysis as the basis of Licensing
because they see licensing as the quick
fix to patenting and it's actually
pretty a pretty good approximation right
so
because you can put these people under
contract and you can enforce that
contract because you know regardless of
whether you can enforce cannabis
infringement at the patent level you
have a contract under which you have set
some terms right and if they breach that
contract it doesn't matter what the what
the the breach was they've breached the
contract right so if the contract says
you can't trade that plant because it's
mine and they do it anyway it doesn't
matter that it was cannabis because
that's not what you're that's not the de
that's not what the contract was is
broken over the Condon was broken over
cuz you did something you weren't
supposed to do and under the terms of
the contract right so I'm sure somewhere
there will be some judge that will try
to throw it out because it's based on
cannabis but realistically this is
contract law and it's not patent law
right so the contract says you can't do
this if you didn't that then you've
broken the contract so the fact that you
did it with cannabis should be
irrelevant so that so it's yes it's like
Laird interests like yeah to be able to
license it they need to have already
patented it but the patented part is not
know the nature of the Nommo oh you
don't have to patent it to be able to
license you just need to be able to line
up no actually not oh that's interesting
exactly so once you so Wow so this is
kind of like a poor man's patent you can
get the analysis done and and show where
the I think you called it a clip point
you know see that those line up thus
proving that it's the genetics that you
did your work on and that is enough for
you to start charging licensing fees
right so now Wow so here's where here's
where the problem comes in because this
only works if you have stabilized your
genetics and you can prove but if you're
just trying to sell an f1 somebody else
can create the same it can create an f1
possibly create it with different
genetics and end up with the same
offspring right so this is why
stabilized genetics and true breeding
genetics are the paradigm in plant you
know agricultural you know business
right because the only way to ensure
that somebody doesn't get there by
mistake is to have it so that it is a
true breeding strain right
where your snip table will only be your
snip table and it can be shown that it
was there and locked in through X
generations of breeding you know and
some guy randomly put a and B together
but then a and B he will never be able
to get that back because he hasn't you
know if he tries to sell fit or cross it
he loses it right so so this is why
again we want as an industry to move
towards seed based growing and genetics
right so F ones are great when you find
something but it should not be the
be-all and end-all it should be the oh
great I have a great f1 now let me do
the work to make sure that I can find
the true genetics and stabilize it so
then it becomes my unique plant that I
can then protect so let me ask you a
question
drilling into that a little bit Reggie
so you know I have heard a couple people
say that commercial cannabis agriculture
will always be a clone or cut based
because you cannot get the you know
seeds to be uniform enough for
commercial mono cropping and for me I
don't think that sounds like the truth I
think that with more work you and moving
beyond f1 working with commercial labs
and stuff people will be able to
stabilize seeds enough so that they can
use a seed get the vigorous growth and
yet have each of the plants in the field
be similar enough that they can handle
them as a commodity would you do they do
you agree that that there's you know
it's just takes a little bit more than
maybe not a little maybe a lot more work
to stabilize these seeds well and that's
where the industry is gonna be well I
would I would say yes so so what when if
you had asked me without all the other
stuff if I thought that was dried say
that's complete and total [__] right
so complete and total [__] and
whoever says that is clearly not a
geneticist or a true you know plant
breeder right and I hate to be the dick
to say that but that's
I mean I hear stuff like that and drives
me batty right so so you know any plant
can be stabilized does it take a long
time sometimes yes right and will it
take longer if you don't have genetic
tools absolutely right but this is why
you have cannabis companies like myself
and Files and others that are doing this
work so that we can build breeding
markers and it's not and it's not just
the breeding markers for THC and CBD
because that's that's baby [__] really
that's the low-hanging fruit that and
and people need to also realize that you
can only breathe so much THC and CBD
into a you know output in the plant
before the plant gets sick and doesn't
grow well in which case then you have an
all over overall yield right so do you
want a plant that puts out 40 percent
but grows poorly or a plant that puts
out twenty eight percent and grows like
gangbusters so your overall one acre
yield is much higher right so these are
the kind of things that people who are
not plant biologists and plant AG you
know in the plant agricultural you know
technology don't understand these things
right so so what is it that we're doing
we're trying to actually find all the
other genes that are not THC and CBD
because in order to make a plant that
has more Tate seed CBD you got to build
it from the ground up you have to have
it so it has more biomass so that it has
you no longer flowering time and all
these other things right so to blindly
look at just you know a gene family and
think you're gonna make a better plant
that way is is is not doing it the right
way right so now when you look at it
from that perspective you need the
breeding tool so that you can grow an
overall healthier better yielding plant
that has an increase in everything right
and that is what the object of you know
building stabilized genetics and true
breeding genetics are and it's done in
every plant because it can be done in
every plant that's just a matter of
organization and and dedication right
and now and now you can add to that
marker-assisted breeding because we have
moved into the realm of where almost
every commercial crop has been sequenced
we have markers that we can follow and
now we can do rapid generation cycling
and
we can do other things that help us
build better plants faster right so all
of these things are done already and can
be applied to cannabis right on you you
got my attention when you said you know
the dedication and efficiency or drive
whatever you said about you know getting
this done and I think that this is one
of the ways places that I get a little
torn about licensing of strains because
you know the whole show we've been
talking about how we want you know the
the over-broad cannabis patent to be in
open domains so that everyone can use it
and and it doesn't because become
individualized IP but at the same time
you know you've got companies and and
and I actually don't know exactly what
neh Pro research is doing there's not
much you can read online even if you
read the patents and I've got an
invitation out to mark Lewis hopefully
hopefully he'll come out on the show but
but you know I have to both like on one
side I like the idea of the genomics
being free but at the same time I'm I'm
really impressed from what I about what
I think NATO is doing where they are
they're using technology dedication
efficiency and skill to do a natural non
GMO hybridization process really fast so
they are you know they're developing
these these strains with incredible
terpenes that then go and win awards and
then charge people to use their strains
and I'm so torn right because I want all
this stuff to stay in the in the public
domain but at the same time as a
cannabis well III guess I can't call
myself a Canada's breeder as someone
who's interested in cannabis breeding I
can't help but be impressed that they're
pulling this off I mean anybody who does
you know dedication to a particular area
and excels at it that's pretty
impressive and yet at the same time I
want it in the public sphere it's it's
it's hard to think about because I you
know I want these companies to be able
to recoup some of them you know not some
but I want them to make profit you know
on all their efforts and money they put
into it but at the same time I want it
to be available to everybody that's a
that's a that's a it's a sharp edge
right there
it is and that gets us back to our the
first set of questions which was you
know Monsanto spends a billion dollars a
year on research right are they supposed
to just give that up to everybody for
free how do they recoup that same thing
with neh Pro right so if if they're
using tools like I'm building here
marker-assisted breeding rapid cycle
generation and you know and we could
have gone down that path but I felt it
was a bad route for us right who's gonna
use my genetic analysis services if they
think that I'm competing with them to
build my own strains right so so I we
chose the steep hill to stay out of that
arena okay and just to offer the
services so that we could help other
people do it right so they Pro is doing
it in-house I and again I did not know
about it until the recent spate of their
stuff that they won and and I looked
them up as well after that and you know
I mean more power to them they are doing
they're doing what Monsanto what Dow
with those companies do that they built
a better mousetrap and then they license
it out for everybody to use right that's
that's how business works yeah you
really it's unfortunate right so because
because the the problem is is that we in
the industry have not been prepared for
business to work that way right we were
caught unawares and now unfortunately
the people who do it better than us are
gonna come in and try to take it from us
so that's that's the sore point and you
know coming up and earning my stripes
through you know patient advocacy and
working with you know medical farmers
and old heritage farmers that's where my
heart is right but at the same time you
know I'm a you know former tech business
strategist so I see the brilliance in
the licensing as well and it's really
torn because I want these heritage
farmers whose lunch is being eaten by
all the new Green Rush folks I would
like them to get paid for for the work
that they've done on on cannabis over
all these years you know during
Prohibition and in the you know with the
threat of you know going to jail these
people deserve something for all you
know for keeping the flame alive
right and doing this important research
but unfortunately you know it I can't
want patents for them but but not want
patents for other people it's a it's a
way by picture than that and that's that
gets confusing and so when people jump
up squarely on one side it usually makes
me a little suspicious you know just
like you're in Mowgli's discussion right
you know like like like the fact that
you guys realize that you were
approaching the question from two
radically different sides and yet you
agreed I think that there's a lot more
of that in the industry than individual
people realize because there's few
people who have done the homework to
understand why some of the things they
don't want are necessary but it's still
fattening still hard to choke down ya
know no doubt about it right because
it's the nature of our industry right we
we've always been this very communal
share or open source kind of thing right
puff up and pass right you know but you
got to do the Hat you got to do the pass
at the end and patents doesn't it's like
papa keep well yes except if we choose
to write so we can do the PUF PUF patent
and then say okay I now let so I pass is
that really what we're gonna say puff
puff pass puff puff patent pass to those
people we wanted to use right so so but
and and this gets into also to other
stuff I don't want to make this a
notable property you know discussion
right but so you can choose to assign
the rights to use that pad anybody you
want once you have a patent right don't
have to charge them for it you can let
them use it for free all right we can do
that right the problem with that is is
that you by doing that by letting some
people have it for cheaper for free you
set the value of the patent low so that
when you turn around in monsanto comes
knocking on your door you can't charge
them a million dollars for something you
gave somebody else for free that's not
that doesn't work in the pet and the pen
domain that way right so so you know so
you know it is you know but if you
choose to just give it away for free and
not charge anybody for it then you can
keep it away for free and not give it
away to the people that you choose not
to give it to it's your patent you can
do anything you want with it so changing
gears one more time before before we
wrap up you know a lot of people are
saying like don't worry about all the
cannabis patents because once they
finally become enforceable with D
scheduling they will be challenged in
court and there's just no way that
they'll stand up in court what do you
think well so in my analysis I felt that
there were some weaknesses in the patent
I felt that one of the things was is
that there wasn't enough attention paid
to the fact that these things were all
f1 and therefore they're there they're
not stable and the seeds that were
deposited and ironically they're
deposited outside the United States
which means you can't bring them back in
the United States to test them at all
because it's illegal but that's another
point so you the issue becomes then you
know in in the potential I lost my train
of thought here so I was asking you how
likely was that would stand up in court
oh and you said you said well there's a
bunch of holes and right right so so
some of the holes are you know that you
have well this is the kind of time I'm
going to be talking about is this this
Friday with AI PLA is you know you have
a the fact that a particular set of
genetics grown different ways will give
you multiple outcomes right so in a
situation in a situation like that okay
you have to ask the question well then
you know what what defines the output
right because none you know they're
claiming you know THC and CBD hybrid
well okay so what's the limitation
behind that you know where do you draw
the line behind something that was part
of the genetics in the minute was not so
in this patent they took some germ plasm
a lot of different germ plasm they have
a whole breeding table of all the things
they did that would and they did it that
which they could peel off a lot of
patents but in every situation right
they tried to claim in f1 right and the
issue the f1 then is hetero zygosity the
patent examiner actually made a comment
about it in the prosecution of one of
the patents and then there was an
examiner interview and it went away and
I'd say that that's probably one of the
the places where I would hammer the
hardest is like you know so why is
something that we have a seed deposit
for and I can take those seeds and I can
show you that when I germinate the seeds
that are undeposited you'll get 40 20 40
you know however many phenotypes so
which one of those phenotypes is the
correct phenotype for this claim all
right that's how I would go about it so
I do think that there are weaknesses I
do think there's potential for challenge
I think it's gonna be a tough a tough
row to hoe only because there's not a
lot of prior art so what has to happen
is somebody's gonna have to go through
and look at all of the Hempfest
and the emerald cups and the High Times
cups and all the data that's ever been
published like on Facebook in those
places because there is no scientific
data available there are no patents
there are no publications where we can
say look straight X has this chemical
profile right so the only way to
challenge these things is to show that
these things existed in the public
domain right so find some of these old
2012/2013 high x cups all these things
that have been published and then take
that with that in hand say okay so now
the genetics is not stable or the
genetics are not stable okay they they
say they have seed deposit X but if we
take C deposit X and we germinate them
look at all the different phenotypes so
that combination of things is probably
the best way to go after these two
analogy these patents the problem with
that is is that you know you're talking
a fair amount of money to get the
background data
you gotta germinate the seeds you gotta
do chemical analysis there's a whole
bunch of stuff that will need to be led
up to because there's no other
to do it so this is going to be a long
drawn-out expensive patent battle unless
it's done by an inter partes review or
an expert interview so that you could
avoid a court battle so right on sounds
like a lot of attorneys getting rich off
this and a great area for up and comers
to go into you know law and biotech side
this sounds like it's going to be a very
exciting playground for a while you know
before I let you go Reggie you were
telling me earlier about the the new
expansion to your lab there at steep
hill why don't you tell me a little bit
about that before before I let you go
because you sounded pretty damn excited
about it yeah no I am said so so we have
steep hills is I mean from the last time
we talked it's not even the same company
anymore dude so we have steeple global
now which is a parrot kind of division
that handles our expansion we were you
know we have steep in the Israel we're
going into Europe we are we're in Canada
we're you know we have negotiations go
on in South America so so steep hill has
become an international company so we
have steeple global we have steeple
ventures which is actually an incubator
arm now where we actually take startup
cannabis you know tech companies bring
them in a house help them with finances
help you know move the science to
validate we've actually split up steep
hill labs into a production and R&amp;D
company now right so now we actually
have a strictly devoted production side
then their job is to do nothing but to
make sure the trains run on time tests
get out in the timely fashion reports
are accurate back on the stuff and and
in the generation of all this stuff I
was able to kind of carve out steep hill
R&amp;D my little area where we continued
the genetic research we still do the
kind of collaborative research with
universities we we do some of the
validation work and and you know
incubator work that it goes into the
companies that we bring in from steeple
ventures so but the the really amazing
thing is is that all the stuff that you
and I have talked about over the years
was it has been done with basically me
Anthony Christian and one point we had
Bob as well Bob
who's as my laboratory director for
genetics but who took a leave of absence
about two years ago because he of some
family issues and and unfortunately the
family issues just keep getting worse so
so you know so all of the work that
steep hill is known for genetically has
been done on the back of like three
people really right so but the cool
thing is that now steep hill R&amp;D has its
own staff so I have my main researchers
I've got a full-time bioinformatics
personnel guy now Keith Allen who came
to me from Syngenta so we've actually
been doing some corporate raiding
ourselves and bringing in some really
powerful people to help really blow up
our R&amp;D and our bioinformatics and
genetics capability the last thing is
that we actually have our own genomic
services division that started up and
it's being headed by Daniela Vergara who
is actually the head postdoc and the the
post like in charge of the cannabis
research at University of Colorado
Boulder and Nolan Cain's lab right so
we've cemented that that that
partnership even further by hiring her
as our director of genomic services so
steep hill has doubled down on the
genetic side and and it's just it's
really exciting the stuff that's coming
out of on a daily basis from my R&amp;D team
is it I mean literally do you know if I
could if I could you know use a an
inappropriate reference it's like being
a porn addict and and having unlimited
access so essentially the invention of
the internet you know I I was at a lunch
the other day and somebody said oh yes
steep hill they've put together you know
a world-class terpene lab like like one
of the best in the world you must be
feeling pretty proud to have been able
to finally put together all the pieces
that you've been trying to put together
for a few years now absolutely and and
let me tell you so once we plugged in
the data just started rolling right now
I cannot tell you so
so before you you know you I was proud
to say oh yeah we have another couple
genes and development for our you know
for our library of genetic services and
and and now it's like
we have we have to develop how many at
the same time I have like a list of 40
genes that were developing all at the
same time now because that's how fast
you're coming out of the biome France
pipeline right now so oh my god well
right on well congratulations on all you
know I'm and I'm like any story well I'm
sure you'll hit on a couple other topics
that will data that I'll have you back
on the show for but more than anything
dude thank you so much for your time I
know it's really valuable and and nobody
really tells this story like you do
you've got the science and the law
background but also the swagger to tell
it how it is so I appreciate you coming
on the show and breaking it down thanks
dude and you're the only person who
appreciates the fact that I'm an [__]
so you got to go with your strengths man
you can connect with Rajee at their
website at steep hill comm and that's
ste EP he'll calm if you've got
questions or inquiries for either Reggie
or steep hill team you can reach them at
info at steep hill com
I'm also there's a great keynote address
that Reggie offered at the Jay canna
cannabis science conference in Portland
two years ago on integrating genomics
and chemical analytics in cannabis
research and so if you if you like how
Reggie tells a story do not miss that on
my youtube channel which is youtube.com
forward slash Shango 'lose you can find
more episodes of the shaping fire
podcast and subscribe to the show at
shaping fire calm and on Apple iTunes
stitcher and Google Play if you enjoyed
the show we'd really appreciate it if
you'd leave a positive review of the
podcast wherever you download your
review will help others find the show so
they can enjoy it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the weekly newsletter for
insights into the latest cannabis news
and product reviews on the shaping fire
website you will also find transcripts
of today's podcast as well for
information on me and where I'll be
speaking you can check out Shango lows
Calm your company want to reach our
national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hotspot at shaping
feiyr.com to find out how thanks for
listening to shape and fire i've been
your host Shango though
[Music]