[Music]
fungus of all kinds are really becoming
popular with a wider range of people
psilocybin is slowly starting to be
legalized for research and therapy while
psilocybin micro dosing has exploded in
every corner of the country we are
hearing reports of fungus that eats
microplastics how turkey tail helps cure
cancer and how lion's mane mushroom are
pretty much your brain's best friend of
course culinary mushrooms have been
enjoyed by humans forever but we are
seeing a huge Resurgence in home and
small farm growing of culinary mushrooms
meaning that rare non-commercial
varieties are popping up at farmers
markets and in the neighborhood trades
last year I discovered that I totally
loved wine cap mushrooms I had never
come across that Kraft mushroom until
gifted it by a home cultivator now I'm
constantly searching for them and
finally the fungus in the soil is
essential for all the food we eat and
the flowers we love especially cannabis
so many mushroom varieties touching our
lives and being helpful in so many ways
if you want to learn about cannabis
Health cultivation and technique
efficiently and with good cheer I
encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter we'll send you new podcast
episodes as they come out delivered
right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week and
videos too don't rely on social media to
let you know when a new episode is
published sign up for the updates to
make sure you don't miss an episode also
we're giving away very cool prizes to
folks who are sign up to receive the
newsletter there's nothing else you need
to do to win except receive that
newsletter this month's sponsor is
Multiverse beans at multiversebeans.com
10 winners will randomly receive a free
three pack of femini seeds from either
gnome automatics or Humboldt seed
company so go to shapingfire.com to sign
up for the newsletter this week and be
entered into this month's and all future
newsletter prize drawings and be sure to
check out the Multiverse beans Instagram
you are listening to shaping fire and
I'm your host shangolos
my guest today is Stephanie Garcia
Mycologist Stephanie Garcia has a degree
in botany and Plant Pathology and
completed her master's program at the
University of Hawaii in tropical
conservation biology focusing on below
ground fungal diversity over varying
environmental gradients on Hawaii Island
after completing her Masters she
proceeded to tour southeast Asia
studying local plants and mushrooms and
landed back in Oregon spending time
between cannabis harvests and the Bureau
of Land Management
she now studies both endo and
ectomycorrhizal fungi and their
associations and benefits to various
plant hosts as quality compliance
manager at mycorrhizal applications
Stephanie and her husband Emery are
expecting their first child in just a
couple weeks so we are especially glad
that she chose to fit Us in before that
major Milestone and if you listen
closely you will hear their dogs norm
and Betty in the background
on today's episode of shaping fire we
will make sure we are all on the same
page regarding the differences between
mycelium mycorrhizae endomycorrhizae and
ectomycorrhizae followed by a deeper
discussion about mycelium specifically
during the second set we will focus on
endomycorrhizae its functions and how
you can damage its functioning by
inhibiting the symbiosis taking place in
the soil and we finished the episode
with a wide-ranging discussion of best
practices for creating a thriving
environment for mycelium and mycorrhizae
including inoculants proper watering pH
proper nutrition and the use of ground
covers welcome to shaping fire Stephanie
thanks for having me Shane go so let's
start off with two bits of vocabulary
that are misused all the time in soil
discussion
mycorrhizae and mycelium will be used
you know obviously the entire episode
today but it isn't uncommon for folks to
use the two words mycorrhizae and
mycelium interchangeably and and they're
not the same thing so will you start by
teasing those apart for us
certainly yeah that's a
that's a good question I like that you
point out that some people can get
certain things confused like that
so when we talk about mycelium we're
actually talking about the vegetative
structure of a fungi so you could think
of it as being analogous to plant roots
so you could think of it as fungal roots
so that's what the mycelium that's what
mycelium is so if you have a mushroom if
you go mushroom hunting and you find a
fruiting body like say you go for morels
right now because it's a perfect time of
year to be looking for morels there's
going to be an entire network of their
root system Underground
now when we're talking about mycorrhizae
that's actually describing a symbiotic
relationship it's a mutualism and it's
occurring between the plant roots and
those fungi fungal roots
so mycorrhizae is is more of an activity
than a physical thing that like that has
a name that's a noun it's it's it's it's
more active than that it describes this
relationship it isn't it isn't
necessarily oh there's a mycorrhizae
right there it's more like ah those are
two that is a host and a fungal network
exhibiting mycorrhizae activity
yeah yeah that would be correct so you
know I mentioned the morale earlier that
is a mycorrhizal fungi but you wouldn't
call their root system a mycorrhizae
right so you could say a morale is a
mycorrhizal fungi but when you want to
describe what how the morels mycelium is
interacting with its plant host that
would be the mycorrhizal symbiosis
so yeah my crazy is really describing
the symbiosis it's used incorrectly all
the time and like you know earlier in my
soil knowledge I definitely was
um uh you know doing that myself so
um and while we're at it because even
though during the first set we're going
to discuss mycelium networks and then
we're going to focus more on mycorrhizae
and set two I am pretty sure that you're
going to be talking about mycorrhizae
um as part of your answers during set
one so we we should probably also get
the the other key vocabulary that we
want to tease apart to which is the
difference between endomycorrhizae and
ectomycorrhizae
yeah yeah so Endo mycorrhizae when you
think of endo you think of inside or
that's the Latin
you know meaning for endos inside
um so really what it's describing is
what's happening more on the cellular
level inside of the root but if we go
even more broadly
endomycorrhizal fungi form symbiotic
relationship with about 80 to 85 percent
of plant species
so all of our aggro most of our
agricultural crops a lot of our
ornamental crops all grasses
so I call them more of our bread and
butter of mycorrhizal fungi because they
associate with such a wide range of host
plants
um now let's go back down into the root
on the cellular level hyphy will
penetrate into the root and it goes
between cells but it also goes inside
the cells
and then inside the cell is really where
the nutrient exchange is occurring and
the endomycorrhizae they make a
specialized structure called arbuscules
so that's the site of nutrient Exchange
um most endomyclerizal fungi also form
vesicles that's a storage structure
these fungi are really good
at helping plants overcome drought type
conditions vesicles they believe for you
know one reason why they can do that so
uh anyway the Endo mycorrhizal fungi
you'll also see them or hear them being
referred to as
AMF and that just stands for arbuscular
mycorrhizal fungi
you can also hear or see them being
referred to as vam that's vesicular or
muscular mycorrhizae micrizal fungi
so they don't
refer them anymore refer to them anymore
as the vam because some species don't
produce as vesicles
so yeah we're getting really detailed
there on the endomycorrhizal fungi but
it is important to understand that these
hyphy of these types of fungi they go
inside the cell and then the nutrient
exchange is happening happening within
the cytosolic fluid
now ectomicorizal fungi on the other
hand they don't associate with as broad
of a host
um Range so they're associating with
maybe five to ten percent of plant
species
primarily conifers
some Hardwoods
and then there are some agriculturally
important plants that form the
ectomycorrhizal symbiosis
so then if we go down to that cellular
level again and we compare it to the
endomicorizal fungi the ectomycorrhizal
fungi also make specialized
structures they do also penetrate into
the root but they also make a mantle so
mycelium will cover the outside of the
root kind of like a sock right so your
foot is like the root
so the mycelium covers the root on the
outside
and then it also penetrates
inside the room but instead of carrying
out
the nutrient Exchange in an individual
plant cell the mycelium travels around
the cells and they call that a heartache
net and so this is another more
specialized structure that they make
they don't produce any type of
our vascules our vesicles
so yeah they're just they're doing all
their nutrient Exchange in between cells
and since we're talking primarily about
cannabis cultivation and the Ecto is
really only uh interacting with I think
you said like 10 or 15 percent of plants
we're probably going to be talking when
we talk about mycorrhizae today we're
going to be generally assuming we're
talking about endomycorrhizae unless you
point out otherwise right yeah that's
correct cannabis doesn't associate with
ectomycorrhizal fungi so right on well
that makes it easier today so so okay so
that's why I wanted to start out there
with the definitions of mycelium
mycorrhizae and then and then
endomycorrhizae just for everybody's
benefit so with that said we will we
will uh jump back and talk uh much more
in detail about mycorrhizae during set
two but but here let's smooth on in
right now to talking about mycelium
networks to get a really good
understanding on what those are so so
mycelium are the fleshy vegetative white
strands that form massive networks in
the soil we now know what does it
consist of like what what actually do
the white strands what are they made of
other than just generally fungus and and
how are they made
hmm interesting
um well fungal cell walls are made of
chitin so that's really what they're
composed of and
they're made through meiosis I mean you
know they're growing just in the same
way fresh fresh growth would occur from
a plant right so they're really
exploratory like you said most of them
are more whitish tannish in color
um mycelium can consist of just one long
tubular like structure and it can also
have SEPTA which divides
divides this long tubular structure
um
and and for folks who aren't familiar
with meiosis
um would you just explain that real
quick
sure so I mean that's a it's
reproduction right so we're basically
having cell division occur
um and then the DNA is being passed
there's a there's I mean it's a pretty
uh technical process and it also depends
on the species right but even even what
you already said just kind of makes it
clear I I what I was trying to getting
at is like what is the what is the the
mycelium making machine and the answer
is itself is right by by cellular
splitting just making itself more of
itself right right right on so for for
those of us who you know are
transplanting our plants or maybe we're
out uh in the field collecting
indigenous microorganisms or
um or or whatever we're doing um we'll
come across mycelium strands that are
like a whole range of colors from like
the bright white which I always think of
as oves those look really healthy and
whereas some are you know more of a
whitish gray or some are like a
whiter-ish beige are are these different
um strains of mycelium that are these
different colors or does or does you
know a healthy thriving
mycelium is it always white and and
these colorations are signs of some kind
of imbalance
that's a really great question
um yeah it is really a species dependent
um you know morels for example they they
don't have this bright white necessarily
mycelium especially when you have them
in culture
um so I would say you know that yeah
there may be some type of environmental
condition that might make them this more
dull yellow
um you know maybe they're not the most
healthy but also we have a lot of
different colors of mycelium depending
on the species
that's good to know too because
um I know you know as I said my question
I thought that I needed it all to be
bright and I should not judge my
mycelium necks were harshly just because
they don't look bright and because that
could that could cause me to incorrectly
diagnose this situation
so if there are different
um strains of mycelium
um how do mycelium networks of different
species interact do they do they you
know explore and then butt up to each
other and then and then connect even
though they're different species or are
these are these mycelium networks of of
different strains
um uh kind of wrapped around each other
but not necessarily connected
a great question Django I'm glad you're
full
uh so I think I would say that's really
species dependent we know in some
mycorrhizal fungi there is competition
so
um you know I know of one researcher
that works on rhizopogon that is an
ectomycorrhizal fungi but they'll be
more competitive for their resources so
um
they don't necessarily they may you know
they may just exist wrapped around each
other but really they're they're
competing for resources
um so so so in that case
um I think that most of us think about
the mycelium networks as being these
these nutrition transport networks and
they're connecting everybody and you
know in my mind I go so far as I think
oh they're trying to help everybody get
along but actually there is competition
between mycelial relationships so they
are they are bonding with networks that
they see as allies and then and then
turning a cold shoulder and not
connecting to networks that they see as
competitive
yeah you could think of it that way but
one thing I do want to just clarify is
that
um there are there are other there's
another group of fungi that we're kind
of forgetting about a little bit we're
forgetting about our saprophytic fungi
so they're not necessarily creating a
network between plants
um you know amongst each other their
mycelium is really there to Decay dead
organic matter and they're the recyclers
right I mean they're recycling the Duff
and so those those are a little
different in that they're creating their
own little Network just so that they can
eat more right so they can Decay more
and then eventually maybe they can fruit
you know I think you're I think you're
right that was good that you picked that
up I I definitely think that I was
putting the responsibilities for
mycelium and saprophytic fungus into the
same basket yeah that's good for me to
tease those apart too so
so um so the the mycelium networks while
I was picturing them being large like
like in uh covering a wide space and
therefore had this idea that they were
also going from plant to plant I don't
know exactly how I was picturing that
but
um but really uh perhaps mycelium
networks are a little bit more localized
based on
um I don't know the project or their the
responsibility of that particular
mycelium Network
yeah I like that you can think of it
almost like their little project because
even thinking outside of the saprophytic
fungi that are decaying this dead
organic matter we also have parasitic
fungi right so we know that those could
spread from
um you know those could certainly make a
network and go from tree to tree but
they could also be more localized just
dependent on is their host available
um what can they infect right
um where do they infect because we have
other fungi that are primarily existing
on leaves that are causing damage there
right
so but yeah I think when we think about
mycelium and one reason why I love
mycorrhizal fungi so much is that we
really think of them more as the
protagonist
and we want to think of mycelium as
being this just incredible thing in this
network that spreads you know between
the trees and like you say try to you
know help everybody get along and
distribute out nutrients really well
um so I think when we think of mycelial
networks we really do think about the
more beneficial kind and that would be
more you know like the mycorrhizal fungi
and if I tend to drift into giving
um credit to mycelium that's for
safrophytic fungus be sure to call me
out on it again because I don't want to
be spreading the Bro Science we're here
to get it right I mean but those are
great too because you know I mean we
would have just meters and meters of
death in our forests and and there's
also some very tasty saprophytic fungi
so we don't want to forget about those
for sure all right so so let's talk
about some of these tasks that um that
we rely on mycelium uh to do so so
um why don't you just instead of me like
just kind of like trying to pull a list
out of the air um you're the expert so
so let me just kind of hand you the mic
and tell us a little bit about the the
varied tasks that my celium is doing
um in the soil
um you know as part of its role
sure yeah and I do just want to say you
know I'm I still don't consider myself
an expert I just consider myself you
know constantly uh trying to educate
myself in the in this pursuit of
knowledge specifically with fungi so
um I appreciate you saying that but uh
you know you can be humble but like we
all we all heard your your credentials
at the beginning of the show and and
you're here because like you know you're
kind of the expert so so I I appreciate
your humility on it but uh I have a
feeling you have all the information
that we're looking for yeah I'll strive
I'll strive to meet those expectations
okay so you want to know about the roles
of mycelium within the soil please okay
so I think I think mycelium's you know
it's main objective and it may be more
of a selfish objective on its part is
to gain enough resources to reproduce
right that's going to be the main goal
it's like I'm going to explore the soil
I'm going to try to gain resources
enough to take care of myself
um so I think that's one objective is
that the mycelium is getting what it
needs to to go through its own life
cycle
um I think another thing is just very
exploratory I think there's like let's
say these side benefits
of mycelium and what it's doing within
our soil so
for those mycelium to be
exploring the soil they're really
contributing to soil structure
um to water infiltration which also
helps preventing runoff
and providing climate resistance
so I think there's um there's a big role
for them there
um if I can go back to my mycorrhizal
fungi for a moment our muscular
mycorrhizal fungi they release a
glycoprotein it's called glomalin and
that is just this incredible protein
that helps to
aggregate soil and that's really
fascinating not only for this
um you know helping to keep soil
structure and the water water
infiltration but it also can hold on to
carbon when your soil has more structure
to it and then those nutrients are more
available
so I think that there's
um a really big role for mycelium
to play and
some of this nutrient cycling
excuse me we also
we also know that some mycelium will
actually excrete
secrete enzymes
and that can help make a lot of
different nutrients more biologically
available ones that wouldn't be
otherwise
and then it's it allows you know the
soluble nutrients to actually be
absorbed and then transported to the
plant
um so there's
I think that these are some of some of
the main ones just right away that I'm
that I can think of
um let's talk about the transportation
of uh nutrition so I'm realizing now
that of some of what I imagined
um mycelium networks doing which would
be like moving nutrition between
different plants that's probably a a a a
larger role than mycelium is doing and
that might be more of a saprophytic
fungus role is is the mycelium going to
be mostly
moving nutrition from the surrounding
soil environment and just bringing it
back to
um the the root Zone
um as essentially to the mycorrhizae
which is going to interact with the with
the plant
um uh so it's it's kind of like it is it
is out searching for nutrition for its
own
um
uh life benefit but then by doing that
it is also bringing that nutrition back
to the mycorrhizae which is which will
will discuss more in detail later is
then is in interacting with the plant is
is my range of where it's doing that
nutrition
work do I have that right where it's a
bit closer to the root Zone
yeah so I think the the saprophytic
fungi and the micrizal fungi they're
really working together so the
saprophytic fungi that those fungi may
be able to break down
um you know specifically more carbon
than the mycorrhizal fungi and as we
know Microsoft fungi they they're really
associating with plants because they
can't they're not able to access the
carbon on their own that's that's the
exchange
um I'll save this for the next session
really but
um
so let's say the saprophytic fungi their
primary role is going to be decaying
this dead organic matter
um you know making carbon available for
the plant but then the fungi or the
mycorrasal fungi they're they're more
exploratory and they're actually able to
deliver the nutrients to the plant
through their symbiosis right so
the saprophytic fungi they may make some
of these nutrients biologically
available but they don't really have
that delivery mechanism unless they're
very close to the plant root Zone
so the mycorrhizal fungi and they're my
celial network is really incredible
because they can increase the root
absorption Zone like our plants can only
reach so far mycelium is so much smaller
in size than a plant root right and then
they can travel for so much longer than
our plant roots can so they can really
become exploratory in the soil
entry areas that our plants cannot and
then they're able to access nutrients
that the plant isn't and then their
mycelium is like a little Highway
of nutrients going to the plant
um I do also want to mention which I
just think is interesting that
mycorrhizal fungi you know there's
evidence to suggest that they've evolved
from saprophytic fungi so some
mycorrhizal fungi still do hold the
genes that can do these other types of
breakdown of nutrients
um so I just think that's really
interesting because
some mycraisal fungi we say are obligate
they have to have a plant hose because
they can't access their own carbon but
then we know some mycrazal fungi are not
obligate and they could they still
maintain some of some of these genes so
that they can exist without the plant
host
so so
um you know we're big supporters of the
soil of the soil food web explanation
for looking at soil here what role does
mycelium play in the soil assisting
microbe communities and and other life
in the soil because I'm I'm guessing
that it isn't just a relationship
between you know uh Breaking Down
Nutrition and transporting nutrition
towards the root Zone
um I'm guessing that that all the
inhabitants of the rhizosphere have got
varying relationships with mycelium that
are beneficial
certainly well we did talk you know
briefly about
soil structure and water infiltration
right and this hyphy
um
you know going through the soil and
allowing that infiltration of water and
then just helping the soil actually hold
the water right and then we did speak a
little bit about how when you have this
really more positive let's say soil
structure it can hold on
um to carbon more readily and so we know
that our soil organic carbon is food for
microbes right so if you have an
increased amount of soil carbon you
typically see an increase in in the
microbial activity
so I think mycelium plays it's like
cyclical right so they grow and they
explore and then carbons held onto and
then these microbes are like oh this is
awesome you know I'm gonna we're gonna
there's gonna be more microbes because
we have more food and
and then they Thrive and then the soil
just becomes
um just more it's just more and more
healthy right right everybody gets fed
when mycelium is doing its job right
um so I know that some people talk about
how mycelium can help remediate the soil
that's been contaminated by a whole
range of things but specifically I'm
curious about
um a pathogenic funguses like that that
cause like you know
um fusarium root rot and things like
that can can our Ally mycelium clean up
pathogens like that in the soil
yeah that's such a great question
um you know I told you I really like the
protagonist fungi so my my Plant
Pathology is it is up to speed but it
just made me think of
um you know there's there are products
out there that are
they're well those are more bacterial
that are kind of fighting the fungi I'm
trying to think of these this activate
you know that's a product that
um but it's bacterial and that's
fighting off the fungi I don't know I
think that's such a good question but I
do remember this one little project I
did when I was living in Hawaii with a
friend and he was really into im04s and
um you know his knowledge is so much
greater than mine so I'm not going to
try to explain anything like that but
we were traveling around to these coffee
plantations that had this pathogenic
fungi that occurred on the coffee leaf
and we made a solution of the imo4 and
it's hard to say exactly which component
maybe was fighting but we we just
sprayed this on the coffee
um you know trees that had this fungal
infection and came back and scored it
and the ones that we scored there was a
significant impact and reduction of that
fungal infection now we know im04s don't
just contain fungi right so
um you know it was a fun little project
but still kind of hard to say and I'm
not really sure of the research on that
yeah that's that's fair enough and and I
think that that your answer points to
two things number one for folks who are
interested in in well cannabis but but
uh networks in general and are just kind
of coming up
um you know and and through University
there is a lot of research around
cannabis and soil science and fungus to
be had you know this is this is a great
time to become you know have an interest
in cannabis and become and be coming out
of school and then and then the second
thing that your answer points out is um
you know we're always talking about the
power of of
industrial indigenous microorganisms
here and Imo for you know while it has
got a significant representation of
fungus in it it's this magical
combination of nature that just just
rebalances things like in in your
example and uh and you know so many of
us uh container based cannabis Growers
um we struggle with fusarium so anytime
I talk to somebody who focuses their
work on on the root Zone I kind of ask
everybody hey do you have a good
solution for fusarium and and and you
know everybody kind of says the same
thing like like like you know the
research hasn't actually found a really
good one yet and generally you should
just replace your soil but but this is
the first time that im04 has been
brought up and and that makes a lot of
sense it would be interesting if if
somebody were to have you know say and
say like it like an installed
you know large-scale bed where it would
be a real pain in the butt to replace
the soil unlike you know like a 20
gallon pot or something which is really
easy
um you know doing uh doing a significant
application of im04 might be one might
be one fusarium solution so all right
well I don't want to get too distracted
off on the fusarium thing but but while
we while we're there um you know I
figured we might as well hit it so so
all right great so um so so now that we
are understanding what the mycelium
networks are doing and that they are are
breaking down nutrition and bringing it
back to the the rhizosphere where where
um I guess I'll say for the moment it
gets handed off to mycorrhizae that does
the exchange with the plant that we will
pick up on set two so let's go ahead and
take our first short break and then we
come back we will start talking about
mycorrhizae you are listening to shaping
fire and my guest today is Mycologist
Stephanie Garcia and you know without
these advertisers shaping firewood not
happen so please support them and let
them know you heard of them on shaping
fire
[Music]
one of the reasons why no-till cannabis
growing is so valued by Farmers is
because the mycelium networks in the
soil remain established from year to
year and we know these fungal networks
are essential because they are the
nutrient super highways that extend far
and wide in the substrate to feed your
plants the trouble with growing in New
Living soils or Blended cocoa substrates
is that it takes most of the plant's
life just to create these mycelium
highways
dynomicoendomycorrhizal fungi inoculant
reduces that time and gets your plant
eating a wider array of nutrients faster
and it's three times the concentration
of the other popular brand in the U.S at
900 propagules per gram of two fungal
species selected specifically for
cannabis cultivation dynomica is the
result of 30 years of research and
trials at the volcani agriculture
Research Institute in Israel it has also
been vigorously trialed by cannabis and
food Growers across the U.S
dynamico is now available at Grow shops
and on Amazon in the United States I
love using dynamico to both speed up the
growth of the mycelium networks in the
soil but also as a biostimulant to make
clone cuttings more viral you can see
side by side showing the comparative
growth on their Instagram at dynomico if
you demand reliable growing results and
appreciate the importance of an active
root Zone in creating a thriving plan I
encourage you to check out dynamico.com
and use the store locator to find out
where you can get yours that's
d-y-n-o-m-y-c-o.com
shaping fire listeners can get 10 off
any size of dynamico on Amazon or
dynamico.com by using the discount code
shapingfire one word no caps
whether you are starting with new beds
or pots or if you want to add some Zing
to tired soil choose dynamico to
maximize your plant's potential
dynamico endomicorizal inoculant
[Music]
you've heard me talk about the
award-winning cannabis seeds that come
from the analytical breeding program of
Seth and Eric Crawford who founded
Oregon CBD seeds in fact Seth was a
guest on shaping fire in 2020 to talk
about triploid genetics
Seth and Eric are now releasing high THC
seeds for home Growers and Farms as grow
the revolution seeds at GTR seeds.com
their high THC seeds are extraordinary
in that they will start to flower at 16
and a half hours of daylight instead of
the typical 14 and a half hours of
daylight that means in most regions your
plants will start to flower outdoors in
the middle of July instead of the middle
of August which means these photo period
plants finish in September and not
October totally upending the photo
period Seed Market
Seth and Eric took their prized early
flowering CBG line and bred it to some
of the most desired verified genetics
out there including Sour Diesel triangle
Kush wedding cake chem dogs Skittles and
others these crosses all Express
powerful photo period terpene profiles
and THC giving you a great High GTR
seeds has a new thcv line with plants
like double Durbin and Gigantor that
boast one-to-one THC to thcv and people
want that thcv
GTR seeds are very consistent true
growing inbred f1s from stabilized
inbred parent lines these seeds are
nearly homogeneous and the plants should
all grow the same there is only one
phenotype in every pack available as
diploids and triploids Seth and Eric's
company is still family owned patient
and employee Centric and partially
powered by their two acres of solar
panels everyone can purchase these seeds
and the entire catalog of Oregon's CBD
seeds at GTR seeds.com go to GTR
seeds.com today and choose something
revolutionary for your next indoor or
outdoor run
[Music]
online cannabis seed Distributors often
seem to be all the same but Multiverse
beans constantly Works to provide you
with cannabis seeds and a buying
experience that you won't find elsewhere
Multiverse beans Works directly with the
Breeders to secure as many packs of your
favorites as possible so that they have
your favorite beans long after others
have sold out some shops simply buy
breeder minimums but I get messages all
the time from breeders saying some
version of Multiverse asked to buy my
entire run
at multiversebeans.com you can find rare
cannabis seeds from Night Owl seeds
including the dark owl sub label
Mephisto genetics Square One genetics
Robin Hood seeds and Ethos and so many
others
Multiverse also initiates projects with
breeders to secure exclusive packs that
you simply won't find elsewhere
Multiverse founder Paul lall sees
himself not only as a curator of the
best cannabis seeds available but also
as a collaborator with breeders trying
to bring novel crosses to the market
that his customers are asking for
Multiverse beans also creates exclusive
stickers for their popular seed
varieties that are available free only
when you order those seeds from
Multiverse
check out their stickers like the badass
recent slap for Mothman by gnome
automatics on Instagram at Multiverse
beans and finally the freebies as you'd
expect Paul sends quality freebies with
every order and when you spend at least
150 dollars Multiverse allows you to
choose your freebies from their special
selections
you can get a 10 discount off regularly
priced items when you use the discount
code shaping fire all one word at
checkout
sign up for their mailing list to be
eligible for their monthly seed giveaway
worth 250 dollars
so go to
multiversebeans.com now for a buying
experience you won't get anywhere else
welcome back you are listening to
shapingfire I'm your host shangolos and
my guest today is Mycologist Stephanie
Garcia so
um during the first set we learned all
about mycelium and that it is also not
saprophytic fungus and all of the
wonderful things that mycelium do
um first for itself then for the plant
but then also for everybody else who
hangs out in the in the root zone so now
we're going to talk specifically about
the symbiotic relationship between
mycelium networks and plants that are
expressed through uh through mycorrhizae
so so we touched on mycorrhizae a bit at
the at the beginning of the first set to
separate endo mycorrhizae and
ectomycorrhizae based on how they
interact differently with with the with
the root Zone with roots themselves
um
let's start with how does
um mycorrhizae colonize the plant root
system of cannabis from from what I
understand you know there is a point
when a when a plant is I don't know new
or young where
um it is not it is not fully colonized
by mycorrhizae
um
by by Fungus that is is is boy it's hard
to talk about it once once mycorrhiza is
not a noun once it's a description of a
symbiotic relationship it's a lot it's a
different way to talk about it so so
how does how do you talk about it
Stephanie I didn't realize it like like
how do you talk about it in the in in in
as a professional who talks about this
all day
yeah I mean I guess you could you know
instead of maybe just focusing on the
mycorrhizae or my you know microsal
fungi you can say the mycorrhizal hyphae
or the fungal hyphy honestly so using
the word mycorrhizae as a as a as a
description of of of of of the type of
fungus so so it'd be appropriate to say
um you know Stephanie uh would you
explain to us how mycorrhiza fungi
colonize the plant root system of
cannabis
yeah yeah all right okay sure I'll take
that all right we'll go with that thank
you yeah so yeah sure so
so when we think about the beginning of
the symbiosis we first want to ask
ourselves how is this High fee growing
where is this coming from right
um
so
now in nature hyphy is the greatest
let's say propagule that we have and so
when we say profile we're talking about
um
if we think about cannabis a propagal
for cannabis is its seed right when we
think about fungi there can be a few
different types of propagules and
specifically our vascular mycorrhizal
fungi
so in nature hyphy or mycelium is the
greatest propagule in nature
so we can start with
um we can start with fragments of
mycelium we can start with spores that's
another thing that would be considered a
propagule right we're trying to
propagate this
um life form and however it propagates
it should be able to then become an
adult or you know go past this
vegetative stage so we've got um we've
covered the mycelium the Spore and then
our vascular mycorrhizal fungi are
interesting in that pieces of Roux or we
can call Root fragments that previously
contained or were colonized by the
arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi can also
act as a propagule so some of these
structures that are inside the root like
hyphy
they are produced within the root those
can also act as propagules so if you
were
incorporating some mycorrhizal inoculum
into your growth system you're going to
have some of these propagules you put
right and you're probably going off this
label recommendation
uh to my understanding there aren't any
products currently in the US that
claim
mycelium as a propuol and I think that
has something to do more with shelf life
um possibly with how you quantify it you
know how it can be regulated things like
that so
um primarily if you were to like let's
say get some mycorrhizal inoculum and
look at it under the microscope you're
going to see spores and you'll probably
see pieces of root
so you're going to start with that right
and then from that the mycelium will
grow
that's going to be growing you know
within your soil
there's a lot of research about you know
the signaling that goes on for these
fungi and how do they actually connect
with the plant root right
um that's really fascinating stuff
because way back when it was really
understood or thought you know believed
that
um the plant regulated the symbiosis so
we know that Plants release through
exudates
um we know that there's a lot of other
types of biochemical signaling going on
but now some of the people researching
the signaling are realizing that it's a
it's a lot more complex than we thought
initially and that potentially the fungi
has a little bit more say in how it
connects I used to think of it like
you know the plant is there the fungus
approaches like it's trying to get into
a party and the plant's like okay you
know you can bring in nutrients you
could bring in beverages for me or you
know whatever I was taught too yeah
right like come on in
um and why would the plant not want to
accept that it's almost like an
insurance policy for the plant that is
going to be getting enough nutrients and
um you know water and things like this
but now there's some you know research
going on to say that there's um it's a
lot more complex communication between
the fungi and the plant but we do know
that root exudates are released I think
we're still really trying to understand
root exudates I know currently there's
about a hundred thousand compounds that
have been identified
um
you know that roots are putting out
there but we know that they play a role
in the germination of spores
um
and then for that ultimate connection
right
so yeah once the once the mycelium
approaches the root there's a very
complex conversation that occurs and
then ultimately they're able to
penetrate into into the root system
and then they continue to grow and it's
actually a physical penetration it is
that's not just like symbolic it
actually you know because of the size
relationship uh the mycelium strands can
actually enter the root itself not just
the root Zone yep that is correct and it
was even just today we were looking for
these uh special structures that they
make when they penetrate it's a
hypopodium and it's a just small piece
of tissue and it anchors the mycelium to
the roots itself but yep it completely
penetrates that and just continues to
to explore you know this idea of of uh
these these endomycorrhizae spending
some part of their life
um inside the plant root
um totally reminds me of the of the
bacterial rhizophagey cycle that we
discussed in detail with uh Jeff
lowenfels back on shapingfire 96.
um you know our our are these two I
don't know areas of science related in
science at all or is it just in my head
because they're just two different
things that enter the plant for a part
of their life
yeah I think everything's connected and
you know in ways like that and I know
that there's a lot of research on now
with their uh I don't know if this is
really a term that's been coined but
mycorrhizae helper bacteria
um so I think things are definitely
working synergistically and
um so yeah I think that that's a fair
comparison right on so let's talk about
one of the one of the the the roles that
the mycorrhizae play uh in this in this
relationship with the plant
um uh the first one that I ever learned
about and I I'm certainly not suggesting
I I know a lot about it is is the the
sugar water for the sugar and water for
minerals exchange
um and would you walk us through that
that like Cornerstone process yeah sure
so that that really is at the heart of
this exchange at the heart of this
symbiosis so we talked a little bit in
the earlier segment about
um how mycorrhizal fungi
they are reliant on the plant host for
their carbon and that's all coming
through photosynthates through that
photosynthetic process
and um so that's really what the fungus
wants from the plant uh we know that
some fungi can exist some of the
mycorrhizal fungi can exist
um without the plant host but primarily
most of these species are dependent on
their carbon acquisition through photos
and photosynthes
um so that's really what they're after
and the plant is willing to engage in
this relationship because they know and
you know they somehow know that the
fungi is able to deliver different and
it's not just the you know more minerals
or micronutrients but even
macronutrients right so
um they they know that the if they allow
this relationship to occur that they're
also going to benefit in this other way
um that maybe they wouldn't be able to
to do as well on their own
I guess when somebody shows up with all
of these you know quality inputs you
you're all you get used to it right
right and why would you not why would
you say no it's like yeah let's go
so um Can does does
mycorrhizae have the ability to live in
the soil without a root or something of
some a root or other uh in order to do
this uh symbiotic exchange like you know
it might not be cannabis but perhaps
it's you know you know a dandelion or
something else but can the mycorrhizal
fungus
survive without a root
um
things that are obligate
mycorrhizal fungi so they have to have a
plant host to carry out their life cycle
now
if they didn't have access to a plant
can they go dormant certainly I see
that's what um how long would that last
I'm not sure
um but yeah we know that there are many
fungi many micrizal fungi that they just
simply cannot carry out their life cycle
without their plant host so they're
gonna need that root system yeah
while preparing and doing my background
research for the episode it was really
interesting to read
um all the different I'll just throw
them I guess in a big basket of
processes that mycorrhizal fungi
um are able to do like you know you know
that Cornerstone sugar waters for
mineral exchange I'm kind of like
picturing this this mycorrhizae in the
middle like you know kind of acting like
like a bartering agent you know going
hey you got those there you got those
here I'll give those here okay all right
go you know gotta like kind of like you
know directing traffic almost right
right but then but then as you continue
to read it's like oh also mycorrhizae
can and can do this chemical uh
transition and then also if it finds
this it can do this and like the more I
read I'm all like it the mycorrhiza has
got this whole toolbox of of of
biological transitions And Trades I
guess that it can do to make sure that
the signals and the nutrition and and
the water and everything is all being
transferred back and forth and I got to
tell you that that it kind of makes them
pretty badass because they're
essentially making their own tools right
there's all these different things that
they can do would you explain some of
the ways that mycorrhizae defends the
cannabis plant itself from like disease
and pathogens and and other things that
might do the plant harm
yeah yeah it really is fascinating when
you when you think about them and it's
one reason I just think the kingdom
fungi is so incredible and why we do
need more people to step into the field
right and how would also like when you
start reading it it really does start to
read like it's intelligent you know like
it really like like it's really amazing
especially when you like see like a tick
tock or something that shows fungus like
beating puzzles and stuff and it's like
damn you know so anyway uh plea please
how how does the mycorrhizae actually
defend the cannabis plants from diseases
and pathogens by using these various
methods it has yeah yeah there's a few
things that come to mind right away I
mean I would say the overall if you have
a plant that's receiving you know more
water more nutrients than the plants
able to acquire on its own the plant
Health overall is just going to be
better right so
you're just going to have a more robust
plant
um a plant that's maybe more resistant
to an infection
um things like that so that's one thing
that just comes to mind right away is
that if your plant overall is more
healthy then it's going to be able to
fight off different things that might
come its way
um one thing that is pretty well
researched is tolerance to not only
things like saline soils but also heavy
metals so if for some reason
um that is happening for you
um the fun the fungi they can actually
mitigate how that is delivered to the
plant and essentially hold it within its
mycelium
so so it like Pockets it away so that
away from the mechanics of the plant so
so that the plant is shielded from it
yeah I think and it's interesting I mean
outside of cannabis growing or
um you know things like that there's a
lot of saline soils and you know in our
world so that's pretty fascinating we've
done some experiments where we we're
just straight feeding in Plants salt
water and the you know mycorrhizal
colonized plants are just they just look
so good and so we haven't done too much
on the heavy metals but there's there's
quite a bit of research on heavy metal
uptake and mitigation of those heavy
metals
um so I think that that's really an
interesting aspect and things that they
can do for your plants
I know that there's other research on
prevention of infection
um
and I I don't know if that's just due to
an increase in overall plant health or
if there's some other mechanism behind
that that we don't fully understand yet
right on so
um
looking at the next question I have for
you I have a feeling that this is going
to be one that you say ah Shango that's
for safrophytic fungus but I'm going to
go ahead and ask you anyway because I'm
super curious of the answer even if it
is saprophytic so so so I was going to
ask you that you know cannabis
cultivators love ground cover and
companion plants for lots of reasons one
being that you know the plants can all
talk to each other and trade nutrients
and you know create pest defense and
then I was going to say would you
explain how mycelium you know processes
the signaling system but that's probably
not mycelium in retrospect is it
um I guess I'm having a hard time
understanding on the signaling system
between the plants yeah I'll give you an
example like like we hear about when
groups of plants even if they're
different varieties are planted together
um uh uh you know that an aphids will
Attack One uh the plants will signal to
the other local plants that it's getting
chomped on by aphids so the individual
plants can use whatever its strategy is
to not get aphids oh sure sure
um yeah I don't really know about that I
wouldn't necessarily give all this
saprophytic fungi credit for that but it
definitely tells me that like you know
since you study mycorrhizae and you
don't know this particular thing that
that I definitely have put this activity
in the wrong bucket well I know that
there some signaling of
and from tree to tree that are colonized
you know by fungi into you know increase
defenses or transfer nutrients over here
because now this plant is infected so I
know that there's Communication in that
way
um so I wouldn't put it past that I just
don't know if I could speak to that yeah
fair enough fair enough
um so
um let's see here
so the more we talk today the more I get
this sense that mycelium is more about
transport and and Breaking Down
Nutrition and and moving it on a highway
towards the root Zone
um but when the Trish but but when the
nutrition gets to the root Zone the the
mycorrhiza
um
symbiosis with the plant kind of takes
over and and does the actual barter
transmutation or process of of
bringing that nutrition into the plant
through this mutualistic relationship
um
and then the plant is then you know
sending the nutrients that it's sharing
back down to the mycorrhizae to the
mycorrhizae
activity
mycelium and then that goes back down
the line what I would like to know is
there is there anything physiologically
different at that connection point
between the mycelium
and the plant root
um where where we would say oh that is
mycorro that's mycorrhizal fungus you
can tell by looking at it versus does it
just look like regular mycelium that's
just doing a different activity
so when you're looking at the mycelium
itself yeah
yeah you know I don't think I could
really tell a difference
um that's really that's really
interesting because the way that all of
us I mean and we can't as people we talk
about a lot of stuff wrong right
um but but it we always talk we talk
about you know mycorrhizal fungi as if
it is like like you know an an
absolutely different type of type of
fungus and and the more we talk the more
that I realize that that kind of as a as
a as an industry we talk about it wrong
um now I will say with um like
ectomycorrhizal fungi we talked a little
bit about this mantle of mycelium that
covers the root system you can certainly
find Roots like that and you can know
for sure like this is mycelium that is
from this is an ectomycorrhizal fungi
right it's very obvious where the
endomycorrhizal fungi or AMF that's a
little bit more tricky because they
don't make this like mantle it's like
this matte of mycelium over the root
system
um so there is that you know I just like
kind of had that thought in there but
yeah I mean if you saw this mat of
mycelium next to your plant and next to
the plant roots and that would be hard
for me to know unless I went I collected
some roots and then I went through the
process of clearing the pigmentation
staining it right and then visualizing
it under the scope
right on well oh go ahead I didn't I
thought you were done go ahead no pretty
much there was just you know to make
sure that this is this was this was the
mycorrhizal fungi that was
responsible for all that other mycelium
I saw but to distinguish it yeah I think
would be kind of challenging right on
thank you all right so um so to to to
end this second set
um I just want to ask you one uh Ecto
mycorrhizae question because when I read
this preparing for the show it caught me
way off guard and I would like to learn
more about this if you know about it I
read that ectomycorrhiza have been known
to lure
springtails to obtain nitrogen from them
how the heck does that happen
I don't know I don't know anything about
that but certainly going to look into
that after this have you ever heard
outside of this particular example have
you ever
um uh you know come across examples of
of mycorrhizae you know acting like they
are are are trapping anything like that
I mean when we learned how like you know
you know aphids farm and things like or
no no it's the the ants Farm the aphid
larva but like that's that's some really
interesting stuff to happen at that that
level of biology right and so so have
you heard you know of any other examples
of mycorrhizae doing that sort of thing
you know it makes me think of like
cordyceps and how that can drive
um certain insects like it can take over
the neurological system drive them to
the top of the canopy
um eventually consume them completely uh
I haven't ever heard that with the ectos
uh but I do know that ectos have a lot
more claims
um to prevent like let's say insect or
bivory I don't know if that's just
because that mantle is you know covering
the root system so it's like this
physical Shield of defense for the plant
um but just knowing that there are other
mechanisms
like the cordyceps
you know I'm kind of a romantic when it
comes to fungi though I'm like they can
do anything right so I'm definitely
curious about about what you read there
and now I want to look into that but
it's not something I'm really aware of
right on well I got I got it uh just
from an article I found through
Wikipedia so it's there if you want it
you know it is really interesting too to
uh to look at all the different tools
that the mycorrhizae has you know it's
got It's got different processes it's
got It's got barters that it can be in
the middle of to get what it needs to
get done
um you know it's got It's got you know
like like the the soil version of like
you know chemical signals and and what
you know and smells I think of terpenes
they may or may not be root terpenes but
but the idea of like all these all these
different tools it's got I I imagine
like oh yeah the Ecto mycorrhizae is you
know excreting some chemical that that
springtails love and then when it gets
close enough I imagine like how the hell
does a how how does fungus move move
fast enough to catch a springtail you
know but again you already said you
don't know so it's it's hard to not
Wonder though you know well it it kind
of just reminds me of
um enzymes that are released right there
they are these types of like digestive
enzymes you can think of them like that
um to break down
the you know non-biologically available
nutrients so but yeah when you think
about how slow the fungi move which is
you know one reason I like them they
just like stay put right but
um but yeah that's that's a good
question and yeah we'll have to we'll
we'll have to try to get somebody that's
listening and enlist in a PhD project on
this right on excellent all right so
let's go ahead and take our second uh
commercial break we'll be right back you
are listening to shaping fire and my
guest today is Mycologist Stephanie
Garcia
[Music]
there are so many seed banks nowadays
that you really have options and who to
choose not only that if you pick the
wrong seed bank you could be in for a
really sketchy ride and that's only one
of the reasons I recommend Gas Lamp
seeds to my friends and listeners who
are looking for a seed bank you probably
already know Gas Lamp seeds as hemora
genetics hemra recently changed their
name to Gaslamp seeds
Gas Lamp seeds is not just another seed
bank Gaslamp is a female operated
Boutique cannabis genetics provider that
only sells thoughtfully curated seeds
from the top names in cannabis breeding
with over 60 breeders and over a
thousand strains to choose from you will
certainly find something you'll love Gas
Lamp seeds has something for everyone
with over 650 feminized strings 300
regular varieties and over 200
autoflowers to choose from names you
know you can trust like compound
genetics Humboldt Seed Company Night Owl
in-house fast buds gnome automatics and
ethos
and we both know that there are other
seed banks who will take your money but
have no customer service I invited
Gaslamp to advertise on shaping fire
after hearing so many good stories about
them from my friends they have a Plus
customer service with Lightning Fast
Response times
in most cases Helene and Caitlin will
get your order out the same day you
place it most seed banks are simply not
this organized or interested in getting
your seeds to you so fast but Gas Lamp
seeds cares you even get free seeds with
every order
Helene and Caitlin get it they have been
in the Cannabis growing scene for over a
decade want some extra freebies use the
code shaping fire all one word at
checkout and they will give you an
additional set of Gaslamp provided
freebies that's an extra 30 in free
seeds
buy seeds from good folks who will send
you great seeds reliably every time
visit
gaslampseeds.com today that's Gaslamp
seeds
[Music]
the cannabis seed Market is filled with
big name and hype breeders fighting to
get your attention and occasionally you
discover a breeder who is breeding
because it is the only thing they care
to do and they would be doing it even if
they never made a dime
that's my friend Craig hartsaw who makes
seeds as magnetic genetics
Craig comes from five generations of
farmers and is earning his master's
degree in Horticulture right now he's
been growing cannabis for 15 years and
been breeding for nine
he hasn't sold many seats because he
really isn't a sales guy but I've
personally been growing his seeds for
years and I know I can always rely on
his seeds to germinate Thrive and smell
and taste great I suggested to Craig
that he should probably sell some seeds
and asked if he had enough stockpile to
bother much to my shock he was sitting
on five full menus in Cold Storage that
he produced in the last two years and
hadn't even tried to sell any of them he
was simply too busy breeding well we his
friends convinced him to make his damn
seeds available to the people and now
they are
for the first time anywhere you can now
buy magnetic genetic seeds at Neptune
seed bank and on streamly.io
Neptune seed bank has just picked up
magnetic genetics for a trial to gauge
your interest they are carrying three
strains from his Mean Mug prominence and
turpinato menus which are exclusive to
Neptune it's an easy way to score his
seeds you can pick up those menus plus
his hillbilly skunk and Candy breath
crosses and more on his profile page on
streamly.io
if you want very affordable seeds that
are exceptional quality with rare
terpene profiles from a good guy go to
neptuneseedbank.com or strainley.io
sometimes it is fun to buy the hype
thing from the brand you admire but when
you're ready to buy The Strain you'll
love from an obscure mad scientist
you're ready for magnetic genetics
magneticgenetics.org and on Instagram
magnetic genetics
[Music]
there are a lot of good people launching
new businesses in cannabis psilocybin
and other psychedelics and it's very
strange Time For Us in the same moment
that psilocybin mushrooms are illegal at
the federal level they are becoming
increasingly legal in States across the
country these businesses leading the way
into the future of plant medicines
require specialized legal representation
by attorneys who have depth not only in
litigation mergers and Acquisitions but
also in psychedelic and other plant
medicines
green light Law Group has been
empowering cannabis businesses since
2014 and as the market has Diversified
into psilocybin and other plant
medicines green light has been right
there evolving with their diverse
clients to provide legal expertise with
a high level of legal Acumen creative
strategy and precision that comes with
an intimate and specific understanding
of both business law and plant medicine
if you are a business owner trying to
navigate the layered local and National
Drug Laws on your own you are at risk of
fumbling these confusing and quickly
changing laws complicate everything
green light law group is ready to help
you when hit with a lawsuit or because
you were shafted by a vendor or business
partner or simply because you want to
stay legal and could use some
preventative guidance before cultivating
a controlled substance as an
entrepreneur
green light law group is a collection of
folks who care profoundly about their
work and I know this is true because I
know the folks from Green Light
there is a huge difference between a big
legal firm who has decided to start
representing a few drug companies versus
working with a collection of high
integrity passionate lawyers who are
personally interested in new plant
medicines and firmly believe in their
power to heal
contact Greenlight Law Group today and
learn more about the services they can
offer your industry-leading cannabis or
psychedelics company that's green light
Law Group at
greenlightlawgroup.com welcome back you
are listening to shapingfire I am your
host shangelos and my guest today is
Mycologist Stephanie Garcia so here we
are in the third set during the first
set we we talked about mycelium networks
and and the roles they do and don't play
in the soil and then we talked about
mycorrhizae symbiosis between the
mycelium and the plant and all the
Myriad tools that mycorrhizae
um have got in the toolbox to be able to
to do all the various processes that
they're responsible for well here in set
three we're going to talk about
supporting mycelium and the mycorrhizae
symbiosis in your garden so we're going
to talk about some best practices and
some maybe some less than best practices
so so Stephanie you know to today we've
been mostly talking about living soil
because that's mostly what shaping fire
you know talks about as a show but lots
of cannabis Growers
use soilless mediums like like Coco coir
and peat or rockwool do mycelium
networks grow in these other non-living
soil mediums
yeah yeah they certainly can
um is it the it
so right so you say they can so so do
they because you don't have as complex
of a biological environment in some of
these soilless mediums as you would have
in living soil
um do they present themselves
differently or are there only particular
strains of mycelium that can take to
that environment
um maybe I'm wrong but it just seems to
me that like with with
um so much less of the biology that
happens in living soil that's not in
Cocoa peat and rockwool that there would
be some kind of differences between how
um mycelium and mycorrhizae present
themselves but but perhaps it's not
yeah you know I think one thing we've
done we've done a few hydroponic studies
um not with cannabis but I know that
there have also been some hydroponic
studies in cannabis with um with
mycorrhizal fungi and
um I know that they're they're able to
establish in that type of system and
maybe
um you know maybe they're not as reliant
on the nutrients because they're really
communicating with the plant root system
I know in these studies that I've read
about with cannabis that
they um they've shown to increase plant
Vigor and so
um yeah I would think that they would
act somewhat different but as far as the
benefit to the plant these studies
suggested that they were you know they
were still able to perform
so I want to ask about uh water and
mycelium networks again but not like
what we talked about a water earlier
about about how mycelium helps create
good soil structure which allows the
water to get through it and and how by
it retaining water it helps the plant
you know
um you know not not dry out in drought
conditions it does all these really good
water retention aspects I want to talk
more about uh we as cultivators watering
the plant I can imagine that
um you know like anything even water
that is helpful can become dangerous if
it's given too much of it and I imagine
that if we you know over water it'll
cause the mycelium networks to rot and
then if we under water
um you know maybe they'll they'll you
know dry out and cyst up so now they're
not working either and so as cultivators
we kind of want to get this Sweet Spot
somewhere in the middle where we're
providing enough water for everything to
thrive but not enough to throw the
mycelium Network out of balance so do
you have any advice around that for us
yeah sure so I think one thing to
consider is the the mycorrhizal fungi
they're they're actually really good at
um helping the plants resist drought
right so there's a lot of mechanisms
they have where the mycorese helps store
the water they can also explore for it
so
it's not I think as big of an issue for
them to be a little bit underwatered
right
um they seem to perform the plants seem
to perform really well with a reduction
in water I know there's been a lot of
research and we've done a little
research with the group I'm with
um on watering them out and some people
would suggest you don't have to water as
much if you you know have this
mycorrhizal Association going
um not really sure how people would feel
about that reducing their watering and
everything like that but um I think that
if they have these root system systems
established then
um they're just really well equipped to
face that
um you know the stresses of drought and
they can bounce back even if water
becomes less and less available I think
that's a really good example of of why
um mature uh soil environments like
whether it's a in a pot or a bed or like
a raised bed or something that that
mature soils with with lots of uh fungal
networks that are mature are just really
going to give you a lot more of a buffer
as a cultivator
um because
um it it's more flexible than a pot that
we that we we just mixed some soil and
threw it in and put our clone in there
and and now that pot is going to be uh
have much fewer defenses than a mature
pot that's packed with mycelium networks
yeah
yeah and you know even thinking about
this over watering
just like we talked about some of the um
you know saline soil and the heavy metal
or you know heavy metal uptake
mitigation the mycelium can also help
with uptake mitigation of water so say
you're over watering
um I think mycelium is really good at
holding that and just helping to deliver
this like really nice amount of water to
the plant
um now I'm not saying you can over water
and the mycelium is just going to take
care of it you know we have to be
conscientious of that as well
but your bandwidth of success is going
to be wider with more mycelium yeah
absolutely
um uh two more or one another question
about water quality
um does does
um does the pH water or how much mineral
content it has on it have any impact on
the mycelium Networks
I mean they don't you know they're
they're similar to other things that we
grow where they they kind of want that
neutral pH right
um we do see responses if they have a
really low PH or really high pH that
they don't colonize and they don't
perform very well
I've had this idea which um is not
scientific just based on observation
um that uh I wonder whether or not high
mineral water
um would be more difficult for mycelium
to transport because of its high mineral
nature I think of it as like chunky
water
um and and perhaps the mycelium either
needs to a separate out the the minerals
that are in the water or B just refuses
to use it
um do you have anything to offer on this
on this idea of mineral water
yeah the only thing I would imagine is
if I was the fungal hyphy or even if I
was the mycelium in there and the water
was too chunky for me to deal with I
would probably try to secrete some
enzymes to break it down to make it
easier to transport
um yeah it's an interesting Theory so
after we break up the soil say for
example uh you know we tend to encourage
um you know no-till as a general idea
but you know sometimes we're in
positions where we just want to refresh
a pot and we want to we want to pop out
the soil and we want to break it up and
maybe we amend it and then and then
maybe maybe we're putting it in a new
pot because our pots are getting old and
janky
um and so the soil is aged soil and it
and and until we broke it up it had a
pretty complex mycelium network but then
we broke it up and so now we've got all
these
propagules strands right and you were
telling us earlier how any one of those
strands can you know start a new a new
network
how long would you suggest that it's
going to take from the the day that I
pop out the soil and break it up and
amend it and put it back into a pot
until those
um uh pieces of mycelium you know find
each other and get themselves uh
reassociated and then are functioning
and doing their job again
so and is in this scenario we're
thinking of you've replanted a plant
there's a plant in there yeah there's a
cannabis start in there is there okay
yeah yeah beautiful so
this is a this is a great question
um I know that if we're growing these
fungi in vitro culture so if we're in
the lab doing this this can take a
couple weeks two to three weeks before
the plant or yeah before the plant and
the fungi come together and create that
symbiosis
um
in this one study I'm thinking about and
it was with cannabis it was about it was
suggested that it's about six weeks but
that there were these benefits that were
noticed even ahead of that time right so
when we run our bio assays we usually
Let It Go eight weeks and that
that's the timeline that we've stuck
with to see this was a really good
colonized root system right
so you know we know that in those lab
conditions everything is like perfect
you know we have this
Spore right next to this root organ
culture and it's connecting like we're
putting it right in this like perfect
condition right and we can see that in a
couple weeks
um we run those bioassays for eight
weeks we have a study here that says six
weeks so
um it's a little more challenging if you
have something that doesn't go very long
like some of our hydroponic studies for
example we we're looking at lettuce well
after a month of growing lettuce
hydroponically it's time to harvest it
right so it was really hard for us to
find really good colonization throughout
and all of the like this huge root
biomass that It produced
so yeah I think we generally tell people
to
that you wouldn't see any type of
effects for you know three or four weeks
um so that's so that's exactly what I
was going for and the follow-up is I
really think that this makes a case that
if we are going to do any kind of that
Rejuvenation of pots where we're going
to be breaking up mature pots uh mending
them maybe re-soiling some and then
putting them back in that um we really
want to do that either much earlier in
the spring or even the prior fall and in
in either case either add like a small
cover crop I love of small plants or or
maybe like a or maybe like comfrey or
something to be a placeholder for our
cannabis plant so that by the time
um you know end of May comes and we want
to start planting our cannabis starts
into the soil that that work of
reconnecting all of the mice celial
strands has already been done because as
as you and I are discussing it you know
a lot of people will will you know break
up the pots do the amendment fill up the
pots and then and then put their
cannabis plants in there within a week
and that tells me that through at least
um you know most of their veg period
that plant is living in a sub Optimum
living environment because the mycelial
mycelium networks are broken at that
point
yeah absolutely and when you think about
some of these like you know we're we're
more in this like agricultural I mean
more in this agricultural type industry
and when we talk about regenerative AG I
mean that's the thing you know you're
trying for minimal disturbance right
no-till or strip tillage but if you
can't do that okay you can't do that
right but like what you're saying makes
so much sense because you can you know
do your amendments do whatever you know
you're you're thinking you really need
to do to the soil and then plant that
cover crop let it sit there I mean
having living roots even with your crop
right we're leaving this type of
compaction and things like that
um it makes sense it's same thing with
like
um crop diversity right or like a
rotation
right you kind of want to get away from
that I've always planted this one plant
and this soil it takes the nutrients
different right and then try to
replenish it with like a type of cover
crop
um you know one thing I was thinking
when
you were saying this was and asking
these questions and something that just
kind of came to mind is
it's really interesting that we will
we'll let these bioassays go for eight
weeks right but there's been so many
experiences I've had where
I inoculate in transplant and I've seen
a clear impact
of a reduction of transplant shock
so it's I'm not really sure exactly what
that's due to is this some type of
carrier effect
um
to somehow the plant know this fungus is
there and they're releasing some other
types of fruit exudates but that's
something that I've witnessed quite a
bit at applying mycorrhizal fungi and
this inoculum is you see this transplant
um
shock like resistance
and that's just something interesting to
me because if we don't see that
symbiosis occurring for
however long it might not occur for but
then we're still seeing some type of
positive impact it just makes me wonder
what else is going on yeah you know
below the ground for sure it does for
sure again more more room for research
for the people coming up absolutely
um Are there specific soil amendments
that either help or hinder
um mycelium and the mycorrhiza symbiosis
um you know the answer may just be well
keep your soil generally balanced and
healthy and and that that's reasonable
but but there also could be like some
amendment that you're like oh this is a
key building block
um you know for mycelium networks and
and you should make sure that you add
this or something
literature about biochar being helpful
um
and you know increasing colonization
um I know that we really avoid having
anything really high in phosphorus so
high phosphorus contents can really
um reduce the level of colonization
so I just say to consider definitely
consider the phosphorus content it's
interesting because mycorrhizal fungi
are so wonderful at acquiring phosphorus
that's like their Flagship nutrient but
if you plant it and if you plant this
plant in this really phosphorous Rich
environment the mycorrhizal fungi
doesn't establish maybe because it
thinks why do I need to be here
yeah my job would be redundant right so
there's a lot of research on
um on on phosphorus levels and
um even fertilizing with a lower p
when that's becoming established right
right on um and I and I've got a
fertilizer question to follow up that
with um you know while we focus mostly
on natural farming techniques on shaping
fire many folks uh choose the ease of
using you know salt-based fertilizers
and a plus b kind of stuff for indoors
how how did these sort of like sodium
fertilizers impact mycelium and the
mycorrhiza symbiosis in any way
well we
really but I know that we had to use
some of that material in our hydroponic
study and the lettuce that study wasn't
as successful but we also worked with
basil and it seemed to still
you know it's still it was still able to
work with it we just made sure that the
Pu was low
um because that's really important
so so to kind of wrap this up a little
bit
um you know this
the more I prepared for this show the
more complex I realized that my mycelium
networks and mycorrhiza symbiosis is
right I'm like I was like you know you
know a couple days into into building my
question path for this episode and I'm
like holy crap this is like two episodes
like and and a college course right like
there's so much here and you of course
is somebody who's dedicated themselves
to studying fungus knows this so so
um as kind of a wrap up there are there
are certainly things that that I didn't
ask you because I didn't know to ask you
because I don't have the the the depth
that you have got and and if our goal
with this show was to you know have
cannabis cultivators be more aware of
mycelium networks to consider them more
um and and how to support them when they
are growing either in beds or in
containers and and and then and then
understand the mycorrhizae symbiosis and
and the importance of it so so we
continually
um you know respect the role that that
the living soul is playing soil is
playing
um what would you uh say is that
something that I may have missed that
would be helpful to cultivators in in
making sure they've got uh healthy and
functioning mycelial Networks
yeah
um I mean I think you asked some amazing
questions I think that you've covered
um things really well especially I mean
everything from the mycelium to
describing mycorrhizal fungi their role
everything like that I think one thing
that we didn't
um necessarily touch on was just
um mycorrhizal products and not to put
any not going to put any type of plugs
in there for any particular product but
what I would tell people to be aware of
is label claims right so if you're if
you want to incorporate mycorrhizal
fungi by going out and buying a product
look at the claim don't just look at
this soil contains mycorrhizae because
one thing I've really noticed
um
through my time with with the company
I'm working with now is there's a lot of
products out there that will claim we
have mycorrhizae right
um but when you look at their claim it's
extremely low
and so you know if you're having a
fraction
of you know a fraction of a propagule
for
you know a cubic inch of soil like
that's really not going to do you any
good right so just be aware
um that there are a lot of products out
there that might have a really really
low claim and so you may think you're
introducing mycorrhizal fungi through
soils or different inoculums but just
try to educate yourself on
on the levels
and if you see something coming in at a
fraction of a propagule it's probably
not delivering what you're hoping it
will
right on that is really insightful I'm
glad that you added that and you know
this is um this is also something that
we talk about when we're talking about
microbe communities right because
there's there's all these like you know
new to the market you know
microbe Community
infusion products right and and and and
and people just buy them and because
they they like the marketing of it but
then
you know you you know if somebody with
with a with a bio biology background
looks at the label they're all like you
know what is this you know you know and
and and I think it's it's all it's good
for all of us to be uh Savvy and a bit
skeptical uh consumers when it comes to
um you know science that we may not may
not be entirely familiar with yeah I
mean really with all of our products
right but but and you know
even seeing claims that you think are
okay cool this seems like a decent
enough
um level
um I'm more of a fan of over inoculating
as long as the carrier isn't going to
cause any type of phytotoxicity
um you know sometimes companies will say
you know apply this much and this is
what's best you know on the business
aspect but
um
I'm I'm a bit more of a fan of giving it
a little extra let's just put it that
way right on right on so another another
good point to know your carrier know
what your filler products are in
whatever products you're using right
yeah so so Stephanie thank you so much
for uh spending your time with us today
and and sharing your insight into
mycelium networks and the mycorrhizae
symbiosis
um uh I know that I learned a lot
especially about the mycorrhizae
symbiosis like when when when you know I
really got to wrapping my head around
that that it is a process more than a
thing
um I mean clearly it broke my brain
there in set one but but um you know
throughout the rest of the show I I
realized that the impacts that that has
as far as how I've been taking care of
my own
um uh growing containers so so so thank
you for um you know sharing your Insight
and and your time and your good share uh
with everybody here on shaping fire oh
you're so welcome it's really been a
pleasure awesome so if you would like to
get in contact with Stephanie Garcia
um you can do so through Linkedin unlike
some of our other guests she's not super
uh active on on you know the Twitter
Instagram uh that we normally give you
that's because she's in the lab uh where
where she's doing the great work so but
but if there's some reason that you want
to reach out to her
um you can reach her on LinkedIn and uh
that's uh Stephanie with uh pH and not
an F
you can find more episodes of the
shaping fire podcast And subscribe to
the show at shapingfire.com and wherever
you get your podcasts if you enjoyed the
show we'd really appreciate it if you
would leave a positive review of the
podcast wherever you download your
review will help others find the show so
they can enjoy it too on the shaping
fire website you can also subscribe to
the newsletter for insights into the
latest Cannabis News exclusive videos
and giveaways on the shipping fire
website you also find transcripts of
today's podcast as well be sure to
follow on Instagram for all original
content not found on the podcast that's
at shapingfire and at changolos on
Instagram be sure to check out
shapingfire YouTube channel for
exclusive interviews farm tours and
cannabis lectures does your company want
to reach our national audience of
cannabis enthusiasts email hotspot
shippingfire.com to find out how thanks
for listening to shapingfire I've been
your host shangolos
thank you