for both cannabis businesses and
cannabis activists the primary goal
nowadays is outreach if you are business
you are reaching out to new customers
establishing your brand experience and
securing market share for activists you
are teaching people about the benefits
of cannabis trying to get legislation
passed and attracting more activists to
the cause well the best way to do that
of course is social media it is
astonishingly cheap compared to print
radio and TV advertising in the past but
even more importantly it is fast and
very responsive so fast that we can even
perform real-time a B tests to find out
what kind of advertising delivers the
message most effectively unfortunately
Facebook and Instagram are screwing up
the efficiency of the process by using
obscure advertising guidelines and
selective enforcement you can have
50,000 or more people in your audience
only to have your page deleted without
warning and suddenly be invisible and
unable to contact all of your followers
it is absurd that this is still
happening and it puts American
businesses at risk across the country
what's worse is that Facebook and
Instagram are now suppressing political
content as well one social media
professional has taken it upon herself
to speak up for all of us and try to get
social media platforms to commit to a
clear set of guidelines so everyone in
cannabis can place advertising in a way
that is not full of guessing and hope
today's guess is Lauren Gibbs founder of
rise above social strategies Lauren
empowers nonprofits and businesses to
use social media strategies that build
communities around brands and causes she
has developed award winning campaigns
coaches business leaders and nonprofits
in social media strategy and is a
sought-after public speaker she
established the original social strategy
for women grow and currently directs
initiatives for Willie Nelson's cannabis
brand Willie's reserve Lauren has held
multiple positions in the US House of
Representatives and has a Master of
Public Administration and nonprofit
management from George Washington
University
and a bachelor's degree in political
science and philosophy from albright
college today she'll be talking to us
about her hashtag and the social Canavan
campaign welcome to the show Lauren oh
thanks Django I'm so excited to be here
on shaping fire today so you know let's
uh let's set out the groundwork for our
conversation today you know in what ways
do you see both cannabis companies and
cannabis activists being treated
unfairly by solar social media platforms
like Facebook and Instagram well the
content that cannabis company is share
is viewed by Facebook as illegal in many
circumstances even when it's advocating
for the legality of cannabis and so and
so in addition to just doing business
there also stopping posts about what
about legalization and states and
different initiatives that are happening
at the state level yes and that's the
most upsetting part I'm of course
there's there's an argument to be made
that cannabis businesses should be able
to advertise like alcohol companies do
but I'm also talking about cannabis
businesses and advocates that want to
advance the cause and those posts
specific to advocacy awareness customer
education are continue to be blocked
every day you know I think that a lot of
us in the cannabis industry we've all
heard of one company or another that got
to you know you know thirty thousand
sixty thousand followers and then all of
a sudden they're gone for a day or two
and then you see them come back and they
say oh we were deleted at 50,000 you
know please like us and tell your
friends again and for for cannabis
businesses that that hits their bottom
line that injures their reach and even
if they're working in their own state
legally but it seems a lot more
mischievious to stop advocacy and the
legalization that that political speech
can you give me an example of an
advocacy campaign that is being hindered
by social media platforms sure right
here in Denver right now we
have a yes on 300 initiative and this is
an initiative delao social use of
cannabis so that people tourists and
individuals can legally consumed in
locations outside of their home that
they own and it's a pretty
straightforward neighborhood social
supported social use pilot program and
repeatedly these ads are being blocked
on Facebook and the reason that they're
being blocked the notification states
that that is being blocked because they
promote illegal activity so and then and
so when when when they complain what it
what does Facebook say when they say hey
we're not promoting illegal activity
work we're encouraging people to vote
yeah well it would be great if when we
complained we got the answer so they
when they when they prompt you with this
response they do explicitly state that
that this ad promotes illegal activity
and they state however as the promote
awareness or advocacy are allowed if you
think we made a mistake please contact
us well cannabis businesses are
contacting Facebook and they even peel
these ads and the appeals just sit in
purgatory you do not get a response the
only time I ever got a response from an
appeal was after I contacted a BuzzFeed
reporter who sent screen grabs of my
denial to Facebook PR and that is not an
acceptable route for other business
owners right so so the first wave cuz
I'm guy I've gotten one of those r ej
are actually I've gotten several of
those those advertising rejections
myself and they all seem like they're
they're kind of just sent back to me by
a bot and there's not even a human
playing along you know from your
research into this do you know how their
process works mean at what point does a
real human even look at my ad well I I
do think that humans do look at a lot of
the ads but they review millions of us
it's it's a huge scope and a lot of this
is outsource some of this happens
outside of the United States and I have
the sense that the ads on the rise above
social strategies Facebook page are some
getting routed into some other approval
process because typically ads are
approved or denied within 15 minutes and
i get facebook a lot of credit for
turning them around really quickly
because you think social media is
incredibly timely so if you have an ad a
super appropriate and topical to
something that is happening in that hour
you can get at approved in 15 minutes
that's amazing well when i post about
cannabis anything related to cannabis
advocacy or even related to their
censorship those ads take between eight
and 36 hours to be approved so that
tells me that someone has to go their
supervisor there's gotta be some
conversation happening internally when
they make that decision for it to be
that long outside of cannabis it is
unheard of to have an ad take that long
for approval that actually makes me
chuckle a little bit thinking about when
I place the advertising for this episode
to see how long it takes them to to
accept it you know cuz like who knows
you're probably on their hot list yeah
well I hope that you report that back to
me I'd be very interested I think that
you know I I don't know some stuff that
I i do get approve it unexpected some
stuff I don't and that's that's the
problem it's a complete black box
there's no transparency we try and
follow the rules around advocacy and we
still get denied sometimes these things
that are that are promoted that are a
blatant violation of the terms of
service but you managed to get them
through so there's a complete and
consistency and application of terms of
service so it's my goal is to have
facebook and instagram provide us clear
guidelines that industry professionals
and advocates can follow and then that
facebook and instagram can fairly
enforce let's uh let's focus in on the
selective enforcement of the guidelines
for a moment you know since you started
the end the social canavan campaign i'm
sure that you've attracted a lot of
feedback and interest from from people
who have you know not had their ads
approved can you give me an example of
of two similar ads that one was approved
and one was not
for no reason that we know about well I
think a classic example is Catherine
Grimm who was on CNN high profits CNN
was promoting that of that series
actively using paid sponsorship to
promote their television show and
Catherine grim as a character on that
show was trying to promote it as well as
anyone in that position would and should
and her ads were getting tonight wow so
that's actually a really great example
so they were they were same or similar
ads one from the media company and one
from the individual human and the media
company was getting accepted and the
human was not wow I guess it really
depends on who you know and I guess that
really makes sense with the example that
you gave earlier about how you have you
know probably bombarded Facebook with
messages looking for clarification but
it wasn't until you know somebody with a
lot of ears like BuzzFeed writing
directly to the PR folks at Facebook
that they had any response at all and
what did they say what do they say when
they responded to BuzzFeed oh they just
say they erroneously denied my ad and
let me state for the record that wasn't
ad promoting a colorado public radio
story about racial disparities in youth
arrest rates for marijuana in Colorado
that doesn't that doesn't even make any
sense i mean sometimes i can even
understand that facebook's lawyers are
so afraid of the cannabis businesses
that that they may want some more
security before i mean i can kind of see
that point but with an article like that
it's only tangentially even about the
purchase and sale of cannabis that's
about you know law enforcement prisons
and race relations how could i see i see
a situation you know yeah yeah is it
because it's it's a lottery every time
you try to promote something you you
really really can't know and i work in
social media outside of cannabis and
well as well and there's never this wild
card that you can act
we use advertising to plan the promotion
of your business your advocacy campaign
and there's some sense of reliability
that that can be a useful strategy to
advance your cause that that's Avenue is
just not available to us so how
widespread did this I mean we've been
kind of picking on facebook so far but
across the different social media
platforms is there some variety of who
is more generous with cannabis folks and
who is less well Facebook and Instagram
are oh you know that's one company and
there they actually have a single set
about advertising guidelines that
applies to to both platforms and you run
your ads through a single dashiell for
that so I would say that Facebook and
Instagram treated equally I don't see I
don't hear much of a crackdown on
Twitter but in my professional opinion
for a lot of companies Instagram and
Facebook is a more powerful tool so you
know I and I often hear people saying oh
you can go over to Twitter where they
don't enforce this or you could go over
to these other cannabis specific social
networks that have so far smaller
audiences but that's just not acceptable
solution to me yeah being relegated to
the back water is not a solution when
you're trying to promote any idea to the
largest audience so we're going to take
our first short break and be right back
you are listening to shaping fire as a
business owner you are incredibly busy
in reality you are responsible for
everything your company does you have so
many responsibilities every single day
that often you just don't have the time
to really dig into something as deeply
as you'd like you know there is more
that you could do to reach out to new
customers and to encourage loyalty and
the customers you already have but you
certainly don't have the time and you're
not ready to hire someone full time for
that role either for you i recommend
blunt branding blunt branding principles
Kirsten Nelson and Anthony Garcia are
focused on improving your bottom line
you know most marketing firms are
excited to make your logo packaging and
website very pretty but they leave
responsibility for improving your bottom
line up to you they don't want that kind
of responsibility but that is
pretty much the most important part of
marketing right Kirsten and Anthony will
help you engage new customers funnel
them to your point of sale and keep them
coming back to you and telling their
friends no doubt this is a paid
commercial spot but that does not mean
they bought my opinion I've worked with
blunt branding on three projects now for
various clients and every single time
they have done more than they have
promised and over delivered on results I
love how they generate new revenue and
focus on that as the goal instead of
just making me a pretty logo similarly
every friend I've referred them to has
come back to thank me and that just does
not happen every day so grab a pen and
paper because the website address is
coming if you want someone to implement
marketing programs that feed your bottom
line give blunt branding a call they
will share proven techniques to increase
your audience and generate sales while
using cutting-edge technology in the
background that make all of this easy
automatic and trackable go to shaping
fire calm forward slash blunt branding
to find out more you can also click the
link in our weekly newsletter blunt
branding marketing that makes you money
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire i'm your host Shango lowson
our guest this week is lauren gibbs of
rise above social strategies so Lauren
before the break we were talking about
how all the social media platforms but
specifically Facebook and Instagram
probably at the worst is selective and
how they apply their guidelines in
accepting ads from both cannabis
companies and cannabis advocacy groups
at the state level and you know kind of
behind this whole thing is this idea
that Facebook is afraid of something and
you know it doesn't take a rocket
scientist to go well it's probably
because it's you know federally illegal
but but even that makes me more curious
because at the state level these
companies are legal and acting as good
actors in their states now I don't know
anybody who's looking into this more
than you are and so you know as the
expert can you give us some ideas even
if they're just suggestions on what
might be going through the minds
the attorneys at Facebook and Instagram
that caused them to be so concerned and
not want to share community guidelines
on this mm-hmm well I think federal
prohibition can't be understated there's
a natural fear of racketeering charges
drug trafficking charges for an a huge
company like facebook but Facebook has
the technology available to geo-target
an eight restrict posts to states that
have legalized cannabis and we can we
can use them when we can get as approve
but why not leverage that technology
even further and allow us to use it and
thrive in that environment where we're
only speaking to customers in our
state's so so what what I mean do that
dude would you think that the attorneys
are honestly afraid of the government
bringing federal racketeering charges
that seems like such an absurd idea and
maybe that's at the cornerstone of this
right maybe this whole topic is absurd
and and that would be something that I
would I would just have to deal with but
but does anybody suggest that that would
actually happen or is it just facebook
because they're so valued and they're a
public company they have to play super
safe well the lawyers are always going
to tell you to play it safe yeah you
know don't point out that something is
illegal federally and we shouldn't do
this and that's that's the heart of my
argument here is that I I think that
honestly I think that Mark Zuckerberg
probably agrees with me on the whole
here and it's going to take a major
national company to show some leadership
and say you know we're not going to
continue to follow this insane federal
law when we have half of the states have
legal cannabis and some poor you know
that's one of the things I've liked
about your campaign for and the social
canna ban because you always tag
whatever platform it's on Zuckerberg
himself and you you you run the campaign
as if you're in conversation with him it
would be so visionary if he would just
step out and magnanimous
we changed the policy regardless of what
his attorneys are saying and instead
just be on the right side of history you
know a girl can dream I'm assuming that
when you tag him in these posts that
you've never gotten a response right uh
I mean my websites been visited a number
of times from Palo Alto so I someone may
be looking at it I haven't gotten a
response though right on yeah but let me
say that you know I I have a lot of
admiration for Mark Zuckerberg he's a
true visionary and I have created a
career out of social media and I loved
it and he does some incredible work and
causing these wonderful shifts in our
culture that allow us to create
community around brands and community
around causes in a way that we serve
lost as a society so I you know there's
plenty of people to comment on my stuff
negatively about Mark Zuckerberg but I
don't approach the conversation as that
adversarial I think that he is a leader
and I think that it would be amazing if
you could go down in history and help
you know shifting to the end of
prohibition you know I think that's a
really good clarification to make too
because you know so often trolls will
put comments like you know screw bark
Zuckerberg or whatever and really you
know I've got friends that I'm friendly
with and we have dinner and we have you
know disagreeing political positions
that doesn't mean I dislike the person
it just means them I you know I would
encourage or educate them to potentially
change their position or not you know so
I think that's I think that's a really
responsible position to take to make
sure that there's a difference between
the human and and the implementation of
a policy you know during the during the
first set you were talking about how to
similar advertising buys were treated
differently one was from CNN and one was
from the media personality that was
trying to do it on their own as an
individual citizen and that then that
CNN there's got approved and the
individual persons did not do you see a
lot of that kind of favoritism taking
place by people who have got PR
apartments oh absolutely I am High Times
has five and a half million followers on
Facebook but when you have a small
business that baby has 1300 followers or
thirteen thousand followers and they get
shut down they don't have the resources
or the clow to appeal it if you're a
major national name and you're having
problems with Facebook and Instagram
they're going to pay attention but when
these small players and in cannabis is a
lot of small players there is this huge
entrepreneurial environment so many
startups and so many people spending
scarce resources to build brands build a
company to advocate for cause and they
invest a lot of time in building these
communities and then they just get
yanked away and they literally have no
recourse you know it's I'm not
unfamiliar with the rumor and I'm hoping
that you can tell me to what degree you
think it's true that you know what these
small players in these new markets
they've got a competitor and so they get
you know everybody at their business and
a bunch of their friends to go and you
know click the button is this offensive
or illegal to our guidelines button and
they all turn in one company's page to
try to get rid of their competitors and
wow I don't know if this is urban myth
or not but you know have you heard about
this strategy working is this something
that you're seeing happen with you and
your clients I i I've heard of this and
you know I think that anyone who's like
an ethical and responsible business
owner would not pursue that strategy
because if you have a good product in a
good cause you don't need to attack a
competition that way you should just be
able to focus on your message and built
following that way but that sort of
underscores that that is a perversion of
the reporting mechanism if we simply had
terms of service that were more clear
provided a framework that we could abide
by then there wouldn't be that weird you
know perversion that allows people to
attack each other yeah I think that's
probably got to be the most frustrating
aspect
all of this is that you know not that
they're not allowing cannabis while that
is frustrating it's that we don't know
where anybody is drawing the lines and
the lines are being drawn differently
for big companies versus small companies
potentially by who the reviewer is of
the ad and as you've told me about you
know when you press an ad sometimes
they'll flip flop their opinion and like
oh that was a mistake you know but but
that is not the way to make social
policy right that does not allow
marketing teams and advocates to plan
out a media campaign that is strong and
will have good reach but also meets the
Facebook guidelines and I think that
moving target is probably what really
annoys people the most well they lose
money because of it because you can't
you can't have a plan and you can't
execute with consistency if you have a
morgan target like that it's guesswork
all the time so i would think that right
now coming up to the elections there's
probably a lot one of those there's nine
states that are looking to move towards
normalization and they're probably very
actively trying to educate via facebook
it's probably a total mess about which
ads are gonna be a loud and from state
to state our people reaching out to you
to you know share their stories with you
what are you seeing on the front lines
I'm so glad you asked this because I do
have people reach out to me but honestly
I would like to see more people reach
out to me because there's no
transparency as to what's going on ads
get denied and people appeal them and I
sit in purgatory and I've just decided
that I'm have to serve as the watchdog
for this problem so when people have
something that's denied I'd love when
they send me a screen grab of their
original post and then a screen grab of
the reason which they were denied which
is often for promoting illegal activity
and that's incredibly helpful to the
cause because we're we're helping
generate a conversation that I mean can
look for patterns of inconsistent
see and help make the case to Mark
Zuckerberg that look this needs to be
addressed because we are just lost here
we can't follow any double roles so I
think having a what having community
support is essential to advancing this
so I hope anyone out there would you
know tag me on Instagram with a post you
can see an me on Facebook or Instagram
with these examples and especially on
him on my Instagram at rise above social
you'll see examples people reach out to
me and someone got shut down and I like
to profile that because it's not about
rise above social is about the community
and these small businesses that are
taking a hit because of this
inconsistent policy we're gonna take a
short break and be right back you are
listening to shaving fire look inside
this crystal ball with me for a moment
I'm looking just a couple months into
the future I'm seeing the future of the
shaping fired podcast the show sure has
grown I've continued to interview
fascinating cannabis industry luminaries
and our audience has gotten huge it has
doubled and redoubled and doubled again
there are high fives all around the
shaping fire world headquarters new
listeners are subscribing everyday and
begin to listen to the back catalogue of
all the great interviews there and that
is where the shaping fire audience
learns about your company you were
incredibly smart today to become an
early adopter and place a commercial in
shaping fires early episodes if you
become an advertiser on the shaping fire
podcast now today you are going to pay a
fraction of the cost will be asking in
just two months and yet all the audience
that listens to our back catalogue of
interviews will hear about your company
again and again it's a great deal for
you pay a small amount now because the
show is so new but take advantage of the
huge listening audience we will have
forever this crystal ball is not a smoke
dream do yourself a solid and contact us
today for rates on podcast and
newsletter advertising email hot spot at
shaping fire calm to find out more
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire I am your
Shengo lowson our guest this week is
Lauren Gibbs of rise above social
strategies so before the break you know
we have kind of brought this to a
crescendo you know there are cannabis
companies that are getting their pages
yanked from them and going back to their
first like again and there's there's
advocacy at both the state and federal
level that's being shut down and no one
knows why because there's no shared
guidelines and we all just assume that
is because the Facebook and Instagram
lawyers are playing very serious defense
well I know that since you started the
end the social canna ban you've taken
this up as an activist yourself but you
probably see what our paths would look
like to get their attention how do we
get this change Lauren well there's one
thing that Mark Zuckerberg certainly
pays attention to and it's community
metrics so when things get shared in a
phenomenal way that that Garner's
attention from from facebook and if we
can increase the organic reach meaning
the unpaid reach of all of my messages
for this campaign we can help get
attention from him because all we want
is for him to have a conversation with
us and I'd like to be able to speak to
Facebook and Mark Zuckerberg about the
ways that this inconsistent policy is
affecting focuses and advocates and we
just want to have that conversation so
individuals can be very helpful to that
by helping share these posts tagged us
and examples of censorship share our
posts for had the word all every like
share comment counts so so when you're
saying sharing you're talking about
specifically sharing posts that include
the hashtag and the social canavan are
you talking about just sharing posts
from one of your social media profiles
so that so that the profile gets more
attention what specifically do you want
people to share to increase the metrics
so that Zuckerberg pays more attention
I think telling your own story with the
hashtag is important and so if you have
experienced censorship yourself I really
want to hear your story how that
affected you and your business and add
the end of social canavan hashtag so
that I can track those conversations and
a lot of those conversations and stories
are going to be worth highlighting so
when you use the hashtag that allows me
especially on Instagram that allows me
to track that conversation and find
those stories and share them lift them
up and give them a larger platform
especially you know after or they may
have been blocked from their twelve
thousand followers and they're starting
with five followers it's hard for them
to get that story out but tagged me and
I'll help you get that story out but
then on Facebook you know I post a lot
of educational content about why this
matters examples of the censorship
examples of censorship in other areas
and sharing those posts is is important
because it helps everyone educate their
own personal networks about why this is
important because the more people that
care the more likely we are to bring
about change do we have any examples of
this happening with another industry or
community has anybody ever you know
pushed and engaged Facebook because
outside what's an example of somebody
who won doing this yeah well you know
Facebook used to censor photos of women
breastfeeding and they would get flagged
from nudity and there was a grassroots
movement on this where women changed
their profile their public profile
pictures to the photo of them
breastfeeding their child and it got a
lot of attention and Facebook actually
changed their policy on nudity such that
you that photos of breastfeeding and
post-mastectomy surgical photos are
allowed so it happened they listened to
a community and there was change and we
just want to be next that seems like a
pretty reasonable requests especially
since you're not necessarily demanding a
change in the policy here you're asking
for a conversation to figure out what
the policy even is absolutely so you
know you mentioned a couple times during
our talk that there are people
who have had their pages spiked or taken
away but then they've gotten them back
so so let's say that we've got a
business owner or an advocate who's
listening and and sometimes soon they
their page is gone and it says because
they're they're violating guidelines
what what what should they do to try to
get their page back well honestly it's a
whack Amole situation I would say file
an appeal but is probably going to end
up in purgatory what most businesses do
is they just set up another account and
start over and you may hear in a couple
months they you know a response to your
appeal and your pages back up and then
you have the problem with having to
reconcile to Instagram accounts yeah and
that's something that's having a coral
reefer several times she said several
accounts shut down after over a hundred
thousand followers and she pops up
another one and you know pick up fifteen
thousand in a couple weeks and then she
gets a notice later that her page was
restored she's like well I was just
spent all the time cultivating in your
community over error and now I get this
back so it's it's a mess it is just a
mess as a waste of resources for so many
businesses so it doesn't sound like
there's actually an elegant solution if
you if your page gets dropped your just
hosed there really isn't a way to appeal
that is timely and you know as as
business people are advocates we just
have to keep on moving forward so and it
doesn't sound like there's really any
way to to stay on their good side I mean
if you are in cannabis in any way and
even reporting cannabis news you could
end up being a target gosh that's
frustrating right and there's a lotta
there's a lot of folks out there and I
know some other social media folks will
advise you know to avoid the use of
certain keywords but even that is not
always a foolproof plan so
before we wrap up you know one of the
important things is for everybody in the
scene to be you know motivated an
activist right a lot of people are
starting to think all you know you know
cannabis is legal in my state and so
people are starting to shift more
towards the business side then the
advocacy side but you know most of the
country is still not legal even if they
are moving towards normalization and so
we as as cannabis enthusiasts all need
to raise our hand to be proud of what
we're involved with and to make our
voice heard so what do you say is the
best the best actions that an individual
person can do to make their voice heard
and to feed you situations that you can
use in building a case for for evolving
these guidelines well what individuals
can absolutely do is share these stories
with me so again sending those screen
grabs of your original post and your
denial notification by DM to me on
facebook or instagram is incredibly
helpful now you know I have been talking
openly to Mark Zuckerberg for a long
time now and I haven't gotten a response
yet so I can't guarantee to anyone that
is actually going to cause reversal but
by contributing their story to what what
I'm doing it's going to help elevate and
we need points of evidence to make this
case for them to pay attention and have
this dialogue with us because it's it's
all hidden right now and if they can
share that information with me and these
stories we can we can have a more
informed dialogue one thing we've all
learned is that crowdsource
crowdsourcing money or ideas or
political influence it's it's the way of
the future you know they the big
corporations can ignore individuals and
even small groups but when we band
together we've got a voice that that
they have to listen to absolutely and
that is that is the point of social
media that's what I love about it that's
what's so beautiful you can make the
kind of impact that you never could make
in the past because
you can spread things and share things
so quickly with your network it's
wonderful so we're that's why I want to
use this platform to change this
situation I love that let's work
together to make this change so Lauren
what can businesses do to be supportive
of this into to help pressure facebook
for guidelines without putting
themselves at too much risk well there
is an inherent risk every day when
you're operating on social media and
cannabis you can get shut down at any
time so accepting that it's just part of
operating in cannabis business on social
media but I invite business owners to be
a part of this message and you know when
I approached Willie's reserved about
supporting the end of social canavan you
know we discussed that that this is
something that could bring some
additional attention from facebook and
instagram to their accounts and
ultimately the answer came down that
they follow the guideline what would
really do and Willie always you know
stands up for what he thinks is right
enjoyed the cause even if it's not
popular even if it's risky so only by
joining our voices together as business
owners can we really make a powerful
statement so I'm so happy to have you
know companies like Willie's reserve on
board supportive of this important
conversation well thank you lauren for
being on the show you can find out more
about Lauren Gibbs at her website rise
above social calm and also look to her
Facebook and Instagram pages for her
latest updates you can find link to all
her social media at rise above social
calm thanks for being on the show Lauren
you can find