[Music]
we are passionate people if you weren't
passionate you probably wouldn't be
listening to this podcast and passionate
people get excited and when I get
excited sometimes I want to do all the
things I want to do everything at once I
don't want to leave anything out I want
to have all the
experiences and usually that works out
for me life can be great like that and
often it can be exhausting and sometimes
I screw stuff up because I'm trying to
do too much at the same time today's
episode is about how to build your
regeneratively minded cannabis farm with
balance it's about building your soil
without blowing up the farm it's about
staying busy without going crazy and
it's about building sustainable future
without being your own
bully if you want to learn about
cannabis Health cultivation and
technique efficiently and with good
cheer I encourage you to subscribe to
our newsletter we'll send you new
podcast episodes as they come out
delivered right here inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week and
videos too don't rely on social media to
let you know when a new episode is
published sign up for the updates to
make sure you don't miss an
episode also we're giving away very cool
prizes to folks who are signed up to
receive the newsletter this month's
giveaway sponsor is fish poop brand fish
poop fish poop fertilizer feeds plants
and microbes and improves soil structure
with Rich organic matter
it contains available nutrients for the
quick feed and undigested organic
material for slow release with a wealth
of beneficial
organisms five lucky winners will
receive a whole gallon of fish poop
along with some fish poop swag so go to
shaping fire.com to sign up for the
newsletter and be entered into this
month's and all future newsletter prize
drawings also it is true that I've been
away for a minute thanks for the
messages from the folks who are checking
on me my father passed away last month
and I was off the farm and back home in
Michigan helping with his end of life
preparations I'm back now and back at it
so thanks for your
patience you are listening to shaping
fire and I'm your host Shango Los
welcome to episode
114 my guest today is Daniel Stein
Daniel Stein was born in Humble County
and grew up in Hawaii he went to college
first for engineering and then for soils
forestry and eventually environmental
science he started farming vegetables
and cannabis in Hawaii doing lettuce
farming and permaculture installations
while caretaking a citrus and avocado
Orchard in the jungle on land that was
part of Terrence McKenna's
ethnobotanical Gardens in fact Daniel
returned to the home in humbold where he
was born and started gardening and
farming in 2000 in 2010 he met his wife
Taylor and they became bryceland Forest
Farm they started selling vegetables at
farmers markets in 2011 in 2016 they
entered the regulated cannabis Market in
in 2017 bryceland Forest Farm won the
regenerative cannabis farm award that
was a great year at Emerald cup nowadays
they grow about 3/4 of an acre of
vegetables 5,000 ft of cannabis and a
small Orchard and perennial garden all
low or no
till today we're going to use Daniel's
parcel as an example of how to approach
growing regeneratively on your own new
parcel or transitioning from petroleum
and salt fertilizers to regenerative
growing the lessons learned from his
parcel can likely be transferred to
yours as well during the first set we'll
talk about assessing your property for
cannabis cultivation building soil and
choosing cover crops and companion
plants for cannabis in the second set we
will discuss water sequestration animal
husbandry and animal fertilizers and if
crop rotation applies to cannabis and we
finished the episode considering
controlled fire burs long-term research
opportunities and the economics of
growing cannabis regeneratively welcome
to shaping fire Daniel
oh happy to be here thank you so much
for giving us some of your time on a on
a busy midweek Tuesday during the Spring
I know that you have got to be totally
busy on the farm right now getting
everything in place for the summer crops
absolutely but it it's really nice to
have the excuse and opportunity to sit
down for a minute excellent fantastic um
uh I like that you have set up Outdoors
um I think this is the first time I've
ever had somebody set up Outdoors so so
you dear listener can enjoy the uh the
the birds of humble during the interview
and I can too excellent so let's get
right into it so you know um I
understand that when you arrived on your
property you knew you had a lot to do to
make your property into a functional
farm and and I think that's the case
with a lot of new
homesteaders what were the biggest
concerns or projects that you knew you
needed to address first off in order to
build out your
farm so I I mean on a homestead level
the first thing was making sure I had a
place to stay but but on on the the land
level the the property had been um
unmaintained for quite a long time so in
terms of gardening the first thing I had
to do is reclear the space where we're
in a forest environment and the forest
had had re- encroached a lot of tree
seedlings uh Himalaya Blackberry white
Thorn various plants that that had re
encroached on on historic Garden spaces
so my first order business was was to
get to clear
some burning some chipping when I could
borrow a chipper I had very little
resources at the time and then um for
cultivating cannabis which which I was
really excited to do here um was
building a greenhouse when I came back
onto the property uh it was 2000 and uh
we were in the 215 days where it was
vague what what the legality was but if
you hid it in a greenhouse where they
couldn't see it and get a warrant you
were you were pretty safe safe so
clearing enough space building a
greenhouse and then as I started to
build out the garden as it was cleared
my next order of business was getting a
soil test so I I knew what I was dealing
with and knew my approach to bringing
that soil and that gardening space to a
place where it was productive again
right on I want to hit on a couple of
those let's let's start with the
clearing so um I don't have a big parcel
my my farm is pretty small it's actually
more like a homestead with a big garden
and um you know I know that when it gets
right down to it if I want to clear
something and want it to be if I want it
to stay clear I need to clear it down to
the roots um it sounds like you've done
a lot of clearing for people who are new
to their property and they they need to
clear things um like uh like Scotch
broom where I live which is absolutely
heinous um um did you learn any tricks
about clearing that that you would
recommend to somebody who is new at
clearing um do it while you're young
um scotch broom specifically there's
great tools for that and and some of
those tools like a weed wrench and and
various tools that are specifically for
for small Woody things under under an
inch diameter stems that give you
leverage to pull things out are
wonderful they work somewhat for
Blackberry one of the things I've
learned in Land Development is it's
really worth just doing it right from
the start you know I didn't have a lot
of resources at the time I was doing
this it would have been worth it to hire
a a mini excavator or rent one and and
just just get it done from the start do
that land disturbance early on on land
that you're already transitioning from
one thing to another where the
disturbance won't make as big of an
impact do the disturbance and then heal
the disturbance with with kind of the
new paradigm of of of a different uh
uh
biological uh pattern happening I like
the suggestion that you're making that
like you know as regenerative Farmers
we're looking to do in most cases as
little disturbance as possible but you
weigh that realistically over time and
over the fact that you needed to be able
to get in your crops in order to make
the revenue to sustain the farm so
you're like all right well I I can
either do some you know careful
disturbance now and and then come right
behind it with a lot of healing or I can
wait and do it the slow way all by hand
and then potentially miss the season
which also will not be good for the farm
and so you you really Wade the type of
disturbance that you're going to do and
I think that Clarity is important well
and even in the long term like there's
the heavy-handed disturbance of of U
bringing Machinery onto the land but
then if you have say small diameter of
foot to 18in diameter trees and you
don't get the roots out you will be
coming back in with a chainsaw depending
on the species of trees and and burning
fuel and using oil again and again and
again um to keep that held back so it's
like uh you know more upfront and then
and then um the lack of disturbance or a
continuous disturbance to maintain that
project you know a lot I it you're your
experience of getting on the property
and then uh first off needing to uh get
a greenhouse going is that's a pretty
typical experience and um I've I've
talked to different farmers and and I
enjoy hearing um how they decided where
to place their greenhouse because on
some properties it's obvious right you
put it in the one place that gets the
most Sun but if if you've got things
like you know um uh seasonal Sun changes
or or sun is available everywhere on the
property um there can be a lot of
competing um uh reasons to of placement
uh how did you come to the decision of
where to put your
Greenhouse uh well
um you know I would have loved to have
been on the land for 5 years before I
made any
infrastructure commitments you know to
to kind of see the pattern of things and
and one piece of advice I would give to
new homes
is really to to think about if you can
make infrastructure that's functional
but not permanent in the early part of
homesteading so like if you do put your
Greenhouse somewhere where it makes
sense when you first do it but then it
makes less sense as time goes on you can
take it apart and move it to somewhere
new um but yeah I I've seen a lot of of
Land Development especially around
cannabis growing make mistakes as far
as that that desire to get in your cash
crop in the first season makes you rush
and make kind of the decisions that you
can pull off rather than the decisions
you want to see in the long term um and
and there's no way around that to some
extent but um I I'm kind of wandering
off I forgot the the aim of the question
at first that's that's all right you
know I think that you make a good point
that the first step on the new parcel is
not to dig uh the first step on the new
parcel is to put down your chair in the
middle of the of the of the area and
look at it with notes and and and really
like think and dream and plan before you
dive into making things and um uh that
planning part you don't want to short
shrift because you know it kind of
reminds me of you know uh the whole
measure twice cut once idea EXA you
really don't want to build the
greenhouse and then have to move the
greenhouse in the same season it's
really better to spend a little bit of
time that you think you might be able to
might should be doing something else and
and really plan out what you're going to
do for the season there I I can't even
count the number of times I I've
confidently made a design or a decision
about something like irrigation ordered
a bunch of parts spent money put it all
together and then realized the areas
where it falls short yeah so a lot of
people um who are coming their property
also have got limited resources like you
did and um they really struggle I have
really struggled on the okay it's it's
my first season and I I need to get
going um I can either do a a fast and
cheap Greenhouse or I can build
something that I'll be proud of and will
last me a long time and and you know
perhaps I can go even later in the
season because if I get an uh an
unexpected snow I'll be able to handle
it you know how how did you weigh that
for yourself the the the wanting to not
waste resources but needing to get
something up but also not having the
resources to just throw money at it and
make something you know make a castle
Greenhouse right out of the bat well I
mean there's a bunch of approaches I I
was very fortunate in that I had access
to a woodmill so I made a wooden
Greenhouse um but since then various
approaches I
there's a lot available online of of
used uh materials you you can get on
Craigslist you can find um galvanized
conduit things like that you can get a a
conduit Bender to to make your own green
houses relatively inexpensively these
days um but the way my first Greenhouse
here I believe I found a a old pile of
used PVC at somebody's in somebody's
yard asked them if they were using it
and made a a quick PVC
hoop and it was the following year where
I had actually had time to f a tree and
Mill it and and build a greenhouse I
like this idea of not only upcycling
your materials in the short term because
that way you can feel a lot easier about
um building a temporary Greenhouse
immediately and then and then as you're
able to collect the higher quality um
materials do that the next season or or
further on um if you're if you're going
to do something short term um it's great
to be able to to get things from from
Neighbors or or shareed online so that
you don't have to spend that money and
you know and also create new plastic
right yeah and absolutely and maybe you
don't need a greenhouse the first year I
mean I did cuz I was hiding plants but
um if you don't use a greenhouse you
start your plants a little bit later it
gives you extra time to prepare your
your outdoor garden and and then you
plant that and you have a crop that you
can use towards building a greenhouse
the the following year I mean uh I I I
can give this advice it hasn't always
been advice I've taken myself um but to
to bite off what you can realistically
chew based on your your budget and your
your time Etc I mean I I have the bad
habit of jumping out of the airplane and
then imagining I can sew the parachute
before I hit the ground but um I I've I
can't say that it's always worked that
well well you know that I think that is
one of the challenges for those of us
who are like you know optimistic
Visionary type folks because um we we
we're always biting off more than we can
chew yeah yeah it it all looks so good
yeah so so let's talk about the the real
star of the farm your soil so um if I
understand the the story um when you got
to the farm it had not actually I mean
it wasn't even really a farm it was it
was a parcel and and the and the soil
had not been cared for in a long time um
you know most of us imagine that the
soil in Humble County is like you know
infused with magic and like good all by
itself was was your soil already good to
go when you arrived or did you know
immediately that you needed to do soil
building um it's actually a combination
because generally the the soil in Humble
County and around here is a very thin C
clay soil as as far as the top soil goes
and and here we have a vein of of really
quality soil in terms of of the soil
structure um the the place we are is
relatively flat and and it has a vein of
aluvial soil where where two Creeks had
come back and forth across and deposited
some soil so so it has a a slightly
Sandy lone strip through part of the
flat area here that being said it was
covered in Brush and was very acidic and
um it it needed a lot of work um so the
first order of business definitely was
testing that and adjusting the the pH to
to bring it back to to
neutral um and then as we expanded the
farm we reached out into more of of the
clay poor soil areas of the farm and and
started working on those soils so as you
um you know once you got the pH back to
neutral from all the all the acidity um
why don't you uh kind of illustrate for
us a couple of the processes that you
did to like build fertility into the
soil um because you know as we know it
takes more than just um you know a good
pH the the soil we want it um uh imbued
with with with microbes and beneficial
bacteria and fungi and and and I'm sure
that you were probably excited about
that part of it cuz because I mean it's
my favorite part because you get to do a
whole bunch of really cool living
projects you know so so why don't why
don't why don't you just kind of like uh
go through some of the the projects like
that that you did um to just increase
the the life force in the soil yeah
absolutely I mean I was relatively Lucky
in that generally unless soil is really
bare you you have a lot of Life Force in
it we we we have a forest soil here so
it is infused with life the the the
challenge here in Humble and in similar
Mediterranean climates is that it gets
so dry during the summer that it it it's
kind of like the winter would be if you
were in Michigan or something where the
the the season that that the life kind
of gets put on hold hold in in that most
active layer of the soil here is in the
summer because it dries out um so a big
part of that for me was developing the
organic matter so that it could hold
moisture a and there could be life there
throughout throughout the season so yeah
a a big part of it was was building a a
stable organic matter in the soil and
and stable organic matter is very
different than Act of breaking down
organic matter both of which you need
the act of breaking down organic matter
is the food for the biology in the soil
the stable organic matter I kind of
think of as the um the
housing it it's it's the buffer it's the
well that that you your plants can draw
from and the place the the pantry if you
will so that is a relatively slow
process one of the early ways I started
putting stable organic matter into the
soil and this is when I had a much
smaller Garden the farm didn't come
until until later was was through
biochar I was doing a lot of of burning
here on the property and learning how to
a as I did um fire safety work and
thinning in the forest learning how to
make burn piles um in a way that
preserved a lot of the charcoal then
soaking that in like a worm casting tea
and then putting that in the soil so
then you have this this repository of of
uh moisture holding and nutrient holding
within the soil and early on I was um
managing the soil with uh a biointensive
style rather than a no till style that's
where you like double dig everything all
the time which was incredibly tiring but
it also really allowed me to to build up
organic matter very very deep in the
soil um I hadn't heard of notil yet I
was I was really excited when I
discovered that about a decade later
you're like oh I'm already doing that
I'm like I I'm I I don't have to dig
everything every year and you know at
that point I I was digging with a shovel
and a fork to be able to do the same
kind of a thing of like keeping soil
structure while air rating um and and
discovering techniques to be able to do
that without as much work was was
mind-blowing to me I didn't understand
it when you first uh suggested that idea
now that I do that must have been a
really fabulous moment when you when you
read a you know a defense of not double
digging and realizing that that perhaps
it was time for that to end all that and
that's particularly backbreaking work
you must have felt like oh I'm free you
know yeah well I it it was amazing
because it kind of came with as we
expanded into being a larger Farm um
Taylor my my wife and I as as we
expanded in to a larger area here on the
property the the first thing we did was
like we well we obviously can't double
dig an acre so we're going we have a
tiller for our tractor we're going to
till and it just felt so wrong and then
we tilled and we were basically
gardening an acre and and we had this
awareness like this we can't Garden this
much we have to learn how to farm and
and farming is a different thing than
gardening a and how can we Farm in a way
that feels like we're taking care of the
soil and and we discovered various
literature about it and discovered
techniques to do that and and become
efficient at the same time as as
becoming better stewards of the the soil
this this idea that that farming is
different than gardening that's a very
provocative statement my my best
understanding of what you're saying
there would be that with with gardening
you're doing things that can be
inefficient because you're not scaled
but when you're scaled to a farm you
have to be far more efficient is that
what you mean by that yeah yeah exactly
um if you're farming um you know
unfortunately you're interacting with
with an economic reality where um you
can't lose money the way you can having
a hobby you know yeah you can have a
hobby where you spend $10 to make a
beautiful heirloom tomato for your
kitchen um that doesn't work if you're
if you're trying to to make a living
selling that tomato so um that's kind of
been the the constant challenge is how
how do you scale in a way that you can
provide food in a environmentally
friendly way in a way that leaves your
land in a better State than you found it
and at the same time is economically
viable um and and it is a kind of a
constant push and pull and and there's
there's no way to do it
perfect we we talk about being
regenerative but really when it comes to
it we're all of us striving towards this
idea of being
regenerative and and it's it's not
something that's easy you you can't um
in in permaculture we talk about a
closed loop system where where the
outputs of your farm become the inputs
of your farm and it's a self-sustaining
ecosystem well that that's a lot harder
when so much of the output of your farm
is leaving your farm never to be
returned so oh so so when you were um
you were describing how uh you were you
were um double dig digging until you
learned about no till because um you
know while while that's while that's an
you know an ancient process it's it's
relatively new to trending again I guess
I'll say um I can imagine that at the
beginning also you were probably doing
things that that we all know as
regenerative farming just because you
had low resources I I was talking with a
guy I never did get his name but um at a
uh at a golden tarp several years ago
and he said he says he says oh I I've
been regenerative farmer my whole life
but when I was young we just called it
being poor and and because like he was
focused on using the materials that are
on the property um and and because he he
he couldn't afford you know the the
fertilizers that you'd get from town in
the same way I want to ask you like you
know you you described how you wanted to
both increase the microbe life but then
also increase the you know what we're
going to call housing or structure that
um that protects and gives
um place for those microbes to
to I want to use the word procreate but
that's not scientifically accurate but
make more incubate them and so what what
were some of the natural inputs that you
found um you know on the parcel or
nearby that you could Wildcraft and put
to work in your soil building it well
early on in building the soil I didn't
really have the awareness of of
wildcrafting input so I think that kind
of the the jadam knf kind of
input um awareness came came to us maybe
10 years ago um early on
I had a lot of wood a lot of wood chips
uh I wasn't doing hugle building with
with large wood partly because I I had
really nice soil and I didn't feel like
I needed to to put wood in the the lower
profile of it to make that work but what
what I did have is a lot of wood chips
for doing
mulching um and although I didn't have
animals myself early on besides um
chicken for eggs and that manure went
back onto the farm um I did have friends
and neighbors who had cows and horses
and and goats and was able to put a lot
of organic matter in the form of manure
and wood chips from from the area onto
the soil and I mean that that really is
like the input you want is is organic
matter especially in a place like
Humbolt the flip side of of what we were
talking about earlier about the the dry
SE and being a time when when microbes
kind of go dormant if if the soil isn't
kept moist and there's not good moisture
holding capacity the flip side of it is
the wet season here is is 80 plus inches
of rain during during the year so if you
don't hold those nutrients somehow they
they wash out all all of the soluble
nutrients so some of the biggest issues
for us over the years have always been
like how do we create nitrogen how do we
hold nitrogen how do we find sulfur how
do we hold sulfur um uh and some of of
the micronutrients and minerals things
that wash out of the soil here just
aren't there unless you find ways to put
them in and to hold them um and the over
the course of gardening here the single
largest way that we've found to build
soil is is through wintertime cover
cropping and and it's it it just is
incredible how much soil you can build
because the winter here when we're not
able to grow crops is is four to six
months of the year so you you're
actually growing a full crop during that
wintertime season entirely just to put
back into the soil and once you start
doing the the noil version of it you're
you're not just putting it back on the
top but all of the roots of those cover
crops get to stay where they are in the
Pathways in the soil that they've opened
up that becomes a porous structure of
the soil and and the exits of the roots
help create kind of a a glue that glues
the soil structure together and then
makes a a porous environment so if you
take a cover crop and you lay the the
the green matter on the top and let that
decompose naturally into the top of the
soil and let the roots decompose down in
the subsoil and in in in the soil deeper
where they are you really quickly build
organic matter deep into the soil that
was a beautiful explanation Daniel that
topnotch yeah I mean like the the engine
for all of it right the engine for
organic matter is photosynthesis and and
to you need to take advantage of the
photosynthesis potential on your garden
soil all the time and it's either you're
you're taking photosynthesis from
another area in the form of straw or hay
or wood chips or even animal manure from
animals that have eaten that and
bringing it to you or you're or and
really not or you're creating
photosynthesis in place and that the the
lovely thing about that is it's so
simple it's there you're not
wheelbarrowing it you're not moving it
around and you can have it um be
nitrogen fixing so that it it also
creates um creates fertility that's
great so so um I want to hit one more
topic or it's actually the same topic
but I want to ask you one more question
before we go to the first commercial
which is um you know the what the
specific over winter cover crop is going
to be um is going to be different
depending on what part of the country
that we live in so so everybody's going
to have their own local plant that tends
to work best for them what I'm curious
to hear you speak to is is number one um
did you choose one cover crop and go
sold with that ever or did you pick a
few different cover crops and and plant
them together for variety and two how
does that crop cover crop fit
into like all of the plants that are on
your property so on your property I'm
assuming that you're going to have these
these seasonal cover crops but then also
you're going to have um uh uh the food
that you're grow growing for market and
then you've got the Cannabis probably in
the greenhouse and outside of it and
then you've got your ornamentals that
you just grow around your property for
fun we we all know as regenerative
Farmers that these plants are all
interacting with each other at a
biological level even even if they're
not planted right next to each other I'd
like to kind of like he hear about like
what was the melody for the different
types of plants that you chose for the
farm um as as you settled in and figured
out what was going to be best for the
farm um I mean we have a a number of
different management strategies that we
have developed and are developing and
will will change over time for for
different goals um how we manage beds
for cannabis is very different than how
we manage beds for lettuce and you know
the big factors are the crop that you're
growing is it a quick turnaround does it
suffer from from competition from Weeds
or does it do fine with that and and
again like we you just said how does it
interact with the plants around it so uh
in our perennial gardens we just do a
lot of deep mulch we have a variety of
plants both for for beauty that we like
for medicinal use for ourselves for
beneficial insects um and then the the
Cannabis is kind of somewhere in between
a perennial garden and an annual Garden
cannabis is such a long-lived annual it
it really plays well with
perennials um and and the way we manage
that tends to be an in between where we
we grow grow a cover crop but we manage
it through crimping and Mulch and and
the edge of the Cannabis beds has has a
a perennial garden of sorts and and that
Garden tends to entirely be
beneficials um for insects that are
Predator insects for cannabis or trap
crops or or things like that um and then
the annual vegetable production
depending on the crop that's going to be
in an area gets a different management
technique and and needs longer to
transition from the wintertime cover
crop to being a a very clean blank bare
slate bed that we can use Cedars or or
transplanting tools on and what I've
really found that I like in terms of
cover crop is doing a cover crop mix and
you can find a mix that that works for
your environment and works for your
needs but but we actually buy a premixed
cover crop that is a combination of of
uh fava
uh vet peas and oats and and what I like
about that is is there's an inherent
intelligence to to plants and their
interaction with their environment and
and
um you find different expressions of
what germinates and what thrives in
different beds in beds that tend to be
low in nitrogen after a year of growing
the crop you've had on it the the
legumes in that cover crop mix really
thrive in beds that have a lot of
nitrogen the the grass really thrives
and it's able to grow a lot before the
heaviness of the winter rains comes and
and hold a lot of that nutrient in its
in its structure versus the legumes
which are building building nutrient
through um its relationship in in its
roots um so so having a mix of cover
crop really helps it thrive in whichever
environment you put it in and that
changes year to year it's not something
I've been able to wrap my head around
predicting what will do well in which
area at which time um the one aspect
we're starting to discover in in the
Cannabis zones especially where we use
crimping as a technique to integrate
cover crop is that the there's a benefit
if you're if you're using crimping as a
technique to having cover crops that
come into flour at the same time cuz
um crimping as a technique really
depends on timing if if you crimp while
a plant is in its most vigorous growth
time it's going to grow right through
that push its way through the mulch you
put on top of it and continue growing
versus if you cover crop um right when a
plant's putting all of its energy into
flowering but hasn't produced seeds yet
it tends to actually be killed by the
crimping technique and start its
decomposition process and so the cover
crop mix we've been using which we've
still used this
season the the oats flour at a later
time than than the vetch and the um the
fava beans so the oats continue to grow
or if I were to wait for the oats to
flour the the fava and the vet will have
already seeded and that could be a
benefit and and I know farmers who are
effectively using already seeded cover
crop and dry farming somewhat so they I
if you're aren't overhead watering say
if you have your irrigation under where
you crimp your cover crop so that after
you do your cover crop it it it kind of
dries out and becomes mulch you can have
a fully seeded cover crop let it dry out
and become mulch your irrigation lines
are under it and then when you get fall
r that causes that to germinate again
and you're already planted in cover crop
oh that's nice yeah and that's that's
theoretical I've heard um some some
really amazing Farmers talk about that
um but I have not tried that you really
got to nail you really got to nail that
time just got to nail that you know and
and and getting it to reced and and all
of that it's something I'd love to
experiment with at some point but but
haven't gotten to yet as it is I'm now
looking for an early earlier
flowering um grain grass that I can mix
in with with my my VCH and and my fava
beans to have them at least come into
fruition at the same time for Effective
crimping you know one thing that is
underlying this this um this philosophy
that you just shared is that when you're
when you're just establishing your farm
is regenerative whether or not you just
got the parcel or if you're switching
from petroleum farming to regenerative
farming um sometimes the first few years
as you're getting your legs under you
it's it's okay to use the same kind of
like off-the-shelf like uh cover crop
mixes and other other things where where
you don't have to reinvent the wheel
like you don't AB you don't have to be
inventing all new farming techniques
your first couple years there's reasons
why um these some of these seed mixes
and and other tools are you know are
things that everybody uses and and so
just you know go ahead and follow the
crowd on some of this stuff until you
get established and you can really uh
fine-tune it for your own particular
parcel well and it and it goes back to
that biting off more than you can chew I
mean I I often still use cover crop
mixes because I don't have the time to
wrap my head around every aspect of the
farm and farmers are doing it especially
now there's so many small farms out
there there there is so much thought
being put into this and therefore there
are a lot of products out there that are
made by Farmers with the thought of of
helping farmers and especially like in
the tool realm and and things like that
that there's a lot available you don't
need to do it all yourself you couldn't
even if you tried and and part of
learning to farm was learning to focus
on what we're good at and and to let
other people do what they're good at and
be collaborative about it right on
that's good those are good words of
advice so all right so let's take a
short break and be right back you're
listening to shaping fire and my guest
today is regenerative farmer Daniel
Stein and you know without these
advertisers shaping fire would not
happen so please support them and let
them know you heard them on shaping
[Music]
fire revenue is tight for cannabis
businesses right now there is no
question about it and when Revenue
tightens businesses need to spend
Smarter on Advertising instead of
throwing obscene money at Hanging your
company's logo from the rafters at your
next convention perhaps consider placing
commercials on shaping fire and if you
are a very small business there is
simply no better bang for your buck than
commercials on shaping fire especially
if your products are for regeneratively
minded
cultivators advertising on this show
allows us time to talk about your
product service or brand in a way that
really lets people know what sets your
company apart from the others bold
people who own companies know that
getting into relationship with their
customers is essential that is what we
offer
we will explain your service or product
what sets it apart as desirable and help
our audience get in contact with you
it's pretty simple really advertising
does not have to be all whizbang smoke
and mirrors nowadays I find that people
prefer just to be spoken to calmly
accurately and with good intentions if
you want to make your own commercial
spot you can do that too with a
commercial on shaping fire you'll reach
your customers in the privacy of their
headphones right now and will continue
to reach new listeners as they explore
the shaping fire back catalog of
episodes again and again for years a
spot on shaping fire costs less than a
postcard per person and the shaping fire
audience is full of smart cannabis
enthusiasts cultivators and
entrepreneurs who are always curious to
learn and right now in the New Year We
are booking the few open spots we have
for the rest of
2024 I'd love for you to be one of our
new
advertisers do yourself a solid and
contact us today for rates on podcast
and Instagram advertising email hotspot
shaping fire.com to find out
[Music]
more fish poop brand fertilizer is an
allnatural fish poop concentrate with
nothing added real fish poop is
extraordinarily complex not only are you
adding the nitrogen phosphorus and
pottassium your plants need to build
mass transport nutrients enhance flavor
but fish waste is also packed with
biological activity and micronutrients
when you add fish poop to your
irrigation water you are adding life
force probiotics and active microbes
these microorganisms include a wealth of
various bacteria and protozoa which
further enhance nutrient availability
for the plants because plants are
limited by the absence of any essential
micronutrient these Trace nutrients are
the difference between having a decent
garden and having a garden that makes
you feel really proud of your efforts
fish poop is a naturally complete Sol
solution that fills in the cracks in
your fertilizer program to ensure you
offer your garden a broad base of
nutrients not all fish poop is created
equally most products with added fish
waste don't reveal their sources or lab
results fish poop brand fish poop
however generates their own fish waste
as a byproduct of their organic
aquaponic cannabis farm where they raise
ornamental koi and tilapia you are even
invited to tour their Farm in person or
on their YouTube channel to look for
yourself this sort of transparency is
wildly rare in the fertilizer Market the
folks behind fish poop are also lifelong
medical cannabis producers who have deep
Connections in the community donate more
product than they sell and support
cannabis prisoner veteran and patient
collectives and Charities to get your
bottle of pure fish poop go to fish
poop.com and to see their entire line of
cannabis products go to ounce of
hope.com that's fish poop brand brand
fish
[Music]
poop this message is for folks who grow
cannabis I'm talking to homeg Growers
patients and Commercial Growers too I'm
probably talking to you when you plan
out your next growing cycle be sure to
check out humble CSI seeds at humble
csi.com Caleb inspecta and his family
have lived in Humble County for over a
hundred years for the last 40 years
three generations of his family have
cultivated extraordinary sensome at
cannabis and humble mesino and Trinity
counties because of his lineage and the
hard-earned experience that comes from
growing up smoking and sifting large
populations of cannabis plants in
Northern California the seeds you'll cop
from CSI will be winning genetics based
on longtime Heavy Hitters and updated
and re sifted to bring out new and
exotic traits and better yields go ahead
and ask around Caleb also known as
inspecta and pirates of the Emerald
Triangle is a breeders breeder he
reaches way back and works with
significant strains recreating them in
new and interesting ways that you'll
love as a toker and a grower as well as
offering you some surprises that will
Delight serious seed Traders and
cultivators humble CSI goes a further
step and selfs all these kimars so you
know all the seeds will be female these
are not experimental feminized seeds
humbold CSI releases some of the best
female seeds available anywhere and it
will show in your garden folks grew
quite a bit of Cs SI humble Gen X last
year here on Vashon Island and everyone
was pleased the patients had beautiful
female plans and didn't have to call
half of their Garden as males the folks
growing for the fun of getting high grew
colorful flowers with exceptional bag
appeal and great highs and breeders had
seven out of seven females in a pack
which gave them a lot of phenotypic
choices take a moment right now and
visit humbled csi.com you'll find an
up-to-date menu of both feminized
regular lines along with photos and
descriptions that's humbled
csi.com
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire I'm your host Shango Los
and my guest today is regenerative
farmer Daniel Stein so before the break
we were talking about the the initial
things to do or at least considerations
as you are uh setting up your farm to
become regenerative rather or not
whether you are a post petroleum or if
it's just your first time on the
property now one of the things that
Daniel hit on was that um you know if
you're building up all this soil you
don't want it all to get washed away and
so that's what we're going to start with
Daniel you know water retention is
really important you know across the
country but especially where you live
because you like I we have this this
drought portion of the summer and um and
there's lots of there's lots of laws
rurally about what you can and can't do
with water and if you find yourself
without out water and you're far out
like you are off grid it's not like you
can just turn on the faucet and then
suddenly there it is um absolutely and
you also mentioned that um you know not
only do you want to retain the water but
you also need to control the flow of
water so that the water doesn't take
away all the nutrients that you're
putting in all this effort building into
the soil so I'd like you to talk through
um yeah let's you know for certain use
your property as example but I'd like
you to talk about it more theoretically
so it so it applies to many people's
Farms talk about water retention meaning
how how you can sequester the water on
your property strategies to do that so
the water stays and then second how you
control the flow so that it doesn't wash
all the good hard work you've done
away yeah well there there's a number of
strategies and it really depends on on
your individual situation needs and and
what your go for for your farm I mean
the answer to so many of of the issues
is organic matter organic matter is how
you can hold water like a sponge it's
how you can hold nutrients it's how you
can you can buffer High rainfall High
Water Events um it it's it's the answer
to so much when it comes to to farming
um and then in in terms of of water flow
if you're trying if your site doesn't
get enough water retention throughout
the season the main thing you want to do
is is get more water to
it and and so doing things like swales
where where you slow down the water
coming across your property and get it
to go into into your system help that
and that's in in my environment that's
not something I've ever really had to do
with a in of rain everything that can
get saturated gets saturated without the
help of bringing more water into it and
as a matter of fact doing swales is is
something you have to be careful about
because if you super saturate areas you
can deal with with landslides if it's in
the wrong wrong kind of an area um we do
use some of those techniques less about
retaining water and more about slowing
water down in areas that we have
plantings that can uptake some of those
nutrients that that would flow out with
water
um so low on our property we have some
swes that are are planted in in comrey
and other things that are deep rooted so
it can slow any water down and and we
can hopefully remove a lot of the
nutrients that would be flowing out with
that water and turn them back into plant
material that we can Harvest and bring
up to to the top of the system again uh
but it definitely is organic matter
organic matter is the sponge it it
reduces water speed flowing through
sandy soil it increases the drainage
capacity of clay soil it it brings
everything into balance I believe this
next question you just answered and it's
going to be organic material but I'm
going to ask it anyway because a lot of
people run into it you know a lot of
parts of the country and and it's
probably even going to become more
common to have a drought period during
the summer and when that happens you
know the the top soil gets um you know
Dusty and and in many places it getss
hydrophobic so that when the rain does
start um it doesn't immediately go into
the into the top soil and it and it runs
and and so people really rely on on
these uh permaculture Solutions like
swales um to to guide it and to and to
also slow it down do you find like the
question is what do you what strategy do
you most like to uh fight the like hood
of um hydrophobic soil so that when the
rains first start for the year um you
don't lose a lot of important soil and
soil chemistry before the soil opens
up well mulch being kind of the best
when it when it's something that you can
work with like if if you're in a
cropping system where you can do a heavy
mulch if you can afford to either bring
a quality straw on or use wood chips for
mulch that will break up the water it'll
slow it down um that works for much of
our farm for a lot of the the vegetable
side of it you know we you can't mulch
around radishes that are in the ground
for four weeks and then pull the mulch
and replant each time so we do have a
lot of beds that that end up being
relatively bare soil even though there
there's cover crop planted in them that
will sprout quickly after the first
rains uh one of the main things we do
for that where we don't we don't have
control of it through something on the
surface of the soil is making sure that
all of our beds are on Contour so in a
way they act like swales so our beds are
on contour and even though we don't have
much of a slope um the they're on
contour and they're slightly raised
above the pathways so that if we do lose
any soil from erosion it goes into the
pathways
and then every couple years we we come
through and we put the the the soil and
and broken down wood chip mulch and
various things that have built up in the
pathways back on top of the beds and it
acts like a a another kind of a boost it
it's like putting compost on top of the
beds MH so earlier you mentioned uh trap
plants and um uh in addition to that and
and and perhaps you can explain the kind
of trap plants that you like um how do
you manage pests on your
property um well different pests
different ways I
mean there there are pests that we can
manage effectively through encouraging
the Natural Balance and then there are
pests that come out of balance um pests
that we can deal with
effectively through the Natural Balance
we we encourage uh plants that are are
uh an ecosystem an environment that
encourages natural predators and often
for us those are are umbles things like
Queen Ann's lace
sisum um various flowers um one thing
that I I a lot of people don't don't
realize is that
the the stage of of much of many of the
Predators that attack pest say if it's
aphids or thrips or something like that
a lot of the Predators that attack those
pests are the larval stage of of the
predator and that the adult stage that
you need to have around in order to lay
the eggs in the right place to have the
larval stage eat nectar and pollen from
specific plants so so when you talk
about beneficial plants it's all often
you're providing the food in the
environment for the adult stage of of a
beneficial insect that will then go lay
its eggs in aphid bodies or lay larvae
that then crawl around on the plant and
and eat thrips um things like that um
the the Trap crops are are interesting
because the idea of a trap crop is
having having a plant that your pests
desire more than your cash crop and one
of the main ones we use in our cannabis
is is actually catnip works really well
for mites mites seem to prefer catnip
over cannabis any day of the week and
and it provides an environment so if we
do have something out of balance we can
if we're using beneficial insects we can
release the beneficial insects into the
Trap crop where there's a a large
population
of of the pest and they can eat the pest
they can breed and then they can Branch
out from there where I if you're if
you're buying an expensive beneficial
insect and putting it on say a cannabis
plant that has
a a smattering of a pest not not to an
epidemic proportion you're wasting a lot
of a lot of that insect they'll they'll
mostly die off of starvation if they
can't find their
food I I like this idea and that is
common in regenerative agriculture that
that these pests are usually coming
because the garden is uh out of balance
and it's it swings one way or another
too dry too wet to to to whatever and
and and when it's out of balance it
creates opportunities for certain pests
to expand and then you've got a problem
and um I think it's really fun because
when I tour regenerative Farms there's
there's just such a diversity of plants
right it's it's it's it's the complete
opposite of a monoculture yeah of course
we've got we've got these you know
fields of cannabis but then you've got
you know you know all these smaller
plants and then and then cover crops and
then uh ornamentals that are just pretty
for the farm and and they're all growing
and then in the summer which is normally
when I do my tours they're all flowering
and gorgeous and they smell good and you
can you can feel the balance of the farm
and and I I think that the the number
one solution for pests on regenerative
Farms is just to grow a lot and a lot of
variety because I certainly have got
great uh results from adding beneficial
insects as well but but you're you're
speaking the truth man when you when you
say that if if you if you're if your
garden isn't already out of balance
there might not be enough food for the
beneficial insects to keep them going
and so it's really going to be better
for you to instead of of spot trying to
fix a problem really focus on the
biological diversity and the flowering
and plant diversity so that um the
plants that you want they choose to come
to your farm and they choose to do their
life cycle on your farm and then you can
save some money on the Biologicals like
beneficial insects um for when you
actually have a problem and and you need
some first aid yeah and abs absolutely
and even even there within that our farm
isn't an island it it is in a greater
environment and so as we've seen more
proliferation of large cannabis Farms as
we've had to move towards using clones
things like that more more pests become
an issue like the the hemp aphid did not
exist for us in any way many years ago
and never would have if we didn't have
some large cannabis farms in our area
that proliferated them um and that that
particular pest poses a unique problem
because our the way our environment will
is bringing that pest into balance is
through a number of predators but one of
the primary ones is the surfed fly uh or
hoverfly and they're those little things
that kind of look like bees but they're
shaped like flies if you've ever seen
them for sure and and they're
wonderful the the issue is the the hemp
Aid comes late in the season during
budding often or early budding
and the surfit Flies follow them and the
way the surfit
fly um feeds on on the aphid is by by
laying eggs which hatch and develop into
larvae which then crawl around and or
squirm around they kind of look like
maggots and and eat aphids and aphid
eggs now the issue with that is it is
bringing it into balance and it is
getting rid of the aphids often times
there's no aphids left in on on Plants
where where the surfit flies have worked
but they also leave eggs and larvae
inside of buds so the the most extreme
version of this is um a number of years
ago um I knew of a jar brand and and the
the surfit fly larvae will remain
dormant at certain temperatures but then
develop at room temperature over the
course of two weeks so there was a a
Jarred brand that that had organic
regenerative cannabis in it and because
it was organic and there were aphids
there was Surfin fly larvae that had
once it was put on the Shelf in the
dispensary at room temperature had
hatched and become flies inside of the
jar oh makes for bad branding yeah
that's a really bad brand experience for
sure so that that particular balance
does not work for us we
can't
encourage surfed flies as the answer for
aphids even though our natural
environment wants that to be the
balance um so we do have to work with
with beneficial insects to control the
aphids early on so that we don't have
what is essentially a beneficial insect
um hurt the the quality of our flower
down the line wow that's really
thoughtful um not only so so the so the
aphids are the original Pest and the
surfit Flies are the original beneficial
but due to the nature of the surfit
Flies the surfit Flies actually becomes
a pest because of their larvae in the
flowers and so actually you need a
thirdparty outside beneficial insect
that will take out the aphids before the
aphids get so significant that they
attract the surfit Flies yeah and so we
do introduce Green Lace Wing which are
natural here but never seem to build up
enough of a natural population fast
enough to deal with the the hemp aphid
which doesn't exist here naturally along
with cannabis which also doesn't exist
here naturally so it makes sense that
that it it is sometimes hard for the
natural system to come into balance with
these essentially exotic plants um they
the the the lace Wing isn't able to
build up a population quick enough to
deal with just the incredibly rapid rate
at which um hemp AIDS
proliferate wow so um and hemp bavid do
like there's it comes to variety there
there's there's strains that they seem
to like no matter how healthy they are
that there's something about them they
like and they're strange they don't seem
to like and and not
all often times it is there is an
imbalance in the farm that causes a pest
to to like something but there there's
often times pests that that do really
well uh um attacking plants and and it
might not be that the plants out of
balance it might just be that that plant
has not developed with a resistance to
that particular pest because they known
each other long enough I that makes
sense especially with you know some of
these uh the the the newer strains that
that that are like a far cry away from
uh land races sometimes sometimes they
just so they just don't have that depth
of uh of genetic protection no they've
they've never seen the sun even much l
they've never been outside of indoor
yeah um so let's let's uh shift gears to
um uh to animals on the property um so
far uh you have mentioned uh chickens as
far as animal husbandry goes and and
using uh manure from Neighbors Farms but
that that was way in the beginning so so
so now that you are more established
perhaps you have other animals too but
but whether whether the animals are
yours or whether you're bringing them
from elsewhere um speak a little bit if
you would to um how uh animal um inputs
if you will uh whether it's their manure
or their their their body uh how how
those are being incorporated into the
cycle on your farm yeah absolutely well
I mean number one it's the the
relationship with humans and animals and
farming it all kind of evolve together
right and the the way I see it is
animals have developed incredible
microbiomes um to be able to digest and
process raw rough food and come out with
a fertilizer
basically so goats are the the primary
large animal we have on our farm and our
goats free roam a large area around our
Homestead they're not fenced in our
Homestead is fenced and and the goats
have everything else um and what they do
is is they gather food they they go
around they they eat a a wide variety of
food they they come back to the barn
three times a day and where they pee and
they poop and and they they make a
incredible compost that we can gather
and and add to our intentional compost
piles every year and it's another way
besides wood ships which are very slow
slow to degrade and and don't have a lot
of nutritive value in terms of um in
terms of
macronutrients um it's another way for
us to to gather biomass from our
surrounding area bring it here onto our
farm and process it into kind of a a
super fertilizer
um and and an inoculant of microbiology
I want to I want to poke at that bit did
you did you really mean to suggest that
the that the goats come back to the farm
to poop and that they they don't just
drop it wherever they are walking around
they absolutely drop it wherever they
are walking around okay no no so they
they come back to the barn they're
they're always pooping right on okay I
was going to I was going to say this a
lot of their poop ends up in the barn
what they do is they'll roam around and
then they'll come back and Loaf and hang
out at the barn and drink water and
during that time they're continuing to
poop all right great the way I heard it
I'm like do they come back to the barn
as a toilet I've never heard that about
goats but but now we're really
developing our our animal training like
bring don't pee not yet no you hold it
till you get back to the barn all right
I I understand more clearly now they're
just they're just always pooping and and
they naturally come back to the barn for
shelter and water and they drop a load
there too yeah good um so do when when
you bring in manure from another
property um how suspicious are you of
that manure like like how much do you
want to know about those animals before
you're willing to bring the manure onto
your property you you want to know a lot
um you know early on I brought horse
manure on and and there's a couple
aspects with horse manure horses are
basically pets to a lot of people most
people worm their horses
continuously and um so wormer horses
things kind of pass straight through
horses so if somebody's giving their
horse horse wormer you basically have
wormer in the manure yeah so you want to
ask those kinds of questions are your
horses being fed any medication another
aspect with horse manure is because
things pass through horses um something
about the way they process you they they
don't process a lot of magnesium so
horse manure is high in magnesium that
will build up over time if that's the
one manure you're using and you'll get
an imbalance between the calcium and
magnesium in your soil um right now one
of our primary manure inputs is from an
organic Dairy where we we get probably
40 to 50 yards of of dairy manure solids
from an organic Dairy which is wonderful
it it's great material um one of the
challenges with that is that they they
dust the feeding stalls in the barn so
so the way that works is is the the cows
get milked they go to to a large barn
with feeding stalls and then they go
back out to pasture and while they poop
in the feeding stalls that gets washed
in into uh a trough where the solids are
separated from the liquids we get the
solids the liquids get watered back out
onto pasture but they dust down those
feeding stalls with wood ash so now that
we've been using that manure for while
we're starting to see an intense buildup
of potassium salts from the wood ash and
so we're having to manage this this
great um biomass that we're able to get
at at a good price um delivered to us
with dealing with potassium
toxicity as as a potential outcome of
that if we don't manage it properly what
does management of that look like that's
a pretty exotic concern for me um it's
actually surpris surprisingly common
with a lot of of heavy compost
applications and especially manure
applications um but the the way it works
for us is we just make sure we age the
compost really well and we don't add
pottassium in any other facets it's like
we used to add potassium in our
amendments to our farm and we just don't
do that anymore we make sure that
doesn't happen and if we see signs
um I believe one of one of the aspects
of potassium
toxicity is a A reduced uptake of
Manganese I believe it is and a reduced
uptake of Manganese during the first few
weeks of of a flower cycle on cannabis
could cause really small buds especially
at the top so when you see like larger
buds lower down on your flowering stock
and as it comes towards what should be
the nice top Cola on a stock it kind of
flattens out
and and stops developing into a larger
Bud that could often be a manganese
toxic a lack of Manganese which either
could be a pottassium toxicity it also
could be the manganese uptake didn't
happen because the temperatures were too
low for the uptake for that particular
strain during its first few weeks of
flowering a few things like that but but
it's like paying close attention to to
what we're seeing on on the the growing
end of it and seeing if we're seeing
those effects right on so we've been
we've been talking a lot about specifics
I want to I want to pull back our Focus
for a minute um and and kind of give you
an opportunity maybe for a little bit of
Storytelling because if we go back to
you know where we are now in talking
about your about your farm and using it
as as an example Farm um you've got very
uh sophisticated and and experiencer
solutions whereas at the beginning of
the show we were talking about your very
very young and immature Farm where when
and when you had no money and like doing
the best you can with what you've got
and so we know that over the last 25ish
years your your experience has been
increasing and the Farm's depth has been
increasing and which sets us up for this
question I'm curious if there were you
know were there uh any Milestones that
you experienced which told you that you
were having a really positive impact on
the biological diversity of the farm and
that things were getting better like in
the soil and in the I don't know the
biosphere of of of your farm when you
know signs that when you saw it you just
like kind of stopped and you're like oh
man we're we're doing it we're doing
it I I there's a lot of that I mean I I
kind of walk around every day and feel
that like oh my God this is this is
amazing it's it's happening it's working
um I remember specifically uh the the
first or uh regenerative Cannabis
Conference did I I don't know if you
were there I wasn't at the first one no
it it was it was right here in my
neighborhood it was at at Beginnings in
bryand here and it was relatively small
and I uh I had a few people who were
there a few of the presenters come up
and do a quick little of the farm um and
and one of the presenters was uh a
myologist who focused on mic
micology and he said oh this is cool
you've been growing cannabis in the same
area for for 10 years or whatever it was
at that point probably more than that
can I take a sample and and do a
mological study of it I was like that
that sounds amazing sounds bad yeah and
so he got back to me about a week later
and he said the um the spores of the
specific um
micis fungi that have relationship with
cannabis are dense enough in this soil
that you could cut it by 10 parts and
sell it as an inoculate
wow that must have for you I was like
what the heck well I I didn't know and I
was like well does that mean we're doing
a good job or that commercial inoculants
are ridiculous and he said a little both
right yeah that that is Fant fantastic
and to to know that um that you know it
was your your soil was that fungally
rich um it really gives you um an
understanding that you've got like room
for error right cuz you're you're not
barely getting by your your soil is
actually
bursting and and you know some of it I I
think you just end up with a lot of
happy accidents you know um like I I
have thought a lot you know while I'm on
my way to bed and don't have a piece of
paper or things like that of you know
the idea of of of micro risal
relationships now there's a difference
between um spores and active micro Risa
that that are in the soil and there's
active microa on the Cannabis Roots what
what makes micor Risa go into kind of a
suspended state is not having those
relationships so if you go into a winter
time where your soil is bare the microa
that's alive no longer is there's spores
maybe maybe it'll build up again but
it'll take longer to build up again in
the spring and I've I've been curious
and I actually haven't done the the
researcher looked at it it's like is
there specific cover crops that that
have the same micro risal relationships
with the same species as does a cannabis
crop or a crop you're growing for that
summer so that you can encourage a
continuity of those species because you
know we see a lot of um you know if you
if you go on Instagram and you look at
people's accounts everybody um posts
these pictures of incredible mycelium in
their soil and and a lot of those
species are wonderful they're good to
have in your soil they're the species
that break down um Woody material or
unbroken down organic matter and and
provide nutrients from it but then the
specific fungal mat the spe specific
micro isal relationships that that
directly benefit the Cannabis um in a
more direct relationship way how do we
keep those alive how do we proliferate
those and and are there cover crops or
or perennial plantings that share enough
of the same species to be able to be the
the kind of safe space for for those
living species to to
overwinter yeah cuz you don't you don't
want the the the really beneficial for
can cannabis like inter AES to suddenly
be out competed by like U wood digestors
only you know exactly and and that's
mostly what you see and like no no shade
on anyone I I love posting pictures of
of all my you know micro isal mats when
I find them but almost always it's wood
digestors whether it's you know wine
Caps or or the staria kind of mushrooms
um that that's what you see a lot
because they're they're the way we're
gardening the way we're we're doing
things whether it's through hugle beds
or through a lot of uh of addition of
carbon in the form of mulch really
favors the wood digestors yeah right on
all right so let's go ahead and take our
second uh short break we'll be right
back you are listening to shaping fire
and my guest today is regenerative
farmer Daniel
[Music]
Stein you've heard me talk about the
award-winning cannabis seeds that come
from the analytical breeding program of
Seth and Eric Crawford who found Oregon
CBD seeds in fact Seth was a guest on
shaping fire in 2020 to talk about
triploid genetics Seth and Eric are now
releasing high THC seeds for homeg
Growers and Farms as grow the revolution
seeds at gtrr seeds.com their high THC
seeds are extraordinary in that they
will start to flower at 165 hours of
daylight instead of the typical 14 1/2
hours of daylight that means in most
region
your plants will start to flower
outdoors in the middle of July instead
of the middle of August which means
these photo period plants finish in
September and not October totally
upending the photo period Seed Market
Seth and Eric took their prized early
flowering CBG line and bred it to some
of the most desired verified genetics
out there including Sour Diesel triangle
cush wedding cake chem dog Skittles and
others these crosses all Express
powerful photo period tpine profiles and
THC giving you a great High GTR seeds
has a new thcv line with plants like
double Durban and Gigantor that boast
one:1 THC to thcv and people want that
thcv GTR seeds are very consistent true
growing inbred f1s from stabilized
inbred parent lines these seeds are
nearly homogeneous and the plants should
all grow the same they there is only one
phenotype in every pack available as
diploids and triploids sethan Eric's
company is still family-owned patient
employee Centric and partially powered
by their two acres of solar panels
everyone can purchase these seeds in the
entire catalog of Oregon CBD seeds at
GTR seeds.com go to GTR seeds.com today
and choose something revolutionary for
your next indoor or outdoor
[Music]
run after you've caught up on the latest
shaping fire episodes do you sometimes
wish there was more cannabis education
available to learn well we got you
shaping fire has a fabulous YouTube
channel with content not found on the
podcast when I attend conventions to
speak or moderate panels I always record
them and bring the content home for you
to watch the Shango Los YouTube channel
has worldclass speakers including Zoe
sigman's lecture understanding your
endoc canabo system Kevin jry of
Wonderland Nursery talking about
breeding cannabis for the best turine
profile Frenchie canoli's Lost Art of
the hashian presentation Nicholas mmud
on regenerative and polyculture cannabis
growing Dr seil agrawal on the history
of cannabis medicine Around the World
Eric vosi and Josh Rutherford on
solventless extraction and Jeff
lowenfels on the soil food web there are
several presentations from Dr Ethan
Russo on Turpin and the endoc canabo
system too while there be sure to check
out the three 10-part shaping fire
session series one with Kevin jodry one
with Dr Ethan Russo and one with Jeff
lowenfels and even my own presentations
on how to approach finding your dream
job in cannabis and why we choose
cannabis business even though the risks
are so high as of today there's over 200
videos that you can check out for free
so go to
youtube.com/ Shango or click on the link
in the
[Music]
newsletter one of the challenges with
buying Autoflower seeds is that often
you'll have as many different fenos as
you will have seeds in a pack that can
be fun sure but so many varieties in one
pack is a sign of an immature seed line
that hasn't been worked enough I prefer
my autoflowers to be worked enough that
each pheno in the pack really captures
the aspects that the breeder was
intending this is why I recommend gnome
automatics to my friends and listeners
who grow automatic flowering cannabis
seeds gnome automatic seeds are not just
crossed and released they are
painstakingly sifted again and again
tested in a wide range of conditions and
taken to a level of maturity that each
plant will be recognizable by its traits
traits that were hard-earned so that you
can have your best grow cycle ever over
the last 10 years Nome automatics
founder Dan Jimmy has become a trusted
breeder and he continues to pour His
passion of breeding cannabis into every
variety he releases for you to grow
check out the gnome automatics Instagram
_ automatics to see the impressive
plants folks are growing you can score
gnome automatic seeds in feminized or
regular at your favorite seed provider
listed in the vendor section of their
website commercial cannabis Farms across
the country love growing gnome
automatics because of their consistency
from seed to seed short grow times THC
percentages and colorful bag appeal
Farms interested in bulk seeds of more
than a thousand should reach out through
gnome automatics.com
while on the website be sure to check
out the gnome automatic shirts and other
merch section too if you want reliable
seeds handbuilt from effort expert
selection and experience choose gnome
automatics welcome back you are
listening to shaping fire I am your host
Shango and today my guest is
regenerative farmer Daniel Stein So
Daniel during this last section I want
to talk about um some macro ideas um
around Land Management and and let's
start with crop rotation um you know we
talked a lot during the first set about
um the the joy of plan planning the farm
and and how that plan can evolve over
the years and you know that you don't
have to do everything the first year um
but you know one of the challenges that
people get into is they really kind of
fall in love with their Farm design and
and where things go and so everything
has a place but but as regenerative
Farmers we also know the benefit that
comes from crop rotation so we're not
trying to feed the same crop with the
same soil all the time but gosh um it's
really easy to not rotate um crops um
different Farmers I've spoken to will
either rotate and some will be like well
I just choose to amend and not rotate um
I'd like to hear what your thoughts
are um I think my thoughts on this is is
do what you can see see where rotations
are important for you and and where they
aren't um and sometimes it it's
self-limiting for instance with cannabis
we couldn't rotate because we had such a
hard time explaining to the Regulatory
Agencies what crop rotation is and we
didn't feel like redrawing and
resubmitting our Maps every year oh um
and but what's interesting is that led
us to a discovery which is that I think
cannabis likes to grow in the same spot
and when I started thinking about it and
and imagining cannabis growing in the
wild you know like a ditch weed for
instance
cannabis produces a ton of seeds that
fall right there and and regrow right
there um so I think cannabis as a plant
is used to growing in its own shadow I
guess you would say um and you know that
doesn't change the fact that crop
rotation can reduce pest pressure
especially pests that tend to overwinter
in the soil or things like that or
wouldn't be beneficial but I I think for
us for our different crops we weigh the
benefit of crop
rotation versus the challenge of crop
rotation and decide individually on each
thing um you know for instance in our
vegetable farm we have a block that is
lettuce production that we don't rotate
because the infrastructure that it takes
for us to have year round lettuce
production in this hot Aid climate
doesn't lend itself well to rotation and
lettuce doesn't see to be a problem in
terms of nutrient use or pest in with
rotation things like um garlic and
tomatoes and carrots we tend to rotate
and primarily our rotation for those
isn't nutrient based because we are so
well provided with nutrients through
compost our rotation tends to be what
crops do a good job of reducing weed
pressure for the next crop that doesn't
do well with weed pressure like for
instance carrots might come after
zucchini because zucchini reduced the
the seed bank of weeds in that area and
then carrots can come after them and
things like that
so it's one of those things uh cover
it's more important to plant
stuff a and get it in the ground than to
get it just right because um at the end
of the day you'd rather have a a you
know carrot that's not perfect than not
to have any
carrots um and it's similar to how I
feel about uh planting with moon cycles
like plant it out try to plant with the
moon cycles if you don't miss it if you
miss it don't wait a month to plant
again because it's better to have it
growing a month then to to hit it on
exactly the energetic cycle
um that bit that you said about right on
do your best that's a good theme for
today you know that you kind of blew my
mind at the at the top of your answer
when you when you pointed out that
cannabis seeds when mature are pushed
out of the flower and just dropped to
the ground at its own feet and start
next year's plants right there at its
feet you know they're they're they're
not they're not air distributed and and
while while they could be distributed by
birds that's that's really not their
main shtick they really are birds crack
them open there you go so so they don't
even they don't even survive the process
so um yeah that that really kind of sets
crop rotation for cannabis in my in a
totally in a totally different realm uh
I'm already envisioning the the next
time I talk to a microbiologist about
the difference between um the root
structures of of of plants that need to
be cover or not cover crop need to be
rotated versus ones who don't because
I'm sure that life in the rizosphere is
entirely different for plants that are
are built to be the same location every
year yeah and and that micro risal
relationship is there too it's like the
roots of the previous year are there
with all of its
microbiology while you plant the next
year yeah and they must have very Burly
exit dates too I'd imagine so it sure
does seem like it yeah right on so so
let's let's talk about another variety
of Land Management other than crop
rotation so you know we we've been
talking about different parts of your
parcel and how they relate but really if
we if we pull the pull the camera out
your whole whole parcel is one big um
land mass of growing as well um what
kinds of Forward Thinking big picture
Land Management do you use on the parcel
as a whole I'm thinking stuff like
controlled Burns and things like that
that can regenerate the property itself
yeah exactly um so our homestad is
perhaps 5 to 10 acres of of the overall
parcel and on 170 Acres most of it is
forested and relatively steep um and
here in in Northern California our our
native Forest environment has been very
affected by by extractive Land
Management and the
exclusion uh of native cultural Land
Management um so when we're looking at
the overall property we're trying to
understand how we take it from this
state where it's out of balance because
of of logging and fire suppression and
get it back into its Natural Balance
which for this area is is a natural fire
regimen and more of an old growth less
less trees more space between the trees
more
biodiversity um so yeah we're we're
looking intensely at that we've we've
partnered with um some local nonprofits
that work on on Watershed restoration
we're doing some big in-depth studies of
of how groundwater moves through the the
soil here basically in this area
geologically we have a a Bedrock layer
that's
relatively impenetrable by water on a
lot of it and then a 20 to 30 foot deep
soil sponge on top of that and and um we
don't have aquafers our summer time
water is the water that slowly moves
through that sponge from from The Ridges
down to the creeks and out so where we
have groundwater Wells where we're
studying infiltration from rain how long
it stays in the soil where it moves
through the Watershed and then we're
going to be doing some some um Forest
restoration work thinning and liming and
and just kind of every bringing it back
into balance Forest restoration work we
could do in that area and see seeing how
that changes the water flow through that
watered and then moving on after we get
to study that for a couple of years to
doing a prescribed fire in that area and
seeing how that affects water
infiltration and does it affect the pH
of the groundwater and how does that
change the soil structure and things
like that so that's kind of the long
range is looking towards how we get this
large parcel back to a place where we
can manage it through the use of
prescribed natural fire and then also
what land management techniques we can
use on a closer level and that's where
things like the goats come in they're
kind of like a biological fire where
they consume a lot of the biomass around
around our area and keep it down so so
not only does it get into a better
balance but it keeps us fire safe we we
are in a fire prone environment and
because of this out of balance
with fire that we have it is um it it's
very catastrophic when it happens as we
all know yeah um you know the way that
you talk about these bigger projects
which um it's amazing that you are able
to find time or create time to do
something that that that is that big and
future-minded
versus just the daily demands of a farm
but really that extra effort that you
put in it's it's it's like the farming
um equivalent of generational wealth you
know it's like it's like you're you're
doing these studies and you're learning
H how the the the farm uh parcel will be
will be better over time with your eye
on 20 and 30 years out so that the you
know you can be a participant in the
evolution of the nature around you but
also that um your farm has got a
reliable backbone
uh you know in case in case your your
kids want to take it over in time or
something like that and I I think that's
I think that's philosophically really uh
important to regenerative farming and
and and often given short shrift well
and and land ownership is funny it's
like um you know I'm here now maybe my
kids will be here maybe they won't but
this land will be here either way and in
terms of like time to do this I'm I'm
super fortunate I I have great
Partnerships um I'm do some grant
writing but I'm working with local
nonprofits that are doing the grant
writing actually doing the work and I'm
just coordinating with them to see that
it's happening oh that's
great um it's so it's wonderful having
people like that working on your
behalf yeah it's incredible and you know
to some degree it's the openness to it
and the the the engaging in the
community constantly in these spheres of
you know a a big part here as the the
economy is Shifting here as as cannabis
economy has changed and gotten
integrated into this larger broken
economy good saying it's shifting is
like the the the the nicest possible way
to put what's going on around you yeah I
mean think it it's honestly it's coming
into balance but unfortunately it's
coming into balance with a broken system
yeah it sure is and that's that's kind
of the way it goes but oh one of the
economies that is starting to take some
of that um burden is is the restoration
economy what we have here is an
incredible amount of of beautiful
forested land in our area and it it
needs work it needs restoration if we're
going to have healthy Fisheries if we're
going to be a fire safe Community Etc so
um you kind of set me up perfectly these
next two questions are uh economics
based and the first one is um uh you
know what is the economic impact of
switching to regenerative farming you
know on a small farm you you weren't you
weren't petroleum base to begin with so
it wasn't that much of a swing but um
you certainly stopped you know double
digging and and other uh potentially
laborious uh practices but you probably
also traded those for other laborious
practices and and okay you're you're
saving money on on a lot of inputs that
a non-regenerative farm would be buying
in town but then but then you also have
to buy materials to do other types of
projects there's like all of these uh
tradeoffs in both directions and so um
so for regenerative farming I think
incorrectly is is assumed to be so much
more expensive to do because you don't
get to use the shortcuts of of of modern
farming which is also happens to be
poisoning everybody so I'd just like to
hear um how you how you kind like weigh
it out about the the economic impact um
for you specifically on regenerative
farming regarding some of the other
options that you have in front of
you yeah I I mean I think for the
options I have in front of me
regenerative farming is by far the most
economically feasible it's like when you
align your values and your goals with
what naturally wants to happen anyway
you're not needing the products
and the the physical energy to fight
against the
flow um on a larger scale yeah
industrial farming benefits from
economies of scale and that's something
that's that's hard to do on our level of
regenerative farming I know there is
regenerative farming at scale um that
that does take advantage of some of
those economies of scale but I wouldn't
have an economy of scale in our type of
farm even if I were to spray poison on
everything and road to till the crap out
of it um you know and when it comes down
to it it's like it has to work
economically if you're doing it as a
business otherwise it doesn't work um
but it also has to work you know you
couldn't pay me enough money to spray
poison on my land I live here um so it
even if that worked economically it
wouldn't work so you have to draw your
boundaries somewhere and luckily with
with regenerative noil farming it it
does work it is less work to not till it
is less work to not spray poison
sometimes you do lose crops to to pests
um as as one of my great um farming
Mentor friends Casey O'Neal from Happy
Day says when when you're selling
products to to customers and your kale
hasn't nice hole in it it's like the
kale is delicious and the hole doesn't
taste like anything it's like it you get
the products you get because of the way
you farm and they it's a benefit it it
it really is a benefit economically so
um I know that I'm kind of inside of a
bubble that that I'm probably in with
you because the people that I roll with
uh literally roll with um we're all into
regeneratively grown outdoor flower
right that's what what we smoke and um
and we're not going to we don't we're
not going to spend our our our our money
um uh buying uh you know a plus b flour
from a dispensary and we're certainly
not going to grow you know salt sodium
flowers we're going to do it
regeneratively in Outdoors um that said
we are in a bubble right and there there
is a market as as a whole and so um I'm
curious to know um have you seen an
increase in demand for your
regeneratively produced cannabis because
you know as somebody in journalism I'm
certainly helping you know raise the
profile of regenerative and all of us
who are in regenerative smoke
regenerative but um I I I'm not familiar
with like how much of the market is
being purchased regenerative and there
you are on the front line so are are you
seeing in increased demand for your uh
quality of cannabis
flour yeah yeah absolutely we are um and
it's an engagement thing it it it's
having direct contact as much with with
Bud tenders as with customers and our
brand which we share with a number of
other regenerated Farmers is is Farm Cut
and what we've noticed with that is is
the product we're coming to customers
with sometimes is a hard sell we're
selling topshelf
flow minimally processed so basically
untrimmed to and uh in quarter ounce
amounts and it the the the hardest part
is actually getting customers to try it
the first time because nearly across the
board customers that try it come back
for more because
yeah objectively there is a difference
in the experience from it so um the the
challenge is definitely engaging with
Bud tenders who often push indoor flower
or Brands they're familiar with whether
out of habit or out of market
dynamics um but I I feel like we have
seen an increase in in people seeking
out regenerative flour and uh an
definitely an increase in the people who
do seek out regenerative flour
back for our brand after they have an
experience with it yeah the proof really
is in the pudding isn't it like after
you smoke outdoor that was you know
carefully grown regeneratively it really
it really does open up um what you think
cannabis can be because of the wider
chirping profiles and you know the
burlin in
general well and the challenge for us
and why we created that brand is you you
can grow the best regenerative flower in
the world and if you don't cure it right
it's not great and you can cure it
perfectly and if it makes its way to
Market in a way that doesn't preserve
that and bring it to the customer in its
best possible form then you also lose
that quality and we kind of created a a
a way to get it to the customer in the
way we enjoy it and it blows people's
minds it's like when you when you open a
jar that's been vacuum sealed and and
not trimmed and you you break it open
for the first time and break a couple Su
leafes off of it it's overwhelming like
the smell and then when you smoke
properly cured properly stored flour the
experience is is just different and more
full and more layered and nuanced than
the experience from some fast DED
indoor um you know there are two other
aspects I want to um uh economic
regenerative aspects I want to focus on
um one you've already mentioned which is
the relationship with Bud tenders right
um because it is interesting that um you
know bud tenders do have a lot of
control in uh uh influence and and where
they drive people for their purchases so
having a good relationship with Bud
tenders is important and in a lot of
ways like you know um that friendship is
also a regenerative farming P practice
in a way in that it's it's creating
community and Outreach and and uh
reaching out with um you know your
philos phos ophy of regenerative growing
and and what that meaning is but but
also and and where I want to focus more
is um the cooperation and Community
spirit that you um need to have with
other Farmers on a basic level when you
are trading resources like oh you know
I'll trade you I'll trade you hay for
manure or whatever the trades may be or
or or sharing equipment those kinds of
relationships become really essential in
regenerative farming when you're trying
to um you know be very resourceful but
then also you you mentioned uh Farm Cut
cannabis um the brand that you've put
together with um you know looks like
four different farms and yourselves
where um you know you you kind of get
the benefits of being a scaled Farm
without having to do the the negatives
of a scaled farm and and and that
synergy only comes together because you
get together with these all small farms
and then market and distribute as one
and we all know that that that was you
know that was attempted at the beginning
of of you know proposition 64 days by
Outsiders where they're oh we're going
to pull together all the small farms and
then it ended up being a big Croc um but
but but now in kind of like the dust of
the Brokenness of of the Cannabis uh
system in in California we're seeing
Farmers come together like really like
over the dinner table in in in a smaller
less grandiose way and it appears from
the
outside um that it's working so so maybe
talk a little bit about this partnership
with um you know that you that you all
are calling Farm Cut cannabis yeah so
that that partnership is is five Farms
including ourselves it's ourselves white
Thorn Valley Farm happy day Farm Farm
Emerald Spirit Botanicals in meno and
down farms in Nevada City area and um
it's just wonderful we're we're
like-minded farmers who came together we
couldn't exactly create a co-op but we
created a brand together that we can
share a and like you'd said share
resources share share the burden of the
tasks um Joseph for memoral spirit is
our our our primary salesperson and he
uh because other members of his family
are taking care of the firm he's able to
travel a lot and and visit dispensaries
and and talk to people about about Farm
Cut and about our products and make
those
relationships and and we've played to
all of our strengths and been able to
develop systems and processes that that
work for us whether it's sharing
equipment or pooling our resources to be
able to say um we have packaging that's
a standard mason jar and we could not
find a good childproof lid for a
standard mason jar that didn't have
plastic in it so we were able to create
one to to go to a factory and say we
want
plant-based childproof lid for for this
size jar and and create that and buack
and bulk and things like that and it
it's heartening it's it's um in this
economic system where it's going towards
integration with the kind of dog heat
dog venture capitalist capitalist world
the the
cooperation and and the building
something together gives us a lot of
Hope and a lot of a good feeling
especially doing it with people we just
like seeing and being around anyway that
yeah totally the doing business with
people that we actually like really
makes all the difference in the world
it's so great you know it'd be really
funny if this um if this uh new
childproof cap for mason jars that you
all invented that that you know that the
patent for that actually ends up
becoming popular because that's actually
a really novel useful idea and ends up
making you all more more income than the
Cannabis itself you know there was there
was somebody already doing it and we
were we were getting those um and they
were great products they they were on
the pricey side but the main thing that
that we wanted is something that didn't
have any plastic and the one we had
initially started with our brand is made
with a flax fiber and a recycled plastic
and we wanted one that was entirely
biological plant-based material and and
that's where we got into it and yeah who
knows what the the long long term of
that I'm I'm just right now keeping my
fingers crossed that that California
could be a big enough market that we can
we can sell a majority of our product
through this brand that is is a joy to
to be part of and um we're not there yet
but we're doing
really well excellent excellent well
it's nice it's nice to see good people
coming together in a good union uh for
for shared benefit yeah it feels great
too I mean it's it's we get such
incredibly positive feedback from from
customers and dispensaries about it that
it even just that alone besides the
business aspect it's like um it's a good
feeling to know that the thing you put
so much energy into creating well and
taking care of well
is is received and acknowledged for
being what it is in the world and and
also specifically the the Farms that you
have partnered with I know several of
the folks and you know like who who
doesn't want to be in partnership with
regenerative farmers who are generally
Happy go-lucky People anyway you know I
mean you know I probably know Casey the
best and you know great success to all
of it you know exactly exactly great
success yeah so so let's finish off with
this question you know like we
intentionally designed this episode
today so that we could talk about your
farm um in detail but really as an
example of what can happen on
everybody's Farm who's listening right
whether or not they're transitioning
from from petroleum farming or or if
they're just coming to their parcel and
and I think we did a did a good job of
that um but but really like direct
advice really could be profound and
inspirational so so let's finish with
that so what advice would you give to a
farmer with a new parcel or who is
transitioning who is just starting out
with regenerative
practices I think the best advice um
would be kind of going if you've read
The Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy the
best advice in the world is Don't Panic
Oh I thought you were going to say to
bring a towel that that's not a bad idea
either no don't don't panic don't stress
do what you can none of us are are on an
island there there's no such thing as a
complete closed loop sustainability
system look at your farm do your best
find find the resources that you have
available and adapt to them find the
markets you have available and adapt to
them don't be too hard on yourself for
the things that don't work
and and don't imagine that that we can
be Pure or to
keep um that we can do everything we
dream as
regenerative right from the
start
I'm you introduced me as a regenerative
farmer I'm not a regenerative farmer I
don't think anybody is a regenerative
farmer I think all of us are striving to
align our farming with natural process
and balancing that with the needs of
being a human on earth right now and
what is available to us and what the the
constraints and the the the burdens that
that that we have to deal with so find
that balance don't get squeezed between
your ideals and your
reality make make your way the path that
that is best for you and then see where
you can prove it towards natural systems
towards more sustainability and make
some
improvement that is possible for you
with each season and go in that
direction beautiful well Daniel thank
you so much for sharing your your depth
of experience and your passion for
farming and doing the right thing and
and your vision for your you know your
own parcel and your own family your own
life I think that um you know through
these words hopefully we've given some
people some new ideas for things to do
on their own parcels and also uh you
know just just put regenerative farming
more into the realm of the possible
instead of the realm of the ideal so I
know your time is valuable and I I
really thank you for spending it with us
on shaping fire yeah thank you it's it's
been really enjoyable and I just hope
everybody gets out there and gets their
hands dirty this spring fantastic okay
dear listeners so if you want to uh know
more about Bryce land forest Farm where
uh where Daniel is owner with his wife
Taylor um uh you can find out that at
bryand Forest Farm on Instagram or on
their website at bryand Forest farm.com
and bryceland is b r i c l n d and um we
would love it if you would uh you know
if you live in California if you're or
if you're traveling there to stop at
your dispensary and buy some Farm Cut
cannabis um their small farm uh
community group and uh if you want to
follow along along with them um you on
IG that's Farm Cut Cana and uh on the
interwebs that's Farm Cut
cannabis.com you can find more episodes
of the shaping fire podcast And
subscribe to the show at shaping
fire.com and wherever you get your
podcasts if you enjoyed the show we'd
really appreciate it if you would leave
a positive review of the podcast
wherever you download your review will
help others find the show so they can
enjoy it too on the shaping fire website
you can also subscribe to the newsletter
for insights into the latest Cannabis
News exclusive videos and giveaways on
the shaping fire website you'll also
find transcripts of today's podcast as
well be sure to follow on Instagram for
all original content not found on the
podcast that's @ shaping fire and @
Shango on Instagram be sure to check out
the shaping fire YouTube channel for
exclusive interviews farm tours and
cannabis lectures does your company want
to reach our national audience of
cannabis enthusiasts email hotspot
shaping fire.com to find out how thanks
for listening to shaping fire I've been
your host Shango Los
[Music]