[Music]
the more I learn about cannabis plants
the more I understand the complexities
of designing cannabis gardens one of the
first things I had to rid myself of was
the belief that everything I already had
learned was correct true learning in any
field necessitates that I remain willing
to adapt my understanding when presented
with new information no doubt this is a
challenge we see on cannabis forums and
social media threads all the time folks
argue vigorously and even get angry
defending what their mentor taught them
even though there isn't any reproducible
support for their relief similarly I
often think that I know what I'm talking
about
only to find out I do not on shaping
fire I'm very careful with the kind of
information I spread because I know
folks trust me to not repeat [ __ ]
today's an episode that makes this most
clear to me I thought I was building an
interview about why banker and trap
plants were so important to the garden
and which ones to choose well I was I
was wrong if you want to learn about
cannabis health business and technique
efficiently in with good cheer I
encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter will send you new podcast
episodes as they come out delivered
right to your inbox along with
commentary and a couple of the most
important news items from the week and
videos too don't rely on social media to
let you know when a new episode is
published sign up for the updates to
make sure you don't miss an episode
also we're giving away very cool prizes
to folks who are signed up to receive
the newsletter there's nothing else you
need to do to win except receive that
newsletter this month regenerative
farming nutrient company ever flux is
giving away their full line of products
to one lucky subscriber to the
newsletter you'll receive a full-sized
bottle of their bio flux fermented plant
booster their bamboo wood vinegar
biostimulant and a big old bucket of
tera flux they're infused biochar blend
you'll get all three make sure to listen
to their commercial during the first
break to learn more and go to shaping
feiyr.com to sign up for the newsletter
and be entered into this month's and all
future newsletter prize drawings you are
listening to shaping fire and I'm your
host
Shango louse today my guest is
entomologist Suzanne Wainwright evans
also known as the bug lady suzanne
graduated from the University of Florida
with degrees in both entomology
environmental horticulture and has been
working in horticulture for more than
twenty eight years and in cannabis since
normalization began her focus has been
on Biological control and using
pesticides properly she has worked
throughout the United States and
internationally consulting to
greenhouses nurseries theme parks and
gardens she is without a doubt the
preeminent cannabis pest expert in the
United States and is a sought-after
speaker for cannabis events everywhere
while I thought today was going to be a
guide to the best plants to use and why
trap and banker plants were so essential
instead we're gonna learn about trap and
banker plants in depth while also
realizing how hard they are to use the
complexities and challenges of using
them in the cannabis garden why the
plants suggested so often on forums
don't actually work in real life and
finally some strategies for making
banker and trap plants work for you if
you're willing to put in the effort
welcome to the show Suzanne oh thanks
for having me so thank you so much for
being here so let's get right to it you
know a lot of people throw these terms
banker plants and trap plants back and
forth they use them synonymously in a
lot of ways and then they kind of put
them all under the category of companion
plants so what I want to do is tease
these apart so they can we can really
understand how to use these more
effectively in the garden so would you
start by defining what banker plants are
and what trap plants are and how they're
different so basically the idea of
banker plants is a food source for your
beneficials an alternate food source
then what you want them to feed on in
the crop one of the most popular
popularly used ones right now in
ornamental production is the aphid
banker plant system and the idea is that
if you release these tiny parasitoid
wasps which kill a foods if you just
release them and you don't have many
aphids in your greenhouse they're all
going to die because they can't they
don't really have a food source and have
a place to lay their eggs so what you do
is you provide this plant and on the
banker plant you're actually providing a
different a fat species so it
it's kind of a complex system that you
have the plant and you have a pest
insect on the plants but what's crucial
is is that you have to make sure that
those pest insects in this situation
these aphids don't move on to your
primary crop so it's kind of a way to
maintain a population of your
beneficials without actually having the
pests in your crop at the time so we're
able to use like an aphid banker plant
system and then we also have one for
aureus which is the minut pirate bug
we're able to use that to build
populations of beneficials in the
greenhouse before the pests arrived so
you already have the standing army of
beneficials ready to go also they can
provide food that your crop necessarily
can't provide because when you look
again at aureus the my new pirate bug it
needs pollen in its diet and most crops
do not have readily available pollen or
the right kind of pollen and so by
providing the pepper plants we're
providing a pepper a pollen source that
aureus really love so that they can
reproduce successfully the flipside of
that are trap crops and they do kind of
exactly what they say is they trap your
pests there's actually been some really
good research done on this and
unfortunately in some situations it's
not been very successful but the idea is
is to plant a crop that is tastier than
the the plants you're actually growing
and to try to draw the pests out of the
the crop you're growing into the trap
crop some people will then either bag
these plants and remove them other
people treat them with a pesticide so
that when the pests feed on them they
die again there's been work trying this
one of the more famous studies was done
up in Canada and they were looking at
poinsettias and eggplants for white fly
management but unfortunately the the
white flies were just way too happy on
the poinsettias
and they wouldn't leave to go to the
eggplant even though eggplants a really
good host for white flight also so it's
it's not it's not that common as seen
the trap crops as banker plants because
the thing you also have to be careful of
is if you put out these plants and
you're growing let's say all these
eggplants to try to pull white fly if
you don't take care of those trap crops
it basically can turn into a pest
breeding system and I see that happen a
lot with banker plant systems too people
forget about them people ignore them and
then like and the banker plant systems
the pepper plants then become breeding
grounds for a fidex so these are
programs that you have to stay on top of
you can't you can't just plant them and
walk away because you do have to treat
these plants for pests crops I mean for
pests insects and mites all throw in
there also
there's also insectary plants those are
plants we use that provide pretty much
pollen and nectar for beneficials that's
a term that's used a bit more outdoors
when you you know plant you know plants
around like well alyssum is one that's
used calendula things like that that
provide pollen and nectar for the
beneficials let's dig into the banker
plants off first because you caught me
off guard I actually never realized that
folks who have got a good program are
actually uh I don't know pre charging
their banker plants with an Associated
species for example like your example a
an aphid but not an aphid that
necessarily prefers cannabis plants so
they are creating a food source for in
this case the the wasps and but but the
the species of aphids that they are
setting up on those banker planes are
actually not one that is harmful the
cannabis do I understand that correctly
yes so
on that particular system we generally
use barley some people use oats but
basically it needs to be a type of grass
there's again there's been studies done
looking at what works the best and
barley produces the most a photonic and
it's the bird cheerio if it is the
species we use and it is it's a feeder
on monocots so it won't move to
dioecious plants it will stay on grasses
so if you are a grass grower you would
not use this system but if you are
growing not grasses you and I you know
there could always be one weird example
but generally you're okay so you know
again if you grow in just seeing as no
we don't use this in those and also
there can be some issues with some
lilies but so far as to date we have not
seen the bird cheerio David actually on
cannabis and so that way you're rearing
these aphids and this particular system
only works with a Phidias coal money
there are several different a fat
parasitoids but this particular system
is for coal money which a coal money
will parasitize things like cotton
Melanie fit and it does also parasitize
the cannabis aphid is it the magic
silver bullet for cannabis aphid no but
it definitely is part of the management
program for it yeah and overall
integrated pest management in the truest
sense yes yes one of the thing I find it
interesting that banker plants actually
have got two very distinct roles that
not only can they be pre-charged with an
associated non pests that can feed your
beneficials because I think all of us
who have used beneficials in the past
have run into the problem that when the
beneficials do their job and suddenly
the pests numbers are down suddenly
there's no food source for them and they
either die or wander away but then also
secondarily since the banker plant is of
a type that the pests also likes
pests are hopefully moving over to the
banker plants as well so so not only are
you providing a secondary food source
for them so they stay alive your
beneficial stay alive but also it
creates a secondary environment that's
not your cannabis yeah but I would never
depend I don't think it's ever really
with the barley it's not really going to
pull any of your pests from your
cannabis now on the pepper banker plant
systems because you know anybody's ever
grown peppers know the Western flower
thrips love them onion thrips can get on
them spider mites can't get it on them
several Avett species can get on them I
mean peppers could possibly function in
a way as a trap crop but and it was
funny I was just talking to another
researcher about this the other day
oftentimes when an insect is raised on
one plant it's very difficult to
transfer it to an alternate host that it
even though we know it feeds on it it
tends to want to stay on the same plant
species that I grew up on and often it's
Prodigy too so again this is why I you
know I'm trap crops not completely sold
on it for four key pest we're dealing
with I would say in cannabis and
ornamentals I'm not talking about
agriculture or other settings but it's
it's it's something that you really
would have to really work on and
generally again it's too much work for
most people to deal with
yeah well the the research alone to make
sure that you're fine-tuning your
alternative pest and also you know pre
charging them they mean this is
certainly a commercial scale you know
you know the commercial folks who are
listening and they're probably getting a
lot of value out of that but that's way
beyond what a you know a state medical
grower or a personal grower probably
going to use so are you saying that if
if our pests are
growing up on cannabis and they have
grown up eating it and so therefore they
like it that in in most cases using a
trap plant that we perceive is going to
be tastier than cannabis might not
actually be an effective that that folks
in cannabis are using these trap plants
but it's really not a solution it's more
of an ornamental solution than a
cannabis solution well until the
research is done and we know for sure
it's hard to have an answer and also
let's take for example bean plants bean
plants are one that we started doing
some stuff with actually in roses
outside and because spider mites love
bean plans if you want to raise spider
mites like well raise them sometimes
here at the house you know I'll raise
them on bean plants that's one of their
favorite food sources when we were using
them in roses is like okay as soon as we
see spider mites on the bean plants
outside we know they're common on the
roses so then is when we would start our
predatory mite program interestingly
enough we found out that it turned out
to be a better indicator plant and
that's really what an indicator plant
lets you know when a pest is in an area
because it indicates to you that it
actually worked out better for flea
beetles because the flea beetles would
actually hit the beans before they would
move into the roses so it actually we
learned something from that situation
but you know I sometimes wonder you know
if we have these bean plants out how do
we know that's just not a separate
population breeding on the beans then
what's actually breeding on the roses
and are those two spots spider mites in
the beans going to move in to the roses
and we don't know until there's study
done with a control it's hard to know
but again the number one problem I see
over and over and over again is someone
forgets about the bean plants they get
busy doing other things and then next
you know you have bean plants covered in
webbing and you know they're infested
with spider mites and a little late it's
a little bit your indicator was probably
10 days ago
and again I I see that happen and the
other thing and I just had a situation
with this in a Maine where somebody
contacted me freaking out because they
had EFA's all over their foliage and it
turns out that they were using a cover
crop and this is this happens all the
time in cannabis losing cover crops
indoors and the cover crops turns into
just a breeding ground for all kinds of
insects and if it's often will you know
if they're not happy or the populations
get high but they'll pick up and leave
and they'll start walking up the
cannabis plants so in that situation the
aphids weren't doing any damage to the
cannabis they were just out looking for
a new host coming off the the cover crop
which some people are using air quote
cover crops as either banker plants or
in Sector II plans but they're not
paying attention to what other potential
pests they could get so as far as
indicator plants go I understand that
there's a lot of specificity from one
pest to another but are we lucky enough
in cannabis that there happens to be an
indicator plant species that is similar
to cannabis perhaps that's a little
maybe sweeter or tastier for these
plants that we may be able to plant
alongside our cannabis that would draw
the pests first and we could keep an eye
on those before they hit the cannabis
well it depends on what pass and you
know if you look at right now what our
major pests and the stuff that I get
contacted about every single day you
know cannabis aphid hand-press it might
root a food those their cannabis
specific they don't live on alternate
hosts at all now I have been contacted a
lot this year about thrips now thrips
because again a lot of what I'm finding
our onion thrips which I will consider a
generalist you know I hate when they say
the name onion thrips because everybody
assumes oh it's just a pest of onions
but that's not necessarily true because
there are a problem in ornamentals there
was just a survey done in Canada and
something like a quarter of all
thrips found in the Niagara region where
onion thrips over Western flour so
they're definitely around but you know
again are they going to want to be in
ornamental pepper over the cannabis we
don't really know and also remember the
immature insects cannot fly so all you
can do is pull adults you can't pull
eggs you can't pull immature mites can't
fly so you really can't pull mites
either so really again this could only
be for flying adults and it's possibly
you know they've already on your crop
laid lots of eggs I just I just see
growers trying to do a lot of this stuff
and I don't to say they get in over
their head but we don't have enough
specifics yet and enough research yet to
support a lot of that and growers have
to stay focused on maintaining these
plants which tends not to happen again I
was at a facility out on the west coast
earlier this year and again we have
banker plans you know the peppers
they're sitting around I'm like well are
you putting aureus on them and they're
like no and I'm like think get rid of
them you know because again they're just
a breeding ground for broad might
Western flower thrips onion thrips
spider mites you know a fado if you're
not going to do the program let's double
back to the interesting comment you made
about cover crops indoors because of
course poly culture is becoming
increasingly popular both outdoor
cannabis growing and now indoor and
there are some great examples of it
because of course the you know having
these other species of plants not having
them the mono crop is really great for
the rhizosphere and for you know the
plants to be able to communicate and
share nutrition and all this great kind
of stuff but but you're suggesting that
these these these indoor cover crops are
also a potential threat will you speak
to that a little bit more yeah well I'm
gonna say this and I've said this a
million times
you know when growing indoors is not
like growing outside and outside when
you do cover
crops you know you've got the natural
ecology the natural soil ish I'm giving
you air quotes on that natural soil
because we all know soils been altered
too much
you also have thousands of insects and
mites that can move in naturally and
help keep things a little more in check
when you enclose yourself into an indoor
grow that sealed up it is nothing like
outdoors you don't have rain wish which
washes pests and bugs off of plants you
don't have again parasitoids just flying
in you don't have all these different
beneficial showing up and basically do
you put up a giant wall against
beneficials getting in
and so when pests get in that's why they
go really crazy indoors because there's
nothing really to control them and
that's again kind of the issue inside is
because a lot of these cover crops have
complex pest systems and people don't
think about managing pests on them so
now essentially you've got two crops
you've got your cannabis and you've got
your cover crop you have to research
what pests and diseases those are going
to get and you have to treat those for
the pests and the diseases now yeah
that's frustrating too especially since
you know I mean because most of the
folks who are going to be running an
indoor polyculture environment they are
probably also the mindset that they are
going to be using beneficial insects and
so that's that that's great on its face
but listening to you describe all of the
different variables that help us when we
are growing outdoors reproducing those
indoors becomes less and less likely
based on you know time resources and
just the difficulty in trying to for
example you know bring in the variety of
beneficial insects that we're able to
get outside so let me so so clearly
you're not a big fan of of you know
cover cropping or probably more
accurately green mulching indoors but
let's turn that on its head for a second
if somebody were to going to polyculture
indoor
even if it's a thin sliced window what
do you think would be the best way for
them to go about it like is there a you
know if 95% of people who are going to
do it are going to do it wrong is there
a 5% best practice that you would
recommend for people who are dead set on
doing polyculture indoors and what would
be your best advice for them well first
of all you know and this is the thing
that you know I've banged my head on the
wall kind of thing because again I get
contacted by numerous growers every
single day and a lot of the polyculture
living soil people freak out when they
find bugs and and the thing is is if
you're trying to recreate indoor ecology
you you're going to have bugs in there
and remember you know less than 1% of
insects are really a problem of economic
you know what we consider economic
importance where they're going to damage
the plants but people want to do this
stuff inside but want to see no insects
at all but a lot of the insects that I
am getting images of are just absolutely
benign things that you know to try
Devore's or you know may be specific to
feeding on the cover crop but if you
wanted to do it the first thing I would
do is I would pick your plant I would
research that plant and look is is it a
host for spider mites is it a hose for
cotton melon a food is it a host for
onion thrips and I would look to make
sure that none not not can it just feed
on it occasionally but is it a major
problems I mean I'm going to pick the
worst possible cover crop ever soybeans
the soybeans are beans the you know
we're talking about four and they're
great for breed being spider mites right
their soybeans would be off your list
I'm also pretty anti marigold because
when we were marigold and greenhouses
they get every pest problem known to man
and they get spider mites they get
thrips issues they have a lot of disease
issues people like to hold marigolds in
this you know holy
vessel of this is amazing plan this is
true you're so right but the problem is
people don't understand genetics they
don't understand breeding a lot of you
know old stuff that refers to marigolds
are actually pop marigolds which are
calendula which are not today's
marigolds and today's marigolds and this
is a whole nother rabbit-hole discussion
these plants that you get today and this
seed you get today have been bred for
human characteristic what do we want we
want them this height we want them this
color we want the big showy petals
they've not been bred for feeding
beneficials for feeding pollinators and
things like that and we bred a lot of
the characteristics out of these plants
that insects needs you look at a miracle
and how tightly pedaled it is how is a
beneficial supposed to get down in there
to get pollen and nectar if you look at
some of the older simpler marigolds that
are more single pedaled
you know it's you have easier access
there same thing when you look at roses
the older Rose varieties that open up
the bees and beneficials can get in
there to the palm end nectar these new
really tight balled fancy roses they
can't have access to it and in some
plant species they've actually bred to
the point they're basically no pollen or
it's useless pollen in the plant so you
have to be really careful about looking
these plants understand just saying
marigold marigolds like saying almost
automobile there's it's a generic term
it can encompass multiple you know again
it could be calendula it could be
different things so it's too broad of a
term so you know I know a lot of people
look at clover and then of course I get
the messages they're freaking out they
got thrips clover mites
oh cool reminds yes and they're very
visible and but again thrips the
secondary way now the question is is
what thrips do they have on the clover
and will it feed on cannabis and this is
where it gets into identification and
you can't just use a hand lens normally
to identify thrip species to tell the
difference between like western flower
onion pretty much have to have super
high magnification or put them under
microscope which is high magnification
you know a few of them like you know
kind of thrips that's easier to identify
but that's super high magnification but
you know you can't just stand there and
say this is that without again you got
to get in there and look at their little
hairs basically on their bodies to tell
them apart
and this is why it's complicated and
what frustrates me when I go to a lot of
these meetings is people just
oversimplify it they're like oh just
apply this cover crop and you'll never
have any past issues if it worked that
way why do I have all these growers
contacting me every single day so I'm
going to go write down that I'm going to
I'm going to put salt in that wound
Suzanne so so certainly people who are
commercial growers who are listening you
know and they've got a dedicated IPM
person and they are you know hopefully
have got the time to do the kind of
research that we've been calling for so
far so that a a proper program can be
developed for their bio region and
particularly their types of you know
environment and plants whether
indoor/outdoor a greenhouse but the vast
majority of people who are listening
today are not commercial growers you
know they've got somewhere between you
know 4 and 40 plants in their yard and
they don't necessarily have the time and
access to resources to do an entire
program with the touring that you have
done so far and and I don't know I know
that I'm talking about an entire country
but bear with me have you come across
any plans that you think are you know
pretty good surefire plants to plant
alongside your cannabis that are going
to provide either some banker or trap
benefits so that people who the same is
the same people who are just like oh I
heard that Mary roads are good around my
cannabis plants so they so they grew
marigolds right and we now know that's
not appropriate but but even though we
know that done properly this is a bigger
question before we go to commercial is
there are there any like varieties that
you think are generally going to help
and if you're good
to plant anything without doing your
proper homework you should go with these
well you know you should ask me what I
do in my yard because you know even
though I don't grow cannabis here you
know I grow tomatoes and I ring all my
tomato plants with alyssum all of them
because we know and there's been good
research looking at this alyssum is a
really good pollen nectar source for
aureus the minut Peyer bug which loves
thrips which will feed on spider mites
and loves cannabis plants whenever I
scout cannabis outdoors whether it be
New York State or California or Oregon
Washington I always find aureus in
cannabis so we know it loves that crop
and again it needs pollen and nectar and
your cannabis isn't going to have pollen
and nectar Tomatoes early on don't have
pollen and nectar but I put the alyssum
around them and then that will feed them
and commercial growers actually grow
pots of alyssum early in the season and
then they sprinkle aureus on there and
they build the aureus population up on
them so that when the thrips come in the
spring they have a whole army of aureus
there for you I will tell you aureus
though needs at least twelve hours of
sunlight or it will you know go into
whether they call diapause which is
basically you know insect hibernation
and you know in the southern regions we
don't worry about that too much but up
north and greenhouses when we start the
alyssum early we just put them under you
know if you don't have artificial
lighting we just put them under
artificial lighting to make sure they
get 12 hours of light first but for the
homeowner the smaller grow you know you
can buy a lissome from seed and you can
just start it I would not recommend
buying finished plants in because you do
not know what they've been treated with
you don't know if they've been treated
with an insecticide you don't know if
they've been treated with a PG R or
anything so it's better off to grow them
yourself
us to make sure but I think alyssum is
one that we have a really good track
record in ornamentals and vegetable with
with that we're seeing it's slowly being
adopted into cannabis and it's got a
good track record of being a good banker
plant as well as a nectar and pollen
resource plant fabulous so we're gonna
go ahead and take our first short break
and be right back you are listening to
shaping fire and my guest today is
entomologist Suzanne Wainwright evans
the bug lady for years organic
cultivators have been looking for a
replacement for using peat moss peat
moss has long been the go-to soil
amendment for water retention in
container growing but organic growers
know that peat moss is an unsustainable
resource and the mining of peat bogs
destroys habitat and releases sequester
carbon but peat must work so well that
many have continued to use it but now
there's finally a revolutionary
replacement for peat moss that shares
the same benefits while also being
sustainable pittmoss sounds and acts
like peat moss but instead of being
mined from fragile ecosystems it
actually is made from up cycled organic
paper and tree bark pit Moss is
excellent at retaining water in your
substrate and creating air pockets and
tiny living environments for microbes
pittmoss instantly increases aeration
nutrient absorption and water
conservation to carefully and locally
sourced pit Moss is the result of
decades long research into the use of
recycled paper fibers pit Moss has the
fluffy nature of peat moss and handles
exactly the same and like peat moss pit
Moss is inert so it won't change your ph
available in a range of preparations
including a nutrient enhanced blend a
coco quar blend and also as an organic
soil conditioner with no added nutrients
pittmoss is also available as an animal
bedding so go to pittmoss calm now to
learn more that's pee itt mo SS calm
growing healthier more sustainable
plants pittmoss for many transitioning
to organic gardening can be overwhelming
there's so much to learn about soil
biology and fermentation bio flux
mented plant booze from ever flux
simplifies organic farming so you can
start growing organically today invented
by a California farmer growing organic
for 40 years bio flux is a fermented
natural farming preparation for those
who want a natural micro booster without
having to brew their own this
extraordinary chemical free growth and
terpene enhancer improves root
development accelerates the conversion
of organic matter into humus increases
nutrient use efficiency and up jake and
increases beneficial microbes activity
in addition to the bio flux fermented
plant booster ever flux also makes an
activated biochar called taro flux that
is infused with the bio flux plant
booster imagine combining the buffering
and rhizosphere enhancing qualities of
biochar infused with a range of
earthworm castings insect frass kelp and
crab meal moister shell and other
ingredients I'm using Tara flux infused
biochar the summer myself and it smells
alive rich and potent these products
have been scientifically proven to match
yields and increase flower quality and
pest resistance when compared to
traditional NPK inputs if you are
looking for reliable organic fertilizers
that will free you up to focus on other
aspects of your garden consider using
the range of all-natural regenerative
fertilizers and natural biostimulants
from ever flux find out more at ever
flux technologies calm or by following
their instagram at ever flux while I
love growing under the Sun there's a lot
of good reasons to grow indoors and if
you're like most folks you want a
lighting source that grows high yielding
healthy plants without using excessive
amounts of electricity BIOS lighting
creates biological lighting solutions
that brings the natural brilliance of
the outdoors into your grow room BIOS
lighting has the attributes that I look
for in a horticultural lighting solution
I've bought those cheap lights online
and they're difficult to work with and
fail in no time in contrast my BIOS LED
light is industrial grade to last a long
time it is ip66 wet rated so little full
your overspray won't harm it it is easy
to clean without taking it down and of
course the most important aspect it is
built for the exact light spectrum I
want four
great yielding healthy cannabis plants
and it doesn't hurt that their lighting
rigs look badass too many horticultural
LED lighting systems are based on
irrelevant performance metrics and
people love to argue online about these
numbers I prefer to judge on par photon
efficiency and how happy my plants are
and the BIOS lights exceed my
expectations in these categories BIOS
lights have an optimized broad spectrum
that maximizes photosynthesis and plant
growth while also providing the ideal
conditions for superior part efficacy
and a comfortable visual experience I
also love their attentive and over
educated customer service folks BIOS
starts with a team of biologists before
getting the electrical engineers
involved they have studied how light
impacts cannabis plants and devised an
overall strategy that works I encourage
you to check out their website at BIOS
lighting dot-com to learn more about how
this strategy can work for you and
shaping fire listeners can get a special
deal use the discount code shaping fire
all one word no caps for 10% off your
entire purchase
that's BIOS lighting calm welcome back
you are listening to shaping fire I'm
your host Shengo Louis and our guest
this week is entomologist Suzanne
Wainwright Evans the bug lady so Suzanne
you know we were talking in the last set
about how you know folks want to be poly
culture and organic and regenerative and
when they try to do that indoors
often they've got a headspace that they
also want sterility right and one of the
things that we know from trying to do
regenerative agriculture outdoors is
that civility is not really our goal
outdoors because we are trying to create
an entire ecosystem back and forth with
the ecosystem around us you know we're
trying to blend with the ecosystem and
not stay separate so that the natural
benefits of the outdoor environment can
be supportive of our cannabis garden as
well well indoors of course we are not
getting the benefits of being you know
couched in a regular organic environment
and so indoor folks they try to walk
this line between we need to keep the
grow clean and
and air quotes sterile so that we don't
run into any disease or pest pressure
but at the same time you know doing that
is not going to be very effective for
trying to replicate an ecosystem what
kind of advice do you give folks who are
trying to walk that line well I think
it's a very difficult line to walk and
again there's this mindset of you can
reproduce outdoors indoors I just I
don't think it's completely possible you
you can be sustainable but you also then
understand that you are running at
higher risk of pests and disease by
doing that I know that's not what you
want to hear but that's especially over
the last few years working with more
regenitive growers is is what I see over
and over again if you're gonna not
change out your soil for example and
you're pumping in you know all these
fungi and bacteria and topdressing with
compost
you know mites and insects are going to
find their way in because decomposers
are going to want to live in that soil
and you're going to have a lot of that
kind of stuff living in the soil and
just again today I was contacted by
somebody else said oh my gosh there's
all these mites in my soil how do I kill
them well they're most likely just
either to try divorce or they're feeding
on fungus or some kind of soil decompose
or kind of thing and they're not hurting
anything but they can get to such high
numbers that you literally can scrape
them off the edge of the beds with
credit cards because they get so heavy
and people don't want to see that but if
you're going to grow in these kinds of
systems that's the kind of stuff you're
going to have to deal with and that's
just that the trade-off and you're going
to have to expect to see you're going to
have a lot more springtails
you're going to have a lot more again of
these decomposing kind of insects and
mites and those systems the question I
get all the time is do they damage the
plants and honestly we don't know and
you know things like springtails which
are kalimba 'la you know we honestly
they haven't been studied as extensively
and the
our numerous species of kalimba so
someone just contact me and say they
have springtails you know super-high
numbers are they going to cause damage
to my crop honestly I don't know because
we don't know what species it is and
does that species actually cause damage
because in Europe they do have problems
in like in theory and production with
springtails damaging the roots on an
theory improper busy trying to kill them
where oftentimes over here and the US
it's seen as a sign of soil health again
I think this comes down to different
species and the different environments
and what's going on so you can't just
make a broad blanket statement that
they're good or bad but the reality is
is if you have a high organic matter
soil you're going to end up with a lot
of them and you're just going to have to
learn to live with them and it brings us
back to you know the you know your your
gospel which is identification is
everything and it's interesting you know
I tore quite a few regenerative cannabis
gardens and how few of them I also see
people having a microscope nearby and
what I continually tell people is you
know it's one thing when you are going
to do kind of like a a non regenerative
synthetic grow when your best practice
is kind of like kill everything right
and and you're just kind of like carpet
bombing your grow with with the things
but but but in a regenerative grow when
you're like okay we only really want to
get rid of the 1% of the pests that may
actually be a threat the only way you're
going to do that is if you get educated
on identifying these these pests and and
and have a microscope which honestly you
should probably have to be making sure
that your compost is active anyway and I
can imagine that you are busy giving you
know lessons to people when you tour
there grows that says you know you need
a bench over here with a microscope
well I generally I find that most
growers don't know how to use
microscopes and if they have microscopes
they don't take care of them which is
painful to me they don't keep the covers
on them because speaking from someone
that had to have their microscope
recently one
microscopes recently serviced future
microscopes cleaned it's $300 put a
cover on it to keep the dust out of it
because yes there's dust in grows but
that's why I really push people the Dino
lights because it's it's it's sealed you
don't have to worry about you know stuff
getting in there they're easy to use you
can take pictures because when you say
microscope microscopes are meant to be
used with slides and a lot of the
insects growers aren't going to slide
mount insects it is a pain in the
backside to do you got to put the
special glue mount down I use like a
little one hair bristle brush to get
their legs in position and get the slide
cover on that's not going to happen
dissecting scopes are more I think would
be appropriate but remember a microscope
or a dissecting scope don't necessarily
come with the camera so now you got to
buy a camera and that's why a dino light
is so easy because it's essentially a
dissecting scope with a built-in camera
and that way you can easily take
pictures and send them because learning
to use a microscope is a whole thing in
itself and I when I saw you when I saw
you present with the Dyna scope at
regenerative conference in Humboldt
I was really blown away by it but I was
I had the impression that it did not
have the sensitivity for everything that
I might need in the garden and I was
thinking oh might as well not get it
because I'm still going to need a
microscope at some point anyway and and
what I'm hearing you say now is actually
making me think well if I don't actually
need the microscope if actually what I
need is a dissection scope that the tool
that you showed us the Dyna scope
actually may be the one tool for for all
the gardeners needs is that your
experience well I don't say all the
needs because I not forgot not prying
out for looking at compost tea compost
you need a microscope when it comes
unpacked for insect stuff you know the
first thing I bought 20 years ago
well first big fancy thing I bought for
was a dissecting scope not a microscope
a dissecting scope you can put a leaf
under you can cut a branch on
because you can put you know things with
height on them a microscope you can only
put things with slides so you have bugs
on the leaf
you don't put a leaf under a microscope
you got to lift the bug off you got to
put it on a slide you got to put a slide
cover on and do all that a dissecting
scope you can just slap it under and
look at it and away you go
a Dynalite basically functions as a
dissecting scope with a built-in camera
now you can buy cameras for your
microscope or your dissecting scope but
when you buy your microscope or Dyna
scope you have to I mean microscope or
dice a dissecting scope you have to make
sure it's a tri ocular camera ocular
system so you have one for each eye and
then you have a third hole that you can
mount a camera on because it is I mean
the pictures people send me in this you
know this is where my grapes - you know
if you want free ID at least meet me
halfway and send me decent pictures you
know stop putting your camera up to the
eye hole on your microscope and trying
to get an image that's blurred around
the edge and all that I mean you know
you can get a Dynalite the entry-level
one is like a hundred bucks I think the
one that's $325 is a better place to be
but you can even get a decent dissecting
scope for like 300 dollars these days
and we're not talking you know yes you
can go spend as much as you want you
know I
you can spend ten thousand dollars on a
microscope but for most cannabis people
the the ones from celestron makes a
really nice dissecting scope and I
really love the celestron microscope I
love that microscope if if you're
somebody that's going to spend ten hours
a day at a microscope counting you know
cells or things like that yes you need
the $10,000 microscope because it will
really reduce the eye strain if you're
just slapping something they're looking
for five minutes and then you're done
you can use these three $400 microscopes
and they work perfectly fine and the one
from celestron that microscope I've had
it now a year and I absolutely love it
I have nothing negative to say and it's
a triaxial one and you can mount a
camera right on it one of the things
that's great about the Dyna scope too is
that it's so compact that it's really
easy to safely pack in your gear and
take with you either out into the field
or you know if you're if you're doing
the rounds over multiple commercial
grows it's just you know most of us
think about us a microscope or a
dissection scope it's very it tends to
be more you set it up and it stays and
it lives in this one place but the Dyna
scope is really you know it's it's
highly mobile so for so for folks who
are going to forget the name Dino scope
I'll go ahead excuse me Dino light like
I just did I'll go ahead and put a link
on the page for the podcast episode at
shaping fire com so going back to the
banker plants in the trap plant Suzanne
you know a lot of people have a
difference of opinion of actually where
you plant them with container gardening
some folks believe that you should be
planting them below the cannabis plant
in the same pot so that they're close
whereas you know from what I'm gathering
from what you've been saying so far and
how I like to do it is you actually put
the plant in its own pot along the edges
of the growing area what do you find is
the best practice I think having them in
their own pots because if they get a
pest problem and they're in a pot you
just pick the pot up and chuck it out
the door and it's gone and with the
aphid banker plant systems we replace
those like every two weeks so it's a
constant revolving door and lissome if
it gets too hot it can stop blooming and
now you've got all this you know just
greenery in your pot absolutely do them
in separate pots they have different
watering requirements they're not the
same plant
I would not plant them right in the pots
I would have them in pots you can remove
the other thing is let's say okay let's
just pretend you know everything's going
great you've got great aureus going in
there with your alyssum but oh my gosh
now we've got him for us it might well
you're going to have to
Spray because I've said this before and
I know a lot of people hate me but you
know I do not think that any of the
biocontrol agents are really controlling
him for us it might all our successes
have been coming in and spraying with a
good solid horticultural oil now if
you've got those banker plants and
they're planted in your pots and you
come in and spray they're going to get
oil in the banker plants and possibly
could either damage the plant because I
don't think alyssum really wants a
coating of oil and also it could kill
some of the insects and you know if
you're going to spray you know something
like Bavaria or I cereal you know
whatever you're going to spray so the
banker plants what we do this is what we
do in ornamental systems as we go
through we just gather up all the banker
plants we take them away we do our spray
we wait a few days and then we bring the
banker plants right back in yeah so that
way you want to keep them in their own
pot so they're mobile you can remove
them and you can bring them back and you
can swap them out when you want and and
honestly that you know if you're going
to be properly taking care of these
plants they're they're you know the food
that they're rhizosphere wants or
whatever the soil requirements are
likely going to be different than what
you want to be doing for your cannabis
anyway yes and you know I had one grower
that he does the diet important again
this is ornamentals but again you know
I've had a bajillion years of experience
in ornamentals than what I've been doing
is how can we take that knowledge and
apply it to cannabis but this one
ornamental grower he keeps lined along
the wall of his greenhouse Mullin plants
with another beneficial insect called
duyst's IFAs it likes thrips white flies
and also snack on spider mites and then
when he has a pest issue then he picks
up a couple pots of the Mullen plants
and he goes and sets them and he just
sisters them next to where the pest
problem is and leaves him there so that
the the die safe is then move into the
crop clean up the problem then
eventually he moves the Mullen plants
back together into their lineup along
the wall where the die psifas can just
sit there and continually breed on the
mullen so he uses them as like a hot
spot treatment so again another reason
why to have them in pots yeah that's a
really great best practice that's an
awesome idea so when choosing them I
mean certainly
it sounds like the the majority of the
time we are going to choose our plants
based on the specificity of what our
pest is and what our alternative
snacking pest will be for our beneficial
insect and and really that will kind of
reverse engineer which plant we want to
go with to sister with with the cannabis
plants there is a secondary awareness
that folks have about annuals and
perennials because some of these plants
that people have a tendency to use
they've got shorter life cycles and and
they really just want to plan it and
forget it right which is part of the
problem but how do you explain to people
or get them thinking in the right way
about you know matching the lifecycle
with of the plant the the the banker or
trap plant with the lifecycle of the
cannabis and my suspicion is you're just
going to say grow a whole ton of them in
their own pots and swap them in and out
yes
yeah they just answered your own
question right on as I was asking and
I'm like I think she's already taught
this today that's essentially right and
you know what and this is not to say
down the road somebody may find the
magic bean that you know you can plan
under cannabis and it thrives and you
know it has no pest issues and but as of
yet we've not found anything like that
and I think having them in separate pots
and try to look for you know again where
there has been a little research done
and not just anecdotal stuff because you
know I mean I know anecdotal is often
times where research starts but I'm just
seeing a lot of people getting
themselves into trouble because remember
people generally don't call me when
everything's hunky-dory people contact
me when there's a problem so I get to
hear about what everybody's done to get
to that point and I definitely see a
pattern of you know cover crops and you
know same soil with multiple multiple
Harvin's planted in it and pest numbers
are just going to build in those
situations
yeah there really is a fine area between
you know citizen science and bro science
you know one of them you're actually
testing things and the other one you're
probably not it's just how you learned
it from your friend or your mentor and
and you know we cannabis people we've
been on our own for a long time and we
haven't had access necessarily to legit
entomologists so I think it's going to
take a little more time for not only
their research to come about and to
actually be done but also for you know
cannabis cultivators to realize that you
know there there is useful information
available outside of cannabis culture so
I think you're going to hate this next
question sue Zampa let's go for it
anyway because you know you are you you
know you are very clear that you know
you have to be aware of your bio region
right and that you know when you answer
a question it's going to be a different
answer for California versus Florida
versus Maine and that all makes sense
however with the cultivators in the
different parts of the country each
having their own sorts of pests that
they need to deal with how do you
recommend like a mental methodology how
do you suggest thinking through what
trap plant or what pests the cultivator
is going to want to think they which one
so they want to prepare for is what I'm
trying to say like you you want to
prepare for the pests that you don't
have yet but but there is a wide range
of pests that that could be a problem
with cannabis plants
so what hints do you give to cultivators
to kind of be precedent prescient and
look into the future of what pests you
want to prepare for because these are
the ones that you're most likely to get
where you live well one of the things is
that for the indoor grows we're seeing a
lot of the same stuff because they're a
bit excluded from you know the outdoor
ecology is when we have you know outdoor
production or greenhouses where the
sides roll up or
hi Tunnel situation where we do have
regional stuff but I you know the one
thing that has been very interesting to
watch is basically how the cannabis
industry has managed to spread their
pests throughout their own industry
because you look at the cannabis aphid
which was somewhat isolated to the west
coast and now is everywhere on the East
Coast and it's moved through people
sharing plant material and cuts and
they've the industry has done it to
themselves they they've completely
shared him present might across all US
and Canada they've totally shared again
the cannabis ef'n they've shared route a
food because even though the Rudy but
species we're dealing with has other
hosts it's not something you're going to
walk out and find in your yard like to
spot spider mite yeah you find those
everywhere but you know these cannabis
specific pests I mean everybody wants to
blame the soil company you want to blame
you know your neighbor but but the
reality is is you brought in plants that
were infected to begin with and so one
of the things I you know where did your
plants come from look at your genetics
if you came from the west coast it's a
good chance you brought hemp Russert or
cannabis aphid right along with it
where if someone's on the East Coast and
like okay we're growing from seed then
they're at very low risk of having
cannabis aphid or hand press it might so
I don't think there needs to be
necessary preventive programs for them
but again you know cuts from other
production facilities especially if they
originated wet West Coast man you better
be prepared especially for him for us it
might and that's that's the problem so I
mean when I think about a program we we
follow the genetics of the plants and
what's their history and then that gives
me you know what kind of risk are we at
and so that's the first place I start
and then you know we look at what their
history of pests have been you know have
you had problems the two spot spider
mites have you had you know history of
you know a fado what species and you
know we look through that to try to put
a program together
and then always you know such a good
scouting program so that if there is a
new pest issue that pops up its detected
early and then that way then we can get
in and decide the best treatment method
which often times when something new
errs discovered you know it may be doing
a knockdown spray maybe the best initial
option unfortunately in most states
what's allowed on cannabis the stuff has
a previous in cannabis is our the very
broad spectrum pesticides they're non
selective in the sense that it kills
good and bad and you know just kills
everybody so often we after we spray we
have to come in and then re-release all
the beneficials where you look at
industries again ornamentals and
vegetables and you know we can be
releasing parasitic wasps and we can be
releasing predatory mites but if we have
a flare-up of a to spot spider mite we
can come in and there's this one
chemistry it only kills like five
species of spider mites and we can spray
it over there it doesn't it only kills
the two spot spider mites and their eggs
it doesn't kill the predatory mites it
doesn't kill the parasitoids it doesn't
kill anything else and so that's what
makes cannabis growing hard is that the
few products you do have are non
selective and they kill everything good
bad and indifferent and so that adds to
the challenge there with with managing
pests and putting programs together and
honestly a lot of these products that
you know are not EPA registered you
don't really know even what's in them
yeah and then we brought in the cannabis
scene so many times that not everything
that's in the product is even on the
label nope and that's why you know I'm
pretty preachy about using EPA
registered pesticides you know and it
was like oh my god pesticides but soaps
and oils are pesticide only means it
kills pests so a good horticultural oil
can kill a pest but it's very safe for
humans to use it's it's it's interesting
because you see some products that have
the same active ingredients and ones EPA
registered and one may not be because
sometimes people will still go ahead and
EPA they'll go and register their
products even though it's not required
on some of these exempt products we keep
on coming to this idea that either the
research hasn't been done for cannabis
or the products have not been that that
at work well have not been you know
properly crossed over to cannabis so one
way or another cannabis is not on par
with all of the work that's been done in
ornamentals due to its historical
prohibition in your seat you kind of be
are able to look both up and down the
railway right you're able to look at
where the cultivators are and the
problems that they are experiencing but
you're also able to look upstream at the
vendors who would you know theoretically
be selling these solutions to
cultivators because they're the same
folks that are selling solutions into
ornamental what are you seeing are you
seeing that these companies are like oh
my god cannabis is going to be so
valuable and so now they are all
hardcore moving into research to cross
apply these these solutions and to come
up with new products or are they kind of
sitting on their hands because they
don't necessarily want to play with
cannabis folk well it's not that they
don't want to play with cannabis put
folk when you just look at sheer acreage
of cannabis in the United States there's
not much realistically and whether it's
a cannabis plant or it's a cornfield if
you're going to use traditional
pesticides it's generally going to be
this that per acre the same amount of
spray so if you develop products for
corn you're going to be able to sell an
insane amount of chemistry if you're
going to sell to a you know cannabis you
know there's the markets in a way not
there it's not worth their time because
they're not going to get the the money
this is the exact same problem actually
ornamentals have and realistically
ornamentals when you look at pesticide
usage over all they use a very small
amount and so really the products often
we get in ornamentals are ones that were
developed for you know soybeans corn you
know big AG and then they're like okay
can there be
application in ornamentals for this and
then they see if they can make them fit
because again overall the ornamental
market is still really not a big
business as far as big AG is concerned
compared to you know again corn soybeans
or even just turf and so cannabis will
probably sister right along with
ornamentals and be considered a
specialty crop kind of like cut herbs
and that basically in ornamental again
we just kind of get the crumbs in a way
now we still get good products but you
know when we get a new pass like right
now in Florida we're dealing with this
hibiscus bud weevil is any chemical
company going to take the time to
develop a chemistry that's going to take
ten years it's going to cost millions
and millions of dollars to treat for
that pest absolutely not because they'll
never get the return on it and it's the
same thing in cannabis its I don't think
it has nothing to do with the fact it's
cannabis it has to do with shear acreage
now if outdoor hemp ever gets to the
levels being grown that like corn
soybeans wheat you know and all that's
being grown at well then they'll
definitely be products for that market
and then it will probably be looked at
see okay can we get a specialty label
for yeah it'll trickle down to THC
products yes yeah that's exactly what
will happen and you know I see mixed
growers out there too because there are
some growers that will just never use a
synthetic pesticide on cannabis you know
that's just and that's fine you know
that's I'm not judging anybody there are
other people that are like oh my god I
can't wait till we have registered
pesticides to make this growing a lot
easier I mean you know you have people
all the way across the board and some
people are in the middle and just like
you know just give me what works and so
it will be interesting to see how if it
ever you know we need to it's all the
legal stuff becoming federally legal so
that the EPA can register products and
and all that stuff but even if then
let's just say tomorrow that EPA
products could be registered through the
EPA for indoor cannabis it's still going
to be years before products will readily
come available we might be able to get
some special use labels which can be
pushed through and those you know our
temporary use labels but you still need
research to back up that it's safe and
cuz you know cannabis is somewhat
considered more of a food crop my guess
is though is that probably the tobacco
companies have already been doing a lot
of testing and they probably got a lot
of research already in their back pocket
just waiting that we don't know about
because it's you know still a lot of
secret secret stuff because there is big
money in this and I think there's
probably more research done than anybody
knows but you can't publicly let anybody
know you've done the research right they
don't want to they don't want to give up
their position or or suggest what
they're working on IPU eyes sounds like
for the for the time being we're going
to be putting together like various
biological hacks and and paying higher
prices when products do come out so
let's go ahead and take our last short
break you are listening to shaping fire
and my guest today is entomologist
Suzanne Wainwright Evans the bug lady
one of the reasons why no-till cannabis
growing is so valued by farmers is
because the mycelium networks in the
soil remain established from year to
year and we know these fungal networks
are essential because they are the
nutrient super highways that extend far
and wide in the substrate to feed your
plants
the trouble with growing in new soils or
blended cocoa substrates is that it
takes most of the plant's life just to
create these mycelium highways Dino
Michael endo mycorrhizal fungi inoculant
reduces that time and gets your plant
eating a wider array of nutrients faster
and it's three times the concentration
of the current leading brand in the u.s.
at 900 propagules per gram of - fungal
species selected specifically for
cannabis cultivation this new product
called Dino mica is the result of 30
years of research and trials at the
volcanic a Greek ultra Research
Institute in Israel it has also been
vigorously trialed by cannabis and food
growers
the us since the product first arrived
here last year you may have already even
heard about dynamite go by its original
name dynamite
now dynamite go is available at grow
shops and online in the United States
for the first time I love using dynamite
go to both speed up the growth of
mycelium networks in the soil but also
as a bio stimulant to make clone
cuttings more virile you can see side by
sides showing the comparative growth on
their Instagram at Dino Maiko if you
demand reliable growing results and
appreciate the importance of an active
root zone in creating a thriving plant I
encourage you to check out Dino Maiko at
Dino Maiko calm and find out where you
can get yours
that's dy n oh my co.com whether you are
starting with new beds or pots or if you
want to add some zing to tired soil
choose dynamite go to maximize your
plants potential Dino my co endo
mycorrhizal inoculants if you listen to
shaping fire and you grow your own
cannabis chances are high that you are
very particular about the inputs you use
for growing people like us painstakingly
self educate on cannabis nutrients and
techniques so we can cultivate the best
tasting and cleanest flowers possible
and when we go to purchase those
nutrients we want to be sure that our
supplier shares our values and is
providing exceptional quality this is
why I recommend build a soil calm to my
friends who care about quality build a
soil empowers organic growers to do
their best work by sourcing and shipping
only the finest cannabis growing
supplies from organic inputs soils soil
testing and pots to Lights growing tents
sprayers and cover crops build a soil
founder Jeremy Silva doesn't just stock
his store with what's available he goes
deep to personally vet each product for
quality and determine that there isn't a
better version of the product that he
could be selling because of this arduous
process you know that your options on
build a soil calm have been carefully
curated to create the
results you are looking for not only
that but the build a soil way is a
philosophy that will permeate your
interaction with the company from
website design to pricing and shipping
to after purchase support Jeremy and his
team always strive to do their best and
give you the best customer service in
the business
check out build a soil dot-com today for
top-tier quality cultivation supplies
and a friends and family buying
experience and check out their
educational videos and extraordinary
social media while you're there to
quality organic growing supplies at
build a soil calm growing cannabis in
greenhouses is taking over the cannabis
industry an efficient and effective
blend of sunshine grown terpene profiles
and the controlled environment of indoor
greenhouses can be the best of both
worlds for many greenhouse operators
though building their greenhouse before
gaining insight into how cannabis
greenhouses differ from ornamental crops
can be the start of a world of hurt erik
Branstad and his team at greenhouse
advisory group have the experience and
technical know-how to help you avoid
these pitfalls erik Branstad has been
helping cannabis growers find locations
design build and equip their greenhouses
for over a decade first starting in
Northern California but expanding over
the last five years to helping clients
throughout the world he has an
impeccable reputation for both depth of
knowledge and kindness and communication
you can hear Erik explains some of the
challenges facing cannabis greenhouses
and how to overcome them in episode
number 41 of the shaping fire podcast no
matter where I go in the country good
people with smart backgrounds still are
making the mistake of building without
knowing cannabis and it causes them to
burn through capital and time fast
everyone has their own failure point for
some it is improper ventilation planning
for others it is surface temperatures of
the building or the plant's leaves or
both some folks that build their
greenhouse from scratch make really
basic errors like placement of the
greenhouse on the property or not
understanding the natural environment
where the greenhouse sits
some have even built a decent greenhouse
but are inefficient in their deploy
of light deprivation techniques and
never really hit their target yields
it's great when you learn from your
mistakes but it's even better when you
learn from the mistakes of others when
you bring on green house advisory group
you will learn from the mistakes of
their many clients and you'll take
advantage of the best practices
developed by Eric Branstad over his
years of working with clients just like
you from location development to
choosing a builder and tricking out your
new green house or retrofitting or
rescuing your failing green house Eric
will help you through it
visit green house advisory group com to
learn more and connect with Eric and his
team that's green house Advisory Group
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire I'm your host Shengo Louis
and our guest this week is entomologist
Suzanne Wainwright Evans the bug lady so
let's take a one-step back to the end of
the last set Suzanne we were talking
about the cost associated with buying
these products and I kind of make this
you know off off-the-cuff comment at the
end as before going to break that you
know we people in cannabis are used to
paying more for things we call you know
the green tax right that we all have to
pay a little bit more for things because
there hasn't been a lot of research done
on a lot of the products that we need
and everybody kind of because the
cannabis is taboo nature everybody
thinks they can kind of stick it to us a
little bit but during the break you're
all like yeah and cannabis people don't
really know how to shop right and I'm
like whoa now that's an interesting
thought so let's break that out for
everybody to hear huh what are your best
practices that cannabis folks should
know about how to shop for these
solutions to get the most bang for their
buck so yeah so what I find is why I
call it the cannabis tax which just you
know bug lady consulting does not charge
cannabis tax on consulting I charge the
same fee whether your ornamental
vegetables or cannabis we appreciate
that season yes well I mean it's to me
it's I mean and I know I get haters this
too but to me it's just another crop I
mean it's just another crop let's solve
the problem and you know move on but as
far as the economics so yes people think
that they can charge more to the
cannabis industry because there's this
idea that they can afford it I don't
think they can
because you know prices get I mean
there's more competition and growers
need to learn to grow without saying to
me it doesn't matter how much it costs
please do not say that to me because it
always matters how much it costs because
again you need to turn a profit if you
want your business to stay in business
what I recommend to my growers is that
when you need to buy products especially
let's say spray products you guys all
know I love with products off oil acts
it's one of my favorite things okay you
need to buy a product well don't go just
on the internet and in search and this
are there you need to get connected with
traditional horticultural supply
companies that have been servicing
greenhouses and nurseries for years
those tend to have your better pricing
because you're going to pay a premium
generally I mean occasionally you can
find a good price on the internet but
generally those companies are going to
work with you with these products and
get you better pricing also I mean I've
had numerous heart attacks over the
years looking at biocontrol agents and
what some of these cannabis people have
been paying you know a sachet that
should cost you know maybe 15 cents I've
seen cannabis people paying $2 through
distributors I know
again this always frustrates some people
but I you know when it comes to buying
the biocontrol agents I think it's
important to attempt to buy them direct
from the insec Therese because generally
you're going to get the best pricing the
bugs are going to come directly to you
from the in Sector II and you tend to
get better information because those
people are the most part trained on
their products I mean just as in the
industry there's some you know idiots
out there but for the most part that's
where you're going to get your best
information pricing also when you call
and ask for pricing because for the
biocontrol agents you are not going to
find pricing for them online if you are
a commercial grower or a larger hobby
grower
you know call them and you know give
them your size and say you know this is
how much you know we're planning on
doing and so that way you can get grower
pricing not necessarily you know retail
pricing off a website because again it's
unbelievable some of the prices that are
charged on some of these retail websites
that our distributors for biocontrol
agents so do your shopping and this is a
something that I recommend again to all
my growers is and you can't do it this
year because everything's canceled this
year but get to you know horticultural
trade shows too and that way you can get
connected with the horticultural again
professional companies that have been
around a long time that sell at what I
call fair pricing you know know are all
cannabis distributors get price gouging
absolutely not but is it happening
absolutely it is so just get connected
with you know these I don't say older
that sounds bad but you know as well
established companies that you know can
provide you biocontrol agents and
chemistry's at you know reasonable
pricing but I guess I should have said
it that way the the the spray products
fertilizers soils and things like that
but again the biocontrol agents I think
are a bit better coming direct from the
insectary it sounds like to that a lot
of these companies don't have their
their priceless online and so it's well
worth adding the extra step to email
them and ask for a price list even
though all of us you know want
convenience because by the time you know
after the after the day in the green
house or out outside by the time you get
around to shopping for this stuff it's
probably in the evening after your
dinner and folks really want a fast
solution and it sounds like what you're
saying is don't just buy from the the
cheapest ecommerce site that you can
find because there's probably going to
be more middlemen there and really it's
worth the extra effort to write to the
company get their priceless or catalogue
add that extra step because you'll be
creating a relationship where you'll be
paying less for a product over time
right yes and so I mean it's one thing
if oh my gosh we just need this product
fine pay whatever to get it but
you know if you know especially with
things like fertilizer I mean you're
going to do that over and over and over
and over again and you need to get some
with somebody that you know is is going
to provide I would say fair pricing
again I mean I just can't believe some
of the the markups I've seen like I'm
Priscilla's I saw online I think was $85
for 2004 similes where you can get them
from an insect reef or 15 yeah yeah yeah
there's there's a lot of there's a lot
of hustle going on in our scene right
now I your comment on when you need it
fast you know sometimes you just have to
get it and you'd pay a higher price and
you go and I was thinking about the same
thing about banker and trap plants for
example people who are at this point in
the season and they're hearing this
episode and they're like oh I think I
want to add some some you know helpful
companion plants to the garden before
the season's over and so you know you
recommend insightfully that you should
probably start with a seed so you are
growing your own and you know that it's
not bringing in any pesticides with it
however if people want to bring in a you
know pre you know starts or pre
established plants
is there a way for that to be reasonably
done or are you saying across the board
do not do this because it's a total mess
to try I think it's a huge risk because
I you know I I needed a foods what did I
do I went down to my local garden center
and bought some pepper plants because
you know what they had a fits on them
you know you could count on it
pretty much the thing is it's it's
interesting though you know when the
plants are grown in densities like that
they have pest issues you plant those
peppers out and if you put them in your
yard David's are going to be gone in a
few days because ladybirds surface
everybody comes in and cleans them out
you put them inside my guest bedroom
window and those aphids thrive to the
point you couldn't even see you couldn't
even see the plant through all the EFA's
it's very interesting because I did I
went down bought a bunch of plants but
some
the garden put some in the guest room
and the ones outside are you know three
feet tall and dark green leaves and the
ones in the guest room are just
encrusted in aphids it just shows you
the difference between indoor and
outdoor growing when just left to its
own because outside mother nature came
in and took care of it and as clean as
you think those plants are they're gonna
have something and you know alyssum it
can have thrips in it there's no doubt
about that
but you know the generally outside it
will bring in aureus which helps keep
the thrips level below what we call an
economic threshold if you were to just
buy a lisam and bring in thrips with no
aureus you bring them into your grow you
close the door what's going to happen
with those thrips the numbers are
probably going to go up and depending on
what species they may move into your
cannabis so that's why starting them
from seed so they're clean from the
beginning again it's really high-risk
and again often times when people
contact me they already know they're in
the dog house because they brought
plants in they shouldn't have done and
usually it's you know that oh my
neighbor
you know just needed me or my friend
need me to watch these couple plants for
him while he was out of town and roof so
this way I really push with commercial
growing facilities to have a quarantine
area it let's say you absolutely had to
bring either cannabis in or another
plant at least hold it for a week or two
separate so you can watch it and see if
any pest problems do develop but you
know for alyssum and pepper
I would absolutely grow those from seed
and we actually again you know back to
what we do in ornamentals which is
interesting because in ornamentals you
know what we do we look to the vegetable
industry to see what they do to manage
pests and then adapt it to what we can
do for ornamentals and that's what
cannabis is doing now we're looking to
ornamentals to see how we can adapt it
for that crop so there's a lot of us
looking across the fence and developing
these systems because the Banger plant
systems were more looked at for
vegetable production and then
ornamental guys kind of shanghaied it
and now the the canvas guys are going to
Shanghai which is fine this is what we
do look to other cropping systems and
adapt it for our growing situation but
for threats because you know I did get a
ton of people in the spring contact me
about three ups especially on the west
coast and when I was out traveling in
January in February on the west coast I
saw a lot of thrips out there so if we
like the thrifts banker plants weather
it well with the peppers we actually
start our peppers in winter that's when
we start our seeds because we really
want them blooming and having pollen and
nectar by February March again depending
on where you are in the US and then as
soon as they're blooming we start
inoculating them with the aureus the
minut pirate bug so the time you know I
will say the northern region we'll just
talk about that for right now wakes up
with insects and we start having thrips
issues in early spring you already have
the standing army of aureus all ready to
go you don't start your seeds in
springtime necessarily we actually start
the Banger plants before we start our
actual crops in spring so I know there's
somebody out here curious about this so
I'm going to go one more step down this
path and say we often will bring in
clones from other people that we've got
a question alene garden and we'll do
some sort of dip can we simply dip these
incoming banker plants and the same way
that we would a clone or does that not
work the same way because there's such a
wide variety of pests that could be on
them well so the the dips again there's
different dips for different target
pests and for things like thrips the
eggs are inside a plant tissue so dips
aren't going to do anything for that so
just just to get that out there um you
you can um you could dip them I'd be
very careful about doing it because like
I don't think there's been any dipping
research done on Alyssa and ELISA like
grow so fast I mean you really there's
no need to I mean you can just grow it
and also the dipping
kill the pests but again you don't know
if they've been treated with a pesticide
a systemic now this is the really kind
of weird not weird thing but most if you
had to go buy something then you
absolutely had no choice
honestly I would probably go to a big
box store and buy them over an
independent garden center and I know I
can hear all the haters already you ask
why well because the growers that I work
with that sell to big box stores like
Lowe's Home Depot Walmart they are not
allowed anymore to use neo Knick
pesticides the systemic pesticides which
can cause a lot of problems with things
like aureus where independent garden
centers have no restrictions on using
that kind of stuff so you are probably
safer that using again something from a
big-box retail place because they have
more restrictions on pesticide use
now I'm sure I'm going to get some hater
emails saying well we're independent we
don't use neo Nick yes there's going to
be independents that don't but they
don't have any restrictions on them
we're the guys that sell to the big box
stores do and I work close with a lot of
them and I you know we can't use Neo
Nicks they're gone from their programs
and what they've done is they've really
stepped up their bio control program
some of these larger greenhouses I work
with a metro line is one it's a hundred
and eighty acre greenhouse when they get
their bio control agents they're coming
on pallets because they're using so many
of them these days um I know that one of
the things that I dare say annoys you is
that when when folks see challenges in
their garden they immediately assume
that it's pass and you know I've heard
you point out multiple times that we
need to know more about diseases too
because more often than not it's
actually a disease vector instead of a
pest vector would you speak to that yeah
again please don't hate me I'm doing
this because I'm trying to help the
industry but you know the overall
knowledge level of cannabis growers
really needs to be elevated higher on on
on on being more technical
unfortunately what a lot of people do is
they look at a problem and then they try
to match pictures online and most I will
say most of the diagnostic images online
for cannabis are wrong and you know
everybody's quick to blame things on
insects because insects are more visible
where pathogens can be a lot harder to
diagnose and so a lot of the times you
know I get images they're like oh what's
you know making these dark spots on my
leaves what insects doing this what - I
do I sprayed it well no it's a disease
problem you know for me at Iowa's it's
not my department doesn't have six or
eight legs you know it's it's it needs
to be dealt with by a plant pathologist
and there aren't many you know actually
educated like when I say educated I mean
like went to college for this
entomologist working in hemp and
cannabis there are definitely some of us
around but there's not many and there's
even fewer plant pathologists and so
this is the problem it's hard to get
good information but there's a lot of
guessing and unfortunately people will
just post pictures on Instagram or
there's lots of Facebook groups and you
know what's wrong with my plant and I'll
scroll through and you'll see 40
different answers and none of them are
right or you may not be able to diagnose
the problem from the image because
oftentimes with nutrition you know you
need to send in for leaf tissue analysis
to get a report of what's actually going
on in your foliage or in your soil and
you know it kind of folds into nutrition
too because people think oh we've got
insect problems no that's a nutritional
problem and you know I talk to people
about you know soil I mean again
agronomy is not my wheelhouse at all I
mean I took it in college and everything
and I know not be dangerous but you know
I'm finding that people don't really
understand
and you know pH cation exchange capacity
people don't know how to do poor through
tests people aren't getting their water
tested they're not getting their soils
tested and and granted you know a home
gardener who's growing three or four
plants probably not going to you know go
through those steps but anything larger
than that if you want to become a good
grower you really need to have good
analysis done to really know what the
problem is
then you know for the next time and for
me personally in my career the stuff I
work with the insect identification is
what I learned in college I learned
basic insect biology and that kind of
stuff but the actual problems I deal
with is is stuff I faced over the last
thirty years and when I didn't know what
it was an insect termite
I'd send it off for ID and then I would
know the next time and so I've learned
through you know getting more educated
by using diagnostic labs and and and
helped and that's what's going to make
you a better grower not guessing that
you think you knew what the problem is
but really finding out really what the
problem is and now since hemp has opened
up you know through the farm bill and
Papa
if you collect your insects you can send
them in and get them identified also you
don't always have to you know with
extension you don't have to put what the
host plant is but a lot of extension now
is working with hemp and you can say
okay these are my pests off my hemp crop
you know what are they and you can get
the proper identification and there's
more testing labs that are doing you
know hemp leaf tissue analysis stuff so
these these places are out there to help
you it's just the industry needs to take
advantage of them I think it's going to
be very interesting to see the the new
skill sets that the next generation of
cultivators are going to have you know
the the young whippersnappers who are
like in their early 20s and they have
hit their you know age of majority at
the perfect time when cannabis is coming
out of prohibition and so they're able
to actually go to university for you
know these types of
you know diagnostic and pests and
agricultural aspects and then come up
and spend their entire life of
cultivating cannabis with the you know
professional supports and education and
versus those of us like you know me at
50 and well 49 whatever um and those of
us who have been doing this in the dark
for so long we have been trying to you
know it's felt like Sisyphus right
trying to trying to push up doing this
you know the rock up the mountain that
it just has it slide right back trying
to do this without the proper tools and
and in the dark so let's talk about
where to find more information on these
banker plants and trap plant solutions
these protocols that you're talking
about right so so if if they're really
unique to bioregion and they're unique
for you know particular species is there
so for anybody who's going to give a
damn enough to do this extensive
research is there a good resource for
them where they can learn about these
these programs like you're the athan
program you've been using as an example
where they can learn what the other
programs are for different pests so they
don't have to reinvent the wheel I'm
sure I know these programs exist but
where do people learn about them well
unfortunately it's not much written and
the problem is - it's a moving target
because things change if you google like
pepper banker plants years ago we were
using black pearl pepper and then some
great research came out of Europe I
think Garba nestling did it where he
found that oh no wait a minute if you
use purple flash pepper you can produce
way more aureus than black pearl
so then everybody's like change okay now
we're recommending this so if you go
back and read older stuff it may not be
exactly accurate and so this is why it's
a moving target of us working out in the
field and honestly the the people like
myself
Ron Valentin who's with Bioware
Kelly Vance with beneficial insectary
who are working in this stuff every day
honestly we're so busy doing it
unfortunately we're not writing about it
and we're not you know we're not you
know you know T I mean none of us do
blogs I mean occasionally we will spit
out a magazine article here and there
but that's what makes it difficult
because most people just want to go to
the Internet and do research on it today
we're if you want the most current
information you have to get to the
meetings where again people like myself
or Ron where we're teaching workshops
because those are going to give you the
most what we know today because again
recommendations I gave five 60 years ago
I know more now and they're not I that
may not be accurate today for a
particular situation and so and that's
one thing that frustrates me about the
Internet is you put an article out there
and it's there forever it doesn't go
away and people then can get dated
information so always when you're
looking at information look at the date
on it and make sure you know is this
still going to be relevant I mean basic
biology yes that pretty much doesn't
change but you know we're smarter today
than we were five years ago on banker
plans but you know for regionality on
banker plants you know we're doing the
same programs in greenhouses and you
know west coast middle the united states
and east coast because there aren't that
many developed programs what is more
likely to change some what are the
regionality of your pest pressures like
this year actually it's been a pretty
bad spider mite year where we haven't
had big spider mite flare-ups and
greenhouses for several years because
the years before this it's been broad
mites so we have you know yearly pests
as well as seasonal pests that you know
make us alter our programs but there's
not one good source nestle to go to now
on the aphid banker plant systems which
i know people are interested in because
they feed parasites can get expensive
and again this program only work
for a phidias coal money which again
works for the green peach and cotton
Melanie food and we'll we know it does
parasitize the cannabis aphid probably
the best place is to get information
from the producers of it not all in
Sector EES support banker plant systems
there's a pretty clean dividing line
down down the line on who does and who
doesn't I'll tell you beneficial insect
area is a huge supporter of banker plant
systems they sell them they work with
their growers with them you can also get
them from SIA you can get banker plants
also from Sierra biological in New York
State and you're able to get information
from them you also mentioned Ron
Valentin before he's written several
articles on banker plants but again
watch the dates because things have
changed and I do believe he has some
literature that he's done for bio works
on banker plants I am pretty sure they
have that up so those are places that
you can get them so you're almost better
off getting them from the actual
companies that are out there doing and
working with it then necessarily
googling and you know it's also kind of
like you know baking a cake back you
know in 1900 your grandma made the best
cake and she'll give you the recipe but
she's not going to give you that one
special ingredient you know why would
any of us put all our information out on
the internet and tell you exactly how to
do everything when you know I've got you
know being a consultant I've got this
problem with and the cannabis industry
everybody else thinks they're a
consultant and people just want my
information that they can turn around
resell it's amazing to me how many
consultants contacting me wanting me to
solve problems for their customers that
they're getting paid to do but they want
to get free information for me so
there's no way I would put all this
information out for free on the internet
because somebody's going to snake it and
sell it ok so to wrap this up this is
going to be interesting because I
normally try to
and my shows on a really nice up note
right but you know this the this our
conversation today has not gone at all
as I planned I really thought that you
know we were going to talk about the you
know the top five or six pests that
cannabis folk are you know mostly coming
into contact this year and we would talk
about our you know our best handful of
trap and banker plants and you know
people should mix and match them in
their garden or something like that but
actually um it's a lot messier than I
thought it was not only the the
identification the development of the
protocols the pre growing plants my god
the the charging them in advance with
non pests benefit for the beneficials
that I'd never considered that that
sounds like a major pain in the ass and
so what what I'm seeing here is that
really for folks who want to go down
this path to help decrease their pest
pressure
it's either a some graduate level
research that hopefully you will do once
significantly for your career grow where
you are and then you have to keep up on
what comes out new every year but it's
you got this big up front research labor
time and then to kind of like build out
your program and or you have to go
really much more hardcore on prevention
so that you don't you know it takes you
don't really have to do banker and trap
plants that's not we're going to put
your emphasis you're going to put your
emphasis on on prevention but that is
not an inspiring finish to a show
Suzanne that is that is not a positive
spin on and right this what what do you
got for me Wow end this on a positive
note let me just give you this again I I
I guess because I try to be so
detail-oriented maybe sometimes I
because I want people to be successful
and I just want people to be aware of
what they're getting into and again if
you talk to
you know some my ornamental growers you
know it's kind of taking them a few
years to really get their stride with
their banker plant programs but once
they got them they got them and you know
that it it it works it is not for
everybody I will stress that I mean I
think I said before I think maybe 5% of
ornamental growers are using banker
plants it's a very small amount it's
you've got to be the right kind of
person to do this but that's set if you
are dealing with aphids whether it be
again not all even species but if you're
dealing with cotton melon or cannabis
e-fit and you're using a phidias coal
money the simplest not cheapest the
simplest thing you could do is every two
weeks you can buy in the barley a food
bank or plant and what you do is you you
get a clump of barley that's grown I
think it's grown in rock wall and it's
covered in Athens and you just go set
that in your greenhouse you know you got
to put some water underneath it some
people will plunk it into a pot and let
it grow and then as you release your
parasites and they're flying around if
they don't find enough if it's in your
crop they'll go reproduce on that where
it gets more complicated is when people
grow their own EFA's but people will do
that for economic savings they buy one
even plant and then they'll you know in
another part of the facility they'll
just basically start a mini aphid farm
so instead of buying a plan every two
weeks they just take a plant out of
there a food farm and set it into their
facility so the easy way to start would
be just to buy a plant in every two
weeks and just set it out it can be as
simple as that but you have to make sure
that if it is coal money is going to
target the aphid you're dealing with and
then that will help you build more
parasitoids in your facility so in the
long run you can actually buy fewer
parasitoids paying for the cost of
buying in the plants does that make it a
little more I chords and rainbows for
you probably not but but it is it is a
it is a good place to get started
because the the mountain
of research is high and for people who
want to get started with something now
that is a great low barrier to entry
thing that they can start with white
that's for indoors now if you're outside
and actually I do a whole presentation
on this on attracting native beneficials
without having to go through everything
the simplest thing if you are outside
biodiversity that is what you need just
plant biodiversity well that's that's
nice and so now there is unicorn and
rainbows right grow outside and grow a
whole bunch of variety of companion
plants all around them so you attract
all the natural beneficials there you go
well I would call them in Sector II plan
sector equals I would call that's right
classes and again depends on where you
are because what you grow in South
Florida is going to be what you know
different than growing in Yakima
Washington but what I've done for my
vegetable garden is I have I first
planted all kinds of stuff out again you
know calendula yarrow
I tried gum free no lesser and then I
just look at the plant
I'll go spend time and I'll just sit I
have a little plastic stool and sit
there and watch who comes to visit it if
I see things that I want coming around
you know surf it flies to Canada flight
that boom I'm going to plant more of
those when I did gum free no last year
nothing ever visited the gum free no gum
FreeNAS out and that's how from my yard
I've selected what plans if you're in
the Northeast Corridor growing outdoors
/ depends date did an amazing project in
2005 where they roped in all these
master gardeners and they give them
little stools and they sat at plants and
then they measured the number of
pollinators visiting the number of
surface fly visiting the number of
butterflies visiting and then they
listed them out and so you know for me I
want you know all the pollinator and
sand fly plants and so I've pulled from
that list a plant in my yard and you
know that generally these plants aren't
the plants you're going to go find down
at your garden center because again the
garden center stuff has been
said for what humans want not with the
insects once so I've been you know
digging deep sin to the bowels of buying
weirdo seeds and you know Pig nan themes
the the mountain mints are phenomenal
for pollinators and toucan it flies and
toucan it flies you go Google toucan
applies to learn about them but toucan
defies our amazing you want them around
and so by doing things like that is how
you can select plants that do well in
your area and if you grow one plant one
year and it's like covered in aphids
like maybe we shouldn't grow that one
this year but if you grow like milkweed
and it gets covered with milkweed aphids
those aren't going to move into your
cannabis and those will provide food
resources for Lady Bird Beatles and
surf'n'fries' and lace wings so that has
now turned into a banker plant in itself
Wow
I like that too because it creates a
sense of momentum you know in the cult
in the cultivation area right instead of
there necessarily being happening to be
all this research upfront these are some
actions that you can do now while you're
ill boning up on the rest of the science
yes and and and this is what I'll do all
look at stuff and then all go to
universe and say hey this is what I'm
seeing can we work on something but
understand that these research projects
takes years for them to happen and it
takes money and time and that's why we
don't get a lot of the kind of this
research because nobody's willing to pay
for this kind of research well hopefully
that stuff will come along soon Suzanne
thank you so much for spending time with
us you know whenever I get the
opportunity to hear you at a convention
you know it's always a fast-paced wild
ride and I learn a lot really fast and I
know I miss more than I even learned and
this has been the same kind of thing
high energy lots of information the kind
of episode that people listen to more
than once so so thank you very much for
sharing your experience both the both
the good and the things we don't want to
hear you know you're invaluable to our
scene and and thanks for
not only doing the ornamentals and the
other plants that you you know have been
bread butter for you all these years but
thanks for coming over to work with us
in cannabis - oh I love working with you
guys I have to say through all of this
the cannabis got through the all the Coe
visit because honestly I not been
working for almost three months now
because I can't travel but you know what
the cannabis people have done a good job
of taking care of me and contacting me
and just checking in on me I mean yes
everybody wants bugs Aidid but that's
fine I enjoy doing that but you know I
really do enjoy working with the
cannabis industry and I've made some
really good friends through it and I
love working with you guys
well fantastic I consider you a good
friend as well it's been nice to chat
with you and I very much look forward to
all this quarantine being over so that
we can say hello in person at
conventions again so if you want to find
out more about Suzanne and her bug lady
consulting you should make sure to go to
bug lady consulting.com and her
Instagram is at bug lady Suzanne and if
you want to keep up on the the reports
and studies and signs that Suzanne finds
relevant make sure to check out the bug
lady consulting page on Facebook because
even though Facebook is not super
friendly with cannabis it's very easy
for Suzanne to post the papers there
because you know links aren't so easy to
use on Instagram so make sure to follow
her at bug lady consulting on Facebook
as well you can find more episodes of
the shaping fire podcast and subscribe
to the show at shaping fire comm and on
Apple iTunes stitcher and Google Play if
you enjoyed the show we'd really
appreciate it if you'd leave a positive
review of the podcast wherever you
download your review will help others
find the show so they can enjoy it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the weekly newsletter for
insights into the latest cannabis news
and product reviews on the shaping fire
website you will also find transcripts
of today's podcast as well for
information on me and where I'll be
speaking you can check out Shango
lowes.com
does your company want to reach our
national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hotspot at shaping
fire calm to find out how thanks for
listening to shaping
fire I've been your host Shango loose
[Music]