[Music]
one thing I can tell you for sure is
that we're doing it wrong we're not
really legalizing cannabis our state
governments are allowing some
normalization of cannabis so tax revenue
can be raised to feed they're bursting
budgets but it's a little more than that
also regulation at the state level is
being implemented mostly by folks who
have little understanding of cannabis
markets cannabis culture and they
certainly don't get cannabis patients so
far nearly every state to allow and tax
cannabis has done very little to embrace
and include the prior Prohibition era
producers what do you think happens when
you allow cannabis culture to flourish
and yet restrict participation by the
heritage growers who produce during
Prohibition well of course they just
keep on producing for the unregulated
market like they always have this could
potentially be a huge mess for the
future of true nationwide legalization
does this mean a new drug war 2.0 where
law enforcement officers could bust
growers not because cannabis is illegal
but because they don't have their tax
stamp this is Boston Tea Party [ __ ] the
states give lip service to decreasing
diversion to other states but when state
regulators try to dominate a state
cannabis market without including the
black market they are directly causing
the diversion of product to other states
and for those who choose not to start
shipping out of state their family
cannabis business must be dismantled
even though they were the ones helping
patients and keeping the flame alive
during the dark days of prohibition and
you know what this mess of diversion
neglected patients and unstable markets
when we blamed on cannabis companies
instead of where the blame belongs with
the regulator's who devised the system
we are doing this wrong this thing being
called legalization what we are
experiencing is industrialization of
cannabis and the demise of artisan
heritage cannabis farming in America and
I am NOT down if you want to learn about
cannabis health business and technique
efficiently and with good cheer I
encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter every week you'll receive a
new podcast episode delivered right to
your inbox along with commentary on a
couple of the most important news items
from the week and videos too don't rely
on social media to let you know when a
new episode is published sign up for the
updates to make sure you don't miss an
episode
you are listening to shaping fire and
I'm your host
Shango Lowe's my guest this week is dr.
Dominic korva Dominic is executive
director of the Center for the Study of
cannabis and social policy he is a
political geographer and public policy
scholar he is an affiliate researcher
for the Humboldt Institute for
interdisciplinary marijuana research at
Humboldt State University dr. Korb is
work has been published in the
International Journal of drug policy
political geography the annals of the
Association of American Geographers and
Acme a journal of radical geography his
dissertation research examined the
political economy of international drug
policy in the Western Hemisphere and his
post doctoral research has focused on
the political economy of cannabis
agriculture in the southern Humboldt
area today we're gonna be talking about
how the licensed and unlicensed cannabis
markets interact
welcome to the show Dominic I Shango
how's it going it's great to be back
awesome so glad to have you here it
seems like it's been a long time since
last time we talked during the very
first episode so here we are again so
thanks for making the time for it I know
your time is valuable well I'm super
stoked to do it you've really done some
amazing work on this podcast since that
first one right on dude so hey the
history of cannabis in America is mostly
told through its black markets which is
why we're talking about it today and and
while there are certainly new markets
being created all around the country you
know these these informal markets have
lasted generations do you think that
it's unrealistic to think that black
markets will disappear simply because a
new licensed and taxable market suddenly
comes into existence well the short
answer is yes but I actually want to
commend you on your use of the plural
when you're talking about these things
and also how you're actually using
several different concepts black markets
informal markets and so I kind of wanted
to start by just reframing things
conceptually a little bit which is to
say that the black market singular is a
super problematic concept in so many
ways
black markets help us get somewhere
by describing the heterogeneous nature
of the different kinds of illicit
informal markets that were talking about
and another another
and related notes I've been encountering
and I have encountered in over the years
you know a certain amount of resistance
to the term black market it doesn't come
from you know an anti black market point
of view but one that is concerned about
you know concepts of race and racial
justice and so a lot of folks these days
are a little concerned because they feel
like it's a racist term I maintain that
it's not but I do want to kind of
respect the fact that folks are actively
you know working on the stigma aspect of
things when they talk through when they
talk about the black markets or informal
markets or whatever so I will also be
using you know the terms a little
interchangeably black market illicit
market here's another one for you
legible and illegible markets and to me
that gets it more like what the meaning
of a black market is it is something
that is very difficult to read right in
no small part obviously because you know
what we know about it comes from stories
comes from anecdotes comes through
things that kind of trickle into our
consciousnesses either and you know face
to face conversations or media headlines
and so there's a whole range of values
attached to discussions about illicit
illegible informal black markets um
that's kind of hard to do that work and
still talk about it you know with any
sense of clarity but it's very important
to note that's you know what we know
about illegible markets are stories and
those stories are framed by interests
and those interests have certain goals
and certainly broadly speaking you know
legal cannabis has as one of its goals
that you know the mitigation of the
black market and of course that's
one of the problems is that when their
story happens it's very singular and
when they're talking about the black
markets what our policymakers thinking
about they're usually thinking about
organized crime they're actually not
thinking about you know the reality of
informal markets that are highly
decentralized livelihood strategies for
many people in the United States so I
think that's when the legal market is
talking about getting rid of the black
markets let's give them a little bit of
credit because you know what they're
thinking of is not actually the reality
you know it's it's a it's part of the
reality and it's one that we should
acknowledge as well that organized crime
certainly you know is part of that
ecology of you know illegible markets
that that we want to be able to talk
about and it is also the one that you
know I think there's a public interest
in in mitigating you know fairly
strongly at the very least with respect
to for example you know very large grows
on public lands you know that do
environmental damage and so forth
I think that's there's an interesting
[Music]
economic justice concept lurking behind
this legal cannabis desire to get rid of
black markets because they're able to
frame the issue of canvas unlike with
the rest of society as one in which
we're actually kind of concerned about
the commercialization of of our economy
and I think that there's a there's kind
of a I think that there's a channeling
going on frustration with how our
economy works and how we'd like it to
work into this debate about you know
getting rid of black markets and not so
with respect to you know the legal
cannabis policy makers goal of
especially you know diminishing the
structural violence associated with
organized crime and so forth and
particularly you know highly commercial
informal markets
I think that I think that the response
that has to say well you know what like
actually the other informal markets have
been doing that work for you for a very
long time
and part of the problem here is that
you're not enlisting them in your
project to actually reduce the harm of
highly commercial you know you know
barely different from you know
exploitative capitalism you know you
know cannabis industry which does exist
and also you know looms very large in
legal markets so is it unrealistic yeah
it's unrealistic especially because
they're using the term black market in a
singular fashion they're referring to
organized crime when in fact medical
markets in formal markets that are
highly decentralized the ones that
actually over the last twenty years have
made you know us cannabis consumption
you a mostly local issue as opposed to
an imported issue and you know they've
been doing that work they've been
getting rid of organised crime by over
growing it you know in the same way
that's you know you over over grow
essentially prohibition so it's a it's
an it's an interesting I think framing
issue that's you know policymakers they
just simply don't understand they don't
get the you know pluralism of illicit
and informal markets and how many of
them are actually quite socially
beneficial and this range is not just to
like a small little home grower you know
with a few plants in the backyard but
you know to me it also applies to for
exists for example you know in
California the unlicensed dispensed
dispensary system that certainly they've
been encountering especially in Southern
California and the LA area in particular
you know over the last 10 to 15 years
and my argument has always been actually
that kind of black market transformation
has been quite helpful because it gets
cannabis off the streets and and it very
least gets it into you you know a
situation where you know people
are not you know doing this you know on
the streets and in public and so forth
but there's like place to go to to do it
so you know the range of like the
concern we have about organized crime
and public safety should also recognize
the ways in which black markets have
been actually dealing with themselves
especially because of you know the
medical cannabis or you know gray market
which is still kind of an informal
market but a little more legible you
know action that's been going on a final
note on the black market situation is
that you know policymakers are attaching
a stigma usually unconsciously to
organized crime and it usually is about
actually brown people not black people
because they use this term you know
cartels and Mexican cartels usually is
the stand-in for all organized crime so
it's you know it's rare that you hear
like a policymaker you know talk about
you know the problem of you know gangs
you know opening dispensaries and to me
again whether you view that as problem
or not really depends on whether you
understand that you know what like this
actually gets cannabis off the streets
and generally detaches it from other
illicit drugs and drug markets you know
I think that's a really good point that
you make that that that that the people
who you and I both know our artisan
growers our family growers are small
undercapitalized producers who we think
are the you know the backbone of the
American heritage grower movement that
that because legislators do are not
really aware of them and don't
necessarily spend time with them and
their interaction with those with those
folks are well actually they think that
those folks are all black market they
they think unlicensed people are cartels
and mass and so they put everybody who's
not licensed in one big basket similar
to how all of we cannabis activists put
all of our legislators in one basket as
well as not understanding and try
to limit our freedoms and so it seems
like we've got it we've got it we've got
a classic negotiation where where each
side doesn't know each other very well
yeah yeah I think so but what are the
stakes of one not knowing the other the
stakes so much higher for policymakers
because they are you know entrusted by
the public to actually create policy
that works and you know their lack of
understanding is you know what's driving
you know let's let's look at Oregon for
example which are already produced way
more than it consumes you know years ago
and then with legal cannabis coming in
you know they licensed a whole bunch
more you know new people and new grows
new license grows they you know they
instead of you know integrating the
existing producers in Oregon you know
they doubled their problem and now
they're calling you know they're blaming
essentially a situation that had
developed a long time ago and is not new
for exacerbating their oversupply issue
right when in fact the proper thing
would have been to do would have been
like you know don't issue like new
licenses take the people who are already
especially in the medical programs and
and and and and integrate them which
they did it first they really did it
first that's how they started was they
they said you know adults over the age
of 21 may now just purchase at
dispensaries and and and they we can tax
that right away right so they kind of
got off on the right foot but then you
know through their accommodation of you
know well capitalized interests who also
didn't understand that they were a big
problem actually making any money in the
system is incredibly you know saturated
as it was
they've create a problem that now they
want to respond to you with you know
more policing which you know has always
been more of a price support for the
black market then for black markets in
general than a something that actually
you know controls or diminishes the
informal market activities
it seems to me that the the only way to
combat air quotes a black market is
either to make it smaller by brute force
like you know Duarte is doing in the
Philippines or by embracing it and
becoming one with it and it seems like
the way that the market is progressing
you know neither is really happening the
war on drugs didn't work legislators
generally get that now and they're
embracing it more and more and yet you
know you already see people who have
already received their license in
California snitching on other people who
have not yet gotten their license
because they're all like now that we
have our monopoly we want to keep all
the unlicensed sellers out and and like
you were saying them not necessarily
allowing the heritage growers in I mean
that's certainly what happened in in
Washington where we had 18 years of
medical marijuana that yeah it could use
some regulation and people should have
been doing more you know lab testing
once they got access to it but by taking
that entire market and saying you can't
play in licensed cannabis
our Washington 502 market and now we're
seeing it happen in Oregon in California
it is structurally creating a black
market by not letting everyone play and
do you think that they're realizing that
they're doing that or do you think that
the fact that oh my gosh the black
market is sustaining even though we're
air quotes letting them have their weed
right do you do you think that they know
they're creating this black market or do
you think that they are just this
ignorant to how social policy is going
to interact with the economic policy
well I mean I think that they just lack
knowledge whatsoever of the dynamics of
cannabis markets I think that that's
probably the biggest issue but I do want
to kind of point out something else
which is that the the licensed cannabis
market is being set up so that you have
to be highly commercial because if you
are not highly commercial and efficient
and able it generates volume at scale
you will not be able to stay open
because you will not be able to pay your
taxes which are all extremely
hi you know you will not be able to pay
your license fees you will not be able
to you know bribe your local city
council to not have a ban hey you know
which is how it works especially in
California you know what they're doing
is actually taking a critique of
informal markets that is founded in like
basically I think a well-grounded fear
of like what commercial you know markets
do which is they don't have any regard
whatsoever for you know social or public
you know benefits or positive things for
society other than generating money and
they're creating a system that is just
that is just just for commercial highly
industrialised exploitative you know
for-profit no room to do any good in
society you know actors it's it's it's
you know yeah and I don't know what to
say about that other than like okay you
have a fear of you know unbridled
capitalism basically so your response is
to create unbridled capitalism you know
and it's it's highly counterproductive
it's like once you're talking about the
license market now you assume all the
licensed actors are all you know good
guys there's no stigma attached to them
and especially if they've got a whole
bunch of investment money behind them
you know you know from the financial
sector which has been wrecking our
economy for the last you know who knows
how long 30 years roughly Wow you know
there's that so that's a lot to chew on
you know the idea that the the
regulator's you know they're essentially
driving without a map that's that's
scary
in and of itself yeah and and the fact
that you know by the wave of their pen
they are you know destroying small
family income and and you know not no
longer holding a place for patients it's
an awful lot of power for people who
don't know what the hell is going on I
would like to mean maybe I'm too
idealistic to think that to the people
who are making policy would at the very
least get consultants who
stand what's going on in the cannabis
market is is no one speaking to them and
giving them the truth that they can they
can make policy bake based on the
reality of how cannabis markets work so
there's two sides to that I think that
in very highly uneven and localized
fashion there are a lot of
municipalities that are more sensitive
to that than others you can look at you
know the Bay Area's equity programs and
you know they're criminal the criminal
record expunged meant part of California
you can look at LA's appointment of cat
Paco to be in charge of you know what
they're doing and that's someone with us
you know the Civil Liberties and social
justice background you know it's
happening but it's highly uneven and you
know to some extent it's not just sort
of an issue with the policymakers ie the
the legislators who are making the laws
but it's the bureaucrats making the
rules and the bureaucrats making the
rules are not that concerned you know
about the reality of markets they're
much more concerned about the reality of
politics and in particular federal
politics and so you know there's there's
an element to which you could argue you
know the Washington system it really was
not rolled out with any real concern
over you know justice in the markets or
economic justice they just wanted to you
know get that system going and do it in
a way that modeled deference to federal
prohibition and I think that like
there's nothing controversial about that
statement it's quite clear I think from
the LCB director from you know from the
folks are particularly well associated
with how our system is gone that's what
they're doing is advertising to the feds
that the feds you know don't come get us
you know go get somebody else but don't
go get us so they'll take you know
confusion with the markets they'll take
a complete breakdown
the traceability system it's supposed to
be you know that the cornerstone of why
it is the feds aren't supposed to come
get us they'll take that all day long
you know as long as the appearance of
deference to you know a federal
department justice is there and I think
that that's becoming a little more
generalized as well I think that's the
way it's evolved towards deference to
the feds is a reflection of the licensed
industry's desires not to get crackdown
by the feds not just the policy makers
desire not to have you know public
employees get arrested I think that as
the license you know the license market
grows those people are managing risk and
the way they manage risk is you know
well who could come get us and if you've
got a lot of a lot of investment money
you know your your concern is with the
feds it's not with local police it's not
with them traceability breakdowns
whatever if there are you know millions
of dollars in no financial system cash
you know propping up your operation yes
you want to you want to actually crack
down on anybody who's not licensed
not just because to protect your own
competition but to you know protect your
place in the market going forward so you
know there's certainly a you know a
greedy aspect to that but there's also
just sort of a risk management financial
risk management aspect to that that's
it's just cold blooded calculated you
know no concern for you know how it
affects the rest of society and in
particular the people were able to get
by because they participate in this
particular informal market yeah that's a
really good point if if if what is
making the policy is the folks who are
bringing the fresh capital into the
cannabis market and their primary role
is to decrease the risk of the capital
the the the idea of decreasing the risk
for the capital does not leave a whole
lot of room
for for patients and small artisan folks
and the lack of the need of like huge
security systems so so let's go ahead
and take our first short break and be
right back you're listening to shaping
fire and my guest today is Dominick
korva of the Center for the Study of
cannabis and social policy while I
certainly still enjoy smoking joints I
moved over to using vaporizers about
three years ago the high was a little
different than burning the flower and in
the end I decided I preferred it for
daily use especially because I have
asthma more importantly though I could
taste my flower so much more it's hard
to express to you how significantly
different cannabis with a good terpene
profile tastes when vaped
instead of burned I have brought my vape
with me to visit growers and they are
astonished by the clarity of taste and
they say they feel like they're tasting
their flower for the very first time the
air vape vaporizer from air vape usa.com
is a great device to use on the go or at
home when you pick it up and feel
satisfying like a medical device
it isn't flimsy like many vape Tsar I
like how the flower is inserted in the
top instead of the bottom so travels are
shorter path to my mouth with the
cannabis at the top I get a hit that
feels more substantial even though I'm
just inhaling vapor and not full-bodied
smoke since I used this vape for flower
hash and concentrates I really liked it
the digital control for the temperature
is right there on the front three clicks
of the button and it fires up to the
temperature I specify really quickly and
discreetly you know vape concentrates
are a milder experience than dabbing but
you still get the potency in your hit
also the taste is great as would be
expected with a low temp tab I love that
this vape gives quick little vibrations
when it gets to the right temperature
that way if I'm chatting or distracted
while it's heating up it lets me know
when it's ready if you are ready for a
nice pocket-sized vaporizer consider the
air vape the new air vape ex has just
come out and it's gorgeous and it
includes many updates you can find more
about the air vape vaporizer at air vape
usa.com if you own a cannabis company
you know that finding good business
partners vendors and allies is an
essential part of your role and building
your business in a new industry like
cannabis doesn't always make that easy
Canha con is coming to Boston in Detroit
this summer and the halls will be filled
with every kind of ally you need for a
cannabis company technology horticulture
packaging marketing legal Human
Resources and media everything you need
for your business will be there and your
customers will be there too because
canna Khan is a premier cannabis
business and networking event with
nationally recognized speakers and the
opportunity to have serious
conversations with your business peers
and investors reserving yourself a booth
at canna con can unlock a lot of doors
for you not only do you get to network
with all the people who pass your booth
but it is not uncommon for canna con
vendors to do a million dollars in
business during the event canna con
Seattle event in February sold out well
in advance so reserve your booths now
for Detroit June 1st and 2nd and Boston
July 27th and 28th attendee tickets are
still available for both events whether
you reserved a booth or attend just for
a day do not miss the opportunity to
become a serious player in your market
visit canikin org for tickets booth
reservations and more information that's
canikin org welcome back you are
listening to shaping fire I'm your host
Shango Louis and our guest this week is
Dominic Kaurava executive director of
the Center for the Study of cannabis and
social policy so you know before the
break we were talking a lot about a lot
about the misunderstandings that
legislators have about the cannabis
market as a whole and why they're acting
on this through regulation is tending to
both kind of make a mess of the
situation but more importantly
sustaining the informal unlicensed
market that they're trying to get rid of
and you know we all understand that and
that many regulators even though more of
them understand cannabis than there used
to be so many of the regulator's just
don't understand that a cannabis is not
an unhealthy bad thing but then also be
we all know that they want to get their
money from the cannabis because they're
like oh wow we've got new money to make
our budget bigger so that we can take
care of our pet programs but me as as as
someone who thinks cannabis is a
positive thing I'm not really all that
into the state adding a sin
tax you know si n like they do with
alcohol or using of gasoline where they
are the attacks kind of discourages use
or says if you want to use this product
you have to pay extra because it's not
good for you I don't understand where
the government gets its right to tax
cannabis where does that go work
historically Dominic well there are a
number of things going on here and and
first let me say that's you know I'm not
sure the the sort of right to tax frame
is I mean it definitely gets us going so
let's just roll with it you know
obviously the government as a term
refers to a whole huge ecology of you
know public sector bureaucracies you
know from the federal down to the very
local level and you know in each state
there are different powers to tax that
are you know permit or not so obviously
in the state of Washington we are not
allowed to have an income tax so let's
start there that makes it very very
important for the legislature to be able
to fund public programs many of which
are absolutely essential such as public
education they've got to find that money
somewhere and they can't tax income so
they tax property and they do sales
taxes well and they have you know taxes
and there are the business taxes and so
forth most of those business taxes you
know also disproportionately punished
small businesses as opposed to large
corporations that can achieve
efficiencies of scale and manage
departments that you know you know pay
people to avoid taxes and you know all
sorts of things so the whole thing is
already the tax regime in the state of
Washington is set up to so really you
know it's there because we need the
money for public programs some of which
you know we may like some which will may
not but we can't tax income which means
that you know this five-year boom
in Washington state especially in King
County Seattle around Amazon as the
state has not really benefited from that
much at all because they have not been
able to raise money from income so they
have been raising you know property
taxes which raises rents you know
they've been you know increasing their
capacity to find and collect fines you
know so what's happening with cannabis
industry actually has a parallel what's
going on in the rest of the state in
terms of the relation between taxation
and and and the public good now it's one
thing to like sort of like put that into
perspective and say that actually the
canvas industry's best move would be to
lobby for state income tax to replace
sales taxes that would be I think one of
the smartest things the cannabis
industry could do because the state is
raking it in at thirty five percent
excise tax and they don't want a penny
less of that right so to replace that
you would essentially have to find a way
to replace that revenue and most obvious
place to replace that revenue would be
to tax all these higher incomes that
have been created in in Seattle around
Amazon in particular um
then there's the level of Taxation and
here I actually just stay on Washington
for now like you can get to the other
states in it in a moment I want to
actually take a moment to praise mark
Kleiman
really weirdly enough I who at the very
beginning of this one of the things that
he did point out was that the state is
going to face a challenge not to get
addicted to taxes basically that's once
once they start raking in the money
they're not going to stop breaking it in
and they're gonna find different ways to
really monetize these revenue flows now
especially in the context of the state
budget that remains broke right it's as
broke as it was during the financial
crisis ten years ago because again we
haven't been able actually raise income
taxes so there's all this wealth around
and no money to manage it we have this
massive homeless crisis and apparently
you no money no money to really deal
with that you know we remain completely
in the hole in public education spending
our infant
structure you know his you know decaying
as in the rest of the country uh and so
you know I do think that you know
collecting taxes on cannabis isn't
necessarily a problem but the problem is
at what rates and and and the justice
for that rates gonna depend on well what
kinds of business are being taxed
you know if it's small businesses then
really high honors taxes is going to put
them out of business and centralize the
the actual you know legal markets and of
course what that is going to encourage
on many fronts is the folks are better
than a below hanging in the legal market
because of the taxes are actually going
to you know create new avenues of the
black market
right so diversion basically that this
is not just simply a function of like
criminality it's a function of you know
opportunity and also you know what does
that business owner facing you know how
are they able to pay the rent on
facilities that you know have a
six-month delay in licensing because the
city hasn't gotten to it yet or the LCB
hasn't gotten to it yet and so like you
know they're almost forced to you know
operate the ones who come from you know
the illicit market in a way that like
floats the boat until you can actually
get revenue coming in right so you know
the high taxes whether or not they're
there you know they're just or not they
certainly seem counterproductive with
respect incentivizing diversion in
particular and that's you know at every
level at the other the other end of it
really you know it's because you know in
Washington State we hand it to the
liquor Liquor Control Board right and
look patrol board took a look at their
own history of you know emerging from
alcohol prohibition and you know has
attempted to sort of copy that even
though canvas prohibition alfalfa Bush
II have are not a very much alike and
neither a cannabis and alcohol broadly
speaking you know you could talk about
cannabis and wine you know you could
talk about even canvas and liquor when
it comes to you know concentrates and so
forth but the end
they you have this tax on cannabis
products that actually is really really
takes a bite out of you know the
botanical product you know at the same
level that it takes the bite out of
these highly processed edibles
concentrates and so forth so the tax
regime is kind of just screwed in
general its counterproductive is it just
is it right is there right yeah there's
a right to do so but again like what's
what's the driving force behind this
well driving force is that in you know
the beginning of the 21st century our
public budgets are broke and they're
broke because of a you know 3040 year
long process that is seeing essentially
the privatization of gains in society
way beyond the ability of the states and
legitimacy state to actually collect you
know attacks on the wealth that's being
produced by the society that we're
creating so there's a long term bigger
problem here and that is economic
inequality in this country and you know
the high taxes here and there have
everything to do with that and the
question is well you know what do we do
about that how do we fund you know
public spending well first you have to
actually agree on the idea that public
spending is a good idea versus a bad
idea and I don't know that like I think
in this country like we've gone to a
place where really like because we don't
see much return for what are you know
what little pittance we actually you
know provide for public servants to
actually create infrastructure create
you know social safety nets and so forth
those are just gone
you know we don't spend money on things
that actually help the people who need
it it is a legitimate kind of revulsion
not funding you know that the stuff that
we fund the 280 attack
is that are actually you know a large
source of revenue for the federal
government right now you know that goes
straight into you know a budget which is
like you know 56% defense and an
ever-shrinking you know percentage of
actual you know social safety nets you
know spending and so forth so it sounds
to me that that actually in how I asked
the question I wasn't actually looking
at the perspective large enough it's
like yeah maybe a sin tax on cannabis is
not really justified or appropriate
based on the product but no one's
looking at it from that regard they're
looking at it as oh my god we've got
this under FUD funded budget and how we
do state budgets is wrong and therefore
we just need to pour money on the beast
to buy us through another budgetary
cycle and therefore we're gonna have
massive taxes on cannabis because
there's not really anybody pushing back
and you know even though you've been yes
Washington is your examples it seems
like this is the same way it's playing
out in every state and is about to play
out in California yes there's no
question I think that that's absolutely
absolutely the case well well that
certainly is saddening right because I
was kind of hoping we'd come out of this
with some kind of of path to try to undo
cannabis tax and that sounds like it's
wildly naive of me because before we can
get rid of the cannabis tax even though
they just got it we would have to both
fix how the budget is even made which is
a monumental problem and now you're
saying that we would have to replace the
money as well and and those those are
both a lot bigger a lot bigger than just
cannabis so what do you let me give you
an example of you know a contradiction
which is you know the founder of the
Washington kanna Business Association
Martin Tobias who certainly doesn't like
that 37% tax and certainly doesn't like
the 280e tax
is also one of the big you know funders
of
the folks who keep washing state from
having an income tax so it's like if he
gets to have his cake and eat it too
right which is that like yeah there's
high taxes but it's driving out the
smaller businesses and and the bigger
businesses can consolidate and take over
the market the cost of those high taxes
in the short term is unpleasant but
really like there is no alternative
because he's standing in the way of
there being an income tax right and
people like him and people like him
include again every highly capitalized
investment fund investing in marijuana
because those people also work against
actually a just and equitable taxation
system and then and and and here we go
with really you know one of the issues
in legal cannabis besides people
snitching which is that the legal
cannabis people are not interested in
creating a fair or just economy they
have no interest in it whatsoever
and I think that's the way that they're
able to both complain about the cannabis
you know taxes but at the same time do
you absolutely nothing on their part to
you know create a society that actually
could in which we could afford to reduce
those taxes is to me something worth
keeping in mind yeah that makes a lot of
sense and it seems to me that going
forward with everybody looking out for
themselves we're probably gonna get more
of this the patients are looking out for
themselves the the legislators are
looking for their own re-elections and
their ability to meet budgets so they're
not embarrassed and the cannabis
business owners that are on of a you
know a more capitalized size they're
looking to protect their markets and so
we've got not very much coming together
in the middle let's go ahead and take
another short break and be right back
you're listening to shaping fire and my
guest today is Dominick korva of the
Center for the Study of cannabis and
social policy
now that the health benefits of terpenes
have become well-known in the cannabis
industry people everywhere are looking
for the purest terpenes without
adulterants the problem with most
terpene providers is that they're not
sourced naturally and instead our main
is a byproduct of refining petroleum and
that's so sketchy the terpenes sold by
true terpenes are entirely different
they are certified organic non-gmo and
food grade that means they are extracted
from real plant sources there are no
solvents of any kind used during the
extraction process they are distilled
only with steam that's right only steam
in fact terpenes from true terpenes are
so pure that you can eat them not only
that but you can stack them with better
results - what I mean is
other companies terpenes have got a few
percent of impurities and when you stack
those terpenes to make a blend you're
adding a variety of impurities that
degrade your final product true terpenes
also has strain-specific terpenes for a
wide range of cannabis strains like
Durbin poison sunset sherbet and
granddaddy purple true terpenes has
robust and supportive customer service
so your questions will get answered fast
and efficiently if you shop for turps
before you know how rare that is so
whether you want to cup your hands to
smell some beta-carotene to calm down
after getting too high or if you want to
dab some alpha pining so your lungs feel
fabulous and your mind feels liberated
true terpenes will provide you with a
truly natural experience if you are a
cannabis product developer these are the
Terps you want to add to your oil or
edible or a capsule or whatever true
terpenes are simply the best your money
can buy don't try and make a premium
product with substandard terms choose
true terpenes for a top-shelf experience
go to shaping feiyr.com forward slash
true Torpy ins to find out more or click
on the link in this week's newsletter
skinny-dipping humpback whales beatnik
poetry the Ottoman Empire soil
remediation interdimensional beings and
tree frogs these are just a few of the
interesting topics you can find in the
audio books library at audible.com if
you like podcasts like shaping fire
chances are that you'll dig audiobooks
too
just like with podcasts audiobooks speak
to you telling you stories and teaching
you stuff here's the thing audible.com
has an offer I want to tell you about
right now they're offering a trial of
their audiobook service for absolutely
free you can go to shape and feiyr.com
forward slash audible and you will get a
free audiobook straight up you can
listen to it on your mobile device
computer or you can download it and
listen to it like anywhere it's really
simple of course they want you to
subscribe to their service after the
free trial and enjoy their audiobooks
forever but you don't have to all you
have to do to get the free audiobook of
your choice is to check out the service
for free so that's the deal your first
book is free it's easy to sign up it's
easy to quit and their online library of
free ebooks is pretty incredible just
check it out go to shaping feiyr.com
for and slash audible to find out more
or click on the link in this week's
newsletter welcome back you are
listening to shaping fire I'm your host
Shango Lowe's and our guest this week is
dominic korba executive director of the
Center for the Study of cannabis and
social policy so during the first set we
we talked about why the informal market
the unlicensed market still exists even
in states that have got a regulated
licensed market and why they're probably
going to continue to exist for the
foreseeable future and during the second
set we focus very much on the idea of
taxation and and the reason why that's
happening and also you know the damage
it's doing in this third set I'd like to
talk about the the kind of market we are
creating in the license market because
you know any that the personality of any
market is created both by the people who
are in it and the regulatory structures
that guide it and I've got real concerns
about the corporatization of cannabis
which historically has been this healing
patient centric even for fun right even
if you're gonna get high and go out in
the forest you were out in the forest
being high and hiking and there was no
regulatory structure but this new
regulatory structure and the people who
are coming to the market I'm not so
confident that the the market that we
are creating is all that healthy what
are your thoughts
well we're we're creating you know an
industrial market right so corporate and
industrial are kind of two terms that
want to tie together but industrial
largely means that's you know it's it's
it's highly centralized it's it's
attempting to you know use economies of
scale and branding and marketing to
create value for shareholders
shareholders in particular not
necessarily for low wage minimum workers
minimum wage workers trimmers bud
tenders and all getting paid twelve
fifteen dollars an hour there's a
there's a difference between like kind
of that model which is you know
corporatists industrial and what we're
talking about we're talking about what
was good about you know the other kind
of black market which was the
decentralized craft version which sprung
up and in many ways is the one that has
been turning back the tide of you know
industrial cannabis you know imports
from you know mexico by what are
essentially you know black market
capitalist drug trafficking
organizations so i think that it's
unfortunate we've gotten to the point
where the legal market wants to create
this industrial corporates you know a
model of what a legal cannabis market is
allowed to be and their main enemy seems
to be you know craft producers who
really like aren't even in direct
competition usually with with the new
sort of legal cannabis industry which is
you know heavy on the edibles and the
concentrates and the bait pens and so
forth and you know certainly there's
flour but that flour is not really you
know because it's happening at scale
it's it's just it's it's it's not you
know it's hard to the consumer to
purchase it based on anything other
you know what's on the package right
it's not the canvas itself matters it's
the package and so we're we're we're
allowing for you know the continuity of
what to me is an economically
destructive model the corporatist
industrial model from that particular
kind of black market and we're kidding
it against as though it could possibly
be against you know craft cannabis which
by the way you know isn't suffering from
problem over supply is not having you
know issues with you know pesticides and
so forth and is in fact you know getting
to people who and you know do not have
you know the financial means to purchase
legal cannabis because taxes to all and
so forth so you know there's a there's a
limited extent to which those markets
are really competing with each other and
it's it's to me it's more of the legal
cannabis is creating these new cannabis
products that are aimed towards new
cannabis consumers and older people and
so forth and that's great that's one of
the positive things that's happening and
there's plenty of room for development
on the edibles side and the concentrate
side and the vape pen side for new users
but for cannabis culture enthusiasts who
prefer flower you know like they don't
want to buy cannabis based on what's in
the package what's on the package you
know they want like a direct experience
in the product itself they want the snow
grape taste great and and even to know
the person is growing it the idea that
that the way the markets work right now
is that you can't go in and open up a
mason jar and get a good whiff of it and
instead you're buying it based on the
copywriting on the package is just
absurd I mean we all know from using the
medicine that that your body reacts to a
terpene profile that your body knows it
needs and so that's what we're used to
going towards and now I mean not not to
men like without even going into the
sustainability of adding so much plastic
to a one-gram right but outside of that
you know the black market will continue
to have this power because you can smell
the
in advance there's a social experience
of interacting with your normal you know
your neighborhood provider and and
there's some more fun too right the
black market can still use copyrighted
names for example like all the malarkey
going on around the strain gorilla glue
and the gorilla glue company you know
suing individual retailers for carrying
a product called gorilla glue while all
those crazy names are gonna continue to
happen in the informal unlicensed market
which just increases the Underground's
prestige I mean to some extent I mean
what that you're referring to really is
a branding you know development in the
unlicensed market that people are trying
to carry over into the licensed market
so there's you know like we think about
black markets we usually think about you
know production and so forth but
actually there's been branding in the
informal markets you know and in
particular strains are kind of brands
now and it's helpful to some extent
because you know there's some big
correlation generally between that brand
name and and what it actually is but
it's it's it's not that effective and
you know I don't really mourn you know
you know the issues that people are
having with using branding from the
black market on on the white market I do
think with it it actually was one of the
problems with the black market is the
extent to which you know these branding
of cultivars has not really matched the
reality of what it is and I think that
you look at the Philo's bioscience you
know work that they've done you know it
at least shows you you know the fairly
large often very large distance between
what the brand name is on even the black
market and what the product actually is
so it's it's fun to do that and also you
know those brand names usually have
something to do with you know the crap
us that the cultivar came out of so that
the names that end up happening or not
that random and often contain a little
bit of genealogy in them which helps you
know consumers get educated about you
know well what's a cultivar you know oh
wait a second
you know there's been innovation and we
can kind of track that but I think it's
I think that it's also important to
understand too that's you know for
especially folks on the East Coast and
so forth it's you know I think that we
are variation of the black market that
is craft and you can smell it and
everything and you have a lot of choice
isn't that well reflected on the East
Coast necessarily where like you know
stuff goes out in bulk and you know it
may or may not be of the highest quality
and they haven't developed a small scale
cultivation system that we have out west
you know as much so I'm not necessarily
sure where I'm going with that but
because I try to emphasize continuity
rights and I also want to emphasize
heterogeneity and so I want to celebrate
you know the craft and creativeness
that's allowed when you don't have
intellectual property lawyers breathing
down your neck
and also to say that you know that's not
necessarily new either
that there's been you know a little bit
of you know inconsistency that now you
know has carried over into the white
market probably because of you know the
Leafly periodic table which is
completely absurd yeah so I want to
circle back around before we close here
you know before before I drifted you off
down the the branding path you were
talking about the commercialization of
cannabis versus social policy and and I
feel like you probably have something
more to say on that because you know
what what do you really think is the
future of cannabis based on how the
regulatory structures are presently
evolving well the future of legal
cannabis I think that there's definitely
room for well-made well crafted
you know cannabis Allah the microbrew
part of the alcohol industry it is not a
very large part of the Oh
all industry but we are definitely
moving towards you know a system in
which you have you know the cores and
the buds and and so forth kind of
dominating the volume I think it's a
that's where we're headed to with the
current situation and I think that's the
craft aspect to it and the innovative
you know different differences that
inter peeing files profiles and so forth
the the non-standardized you know a
product that results from non
standardized production systems there's
gotta be some of it in there but like
we're definitely it favors the very
large sort of industrial corporate
commercial products that I'm not that
interested in for anything else either
you know like I'm a no logo guy you know
like I'm not into you
you know standardized you know products
made by you know uh sweatshop workers in
China right and of course you know
that's kind of where we're headed
towards the sweatshop workers in China
model which is a return to you know the
the organized crime model really which
was you know didn't benefit you know the
the laborers who worked in the fields as
much as it benefited benefited the you
know the DTO Chiefs and and the the
government officials they paid off it's
it's kind of like well alright so we've
decided that the legal model is going to
be the cartel model of production and I
think that that's just ridiculous and I
don't want that and I do feel like
that's kind of where we're headed right
now but California is a place where this
is getting played out in a way with a
lot more resistance you know you have
very very large trade groups there that
are that have been on this since the
beginning a concern about commercial you
know capitalist canvas basically and by
capitalists actually I don't mean
necessarily anything other than
financial capitalists you know because I
do believe that you know there are
different kinds of capitalism and
certainly small business capitalism is
is helpful and worthwhile as opposed to
you
the kind of capitalism that devours
small businesses which is financial
capitalism right on that makes a lot of
sense and it makes me really hope for
for how California plays out I mean I
know you and I both spend a lot of time
down there both with the with the the
heritage producers and with the
transitioning retailers and and you know
I spend a little time with legislators
you certainly spend a lot more time down
there with those folks than I do but but
you know California being as big of a
market as it is and having so many
forthright people involved and having so
many you know really top-notch cannabis
trade organizations in the state
hopefully there'll be able to push back
against things like the removal of the
the one acre cap and and you know the
local moratoriums and and pull other
things that that can could make or break
California so so for those of you in
California who are listening our hearts
and minds are with you and we really
hope that you that you really do us all
right because you know the way that
California goal goes is probably the way
that the rest of the country is going to
go I mean those of us states like us in
Washington who have you don't bend the
first to you know normalize if not
legalize we were we were more test
States but California is like the big
leagues now and if they can pull it
together and push back against some of
these policies that are a mess in in the
early to regulate states
I think it'll have a lot of impact on
the rest of the country I share those
sentiments completely yeah we're we're
pulling for you California right on any
way we can but like if things are gonna
change it's gonna be because of you not
because of what happens here in
Washington Dominic thanks so much for
being on the show you know I always love
having you as a guest and because you
approach this in such a clean academic
way and without all a lot of the hype
that not only you get online but but
also comes with some of my other kinds
of guests so so thank you very much for
sharing your your you know ability to
get right to it and lay it all in
historical perspective so thank you very
much
Thank You Shango always a pleasure if
you'd like to learn more about Dominic
korva and the Center for the Study of
cannabis and social policy you can visit
cannabis and social policy org there's a
wealth of good reading on the blog there
for folks interested in the reality of
cannabis policy and if you really are a
walk if you loved this episode and you
want to hear more of this make sure you
go back to shaping fire episode number
one where Dominic Corvette and I talk
about a policy transfer between the
states and how likely it is that early
to adopt states will be influencing the
policy of the rest of the country you
can find more episodes of the shaping
fire podcast and subscribe to the show
at shaping fire calm and on Apple iTunes
stitcher and Google Play if you enjoyed
the show we'd really appreciate it if
you'd leave a positive review of the
podcast wherever you download your
review will help others find the show so
they can enjoy it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the weekly newsletter for
insights into the latest cannabis news
and product reviews on the shaping fire
website you will also find transcripts
of today's podcast as well
for information on me--and where i'll be
speaking you can check out Shango lows
calm as your company want to reach our
national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hotspot at shaping
fire calm to find out how thanks for
listening to shaping fire i've been your
host Shango lows
[Music]