[Music]
compost is one of those words in natural
farming that means a lot of different
things to different people and yet we
have conversations about compost
assuming we all mean the same thing
I certainly didn't grow up around
compost or compost tea and I only really
started considering it when I started
focusing on natural farming techniques
as an adult
and then of course I read teeming with
microbes by Jeff lonefels and got really
interested
if you've been listening to shaping fire
for a while you've probably been sitting
right here with me as I had some of my
biggest breakthroughs in understanding
what compost is and why it is the
essential building block for natural
farming
today is one of those shows and I bet we
learn a lot about compost together if
you want to learn about cannabis Health
cultivation and technique efficiently
and with good cheer I encourage you to
subscribe to our newsletter we'll send
you new podcast episodes as they come
out delivered right to your inbox along
with commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week and
videos too don't rely on social media to
let you know when a new episode is
published sign up for the updates to
make sure you don't miss an episode also
we're giving away very cool prizes to
folks who are signed up to receive the
newsletter there's nothing else you need
to do to win except receive that
newsletter so go to shapingfire.com to
sign up for the newsletter and be
entered into this month's and all future
newsletter prize drawings
you are listening to shaping fire and
I'm your host Shango Los
my returning guest today is soil
biologist Leighton Morrison
Laden is a lifelong Enthusiast of both
aquaponics and living soil his obsession
with Biosphere 2 led him to set up an
aquaculture at the rodeo Institute
Leighton worked with world-renowned
biologist Dr Elaine Ingham blending his
aquaculture byproducts with compost and
worm castings to prove that natural
inputs could replace synthetics in
commercial cultivation
Layton consults widely for agriculture
soil regeneration and Commercial Land
Management projects throughout the
United States including recently working
on the Wallace Annenberg Wildlife
crossing over Highway 101 in California
that will be the largest Wildlife
Crossing in the world
Leighton is currently founder of Kingdom
aquaponics and invented their line of
living compost and compost tea living
soil products Layton's a sought after
speaker and co-host of a weekly podcast
on the future cannabis project YouTube
channel
Leighton has been on shaping fire a few
times before episode 54 about geology
and biomimicry in living soil
cultivation this was the episode that
brought leighton's popular soil horizons
concept into Mass adoption episode 59 on
water and watering episode 82 about
properly using aerobic and anaerobic
soil amendments to meet the needs of
your soil at different stages in episode
87 where we do a debrief on the first
cycle of the shaping fire indoor growing
tent where we test regenerative
techniques indoors including his
Horizons model for living soil
so you might ask Shango why bring back a
guest for a fifth time and that's a fair
question and I have two answers
first have you heard any of the Leighton
Morrison episodes they're incredible the
depth in them is hard to ignore Leighton
has the scientific background plus is an
Ardent natural farmer and he actually
grows stuff and doesn't like live in a
lab he is kind of like Indiana Jones in
a way he has the academics down solid
but he spends most of his time in the
field applying these skills and Orchards
and soil regeneration projects research
and development cannabis cultivation and
he's even a consultant for the Dallas
Cowboys keeping their grass practice
field thriving
second I looked for someone else to be
on this show I got referrals from
friends and peers everyone I looked into
was an expert at making thermal compost
scoping compost and teaching it for this
episode though I needed a scientist who
could look Beyond this one category of
thermal compost to the larger picture of
soil microbinoculation which is what I'm
most interested in and I think is what
people actually want when they make
compost tea with thermal compost so in
the end I called up late and I asked him
to join me for this episode and that I
wanted to go big and cover a lot in one
episode
during today's episode the first set is
a review of different varieties of
compost their benefits and challenges
with a special consideration for the
home grower during the second set we
talk about creating the highest amount
of microbe activity in compost cold
compost and how to use it without fear
of pathogens and we wrap up with the
third set discussing compost grain
structure how to make premium cold
compost cold compost extract and even
make compost shelf stable for use
throughout the year
welcome back to shaping fire Leighton
oh thank you Shango I look forward to it
as always yeah man it's always great to
have you here so let's get right into it
you know I've been thinking about doing
this show about the varieties of compost
for some time
um but I really didn't decide to pull
the trigger on it until you and I had
that conversation just a few days ago
where you started kind of like teasing
apart
um this compost question I had in my
head and and you know even though the
the goal of today is to kind of uh talk
about the the science of
um the science and the biology of soil
structure I want to start with the
rather mundane
um question that I approached you with
because even though we're eventually
going to go somewhere heavier and more
biological I can't be the only one who
is a cultivator who who looks at these
different varieties of compost that we
have available to us and and trying to
figure out which ones are most viable
and which ones are like you know garbage
and I shouldn't even consider so
um so so let's let's go through the list
of the the six varieties of compost that
I have come in contact in my world and
let's just talk about each of them
individually so that when when
cultivators who come in contact with
these other types of compost know how to
judge them okay so so let's start with
the most common kind of compost which is
the bagged stuff that they sell at the
store and and I'm not even really
talking about necessarily like really
good quality bagged compost which I'm
assuming there is such a thing I'm
talking about the kind of stuff that
they sell for six bucks in front of the
grocery store in the spring and um you
know that stuff come different kinds of
company bag those up where I live
there's a company that actually collects
um uh yard refuse yard and garden and
food refuse
um from in front of people's houses and
then they take that to their big
facility and they are quote make compost
and and then when it's done they put it
in a bag and they sell it back to us for
six bucks all right and so
um you know it says compost and and so
many people are buying it for their
Gardens and to make their raised beds
and lots of people putting it in pots
but you know I buy you know when I used
to buy these I you know you buy it and
you rip it open and um and I would smell
ammonia and it would use it would often
have white on it and I'm all like I
don't I don't think that's mycelium that
looks like some kind of white rot or
something
um and then when you know as I've gotten
more mature in the living soil scene and
I've seen the kinds of composts that um
living soil
Artisans make I remember like how how
dare they sell this bagged stuff is
compost is it even compost so so let's
talk about that first
um it kind of explained to me I mean I
know each company makes it different but
I think that by probably by the time
it's in the bag they're probably pretty
similar so so teach me a little bit
about what my expectations should be for
that compost that's in a sealed plastic
bag
all right
um so let's start with the word compost
uh the word compost is a process it it's
not a product it's not a so I think that
that's where the real conversation
um begins is that okay there are a lot
of different types of compost and again
because I don't have a better word
um to choose we're going to use that
word we'll get into what it really means
I'm sure in another set but for the
beginning let's just say this is a
compost
so when you smell ammonia
um that is part of the thermophilic
breakdown of organic matter you said
well you called it junk well nature
doesn't make junk
nature just breaks down
um organic matter
um into carbon and nitrogen all living
things are made of carbon and nitrogen
along with you know other elements
uh from the periodic tables so
just for the sake of keeping it simple
when you smell the ammonia you are in
still in what we call a thermophilic
phase you haven't you haven't shifted
into the mesophilic
um so that means that active
decomposition is happening and that
ammonia smell is the release the
byproduct
of the thermal fights
um knocking the carbon and the nitrogen
off um they can't they can't eat too
much nitrogen they really are there for
the carbon and so that nitrogen is being
released in an ammoniacal gas ammonia
gas
so that product is is unstable if you
apply that to
um like healthy young plants you're
going to kill them because basically the
thermophytes are going to stealing
carbon and releasing the nitrogen
and therefore starve the plant out
because the plant actually wants the
nitrogen or or I should say the
mesophilic bacteria want that nitrogen
to break it down and release it to the
plant so that they get more exudates so
you're in a
you're in kind of a bind and and the
other thing the white you saw
well that's actually octino bacteria a
lot of people confuse uh that white for
mycelium but it isn't it's just
basically
um the actina bacteria
um and it's indicating heat it's that
there's still quite a bit of Heat
present in in that compost
so that being said
um you're dealing with a product that is
unstable
it wouldn't even be considered you know
poem which we'll get into later but
let's let's keep me on track here right
on um so the the the the stuff that's in
these bags it sounds like it'd be fair
to just call it immature like it is if
if our goal was it was a thermal compost
um I think what I think you're
suggesting to me that like like it
wasn't finished correct it was unstable
I see I think unfinished is a great way
to put it all right so so
um as as we know from anything uh that's
made at a scaled level like like even
cannabis flowers if you're scaling
things up so often the product that
comes out is
um you know not premium and so these
companies these companies are making
like just like thousands and thousands
of these bags and they're kind of
rushing them through and so the fact
that we are seeing that bacteria and
we're smelling the ammonia and it's
still breaking down
um uh it's essentially just saying that
they rushed the process
absolutely and the other thing you have
to keep in mind too is that at these
compost yards they don't have the
ability to separate the greens and the
Browns
so that's probably one of the most
critical uh pieces of making
um especially biological compost is that
you have the correct ratio of greens to
Browns if you have too much greens you
have too much nitrogen it's going to go
hyperthermophilic and there's nothing
you can do to stop well there is and
we'll get into that I'm sure later but
there's nothing you can do to prevent
that thermophilic phase from continuing
until it there's no nitrogen left
to be broken off to steal the carbon
so that being said if you can manage
your greens and Browns you can put a
predetermined point in time and say well
you know after six months this is going
to have be gone through the thermophilic
and into the mesophilic mesophilic means
stable safe to apply will not will not
steal nitrogen from my plant
and will be a suitable source of of soil
organic carbon that will provide all
kinds of benefits to soil
so
um so is there a use case for this right
you mean you said don't put don't use
this stuff on young plants
um because it'll it'll steal from them
well I would naturally take that and say
well then I I sure as hell don't want to
put this in my beds and put my clones or
my my seed starts into it and then I'm
all like well I probably don't want to
use this in my pots either like is there
is there any use for these things that's
that's a great question so
um yeah it's a herbicide
it will kill plants yeah yeah so in my
workout here in Cali
I'm working with a lot of different
farmers and a lot of different
um you know Growers of different things
when I found out that um
this company compost company that I've
been working with
um was using it as a herbicide I was
horrified it was like oh my God what are
we doing and then I stopped and went
wait a minute
I don't care if it's herbicide it's
still carbon it's still getting put into
the soil it's still providing a longer
term
source of fertility and CEC cation
exchange capacity which is a valuable
resource for uh providing long-term
fertility to plants whether they're you
know strawberries or trees it doesn't
matter so the fact that they're actually
taking this stuff and turning it in is
actually a benefit because when you stop
the thermophilic phase by taking this
immature compost and you till it into
the soil you've you've basically
prevented those thermal fights from
um producing that excess gas so
therefore you've actually put some
ammonical or nitrate based fertilizer
into play because it's no longer gassing
off so it's it actually has a couple
different benefits so that being said
what do you do with this compost
um I I would use it as a top dressing
for for a mature lawn or a top dressing
for a mature tree I wouldn't I wouldn't
go heavy with it but I would definitely
like sprinkle on up you know half an
inch and then just kind of massage it in
because you're going to get some benefit
from it in in that regard but no way
would I put seed starts or clones or
anything else into it because you're not
going to get a good result
so it sounds to me that unless we're
talking about uh putting a whole bunch
of it on on a on a field or or a or
distributed you know cultivation area
there really isn't much application for
this in cannabis growing which is kind
of our point
correct all right so unless unless you
take it open it and and pile it up and
let it go through the phase let it so if
you bring it home and finish yourself
incorrect correct
um well we might as well hit that how
would somebody let's let's say that
somebody only has access to this kind of
stuff how would you easily finish it at
home assuming you don't have a farm
um so you take it back to your place and
then blend it with
um other sources of carbon so wood chips
uh straw or not straw yeah straw because
straw is more of a brown than it is a
green it's not hey hey is a green
um and leaf litter anything any source
of brown maybe maybe your last year's
soil too yeah yeah it'd be a great way
to to use up some excess soil
um so you just blend it together and
then pile it up and and stick your hand
in there and if it's if it's heating up
add more Browns until until you get to a
point where it's no longer heating up to
a point where it's uh uncomfortable for
your arm I mean it if it's if it's at 85
degrees
which in many ways is the sweet spot for
biological Generation
Um it's going to feel kind of cool to
you because you're you run at 90 what
eight degrees so so it wouldn't be
uncomfortable now if you stick your hand
in there and it's hot that means it's
above 100 degrees uh 110 120. it begins
to get very uncomfortable if if it's 130
it's going to start to burn your arm so
that's a good way to gauge in the field
without a compost thermometer
how you're maturing your compost
all right cool so let's go to
um uh the next uh I'm I'm making up
these kind of [ __ ] categories myself
so uh let's go to the second [ __ ]
category which is
um uh home food waste compost now I want
to be clear we're gonna the next the
next variety we're gonna talk about is
like like
food waste compost made by an organic
Gardener who's like read a book and
watched some videos and they know what
they're doing right so what what I'm
talking about more specifically are
people who've got their heart in the
right place but they don't really know
what they're doing all right so so
they're people who they are producing uh
home food waste maybe they're getting
some some stuff for their neighbors
um they don't have anybody with
neighborhood pigs to give them to so
they're putting it in a pile and
whenever they remember it
um you know it'll get turned a couple
times a year or whatever and then
eventually it you know it does break
down it stops to smell it's probably got
some like big chunks of stuff in it
right and um but uh so it's it's kind of
lackadaisical compost but but I come I
come I run into that all the time I will
often post to the Vashon Island you know
a farm or or food cultivators list and
say like hey anybody got excess compost
that you're looking to get rid of
because I don't really have a lot of
space for that and um and and you know
sometimes I'll get good stuff but most
the time it's this this stuff I'm
talking about where where people are are
making this like kind of like
lackadaisical pile and they're like yeah
come come take this stuff so that I can
feel good that I've like moved it back
into
the biosphere
um but I don't know what to do with it
right so so so
what are your thoughts on on this kind
of stuff I'm I'm guessing you're going
to start with it is also immature
um yeah and potentially pathogenic
um yeah so that's why when you're
dealing with food waste you really
only have three ways to responsibly deal
with it if you just take it and pile it
up in the backyard it's gonna stink it's
going to attract pests uh ants uh
unwanted Critters
um you know raccoons you name it so not
really a smart thing to do a lot of
people that have food waste will often
add it to a static compost pile which is
yard waste sleeves and chips and
everything else that you've collected in
the spring after the winter and piled up
and and that's a little bit more safe
way to deal with it because you're not
going to attract to those paths
necessarily at the same level you would
if you just piled it up and let it rot
in the backyard
and you'll also get some benefit to
adding in those Browns again greens and
browns food waste is pure nitrogen so
it's it's gonna go hot
um it's gonna stink it's gonna gas off
both methane ammonia
um as and and like putrification gas you
know gas is that not don't necessarily
uh you know they're not good terpenes
put it that way
so
um as far as like dealing with with you
know food waste
my recommendations is to
um get people to either feed them to
worms which is a safe way of breaking
them down and and avoiding
um you know pathogenic uh
cross-contamination which is a real
issue if any of you have you know gotten
an upset stomach due to something that
you ate that was not particularly
healthy then you would understand that
this is not something that you want to
have happen to you an upset stomach is
no joke
so um in handling that it's it's really
you know again feed it to worms first
then take the Varma compost and use that
as a supplement in your compost or as a
top dressing but again it can't be gooey
it can't smell bad
um it has to have had the opportunity to
break down to a point where it's no
longer going to be potentially
pathogenic
so that's really the the only
responsible way to deal with with like
food waste another thing is is you can
you know do something that's a little
bit more
um
how we say old style which is to dig a
hole and put your cup put your food
waste in there and put a lid over the
top of it and just let nature do its
thing
um and and that's what we would call an
anaerobic digestion because it's going
to stink like hell down there
um but the microbes will naturally break
it down and convert it back into organic
matter
um so there's another way for you to
safely deal with your food waste
um and you know a lot of times you've
got to keep in mind too like you know
people oh eggshells eggshells are great
well they're also got a lot of E coli on
them uh same with meats you know those
those meats and and dairies are are a
little bit more tricky to compost than
just fruits and veggies um and fruits
have their issued too because they have
a lot of sugar uh they can attract a lot
of pests but when you get into these all
right I'm gonna throw everything
including the kitchen sink no pun
intended
um into my compost pile you really gotta
go thermophilic you got to cook that
stuff hard to prevent any kind of again
attracting pests or or potential
potential pathogenic
um
you know uh cross-contamination
well a I never considered the pathogens
and I think that's really important but
I gotta tell you I just got to say you
really got my attention with this
um anaerobic
compost hole
um that sounds like a really fun project
um is the stuff that will come out of
that like rich and delicious for my
cannabis plants
after it goes through the digestion
process absolutely how long does that
process take depends on how much you
piled in there and if you continue to
pile on top of it I mean it's think of
it like uh like you ever seen a flow
through Verma compost uh system yeah
where you take from the bottom and you
feed the top
in the hole the bottom is going to be
where the value is
um not the top where you just added
stuff so basically you have to let that
sit for
because you can't Harvest from the
bottom unless you try to cross tunnel
over yeah yeah that's much probably too
much work certainly I'm imagining like
Phil Phil like digging a hole filling it
with like
um kitchen waste and then when it's and
then then just fill the hole and then
just cover it and leave it and then go
dig another hole and then like maybe
I've got like nine holes and I think
you're about to tell me about how long
that would take and so like okay I make
the holes and then after X variable
amount of time I know that I can go back
to Hole one and use that and then like
some weeks later I can go back to Hole
two and then when I pull hole one I can
go refill it so so how how long let's
just say like you know reasonably since
I don't have a backhoe I'm probably not
going to dig a hole that's you know much
bigger than three by three let's say I
wouldn't even go that big just use a
post hole digger
right so just dig a post hole you know
like me it's a really small eight inches
around yeah six eight inches around I
mean how much food waste do you generate
not a lot yeah so I guess yeah I guess
that's true huh and a great way to
um store it
is actually to freeze it so that you can
just freeze as you go throughout the
course of the week maybe it takes two
weeks to to store up enough for a one
post hole
and you know dig the post hole mark it
with a flag and then cover it over with
soil on top and if you go back probably
I don't know maybe three five months
three to six months you will have this
amazing black organic stuff with tons of
worm castings in it wow like and then
and then if they're not three by three
holes I could you know I could easily
make 25 of these in a row each with each
with their own plant tag giving me their
the date that I capped them off do I
need to worry about the um the E coli
from the eggshells when I do this style
no because everything is going to break
down
um you're going to have rapid
decomposition and an anaerobic digestion
system
so the the E coli is just going to get
consumed by other biology
um what if what if I'm a cultivator
who's in the ground
um and I have got like a a cultivation
field let's just say I've got three rows
of five plants you know and uh and so
I've got like 15 plants could I just
um make these post holes like around my
garden and then just like never get them
out just like put them in and and just
cap it and just say you know all all of
this all these nutrients will eventually
be accessed by the root Zone and they'll
be pulled from you know three four five
feet away from the plants and they'll
just be pulled over by nature and so I'm
just kind of um creating these little
post holes like little caches of
nutrition for the soil and the plants is
that legit absolutely and I mean you
could take it even further and
um when you harvest in the fall
um
you know go next to the root ball
obviously I don't want you to take that
out it's valuable nutrition but go next
to it and dig a hole and put it in there
and next to your plant right on top of
it it'll have six months of digestion
yeah all right Black Gold dude Black
Gold that's really a cool idea all right
now there is one other piece that I left
out in in dealing with food waste
um it's called fermentation
now that's been a big topic over the
last five years or so you know Jay Dom
and and natural farming methods and so
one of the other things you can do
especially if you have a situation where
you just you had a party and you have
all this leftover food like you know
hamburgers hot dogs steak chicken pork
whatever
um but you just you're overwhelmed if
you have a trash bucket full of food
what you can do is actually take that
and cover it with water and put a uh
like a wire mesh or wire cloth over the
top of it so it's held down and weighted
um so that the food and everything
underneath it is under the surface of
the water
now this is a way to
basically uh break it down into enzymes
very very quickly and then those enzymes
can be used in for in again in a thermal
thermophilic compost
and really make that compost explode
biologically because you've got all of
the secondary and tertiary metabolites
uh in in biological food and so of
course the biology is just going to go
ballistic when it comes in contact with
the stuff because it's just ready to eat
it's like you know McDonald's and Burger
King
so that's another component to dealing
with with you know food waste now do
would I recommend you know doing that on
a smaller scale probably not because
it's going to be a pain in the ass
whereas you know digging a post hole and
dumping you know some Frozen
um scraps for last two weeks is a very
easy to do method whereas this
fermentation process takes a little bit
longer and again now you've got this
bucket that you have to let sit for a
minimum of probably seven days until it
you've gotten through the the
fermentation process and you're probably
going to see foam on the surface of the
water and other indications that it's
still very highly active and so you do
not want to uncork this while it's in
this again
um
anaerobic digestion because it's going
to stink like hell but after a period of
you know you know it depends again on
the size of the container how much
you're dealing with how much meat versus
how much vegetables as to how long it'll
take to break down but after a period of
time it won't even stink anymore it'll
be slimy you know you'll probably get
like a mother
um you know like a kombucha mother on
the top of it
um but it won't smell anymore and that's
when you know okay this this stuff is
rocket fuel for biology now I take this
and add it to my compost pile it will
not stink and all of those mobile
nutrients
um that could wash through the soil very
quickly if it rained will be consumed
very quickly by the biology
wow right on and and when it's in the
stank stage do not get that stuff on you
your evil smell for days
exactly all right so our our next
category
um is is going to be uh what for lack of
a better term I'll call it curated
compost so this is the kind of compost
that is made by you know organic
gardeners your friend who who knows
better took a class and you know read a
couple books
um they know what they're doing and so
they're they're they're creating their
pile and you know maybe they're even
um you know making sure that certain
types of food stuffs are in there so
that the compost that comes out of it
has a particular nutrition ratio that
they're looking for and uh and and it's
getting turned on time and they've got a
compost you know thermometer and so you
know we're talking kind of like creme de
the creme of of heated compost piles and
and you're very lucky they like you they
like the weed that you're growing and
they say hey I've got I've got extra of
this stuff you know you break when you
want to bring over your pickup and you
know get what you want and then you're
like hell yeah and you go over so so
tell me about this compost compared to
the other stuff we were talking about so
far
all right so I'd have to believe
um
that this this compost curator has has
gone through the thermophilic phase and
into the mesophilic in other words
didn't rush it
um use the proper green to Brown
relationship
um whether they used food waste or
manure we we call those High nitrogen
sources as long as they're using High
nitrogen sources responsibly so less
than 10 percent
um and they are going through the
process of turning it like you said
until that gets to the point where it no
longer continues to go thermophilic now
you've pushed it into the mesophilic
phase now you have a what I want to call
nutrient dense compost
um so there's a high value of nutrition
there but I'm not saying that there's
biology there and this is this is
something that I've learned over the
years I've you know been across the
country I don't know how many times
worked with clients all over I've worked
with people that's oh my God I make the
best compost you know old hippies that
you know they've been around for a long
time uh worked with Dairy Farmers horse
Farmers you name it
generally speaking the one piece that
they're all missing
is the biology
biology takes
perhaps a year or two to come back into
that pile after it's gone thermophilic
to a point where it would get into the
realm just getting close to the realm of
what I would call a biological inoculant
so that guy on the farm who's you know
through his you know his yard scraps and
his his vegetable scraps probably not as
meat because he doesn't want to attract
the pests into his pile and and you know
turn it or left it static I mean that's
another way to deal with it
um static just takes longer for it to
break down but you're getting you're
going to get a better biological compost
from static versus turning because every
time you turn that pile every time you
expose those microbes to UV to oxidation
through exposure to air
um you're you're knocking them way back
you're you're basically
pushing them into a cyst form or into a
um you know a form where they're being
consumed by other biology so you've
turned them into a biostimulant which is
basically what happens to thermophytes
in a Mesa little phase they're being
consumed by other bacteria and protozoa
and and converted into a what we call a
biotic bank account like it's there and
it will be available when uh the time is
appropriate for for the next level of
bacteria to be consumed and released in
plant available form so you're you're
basically like
banking a biostimulant in a situation
like that but you're not you're not
producing
um biological compost per se
if I was clear on that so so
um this this this compost that we're
talking about that is finished and it is
stable
um how are we going to
um you know we can use that in in all
the ways that we normally think about
compost at this point right is a correct
as a top dress is a soil amendment all
that kind of stuff exactly so unlike the
other ones that we've talked about so
far that have got limitations because
they've never become stable this is the
first one in the list where we can feel
pretty safe doing whatever we want with
it yep and again test it you know stick
your hand in it pile it up and and feel
if it starts to heat up again if it if
it heats up
um then you're still in what we would
consider decomposition phase
thermophilic phase but if it doesn't
heat up or if you stick your hand in
there and it feels a little cool to you
then you you know you've got a uh stable
um organic matter all right cool man we
have to introduce that at some point in
the near future so instead of calling it
compost we need to call it
um like those terms that I've talked to
you about like ground up organic matter
gum uh Palm particular organic matter or
MOA mineral Associated organic matter
because now you're getting into that
point where
it's it's it's in a phase of
decomposition so everything
starts with with
soil and plant growing and then breaks
back down into soil eventually yeah we
need especially since you pointed out
the beginning that compost is really a
process and not a product we really need
new vocabulary words for these various
products that we're talking about
because people say oh my compost your
compost and really people are comparing
very different things because they're
they're not all at the same
um maturity status
attitude we did a compost cup out here a
year ago the Ventura County Compost cup
we brought in all of the local compost
producers everything from you know the
family Gardener to uh you know these big
companies that make it and you know
these you know experts these These are
Heavy Hitters that came we had 10 judges
uh one was a uh soil scientist from
rodale
others were business owners
could produce large-scale amount volumes
of compost
all the way down to guys that make what
I would consider uh Moen mineral or
Associated organic matter
um and and we put them all out on a
table and I spent three days prior to
this microscoping every sample to see
which ones were would would I consider
biologically
um
inoculant
and so we had these 10 judges I was not
one of them because I was biased because
I already looked at everything
uh and we had them analyze it and vote
on you know each category we had Verma
compost we had food waste compost we had
uh thermophilic compost we had static
compost we had yard waste compost and
you name it horse horse manure compost
and each one of them looked at the
samples and then voted based on
appearance
only one person out of those 10 judges
actually sniffed it and that was the
soil scientist
and then when it was all done and they
all voted at the end of the competition
I I stood up and I said hey
you know I I really appreciate you guys
taking the time to come out here and do
this but I want to point out something
that you guys basically determined the
value of the compost on appearance only
and everyone kind of looked around at
each other like oh [ __ ] you know
he's right how how are we
qualifying or quantifying why this one's
better than that one
by appearance
so I point out hey we did no testing so
we have no idea which one's nutritional
and which one's not
um we don't know which ones could
potentially have high salt or or heavy
metals like the horse manure compost
very common to have high aluminum in in
horse manure as well as high salts
sodiums on both detrimental to plants
um and and also I biologically scoped
all of these but that wasn't even taken
into consideration as to
again
stating that this was better than the
other ones in that category and it was
extremely eye-opening like that
conversation that the room just exploded
inside conversations at that point
everybody was like oh my God I never
thought about that way and so it was
really eye-opening to basically put that
level of of experience in a room
together and and turn them on their
heads because they basically had no real
evidence to determine which was better
than the other ones except for visually
[Music]
all right so let's go to our next
category so the next one
um uh I kind of just put in its own
category because I really just thought
that
um
worm castings were just like a a part of
all compost and that was it
um but then
um folks might recall uh Chandler from
uh from wormies who was on the show a
couple episodes ago talking about worms
and
um like he was kind enough to send me
out a bag of uh the wormies Verma
compost that they make so that I could
see what a Verma compost was like and
dude it's it's unlike anything else that
I would call compost
um it is uh it's it's uh it's smaller it
smells sweet it is it seems more uniform
it seems a little bit heavier
um uh you know when the when you know
again something that's called compost
right but really you were talking about
the pass-through
um uh worm bins earlier that stuff that
comes out at the bottom which is the the
worms
um the worm casting so they're poop with
um you know whatever kind of like soil
or hay that might have been thrown in
there to kind of even it out and make it
a pleasant living environment I guess
um that stuff while called compost is
really its own thing and
um and so let's talk about that itself
so so you know you get a uh you know
somebody gives you Verma compost and and
it's you know vastly worm castings
um let's let's talk about what what the
the attributes of that compost would be
okay that's great
um so when you are um
doing Verma compost at scale you have to
start with betting right everybody you
can't just throw food in a bin and throw
some worms in there because they won't
survive the whole thing will go
anaerobic and and the worms will turn to
slime so you need to create a bedding
that the worms can Retreat to
um to do their thing whether it's breed
or or rest
um and then an area for them to work
through to get their food they don't
want to live in decomposing food they
want to live in their bedding but they
want to be able to eat
so think of it that way all right so
um and again thank you for for observing
the weight of it because that's really
really important to understand that's
why Verma compost is so unlike other
forms of compost because it's pushing on
the Moa mineral-associated organic
matter side so mineral Associated
organic matter is highly stable
long-term in soil and provides great
benefit to helping the the the soil food
web to begin to build Aggregates micro
and macro Aggregates which is important
for soil Health but I'm not going to go
down there so why is Verma compost so
much different well those worms have
chewed through
that material consuming bacteria
and pooping out
um nutrients highly nutrient dense
little poops because they're really
there to eat the biology they don't
really want to eat the nutrients per se
um they they will try they will help
move those nutrients throughout the
entire uh worm bed which is again
mutually beneficial because now you're
getting an even uh
even amount of nutrients throughout the
entire system it's not like this
pocket's going to be heavily ladened
with with this nutrient or that mineral
it's been pushed through the whole
system
so yeah worm castings are very special
because they are uh very nutrient dense
and highly biologically available in
other words if you put those worm
castings into or top dress and then
apply a really good compost extract
biologically Rich compost extract or tea
those those things will be broken down
extremely fast and stored in the biology
so that they're not mobile and again
this is really important to understand
nutrients if you just take raw nutrient
like a secondary tertiary metabolite you
put it on the soil and it rains that
stuff's gone it's going to get washed
through and down into the lower soil
systems where it's no longer going to be
as available for the plants so you've
you've you've gone backwards You've Lost
Your minerals You've Lost Your nutrients
so that's why it's so important to have
that biology on on high numbers so they
can consume those secondary in tertiary
metabolites stored them in their biota
in their body
so that now when it rains they're stuck
to their biofilm that stuff's not going
anywhere the only time that stuff that
nutrient in in that bacteria is going to
go somewhere is when that bacteria is
consumed by a protozoa or starved to
death by a lack of exudate and becomes
available to the plant
so that's why worm castings are just so
special is because they are basically
secondary and tertiary metabolites ready
to be consumed by biology which will
then store it as a a nutrient bank
system for when the plant wants them
special stuff yeah it totally special
stuff and and um you know I copped to
this you know when when we did the uh
you know uh you know making friends with
Worm episodes like I don't know three or
four back with uh with Chandler
um and like I'm honestly new to worms
like I I like worms I make sure that
I've got worms in my pots but but mostly
I would just I've always thought about
them aerating the soil and and but it
wasn't until you know we talked with
Chandler that I realized that they are
these like super efficient processing
machines biological machines that are
just taking these um
this biology that's not super accessible
to us or our plans and running it
through their bodies and pooping out the
other end something that is Rich and
valuable to us and this is that's pretty
badass yeah it is yeah it is all right
so let's go to the the fifth category
now
um we're down to our last two here so
the fifth one it kind of I'm not sure if
it totally fits in this in this group
but um since this is where
um my curiosity started for this episode
today I definitely want to include it so
um for the last I don't know five or six
years
um I have been using
um uh both of the the compost tea making
products uh from green bicycles
um and uh uh Kevin chaudry turned me
onto this stuff uh one day when I was
visiting
um Wonderland Nursery because uh Patrick
the founder of green bicycles had come
by and he had you know this huge 35
gallon uh container of this this this
what looked like powder and Kevin says
you know I swear by this stuff it makes
great compost teas you should you should
try it and so I have and I loved it I
got great results and I've been using it
for years
um and so so the stuff from green
bicycles though is very unlike the other
stuff that we've talked about so far
today because
um the green bicycles products is is not
like uh food Refuge or
um
um Glon clippings or or cuttings from my
cannabis plans it is a blend of what I
think of more as soil amendments right
so there's you know there's there's
guano and feather meal and crab shell
and you know the kinds of stuff that
that we all in the regenerative scene
um are known to use to build our soil
and and so um he's got two versions of
the product uh one of it with
um molasses that's dried in there and
and then one that's not and the one
without the Molasses is kind of seen
more as a soil amendment and the one
with molasses is is
um is used more as a compost tea and so
so I've been using this stuff for years
but it wasn't until again I started
following
um uh um you know the wormies uh
Instagram and Chandler's Instagram uh uh
I think it's jet Gardens
um that I that I really started
realizing that the stuff I was making
compost tea air quotes out of
um it was not it didn't look like
compost to me anymore it was it was a
bunch of amendments with molasses and so
I I would always like take that and put
that in my um my bubbler that I got from
t-lab and um and it'll Bubble Up and it
makes this like beautiful compost tea
that smells great and and my plants have
have done well on it but but but
um I I'm like where where's the biology
part of it and and is this its own
category which which I have just started
calling a nutrient tea which that
category may or may not exist but like
I'm on my own path right I just came
across it my own and everybody else
probably already knows about this so so
I've been using this and so so a I know
it works B I love the ingredients
um but C I don't know if bubbling it is
actually doing me any good because
they're I don't think that there's any
living biology but there's got to be
biology that assisted up that was you
know on the feather meal on the crab
shell you know contained in the back
guano so so there's like like there's
like cysted up sleeping biology in there
I'm guessing
um and then I go ahead and you know fire
it up and then I get nutrition with I'm
guessing some amount of biology so so
please speak to that which is a very
different
it's a very different product to put in
in the same bucket as as compost but I
really feel like it's got its own
personality and I don't know how to
resolve it with the rest of this stuff
oh it definitely has a personality and I
I appreciate the the term nutrients
solution or or
nutrient tea would be the appropriate
way to describe it
um the big difference between compost
extract and teas versus a nutrient
tea would be the lack of humic acid the
lack of fulvic acids
um those are
biological superfoods
so basically it's like a One-Stop shop
for for your entire soil food web by
using
um you know these these compost extracts
that are very high in humic or folic
acids
so that being said now we've we've
separated these two by that one critical
ingredient now let's talk about the two
different varieties one with molasses
one without molasses I would tend to
believe the one with molasses would be
working a lot quicker so a short term
whereas the one without molasses would
be more of a long-term nutrient T and by
that I mean that when you apply that
nutrient solution onto the soil
um you're you're assuming that that
solution is going to be absorbed by the
existing organic matter
um and then slowly released by uh the
bacteria that are mining it and storing
it in themselves and then they become
available to the protozoa which pooped
out to the plant Etc so one is a short
term one is long term the short-term one
with the Molasses is going to stimulate
all kinds of microbial activity we know
for sure that that the bacteria just
love molasses
um there was I I years ago I it got
explained to me and I forget what it is
but it has something to do with the fact
that the sugar has only been processed
to a certain point it hasn't been
refined yet and that's why the bacteria
love it so much because there's again
the secondary tertiary metabolites
haven't been refined to a point where
that they're more difficult to break
down
so you're going to have
biofilms built up on all of those uh
nutrient inputs so just recently NASA uh
came back with an article about how they
had slapped some biofilm on the outside
of the space station at three years ago
and they scraped it this year and
brought it inside and yes it was still
live even though it had been living
in space which is you know
how could anything live in space right
well it goes to show that that biology
is
incredibly resilient
but it also goes to show that the
biofilm is so powerful that it can
protect those organisms pretty much in
any Con in any environment you can
possibly come up with
um at some point I I tend to believe
that we will find
um that perhaps life even exists in
Flames uh that there's some kind of
biology that we haven't quite uncovered
yet but that's a whole nother story yeah
that sounds like a whole different
meaning for the shaping fire podcast
name right right
we'll get there someday hopefully but um
anyway just stay stay on topic here so
that being said that yes when you when
you add the dry molasses and you put it
in water and you bubble it you you're
going to
um get a bacterial explosion uh plume
for lack of better words and you're
going to be pluming out the organisms
that we're consuming
had had created their biofilm and and
their protection their home on those
individual uh nutrients whether it's
crab meal horse uh whatever uh feather
meal crab meal
calcium whatever it is but they will
have bacteria that specifically mine
those components and now you've grown
them out so guess what when you pour
them on your soil
you're going to have an explosion of of
the biology that has that nutrient
stored up in its Pantry that is now
going to be consumed by the protozoa and
nematodes that you have present in your
soil system or or the or the
microorthropods to not forget about them
um and the worms don't forget about them
right because they're all working
together to release this nutrients
um back to the plant and so um that's
that's what I would say to to this uh
green bicycle uh nutrient solution is
that it's it's an amendment but yes it
does have some uh biological
constituents that are available on those
nutrients that mine those specific
nutrients so very targeted biology cool
and you know I I started with it just
because you know Kevin chaudry said so
right and I trusted his opinion and it's
worked for me for years and it's it's
funny that now like whatever five six
years ago you know later now I'm really
getting to the point that I can even
think about more what it is
um so I'm you know it it works for me
even without knowing exactly what it is
so
um so I like that kind of product I
wanna I wanna clean up before we go on
to the next topic I want to clean up a
couple of the things that I got wrong uh
um so wormies Instagram is obviously
easy because you know how to spell
wormies but but Chandler michalski who
was the guest for the for the you know
getting friendly with worms shaping Fire
episode like three back I got his
Instagram wrong I looked it up real
quick it's actually jet house Gardens
and so nothing worse than you plug
somebody whose Instagram is very
educational for you and then you plug it
wrong you know I didn't want to
interrupt you but I was going to clarify
that right I'm glad you did I'm glad you
did right cool yeah so I wanna you know
I want to do Channel or solid so I
wanted to clean that up and then um and
then anybody who is interested in
looking at that green bicycles products
um uh it's kind of weird because green
is actually spelled
g-r-e-a-n and so that's that's you know
that's Trixie and will totally destroy
your Google results without it and the
the two products that I mean it's their
only two products but it's the two ones
that I've used all these years is the
Happy Endings compost tea mix and the
ocean Bounty flowering mix
so um for for anybody who wants to look
into that and you can get that stuff on
Amazon and their website so all right so
moving right along so so we're coming up
here to the end of this like huge first
set and and and
the the compost we're going to talk
about next number six this is actually
going to set us up for set two because
we're going to talk about this variety
of compost
um during most of probably all of set
two so so
um so just just set us up there Leighton
and then and then I'll take us to
commercial so the sixth category is the
stuff that you sent me man like like I
had a problem in my you know I know
you're a compost expert you can solve
for all these people you got this crazy
ass lab in your in your garage and
another one in Connecticut like like I
know you're like mad scientist compost
guy but like I had not actually ever
seen
like what you make right like I've
always I've always appreciated you for
our our friendship and conversation but
but I I you know I never seen any of
your compost and so
um so I had a fungus nap problem which
we'll talk more about in the third set
but you're all like hey man let me let
me send you something to fix that and
and you you shipped me up
um uh two different bags of this compost
which was unlike any other compost that
I had ever come across
um it was you know a small granular and
it was rich and it smelled so good I
wanted to eat it and it like I mean not
to sound too woo-woo I I feel like I
felt it alive I felt like I was getting
Vibes off of it like when I opened it
like I was like you know I got like a
hit of the smell and I'm like whoa what
is this this is very unlike anything
else that I have been given as compost
and then um you know you told me to just
uh you know um uh I think you had me
Brew it and and then and then I put it
put it on and it caused all of this like
immediate biological change which we're
gonna talk about more in set two
but this after talking you with talking
to you more about it
um you explained to me why this kind of
compost is in a category all of its own
so so please explain what's different
about this cat this category of compost
that I had never even considered and and
then set us up and then and then I'll
take us to commercial
okay so we'll get into the process in
the next set but bottom line is it's a
biological inoculant
um the foundation of it is Palm so
particulate organic matter so you you
notice that really fine particulate but
you also noticed it was super fluffy and
that's the key to this uh that
fluffiness allows for gas exchange it
allows the for heavy colonization of of
you know huh
very very diverse biology
um in a way that uh does not force
competition
so not everybody's fighting for the same
resource they're just there in
suspension
um just to be woken up and and
by you whether you're Brewing them or
top dressing with them
um so basically it's look at it like
Condominiums I'm building you know every
one of those tiny little
particulate is a giant condominium a
City full of all different types of
biology that are there basically just
waiting to be provided with the
environment that they can really
um you know expand it and and thrive in
so that's why that's different and we'll
get into the ingredients in the process
uh in the next set
hit the hit hit the key thing for me
though which is
um the fact that it's it's not a thermal
compost
now it is not and and in most ways it
would be considered uh immature and the
reason
um it would be considered immature is
because when I take this start product
which is the the biological compost that
I made uh non-thermophilic we call it
cold composting
um I screen it
uh numerous times and so I'm screening
out the big stuff
I'm using
forces to break off all of the organisms
the human can folic acids to break down
the little pieces that are tend to be
clumped together or sheared off of a
bigger piece of organic matter so it's
those mechanical processes and then the
screening that allows me to get that
poem those fine little particulates
and suspend them in a solution so that
they can be colonized by all the
different diverse bacteria and biology
that I've put into play and this idea
that it's a cold compost I haven't heard
that term before I like it
um you know when we talked about this
earlier in the week it was interesting
because you said you know all of the
other compost all right probably not the
vermiculture but but most of the other
compost that we have talked about today
they have all been heated to like what
165 or something because because people
are trying to you know kill the seeds
and you know make it make it little more
inert but but really that's also killing
all the microbes which is really what
what so many of us natural farmers are
chasing after and it really astonished
me that you know to realize that I'm
always thinking about
um using my compost teas because I want
to pour microbes into my soil to help
buoy the rhizosphere but really
um if it's a thermal compost it means
that like that stuff's like mostly been
wiped out already versus this
cold compost where even though we'll
talk more about this in a second it
sounds like it's dangerous because it's
all like wild in there like what I
imagine I'm doing with a thermal compost
tea really is happening at a much
smaller level than if I were to use a
cold compost tea
correct and the one thing you're missing
too is the most important reason to go
thermophilic is to kill pathogens all
right so they kill weed seeds yes that's
a byproduct of of the process but the
goal is to
um knock back all of the potential
pathogens remember a lot of a lot of
compost is based on manures right
high-end
um anaerobic digestion which is the
other piece that we did talk about
um but the thermophilic component is to
basically
provide the same thing as an anaerobic
digestion you're killing everything
and then starting over starting fresh
and so yeah that's that's why
I went to
um cold composting was because I could
not get the the biological diversity
that I was looking for when I went
thermophilic
but again I don't use any manures I
don't use any food waste I use purely
vegan compost so this is just plants all
right so we will dig into that uh even
more uh for set two and uh and if you're
still with us uh I appreciate you this
is this is a solid hour first set which
is the longest first set I've ever had
um but um I care very much about this
topic and um and there's no way that I
wanted to do this topic again short
shrift right like if we're gonna do it
let's freaking do it and and so if
you're still here with us and you're
caring about all this like you're our
kind of people and I really appreciate
that you're here so um we're gonna go
ahead and take a short break and be
right back you're listening to shaping
fire and my guest today is soil
biologist Leighton Morrison and you know
without these advertisers shaping fire
would not happen so please do support
them and let that you let them know you
heard about them on shaping fire
[Music]
once you've discovered the benefits of
using cannabis it's a very small step to
start making your own Edibles gummies
lotions tinctures and concentrated oils
at home
magical butter has been helping cannabis
consumers become self-sufficient for
over a decade with the easy to use
magical butter countertop Botanical
extractor you can create high quality
cannabis products to your exact
specifications at a fraction of the cost
of store-bought edibles
I talk a lot on this show about the
importance of Home growing so you don't
have to rely on others to feel healthy
well the magical butter machine can
Empower your personal health by putting
you in control of how you use cannabis
in your daily life
I've been making my own Butters and oils
on the stove for years and I much prefer
the ease of using the magical butter
machine I just set it and walk away with
the Simple Touch of a button the magical
butter machine grinds Heats stirs and
Steeps your herbal extract all at the
correct time interval and temperature
for the perfect infusion every time as a
result you achieve your desired infusion
easily safely and consistently check out
the magical butter Instagram to see the
machine in action and don't feel like
you have to go It Alone there is a huge
community on Facebook called magical
butter users United sharing recipes and
best practices so you can learn at your
own pace from others who are already
doing it successfully
now is the time to get your own magical
butter machine and save money while
enjoying cannabis
use the discount code shaping fire one
word no caps to get 10 off visit
magicalbutter.com today
[Music]
one of the reasons why no-till cannabis
growing is so valued by Farmers is
because the mycelium networks in the
soil remain established from year to
year and we know these fungal networks
are essential because they are the
nutrient super highways that extend far
and wide in the substrate to feed your
plants the trouble with growing in New
Living soils or Blended cocoa substrates
is that it takes most of the plant's
life just to create these mycelium
highways
dynomicoendomycorrhizal fungi inoculant
reduces that time and gets your plant
eating a wider array of nutrients faster
and it's three times the concentration
of the other popular brand in the U.S at
900 propagules per gram of two fungal
species selected specifically for
cannabis cultivation dynomica is the
result of 30 years of research and
trials at the volcani agriculture
Research Institute in Israel it has also
been vigorously trialed by cannabis and
food Growers across the U.S
dynamico is now available at Grow shops
and on Amazon in the United States I
love using dynamico to both speed up the
growth of the mycelium networks in the
soil but also as a biostimulant to make
clone cuttings more viral you can see
side by side showing the comparative
growth on their Instagram at dynomico if
you demand reliable growing results and
appreciate the importance of an active
root Zone in creating a thriving plant I
encourage you to check out dynomico.com
and use the store locator to find out
where you can get yours that's
d-y-n-o-m-y-c-o.com
shaping fire listeners can get 10 off
any size of dynamico on Amazon or
dynamico.com by using the discount code
shapingfire one word no caps
whether you are starting with new beds
or pots or if you want to add some Zing
to tired soil choose dynamico to
maximize your plant's potential
dynamico endomycorrhizal inoculant
as cannabis regulations become more
demanding and consumers become more
educated it is increasingly important to
avoid the use of chemical pesticides
when cultivating cannabis beneficial
insects have been used for decades by
the greenhouse vegetable and ornamental
plant industry and today many cannabis
cultivators are moving from sprays and
chemicals to beneficial insects
copert has the beneficial insects mites
and nematodes microbials sticky cards
and air distribution units you need to
partner with nature to defend your
garden
whether you manage Acres of canopy or
have a simple grow tent in your home
culprit is ready to help answer your
questions and help you transition away
from chemical sprays towards clean and
natural solutions
since 1967 covert has assisted growers
in identifying pests and devising
reliable Solutions while providing
healthy insects and mites that will
protect your yield
since the 1990s covert has been a leader
in cannabis Pest and Disease Control
worldwide and have highly trained
Consultants to assist you in Canada and
the United States from coast to coast
with their Global Network of grower
support covert can help visit copper.com
choose your country and get detailed
information that's copert
k-o-p-p-e-r-t.com
for the most up-to-date cannabis-related
biological control information you can
also check their Instagram at covert
Canada
you know getting away from pesticides is
good for health and good for business
and culprit is ready to help visit
covert.com today
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire and I am your host
shangolos and my guest today is soil
biologist Leighton Morrison
so here we are at set two during set one
we looked at a wide variety of the
things that we come in contact with that
is labeled compost and we did our best
to make sense of them and we found
ourselves at the end with um you know
focusing on the kind of compost that
that I think that I'm usually looking
for
um you know you know much of the other
types the you know the curated compost
and the vermiculture compost and the
nutrient compost like like all of that
stuff is are things that I use in my
garden but most of the time myself as a
natural farmer interested in
regenerative
um you know cultivation and feeding the
rhizosphere I'm really wanting to you
know feed and add microbe life I want to
add biology and
um and and so we we ended the first set
talking about
um a cold compost that have not been
heated that where all the biology is
still alive and so in this set we're
going to talk
um a bit about the difference between
that and the and the other composts and
the biology and also I'm very interested
in um you know if if one of the reasons
we heat thermal compost is get rid of
the pathogens that makes this unheated
microbe inoculant this cold compost
sound like wild like the wild west so so
so so let's start
um with the difference you you have
spoken on this on this show before uh
briefly about the difference between
soil science and soil biology and
um you know I I my you know back of the
envelope is just like soil Sciences
nutrition and minerals and soil biology
is living stuff but but honestly we
haven't gone into you know in depth so
far so I could I could have it wrong so
so why don't we start there there and
then we can start to hang the rest of
the conversation on that Layton all
right that sounds good and you know
thank you again Chango for doing this
because you we're we're having a
conversation that has needed to happen
for many years now about you know
whether it's a compost is should be
called compost or whether it needs other
names and and you know just recently in
the last couple years I've seen you know
like particulate organic matter and Men
associate organic matter come about as
as words that are provide value
um and and this next part which is also
equally as important is is the
understanding that soil is actually
three components
is the physical sansil clay and organic
matter and their relationship which is
very important second is soil chemistry
and third is soil biology soil science
base everything on
two of those three pieces which is the
physical and the chemical and this is
due to
um
economic based
systems and like human reductionism
right we always we always value life
last right it seems to be the way it
really seems to be the way especially if
you look at where we are as a species at
this point in time
we won't go there all right but
basically soil science is is chemistry
heavy everything has been based on
building fertilizers to grow more crops
to feed more people regardless of
nutritional value which makes no sense
to me the only real way to achieve
nutrient dense food is through biology
it's that critical
biogeochemical interactions that allow
that plant to pull up these nutrients
um and and and regulate itself as to
what it wants instead of being force-fed
NPK so
that is why there's this huge disconnect
in soil science versus soil biology
until Dr Lane Ingham
made the world aware that there is life
under their feet people didn't even
consider soil biology as as a real thing
and so in many ways she's pioneered the
eye-opening of of the masses to the fact
that there is more uh going on in the
soil than just physical and chemical
that there's this critical Bridge called
biological that allows the chemistry to
flow in and out of the physical
components and into the plant directly
so that's that's an important
conversation needs to happen is that you
know the soil science world has got to
knock down the Ivory Towers of just
chemistry and really start to open up to
this
interdisciplinary mode of operation that
will unlock these really important
Secrets I sent you a paper recently
which I'm sure you're going to enjoy
reading time and time again because
there's just so much information in that
they're basically kind of explains that
this this
organic matter we're not going to call
it compost anymore it's organic matter
it's just in different phases of
decomposition
provide this incredibly powerful
home
um City uh Globe considered a planet
that that aggregate is a planet and
inside that plane it is all of this
magic that's going on that that's
protecting itself it's evolving
um it's it's producing uh more inoculant
for for more expansion for for better
soil structure to to accept moisture the
more moisture that goes in that gets
held in those Aggregates the more
densely populated they can become the
more they can clean the water the more
they can provide foods for other
organisms so it's really the the
foundation of everything is that
biogeochemical processes that are
occurring with inside that aggregate now
is that aggregate uh poem or moan well
that's the thing is when you get into
mineral Associated organic matter you
get into a environment where you're
compacted now you're you're you don't
have of the gas or air exchange I should
say you don't have the CO2 leaving and
the oxygen or the air atmospheric air
coming down you don't have the the same
ability to to aggregate that's why it's
so much more stable than poem
um so I'm sorry I got Way Off Track
there but I think I think that's
important to really differentiate the
difference between
um these phases of of decomposition sure
I'll bring you back in but but since you
mentioned the paper that you sent me
yesterday we might as well plug it and
um I will also have a link to it on the
page for this episode on the shaping
fire website
um but the but the but the the the the
the the science paper which was a
fantastic read last night is called will
fungi solve the carbon dilemma and it's
by uh s Emilia hanula and Ellie mauryan
um anyway it's it's it's a fascinating
read and um and we'll be talking more
about the the fungal aspects of this
paper you know towards towards the
latter half of this set but
um what you're saying Leighton is is
spelled out very specifically uh they're
talking about having an increase in soil
biology especially with fungal heavy
compost
um creating all of these soil
opportunities that are not available to
the soil when not using biologically and
fungally active
um agricultural soils so so anyway
that's that's the paper and so we'll get
back on topic here so
um so we're talking about the difference
between the soil science and the soil
biology and and how most of uh most of
compost and and everything is looking at
the at the chemistry and the physicality
of the soil and not the biology
um I would like you to speak to this
idea of the the
um
the the the variety of biology right
because NPK is so reductionist and and
and most of us in cannabis were were
brought up thinking you know hit our NPK
numbers feed the plant or you know if we
came from the bottle Forest feed the
plant and and and and what we are trying
to tease out is that um you know the
compost which is is is the central the
focus of our topic we want it to be as
biologically active as possible and and
the way for us to do that is to not cook
it like a thermal compost so I would
like you to speak to what that uh
process is like to produce a compost
that has not been cooked because
creating a cooked thermal compost is the
only thing that I've ever heard of
so again let's not call it compost let's
call it organic matter fair enough right
and organic matter is
probably the largest uh source of
nutritional holding capacity all right
this is where biology meets chemistry so
most people understand what a cation
exchange site is or cation exchange
capacity so that capacity is the ability
for nutrient solution to be held on the
bond site so that it's not mobile and
therefore safe and secure for later
Harvest by the plant and the biology all
right so that's that's really important
to understand
um
so that being said
uh trying to reel it back into
understanding
the thermophilic process of breaking
down organic matter
um I think that
um the best the best way to approach it
is is to
understand that when you get over 120
degrees you are losing biological
diversity when you hit 130 degrees you
have lost pretty much everything it's
now just thermal fights that are living
in that organic matter or on that
organic matter I should say so
that's why if your goal is to achieve a
biological compost you have to be below
120 degrees now
back in the day when I was studying
under Lane there was always this issue
of well you know you can bring in
pathogens and you can cause you know
plant problems uh you know
deficiencies and and all of these other
things because you've brought something
in from somewhere else and you've
applied it uh perhaps inappropriately
um onto into this pod or onto this plant
and
my argument's always been that um
diversity will out compete
um
reductionist so if I've reduced this
down to just thermal fights the
potential for a pathogenic outbreak is
way greater than if I had a very
biologically diverse compost system
this was one of of many conversations
that Elaine and I agreed to disagree
about was the fact that for her
she has a an incredible reputation a
celebrity status so she has to be very
guarded about what she says because
people will inappropriately be morons
and and use more uh because a little is
good oh more is better well that's how
you get into these problems with
pathogen
cross-contamination
with deficient nutrient deficient issues
because what happens is you you've
created a newt lock or you've created a
pathogenic inoculation
so that's why it's critical that
that she maintains that the only way to
make safe compost is to do it
thermophilically and I agree with her
because humans are just humans they they
tend to do stuff without really thinking
first and and you know making sure that
they are crossing the t's and dotting
the eyes responsibly
um it tends to be oh whatever's easy and
quickest for me is what I'm going to do
and that's not the appropriate approach
when you're dealing with these critical
types of uh biological exposures
um there's there's some composts that
I've made that are are definitely uh
potentially very dangerous to play with
because if I have underlying health
issues and I'm playing with
pseudomonobacteria the potential for me
to actually make myself very sick is is
is real
um I think that in many ways I've I've
benefited
from my work playing with anaerobic fish
manure
um because I early on was getting
exposed to this stuff and like you said
earlier if you get that stuff on you
it's days
before you don't stink anymore so
there's there's you know some serious
issues to it and but I learned very
quickly
um I never got violently sick I
definitely uh you know had some stomach
issues you know early on when I was
playing with the stuff because I didn't
completely understand
um about the difference between
anaerobic digestion and and aerobic
aerobic microbes versus anaerobic
microbes and and the potential for uh
them to make us very sick so
that being said
um let's let's delve into
what is a cold compost versus a
thermophilic
um
in the cold composting situation
um The Sweet Spot
for massive
protozoa production and the reason I'm
using protozoa is because they're the
ones that are doing all of or the vast
majority of nutrient cycling in other
words the nutrient cycling is that this
bacteria has all this good stuff locked
up in it including nitrogen and this
protozoa wants to eat that bacteria
because it wants the carbon to make
itself grow and get bigger does it want
the nitrogen doesn't care about what's
in the pantry of that bacteria so it
consumes that and it poops out pure
nitrogen and all of these other elements
in a plant available form and that's
critical
um in pretty much all soil systems that
I look at the number one issue is the
lack of protozoa that would be the
flagellates and amoeba those are the
aerobic ones the anaerobic ones are the
ciliates and then you get some faculties
which we're not going to get into that
it's just
it's just the bottom line is The Sweet
Spot is 85 degrees
and 70 percent uh moisture content so
when you squeeze the stuff you will get
water drops forming in between your
fingers
that tells you that it's above 50 if you
get no moisture you're about 50 percent
you get drops now you're pushing into
the 60s 70s and 80 moisture
that's the sweet spot for for protozoan
production
um it is also generally uh a sweet spot
for what I want to call
fungal
sporulation and germination
um
in the soil system itself
um plants don't like it uh that humid or
that that much higher moisture that's
when you get into root rots and you get
into other disease-causing uh potential
pathogens whereas in a compost pile it's
a different animal now we're not dealing
with plant life yet we're just dealing
with protozoa and production
and when I'm applying
um this well I probably need to go
through the process of of how I do it so
I'm I'm taking these vegan
um compost so it's just plants no
manures greens and Browns the ratio is
is always 66 percent Browns 3 uh three
and a half percent greens
um and you are using a tremendous amount
of water to to get that to begin what I
call the thermophilic rise we never want
to get to the thermophil process that's
130. we've got to keep it below 120. I
generally tell people keep it below 115.
if I get to 115 I gotta flip it as a
matter of fact I got to flip a pile this
afternoon because I'm at 115 right now
that being said
let the temperature go up to a certain
point 115 is Max and then I flip it if
it doesn't get to 115 then I never flip
it
um I just let it do its thing and I
watch it until it starts to come down
not quite to ambient Ambient would be
the the temperature outside environment
so today it's 75 as always and sunny so
when it's 75 degrees and I know it's
gone through the biological process or
the thermophilic rise that never got to
thermophilic phase so I brought it up
but I kept it in the mesophilic now
that's considered immature compost
because it's not really well broken down
so how do I break it down at that point
well that's where I get into these
mechanical forces I use agitation
aeration vibration uh spin so gravity
all of these things to to get that
immature compost
to
harvest the the things that I'm looking
for which is the biology and and the
smallest bits poem particulate organic
matter that I can get through that
process and then whatever's left goes
right back into the compost pile again
are you describing
mechanical processes that you
um uh submit the
immature the immature organic material
to
um that replaces what is normally done
by breaking down with thermals or time
or because again right you can you can
stack up a pile of ships uh or or any
organic matter for that map matter any
organic matter for that matter
um and it will go through a decom
decomposition phase whether it gets hot
whether it goes thermophilic or not it
doesn't matter I mean I don't know about
you but growing up in New England we had
to rake leaves every fall and we would
take those leaves and dump them over at
the edge of the swamp and that pile
would be like five feet tall me and my
sisters would jump in it we'd have a
blast throwing these and you know
running down the hill and fast as we can
trying to dive into the pile but come
spring that pile was gone it was just
this low lump of
what was left of we call it leaf mold
nowadays but just what was left of all
those leaves
so that went through a breakdown process
but it never got hot it never we never
saw those piles steaming so there was no
major heat exchange but there was
definitely some minor heat exchange in
order for that to break down
when you add the water the um the the 85
degrees and 70 percent moisture that's a
that's a lot of moisture
um uh is the water involved because it's
there to keep the temperature from
spiking I think you called it a
thermophilic rise I'm not very familiar
with that I'd like to know what happens
during the thermophilic rise and what's
what what's happened like why why so
much water
so the water
is broken into
H2O all right so we have oxygen and we
have hydrogen there are a lot of uh
arterial constituents that that thrive
on hydrogen so they consume hydrogen as
a fuel source to break apart the
nitrogen in the organ organic matter or
the carbon off of the organic matter
all right so
there are also other forms of bacteria
that consume the oxygen
to do their part in Breaking the
nitrogen and the carbon off of each
other does that make sense yeah it does
so water's the food water's life right
there's no joke to that water is life
without it and nothing ceases to exist
so that water is just a fuel source it
has nothing to do with with with
regulating temperatures not we're not
putting out the fire we're just
providing a food source for the biology
to do their part in Breaking the
nitrogen and the carbon off of each
other and so
um uh let's see I'm gonna try to do a
summarization to this point so so what
we're trying to do with the cold compost
is that
um we are going to a use only plant
matter so we don't have to worry as much
about pathogens like E coli and then
we're not going to let the temperature
go above 85 degrees but especially 120
but 85 is really our our goal
um so that the the the pile
um gets warm naturally from the breaking
down but it doesn't get hot enough to
kill our microbes off and we can get
away with that because we're only using
plant material instead of animal
material which can cause the pathogens
and and then we are also going to do uh
mechanical processes to this organic
material that will further break it down
to create more of these biological
opportunities in the soil for life
which also breaks down the compost in
ways some of the some of the ways that
we would get from a thermal version as
well so we're we're choosing to not use
the heat of a thermophilic compost and
instead we are using a safer inputs and
also massaging the soil in ways that
opens up opportunities and so we have
what is essentially yes a riskier or I
love what you said earlier a dangerous
compost
but we have decreased that risk by not
using animal products in there and we
are making it more diverse and more
effective by doing some of these
mechanical preparations too
yes and I think the other thing is that
you missed is seats right when I when I
harvest greens and Browns and I harvest
greens and Browns
um I don't
Harvest plants that have gone to seed
because I don't want the seed in my
compost what I want is flowers but I
don't want the seed pods so that's
another piece of this that's important
and the other one which is we're missing
on is diversity like I I collect like
every type of green I can find every
type of brown I can find
um and then I use those proportionally
uh volume not by weight
to make my pile and the reason it's so
important to get the diversity is
because of endophytic biology
it's a little bit deep but we gotta go
there all right so the end of fights
that live inside those green leaves and
luckily we just did the Jeff lowenfels
show on uh bacterial endophyte so
anybody who just listened to that show
is already going to be up to speed on
this so so folks who want to hear more
about this go back and listen to the
show about the new Jeff lowenfell's book
with that please continue
all right so but there's both endophytic
bacteria and there's endophytic fungi
that live inside the plant itself so
when that leaf
um is fall comes and it dries out and
falls to the ground if it lands on the
ground it's going to release
um sap robes uh this is a type of fungi
that decomposes organic matter but it's
also going to release decomposing
bacteria
um say it lands in the water
well it's now going to become aquatic
microorganisms now you've heard me talk
about the great mass migrations uh
before the great human expansions and
this here again is a subject that is uh
somewhat debating or debatable that that
there is microbes that live can live
both terrestrial and Aquatic I'm a firm
believer of it but there's plenty of
people out there that would say I'm I'm
batshit crazy on this but
that being said I have proven it uh to
myself many many times in the products
that I've done
um one of the key things that I focus on
is diatoms those are
specific organism that lives generally
speaking in aquatic environments and it
produces or they produce oxygen via two
different sources that's why they're so
powerful one is through photosynthesis
and the other is through
consuming biology consuming bacteria
consuming nutrients that are are in the
water system and then using their own
internal
biological factories to take that
nutrient out of the water and build
their shells and build build their uh or
I should say divide and continue to
expand as a population so I've applied
I've applied
diatom based
um
well it's one of my ingredients it's
called fish Brew for lack of better ways
just let's get right after it so fish
Brew uh the the farm on Cape Cod has
fresh water diatoms like I've never seen
before and I got so excited when I found
this stuff because diatoms are a great
indicator like you I can apply uh
diatoms to your soil and I can come back
next year the year after the year after
year after and I'll be able to find them
if they're healthy they will have a
chloroplast and I can see the their
nucleus and their other you know
oreganellos if they're not healthy if
they're dead they're just an empty shell
made of silica and silica has a tendency
to last uh quite a while in the soil so
there's a great indication that I can
take aquatic organisms and put them in a
terrestrial environment and they will
survive
um so that being said
when I take my
um low temp compost
and I
throw it into a situation where I'm
using agitation centrifugal force
aeration soft collision and I'm breaking
off all of these pieces of of what I
want to call
pre-digested organic matter so it's in
the digestion process but it hasn't been
completely digested into like a palm or
a mom if there's still very much a lot
of organic matter that has not gone
through any kind of decomposition so now
I've I've taken that I've I've banged it
against each other I've pulled off all
of the little bits that have decomposed
um and I've I've done this in an aqueous
environment with fish brew and and some
worm castings
so now all of a sudden I have all of
this suspended stuff
uh in the water column it looks like
chocolate water so it's very very uh
rich with humic acids which we've talked
about as as the biological SuperFood
I've introduced all these microbes from
from fish Brew which is like incredible
if you look at the the DNA sequences of
what they've done it's called Meadow
meta barcoding where you're getting a
general idea of who's present or who's
been there
um which gets deeper into horizontal
Gene transfer which we can't go there
today but that being said is now I have
all of this diversity I have all the
endophytes from from the decomposed
organic matter I all of these uh
biological constituents that came in on
the fish brew and then I have all of
these secondary and tertiary metabolites
from the digestion of the worms that is
called worm castings
so this in many ways you know when I
started this journey I had no idea what
the [ __ ] I was doing but now 14 15 years
later I'm really seeing like that was
like uh what do you call intuition
Instinct drove me down that path of well
everyone talks about how great worm
castings are I should add some of those
oh and I know how good fish manure is
because every time I play with it and I
appropriately aerobically stabilize it
and I poured on Plants man of those
plants explode and I also know the value
of compost and and the fact that it
brings in these these superfoods like
humic and fulvic acids as well as all
these secondary and tertiary metabolites
that that are happening during the
decomposition phase
so bam there's a there's a grand slam
Home Run For You by adding all these
things together
using mechanical forces to separate them
and then using uh what I call dewatering
Technique which is through vibration
vibrating the organic matter to shed all
of the liquid off of it
now I have a biological super
Secret Sauce whatever you want to call
it now if I want to make that shelf
stable then I have to press it so take
the dewatering to another level
and then I take that and fluff it up and
that's what you got was was that
po inoculated poem that's easy to work
with just put it in a glass of water
Stir It Up as a matter of fact on the
podcast couple weeks back I actually
drank some I put some 11 year old
product in a glass of water stirred it
up and drank it on camera because I've
been telling people that I eat this [ __ ]
all the time every time I work with it I
get in my mouth my ears it's always my
fingernails are always dirty so I'm just
constantly being inoculated with this
stuff so I proved that hey it's not
going to hurt you it's actually really
super beneficial to your your entire
digestive tract
because you're putting in microbes that
aren't there or weren't there or haven't
been there for a long time that are
doing again all these crazy biogeo
chemical reactions that we have only
begun to discuss because science is
moving into an interdisciplinary mode
because the reductionist side of it has
realized we can't just keep reducing
everything down to nothing and then not
talk to anybody about how does this
affect their work or how does this
affect that processor so it's an
interesting time to be alive as these
things are happening but we don't have
the technology yet to really delve down
what those processes are and why they're
so important and how they are affecting
everything around them
so again if if you don't have the
technology but you have the know-how
well then that's the key to the whole
thing is all right I don't know why it
works but I know it does work so I'm
going to keep doing it
and that's go ahead okay so so
um you know bringing this home a little
bit to uh like how it can be used by the
cultivator
um we it sounds like this cold compost
inoculant does all of the things that we
think a thermal compost will do uh the
you know we we we we use a thermal
compost as an amendment we use a thermal
compost as a as a top dress we use a
thermal compost to make compost tea why
do we do that because we want to add
um you know life Vibrance uh to our
plants but we know because they've been
cooked so hot because you know that's a
smart thing to do when there's pathogens
um that that it's it's actually not as
vibrant with life as as we would hope it
would be in our Gardens and so what
we've done with this is we have used a
lower temperature and we have gathered
our microbes and and protozoa and other
biology we have we've gone through the
effort to bring them together from these
three different directions and and we
are actually creating a air quotes
compost which is essentially organic
matter that is actually what we think of
when we think of compost but the common
form of compost that we get which is
thermal actually is not supercharged the
way we really want it to be and so this
cold organic matter because of the Care
we've put into it is actually what we
idealize about compost
yeah biomimicry right we talk about
biomimicry all the time I've had
arguments with people that say there's
no such thing as as compost in nature
and I'm like no you're wrong look at
every time there's a flood
that's all piled up all the sticks and
brush and algae from the bottom of the
river is piled up and that's float Sam
that's a compost pile underneath the
forest that's a compost pile that's just
a giant compost pile dead animals dead
sticks leaves you know plants that have
come in and gone out
um they're all creating compost now that
compost doesn't heat up in the forest
floor nor does it the float sand the
pile that's you know left by the side of
the river
those don't heat up those are those
would be considered cold compost do they
heat up to some degree well I'm sure in
in the pockets of it when it's really
dense and compressed that's going to
heat up but is it going to go
thermophilic no it's not it's not gonna
it's not gonna ever get to a position
where it could combust and that is the
end of the thermophilic phase if you let
it run wild is combustion is when the
microbes start to produce alcohol and
then and then it can you know
self-combust
so you know again thermophytes are are
important to understand and and
getting your head wrapped around the
fact that you do not want to
cross-contaminate you do not want to
deal with pathogens you do not want to
deal with seeds thermophilic process is
a great way to bypass that potential
problem
all right so um I want to go back to
talking about the the actual physical
structure of good compost uh during the
third set we're gonna we're gonna talk a
little bit more about your actual
manufacturing techniques all these ways
that you massage it but um you
um you know you made a special point to
talk about
um you're breaking the pieces down to a
small size using these other methods
that we're going to talk about but you
were very specific that the reason that
you're doing it is to make these organic
matter grains have lots of Housing and
Community opportunities for the microbes
and protozoa and amoeba and other
denizens of the rhizosphere right so so
talk a little bit that about that would
you about the the actual physical
structure of good compost
so this goes back to poem particulate
organic matter and moem mineral
Associated organic matter mineral
Associated organic matter is going to be
very dense kind of like
um worm castings except for even more
dense so think of bulk density how much
something weighs by volume
and those weights are going to be
indicators of
how long that material that organic
matter is going to last in the soil
system
as well as how quickly it will release
its nutrient
so poem will last two to three months in
an organic system uh Moen
will last two to three years so there's
a big difference what does last mean so
um you throw
um
poem down on uh on an orchard in three
months it's going to be gone it's going
to be decomposed by all of the biology
not the thermophytes but the other
decomposers whether that's fungi or
bacteria but it's going to be it's gonna
go away it's going to have been used up
as a nutrient
for the plants that you've applied it to
does that make sense yep I do okay so
again the the moment is going to last
years and the poem is going to last
months so what that tells me is that if
I colonize.com
and I apply it
then what's going to happen is we're
going to have a fast nutrient release
within within three months it's all
going to be gone it's going to be
consumed and released plant available
or at least stored in the in uh biology
in the bacteria
um whereas moam
um you're not going to get that fast
release you're going to get a really
really slow release which is good for
soil structure
because you want you want concrete
foundations you don't want to build your
your Palace on bamboo stilts right
but if I'm trying to get uh
inoculation
I want to get those microbes that that
have set up shop and and in these
condominiums on on this poem
then the best way to do it is use the
poem because I know it's going to have
released all of that biology into the
soil relatively quickly and to be honest
with you
moam is so dense the bulk density is so
great that you again you don't have the
ability for
um you know Mass colonization you
it's too dense it doesn't let the oxygen
in to feed the bacteria that in turn are
are providing food sources for the
protozoa and it gets complex but I I
think I explained it okay there yeah and
so um the the you want to have these
these small fluffy
um you know granular I I guess it's
probably the outside of them are also we
don't want anything like Smooth
um so it creates all these like small
micro hotels for all of these microbes
that is essentially the point exactly
dude like remember when we were smashing
up rocks yeah oh God yeah I remember
smashing up rocks to make my uh to make
my regen tent with the with the soil
horizons oh my God yep so no smooth
surfaces yeah
think of it like
if you polish something it's very
difficult for oxidization for uh you
know any kind of mechanical
um Force to to break it down so that
polish is is protection and and yes you
you want porous you want surface area as
much as you possibly can get so things
can get into the cracks and set up shop
and set up their biofilm and start to
expand out but they can't do that on a
smooth surface
they don't have the benefit of of the
protection on three sides they're
they're basically Exposed on 180 degrees
on a polished surface where if they're
in a little crack or a crevice there's a
very small exposure to to the outside
environment all right that makes sense
especially with the word porous that
that gives me the picture I'm looking
for so um so the last thing I want to
talk about here in set two
is um uh what is essentially the point
of the of the paper we for we referred
to earlier
which is talking about how you know in
this cold compost that we are are
creating
we want to have there be a variety of
fungals there
um and so like of course there is you
know you know basic funcles that that
we're all familiar with like mycelium
but this paper goes into uh depth that
there is a wide variety of different
fungal participants that the more of
them we have the more a combination of
fungals and bacterias and nutrients it
it becomes this kind of wild mix and
match where it like a buffet that that
um like everybody can get what they need
but you know I've never really heard
anybody talk too much about the variety
of of fungals except for like oh do you
want to make a you know bacteria
dominant
um compost tea or do you want to make a
fungal dominant compost tea that's about
as far as I generally hear it so would
you please address the the fungals in
the cold compost their importance and
um you know as much as you can tell us
like what they're doing there
okay so you hit on a couple of really
important parts
um first one is IMO right everybody's
like IMO IMO and Imo is the foundation
of natural farming what is IMO well I'll
be honest with you it's yeasts it's not
saprophytic fungi it's basically the
precursor the the the successionary
system that has to be in place in order
for sap robes to do their work to come
out to have an environment where they
can survive so it goes back along the
same understanding principles of soil
succession so you start with a very low
F to B ratio swamp uh non-associated uh
plants more bacterially dominant
and then you move all the way up into
the conifers which are
very funly dominant and and wide variety
of different uh constituents that in
play so in order to build that um
Foundation or that roadway so that you
can bring in the groups of uh following
the successionary groups into play you
need those yeasts you need those
um lower successionary fungal uh
um
life forms I'm going to use that term
because there's so much we don't know
so little in that paper they talked
about knowing about
.01
about what the [ __ ] is really going on
in these bylaws when I read that I
actually screenshot it and circled it
and sent it to some of my compost
friends I'm like do you know we only
know what 0.01 of of the microbes even
are like I I was astonished to realize
that we know almost nothing about what's
in our soil uh-huh and and then worse
yet uh the interactions
and those interactions are the key to
the whole thing
like like why does the thermophite heat
up why why is why is that getting out of
control why is it because I put so much
nitrogen in there that if this pile is
going to combust like what is that
biogeochemical process that's happening
that's creating so much heat it's it
gets crazy
um so you know that being said
IMO works so great because it's putting
all of the foods and the successionary
species that need to be present for some
of these older later succession species
to come into play
so um
in in understanding the compost process
in getting a fungally dominated compost
you've got to have those yeasts to to
even begin to get the sap robes to come
in and do their thing and we're not
going to get into my Horizon but we're
going to stay with decomposing fungi for
right now and the yeasts and the moles
those are decomposers so they're good
guys to have to bring in think of prey
Predator we talk about this all the time
so the yeast
the molds are like deer and the sap
robes are like the saber-toothed tiger
or the leopard that's going to come in
and eat them so that's how you get that
system to start functioning is by
creating the prey so that the Predators
come in
um so where are we going to get our
Predators from well we get them from old
rotten wood chips that's one of the
major sources for getting
decomposing saprobe fungi you call
mycelium a lot of people don't
understand that mycelium is actually
like a chord it's filled with hundreds
if not hundreds of thousands of
different individual organisms that are
all working together
uh like a internet Super Highway and
that white coating on the outside that
is actually a protection uh against
oxidation so that when if that if that
individual organism that individual sap
robe actually got exposed to oxygen it
would disintegrate or or exposed to UV
it would it would disintegrate so that
white coating is actually to basically
think of it as the the wrapping around
your electrical cord it's to prevent
something from going catastrophically
wrong
and
the the most interesting component of
that is that when you find that you've
that mycelial cord in your
old two-year-old wood chips and you pick
it up and all those other little pieces
of of organic matter are hanging on like
a web underneath it now you know you've
got
uh many many different later
successionary species of sap ropes so
that's why again if you if you take the
time to actually Harvest these chips
that are loaded with mycelium and you
heat it up over 120. you just wasted all
your time you killed everything
so that's why it's so important that you
keep this at a lower temperature so that
they will colonize your organic matter
so that when you go to actually strip it
or use it they have gone through a
sporulation phase where they have
uh until a point where they grew out a
ton of spores or clubs or feet depending
on you know which
Camp you want to talk about as far as
you know what the different sexual
methods that this fungi do to produce
their offspring
so I want to ask you about these
different sources for these mycelium
these varieties of fungals because we
know we want them and we know we want a
as you know as wide of a variety as we
can and we know that the these you know
using IMO indigenous microorganisms
that's like a uh that's a a simple
low-level version that will evolve some
fungals which is great but then we're
also going to throw uh wood chips into
our our pile because we want to capture
these hundreds if not thousands of
varieties of fungals I'm guessing though
that
um we probably want to pull our funcles
from a couple different sources so uh
you know uh you know our IMO box is
fantastic uh our our wood chips that's
fabulous what are a couple other places
that I want to hunt for wild crafting
these fungals to bring it back and put
it in my pile so I can have it be not
only fungally dominant but hella diverse
fungally dominant all right so let's
let's clean up uh the Achilles heel of
IMO so
it is taught and most people understand
or believe that that IMO collection IMO
one is going to have all of the fungal
constituents that you're looking for it
does not it only has the foundation the
yeast and yeah it's probably got some
spores
but it's not
nearly as diverse as one would think uh
generally you see the the microscope
slides people post on Instagram those
are called pin molds they're very
important uh foundational creatures for
succession to occur so are you producing
a [ __ ] ton of pin molds but when you
introduce IMO 3 which again is going to
be uh
uh
very
pin mold heavy
and you introduce that into a imo4 which
is when you blend it with soil
that's when you're really going to get
your fungal colonization that's when
you're going to get your sap robes your
your more later succession fungi to come
into play because there's the food there
for them right there's all those pin
molds doing all their thing that is
providing the foundation or the paving
the highway for the sap ropes to come
into play
so
if you're looking for you know a
slow version of of getting to a fungal
dominance then yeah that works great but
the problem is if you don't have super
healthy soil to blend with your imo3
you're not going to get this the kind of
fungally dominant compost that you're or
organic matter that you're talking about
so back to how do I get this into my low
temp pile all right so number one is is
finding the old one to two-year-old
Punky wood chips with the mycelium
is going to have tremendous diversity in
it because that cord the thicker the
cords are and the more long and Webby
the chords are the more different
organisms you're getting saprobes
um
the other piece of this puzzle too is
foods like what are fungal Foods well we
know like steel cut oats
um there's a bunch of them and you you
can research this on your own
but the other
wonderful place to get
saprobes are from Leaf Duff
so I talk about uh prevailing wind right
so everywhere you go there's generally
what we consider uh the winds Direction
the most days is going to be blowing in
this direction so basically you go to
wherever
um there's a stone wall a downed tree a
creek or a depression and the leaves
that blow across the yard will fall in a
natural pile
either behind that log or you know in
that depression there you go there's an
incredibly diverse uh indigenous sapra
fungi Factory for you to add to your
compost so again diversity diversity
diversity leaves chips
uh hey hey it's another good one or not
hey straw straws is already going to
have decomposers attached to it
um and then yeah if you can add some
Amic acids
um they're also a very good again
biological superfood they're good for
both bacterial and fungal kingdoms
um then you're gonna have uh incredible
success and then there's one last piece
of this puzzle if you're in a place
where you don't have access to these
kinds of things you can you go to your
local mushroom producer and ask him for
a spat mushroom block you do not want
mushroom compost because mushroom
compost has gone thermophilic and
they've been forced to kill all of the
biology because that's what the USDA
requires of anybody who's making
commercial compost has to hit that
temperature usually it's 150 three times
over the course of x amount of days
depending on what state you're in
um so if you get mushroom compost you're
getting you're not getting organisms if
you if you hit the mushroom block now
you're getting the organisms
wow that's really cool I have access to
many mushroom blocks which I will now go
get
um so I want to I want to take this idea
of wild crafting it I want to kind of
say I want to apply what you just said
to my world and and and then everybody
can kind of like do that in their own
heads for where they live so you're
talking about uh collecting these Leaf
collections that have naturally come
together
um you know in indentations and along
tree lines and stuff like that and so so
if if I'm wanting to do that kind of
collection in my neighborhood and so
that I have got the widest uh diversity
of fungals uh in my cold compost as
possible for me I would for example my
neighbor has got a long fence
and so the leaves like we I've all seen
in like you know Suburban neighborhoods
even though I live way out
um the the leaves blow against the fence
and they collect at the bottom and so I
can imagine going over there with a five
gallon bucket and just like like you
know smooshing all of these leaves
together and filling that bucket up and
so then okay great I've got a I've got a
collection from this particular bio
region along my neighbor's fence I also
have got this um uh huge ass uh Tree in
my yard and um because it the the base
of the tree kind of swells up because of
the old root structure there's always a
whole bunch of like magic like sitting
in there too plus as as you've talked
about before
um there's all of these these yeasts
these imos that actually kind of fall
from these trees these these fungal
dusts that fall from the trees so so all
right I will collect all of the leaves
that are at the bottom of the tree as
well and I'm going to get a little of
this little fur fur pit bits and
Fir fur bits and uh and some leaves and
you know I don't know random
organic matter debris and so like I'll
fill a bucket with that and then and
then maybe I would go over to the um the
Estuary here on the island go over to
like Fern Cove
um because there's all these different
leaves that that get collected in the
brush that is along the along with salt
water so so maybe I'll get some salt
spray and like a different variety of
funguses because that's a yet another
different environment and I'm thinking
to myself I want to I want the
environments to be different because
these different biological environments
are going to have different fungals so
now I've got like these three buckets
full and of course this could be you
know you could do as many as you want
but for this example I got these three
buckets and I'm now gonna put those in
the pile along with my IMO and so I've
got I've got the the very basic IMO
yeasts and I've got the way more complex
fungals from three different areas near
where I live plus I've got all this
higher end cool mycelial action going on
and all the hangers on that you
mentioned and so boom is is that by
ideal yes um just a couple little points
so when you're collecting Leaf stuff
you really want to scrape back the dry
leaves on the top and you want to get
down into the layer where they're kind
of slimy
that's where the magic is not in the in
the top layer that's dried out the top
layer that's dried out will then get
covered by this year's crop of leaves
and that'll press down and then become
the wet nasty slimy
underneath for for The Following season
so you're again you're looking to get
partially decomposed naturally
decomposed organic matter in the form of
leaves that have started to break down
and I always encourage people to maybe
this is the perfect place to use that
commercial compost for six bucks is is
to wild craft responsibly and bring
something in and leave that in place of
what you've taken out so that way if you
spread you know you've taken out say six
feet of of this uh you know top inch or
two of this leaf mold you can then
spread that commercial compost down and
then cover it back up with the with the
dried out leaves and you've not just
just totally Disturbed or [ __ ] Nature
by leaving a big scar oh I love that and
we've already talked about how while it
might not really work well for a compost
it actually works great as a fertilizer
and so and so we are we are helping
diversify that area right on wow okay
cool and then one other piece for
mushroom blocks is that people have to
understand that when they take that
mushroom block
um and they leave it it's going to get
this liquid slimy stuff in the bag
that's actually a biocide that's
produced by the fungi to protect from
bacterial infections and or yeast
infections or anything else that fungi
is doing everything it's can to to build
a fortress with the white cake around
the outside edge but it's also releasing
these uh biotoxins to fight off anybody
that could possibly compete with them so
what I generally tell people to do is
take the bag
and run it over with your car on soil
so you smashed it and then just leave it
in the bag so it gets nasty it should
get all different colors in it but it
shouldn't have any real liquid build up
because that's the biocide that you do
not want to add to your compost pile
because you will knock back your
diversity so the dealing with mushroom
blocks is a little bit more
creative than than one might think but
the longer you let those blocks dry out
and if it's raining it's raining doesn't
matter just just don't allow that
biocide to build up in the bag run it
over you know you don't want to rip all
the plastic off leave leave the plastic
on it until you're ready to actually
introduce it into your compost pile and
then when you're going to introduce it
into your compost pile it's going to
have this funky smell to it and again
remember our noses are there to protect
us to warn us from dangers so when you
smell it you're going to kind of like
pull your head back and go oh that
smells really funky
yeah that's okay it's kind of like when
you ferment things it smells funky like
you're not going to want to eat this
stuff but when it has that funky smell
to it you know it's ready it's going to
be providing all kinds of secondary
tertiary metabolites for everything to
kick in the only part of that I want to
tease at is the running over it with
your car I I believe that the car is the
only our goal is to break up the cake so
that the the white on the outside that
is providing the protective barrier for
the cake
um gets destroyed right like that's
Disturbed Disturbed okay so so like the
cakes that I have come in contact with
actually break up very easily in the bag
by hand and so it would be just as
effective if I just take the bag and I
hold it you know well with my two hands
and just you know twist my hands in
different directions and so break the X2
interior of the cake up a bit and then
just go with that right there's that's
that's the only goal of it right
with uh
I can't explain it biogeochemical
process that that's occurring but I have
noticed that when I do run it over uh
again I'm not I'm not trying to break it
up I'm trying to just kind of like
squish out any of the biocide and
disturb that that outer coating so that
now the local indigenous biology can
come into play and have fun with it as
well because there's still a tremendous
amount of resources
in a nutritional value that's locked up
in that block that that fungi is trying
to protect so I want to I want to expose
it to my local environment so I'm
getting all of my indigenous
microorganisms to colonize it as well so
that's why I'm saying like just run it
over uh again you don't want to tear the
bag off of it you just want to you just
want to like pop it so that you know
again air exchange can come in the bio
side gets squished out and then let it
sit and Get Funky Man the more funky it
gets the more diverse
um of of in uh
the more diverse of microorganisms that
you'll get from your micro environment
does that make sense yeah I totally
follow all right so we're going to go
ahead and take another Break um and then
we're going to finish up with set three
we are going to talk
um uh more about the the mechanical
massaging
um that Leighton does uh to create these
uh Community opportunities in the
inoculant organic material and then
we're going to talk a little bit about
how to actually
um to use this in your garden
um you are listening to shaping fire and
my guest today is soil biologist
Leighton Morrison
[Music]
for decades Americans have enjoyed
cannabis flowers and joints and bongs
and bowls and now with the normalization
of cannabis use increasing across the
country we have the opportunity to enjoy
smoking cannabis luxuries that simply
were not attainable before
North Coast hand rolls blunts cannons
rosin infused donuts and canagars
available in the state of Michigan
North Coast focuses on Flavor over
everything else instead of growing their
own flour North Coast goes out into the
cultivation community and creates
relationships with the best Growers
working with the best new cannabis
varieties available
surely heavy THC is a factor but North
Coast focuses on Aroma complex terpene
profiles and taste that continues
throughout the entire smoking experience
the North Coast team curates flowers
like others curate art they seek out the
best talent build relationships helps
them take their product to the highest
levels and then buys their well-cured
flowers in order to hand roll them just
for you I really like their hand blown
glass tips
and North Coast has branched out Beyond
canagars into rosin solventless thca
diamonds and exceptional hash rosin
carts for on-the-go cannabis
connoisseurs too
North Coast provides you with attainable
luxury offering you an Ultra Premium
smoking experience at a price that seems
reasonable and repeatable
to find out more about North Coastline
of cannabis products visit their
Instagram at
northcoast.rolling that's North
coast.rolling and when in Michigan ask
for North Coast at your favorite Shop
North Coast
[Music]
there is no doubt that auto flowering
canvas plants have finally come into
their own and Night Owl seeds Works
tirelessly bringing you Autoflower
genetics that are reliable thriving and
with extraordinary terpene profiles
Night Owl seeds is an industry leader
because of the focus work of their
founder Daz Daz is Passion about the
cannabis plant and pushing what
autoflowers can do and cultivators know
that these efforts show through in his
seeds and Night Owl seeds really are
extraordinary just take a look at the
thousands of photos and by fans on
Instagram the proof is there and obvious
terpenes are complex and Rich plants
have Vigor if you are a fan of Mephisto
genetics like I am you'll likely also
love Night Owl seeds Night Owl founder
Daz worked with Mitch Mephisto to build
the Mephisto brand for years including
breeding mephisto's much-loved sour
stomper and Cosmic queen cultivars I'm
growing both night owl and Mephisto this
year because I want the best and Night
Owl seeds knows how to cultivate
Community too Daz puts out great
stickers exclusive packaging for limited
runs and desirable freebies he really
draws you in if you love Creative
branding Night Owl even has the secret
owl Society text Club just text the word
Night Owl one word to
760-670-3130 for early announcements and
exclusive opportunities of course you
can see lots of photos and find out
about upcoming drops by following the
night owl seeds Instagram too at
daz.nightowl that's d a z dot Night Owl
you can get your packs of Night Owl
seeds at several Distributors including
DC seed exchange insane seeds and hembra
genetics that's Night Owl seeds there's
a difference because we're different
for years organic cultivators have been
looking for a peat moss replacement peat
moss has long been the go-to soil
amendment for water retention and
container growing but organic Growers
are recognizing now that peat moss is an
unsustainable resource and the mining of
peat bogs destroys Wetland habitats and
releases sequestered carbon but peat
moss works so well that many have
continued to use it now there is finally
a revolutionary replacement for peat
moss that provides better benefits while
being a sustainable choice
pit Moss sounds and acts like peat moss
but instead of being mined from fragile
ecosystems is actually made from
upcycled organic paper and cardboard
headed for landfills pittmoss is
excellent at retaining water in your
substrate and creating air pockets and
Tiny living environments for microbes
pit Moss instantly increases aeration
nutrient absorption and Water
Conservation too
carefully and locally sourced pittmoss
is the result of decades-long research
into the use of recycled paper fibers
pit Moss is lightweight and easy to use
and pit Moss is an earth so it won't
change your pH
available in a range of preparations
including a nutrient enhanced blend and
an organic soil conditioner with no
added nutrients pit Moss is also
available as an animal bedding for
horses chickens and small animals
you can save 15 percent with the
discount code shaping fire one word no
caps when shopping on pitmoss.com so go
to pittmoss.com now to learn more that's
p-i-t-t-m-o-s-s.com growing healthier
stronger more sustainable plants pit
Moss
welcome back you are listening to
shapingfire I am your host shangolos and
my guest today is soil biologist
Leighton Morrison
so before during the break late and I
were talking about uh the inputs that
for this cold compost
um because when I visited him there in
Ventura uh I don't know right before
kovidi started
um he had all this stuff in his backyard
that he was growing it all looked like
like weeds and shrubs and stuff and I'm
all like oh you know what are these
plants and you're like oh I'm growing
this stuff for my compost and I didn't
think much about it and moved on
um but it's not until today that I
realized
um whereas most of us will wild craft
our inputs for the compost or or we just
produce it like you know
um you know air quotes accidentally on
our property
um Leighton you actually are growing
um green inputs that you know you like
for making your cold compost and the
idea of of growing specific things
intentionally just to to kill it for
your compost is really interesting and
and and I found it kind of inspiring and
I'm probably not the only one so before
we like move on um why don't you just
hit on that like like what what are you
growing for your compost and and why do
you bother
well that's a good question
um Chango uh I've found that again
diversity diversity diversity is the key
to making some incredible end products
and so
um yeah I grow uh indigenous uh grasses
pollinator plants flowers uh even even
some little shrubs and and basically I
don't kill them I just cut them back
from time to time I don't let things go
to seed that I put into the pile so if I
see something that's going to seed out I
either just let it seed out and then
wait till it's done seeding and then
take the brown because the plant dies
after it seeds out and just make sure
that I'm getting all the seeds off of it
and leave them in place in the soil and
then the greens of course I I trim back
the grasses I love flowers in my compost
pile I think they just bring a whole
other level of
biological uh superfoods to to the
decomposers that they wouldn't
ordinarily get
um so yeah I think that everybody if you
got a little corner somewhere you can
obviously just buy green manures seeds
or wildflower seeds or whatever
whatever's locally grown or uh locally
responsibly grown in your area
why wouldn't you and again you know I'm
I'm blessed I don't go through a
a harsh winter here yes we have certain
plants that do die back in in the Colder
Weather but for the most part everything
pretty much grows year round so I'm very
blessed in that regard but if I was to
say do this in New England
um I typically would build a pile in
Spring and I'd build a pile and fall so
I'd be harvesting
um you know the the whatever I could get
my hands on in the spring like the new
stuff that was popping up
um and then in the fall I would
obviously be collecting stuff uh
throughout the summer to to build the
pile and the pile in the fall so it's a
little bit trickier in in an area where
you have a true hard winter to do this
but even if you only Built one pile a
year you'd be fine
um but you yeah there's no reason why
you can't Harvest
um the the local you know or grow
whatever you feel is is important for
your area
um and then use the biomass in your
compost pile I like the idea because you
kind of put it on its head right because
like I take this stuff you know I grow
flowers and all this kind of stuff on my
property too and I just they naturally
find their way into a pile but the fact
that you kind of went backwards and
you're like okay what stuff do I like in
my compost that and now I'm going to
grow that like
um it's it's a diff it's it's a subtle
but important difference from oh I I
grew all this stuff because I just like
the flowers and I hope it makes good
compost versus I want good compost so
I'm going to pick the flowers and
grasses that make good compost that also
I happen to like it's like it's it
changes the direction of the decision
making and I find that uh kind of
delightful
yeah and and don't get me wrong I mean
I'll actually like pull up roots and use
those in the compost as well so if
something seeds I'll let it seed out and
then I'll pull that plant because I know
I've got seeds that are going to happen
pop next year and I'll I'll compost that
root ball because that's got the
rhizosphere in it
right on so all right so here we are in
set three and um the the two main things
I want to talk about is first
um uh you know you have talked about the
mechanical ways in which you manipulate
the organic matter to make more porous
Community opportunities for all the life
forms in the rhizosphere and
um you know we've kind of just hit on
that a little bit and then I've refer to
it as massaging but like I've been to
your workshop and seen all the stuff
that you do and and I think so far we've
given everybody a pretty good
um road map for how to make this at at
their house except for this part so
would you
um take us through the different
mechanical manipulations that you work
the organic matter through so that it is
Optimum for an inoculant
um
process yeah sure as a matter of fact I
recently did a uh a video a one-hour
lecture and uh an outline with a friend
of mine Jimmy Perkins who's actually
going to put it up online at some point
and we talked about charging 50 bucks
for it but it would be a great resource
for people to actually physically see
what I'm talking about and how I go
about it
um so that's that's something that it
was designed for uh the homeowner so
it's it's using mechanical forces on a
smaller scale than what I do
um but needless to say these mechanical
forces are scalable so I have a 85
gallon compost or excuse me um
yogurt maker that I converted into uh
one of my strippers and actually I call
her Raquel
and my other stripper I call her Sandy
because uh I went through superstorms
Andy and Sandy Hook in New England and I
said you know what poor Sandy's got a
bad name let's let's make something good
out of the name Sandy so the one that I
travel with is is Sandy and it was
basically a older washing machine that I
converted
um to do this uh what I call soft
Collision
so in a soft Collision think about uh
the two of us standing in a pool
um you know up to our neck in water and
under water I punch you like you're
gonna feel it you're gonna feel the
force of it but it's not going to hurt
you like if we were standing in the air
and I did that you'd you'd feel some
serious pain so that's the kind of
philosophy that I want you to think
about when you are talking about soft
colliding
organic materials or matters together in
a way that you're brushing off the the
loose pieces uh the fungi the the the
biology
you're not damaging it you're you're
basically using its own biomass to to
break off the pieces that are suitable
and ready to be used as poem to
inoculate your soil
all right so number one is soft
colliding using a washing machine would
you give a quick description of of your
retrofit of that washing machine yeah
um do you have to find a really old
machine
um the newer ones have uh a lot of
different sensors and computers thanks
to China
which I've tried desperately to convert
uh to many many lost hours and
frustration because as soon as I get rid
of this control that sensor is tripping
and now the machine won't go on or or I
I keep this control but I get rid of
that sensor because I don't want it and
then now this control will no longer
function properly so you have to find a
very uh old machine like it I don't
think you can get them anything after
2000 you're probably not going to be
able to convert so that being said
there's not a huge pool of these pieces
of equipment that have survived that
long in a junk pile so it's it's not a
particular easy
way to go about this I mean I did I did
this conversion back uh in about
2010 was when I made it but I had access
to you know used appliance stores that
were
had plenty of older inventory that I
could manipulate so bottom line is you
know you have to gut it so you have to
take the whole thing apart power wash
the inside get rid of all the residues
all the soap scum you gotta replace
bearings you know check for uh wire
phrase but you're basically looking at
you know taking all of the wiring out of
it so you basically have two functions
Spin and agitate and no time restriction
like all those little control that the
little dial you bypass that whole thing
so it it's not something for the
light-hearted you've got to be somewhat
of a mechanical or high Mechanical
Aptitude and somewhat of an inventor to
actually do this but it's possible if I
did it anybody could do it
so that being said
um the the more simple way uh for a
user-friendly small scale application is
to just use a paint mixer or a compound
mixer and a cordless drill on a low
setting and that's where I did this
video with with Jimmy so that uh you
know people could see oh wow this is
really actually quite simple
and in in my work I've I've taken a
little bit further because I'm really
trying to produce the most powerful
inoculant I can so I also use
um along with agitation
I use aeration so I I have a little air
pump that that pumps air in down into
the agitator and on the agitator I
created these whips out of polyethylene
pipes that go all the way out to the
edge of the barrel so when that's going
back and forth those are basically
acting as a sweep to sweep the material
off the floor of the uh washing machine
and with the aeration now is it sweeps
it's blowing the stuff up into the you
know higher up into the water column and
then only to sink back down in the
center and repeat agitate and repeat
repeat repeat or what is it rinse and
repeat so by doing that I'm I'm adding
another level of
um physical Force to this organic matter
so it's colliding on the way up it's
getting swept it's getting ground it's
getting pushed into each other and then
of course I'm adding a tremendous amount
of oxygen dissolved oxygen into the
aqueous solution of fish brew and water
so I'm really getting another added
benefit by by doing that but again
without without a proper piece of
equipment it's a lot more difficult to
do that the yogurt mixer has sweeps on
the outside pushing in it's a cone
bottom and of course I've used a
tremendous amount of oxygen blowing up
through the center of that so that's
creating that same aeration
agitation that I did with the with the
washing machine
um and then on top of that I have two
impellers opposing each other so one
impeller is pulling from the bottom and
throwing it up and the impeller above
that is actually throwing pulling from
the top and throwing down so I'm getting
three levels of of agitation with that
piece of equipment and I the reason why
is because I'm trying to do it um as
efficient and as quick as possible so
I'm using all the different forces uh
possible to you know again produce a
high volume of uh you know super
powerful inoculin in a short period of
time so if if this washing machine that
you have
um uh messed with it's got the organic
material and water in it
um
what's coming out of it like like uh all
right so inside the barrel
um you'll see that it's got holes little
tiny you know eighth inch drill holes
all the way around it so that drill
those drill holes are acting as a screen
so when I'm washing my compost anything
bigger than an eighth inch isn't going
to get through those holes it just stays
in the barrel and when I spin it I'm now
pulling all of that moisture out of that
product or out of what's left in the
barrel and then what's left in the
barrel I just scoop up and I throw it
right back in the compost pile again
so that's the first level of screening
and so and and and the water that's
coming out of it that is not a waste
product no that's actually the that's
the goodies that's the point
so so you're using the water and the
agitation to
um strip everything out of your organic
material
um and while while you're still going to
throw that organic material back in the
pile the goal is to
um have the organic material give up its
goodies right right and release all the
humic acids fulvic acid secondary
tertiary metabolites along with all of
the biology that went in there and again
I'm using fish Brew in that process so
I'm basically using uh about a gallon
and a half of fish brew and about
three and a half to four gallons by
volume of compost in that one process
now on a smaller scale you can do this
in a compound bucket and you know buy a
quarter a gallon of uh fish Brew
add that in there with you know a couple
handfuls of compost you know agitate for
15-20 minutes on slow and you'll get the
same end results you just won't have
been as efficient in removing all of
those organisms and components that
you're looking for right on and I know
you and I both share a a love of the
fish Brew product but I'm always trying
to make people
self-sufficient so if somebody doesn't
want to buy the fish Brew they can you
know go their own way and collect fish
poop so find themselves an aquaponics
company or whatever the point is is that
you know fish Brew is the easy way to go
but but you can also do this if you use
your aquarium water oh absolutely
aquarium water is wonderful I mean
personally I don't know why every farmer
does not have at least a freaking you
know aquarium at the and instead why not
a fish pond why not you know I always
promote aquatic microorganisms as so
important and one of the biggest missing
pieces from the soil because we don't
have mass migration anymore we the soil
used to get inoculated every time a
migration occurred but that doesn't
happen anymore so Amos are in my mind
the the foundation of of creating
regenerative healthy soil so without
them what are you really accomplishing
so another way to to get aquatic
microorganisms is to do a a wild craft
of kelp or or algae uh duckweed any of
those things
um and you basically in aquatic plants
you put them in a bucket put the wire
mesh on top put a brick on it so that
the plants are all submersed below the
water put it in the hot sun for three to
five days depends on where you are and
what temperature you're at but what
you'll see is a white frothy foam that
raises to the surface and again it's
going to have a funky smell so your
body's gonna be like ooh that's weird
what is that so you're going to kind of
get a reaction to it it's not going to
smell like poop but it's not going to
smell like forest floor either it's
going to smell funky kind of like those
mushroom blocks
um but that is a very powerful aquatic
microorganism uh inoculant that you can
pour on your compost pile and you know
it's funny that that you say that about
fish brew and I just traveled the entire
country and I we did soil micro uh soil
awareness classes I I think I did seven
of them
um across the country and I had the same
answer at every one of them I'm like
dude you need fish Brew dude you need
fish brew and I've got to the point
where I was like man these people
probably think I own fish Brew in
reality I don't I have no stake in it
all I can tell you is that I've been
using that product
since rodale since the Inception of
trying to do this actually before rodale
I'd come to realize that there was
something really special about fish
manure because every time I put it on a
plant I'd see plant reaction that's the
whole reason I went down to Rodeo to
talk to this woman named Elaine who had
no idea who she was and show her this
stuff and put it under the microscope
and she came back and goes holy [ __ ]
where did you get this
so it is the the the missing piece of
the pie the biology just like in soil
science they're missing the biology
everybody's missing the biology and can
you do this
with your own compost absolutely you
have two choices time or money how much
time you got if you don't have a lot of
time then you need to spend the money if
you don't have a lot of money then
you've got to spend the time but can you
do it without fish Brew absolutely but
it's gonna take time and end trials and
and you know learning how to work with
um aquatic organisms
all right so back to how you are
mechanically uh breaking up and
stripping your soil we've got the first
one which is your soft colliding washing
machine what's another one
okay so soft colliding
um aeration dissolved oxygen in the
water again adding those other elements
because every time that bubble comes up
it pushing something out of the way and
displacing and putting it back into
mechanical uh
back into a mechanical force position
so then after you go through uh those
basic or I want to call beginning
processes of of pulling apart the
organic matter the next would be uh
through dewatering so by dewatering
there's a couple of different ways to do
it um there are some really cool screw
presses where you'd feed in this slurry
at the top of it
and it has a big auger in it and it
presses that material until the liquid
oozes out the sides and eventually you
just get this cake that comes out the
end where where when the screw pressure
has gotten so great that the end of it
will kind of open up a little bit and
let let some of the dewatered organic
matter to spill out into the waste pan
I've also used uh personally I've I've
went toward what's called a concrete
vibrator it's used to mount on the walls
of Foundations so that you're vibrating
the concrete to get all of the air out
of it and I use that in conjunction with
a metal or wood frame and with a
stainless steel mesh screen did I String
like a guitar
and then I suspended on these rubber
isolators so that the vibration is only
occurring on the screen and not
vibrating everything else around it so
I've basically isolated the vibration
and when I hit the certain if you do
this you get the variable speed and you
turn it up or down and you'll get this
point where it's called resonance
when everything is vibrating and the
liquid just pours out of it if you're if
you're not right what's going to happen
is the top is going to start vibrating
and you're going to see all this air
bubbles and stuff coming up but when you
hit that sweet spot that resonance
you're not seeing any surface action on
the top but you're just hearing the
water pouring out of the bottom
that has a couple of different
advantages first of all yes you're
getting the maximum amount of liquid out
of that organic matter that is otherwise
over saturated
but through vibration
your exciting electrons and this gets
really [ __ ] deep but excited
electrons tend to want to interact with
each other
um they want to hold they want to bond
so one of the most interesting phenomena
that's behind this process is that I
noticed after I've vibrated it
and say I want to sift out some
rejuvenate or some Alliance which is one
of the two products the solid products
that I make
I will see you know the liquid goes
through and then the clumps on the
surface
start to clod they start to attach they
start to form micro Aggregates almost
immediately it's it's crazy Shango
um and I've noticed too that when I take
it to the next level and and you know
stabilize or completely dewater the
alliance or the rejuvenate
um I basically put it in a giant press a
screw press and I just keep cranking it
until I squeeze out what is literally
pure folic acid
um I then take that cake
and I again run it through a vibrating
screen to create that soft fluffy stuff
that you talked about earlier in the
show when you put that stuff on soil
oh my God automatically clay platelets
sand particles they just start to bond
together and create these
microaggregates I can only explain it
through my understanding of of quantum
mechanics that when you stimulate
electrons and and protons
um that you can actually create these uh
paramagnetic charges
um that begin to want to attract or
repel based on their charge
I know that was a deep one no no makes
sense though so I've got five of these
so far soft gliding washing machine
aeration bubbles dewatering press
concrete vibrator and then a vibrating
screen what else what else is that it is
another one I would say that's the
majority of it I mean again
um your goal here is to lower the
moisture value of the product if you're
trying to make it shelf stable if if if
shelf stability isn't an issue and you
just want to make it and use it then you
don't have to go through um all of these
processes like you you can just like
literally like just take it mix it I
poured it into a paint strainer which
was stupid I should have used a insect
screen because in turn we're only
putting it in a watering can and
watering it so I don't need to take all
the big chunks out of it
um the the more chunky it is
um the better and higher level of
inoculation that you can create uh
quicker so again the chunkier the better
so I think those are pretty much the
primary forces and then it's just a
matter of all right how are you applying
it okay and that'll that'll drive you to
all right I got how to screen it to this
level because I'm running it through a
diaphragm pump please do not use
centrifugal force centrifugal force
creates cavitation cavitation kills
biology so you don't want to have any
kind of uh
mechanical
pumps that that will create cavitation
or centrifugal force you want to use a
diaphragm pump so if you are using a
diaphragm pump and you've got spray rig
or nozzles that you've got to deal with
then you have to screen to that level to
get it out there in the field so I want
to I want to take a pause here and and
like for people who possibly like me
these last five steps that you have
mentioned
um were are very
um off-putting right because like I'm
not I I wouldn't do this stuff right and
and I think it's important to to point
out that the the point of the show was
to encourage folks to make a cold
um a cold compost which is essentially a
organic material microbinocular and you
don't have to do this last part all you
needed to do was just not ha you know
put the care
into collecting your plants and then not
let the pile get too hot
um like that's that's it that that's the
whole point of what we're encouraging
folks to make and but but to do it right
you need to do things like you know make
sure you avoid your pathogens by using
plant material only and make sure it
doesn't get too hot and then like the
stuff that we talked about during set
two
these things that we're talking about
now
uh number one they remove the water to
make your final
um material shelf stable but also by
breaking it up it creates
um lots of places for microbe life to
attach to the soil like it means that
the the the compost will be quickly
integrated into wherever you place it
and also
um increases the places for Community
right because there's all these like 360
degree ridges everywhere but but but if
if we lost you here at the beginning of
set three with this mechanical stuff
don't lose heart because you don't you
don't have to do this part this is this
is really just a way to finish it
if you need to you know make it stable
where you're gonna you know make it once
a year and then let it sit all year
right you don't have to do this no you
don't have to do this but the reason
that this is important to understand is
all about delivery
so we've grown these organisms we've
we've done the work we've made this
beautiful biologically Rich compost how
do we get that biology into the soil
um effectively and efficiently the only
way to do that is with liquid because
the liquid will help move those
organisms down into the soil profile you
take your compost this amazing stuff
that you made and you top dress well
fifty percent of it's going to get
oxidated and die or exposed to UV and
die so how effective did you get those
microorganisms down into the soil not
very effectively you lost 50 percent of
them so you're actually making two
products here
um the the one product is the actual low
moisture
inoculated compost that even though you
know you've removed most of the water it
is still brimming with life and and it's
essentially a dry good that you can sell
in a bag but then there is a secondary
product or useful product which is the
the water that keeps on coming out of
this stuff which is just also brimming
with life and and that you're you know
we don't care about it being shelf
stable you're just going to pour that on
your plants right and that's the key
again is delivery so how do we get these
microorganisms uh into a condominium
where they have food water and cover and
then how do we get them down into the
soil profile where they're going to be
safe and sound and and continue to grow
to inoculate so the the the other
product that we're talking about is
harmonize
um highly unstable like if you leave
this in a bucket for a day maybe two
you're talking about the water right
yeah the liquid um it's going to go
anaerobic because there's just so much
what's called biological oxygen demand
bod because there's so much at going on
in activity they're stripping the
dissolved oxygen out of that water at
such a fast rate that it it can't
survive and if it goes anaerobic well
now I've defeated my whole purpose my
purpose was to get
minerals nutrients biology into the soil
so that it could do its work and it was
no longer Mobile in other words if it
rained it didn't wash away but if I go
anaerobic I've basically made a nutrient
solution that's all the plant needs
right there in that liquid even though
it smells like hell
if I pour it on that plant the plant's
going to be able to take it up really
quickly but if it rains or I water I've
washed it all out of the profile so I
think that's the real missing piece is
mobile or not mobile what am I producing
and my goal was always to produce
non-mobile nutrients that in the form of
biology that could be there for as a
nutrient bank for forever for thousands
of years
so that's again the mechanical side of
this is how to effectively and
efficiently deliver this very sensitive
biology down into a place where it is
safe and it has food water and cover and
if you are somebody like me who is very
interested in a cold compost but I'm not
going to do the mechanical aspects of
this it is also fabulous and way better
than your thermal compost if you were to
just make this cold compost pile and
then make a compost tea with it and just
pour it on your plants and get right to
it that's the That's essential
essentially what we did we made a
compost extract not a tea like yeah you
could take this biological compost throw
it in your Brewer whether you put it in
a bag or free Brew it personally I would
free Brew it which is basically just
throw handfuls in there bubble it for uh
30 hours again we need to touch base on
that why that's such a critical point in
time
but now I've made a compost Brew so I've
taken a handful of this compost that I
made the cold compost threw in a little
bit of sugars again it's uh you want to
make sure you're using
unsulfured black strap molasses no more
than one ounce per 20 gallons if you do
use more you're going to raise the
biological oxygen demand bod and you're
going to have an anaerobic [ __ ] show so
you've got a very very little bit of
foods
bubble it for 30 hours and then use it
up by hour 36. the reason being is that
between hour 20 and hour 24 is when you
start to get your high level of protozoa
and production in other words you've
provided the bacteria you provided the
deer now all of a sudden the Lions the
Bears and the wolves are coming in and
they're breeding like crazy because
there's so much food in the source and
that's why it's critical that you wait
till hour 30 so that you've had a good
six to eight hours of high level of
protozoan production because at the end
of the day everybody's missing the
protozoa it's all about the protozoa we
all have bacterially dominant soils
so what is the missing piece protozoa
they're the ones that are eating the
bacteria and releasing that plant
available
so the other point is that yeah if you
just took this uh this cold compost and
you threw it in some water and agitated
it with your hands and then poured it on
your plants now you've basically made a
compost extract with it so do you need
the mechanical stuff no you can use your
hands but if you're gonna take the time
to actually massage it with your hands
for a period of time wouldn't it be
easier to use a power drill
you know so yeah no it's going to say
it's it's all about delivery how are you
getting those organisms into the soil
the most effective and efficient way and
I think the key to this is go ahead and
make your cold compost pile and once you
have that there's a whole bunch of
different ways that you can apply it but
but we're encouraging you to make the
pile and don't overheat it and once you
have that you can do it the easy way
which is how I will be doing it which is
to take a you know a few handfuls and
bubble it up for 30 hours and put it on
your plants you want to take that
further because you know maybe you're
scaled and you want this to be available
to you in a few months well then go
through more of the mechanical stuff
press out the water and then you can you
can put that um that compost on the
shelf and it will be ready for you when
you need to use it in a few months and
you can use that water now so
um but but really it's all about getting
getting that pile made and not having
the pile get hot
I'm into that dude all right it's all
about making ingredients one interesting
uh footnote I would like to throw in
here is that people will be astonished
at all the unexpected benefits that come
from using a
um a biology Rich cold compost and the
one example that I want to have because
it's really hard to say oh my plant's
color got so much better and and oh like
look like the the flowers were so good
and oh my gosh the flowers tasted better
I felt like it had a wider terpene
profile than I normally get all that's
true but it's really hard to to to
measure that but what I can tell you is
if you go back in the in the shaping
fire Instagram you know we've got these
this four by four indoor bed that um you
know even though I'm using electricity
for LED lights I'm trying to use
regenerative techniques indoors uh it
kind of has an experiment
um because you know doing region
regenerative stuff indoors has got its
own challenges and so I I did that and
um I ended up with a fungus gnat
breakout for whatever reason and um and
I'm like you know I'm talking with my
providers about the beneficial insects I
want and all this kind of stuff and and
I call you to [ __ ] because we're
friends and we do that and I'm like I
got this situation and you're like oh
let me send you up this cold compost
um that I've made and then bubble it up
and pour it on your bed and I'm like I
don't know I don't understand how a you
know a freaking compost tea is going to
um you know get rid of my gnats if
anything it's going to make the soil
more wet and I'm going to get more
fungus gnats and you're like well first
of all it's not a tea it's an extract
I'm like oh all right and uh and and
then but then you said you said just do
it and I'm like all right well I trust
you enough I just you know very often I
will just do the stuff you say and and
then watch for the benefit and then and
so that's what I did and I'll be damned
it was like I I I made this and I put
the five gallons of it um first I I I
sprayed it on the top so I made sure
that I got all the top areas but then I
just kind of like poured the rest in
and
um you know I was I had no fungus gnats
within 48 hours I was flabbergasted and
I called you and I'm all like what kind
of sorcery is this and and how did you
explain it to me
it is sorcery
um basically what you did was you threw
down a bunch of hungry microbes uh and
with a food source of of fungal larvae
uh fungal Nat larvae all over the place
so they just went to town it was like
buffet time
so yeah so so the the Predators
essentially that were in this highly
inoculated extract they went and they
ate all the larval of the of the fungus
gnats and like I never even considered
that approach to fungus gnats and it
worked nearly instantly and was like you
know very economical to do
um but that is just an example I want to
give folks for you know once you start I
mean we all love the microbes right and
we all believe in IMO and we all believe
in using nature as our Ally but this is
kind of next level
um and I encourage folks to to to do it
so all right so uh in in bringing us
kind of like to a close here Leighton
you know we we talked about
you know what kinds of compost or things
that are called compost are available to
us and and we talked about what those
options were like and and and some of
them like Verma Verma culture compost we
freaking love and and some of it like
the bag stuff we don't really love
um but but the one thing was that we
wanted to encourage folks to not heat
their piles and so so people go ahead
and they they they they don't Heat their
piles they're using clean non-pathogenic
um green materials and Browns and and
then they and they have this and they
make it and so now they've got what what
is going to be the nature of the pot
container or the soil if you're going
right in the ground kind of bring us
home here by describing the nature of
the soil after this application versus
the nature of their soil before the
application and and we'll end with this
okay uh that's probably the whole point
of this conversation is soil aggregate
um that's the reason you use compost
um and that's the reason we use microbes
is because they actually form
um aggregation and what is aggregation
aggregation is like a little
clump of sand silk clay and organic
matter inside that Clump is is
waterfalls and and ponds and cities and
walkways and parks and all kinds of
different creatures and organisms
considered a zoo and so inside that and
and it's in this article that talks
about the magic the the biogeochemical
reactions that are happening inside that
aggregate it's we don't have tools to
measure this yet we don't have the
technology to test it or monitor it or
actually
scope it in situ there is a new
instrument that was invented I believe
last year that is a microscope that you
push into the soil
and you can leave it there for for days
weeks and monitor this [ __ ] those are
the kinds of tools that we're going to
need to really Advance our understanding
on how valuable soil Aggregates are and
Aggregates are a combination of fungi
bacteria protozoa the physical side of
it as well as the chemical side of it it
is the is the is the triple threat it's
the physical the chemical and and the
biological coming together and that's
why the Aggregates are so important
again Aggregates let the oxygen down
lets the CO2 out back up to the plants
it holds water it allows water to
infiltrate into the soil so it's not
just running off and creating erosion so
aggregation is is the critical
Foundation to soil Health you can't have
Aggregates without good biology it
doesn't exist you have you have
compacted soil because you don't have
the biology but once you have the
biology and the organic matter in play
you will begin to form Aggregates so
again that's why I went through this
whole process of vibrating [ __ ] and
elect
exciting the electrons so they will form
these Aggregates extremely quickly
that's the whole purpose of taking this
biological compost and uh manufacturing
it for lack of better words
um so that you're getting a faster
response in in building the soil health
and building those aggregates
fabulous so you know it's not lost on me
and I I think this is one of the reasons
why as I learned more about cold compost
extracts why I kept on pursuing this
until I figured out what this was enough
to do a show about it I really think
that this is the future of regenerative
farming I think that you know thermal
compost has been a great tool for the
times but we are sophisticated enough
now to know how to work with the
microbes and to know that you know our
biggest role is to a stop [ __ ]
killing all the microbes and then second
you know add microbes and help them help
incubate them and make more of them as
much as possible because we're not
really the ones that are going to clean
up the mess we've made it's really the
microbes that are and so if we are
dedicating ourselves to not only working
Within
the natural forces of the Earth but also
to play our role to maximize them I
think that's the only direction that
makes sense
agreed 100 I mean we've we've learned
how to break [ __ ] down now we gotta
learn to put things back together again
the way nature would have through
biomimicry and not not through
our ego and for lack of better words I
think I think that is the best word man
Leighton thank you so much you know um I
always appreciate you
um you know both our friendship and then
having you on the show but this was
extra special today and um I appreciate
you sharing these these insights some of
them pretty damn revolutionary and
um and also you know slogging through
three hours of this I'm I'm exhausted
and I'm not even the one that was
talking so uh so thank you so much man I
I really appreciate you I appreciate you
too Shango you've been doing a lot of
hard work for many years and you bring a
very important message to to the
community as well as the general
population as a whole and so it's an
honor it's a pleasure for me to be able
to share what I've learned in my
experiences with you and and your
audience so thank you right on so if you
want to uh follow along with uh Layton's
exploits there are two ways to do that
um the first way is uh on Instagram uh
you can follow his Instagram profile
well at Kingdom
aquaponics LLC and I'll tell you
straight up like he's not a huge social
media guy because he's usually filthy
and in the field but he he does post
stuff to
um the Instagram it is always
interesting and when he goes on tours
you'll find all that stuff and you know
if if you have some reason you want to
reach out
um he does check his Instagram messages
so so that's Kingdom aquaponics LLC and
then also you can also find Leighton
every Thursday uh co-hosting his own
show on the future cannabis project on
YouTube
you can find more episodes of the
shaping fire podcast And subscribe to
the show at shapingfire.com and wherever
you get your podcasts if you enjoyed the
show we'd really appreciate it if you
would leave a positive review of the
podcast wherever you download your
review will help others find the show so
they can enjoy it too on the shapingfire
website you can also subscribe to the
newsletter for insights into the latest
Cannabis News exclusive videos and
giveaways on the shipping fire website
you also find transcripts of today's
podcast as well be sure to follow on
Instagram for all original content not
found on the podcast that's at
shapingfire and at changolos on
Instagram be sure to check out
shapingfire YouTube channel for
exclusive interviews farm tours and
cannabis lectures does your company want
to reach our national audience of
cannabis enthusiasts email hotspot
shippingfire.com to find out how thanks
for listening to shapingfire I've been
your host shangolos
thank you