[Music]
everywhere you look
cannabis enthusiasts patients and
consumers are turning away from
pesticides most pesticides approved for
growing food are not approved for use
with cannabis and yet there they are in
the market all the time these food crop
pesticides may be tested as safe enough
in very low doses when watered down and
outside in the rain on food products but
most have never been tested to be burned
and inhaled into the lungs like cannabis
often is and even more so been
concentrated like cannabis oil for
dabbing pesticides run the range of risk
from untested for safety when growing
cannabis all the way to specifically
toxic when used in cannabis and the
crazy thing is is that some people and
even companies still use them many
growers have grown accustomed to relying
on chemical pesticides when they get
spider mites or rust at my door any one
of the nasty bugs that attack cannabis
crops nearly nobody wants to use the
sketchy pesticides but some growers just
don't have the experience to rely solely
on holistic horticultural practices and
that's too bad too because people have
been growing without chemical pesticides
for decades
it's just that cannabis happens to be in
a pocket of modern agriculture that has
been late to adopt the damn thing is
that many states are not even testing
regulated cannabis for pesticides they
do it on an honor system and that sure
has not worked out well so far when the
state does not test for pesticides it
pretty much makes a mockery of the legal
systems claim to provide a superior
product to the black market in the legal
market right now you still have to know
your grower and that's the same thing as
unmet unregulated medical was cannabis
consumers are beginning to get educated
though about pesticides and pesticide
regulation and are starting to demand
cannabis grown without pesticides and
using other sustainable growing methods
like using living soil cannabis growers
with vision though have seen this coming
for a long time and many growers are
already migrating away from pesticides
and are leading the industry with really
clean canvas
products that consumers flock to today
we're gonna talk about working with
nature instead of against it we're gonna
talk about using beneficial insects as
allies to eat the bugs that are pests
and there really is a difference some
bugs will defend your garden instead of
destroy it and this is a
well-established agricultural practice
it's not new it's just new to cannabis
like so many other things now that
cannabis is being normalized today we're
going to encourage you to use bugs and
not drugs
to defend your cannabis garden if you
enjoy hearing frank discussions that
dive deep into cannabis health business
and technique I encourage you to
subscribe to our newsletter every week
you'll receive a new podcast episode
delivered right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week and
videos to don't rely on social media to
let you know when a new episode is
published sign up for the updates to
make sure you don't miss an episode you
are listening to shaping fire and I'm
your host
Shango 'lose my guest today is Shane
young Shane founded natural enemies in
2014 to focus on encouraging the use of
beneficial insects in commercial
cannabis prior to that Shane managed two
acres and acres and acres of ornamental
greenhouses for a greenhouse growers
magazine top 25 horticulture company
after personally designing transitioning
and running the company's successful
beneficial insects program he chose to
switch gears and bring his expertise to
the cannabis industry to help producers
reduce residual pesticides in medical
cannabis
welcome to the show Shane hey Shango
thanks for having me on man it's nice to
connect again yeah totally it's great to
have you back on so you know for most
growers familiar with using insects at
all they're used to using ladybugs and
praying mantis to fight pests in their
garden what are the advantages to
cannabis growers to move beyond using
these traditional bugs and using a wider
range of beneficial insects like the
commercial ornamental horticulture
industry does ya know good question and
when you're talking about preying mantis
and ladybugs those are kind of
generalist per se that you know they'll
feed on many different things that may
be in your garden they may not be as
aggressive as aggressive as some of the
species that we carry though
what we do at this stage is there's very
specific predatory mites that are
actually used for you know the pest
concerns that people have in their
operations you know the biggest thing
that we go into is we start from the
bottom you know fungus gnat issues rue
David's and cannabis and then it goes
into broad mite and rest of mites are
completely you know tearing companies
apart because of how how difficult it is
to figure out what you have because the
magnification is so small to see these
pests in and then you still have the
common ones you have to spot spider mite
thrips a lot of different things so the
species that we carry are very specific
and I guess they're kind of cultured
specifically for one job in mind and
that's you know what the pests are that
people have right on why wouldn't I want
a more generalized insect to be working
for me instead of a specialist so that
it just you know I can use one insect
and it gets rid of all my bugs or is
that just unrealistic no it's a good
question and it makes sense it you know
there's nothing wrong with having a
generalist out there you know it's
helpful in a lot of different situations
I guess you'd say but when you have a
specialist you know they have one main
job and that's to get a get rid of the
pests that you have that you're most
concerned with you know what I mean I
mean if you have a ladybug and praying
mantis they're not gonna do a whole lot
for the microscopic mites that you're
after so you want to use specific
species that are geared towards your
specific pest eradication comes about
they clean things up a lot quicker
basically rather than just a generalist
that's roaming around eating basically
yeah that makes sense now I know that
you just mentioned a few of the the
pests that you deal with but I want to
get a better picture of of what kind of
pests beneficial insects can be used
against so you know every grower pretty
much has got their archenemy right the
thing that they've been trying to get
rid of on and off for you know some time
you know can you give me a you know an
idea just name off some of the most
common pests that you are working with
so people get an idea of oh alright the
one the one that I'm concerned about is
on the list yeah no it's good and it's
been fairly simple to you know compile
this this list of what people's concerns
are you know coming from traditional AG
it was you know very common pest in
agriculture versus when I come into
cannabis it seems like one of the most
common pests
we encounter again our from the routing
system you know fungus gnats and the
biggest thing about those is that the
larval stages of those will feed on your
routing system of your plants which you
know I believe is one of the most
important part of your plants I mean
obviously the flower on the backend is
great but you know you have to have
healthy plants moving into you know from
mother to veg into your flower room so
plant health is number one and fungus
nets I don't think anybody should take
lightly I mean they spread diseases they
carry other pests with them and they can
spread to a room and you know and can
become real a real issue if you don't
take care of it the biggest thing about
that is what I learned is the amount of
watering you know that the cannabis
plant demand it amazed me because I had
never cultured you know cannabis I'd
never grown it myself and I just recall
working with one of the 502 growers in
Washington that where I gave them soil
mites to take care of their fungus gnat
issues and you know two weeks later he
called me back and told me I was full of
[ __ ] basically and I'm like god I'm like
the only reason I know these don't work
is you know they could freeze or if they
could drown out basically so he's like
dude he's like you know how much water
we're feeding our plants at this point
and you know when he told me a gallon of
water for a three gallon bucket every
two days possibly my first thought was
that we were pushing out reproduction
basically so we ran some trials we did
additional applications to be effective
with these things fungus gnats but you
know what's tearing people apart is rue
de foods as well those are huge pests
that people have problems with and and
and you know I'm always honest with
everybody they got to be one of the most
difficult to to get rid of to eradicate
generally when we work with people we
talk about sanitation first we talk
about scoping their soil that they're
bringing in basically you know because
eggs can be in that soil so rather than
trying to cure them of a situation with
our product we try to get to the root of
it on you know what can what steps need
to be taken first before we start using
our product moving forward and then it
comes to rates at that stage to be
effective so fungus gnats rue de fits in
the soils is common is very common on
what we deal with moving forward from
there like I had mentioned earlier you
know to spot spider mite has to be one
of the most common pests whether it's in
cannabis or it's like the poster boy of
bugs in cannabis
it's fairly common I mean everybody
should know it a two spots spider might
looks like it's been around it's very
visible by the eye it's easy to tell
what it is so pest identification is
simple but yeah it's been around a long
time and from there you know thrips are
very common as well in agricultural
crops regardless of if it's cannabis or
not but a couple the most difficult as
well has been broad mites and the hem
press it might as well and you know I
spoke about two spots spider mites you
can easily identify them because you can
see them with your eye depends on how
old you are Shango but you know for the
most part you're gonna need a scope
you're any the high-powered scope to
take a look at these things from what
we've gathered 60 plus magnification is
what's needed and you know my old my old
position as a plant health manager I had
the luxury of being twenty minutes away
from Oregon State University had a
research facility next to us an
extension service and we were able to
touch base on you know what they use in
research for out in the field and you
know in their in their offices when they
have things so that's where I started
about ten years ago is using specific
scopes in able to have pest
identification and what's actually
coming up more that I really didn't
focus very much on was is foliar a fits
as well it's probably been about in the
last three and a half years one percent
of one of the pests that we deal with
but you know this last year it seems to
be like there was a string of growers
that continually ran into it and I don't
know if that is because of our reach at
this point as a company on how many
people that we work with where we are
receiving more calls about it but it
just seems like it's a growing pest
concern with people as well right on you
know my experience supports what you're
saying about the once that once you've
got roof a if it's or or some kind of
infestation in the substrate that that
things can go to hell pretty quickly in
my experience once once they're in the
roots the whole plant starts to get a
little you know sick and lakhs of days
ago which creates an opportunity for you
know secondary pest so maybe we can
consider the the root pests to be like
the gateway pest which which you know
breaks down the Hort the Trojan horse
through the door and then and then the
secondary pest come do you find that
happening at the commercial level as
well oh yeah no you
you hit it right on the head man I mean
like I spoke about previous a healthy
plant you know sanitation from the very
beginning these are the key step there's
not one thing that you do in pest
management that's going to take care of
all your problems it's a it's a whole
slew of things that go into it you know
sanitation general plant health if you
have a problem in your rating system and
you have a weak plant basically it's
it's opening itself up to other issues
concerning no secondary could be disease
it could be additional pests because you
know it's kind of like you and I if
we're sick we're not at our best
basically there's no way for us to fight
off other things except we got to get
through it so you know at the commercial
scale for sure man I I think people are
still going through you know even though
I guess recreational use has or
cultivation has been around for you know
four to five years maybe six I can't
recall when it passed in Colorado but
you know all these people are still
figuring out how to grow at scale you
know any man in it I can't imagine it
being an easy task at all when you're
used to growing 20 plants or 50 or
whatever it may be you know now you have
to manage a team you don't you don't
just get to be with your plants every
single day you're doing other things as
well even though you're head of
cultivation or you're just I p.m.
management whatever the company may be
there's so many things that need to be
done you know we work with people as
50,000 plants I mean I can't imagine
even doing that myself so yeah
definitely you know to answer your
question in a roundabout way plant
health is great and one of the key
things in using an integrated approach
to pest management with beneficial
insects but yeah you hit it right on the
head when you're using beneficial
insects to defend your garden do you use
that strategy at all like some growers
do where you you leaves a couple sick
plants around as sacrificial lambs to
attract the the the pests or does that
just create an environment for new and a
you know secondary and original pests to
come into your garden well the way that
I have always been trained is if you
have a weak plant you want to get it out
of there you know you don't want to
contaminate anything else in your room
because it could bring it to your plant
but also the surroundings of the plant
that's sick I guess you would say
so just in you know a training of mine
has always been you know cleaning up a
leave deadly
was dead you know twigs things like that
if it's a sick plant get it out of there
you know cut your losses
sometimes basically and just get rid of
it may make things a lot easier for you
moving forward but for the most part I
would get rid of it then try to save it
you know when you talk about sacrificial
plants you can use companion plants or
beneficial plants basically that can and
this may be outdoors where you can wear
it kind of invites beneficial insects or
the natural you know predatory predatory
insects from the outside into your
garden outdoors indoors it's a little
bit more difficult when people are
working in sealed rooms you know yeah it
kind of doesn't really make sense
indoors but it can be helpful in the
pots you know it goes back to plant
health quite a bit right on so and I
think that the you know the elephant in
the room as far as like adoption of
beneficial insects always seems to be
growers who have relied so heavily on
chemical pesticides for all these years
growing underground during the
Prohibition era you know indoors that
that they have they've worked out their
tech they know their schedule they and
and they're like you know they depend on
it to deliver and and now because of the
huge pushback both by state regulators
and by individual consumers who don't
want chemical pesticides sprayed on the
plants suddenly now you know a lot of
these traditional growers are being
pushed to have to consider beneficial
insects and give up the bottles that
they've you know that they've wedded for
all of these years you know what do you
say to these growers that are clutching
on to their chemical pesticides to help
move their heart if you will away from
using what they've relied on move them
towards what is a more holistic solution
and working with nature how do you get
them over the hump of belief it's a
great question and it's obviously
something that we deal with on a daily
basis you know and you know not to
defend people who want to use sprays in
their garden because things have worked
well in the past but you know to say
something about that a lot of people
that's been their only option that's
what they're that's what they know you
know anything that's helped
people are trained at this point you
know bein at the company I was that
previous to my and he you know we had a
we have a preventive spray program for
twenty eight years that was in place and
my my reach or might jump into
beneficial insects was the
ineffectiveness of sprays it was worker
safety that I was concerned about it was
managing people around sprays and not
growing plants anymore
so to kind of answer your question we
don't I guess I'd say education is first
I'm not here to try to talk somebody
into using our product I try to give
them information on the benefits of
using our product you know the species
that we have and and what we can do for
you and with you and how that
transitions to you know health all
around whether it's you plant or you
know the consumers who use it on the
back end as well you know obviously you
know passed pesticide testing too so
that's a huge thing that is coming up in
the industry that's gonna be looked at
well if not coming up has been around
for a while that's continually looked at
on a daily basis so I always you know
taught nothing just me but my guys in
the office and I think I might have
chosen these words from you in the past
in conversation Shango that you know
it's even on our website it's choose
beneficial insects I tell my guys we're
not here to hard sell people we're here
to educate them first on what can be
used for their specific pest concerns
you know and then moving forward let's
hold their hand let any questions that
people have that come up you know
whether you've been using bio controls
for two years or ten I still get calls
from people that I set up a program four
years ago that have been a customer for
a while
that have a question that comes up you
know a lot of it is experience and I
think the biggest hurdle besides the
skepticism of it actually being an
effective pest management tool is is the
way that you kind of have to see to
believe
type thing like it actually works for
you you know what I mean
yeah well hit that party even harder
right give me an example or two of a big
trend a big commercial grow that has
made the transition because a lot of
folks they're just afraid of jumping
without a parachute or feeling like like
if they go if they start making the
transition and it doesn't work out that
they're gonna lose the whole crop like
give me a leave me a win success story
here so people can kind of picture
picture how it works at the
level during the second part of the show
we'll talk more about walking somebody
through the transition but just jump to
the end and give me an explanation of a
win well it's funny bring that up I mean
and and before the show I was as we were
speaking about a new hire of mine that I
have you know he was an indoor tier
three producer in Washington and I
didn't know this until he was actually
working in my office but I recall I
think it was December of last year when
I started working with his company and
he said Shane you know what can we do
for this here's our problems and I map
out controls that I usually want to tell
people if it was me this is how I would
approach it basically here's the species
to use here's what's gonna be aggressive
here's the days to order here's how much
to order basically this is what I think
is going to be effective for you and at
that stage he kind of took it and ran
with it calls me week later asked a
couple questions and within two months
he had a full transformation of you know
when I say chemicals I use that term
loosely as just sprays but they were
using Omri listed organic spray as
basically a lot of the times are
oil-based which are you know immediate
gratification it dissipates quickly but
within a couple months we had fully
transformed him over fast forward into I
just hired him two months ago to
represent me in Washington State and and
he's like you know when I called you a
year ago basically he goes I had to I
had to give my owner a guarantee that
your product was gonna work he goes you
never guaranteed that your product
wasn't work you actually told me this
isn't a guarantee man you know what I
mean this is this is what I think is
gonna be helpful again here's here's
what what I would use and what we would
do and he ran with it from there so
again in our previous conversation it
seems like a company needs to have that
guy there that is really interested in
doing it if there's an owner that's
pushing his head grower to do something
else that that is out of their comfort
level then sometimes it's really
difficult so I try to lay things out up
front towards people on where their
roadblocks may come in at where we might
have problems because I don't want to
make it guaranty and again it starts out
with education so I think that's an easy
story to tell as this guy tells me how
he works for me I was like yeah I
basically told the owner that I was
gonna guarantee that this is going to
work and he goes basically crossing
fingers everything worked out real well
and it's no issues at this point so
you know that was that was a great
success story in my head after hearing
from him we kind of went behind my back
and made the guarantee on his own to his
owner not for me basically yeah yeah I
get that and there's there's so many
variables to it and and you really do
need somebody on the inside who's going
to be dedicated to learning a little bit
about it and and paying attention to it
because it's you know while it is a a
comprehensive solution and works really
effectively it's not like a real simple
plug-and-play it isn't like a set it and
forget it kind of thing you like you
know most solutions for for a big guard
and you have to you have to massage it
let's go ahead and take our first short
break and be right back you're listening
to shaping fire and my guest today is
Shane Young founder of natural enemies
biocontrol
as a listener of shaping fire you
already understand the importance of
living soil when growing cannabis when
you have active microbe communities in
your substrate you go way beyond simply
fertilizing with nitrogen phosphorus and
potassium having active microorganisms
in your substrate supports vigorous
plant growth throughout the plants root
zone making for higher yields and
thriving flowers mammoth pea is the
first organically derived microbial
inoculant that focuses on your plants
nutrient cycling processes to release
soil phosphorus and other micronutrients
from they're bound forms making them
more available to the plant increased
levels of phosphorus will also keep
inner nodes shorter and focus your
plants energy on bud production not only
that but the microbes act as a defense
shield for the plants rhizosphere
by out competing potentially harmful
pathogenic microbes pretty cool right
mammoth pee not only unlocks the
nutrients in your soil but it also helps
protect your plant from disease mammoth
Peas beneficial bacteria act like
microbial reactors continually producing
enzymes that release nutrients mammoth
pee was developed at a u.s. university
has been extensively tested by Colorado
growers and independent laboratories
mammoth pee is proven to increase growth
and enhance blooming one of the great
things about supplementing with
microorganisms is that they won't
compete with whatever fertilizer program
you're already running simply dose on
top of your fertile
our schedule for increased benefits to
learn more and to find out where you can
buy ma'am at pee near you check out
their website at wwlp.com light
deprivation solutions into your
greenhouse you can often add two or
three additional growing cycles to your
year when you pencil out the financial
benefit of those additional cycles
you'll realize why commercial scale
light deprivation technology is remaking
the cannabis industry what used to be
done by pulling tarps over hoop houses
has been scaled up over the last few
years in such a way that it's become
mechanized easy and affordable to even
small-scale commercial cannabis
operations forever flowering greenhouses
is the industry leader in light
deprivation greenhouse design and
operation for the commercial cannabis
industry their team of greenhouse
experts have been in the fields of
Northern California for decades and
they're now building greenhouses for
commercial cannabis companies across the
country if you are new to light dep and
growing in greenhouses i encourage you
to go back to shaping fire episode 13
with guest eric Branstad of forever
flowering I talked with Eric about the
importance of intelligent greenhouse
management as well as the huge financial
benefit of incorporating light depth
techniques there are so many aspects of
utilizing a greenhouse that can go wrong
from temperature and airflow to light
depth and workflow forever flowering
will help you produce crop after crop of
well-cared-for flowers they can help you
retrofit your existing greenhouse with
light def and other modern systems at a
level that fits your budget if you're
just starting out forever flowering can
help you plan and build your new
greenhouse so that you get started on
the right foot the cannabis business has
enough risks without trying to go it
alone with your greenhouse contact
forever flowering greenhouses to partner
with folks who have an indisputable
reputation as knowledgeable and easy to
work with go to shaping feiyr.com /f FG
to find out more welcome back you are
listening to Shay
in fire I'm your host Shango Louis and
our guest this week is Shane young
founder of natural enemies biocontrol so
during the first set of the show we
talked about the approach to beneficial
insects and what they are and and why
they can be a great teammate for
defending your garden so so now we've
kind of given everybody an idea of what
beneficial insects are about let's talk
about thinking through the story problem
of introducing beneficial insects to a
garden when you go and you meet with a
new client I'm sure that you walk them
through a first couple steps so you can
figure out whether or not the garden is
is in an inappropriate target for
beneficial insects and to kind of think
through what the transition will even
look like will you walk all of us
through that so that people can consider
it for their own gardens sure and you
know most Gardens are a proponent or it
can be used with beneficial insects a
lot of it has to do with people's pest
issues and as we spoke about there
specific species that go after certain
pests but you know it seems like
companies that culture or their culture
beneficial insects they've been around
for thirty plus years you know it isn't
anything new again it's a matter of
Education I'm showing a customer what
can be used and it's not just what that
we run into but we also pride ourselves
on giving people the why you know what I
mean I don't want people to come to us
and be like tell me what to do give them
something to do and they don't take any
you know if they don't take any steps on
their own to make sure it's working
right but we want to provide them what
to do we want to provide them why to do
it and then we leave a lot of work on
them as well because because it's not
like what you said earlier it's not like
you said it and forget about it
you know sprays isn't that way either
there's a lot of monitoring that goes
into it so you know new walk into a
facility it's that you know obviously
introductions its pest concerns its you
know where do we start and what do we do
and my biggest thing with people is or
with companies is obviously you know we
want to start with your mother plants we
want to start with your veg we don't
want to we don't want to start at the
very end where you're having spider mite
problems that you know seven weeks in
the flower and you know what do I do at
this
and I kind of leave them on their own
for that to figure out but you know we
can be helpful as well it depends on
what state they're in and what they can
and can't use basically so walking into
a facility it's again just gathering
information its fact-finding to see what
their production is like see what their
protocol is see what they've been doing
in the past and you know why they're
coming to us to really formulate a plan
to be helpful to these people and you
know I talked about what sprays they've
used in the past there's some chemicals
that can be used that will actually
deter predatory mites from even coming
in helping so it's up for an information
it's when to use it how to use it
properly and where to begin
I generally try to talk people into
regardless of how big a company is you
know you obviously want to jump in right
away and take care of all their rooms
you know that they have problems with or
interested in but we actually try to
start with people in their mother rooms
and if they're sharing that with a vege
as well because if you start out clean
and your plant is healthy and you push
that into flour you know chances are
there shouldn't be too many issues going
into the last flowering stages there you
need to have somebody that is again
interested in doing this you want
somebody to take responsibility you want
people to scout and monitor and tell us
what they're seeing so that you know we
can make our comments on what they're
seeing and why that is basically it's
not always the what it's always the why
you know why they're seeing this
basically it's being informational to
people it's interesting because what
you're describing is a balance right
it's a you you want to continually
course-correct
as you go so that you can keep this this
balance where where the plants are
healthy and the beneficial insects are
able to do their job and and just keep
the population of the pests as low as
possible I'm assuming that it never goes
to zero it's about keeping them in
control know you touched on it and we
have different types of customers and we
have customers who want zero tolerance
and where I came from zero tolerance was
not feasible but I kind of disagree with
that if you pay enough and you use
enough species and predators a specific
amount of time you're not gonna have any
issues we have a lot of companies that
you know
rather than using the scouting and
monitoring technique they would rather
pay more upfront with us to have the
specific program in place where they
don't have to worry about it and that
concerns me because regardless of how
much you put in there could always be
something else that may come up you know
if you're using the species that's
specific for thrips you know maybe
you're getting spider mites or vice
versa
so it's real difficult I'm sorry it's
not difficult people just have different
ways of approaching pest management but
when you do have a small pest population
if I tell people I'm smiling right now
Shengo it's like it's a pest
it's called pest management for a reason
you know what I mean it's monitoring you
know populations of good versus the bad
and you know do I need to make a
decision and what product do I use is it
slow release a che or is it active
adults you know to help clean up my area
quickly so again that's where we come in
to be helpful as people sure that makes
a lot of sense and I and I've heard
people poopoo beneficial insects about
how they're not a hundred percent and my
thought is you know the people that I
know who spray enough to feel like
they're at a hundred percent they're
putting themselves at risk with other
plant problems because they're spraying
so much you know especially if they you
know if they're if they're spraying oils
and they're moving towards bloom you
know you use this example that I found
very interesting you said you know you
want to start with the mother so you get
them early because you don't want to end
up in week seven of bloom with with
spider mites and so what if you do find
yourself at week seven with spider mites
can beneficial insects be used for a
like an acute hot problem now in bloom
like like Edda at the end or is it is it
too late at that point for beneficial
insects to have helped and you you
really have to start early in your cycle
so one thing to comment on well is when
you say people poopoo you know
beneficial insects you know that's why I
got into it because my spray program
wasn't as effective as I thought it was
you know I mean so there's there's
there's two sides of the story obviously
you can spray and still have problems
you can use beneficial insects and still
have problems with it you know I just
want to comment on that off the bat
that's what transition to me on
beneficial use is because the spray
program I had put in place actually as I
got I just sprayed a couple days ago and
still have mites over here I'm like it
doesn't make sense so what's a better
way of dealing with things what's more
effective what's healthy you know to the
safety what's healthy and safety and
safe you know for employees that you
have is is looking for something out and
again it goes back to education on that
fast-forward to your next question on
you know what if you do find yourself in
bloom in week 7 your cropping out in 8
weeks you know it's difficult I'll be
forward with you it's difficult to take
care of a problem at that stage with
beneficial insects because you have a
very limited pool of what you can pull
to use that for a lot of the times the
predatory mites are they find it very
difficult to crawl across you know the
flower and the trichomes you know you if
you can imagine a tiny little insect
trying to climb across you know hairy
plants and then you and then you add the
stickiness of the flower into it it's an
unfriendly environment number one so
that comes before it gets to that stage
that's where the monitoring and scouting
comes in on you know if we have any
issues let's take care of it before it
really gets into this stage at that
point there's a couple products that we
do use that I call our fliers versus
predatory mites that are roaming around
the canopy of your plant that can be
helpful and again all honesty Shango I
tell people Mike you can use this
obviously there's no guarantees going
into it and it's going to cost you a lot
of money you know to clean up a
situation quickly because that you need
to understand that there's also a life
cycle of pests that you have and when
you introduce a beneficial insect or a
predatory bug I guess you would say it's
not like they sit there and eat all day
long until your pests are gone you know
they have a resting phase similar as we
do they need to rest then they need to
reproduce and be able to eat again I
mean so yeah I mean it is difficult at
that stage yes it can be done I tell
people you know physical removal might
be your best bet rather than buying
product from me why don't you use one of
your company employees you know you can
use a low powered vacuum cleaner you can
physically remove them with you know
paper cloth towels that are wet
basically and then people laugh at me
they're like you how many plants that we
have problems with and I said well you
know this could have been prevented
basically with different techniques
heading up to this item and yeah it does
so it sounds like so yeah if you have an
acute problem right before you harvest
yeah you can throw money and beneficials
at it
labor and do your best for it but really
you know you may want to just start with
your mother plants and and understand
that the the cycle you that you're in
right now may not be as successful as
you want but start on the next sex cycle
and and be forward-looking you know you
said something else that I found really
interesting you know one of the reasons
why some people push against beneficials
is is because the trichomes are so
sticky and they're so effective at at
gumming up and grabbing insects that
people say to me you know why would I
want to add more insects to my garden
because then my final product is going
to have more dead captured insects in
the trichomes so so when people when
people ask you about that what do you
say I try not to laughs number one well
know that you know and again and I hate
to keep preaching the same words but
education becomes first you know what I
mean that's a you know a lot of times
like I said it's an unfriendly
environment for them were we physically
we've watched these things because the
natural searching of a predatory might
in general you know if it's on your
plant or canopy is to go upwards
basically and I recall being in Portland
here one time and a guy called me as I
came and you know what we're doing is
not working and I want to make sure that
we're doing at the right stage and this
is when I started out four years ago in
cannabis and I remember walking over to
this place and and literally releasing
the species called per simulus excuse me
for two spots spider mite and instantly
I basically just watched it climb up the
stem and it gets to the flower and it
turns right back down and then it climbs
right back up and goes down up and down
up and down up and down and basically
it's gonna die of exhaustion a lot
quicker so when people are concerned
about species or predatory mites getting
stuck in their flower for the most part
they don't go there
I guess you would say because it because
it's difficult for them and it's really
hard for them to thrive and even move
anywhere in that stage if I can recall
in the last four years doing this of
pictures of people sending predatory
mites like pictures of their flower to
me and they're like hey man this is
stuck in it and you know what is it
number one because there were new
customers of mine and I'm like god that
looks like a predatory mite and I've
literally seen that picture one time I
guess you'd say in four years where it's
stuck on a flower
the only other
it wasn't a predatory mite it was
actually a money pirate bug and it's
called aureus and the aureus was stuck
directly in the flower my customer
pulled the aureus out and there was a
spider mite in ER that it was going
after basically got kind of stuck in
like a hole basically going after it the
flower and I mean other than that
there's I haven't received any responses
from people that what you gave me is not
working out because it's ending up in
our flower to ending up in our buds that
makes sense it may it kind of just
suggests it's a it's a growing myth
right that that yeah we've all seen you
know bugs usually flying bugs in the
trichomes but you're saying yeah that's
not the bugs that we're adding so just
because you've seen bugs caught in your
trichomes doesn't mean that these are
the same beneficial insects that you're
gonna use the defend your garden would
that be a good way to say it yeah that's
a good way to say it I mean things that
you see that are flying I mean the first
thing that comes to mind is fungus gnats
you know and people have an outbreak of
fungus gnats that's one of the bigger
problems rather than them spreading
disease through the routing system the
adults that you have are more of a
nuisance in traditional AG but in
cannabis they get stuck to the flower so
it's like it becomes a real pain in the
ass for people to deal with and work
around at that stage so you know a lot
of the times what we offer to people as
product as well we show them pictures of
them images this is this is what it is
because we don't want them to call us
two weeks down the road we like god I
got this I got this other pest basically
and they'll send us pictures are like no
these guys are on your side you know
this was this is what we talked about
two weeks ago these are your teammates
killer of it yeah nice to those guys so
you know again it's it we're trying to
formulate as a company be as helpful as
possible to people give them not as many
options as possible really limited
options on what we seem to be most
effective in certain situations you know
that was one of the most difficult
things for me when I started out
biocontrol is I felt like I learned a
lot on my own but I had to go through so
many resources a lot of people a lot of
time in order to formulate what I
thought was best for a situation
something could be different based off
experience you know that you run into or
other people so you know again our
company is focused on being helpful to
people offering them education on what
to do and and what
like this is what we found to be most
effective you can get information from
somebody else and it may be different
and that's great if it's helpful and
effective to you that's awesome
we appreciate it you know what I mean
but we just kind of speak from
experiences grow or feedback and
personal experiences through here yeah
right on that's one hell of a sales
cycle you know you you play this role of
evangelists and you know these are more
than customers they're actually you know
getting a partnership with these people
because it has to evolve over months and
there's a lot of education back and
forth yeah I totally get that so so
let's get down some some more
nitty-gritty so so once a grower has
decided that they want to make the
transition from spraying to using
beneficial insects break it down for me
what that looks like is it as simple as
you know day one comes and the spraying
is done and and that's the same day you
release the beneficials or is there a
clean up the plants period where the old
pesticides have to you know volatilize
and go away before you can add the
beneficials so what we start to do with
people is you know keeping or speaking
about what's already been spoken for us
you know sanitation plant health we talk
about those things but what we also talk
about and that's changed I feel in
cannabis and again this is this is my
thoughts on what's happening is and when
I came from traditional agriculture my
rates for beneficial insects were based
off per acre whether it was ten twenty
or thirty thousand predatory mites per
acre this is the species that we've used
this is for the reason on how they're
gonna help you basically when I started
recommended in cannabis it became
difficult because that wasn't working
very well for me and I had to make
changes at that point you know again
number one is not starting with your
flower plants it's starting from the
very beginning you know what that does
it eliminates a lot of cost with people
it gives them a chance to work with
things slowly and see it as it walks
through from you know mother plants to
their cuttings to veg before it gets
into flower it gives you three or four
weeks to kind of have that education and
balance and information on you know what
to use and how to use it when you talk
about pesticide use it's difficult to
nail down like specific you know do this
one two three basically but what we do
with people is we ask them again
you know what your procedures been like
in the past what's your pest concerns
basically what's your pest level at this
point you know and if they can't answer
some of these reasons you can only give
them a broad answer I guess you would
say does the whole does that whole grow
have to be sprayed down and clean
because I'm assuming that you know if
they're spraying residual there'll be
residual pesticides on surfaces and
those would injure the newly introduced
beneficial insects right I want to
encourage people to spray everything
down to clean things up I I personally
think that has been used differently by
each company you work with each person
that you may work with at this stage I
prefer to I prefer to have there be a
pest level of some stage so that there's
a food source for the predatory mites to
start working against depend on what
your pest is rather than spraying
something down to clean it up I mean yes
you can't approach it that way as well
but then you need to wait X amount of
days depend on the product that you use
because there are residuals that are
left over but again you know what's nice
is seen what states are allowing
cultivators to use at this stage because
a lot of it is oil-based which
dissipates quickly which doesn't leave a
whole lot of residues you know what I
used to do about eight years ago
starting to use it as I ran trials on
what I sprayed and then and then spray
my plants with water just for hydration
you know what I mean that helps helps
wash residuals off so maybe you can you
know take that from seven days down to
five days where we can apply the
beneficial insects specific products
it's kind of what it's all about Shango
because there are things that you can
spray a day before and then release
beneficial insects you know the next day
or two days later it may not be an
insecticide per se may be a bio
insecticide which are a lot of active
fungus is that people can use that do
not leave residuals that don't have any
you know re-entry hours after you spray
them or it's limited to like four hours
so it really depends on what they've
been doing prior you know and kind of
where their focus is on where they want
to go and if they really want to try
this thing you know if they really want
to walk the walk then you know we asked
very specific questions before we start
working with somebody the most difficult
thing is when people call in say hey can
you send me some predatory mites I'm
like yeah we can you know help me out
here so what happened about three years
ago
we started creating what I call a new
customer inquiry which people can fill
out online and that basically gives us
90% of the information that we need to
be helpful with you and to show you how
to walk from step one to step two to
step three you know if you're using if
you're using Avid or orthene or using
something like this residuals maybe
longer than if you're a man I just use
you know I just use a botanic garden my
product which is an active fungus you
know it's it's we could probably start
the very next day or two days later
United means so the new customer inquiry
really gives us information needed to be
helpful to people and when they can
start what they can use and kind of what
to expect moving forward in a program
yeah right on and you know as we've gone
on I know that it pains you to go back
again and again to the idea of the
education aspect and that's how primary
that is but but the more you talk the
more I get it that that each grow really
is its own environment and the what
they're spraying is a variable and and
there's just so many variables that is
not one solution fits for everybody and
and so really it's about getting in and
and and participating with them to
figure out what their problem you know
program is going to be and then and then
and then and doing the transition so so
I want to talk more about the the
transition and especially about
application rates but we need to take
our second break so we're gonna take
that break and rate be right back
you're listening to shaping fire and my
guest today is Shane Young founder of
natural enemies biocontrol
as cannabis normalization sweeps the
country knowledge of how to grow
cannabis naturally and without synthetic
inputs has become more and more
available in fact probiotic growers are
experiencing large yields and
exceptional terpene profiles without
using chemicals banned in their state
move away from the risks inherent to
chemical nutrients and instead invest in
your soil use your soil again and again
reducing costs and improving the
vitality of your soil with each cycle
keep it simple organics has been a
leader in aerated compost teas for years
and now provide premium soils and
nutrients to the cannabis industry they
offer a full
all natural inputs for building your
soil feeding microbe communities and
brewing nutrient and compost teas they
can even help you test your soil to spot
deficiencies that may be holding you
back check out their website at K is
organics calm enter the word Shango into
the form at checkout to receive 10% off
your first order stop pouring bottled
nutrients on your soil only to throw it
out each cycle start building living
soil that will serve you for years to
come visit K is organics calm and grow
healthy thriving cannabis now that the
health benefits of terpenes have become
well known in the cannabis industry
people everywhere are looking for the
purest terpenes without adulterants the
problem with most terpene providers is
that they're not sourced naturally and
instead are made as a byproduct of
refining petroleum and that's so sketchy
the terpenes sold by true terpenes are
entirely different they are certified
organic non-gmo and food grade that
means they are extracted from real plant
sources there are no solvents of any
kind used during the extraction process
they are distilled only with steam
that's right only steam in fact terpenes
from true terpenes are so pure that you
can eat them not only that but you can
stack them with better results - what I
mean is
other companies terpenes have got a few
percent of impurities and when you stack
those terpenes to make a blend you're
adding a variety of impurities that
degrade your final product true terpenes
also has strain-specific terpenes for a
wide range of cannabis strains like
Durbin poison sunset sherbet and
granddaddy purple true terpenes has
robust and supportive customer service
so your questions will get answered fast
and efficiently if you shop for turps
before you know how rare that is so
whether you want to cup your hands to
smell some betta carry off lean to calm
down after getting too high or if you
want to dab some alpha pining so your
lungs feel fabulous and your mind feels
liberated true terpenes will provide you
with a truly natural experience if you
are a cannabis product developer these
are the trips you want to add your oil
or edible or a capsule or whatever true
terpenes are simply
best your money can buy don't try and
make a premium product with substandard
terms choose true terpenes for a
top-shelf experience go to shaping
feiyr.com forward slash true tour peens
to find out more or click on the link in
this week's newsletter welcome back you
are listening to shaping fire I'm your
host Shango Lowe's and our guest this
week is Shane young founder of natural
enemies biocontrol
so in this last section I want to talk
about what it's actually like to do the
application process how do you go about
applying the beneficial insects to the
plants that's a great question because
the problem that people or growers have
been seeing is that you know information
on the packaging on the leader
containers or whatever you're using for
application you know some of them say
spread these all over your flower and
that's you know that that's not what you
want to do in cannabis at this stage
because you're gonna be spending a lot
of time trying to clean that up if you
can eventually clean it all up basically
so that's very difficult for people to
do it so again it comes with you know an
initial conversation possibly people
reaching out on how do I apply this but
for the most part we try to write it out
for people we try to make things simple
on you know obviously the label is going
to say this I'm sorry to say you're not
gonna follow that you can't do that
that's not the way of doing it so it's
difficult it could come up in
conversation it can come up by email
whatever it may be can you give an
example can you get real specific there
Shane what kind of application example
would you see on the labels that that
that you would educate somebody through
like I try to make sure that the
listeners have got you know real
actionable results so give us an example
of why cannabis is different from the
other crops that that they're beneficial
insect may be labeled for sure no just
when I touched on again one of the label
says to spread the product over your
flower and it could be my first thought
right now is that specifically for a
thrips predator whether using Swirsky or
cuca marisa of species for it you know
because they want to say to spread it
across the flower because that's
generally where the thrips are going to
congregate basically so one thing that
you could do is i
feel it's an old method of control but
still an effective method is you can use
it to apply to the base or the stock of
your plant basically you can create
piles towards the stem where they'll
crawl up and your plant that way a
secondary way that you can do it is is
what we call in the office we call them
hanging baskets and what's funny is I
used to I used to try to figure out a
more effective way of application for
product as well a long time ago so I
actually used to buy like Dixie Cups or
Solo cups and I would poke holes in them
and use like not wire hangers but like
ornament hangers to hang out of my
plants and I would dump product into
these cups and then I would hang them on
the plant because the active adults are
gonna crawl up the plant up the cup into
your plant basically and then just years
ago biocontrol companies started
creating what they call hanging baskets
where they're already pre-made for you
to do an application for so what's
difficult is when somebody's like yeah I
follow the directions and this is what
happened
sometimes you can't give that
information out you know on the on the
application so we actually try to
provide like an application sheet for
specific species when we work with
people as well so that you know when
they're choosing to do something again
we want them to be effective so we want
to give them the most information to be
effective which is how to do the
application at that stage so that that's
really what comes to mind of mice on my
site when Yasir
does the choice between using say for
example a hanging basket or a sachet do
those different application techniques
depend on the the type of beneficial
that you're adding or the size of the
garden or just simply the preference of
the grower it actually touches on a lot
of different things preference of the
grower yes there's a couple different
ways of doing an application you know
there's one thing called the slow
release sachet which is an actual
breeding bag is what I call it that
slowly release predatory mites into the
canopy of your plant and when I stress
to people as these are truly used as a
preventative maintenance unit I mean
because if you have a problem you want
to use active adults if you have a
problem if you have a pest issue you
don't want to use slow-release ashes on
that plant yes it will be helpful in the
long run so you can do the sachets and
the adults in the same application
basically that gives you more immediate
control and then it gives you
long-lasting control of the sachet that
you've already
applied to it different species are
available in different different forms
of application for the most part that
come in slow-release ashes they come in
active adults which at which I call you
know the bulk leader containers or five
liter bags can be used for commercial
growers that use more product
you know there's Flyers that can just be
released that fly you know that can kind
of encompass your growing space on their
own where you don't have to apply them
to every single plant or every third
plant by any means so it just depends on
the predator that you use I know that a
lot of the the breeders of these
beneficial insects they sell them with
application rates that were devised for
ornamental plants and cannabis is a very
unique lady what we know what have you
seen as far as a you know any difference
in application rates for cannabis versus
you know boring industry standard plants
yeah it's a it's a great question and
it's I don't say unfortunate that I
can't change my information online
because I get that information direct
from the suppliers who actually culture
the product you know and I mean but when
you touch on it when I started
recommending in cannabis agricultural
rates I would calculate out by square
footage you know what I mean it's kind
of what I used to do per acre basically
calculated out in square footage what
can be used and I just remember selling
my first liter of soil mites for fungus
net control and God the guy I don't know
how many plants and is you know a
thousand square front room and I'm like
yeah you know what one liter of soil
mites per 1000 square feet you know
that's the rate of use for the last
eight years
doctor [ __ ] out of your fungus gnats and
again you know two weeks later he's like
no it's not working and that's when I
got into well why isn't it working you
know what I mean and the amount of water
that's being applied to the plant cuz
not not just for the hell of it you know
it's because it demands it so much it
grows like a weed it it needs that water
and basically for for growth at that
stage so just starting from that small
arena of more soil mites more often we
had to get some in every single pot so I
ran trials for I don't know if it was
four months or so you know offering
product splitting product with people
who were interested in using it on kind
of formulated
plan for them moving forward on how to
be effective using this product and is
it going to be cost effective on our end
you know but when you talk about cost
effectiveness you take out labor of
sprained you take out the health of the
plant basically you take out any chance
of getting knocked for a pesticide test
all these different things so I guess
looking over it and talking to the guys
in the office here that we deal with
there's a very few growers that we have
that use traditional AG rates and are
very effective with it there's very few
and far between so for the most part you
can times the rates by five just to give
you a generalization but it also depends
on what you're doing on the back end you
know you made the comment about hit it
you know or apply it and leave it you
know earlier on in the conversation and
you know you can't do that with anything
you can't do that if you have a spray
program because you still need to
monitor there still may be a pest issue
or a pest present at that stage where if
you don't take care of it right away
it's going to you know quickly become
larger and larger as you move on so you
know I hope that it kind of it kind of
helps answer the question that you were
looking for yeah yeah it does so do you
find that based on bioregions for
example where where the plants are being
grown in the u.s. that you either need
to choose different beneficial insects
or the application rate changes because
I assume that if you're doing
applications you know in in the cold
northwest it's gonna be a lot different
in the hella hot Arizona yeah no a great
question and a lot of it has to do with
one you know choosing the correct
species for the pests that you're after
you know number two it does have to do
with the heat and also the humidity of a
region where you're at you know a lot of
times lower humidities are gonna dry out
the eggs of the predatory mites which
causes problems or which delays
reproduction basically it takes longer
to do that so you know I've been
approached by a lot of people who you
know they're running ten fifteen percent
humidity throughout the summer and my
comment is no these these are not
documented to do that we may need to do
again applications more often to be
effective we may switch it up rather
than using these sachets which are
probably going to release slowly in your
crop and not a little bit quickly more
quickly at a place that has 50 percent
humidity or 60 you know what I mean
which is fairly ideal for Reaper
action and I just go into again I'll
honestly I'm like hey man this was three
years ago at a guy that's like hey your
session is lasted five five weeks we had
12 percent humidity for three months I'm
like I don't understand how that was
possible but showing them how to open
the packages up looking to see if
there's reproduction finding them on
their plants and what they're doing I'm
like you know so it's nice to be able to
push the boundaries of what they're
documented to do specifically and tell
people it's not documented for it
generally we don't recommend to do it
but this is what I would probably choose
in your specific area it's built a
little bit better for the lower
humidities it's able to reproduce a
little bit quicker than another species
that we have you know and we kind of go
from there and that's where the feedback
comes in Shango that's where we can't
just give somebody a program they walk
away and use it and never hear from them
again because there's always feedback
that we can use from everybody that we
can help other growers with on if this
didn't work well you know we had another
guy that did this you know what I mean
and it was very successful for them but
a lot of it has to do with you know
again from the very beginning is you
know sanitation plant health monitoring
scouting being able to know what pests
are what so pest identification is key
that we're using the correct species
from the very beginning you know we're
not going to be very successful so right
I like it that can beneficial insects be
used in outdoor crops yeah we use it
many times yeah all last year all last
year
indoors is great outdoors yes for sure
there's no problems using it do they do
that do the beneficial insects walk away
from the cannabis plants I mean I always
figured that released with an indoor
program they were you know they were
penned they were captured inside of the
greenhouse or the building or whatever
but if you go outdoors you know they
could just walk away yeah so it depends
on what you're using obviously you know
there's Flyers that make me nervous on
if you release them they're just gonna
fly away but you can also create
attractant plants to keep them near
basically that gives them an additional
food source if they don't find it on the
plants at your art that you have as you
talked about them walking away it
becomes like an application technique as
well you know if you're applying them
directly onto your plant there's so much
canopy space that these guys need to
move you know how small they are you
know in order to walk around a plant
it's going to take them quite a while to
do so for the most part they're not
going to crawl down your stem and out in
the dirt and go somewhere else in our
experience they generally stay on your
plant they're looking for food you know
they're predators versus the pests that
you guys have there you know a lot of
the times they're slow because all
they're doing is sitting there feeding
on your planet you already mean
versus versus what we offer people
they're looking for food generally
they're gonna be a little bit faster
basically and they need to find food in
order to maintain right on do you have
to use higher application rates outdoors
yeah again it you know it's a general
question but depends on the region that
you're in depends on the humidity that
you are but again it depends on a plant
counts as well and what the sizes of
your canopy are we find it you know a
six by six plants treated differently
than it one by one plant there's a lot
more canopy space that needs to be
covered so yes I would say so yeah one
of the things that I find interesting is
that you know the these beneficial
insects and and how they do what they do
it's not it's not new it is something
that the horticulture industry has been
using for decades and what you are
bringing to the table is being the you
know being the first person in the
industry to start transitioning and in
learning the ins and the outs of
applying what's been used in
horticulture for decades to specifically
what's going on in cannabis so as a
corollary to that I have this question
are there new any new beneficial insects
that you see coming online in the future
is like is there like you know the the
new one the new model or is that not
does that not really happen much in the
beneficial insects scene where you've
got your you've got your set of specific
and generalized beneficials and all of
the novel 'no sand innovation is
happening on application and education
no it's a good question and for the most
part as far as I know and it could be
false but I don't think it is a lot of
things that are cultured and supplied in
the United States that they have to be
native to our specific area in order for
us to offer them to other people so I
think pretty much what here what is here
now is what's gonna be around for a
while there are companies that offer
different species or additional species
to do different things basically and
each
company has their own you know they have
their own choices of what they want a
culture on their own but you know when
you start working with us again I think
like I said in our previous conversation
is that we try to take a lot of that
information out for people and just give
you what we feel is the most effective
and which limits you know to make keep
it simple I guess you'd say with a lot
of people is we try to simplify our
responses towards people but III I think
what it is is it needs to be native in
order for it to be sold and supplied
here in the United States yeah right on
so um you know right here before we wrap
up I want to give you you know a
platform to talk specifically to the
commercial you know master growers who
are listening and are interested in
moving away from the synthetics or the
sprays and in any way and move over but
they still have got concerns about you
know how much risk there will be during
the transition and also would they you
know decrease and yields so so you know
why you just address that on our way out
here what do you say to the commercial
grower who wants to go in this direction
but they just they need it put in the
right terms for them it's a great
question and I think you know throughout
our conversation today I've touched on a
lot of points for for people to feel a
little bit more comfortable using this
as you know you touched on it about even
how beneficial insects have been
cultured for decades you know what I
mean when I started doing using them 10
years ago you know I remember going to a
class there was three people in the
class then the next year there was 10
and then there was 15 then there's a
hundred then there was only standing
room as the years go on and people
become educated on what you can use them
for I think that's really going to steer
a lot of people in the right direction
a lot of the pesticide testing is going
to steer people to use beneficial
insects first and if they need to use
chemicals by any means they've you know
they in order to make them a little bit
more comfortable they might reach for
that as well but I think what you're
gonna see is higher flower content on
the back end you know you're not going
to be spraying your plants with anything
which is gonna which is going to cause
no stress which allows them to go to
their natural capacity I mean that's
what I saw when I ran trials ten years
ago is 30% growth increase
some plants that I just used beneficial
insects for you know aphids spider mites
fungus gnats versus a traditional
program of horticultural oils that I use
on a different plant basically 30 30
percent increase it's amazing to see and
once you see start believing and then
you start and then you start seeking
more information on God how can I do
this even better we get a lot of reports
from a lot of different people telling
us about how healthy their plants are
these days and how much more flour
they're receiving and you know it's it's
not everybody but there are people that
have really taken the time to do that
and to seek the information to be
effective for it and I don't want to
push anybody to do it if they don't want
to again you know our website says
choose beneficial insects if you're
interested we're more than happy to help
and to give you the specific information
that you need and to help you you know
from day one moving forward because
obviously we want to work with you five
years down the road we we don't want to
just talk with you one day give you
product it doesn't work and you be done
with it even if somebody doesn't order a
product for awhile we still call and
follow-up to see how things are going
what happened what can we do different
you know I mean so there is it can be
time-consuming for some people to try to
learn how to do this but if you have
somebody at your company that's willing
to grasp this and really go into and
seek information and do it then that's
gonna be your best bet at this stage
right on well Shane thank you so much
for being an educator about this you
know the show you know the shaping fire
show we are very clearly you know
probiotic living soil working with
nature and not down with synthetic
inputs and we don't take you know
synthetic input advertising money and so
it's very refreshing for me to talk
about a topic where we can we can get
garden pests under control by working
with nature instead of trying to
dominate nature you know I agree and I
appreciate you reaching out Shango it's
nice talking with you
right on thanks for being on the show
Shane I really appreciate your time take
care ma'am see ya
if you'd like to find out more about
Shane young beneficial insects and
natural enemies you can visit their
website at natural enemies biocontrol
com so natural enemies really only
serves the commercial industry but their
website is still fantastic place to get
educated
natural enemies biocontrol calm and if
you'd like to hear more from Shane young
you can check out my youtube channel at
forward slash Shango Lowe's to check out
Shane Jones speaking on Vashon Island
you can find more episodes of the
shaping fire podcast and subscribe to
the show at shaping fire calm and on
Apple iTunes stitcher and Google Play if
you enjoyed the show we'd really
appreciate it if you'd leave a positive
review of the podcast wherever you
download your review will help others
find the show so they can enjoy it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the weekly newsletter for
insights into the latest cannabis news
and product reviews on the shaping fire
website you will also find transcripts
of today's podcast as well for
information on me and where I'll be
speaking you can check out Shango lows
calm your company want to reach our
national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hotspot at shaping
fire calm to find out how thanks for
listening to shape and fire i've been
your host Shango lows
[Music]