[Music]
weed used to be just a local thing it
was essentially your pot dealer and your
friends you smoked it with but now that
the US has taken its boot off everyone's
neck regarding prohibition weed and pot
has become cannabis and is now a global
business phenomenon countries are
trading back and forth and the ancillary
businesses to cannabis are stretching
out to become Global businesses this
Brave new world has many of us flying
around the world to make these
connections and spread cannabis
friendship everywhere we can fly to and
as we extend a friendly hand to cannabis
enthusiasts around the world we get to
learn their traditions and cultures
around this most amazing plant if you
want to learn about cannabis Health
business and technique efficiently and
with good cheer I encourage you to
subscribe to our newsletter we'll send
you new podcast episodes as they come
out delivered right to your inbox along
with commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week and
videos too don't rely on social media to
let you know when a new episode is
published sign up for the updates to
make sure you don't miss an episode also
we're giving away very cool prizes to
folks who are signed up to receive the
newsletter this month we're giving away
prize packs from Mammoth microbes
including retail sized bottles of
Mammoth P micro inoculant and a bunch of
Swag to go along with it there's nothing
else you need to do to win except
receive the newsletter so go to shaping
fire.com to sign up and be entered into
this month's and all few future
newsletter prize
drawings you are listening to shaping
fire and I'm your host Shango Los today
my guest is Colin Bell co-founder of
Mammoth microbes and he was kind enough
to bring this month's prize packs with
him Colin isn't here to talk about their
products though he's here to talk about
the cultural experiences he has had and
the kind folks he has met during the
last two years traveling to nearly every
continent to set up Mammoth microbe as a
global business I'm the show today we're
going to talk about the different
approaches to growing cannabis in
different countries what it's like
trying to evangelize cannabis in
countries that still have prohibition
and how no matter where you go in the
world cannabis people become fast
friends even if you don't speak the same
language welcome to the show Colin
Shango it's great to be here how are you
doing my friend uh doing fantastic so
glad that uh you would be able to spend
some time with us I know that you are a
busy cat and uh watching your Instagram
over the last like 18 months you seem to
you seem to be like traveling everywhere
so I'm glad I caught you in your office
for once so that we could have this
conversation and you know let's let's
start right off at the top about like
the different areas of the globe that
you have been to you know make new
cannabis friends in the in the last year
and a half uh I know from watching your
your Instagram that um you were you were
really interested in how different
regions of the globe um had different
uh I guess we call them Legacy growing
uh Styles and it was different from
place to place um could you go ahead and
and tell us a little bit about that
about how how the growing is done
differently in different parts yeah
absolutely for sure and I want to start
by saying I have an awesome job we have
an awesome company and being the
co-founder allows me to get a great team
on the ground and then go engage with
the Cannabis community on a global scale
not only to outreach the business but to
develop our our Global Network you know
one of our cultures and and and core
competencies uh and core values is
developing community and we want to do
that around the world within this
industry and that's what I'm getting to
do so it's fascinating and saying that
you know we started our Global footprint
uh campaign to get microbes uh used
across the world in this cannabis
industry just a short year ago and we
have been successful in traveling
through UK and many different places in
Europe and Israel and Australia and
countries through South
America and done the education and
support and brought product our product
to these countries and and and gotten
great adoption so it's been quite the
journey and quite the education I have
such a different perspective on the
world as I engage people in the world in
these different countries in these
different cultures within our camp
cannabis community and the growing
Styles as you mentioned are vastly
different from these different areas
I'll give the example of our neighbors
in South America as an example there's
some economic constraints to the
products and the technologies that are
available in some of those countries and
just the styles of growing and the
culture of using nature and using soil
and being organic and organically
oriented I will say has really shaped
the way these Growers grow cannabis in
South America and Uruguay and Columbia
are excellent examples where there
aren't as many inputs used and there's
more natural additives that are being
used and I actually have one of my
partners as an example in Uruguay urugo
Juan what's up my man he did a study
that just blew my mind and this is our
partner our distribution partner in one
of the great strores ugro in mono
Uruguay he did a controlled side by side
using completely organic natural
substrates in the same room as a
hydroponic system same strain same
climate same light same everything half
the room was hydroponic mineral half the
room was organic completely and the same
strain of plants looked completely
different they tasted completely
different and the mindset through much
of the much of South America and the
world for that matter now has focused
not only on yield but but maximizing and
enhancing the quality of this plant
meaning the smell and the
flavors uh that this plant can give off
there it's Tarpin and flavonoids so how
I like to characterize some of those
environments is organic and outdoory or
merging Organics into the indoor grows
much more so than in Europe and the UK
where it's heavy mineral heavy Ure to uh
focusing especially in the UK on
Strictly deep water culture Hydroponics
where Organics are not used and they're
just now the concept of Organics is just
now starting to emerge because of the
acknowledgement of enhanced plant
quality when using Organics and that
goes for the microbes also and so in
South America we can say very open to
Organics
nature type inputs in Europe in UK and
and even somewhat in Australia where we
do a lot of business the use of microbes
is somewhat
new and it's a process an education
process and that's what I engage in
let's let grow Growers understand how we
can Bridge natural processes into these
conventional mineral uh growing
practices and still enhance not only
yields but maximize your plants
phenotypic potential so they can get the
quality that the plant is actually bred
for I I think it's really interesting
that that uh South America would have um
uh such an organic base and and is kind
of provides proof of that you can do um
Quality organic plantings without a lot
of expensive inputs simply by using uh
you know compost teas and local
amendments because you know th those the
people there have not traditionally had
the economic wherewithal to be able to
afford the expensive Western fertilizers
and then you compare that to the UK
which obviously is is very affluent and
so moved towards Hydroponics and all
these you know mineral-based um bottled
nutrients because it it was the thing
right it was the thing that affluent
farmers were using but now you know
people we're kind of having a uh you
know a reconsideration of bottled
nutrients as a as a cannabis community
and and and so the you know folks
throughout Europe are starting to look
more towards you know what what people
will often describe as simpler organic
but anybody who's ever studied knf knows
that it can get complex really fast I
think that's interesting how the level
of affluence directly uh impacts the
style of growing I think that's a really
good way to characterize it and it's
absolutely true and it's intuitive if
it's been told to you but it was kind of
a surprise as I was I was engaging in
these different areas and these cannabis
Growers and just learning how they're
growing and and the focus on that too
Shango I'll tell you um and the UK is a
great example I'll call it the Quest for
Quality as ear even a year ago you know
the idea was Growers are basically focus
on yield because in the darker uh
colored markets so to speak the black
markets the gray markets I'm not sure if
I love the term Black Market I don't
know why it's a pretty common term but
where the regulatory pressure
is is more less
developed or what's there's not
regulation and people are kind of
working underneath some of the
legalities to get this plant in the
hands of
consumers the plant typically has a
higher value because there's that extra
level of risk and people really focus on
yield in those particular markets and
historically that's just been absolutely
true throw everything at the plant that
you possibly can to get the yield oh so
like lots of pgrs and stuff oh my
goodness
yeah and that's just recently started to
turn around where it was fascinating
this is a good example too when I was at
spannabis last year and I'd already
engaged with a lot of growers in the UK
by then for the first quarter of the
year in 2018 and we're talking about
March 2018 when our team was in Spain
and I was there also a lot of UK Growers
go there also and many came to me at our
booth and they show me these flowers and
they were very concerned because they're
super dance super Rock hard
and they would ask man do you think this
has pgrs in it didn't have any flavor
the smell was off and the concern was
that it's unhealthy and it definitely
wasn't appealing to smoke you know the
the harsh I don't know if you've ever
experienc that where you kind of get the
harsh throat uh yeah unfortunately I
have I do know what you're talking about
yeah I think everyone's experienced that
at least once and the consumers want to
get away from that it's not it's not a
good experience
and this quest for quality not only in
terms of uh better growing practices but
in the genetics has just skyrocketed in
that market and in other markets through
Europe because of the influence of the
US to a large degree um over the last 12
and 24 months and so
now everyone obviously still wants to
maximize the yield in their crop but
everyone also really needs to maximize
the quality to distinguish themselves
and and I see that through that quest
for Quality through Amsterdam through
Spain through UK through
Australia what I think is fascinating
also is different areas uh have some
kind of endemic I'll say genetic that
seems to persist through all the
different strains Amnesia Hayes is a
perfect example when you engage with
with the shops in in Amsterdam and
Amsterdam was basically the
Cornerstone of the Cannabis industry for
a long time in Europe it was very well
known it was the center of genetics it
was a center of activity and it's gotten
a lot of criticism recently because the
diversity is not there and that's not my
words it's just the data that I've been
that have I've gathered uh from hearing
a lot of people talk about what they can
get and the genetics um are kind of
constrained and more so through UK and
Amsterdam and Spain and everywhere else
the focus on Colorado and even more so
California
genetics is dominates every conversation
and it dominates the pricing of flower
also so in many cases through those
different regions if you have California
genetics you can get double the price of
your flow that you can from like
genetics that were just inherent from
those regions wow that's really
interesting so so wow so many so many
things to talk about so all right so the
first thing I want to hit on is that
it's interesting because you know
Barney's Farm genetics and such are
still remain popular here in the US uh
because they're less common and so those
can sometimes get a a premium price for
European genetics um but you're also
saying that the that the opposite is
also true that our our you know we've
got such talented breeders here in the
United States that people who have have
um stabilized those strains and then
they find their way to Europe that's
getting the premium and the another
thing I want to hit on that is you know
you said oh you know a lot of this uh uh
let's say demand for bag appeal and
tarpine profile instead of just raw
weight raw yield is because of American
influence I bet you that to a large
degree it's because of Instagram too
right because we've all like you know
since we were all kids we've all been
influenced by High Times magazines and
the centerfolds and stuff but clearly
High Times magazine does not have the
level of influence compared to you know
Instagram breeders as a whole did you
find that a lot of people were coming up
to you with questions or wanted to show
you things and everybody was going to
Instagram profiles back and forth yes
and it's a pretty new thing you know
because of the state of the regulat
environment in these different countries
people are very lowkey in Holland you
know that's changed just recently uh in
the UK people have been lowkey forever
and not very many people until this last
12 to you know within the last two years
have really started to even engage in
Instagram but since then it's just the
platform that everyone goes to to
educate themselves on the different
breeders the different strains that are
available there's actually a lot of
exchange that occurs on there um this is
kind of a a side note but you know
there's a lot of people that are
advertising their flowers on on that
platform no doubt about it yeah actually
watching uh us Instagram uh uh Heritage
or black market sellers is hysterical
because some people are not even they're
not even trying to be subtle about it um
and it's kind of a it's it's kind of a
fun Pastime to watch those so uh earlier
on you mentioned that you know a lot of
the the technology and uh fertilizers
were not available um in South America
and so they were doing it you know down
home organic style the way they've grown
their other food just because they can't
afford the fancy mineral stuff which you
know we're kind of turning away from
anyway but I bet you that also goes in
almost all the countries that you talked
about for analytics right um uh so these
people are kind of of like like the
United States was 5 years ago before we
had cannabis Labs all over the place and
so these people are kind of breeding and
growing and and purchasing blind because
nobody can really tell uh you know
potency and pesticides and pgrs all
these things that that we commonly test
for now um those those just don't exist
everywhere yet yep it's non-existent
it's not required and so there's no cost
that's being there's no investment
that's being put into those verticals
that's absolutely right and it's pretty
fascinating to think about how much
we've evolved and you know we talk about
you know the genetics coming from the US
or why do we know about that because we
can actually collect the data we have
the freedom to operate to do proper
breeding to do proper testing and to
answer those questions with high
confidence uh to for for further uh
selection of breeding Generations
and how do you know what you're breeding
if you can't test it I don't have the
answer to that I don't think you do know
no and so it's
really not been well informed except for
you know the visuals and you can
actually uh try product afterwards and
see how those plants are responding and
how well you like them but the the level
of confidence for breeding and actually
creating gen genetics has gone way down
and and European genetics has has been a
Powerhouse and it just amazed me two
years ago when I was introduced uh to
the European genetics world I was blown
away and you know you can buy three
seeds for what $40 I was like what is
going on here talk about the redefining
uh what a money tree looks like just
from a genetics perspective but that has
quickly uh evolved in the US also and so
as Industries evolved one of the
questions I get yet because you know
coming from Colorado and being in the US
and then engaging in all these markets
where legalization is happening and it's
happening pretty quickly but a US is is
leading so I'm like the guy that's
supposed to have this crystal ball that
says you know what does this look like
for us two or three or four years or
what does this look like for us after
legalization happens and and actually I
I can be a resource for uh these folks
in different countries to answer those
questions because there's a pretty high
confidence that we know what it looks
like
as growing becomes legal as uh flour and
other THC consumable products become
regulated the economics and supply and
demand play into effect and it can
affect the whole value chain and so it's
really fun to kind of shed some light uh
and that's another thing that I do often
that's one of the biggest questions I
get what does this look like when when
when our country becomes legal and so
one of those questions also and one of
those details is well when regulation
happens so does the testing and so it's
coming across the board so um you know
when when uh cannabis enthusiasts come
to events um if there's somebody there
that they're all excited to see you know
like a like a major breeder like a mean
Jean or or a celebrity like a Tommy
Chong or a Snoop Dog or something you
know cannabis enthusiasts who are
growing at home they'll bring like you
know you know a bag or something of
their best stuff to give to their hero
right and and and um I would think that
for you being a uh you know a cannabis
research scientist and an American which
is you know ex kind of exotic in some of
these places and and you're going to
these events some of these people are
are bringing you those bags right
they're they want to show you what they
grew and got your feedback like what is
the range of stuff that that you saw I
mean would were you seeing great stuff
and then like you know crappy pgr Laden
stuff or or uh just just just give us a
snapshot of the kind of stuff that
people are showing you and and actually
probably giving you
too yeah so I love my job I'm just gonna
say and one of the reasons I love my job
is because everywhere I go and this is
kind of a layered question people love
to share and to show uh the Wares of
their of their productivity and so I do
get gifted a lot of flow across the
world no matter where I mean forget
about the states in the UK through Spain
Australia uh Latin America and it's very
different what I will say is that a
little biased because now we've been a
company for about three years and
Mammoth uh our our our technology
Mammoth is used in a lot of places and
people are giving me Mammoth grown you
know and so it's it's it's like it's
like hey I used your product to grow
this and so there's a little bit of a
bias it seems like I'm getting mammoth
own uh product everywhere and and you
know I've probably told you this story
before I can't go anywhere for a week
much less two weeks without having a
huge like a lunch pail full of different
Bud from from different Growers at the
at the hydro shops and or the grows that
I'm working with and engaging with and
so it's a it's a fun exercise and
regionally it's just completely across
the board different there's a lot of
chronic and chronic inbred strains uh
through Spain because inherently that
strain
um is grown in that area the Amnesia hay
stuff is you can taste it in almost
everything growing through the Holland
area there's some different strains that
are just um very very well known the
cheeses is an example of the UK and
they're starting to get away from that
there's some other strains that are just
kind of inherent uh for the Australia
Market I've seen probably
more
organic and probably less potent uh
strains the further south we move in the
Americas towards uh South America
through Columbia as an example where
there'll be some expert Growers and PR
an example they had their first Cannabis
Cup and as an an an Emerging Market
there hasn't been the education and
education is key to maximize
the grower knowledge and
capabilities to grow high quality
strains and so in Peru there's a lot of
room for Growers to improve and there's
a lot of room to also get better
genetics in there Columbia is another
example where there's not going to be as
high quality
generally uh of flour in Columbia as
there would be in Colorado or California
I'll say to preface it I had my South
American team come up for our holiday
party in sales training in December and
we just toured through South America
just before that November and the first
part of December and I took them to some
dispensers into uh a cultivation
facility a a commercial cultivation
facility in Denver and a dispenser here
in Fort Collins Colorado and it was the
best flower they'd ever seen and the
best flour they had ever smoked and
they've been engaged in the industry
their whole lives and the range of Ages
was from 25 to 35 years old a bunch of
young men yeah and most of the time
they've engaged in the in the in the
South American markets and so so so two
more things I want to hit on before we
uh break for our first commercial um I
want to I want to give you a uh uh an
opportunity to tell the bridal story
which I'm sure that you you're getting
and then and then after that would you
go into the the we haven't hit on Asia
yet and you've got some interesting
stuff to say about Asian growing co-ops
yeah yeah so for sure so I guess I'm I'm
honored to be again able to engage uh
professionally in what I do which is
just engage with Growers trying to bring
them value and what I get everywhere I
go it's a lot of hugs and I love that
too uh and and one of the shows we were
at in Columbia in Med Jean a young man
and having you know talking to him
someone on Instagram Etc and he had some
product and he was a grower and he was
using Mammoth and and it was a really uh
Charming story where he told me he felt
like our product after he started using
it he felt like his plants uh were
getting married because they got so
Frosty that was like they were putting
on a nice white wedding gown uh so just
it goes to show to the increased quality
that he was experiencing with the same
strength he's been grown for a long time
just by incorporating our microbial
Technologies to enhance uh nutrient
uptake and even that example right that
that's such a culturally relevant
example that's not that's that's
probably not something that you'd get
from an American right that if you know
in in in you know South America where I
don't know the whole kind of wedding
culture is more integrated I don't know
differently than here um I think that is
a it's it's very poet
it was very poetic it moved me and uh I
I like to tell that story it's just a
really cool thing and and the thing is
as you know too everyone is so
passionate in this industry and if you
can help someone especially in this
industry you've just made a friend for
life and all we do is try to create
value and and provide solutions for
cabis Growers that's 100% of our focus
and I love being able to do that and in
doing so you know we're just we're just
creating friends all over the world we
love it so let's finish up first Set uh
break us down a little bit about uh
Asian growing Co growing co-ops and
recipes yeah so this is something that
was new too and as you can imagine I was
first really exposed to this in the UK
and as I move to Europe and Australia in
particular it's apparent that there's
different uh cultural groups that move
into areas uh to dominate the black
market there's uh as Asian groups
there's Russian groups there's Armenian
groups there's polish groups and
depending on who has this stronghold
it's kind of a an organized situation uh
they take chunks of the market to
control it and there's uh Asian
Vietnamese groups that have done this
for years and have been very successful
and they've developed and what I
understand is there's main families that
kind of
control the the global Asian growing
throughout the world world where they
have families in Canada and in UK and in
Australia and it's a very interesting
and a very hard nut to crack to actually
get them to adopt because there's many
many different grows that one family
might control and there's one recipe
that they all have to follow and so
there's a language barrier they go to a
certain amount of stores where there's a
language barrier they only deal with
their own kind and for me to try and get
in and learn more about this growing
it's been pretty intensive but what
happens is they follow the same recipe
they don't ask questions and in order to
get on that list has been quite the
challenge and so these main families
especially in Australia have
acknowledged uh our efforts in trying to
allow uh to bring these Technologies our
technology to get better yield and
better quality which is typically known
as especially in Australia they call it
the brown which is like hit with every
pgr known to mankind it's what the T
it's what the tourists buy and you know
all the locals are like don't get the
brown don't get the brown mate and and
the some of these Asian groups have
picked up Mammoth because it allows them
to get away from that stigma of the
brown and to improve the quality of
their grows and so just the just the
structure of how different groups are
growing and where they're organized and
located has been quite the education I
love the idea of these vertically
integrated Asian growing co-ops that
have
got Loosely I'll say family but they've
got these these vertical families set up
um and and if if you're part of this
growing vertical you use the same
recipes as everybody else in the clan
and um it's kind of like a cultural
franchise you know it's like it's like
your whole family you've got all these
different locations but you're all doing
it the same way because it's what you've
decided uh works and decreases your
growing risk the most and the idea that
they've they've got something like that
without formal contracts that's just the
way it's always done I find that very
culturally interesting yep and it's
actually a very important to understand
that from a manufacturer standpoint uh
and it goes down to the very unique
detail of even packaging they get uh a
blueprint of what the bottle looks like
and that's the color bottle they're
going to buy with the color label and
the color caps and there's been cases
when I've known without say going into
names a manufacturer that decided to
change the color of their caps their you
know their closures to Blue where it was
white and they had to stop the the
grower stopped buying it because they
were supposed to buy that product that
had the White Caps not the blue caps and
you can't get it through to them so not
to manufacturers out there packaging
matters don't change packaging if you
don't have to it can cause more problems
than bring
value good good argument to uh take more
time uh uh developing your packaging at
the beginning so you don't have to make
a change at the end of year one exactly
for sure right on cool well this is all
great stuff let's go ahead and take our
first short B and break and be right
back you're listening to shaping fire
and my guest today is uh Colin Bell
co-founder of Mammoth microbes
living soil and regenerative cannabis
agriculture are surging in popularity
and to implement these biological
Solutions real science education is
vital if you are interested in all
things probiotic growing you will
probably want to attend the upcoming
science of organic regenerative cannabis
cultivation conference Joshua Rutherford
of Dutch blooms has lined up an
incredible array of Educators for the
traveling event the teaching staff
includes Leighton Morrison and Elaine
Ingam on soil biology Chris Trump
talking Korean natural farming
Kevin jod on cannabis genetics Kelly and
Josh from dragonfly Earth medicine
Suzanne Wright the bug lady Dr Robert F
on natural bio stimulants Steven raisner
on aquaponics and Chip Osborne on soil
testing and even more folks will be
there there will be a grower panel a
breeding panel and a Dem certified
Farmers panel Joshua has even built in
significant informal time for you with
the teachers as well the teaching staff
is just as excited to work with you as
you are about attending and there's no
advertising at the event no vendor
booths your tuition is what is paying
the staff so they all be very present
and attentive to you not a corporate
sponsor even better the conference is
not just for folks on the west coast
humbold California is hosting one event
for sure but the show is going on the
road to Vancouver British Columbia
Portland Maine and an Arbor Michigan get
out your pen now because I'm about to
give you the website this is a fabulous
opportunity for you to hear from an
array of nationally recognized topshelf
soil Educators all in one place not only
that this isn't just beginner stuff like
you get at most conventions this is an
intensive for people like us who totally
nerd out on the rizosphere the website
is regenerative organic
cannabis.com that's regenerative organic
cannabis.com you can also find a link on
the shaping fire Instagram and
newsletter cut through all the
misinformation out there and don't miss
this opportunity to learn real soil
science
this message is for folks who grow
cannabis I'm talking to Hom Growers
patients and Commercial Growers too I'm
probably talking to you when you plan
out your next growing cycle be sure to
check out humble CSI seeds at Humbolt
csi.com Caleb and Specta and his family
have lived in Humble County for over a
100 years for the last 40 years three
generations of his family have
cultivated extraordinary sensia cannabis
in Humble mesino and Trinity counties
because of his lineage age and the
hard-earned experience that comes from
growing up smoking and sifting large
populations of cannabis plants in
Northern California the seeds you'll cop
from CSI will be winning genetics based
on longtime Heavy Hitters and updated
and rifted to bring out new and exotic
traits and better yields go ahead and
ask around Caleb also known as inspecta
and pirates of the Emerald Triangle is a
breeders breeder he reaches way back and
works with significant strains
recreating them in new and interesting
ways that you'll love as a toker and a
grower as well as offering you some
surprises that will Delight serious seed
Traders and cultivators humble CSI goes
a further step and selfs all these
kimars so you know all the seeds will be
female these are not experimental
feminized seeds humble CSI releases some
of the best female seeds available
anywhere and it will show in your garden
folks grew quite a bit of CSI humble
Genex last year here on Vashon Island
and everyone was pleased
the patients had beautiful female plans
and didn't have to call half of their
Garden as males the folks growing for
the fun of getting high grew colorful
flowers with exceptional bag appeal and
great highs and breeders had seven out
of seven females in a pack which gave
them a lot of phenotypic choices take a
moment right now and visit humbled
csi.com you'll find an up-to-date menu
of both feminized and regular lines
along with photos and descriptions
that's humble
csi.com welcome back you're listening to
shaping fire I'm your host Shango Los
and our guest this week is Colin Bell
co-founder of Mammoth microbes so during
the first set we talked a lot about um
the differences in growing techniques
and culture um across Europe and
Australia and Latin America and Asia
well a lot of what you have been doing
during the last year and a half Colin is
essentially evangelizing living soil um
you know the same changes that have been
happening in the US as prohibition
starts to recede people are able to talk
more online we're being able to visit
analytics labs to learn you know people
are starting to to rely on synthetics
less and essentially your job when you
went over there was to meet people and
create community and kind of encourage
people to use soil more and to stop
putting pgrs and chemicals in their
stuff just for their own health can you
tell me a little bit about you know what
it's like to encourage people to
essentially start over on a new kind of
growing technique I mean you told us in
the first set that that uh Europe was
very much well especially the UK were
very much into Hydroponics and you're
like no I think maybe you should you
know get rid of everything that you've
done up to this point and start in this
you know in this new way how did people
react to your your message as a as a
living soil
evangelist I will start by saying you
know I have a PhD in microbiology and I
feel like I've been a living Soul
evangelist for my whole life at least my
whole academic career I just wasn't a
very good one until I was able to
actually apply some of my academic
training uh into the market where I
could engage Farmers more and yes of
course we know and science has well um
supported that the
natural processes that occur in soil
that are facilitated by soil microbes
both bacteria and
fungi do support plant Health plant
development and plant yield no questions
asked we also know that the interactions
between chemistry and cultivation
although we do deliver nutrients to
plants using chemical fertilizers and
they're in layoff forms we are missing
something and we know that whenever we
can incorporate some of the nature back
into the rizosphere or the plant root
Zone and nurture those exchanges those
plant microbial exchanges that have
evolved since the beginning of time the
plants respond to it favorably I feel
like we bring the natural exchange back
to them to allow them to maximize their
potential I'll also say that I've talked
to hundreds and hundreds of farmers in
many crops and Farmers don't like to
change anything no matter what they're
farming and so that is quite a steep
hill to climb and thinking about that we
have to understand how to bridge the gap
of nature or natural
Technologies like using microbes like
using living soil into existing
management practices without having to
ask the farmor to change everything
because that could be a very long
adoption
cycle and so so when you approach them
what are you finding and I and I know
I'm trying I'm about to take your entire
Global Experience from the last two
years and and and bring it down to one
example but generally speaking when when
you meet these people are they hungry
for the new organic knowledge where
they're they're all like you know
explain it to me five ways so that I can
understand it in my language or are they
you know you are a farming colonist you
know and and you're you're trying to
change our ways for no good reason I
think that I approach it a little
differently and it's practically too
what I focus on is the value and then
then you talk about how to get the value
you know every farmer is looking for
Solutions they're all looking to enhance
if it's food nutritional quality of the
food and yield if it's cannabis it's the
quality of the Cannabis and the yield
everyone wants that and if you can
improve that you have an audience the
next question is how and so it's the job
of Manufacturers like myself and many
others to bridge the needs of farmers
with a technology that's readily
adoptable I think there's a lot of great
te Technologies out there that if it
doesn't have that adoption that easily
adoptable characteristic it's not going
to be successful in the market because
it's just a huge barrier and so as an
example and this is uh probably the
biggest push back we've had is in the UK
early on and and just so you know we
have awesome adoption with our
technology in the UK which is a huge
Testament to how well microbes work
across a wide range of management
practices cultivation practices and
cannabis we got the best new product of
the year in late 2017 it's an amazing
success story but with the hydroponic
Growers who
use sterile techniques where they pour
bleach or they pour hydrogen peroxide
into the reses regularly to kill all the
micro life and mostly to control
pathogens uh that's why they do it and
that's a huge pain point and so how can
I educate those Growers who know they're
pouring in uh
disinfectants Things That Kill microbes
into their Grove to use
microbes well you educate on ecology and
let them know that plants have evolved
with microbes and microbes do benefit
plant growth and what we're trying to do
is mitigate pathogens but we're not
trying to kill beneficials and so from
an ecological perspective you can start
to educate on ecological nich Theory
competition Theory where if you can
flood root zones with beneficial
microbes bacteria and fungi it actually
in some ways these microbes act as a
bioshield
blocking pathogens and blocking
potential infection sites to limit
pathogen infection and that's one angle
along with the fact that if you can
maximize absorption of nutrients for
plants using these natural microbial
Solutions which is synonymous with a
living soil Bridging the Gap starting to
acknowledge that at least components of
living soil can be applied across all
cultivation practices you get people
thinking and you can get samples in
their hands and they have to see the
results every farmer wants to see
results with products they adopt with
products they're trying and if there's a
positive result you have just won over a
customer and they're going to buy your
technology because they want those
Solutions and not only that but they'll
tell all of their friends right because
no one keeps quiet when they've just
grown their best flowers ever right
everyone tells everybody I do I do I I
want everyone to know and you know
Shango that goes even for let's talk
about we're talking about cannabis but
think about home tomato Growers there's
a lot of really Avid not to change the
subject Avid tomato Growers and I'll
tell you what when I used to when I was
younger and I used to grow these big
tomatoes and they were delicious and
huge I would go show all my neighbors if
they look you know because you're kind
of racing with all your neighbors to get
the first tomatoes and get the best
tomatoes and get the biggest tomatoes
and it's no different with cannabis or
any other crop people get excited about
their achievements and they want to
share their achievements and in this
industry we want to share our success
and we should share success and so
that's exactly right if you have great
results you want to share it and that's
one thing that's very exciting we were
talking about social media but in
general you know if you have something
that works it will get out there as a
model we feel like everyone should try a
sample of our technology as just as an
example because we feel like you'll have
a good result and if you have a good
result that means we're bringing value
to Growers and we're going to be
successful as a company and that's kind
of how it works I think it's really
great how you pointed out that no matter
where you traveled even if people were
looking for new and better growing
information that everyone was proud of
growing cannabis and that they were
proud of the Cannabis they were growing
I like that as being a universal that
that no matter where we are no matter
what we can what kind of inputs we can
afford whether or not we have to do it
in the basement because of prohibition
or whether or not we can grow outside
because there's Medical in the country
um the idea that everybody is engaging
with the cannabis plant and it's making
them feel good I think that is a
wonderful Universal for our cannabis
Community there are way
more similarities across the world
within our industry than differences if
I engage any Cannabis Conference or any
group of cannabis Growers I could have
the same exchanges with groups that I
meet in
Colombia and groups that I meet in Spain
or Australia or the us or the UK or
Israel we all have the same passion for
this plant and for this industry and
it's uh a similarity that the world
within this industry shares for sure and
I'll give you an example that you just
kind of hit on this is last time I was
in Australia we were in Perth which is
one of the most isolated cities in the
world very very cool and cannabis is
very illegal and we're going and
engaging in the hydroponic grow shops
and one of the last ones and one of the
very last days I was there for a 10-day
stretch last October and I met a guy who
was super cool older guy he' been
growing there forever you know everyone
keeps it on the the DL man you have to
be very discreet and it's not like
you're taking selfies and Instagram
pictures with these people you can't do
that you can't take pictures in these
stores because they don't want their
faces shown it's a it's kind of a risk
but this gentleman I started talking to
him talking about the technology he got
super excited obviously I gave him some
samples and he was like man you've got
to see what I'm doing and he lived an
hour away and he was like can you please
wait for me here I really want to give
you a gift you know you're from the
States and you're doing this I'm really
happy and you know it was just ecstatic
I'm like I'll wait for you of course I
waited there 2 hours hung out you know
had a great time it's fun hanging out
the hyro shops I really love those
stores and he came back and gave me
handfuls of four different strains of
amazing cannabis that he'd been you know
nurturing and growing and breeding for
years it's just a testament man he went
two hours basically out of his way to
share to gift to be kind and I'll never
forget it that's really great and you
know I can the idea of going back to not
being able to show you know faces on
social media around flowers it's like oh
my gosh what a you know what a what a
jump back to you know seven eight years
ago and at the same time I'm thinking of
how many people who are listening to the
show right now who are in states in the
US that that's still the reality you
know I I'm I'm very fortunate to live on
the west coast and in Washington and and
to have been able to participate in all
of this so early um but you know
thinking about these you know uh you
know your story in Perth that could just
as well be be some of the places here so
so to everybody who's listening in a
Prohibition State hang in there folks
we'll we'll we'll we'll make our way to
you soon enough um change is coming yeah
change is coming so um one more thing I
want to hit on on on the evangelizing
you know um how much challenge did you
have with language right I mean the the
flower itself and the smoking of It kind
of transcends language you know you get
together people everybody knows how to
how a joint works and if you just like
Pass the Joint around a circle and
everybody smiles and laughs and you know
you know some amount of broken English
uh can work and I don't know what
languages you speak but but you know
what was it like for you to talk to
people in so many different countries
with so many different languages
I think talking and communicating are
two different things I don't I don't
speak Spanish well and that's one of my
goals for 2019 it was a goal for 2018
and I just traveled so much and it was
in so many different places obviously
there was it made it hard for me to to
hunker down and and be a good student to
learn the language I do have great uh
Spanish-speaking Partners through Mexico
and South America and in Spain and they
helped me a lot no doubt about it but
there's a body language and there's a
you know how what what does a hug mean
to you I don't have to say anything to
know exactly what that means pass me a
joint and give me a
hug that happens everywhere you know and
the and a smile and the look of man this
is awesome and a headshake and of course
we communicate we do a lot of
communication I communicate with many
people on Instagram and direct messaging
and and emails to a lesser degree now
thank goodness I'm trying to get away
from the emails completely one of these
days that's probably my 2019 goal also
um and the WhatsApp is another wonderful
tool that everyone around the world uses
that in itself allows me if I can't
understand every word even through
Reading I can translate it and engage
and understand the messages and
translate it back and and and and
communicate so I think communication is
just the effort you put into it and I
put everything I have into communicating
it's so important to me right on hey
let's go ahead and take our second uh
short break and be right back um you are
listening to shaping fire and my guest
today is Colin Bell co-founder of
Mammoth
microbes growing cannabis in green
houses is taking over the Cannabis
industry an efficient and effective
blend of sunshine grown turpine profiles
and the controlled environment of indoor
green houses can be the best of both
worlds for many Greenhouse operators
though building their Greenhouse before
gaining insight into how cannabis green
houses differ from ornamental crops can
be the start of a world of hurt Eric
Branstad and his team at Greenhouse
Advisory Group have the experience and
Technical knowhow to help you avoid
these pitfalls Eric Branstad has been
helping cannabis Growers find locations
design build and equip their green
houses for over a decade first starting
in Northern California but expanding
over the last 5 years to helping clients
throughout the world he has an
impeccable reputation for both depth of
knowledge and kindness in communication
you can hear Eric explain some of the
challenges facing cannabis green houses
and how to overcome them in episode
number 41 of the shaping fire
podcast no matter where I go in the
country good people with smart
backgrounds still are making the mistake
of building without knowing cannabis and
it causes them to burn through capital
and time fast everyone has their own
failure point for some it is improper
ventilation planning for others it is
surface temperatures of the building or
the plants leaves or both some folks
that build their Greenhouse from scratch
make really basic errors like placement
of the greenhouse on the property or not
understanding the natural environment
where the greenhouse sits some have even
built a decent Greenhouse but are
inefficient in their deployment of light
deprivation techniques and never really
hit their target
yields it's great when you learn from
your mistakes but it's even better when
you learn from the mistakes of others
when you bring on Greenhouse Advisory
Group you will learn from the mistakes
of their many clients and you'll take
advant of the best practices developed
by Eric Branstad over his years of
working with clients just like you from
location development to choosing a
builder and tricking out your new
Greenhouse or retrofitting or rescuing
your failing Greenhouse Eric will help
you through it visit Greenhouse advisory
group.com to learn more and connect with
Eric and his team that's Greenhouse
Advisory
Group now that the health benefits of
tpin have become well known in the
Cannabis industry people everywhere are
looking for the purest tpin without
adulterant the problem with most tpine
providers is that they're not sourced
naturally and instead are made as a
byproduct of refining petroleum and
that's so sketchy the Tarpin sold by
true tpin are entirely different they
are certified organic non-GMO and food
grade that means that they are extracted
from real plant sources there are no
solvents of any kind they are distilled
only with steam that's right only steam
in fact turpins from True turpins are so
here that you can eat them not only that
but you can stack them with better
results too what I mean is other
companies tpin have got a few percent of
impurities and when you stack those tpin
to make your blend you're adding a
variety of impurities that degrade your
final product true turpins also have
strain specific turpins for a wide range
of cannabis strains like Durban Poison
Sunset sherbet and Granddaddy Purple
true turpins has robust and supportive
customer service so your questions will
get answered fast and efficient I if you
shot for TPS before you know how rare
that is so whether you want to cup your
hands to smell some beta cophine to calm
down after getting too high or if you
want to dab some pining so your lungs
feel fabulous and your mind feels
liberated true turpins will provide you
with a truly natural experience if you
are a cannabis product developer these
are the TPS you want to add to your oil
or edible or capsule or whatever true
turpins are simply the best your money
can buy don't try and make a premium
prium product with substandard TPS
choose true tpping for a topshelf
experience go to shaping fire.com sltr
tping to find out more or click on the
link in this week's newsletter welcome
back you are listening to shaping fire
I'm your host Shango Los and our guest
this week is Colin Bell co-founder of
Mammoth microbes so before the break
Colin we were talking about how some
people that you met didn't want to take
selfies with you because they are in
prohibition country still and and they
can't have their face and name attached
to their cannabis enthusiasm um I'm
curious what other things that you
experienced around like prohibition
Vibes because a lot of these countries
that you've gone to are still very much
early in the transition towards even
medical before even getting to adult use
and um and and taboo is in the air and
potentially danger so so what do you
have to share about what it was like to
to be in prohibit prohibition countries
yeah so you know it's actually very
exciting in some ways I'm a scientist
that came from the University and now
I'm navigating in this cannabis industry
which is I would say regulatory wise
dark great of black markets yeah
throughout the world and with that comes
a level of risk you know going from
country to Country engaging in this
industry you have to be very discreet
and to uh what I what I think is really
important I keep on using this word
engage is to talk to our customers to
talk to Growers to learn more I learn
and grow and that's what I
starve uh starve for is education to do
that I have to find Growers and to find
Growers sometimes in illegal markets you
have to put yourself in positions where
you are in areas where illegal activity
is occur
and I'm okay with that I think you have
to be very discreet you have to be
mindful of your environment when you're
navigating hopefully you know the people
you're working with and engaging with um
and and I do more than not I've gotten
some great relationships an
example uh within this last year I was
with some friends I've met in this
industry that are great people uh no
names of course and they invited me to
go to a special session which is I
didn't really know what to expect it was
just a gathering is what I knew and so I
was given an address very discreetly and
a time to meet and when I get there and
I had to take a train for hours from
where I was staying in Newcastle so it
was um just for the record not in
Newcastle and I'll leave it at that and
when I get to this place I get off a
train and get at Uber and it's in this
old industry part of town uh late on a
weekend night completely isolated in an
old industrial park and I see a couple
of cars and I kind of Wander over there
and it's dark you know and I am alone
and you see this guy who you know looks
big and kind of um
dangerous and you make this assumption
that this is where the thing is and you
go up and you're trying to be modest and
I have a little leaning to cuz I'm a
foreigner uh from from America at least
from the US and um I text my friend I'm
like hey I think I'm here so they come
down but this thing turns out to be this
huge like event um this exchange this
swap meet and there's security you go
through two levels of security you go up
to the third floor and this is all in an
abandoned warehouse in this dark again a
dark industrial park and as soon as you
get to the third floor and you open up a
couple more doors there's 400 people in
here there's music there's a coffee bar
there 's a regular bar there's some food
and it looks kind of like you know like
a craft fair you ever been to a craft
fair yeah sure there just a bunch of
card table set up lining the walls
halfway around this huge room and it's a
bunch of people with their product
either they're extracts or they flour or
some people are selling glass so it's
kind of like a craft bear or a swap meat
for cannabis all 100% illegal and it was
a lot of fun people were smoking people
were purchasing people were were buying
and selling and smoking a lot and it
turned out to be a wonderful time but
again you would never know about it
unless you're engaged in the industry
and you
know I felt comfortable because I
trusted the people that invited me to
this thing but I had a couple other
people that I knew that I was working
with in the UK that was like you know
what wouldn't do that mate and so I was
like okay I know I was like I I I I
respected their opinion but I went ahead
and checked it out yeah I was really
glad I did up until you open that last
door and you suddenly see people with
cocktails in their hands and smiling up
to that up to that very last point it
all sounded sketchy as hell right and
you're like oh man as a matter of fact
it's a good thing to point out that some
of the countries that you were like you
know when you told me that you were
going to Colombia I was thinking to
myself dude they snatch Americans there
what are you doing like like did you
ever feel I mean except for maybe when
you were walking up to that warehouse
you just told us about were you were
there times when you felt like you were
in bodily danger uh trying to hunt out
these these folks who are doing proh
prohibition era
grow I think that in some areas or some
countries it's pretty close by you know
I'm always with people that are
typically always with people that are
from those particular regions or cities
like in meene and you have a second set
of eyes and a good intuition of people
that are on the ground that know you
know if there's a bad neighborhood or a
good neighborhood this is a pretty fun
example not to name names but one of my
uh one of our teammates a year ago uh
got in a cab and he was looking for some
flour we didn't know anyone in medene at
that time and this young man is from
Mexico and he's pretty and he's from
Mexico City and so he's used to very
rough areas and this cabie took him to
this other area they stopped and and in
my teammate he was like man Colin it was
like like I wouldn't welcome to come
because my complexion was too light in
da and and this young man although he
was from Mexico He was ordered to stay
in the cab and only the cab driver could
go in to exchange because it was that
dangerous and so it's
it can be sketchy but I've never ever
felt like in danger at all quite frankly
CU I'm around the right people and
there's bad areas and and dangerous
areas and and and safe areas in every
city it happens but it's it's if you if
you take care of of where you're going
it's really not an issue It also says a
lot about um you know if any of us were
to go to these places and and try to
hunt up these beautiful markets you're
describ desing that that that having a
trusted local is the name of the game
you have to do that no matter what in
every country you're not going to go to
Australia or UK even if you engage and
speak the language and necessarily find
the people that you want to trade with
you you should have people that know the
area and and know people so you can get
so you can get connected with with the
good guys so to speak so so this this
question may be a non-starter but it's
kind of a a shot in the dark so and and
maybe I'm being too informed by
Hollywood that's possible too but I was
curious if you came across like nutrient
cartels right because in these different
countries that you're going to they've
been doing things the same way for a
long time generally and whatever
nutrients are being input into you know
the Hydroponics or whatever somebody is
selling that stuff to them and then and
then you come in and you're talking to
people about at the very least a new
product um which probably actually
doesn't compete with a lot of the stuff
they're already using because it's so
unique but more so you're starting to
teach people living soil which is a
whole different system which will upset
the apple cart on how some of these
people have been making money did you
experience any like you like cannabis
nutrient bad guys you know who are who
who did not appreciate your
presence no but I do agree that there's
that potential and honestly with a
category we're in and we're in the
additive category it's a little agnostic
to the nutrient inputs but there are
some clicks I'll call them clicks that
are very strongly opinionated on their
position in the marketplace and they
control that and protect that as much as
they possibly can and so if I was moving
in to the UK with another nutrient line
or austr with another nutrient line I
don't think that I would be successful
it's just a a lot of history and a lot
of products are already there and a lot
of groups have already taken up a lot of
the market share where we're coming in
with kind of a new category we're coming
in with life in a bottle that's going to
enhance everything you're putting in to
maximize nutrient uptake and the
synergies there alleviate a lot of that
for us H right on that's interesting so
this next question
um it's kind of a different flavor than
than the rest of the questions that I've
asked you um uh when we had uh colum
Riley on the show we talked a lot about
the Biore regionalism of microbes and
how if you're going to make you know
nutrient compost teas it's really great
to use local compost that hasn't been
shipped across the country so that you
are um you are breeding more microbes
that are local to you and will do well
in your soil your weather and all this
kind of stuff right and and you know i'
I use Mammoth p uh in in my summertime
grow and uh I and and that's got a
particular microb mix in it so so I am
curious um I guess it's a two-part
question number one did you find that
people had any uh Fidelity to the idea
that they've got local microbes and and
the second part of the question is um uh
the microbes that are in your product
appropriate for all these different
Biore regions that's two really good
questions and I could kind of spend a
lot of time on that but I I I will
abbreviate and I'll say that you know I
think overall there's a lot of ubiquity
where you'll find the same microbial
groups everywhere and so microbes
bacteria and fungi can adapt to
different environments and I want to say
that the environment
selects why there are so much diversity
in any one particular soil is because as
winter and summer uh Seasons uh
fluctuate and change over time they're
going to select for microbial resilience
of some microbial groups and other
microbial groups are going to really be
stressed by that change in in weather
for example and so you want to maintain
that function and the resilience helps
that having microbes in from a local
Source definitely helps Bridge the
confidence that if you're in ucing them
to the same climatic or environmental
conditions you should have confidence
that they're going to persist what I
will say is microbes in nature and
microbes even in a cloth pot are not the
same environment at the microscopic
scale it's very different and what we
want to do is make sure we nurture
microbes that are very highly functional
and very persistent and so I'll say as
the environment selects as a great
example and this is this is reflecting
on my experiences in manufacturing or
the R&amp;D for manufacturing our technology
you know we started off with soils from
across the world because we wanted to
nurture the biodiversity and the
functional diversity of as many microbes
as possible what we did is we put them
through a functional trait selection
platform and an environmental trait
selection platform to maximize the the
functional aptitude of any kind of final
product but also to weed out microbes
that couldn't persist in Environmental
stressful conditions that were
characteristic of farming practices or
the management practices that that
Growers use in Hydroponics and cannabis
cultivation and we started off sh with
over 10,000 microbial species and after
we imposed them through our our
selection platform after many
generations we ended up with four
microbes which suggest that most
microbes aren't effective and
appropriate for
farming practices and we have to select
the right microbes for our cultivation
practices and that's where we can get
confidence uh with with uh biotech
companies looking to solve uh Solutions
or looking to develop Solutions
microbial solutions for cultivation can
help Growers use microbes with
confidence and Precision in their
Precision agriculture practices right on
so Colin thank you so much for for for
being a guest on this very different
kind of show right I mean every time
I've talked with you before we jump
right into soil science and that's a
happy place for both of us I know um but
when you you know when you started
telling me about these these cultural
experiences and these people that you
were meeting you know I knew I wanted to
hear more about these stories and and I
figured that the shaping fire audience
would appreciate it too so I appreciate
you uh you know sharing a different side
of yourself with us so that we could all
you know be a little more aware of this
This Global Village of cannabis
enthusiasts we have brother awesome man
I really appreciate it as always I'm
looking forward to seeing you next and
let's keep growing buddy right on
brother thank you very much if you want
to follow up with Colin or find out more
about the mammoth P product uh you can
go to their website at Mammoth
microbes. and if you enjoy Instagram
like the rest of us do you can go to the
mammoth microbes Instagram creatively
enough at Mammoth microbes and if you're
if you want to follow Collins travels
specifically or to reach out to him the
best way to do that is via his Instagram
which is Colin W Bell so that's c l i n
w b l and that's also on Instagram and
if you caught that earlier during the
the interview he prefers Instagram
messages to email so we're not even
going to bother giving you an email
address just just reach shout to him uh
via that you can find more episodes of
the shaping fire podcast And subscribe
to the show at shaping fire.com and on
Apple iTunes Stitcher and Google Play If
you enjoyed the show we'd really
appreciate it if you'd leave a positive
review of the podcast wherever you
download your review will help others
find the show so they can enjoy it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the Weekly Newsletter for
insights into the latest Cannabis News
and product reviews on the shaping fire
website you will also find transcripts
of today's podcast as well for
information on me and where I'll be
speaking you can check out Shango
los.com doeses your company want to
reach our national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hotspot shaping
fire.com to find out how thanks for
listening to shaping fire I've been your
host Shango Los