[Music]
at the end of every cannabis season
plants are cut low on the stock and
taken away to be processed what remains
is a small nub coming out of the soil
below in the soil is a very much alive
and active cannabis root system
interacting with mycorrhizae microbes
and nutrients other than being a trophy
showing how thriving a plant was before
it was cut down there's not been much
use for the plants root ball in modern
cannabis medicine until now if you enjoy
hearing frank discussions that dive deep
into cannabis health business and
technique i encourage you to subscribe
to our newsletter every week you'll
receive a new podcast episode delivered
right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week and
videos to recent videos have included my
presentation at the Veridian staffing
job fair describing a proven strategy to
find your dream career in cannabis as
well as the sustainable greenhouse
design panel I moderated at the Imperius
cannabis Expo in Phoenix
don't rely on social media to let you
know when a new episode is published
sign up for the updates to make sure you
don't miss an episode you are listening
to shaping fire and I am your host
Shango 'lose my guest today is natasha
rizz natasha has a PhD in experimental
medicine from the University of British
Columbia and also holds a Master of
Science and a Bachelor of Science in
human nutritional sciences natasha has
over 15 years of experience as a health
and nutrition researcher and has
published seven first author
peer-reviewed publications to first
author reviews and co-authored eight
peer-reviewed publications natasha is a
researcher and product formulator
specializing in cannabis and other
compounds that target the
endocannabinoid system Natasha is
co-founder of rizz Remy skincare and
therapeutics where she designs topical
products for pain and inflammatory
conditions as well as beauty today we're
going to talk about Natasha's new paper
entitled cannabis roots a traditional
therapy with future potential for
treating inflammation and pain as
published in the Journal of cannabis and
cannabinoid research and co-authored
with world-renowned cannabis expert dr.
Ethan Rousseau and david reme yard
welcome to the show Natasha well thank
you for having me so your paper is so
much more enjoyable to read and
accessible than many others I've read in
science and in some parts it feels as
much like a history text as a scientific
paper what's the difference between a
paper like this one and one that is
simply reporting the results of an
experiment yeah well I don't know about
simply reporting the results of
experiments because lots of work goes
into reporting that but what's different
about what we've created here is we're
like you said we're going through the
history of how cannabis roots were used
and then we're trying to find clues from
newer research to incorporate some of
that together to show that the active
compounds that are found in the cannabis
roots even though they haven't been
studied specifically from the cannabis
roots there is some other research we
can put together where as and when
you're looking at a research study
that's reporting on something new or a
single compound they're really going
into the details of the experimental
methods and usually they're showing
multiple ways of doing an experiment to
show that there actually can convince
you and prove that their hypothesis is
correct
whereas this may be more enjoyable to
the non scientist reader because it is a
nice history of how the roots were used
and then does a brief summary of some of
the literature showing again like how
these octave compounds would have been
used for treating inflammation or pain
or other different conditions and then
we summarize the research by showing
methods of application and it is
interesting you say it's different than
other papers because when we first
submitted it it was actually to another
Journal and they didn't really
understand I think so they thought even
the title that we weren't actually
talking about the roots of cannabis they
thought it was like a folksy like again
back to the roots right yeah and I had
written a lot of there was even more
information about kind of forward steps
of how to use the roots in recipes and
things like that
and they even made kind of a snarky
comment like oh this reads like a
reader's digest paper oh man that's a
dish that's not cool they didn't
understand the paper and so and that's
part of the reason why it took us a
while to get this paper published
because really Ethan and I started on
this project and my husband Dave
Remillard is also an author so the three
of us have been working on this project
for about a year and this is really how
Ethan and I actually became friends and
colleagues was back at ICRS of the
International cannabinoid Research
Society meeting in Vancouver in 2013 it
was in Vancouver and that was my first
time going to this meeting and my first
time meeting Ethan and so when we first
met I said to him what are you doing
with the roots because he was still with
GW Pharmaceuticals back at that time and
he was like Natasha what are you talking
about the roots and so we had a
discussion about it and I'm like well my
husband David he's he he's a legal
cannabis grower in Canada and he we've
been using the roots to make topicals
and so he was fascinated by this and
Ethan went back and he went through the
literature and he put together this
really nice 30-point power page or
PowerPoint presentation going over the
whole history of the roots and then he
sent that to me and he was like Natasha
we have to write a paper about this and
so that's really why the first part of
the paper really is an overview of the
historical use of it and it's a lot of
quotes and so we had to put that
together as kind of a story and start
putting it in some different themes so
yeah like for fever for inflammation for
skin burns for hard tumors even for
childbirth there's many different ways
throughout history that people have been
using the youth the roots and
I know there's people who are making
products these days but in the
scientific realm and in the academic
realm no one was talking about the route
so we felt it was really important to
get this information put together
published to start getting more interest
and actually pursuing some of these
compounds you know gosh I've got a bunch
of things to say so so let's see lurch
where to start so number one going all
the way back to the roots you know when
I was talking to people about my
excitement about interviewing you on
this show I too had to clarify because I
said oh yeah I'm doing a show on
cannabis roots and they're like didn't
you already do the history of cannabis
with Sunil Agarwal like in Episode five
I'm like yeah not those kind of roots
the rootball and then you could see this
look of bling this and then they're like
cool you know because you know uh you
know mostly you know we throw away root
balls but but after your paper I think
people are gonna be using them a lot
more and then and then also it's fun to
hear you talk about your your meeting of
ethan cuz i got the other side of that
story he and i rat lunch and he saw like
yeah natasha asked me about root balls
and he says i lit up and i say any saw
like i knew right away that we'd be
friends you know because he's you know
had an interest in root balls too but
had never really actually had a chance
to dig into it so right on so you know
since you're reaching back so far into
ancient medicine for a lot of these
texts where there's some ailments that
were you know enshrouded by outdated
language that you had to do secondary
research just to figure out what they
were saying they were using the root
ball to cure yeah a little bit and i
tried to clarify especially when they're
referring to hard tumors we weren't sure
if they're referring to cancer or more
like an abscess or a sore or a type of
ulcer that has like tumor hard tumor
like properties so we were pretty
careful in how we interpreted those
interpretations of how're they were
using the roots and even when we looked
at some of the compounds in the roots
and went into newer studies
with cell culture experiments and animal
studies it they didn't really find much
anti-cancer activity with these
compounds so we were careful with how we
covered that part of the routes just
because we know there's so many
potential anti-cancer properties with
the cannabinoids and other parts of the
cannabis planet but the roots might not
be the best for anti-cancer properties
the area where it was very exciting and
I see a lot of potential for the routes
is more for topical use so putting it on
top of your skin and using it to treat
inflammatory conditions redness
arthritis and also gout there's numerous
mentions like it was almost hard to
summarize it all without just going on
and on and on about how often the
ancient medicine makers were using
cannabis routes to treat gout so that
was exciting to read about especially
anyone who's ever suffered from gout or
tried to find treatments for it
a lot of them don't work that well so
and actually I should bring up when I
was so when Ethan and I were first
working on this paper he invited me to
patients at a time in Baltimore last
year to speak about it and so that was
great I got to do a talk at the
conference met a lot of amazing people
but this one man came up and he was a
cannabis farmer and he came and talked
to me after and he was telling me that
he doesn't consume any cannabis and he
was working on a count of his farm and
he was like I wasn't touching any of the
cannabis my only job was to handle the
root waste and so he said he was
handling all the root wastes and they
were keeping some of it in the freezer
just on the like hey this might have
some properties and he said just by
handling the roots his goat and his his
toes had gone away and he had made that
connection and he was just like blown
away after he saw him I talked as he was
like oh my goodness just by handling
them my goat had gotten better and so
that really intrigued me and so I kept
talking about the goat
I personally don't haven't experienced
any of these types of treatments or like
I don't suffer from many goat or
inflammatory conditions so I can only go
on what other people are telling me but
I definitely think it's an application
of the roots that's worth pursuing right
on so I know this next question is big
so I'm gonna kind of set you up for it
and let you go here so so you know one
of the things that struck me immediately
in reading your paper is that you know
you're talking about a whole new
community of active compounds then we're
usually talking about with cannabinoids
you know usually when I read papers I'm
pretty familiar with the active
components but most of the active
compounds in the root are new to me and
it's really exciting to have some new
healing attributes of cannabis to learn
about so before we get into the
historical healing applications for the
compounds after the break before the
break would you review that just the
names of the active compounds from the
abstract of of the paper to kind of
familiarize us with their names so that
when we start talking about their
applications folks are a little familiar
with what they are yeah so what's really
interesting about the roots is they're
very low and cannabinoids like THC and
CBD what they contain is other compounds
so one of the main compounds we talked a
lot about in the paper is called free
Delin so this is found in the root set
of oat it has reported from older
studies at twelve point eight milligrams
per kilogram and then there's another
compound called epi free d'leh epi free
to lentil and that's about 21 milligrams
per kilogram so these two compounds are
triterpene ODEs and they've been
isolated from other plants they're found
in many other plants as well as cannabis
and so they've been isolated from
cannabis and characterized but no one
has specifically studied them from
cannabis but they've taken them from
other plants and done some preliminary
animal experiments and shown that they
have really potent anti-inflammatory
activity anti pain anti redness they can
help prevent the influx of inflammatory
cells and so those compounds are most
likely the active compounds that are
providing a lot of the anti-inflammatory
activity there's also some interesting
alkaloids that are in the roots called
cannabis a Devine and this compound has
been isolated from cannabis root but
there's no research on it so we don't
actually know what this compound does
and then another thing that was
interesting is there was one report of a
group isolating carvone which is
monoterpene it has its the major
monoterpene found in spearmint so when
you smell that spearmint minty scent
that's pretty much carvone you're
smelling and so they found that the root
had this distinguished smell is what
they said and then they want to further
analyze it and found that it was Carbone
and Carbone is interesting because it's
being studied also as an
anti-inflammatory anti-pain compound
especially with regards to like
spearmint essential oil there's a
clinical trial where they're studying it
topically like putting it on your skin
for treating osteoarthritis so we can
take some of these compounds and then
start put that the story together and
realize like oh all these compounds are
playing a role and who knows some of
these old concoctions may have well had
some local sake contamination or
whatever cannabinoids from other parts
of the plant so realistically I think
whole plant formulas that include parts
of the roots and the cannabinoids will
work best but I think these compounds
and the roots have a lot of potential to
also play a role with helping with a
variety of medicinal applications
including redness inflammation and pain
right on before we go to break one last
question you know these these new active
compounds that we're learning about I
mean they're not new to science but
they're new to a lot of us cannabis
medicine folk you know we're suggesting
that they are something other than than
cannabinoids because we're talking about
them and cannabinoids yeah you know why
would you say scientifically that
they're not considered cannabinoids like
definitionally why are they not
cannabinoid
well a cannabinoid is a unique compound
that's like THC CBD like there's this
it's a class of structurally like you
eat compounds and so these are just
different completely different compounds
though they're just I I want to clarify
too a lot of people are really confused
about cannabinoids being found in other
plants I saw some people talking about
it on Facebook today and arguing about
it and using one of a thens paper to
justify their point but they were
actually arguing the wrong thing so when
we say cannabinoids these compounds are
specific to the cannabis plant and
that's like THC and CBD and there's many
other cannabinoids
but there's compounds that in other
plants that act like cannabinoids and
can work through the endocannabinoid
system in our body but people are saying
oh there's cannabinoids and other plants
but there aren't so anyway cannabinoids
are a unique family of compounds that
are unique to the cannabis plant but
they're not found in large amounts in
the roots
thank you that's that's the answer I was
looking for and you took it even farther
along that path you know we had dr.
Russo on the show talking about how you
know his nutrition paper write a
nutrition to support the endocannabinoid
system and a lot of people took that
paper as you were describing that oh
look there's cannabinoids and all these
a lot of things like well they're not
really cannabinoids in these other
plants they're just other nutritional
plants that support your endocannabinoid
system so yeah take your cannabinoids
but also take this other nutrition and I
think that's a good delineation you make
yeah and like especially with beta
carrie awfully lot because and there's a
paper that kind of is at fault here the
way the title is it's like oh here's a
they call it a cannabinoid but beta
carry off lean works through the cb2
receptor and it works through our
endocannabinoids system and can boost
cannabinoids but it is not a cannabinoid
right you know just making it all very
very clear yeah yeah so so let's go
ahead and take our first short break and
be right back when we get back we're
gonna be talking about
the actual health benefits of using the
rootball system you're listening to
shaping fire and my guest today is
cannabis in cannabis health of
researcher natasha rizz we humans are
attracted to plants because they offer
us relief and are a whole lot of fun
sometimes though the best parts are
buried inside the plant and we need to
use specialty extraction technology when
it comes to cannabis it is
extraordinarily important to extract its
precious oils without changing them in
the process we want to preserve the
properties of the cannabinoids terpenes
and other constituents that all work
together since 1994
Eden labs has been developing extraction
technology and processes to do just that
Eden labs was founded by a cannabis
loving engineer during the early days of
medical marijuana in California and the
expanded Eden team has been designing
and building industry-leading solutions
for cannabis extraction ever since
Eden labs flagship product is the newly
improved High Flow co2 extractor as
other extraction companies enter the
market it is the high flow from Eden
labs that everyone chases and tries to
compare themselves with not only that
but the improved automation software
allows data to be collected stored and
studied Eden labs can outfit your whole
lab Eden's coldfinger
ethanol extractor creates astonishing
whole plant extracts working alone or in
tandem with an initial stream distilling
step to isolate monoterpenes before
extracting the rest of the botanical
constituents Eden offers you many
options including vacuum distillation
column distilling stirred reactor units
and accelerated solvent recovery when
you partner with Eden labs your lab team
is enrolled into the Eden labs training
program to boost their understanding of
Eden's best practices to ensure that
your outputs are exactly what you
require for your application whether it
be dab oil oil for pen cartridges or
edibles when you work with Eden you're
not just buying the tech you are buying
dedicated customer support to help you
attain your business goals - you can
hear Eden's CEO AC Braddock talk about
the company's values during shaping fire
episode 19 that was all about co2
extraction
so many of the new companies in the
market just smell opportunity slap an
extractor together and hire a marketing
company Eden Labs has been listening to
feedback from extractors and consumers
for about 25 years now they care about
both you and your consumer partner with
Eden labs to extract astonishing
cannabis oils and terpenes that you will
be proud of go to shaping feiyr.com /e
Dhin to find out more now that the
health benefits of terpenes have become
well known in the cannabis industry
people everywhere are looking for the
purest terpenes without adulterants the
problem with most terpene providers is
that they're not sourced naturally and
instead are made as a byproduct of
refining petroleum and that's so sketchy
the terpenes sold by true terpenes are
entirely different they are certified
organic non-gmo and food grade that
means that they are extracted from real
plant sources there are no solvents of
any kind they are distilled only with
steam that's right only steam in fact
terpenes from true turbines are so pure
that you can eat them not only that but
you can stack them with better results -
what I mean is other company's turbines
have got a few percent of impurities and
when you stack those terpenes to make
your blend you're adding a variety of
impurities that degrade your final
product true terpenes also have
strain-specific terpenes for a wide
range of cannabis strains like Durbin
poison sunset sherbet and granddaddy
purple true terpenes has robust and
supportive customer service so your
questions will get answered fast and
efficiently if you shop for Turk's
before you know how rare that is so
whether you want to cup your hands to
smell some beta Kari awfully calm down
after getting too high or if you want to
dab some pining so your lungs feel
fabulous and your mind feels liberated
true terpenes will provide you with a
truly natural experience if you are a
cannabis product developer these are the
Terps you want to add to your oil or
edible or capsule or whatever true
terpenes are simply the best your money
can buy don't try and make a premium
product with substandard terms choose
true terpenes for a top-shelf experience
go to shaping fire calm boards
true terpenes to find out more or click
on the link in this week's newsletter
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire I'm your host Shango losan
our guest this week is cannabis health
researcher Natasha rizz so now we're
getting into the heart of the topic so
the theme of the paper seems to be that
historically healers of all kinds use
the root ball for a range of
inflammatory issues and infections and
fevers there are so many different
active ingredients in applications that
I actually found it hard to create you
know like a cogent path of questions for
you
how do you prefer to talk about the
medical applications in a way that
people can make sense of it yeah
so I parts that I really like to focus
on are the topical applications so
putting it on your skin there's hints at
various ways of using the cannabis root
including oral even as a suppository
like indirectly to help with infection
but when throughout history anyway when
people are using the root orally or
indirectly it seems to be more for a
specific purpose so like a medical
purpose not necessarily like something
you'd want to do every day whereas the
topical applications like on the skin
seem like something that you could use
consistently so when patients are or
through history when people were taking
it as an oral drink it was more for
during childbirth when they were having
issues with like they couldn't stop
bleeding and so there's historical
accounts in China of using the root
concoction as an oral supplement to help
with bleeding during childbirth whereas
there's a richer history and many more
accounts of cannabis root bombs and
water extractions being used on the skin
and even I should bring up like if
anyone's working with cannabis roots you
want to be really careful of where
you're sourcing the material from
because cannabis is really good at fight
over mediation meaning it can suck up
bad things from the ground and count
is really good at sucking up iron and
heavy minerals that can accumulate and
could be dangerous if you're using it
for medicine so it might be better use
roots that are grown through hydroponics
or at least in soil that you know
doesn't have a mineral contamination or
a heavy metal contamination so just keep
that in mind so that might also be part
of the reason why taking the route in
orally might be you might have to be a
little careful about it whereas putting
it on your skin it just seems there's
such a rich history of using it that way
especially for as I mentioned several
times gout arthritis and joint pain but
the other thing that also came up
throughout the historical accounts of
all the hemp root use was water
extraction so we know that cannabinoids
are fat soluble compounds and so most of
the time when we do extractions with
cannabis flowers or the parts of the
plants we're using fats or alcohol or
things to extract these fat compounds
the thing that was really interesting
about the roots is throughout history
it's very clear that they're using
boiling water or some kind of heated
type water extraction and so I'll go a
little bit over of the different ways
they're using it one is they're drying
the root and using it as a powder and so
there's accounts of just using that
powder as like remix it with water and
using it on like a cut or as a poultice
and then there's other accounts of
taking the root and shredding it that
might be a bit difficult because the
roots are pretty hard and then there's
other accounts where they're taking the
root cooking it in boiling water and
then using that water extraction either
to soak like other things in and then I
put that topically like as a compress or
they're taking let me see the roots
there oh so they're also even taking
that water extraction and like boiling
it down to making almost like
like a paste or a SAP and then they're
using other ways where they're taking
even alcohol extractions or the recipe
that we used personally at home to
process some of David's cannabis roots
has been actually to take a blend of fat
and water and cut that in a crock pot
and use that to extract fat soluble and
water soluble compounds and then what
you do after that is you put it in the
freezer and then you freeze off the
water and then you can separate the fat
and the water compounds and then do
separate things with that so yeah
there's a lot of different things about
the roots that are different than the
way most people are processing the
cannabis plant and so the main thing is
the water extraction and the other thing
is that people are mostly using it
topically versus you know smoking it or
eating it sure that makes sense and and
during the third set we're gonna talk a
little bit more in detail about how to
make those but for the moment I want to
hit on you know I think that it's
interesting that that there are all of
these different procedures for getting
the the compounds and touch with the
human body but it's interesting that
there was so much experimentation all
these different ways to essentially just
get the friedlin and carvone and other
active compounds just to touch the body
right I mean whether it's by boiling or
or cutting it up or making a poultice
it's just like these are these are
different methods to essentially do the
same thing which is get those essential
active compounds against the skin or in
lesser cases into the body through a
drink right yeah exactly yeah so
different different you know healers
would use different techniques based on
you know what their personal beliefs
were or what was what was available to
them one of the things that I find
interesting about the this approach too
is you know
you've talked about a wide range of
ailments that helps with you know gout
arthritis joint page hemorrhaging from
after a pregnancy fever I mean this is a
it was a pretty wide range and normally
when we're talking about cannabinoid
medicine we're like oh it's because it
supports the endocannabinoid system
which is the body's master regulator and
balances so many systems that that you
know it all helps the EC s and then the
ec s takes care of rebalancing
everything and then you get all this
relief but that's not what we're talking
about this time and so what's different
with this from what it sounds like is
that we're actually trying to get these
particular active compounds for what
they uniquely do to our body's system
themselves so the carvone is doing one
thing and the Friedland is doing one
thing instead of how we normally think
about cannabinoid medicine which is oh
it all turns on or off something in the
EC s yeah and I mean these the EC s is
so like it's everywhere on our body so
I'm I would be surprised if these
compounds weren't somehow targeting the
endocannabinoid system and we can kind
of think of inflammation pathways in the
way we think of the endocannabinoid
system so when we say something's
affecting inflammation that's a very
complex process there's many cells
there's many types of inflammation some
types of inflammation are good some
types are bad and then there's early
modulators of inflammation that I like
to think of as like cells coming in with
machine guns where they're just you know
trying to take out every kind of invader
but are also causing a lot of damage to
the host and so when we're saying that
these compounds are targeting
inflammation it's not only bringing down
redness and like swelling and it's also
bringing down on pain and as most people
know inflammation is an underlying
mechanism for many many different
diseases so even if you have a condition
that there may be no cure for if you can
get the inflammation under
control your symptoms will feel better
so even just targeting some of these
pathways we're gonna get I mean
seemingly like oh it does so many things
is this actually real but all of these
underlying mechanisms play roles and
many many different diseases so we can
say something like skin burns and heart
tumors and fever may not seem like
they're related but they could all be a
part of the same condition and so if
you're targeting it's kind of like
pulling the string of the yarn ball you
know you if you get the the inflammatory
processes under control the whole host
will start just feeling better and kind
of the body will work better and be able
to sort itself out even if we look at
something like modulating stress like so
I work a lot with patients with
inflammatory bowel diseases so Crohn's
and Colitis and these are
gastrointestinal conditions that
inflammation and pain pay play a big
role but stress and psychological just
how you're feeling about your body plays
a huge role in the disease and when
patients are in a state of stress and
anxiety their body doesn't work as well
and so it can't work as good and so even
just getting that stress under control
sometimes that can help get the
inflammation under control and then all
of a sudden the patient starts getting
less ulcers and so I think we have to
even take these like stress relief seems
like such a simple thing but it's it's
such a you know an underlying mechanism
for so many diseases that if we can get
basic things like stress inflammation
just things that really affect everyone
and have highs and lows throughout the
day but there's so many nutritional and
lifestyle factors we can do including
cannabis right on that makes a lot of
sense you know so often when working
with a cannabis patient we find out that
yeah the cannabis helped them but
actually once they started sleeping
properly they started getting better
just because they were getting proper
sleep you know it's we got to take care
of these basic systems you know one of
the things I like about how your
paper is laid out is that you know at
the beginning you go through an
explanation of you know that gives
context and the different active
compounds we're working with but then
you go section by section on the
different ailments that you can get
relief from and before we move on I want
to make sure that we hit a couple that
we haven't hit so far because you know
we've we've talked about you know
infection and fever and gout but but
let's and and postpartum hemorrhaging
but let's talk about a sexually
transmitted disease why don't you hit on
that yeah so this again we kind of
hesitated to put this one in because
there was one quote to it but it was
interesting and I have the paper here so
I mean I'll read it a little bit but so
there was one report of cannabis root
being used to help with gonorrhea so in
the seventeenth century a german-born
botanist employed by the Dutch East
Indian company I think it's interesting
to get some context of who these people
were so anyway he the quote says that
the Moors took the route of the male or
the flower bearing plant and they used
it to feed and who those who were held
fast unclean but with gonorrhea I mean
these quotes the wording is a little off
the old English is really a mess yeah so
basically we took that from this account
they were eating cannabis root to help
with gonorrhea but it's really unclear
from this account how it was prepared so
yeah we just had it in there as a quote
saying this because I feel like when we
make and ethan was really a good mentor
for putting this paper together because
he was saying even these accounts that
may you know have a little comment about
it's our responsibility to put it
together so if someone does decide to
research that further it's like hey that
there was an account of that and someone
was using that and as we know what the
cannabis plant it does so many different
things that sometimes there's this
condition that's seemingly out there
that you're like oh does it do that and
then you find out that it
actually can't help with that condition
so yeah I was an interesting quote that
came up so we decided to include it well
I think that this paper really does open
a lot of doors right because it's not
like this is the final word on any of
this what you're really doing is opening
a door to new directions in research by
giving you no historical survey of how
you know older cultures have used the
rootball for for a wide range of things
and I think that's one of the great
things about the paper another one I
want to hit on is the GI tract because
you know we all know that Canada's yo is
used by anti mimetic Eunos to stop
people from vomiting but also you're
you're suggesting the the roots can be
used as a you know essentially a tummy
tuck a tummy tuck that would help a
whole range of ailments yeah and it's
interesting because of the accounts with
the route bomb in or so the root ball
and reference to Castro intestinal
activity is actually being used to
induce vomiting
so yeah I'll read a little bit the
cannabis roots have been used to protect
against vomiting but also to induced
vomiting so in Chile hemp roots have
been used as a purge ative and so the
way they were using it they were mixing
it polarized with wine and recommending
it for weaknesses and pains of the
stomach and so that's really interesting
to me again because I know more about
how THC and CBD the cannabinoids can
affect the gut and play a big role
especially in inflammation and in
helping with nausea and vomiting
although we also know that there's a
condition called cannabinoid hyperemesis
syndrome or some people respond badly to
high amounts of cannabis and it actually
can induce vomiting so yeah I think this
whole system and the way cannabis can
interact with our gastrointestinal
system it's by module so it can induce
things and it can also suppress things
and it's all dose dependent and also
dependent on the person's Constitution
so yeah I think it there's more
search that's needed to be done but yeah
it's interesting that the roots also
seem to have some gastrointestinal
activity also I like that word you just
used by module that's a new economy
thank you for that so um so one of the
things that that is curious is that you
know the the survey of the research
talks about mostly about you know
old-school healers but then you know the
the last section of the paper really
focuses on free de lijn and and it's
kind of like once removed right because
people have not been doing organized
studies on root balls in modern time but
free de lijn which is in the root ball
there has been research taking place and
so under under that flag would you talk
a little bit about how free de lijn
impacts both cardiac activity and
estrogenic activity sure
so yeah with estrogenic activity this is
still an area that more research is
needed but because there were the
mentions of cannabis root being used
orally during pregnant Ursaring
to help with childbirth and bleeding we
were trying to figure out some rationale
why that would be and so we found a
little bit of evidence that Freda lien
may have some estrogenic activity when
it's been isolated from other plants and
this one plant that's really rich and
free Deline sorry well I butcher the
name Sissis Quan drag ulis I'm not
actually sure what this plant is but
it's an edible plant found in hotter
parts of India and West Africa and this
plant is documented in err Veda for its
medicinal use in goat syphilis venereal
disease and also as an aphrodisiac and
it's really rich in free Deline
and then there's also another plant
where Frida lien was isolated and they
did some work with rat models where MIT
didn't have their ovaries and they found
that the free Deline
section when they fed this to the
animals and improved their sexual
behavior and they found that this was
related to estrogen activity with an
increase in uterine weight and arise in
serum estrogen so again these are very
preliminary studies but it hints that
there could be something more going on
and then the other one oh you brought up
was the cardiac activity yeah so this
again was another place we had a bit of
issues with because there is some
confusion where there was a report in
the Journal of American Medical
Association JAMA thinking that the
cannabis roots might be an issue and so
the way we spun it was throughout
history there's no mentions of any
cardiac activity in cannabis roots but
then there's this 1971 report in the
Medical Journal and so I'll just read
what we wrote it says in 1971 Roger
published an account in JAMA
recollecting his physician uncle using
Indian hemp roots to treat edema in 1931
and then this prompted an investigation
later on by this other researcher who
infused cannabis roots with whiskey into
guinea pig hearts and what happens is
the heart rates dropped from 240 to 60
so they're saying oh this caused the
heart to go slower and so they were kind
of concerned about this and then but the
issue is that we think or Ethan thought
anyway that Roger made this account from
1971 he may have mistaken the cannabis
root for Indian hemp which is another
plant because that this other plant does
have some heart related issues and so
anyway the long story short we concluded
that this report was likely untrue and
there actually is no actual toxicity of
cannabis roots and then again this sort
of confusion is avoidable by using
proper or Latin names so
again this stuff needs to be clarified
and more research needs to be done and
even making sure that there are no
dangers but throughout history in the
quotes we didn't come across any
mentions of cannabis and heart issues so
it's so exciting though right because
like it's almost like we're finding
another cannabis plant like we love
cannabis we love all the oils that we
can get out of the trichomes and and
we're just beginning the research on
that and then all of a sudden now we're
talking about root balls with an entire
different set of active compounds and
it's like oh wow look there's you know
what there's nine different sections in
the paper and it's like wow there's
there's tons of room for research in
each of the nine second in each of the
nine sections it just opens it up so so
this is a call out to all you citizen
scientists out there to to get on it
after the break we're gonna talk about
how to do some of these preparations
with as much of instruction as we can
pull out of Natasha so stay with us
we're gonna take a short break and be
right back you're listening to shaping
fire and my guest today is cannabis
health researcher and Natasha rizz if
you grow cannabis with sunshine you can
often feel limited by the seasonal cycle
you want to grow sustainably and save
money so you use as little electricity
as possible but if you haven't studied
or implemented light deprivation
techniques into your greenhouse you're
leaving a lot of money on the table by
incorporating light deprivation
solutions into your greenhouse you can
often add two or three additional
growing cycles to your year when you
pencil out the financial benefit of
those additional cycles you'll realize
why commercial scaled light deprivation
technology is remaking the cannabis
industry
what used to be done by pulling tarps
over hoop houses has been scaled up over
the last few years in such a way that
has become mechanized easy and
affordable to even small-scale
commercial cannabis operations forever
flowering greenhouses is the industry
leader in light deprivation greenhouse
design and operation for the commercial
cannabis industry their team of
greenhouse experts have been in the
fields of Northern California for
decades and they're now building
greenhouses for commercial cannabis
companies across the country if you are
new to light deep and growing in
greenhouses I encourage you to go back
to shaping fire episode 13 with gas
Eric Branstad up forever flowering I
talked with Eric about the importance of
intelligent greenhouse management as
well as the huge financial benefit of
incorporating light depth techniques
there are so many aspects of utilizing a
greenhouse that can go wrong from
temperature and airflow to light DEP and
workflow forever flowering will help you
produce crop after crop of
well-cared-for flowers they can help you
retrofit your existing greenhouse with
light depth and other modern systems at
a level that fits your budget if you're
just starting out forever flowering can
help you plan and build your new
greenhouse so that you get started on
the right foot
the cannabis business has enough risks
without trying to go it alone with your
greenhouse contact forever flowering
greenhouses to partner with folks who
have an indisputable reputation as
knowledgeable and easy to work with go
to shaping fire com ford slash FFG to
find out more if you like podcasts like
shaping fire chances are that you'll
like audiobooks too just like with
podcasts audiobooks speak to you tell
you stories and teaches stuff here's the
thing audible.com has an offer that I
want to tell you about right now they
are offering a trial of their audiobook
service for absolutely free you can go
to shaping feiyr.com forward slash
audible and you'll get a free audiobook
straight up you can listen to it on your
mobile device computer or download it
and listen to it you know like anywhere
it's really simple of course they want
you to subscribe to their service after
the free trial and enjoy audiobooks
forever but you don't have to all you
have to do to get the free audiobook of
your choice is to just check out the
service for free and the service is
pretty great there are whole sections on
permaculture sci-fi history biography
hell you can even listen to a book about
card counting in blackjack and whatever
it's all pretty rad so that's the deal
your first book is free it's easy to
sign up it's easy to quit and their
online library of free ebooks is pretty
incredible so just check it out go to
shaping feiyr.com forward slash audible
to find out more or just click on the
link in this week's newsletter welcome
back you're listening to shaping fire
and I'm your host Shango Louis and our
guest this week is cannabis health
researcher Natasha rizz so you know so
far in the show we have talked about why
the root
all is so healthy and all the different
ways that healers of all sorts have been
using it you know where they live over
the years but you know there's not
really a lot of information in the
archives of how they actually made the
preparations so I know that I'm gonna be
asking you questions Natasha that you
are probably haven't been provided
answers for but but you know we all know
that that after growers are hearing the
show that they're gonna be doing some
experimentation with root balls come
this fall because you know who wouldn't
and so I want to go through four of the
preparations that are talked about in
your paper and just give me the best you
know the best information that you have
gleaned and I understand that there's
going to be some some vacuum there and
and we'll just tell people to try it so
so here so here here are a handful of
questions that you may not know the
answer to so so the main one that I was
attracted to is the decoction by boiling
and you know the idea of boiling
something that seems easy enough but but
just generally I'm curious from you you
know when you boil it do you cut it up
into slices first how much water might I
use how long might I boil it and then
when I'm done do I want to reduce the
water so that the the finished liquid
agent is actually more dense yeah those
are all great questions and I I'm
anticipating there's gonna be so many
interesting concoctions coming up of
different ways to prepare them so the
ways that we've tried is first off
cutting the roots is very difficult
we had like they're very hard and so I
still haven't figured out the best way
to process them into pieces so at this
point in time we've just been breaking
them as best we can
I've also heard someone suggest putting
them in liquid nitrogen and then
crushing them that way would be a good
way to try it but I haven't played
someone with on so that might be the
solution to that issue
and then basically putting as much water
and root together I mean the more the
better to just you have to like even a
one to one if it possible and so again
when you're making water extractions
there's issues of microbial or bacterial
or mold growth because as soon as you
have water and a compound the shelf
stability isn't as great so that's one
of the reasons I haven't played as much
with the water extractions but I think
if you were gonna do a water extraction
you would wanna like you said
concentrate it down after and so that
there was reports of people doing that
where they would take other roots in the
water
I mean chopped or is chopped up as you
could get them and then infuse that in
the water and then again what are the
proper temperatures what is the proper
timeline I can't give much suggestion to
that except the throat history it was
boiling so I'm guessing it's gonna be a
heavier boil I don't know what the I'd
have to look into what the exact
temperature timepoints for compounds
like free tooling and those things to
potentially be breaking down I'm not
sure what that is but and then you'd
also have to experiment with how long
are you boiling it for because when a
lot of people make their even like their
cannabis flower infusions
in coconut oil or something sometimes
they're cooking that for a 30-minute
infusion or they're doing a three-day
infusion right so I think depending on
the length of infusion you're gonna do
you're gonna extract four compounds and
again there's water extractions there's
fat extractions and then I haven't
experimented with alcohol extractions
yet but I think that's gonna be a really
nice way to bring out both the fat and
the water soluble compounds from the
roots and then yeah I think once you get
either your root powder or your root
extract or the water or the fat
extraction or your boiling that down
after you've done the water extraction
to get really like a gum tar resin then
I think that will be your your comp
that you're then gonna have to
incorporate into other bases so like
your base cream for instance and like
when working with cannabinoids there's
many different things you have to
consider when you're putting making
topicals and a big one is absorption so
with the fat soluble cannabinoids a lot
of them stay in the surface of the skin
and that's why a lot of people like them
is because they don't go systemically
but there's also permeation enhancers
and compounds you can add to your blends
that can help boost absorption and maybe
get some of these compounds into your
body and systemically so of course when
you're making these hemp or the cannabis
root concoctions and you're putting them
into your final blend and those are
things you'll have to consider is do you
want this blend to stay on the surface
of your skin or do you want it to absorb
into your skin and so that will depend
what kind of formulation you put and
then again you're also gonna have to
consider what kind of what's your target
for this for this formula are you is it
for a soar is it for a burn is it for
inflammation and pain is it for just you
know a hand cream because your hands are
dry because then that will depend again
what kind of blend you're gonna put
together and how you're gonna I always
like to think of who my end user is
before I make a formula just because if
it's nice it smells good it absorbs good
but it's not for the right application
no one's gonna use it so I think the
same thing with the roots is there's
many different ways to prepare it and
then again are you gonna make like if
you're concerned about drug testing and
having THC in these compounds
um the roots are nice because they
wouldn't test for THC or any of these
other compounds so you might want to
just make your root blends alone or if
you want them to work even better I
would add the cannabis flowers in there
too because of course the cannabinoids
and teepsy CBD those are going to make
everything work
a bit better for topicals especially so
yeah so we talked about that trying to
think oh yeah oh I I think it's um I
I've just realized while you were
talking that I'm gonna have to find a
lab that actually tests for free Toulon
because I bet you that my you know my
local cannabis lab that's probably not
one that they're checking for all the
time I'm gonna have to check in with
them and find somewhere because now I'm
gonna you know I'm I'm devising these
little citizen science tests that I want
to do myself this fall with the root
balls and I bet you that I'm not going
to be the only one so let's let's talk
about pull test a little bit so we got
the decoction by boiling pretty clearly
you know poultice I think the only time
I ever actually come across that anymore
is like in like survival movies you know
where you know some some ancient you
know Yoda heal or you know take some
some you know moss or something off the
ground and then they littered against
this and then it's magically healed in
the next scene you know I'm so but but
you know how would you actually make a
poultice out of the the root ball um so
a poultice is basically just like a mash
of herbs that you're putting together in
something like like cheesecloth or one
of those like even just like a
tablecloth like a cloth that the liquid
can then permeate through and so it
would be similar to how you're doing
like even what you could do is you could
put a root mass in there and kind of
close it off and like a dish cloth tie
it up at the top and then you could like
boiled out in water and then that
poultice you could then remove it kind
of squeeze out the excess and then put
it on topically so that would be more
for like spot treatments like say you
had a rule ankle or your knee was
hurting or you had a wound somewhere
then you'd want like and a poultice
isn't necessarily the most it's the word
like convenient because it's a big
massive plant you're in this concoction
that you have to hold on to your thing
so it's more of a home treatment I guess
but what's cool about again with the
poultice you can combine other herbs and
other plants so again what your and who
your end user is and what the condition
is will depend on what herbs and what
plants you put together when you make
your poultice it sounds like one of the
common issues amongst all of these is
just breaking down the root right to get
it to you know to either cut it or mash
it or or put it on the cheese grater or
whatever you're gonna do getting it smut
into smaller pieces is going to be the
the challenge the the next one that's in
the paper is pulverized and mixed with
wine so tell us a little bit about how
that would look yeah so I haven't
experimented with that one at all but
I'm guessing it would be similar to
getting and again we could talk about
are we talking about older roots are we
talking about younger root because I
think there's another whole spectrum of
playing with the root and trying to
figure out different medical
applications because if you're using an
early root I mean we'd have to look at
how these different compounds are
developing because they're not even
really saying in the papers like how old
the root was when it was analyzed so if
we were using younger root it would be
easier to break up and mash and make
some of these concoctions but maybe it
doesn't have the compounds you're
looking for whereas the older root might
be harder to work with but might have a
different profile of compound so again
those types of analysis need to be done
and alcohol why would be a nice
extraction basis because it can bring
out all the fat soluble and the water
soluble compounds and it doesn't have
the risk of microbial like bacteria or
mold growth to the same extent that just
water does so it you can get some better
shelf stability if you're using alcohol
versus water and what wine generally
just makes everything better yeah
especially with the bitter medicine so
the last one is raw juice and I was just
imagining if if we're trying to struggle
for what to break it down what
a cannabis root ball would do to my
macerating juice or god help us but it
seems to me that maybe maybe an apple
crusher would would might be more the
appropriate tool for the job than
something in the kitchen
yeah when I saw the juice I was I was
same thing like how I don't put that in
here juicer yeah so again I'm wondering
if they're using younger roots because
they've got some more give to them
versus the older roots which would I
mean I don't think they were using
juicers back in the ancient maybe though
but yeah that one I haven't played with
it also
that's readers please give me your her
listeners please let me know how that
one goes yeah totally I think that's one
of the great things about both your
paper and the show today is really this
is not a show about having all the
answers this is about this is a show
about all the new questions and I think
that's really exciting thanks so much
for joining me on this show today
Natasha this is really groundbreaking
work and I bet you there's a lot of
people who are listening who are as
excited to play with root balls as I am
now yeah and I'm really excited to hear
about all these experiments and I'm
excited to see how people come up with
some new treatments and oh is harnessing
the cannabis plant to help us right on
so so if you want to read the paper you
can go ahead and go to the shaping
feiyr.com website there's a link to the
paper right there on the page for this
podcast episode and you could also find
out more information on Natasha rizz at
WWE is Remi calm and that's our y'see
r.e.m Icom and also Natasha is really
present on Twitter and you can follow
her on Twitter at at RIT so that's T a
sh ry z you can find more episodes of
the shaping fire podcast and subscribe
to the show at shaping fire calm and on
Apple iTunes stitcher and Google Play if
you enjoyed the show we'd really
appreciate
if you leave a positive review of the
podcast wherever you download your
review will help others find the show so
they can enjoy it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the weekly newsletter for
insights into the latest cannabis news
and product reviews on the shaping fire
website you will also find transcripts
of today's podcast as well for
information on me and where I will be
speaking you can check out Shango lows
calm your company want to reach our
national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hotspot at shaping
fire calm to find out how thanks for
listening to shaping fire I've been your
host Shango lows
[Music]