[Music]
foreign
to a lot of roots reggae when I was in
my early 20s being a stoner in school
generally meant that there was a lot of
Reggae around but in my early 20s I
discovered the band Israel Vibration
specifically and everything changed
there are many other bands in The Roots
reggae genre but for me Israel Vibes is
the quintessential Roots band for me
anyway Israel Vibration embodies the
essence of roots reggae through their
messages of spirituality social
Consciousness and Liberation their use
of Rich Melodies uplifting chord
progressions and melodic horn
Arrangements further contribute to their
quintessential Roots reggae sound
they address themes such as African
identity Babylonian system criticism the
struggle of the oppressed and the
importance of faith and perseverance
Israel vibrations lyrics resonate with
the poetic nature of roots reggae
encapsulating the struggles and hopes of
the Jamaican people
surely I listen to lots of the popular
reggae at the time and these themes
imbue most reggae but I didn't
understand the authentic roots and
meaning of Reggae in my soul until I
listened to Israel vibrations
similarly we can talk about the
importance of cannabis Roots a thriving
rhizosphere and root Zone and the love
of a thick mass of healthy plant roots
but only when we really lean into Roots
culture cannabis root science well we
have both the heart and the knowledge to
grow our best cannabis plants ever
if you want to learn about cannabis
Health cultivation and technique
efficiently and with good cheer I
encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter we'll send you new podcast
episodes as they come out delivered
right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week and
videos too don't rely on social media to
let you know when a new episode is
published sign up for the updates to
make sure you don't miss an episode also
we're giving away very cool prices for
folks who are signed up to receive the
newsletter there's nothing else you need
to do to win except receive that
newsletter so go to shapingfire.com to
sign up for the newsletter this week and
be entered into this month's and all
future newsletter prize drawings
you are listening to shaping fire and
I'm your host shangolos
my guest today is plant biologist Sarah
Lane
Sarah Lane is wrapping up her PhD in
plant and cellular biology at University
of Victoria her work primarily focuses
on root exudates that are involved in
Iron uptaken plants and their potential
medical benefits Sarah consults for
licensed cannabis cultivators in Canada
and is an avid living soil cannabis home
grower due to her University Research
needs she is also very experienced in
fog panics and hydroponics
Sarah has a wicked large Plant
collection and is currently designing a
specialty terrarium for growing Cloud
orchids
Sarah Lane appeared on shaping fire 99
just a few episodes back talking about
the symbiotic relationship between roots
and other residents in the root Zone via
exudates
during the first set today we will look
at how roots and root hairs are created
how they absorb nutrients the exudate
relationship and how different
fertilizers impact the root Zone
the second set is devoted to root
structure we will look at the various
forms of root structure in soil cocoa
and hydroponic systems and why they work
and don't work
we will look at the relationship between
root structure and the soil food web and
we will discuss how various growing
containers impact root structure and
what that means for your plant and
finally we will finish off with a
discussion of best practices for growing
a healthy and thriving root structure
including water PH soil amendments and
cover crops welcome back to shaping fire
Sarah
thanks for having me I'm happy to be
back so glad to have you you know I
don't usually ask guests back right away
but our discussion of root exudates
during episode 99 just brought up so
many root related questions for myself
and then in the comments online that I
just knew that it was probably better to
just invite you back right away and push
forward into our discussion of roots and
root structure so so thanks for making
the time to come back right away
I'm so excited so let's let's dive right
into it and we're going to start out
with some Basics because it's become
pretty obvious
um over the years I've taken questions
from audience members and and you know
the people who I talk with at
conventions that there's a lot of us in
cannabis cultivation that kind of take
roots for granted and so we're going to
start with some basics of what Our Roots
and and how they form so so let's start
with the ultra basic what are Roots made
of and how are they formed by the plant
oh goodness
um so roots
optically an old chicken of the plant
that are made up of a couple of
different types of tissue there's a
vascular tissue to help transport water
up into the nutrients up into the rest
of the plant it's surrounded by some
other tissues that can kind of respond
to the environment there's an epidermis
layer that kind of acts like a skin
around the whole thing to prevent like
microbes and things like that from
getting in and the purpose of a root is
basically to provide anchorage so that
the plant stays put and can survive wind
and all that kind of stuff but it's also
for um for getting nutrients into the
plant
my understanding is that there are
different types of roots um I you know
there's there's like the primary Roots
the big chunky parts that we can see but
then they they seem to have like smaller
and smaller branching Roots all the way
down to the roots root hairs how many
different flavors of roots are there oh
so many so many flavors it also depends
on the type of species so very broadly
the type of root system that you can
have depends on what species you are and
like for I think for most angiosperms so
those are the flowering plants um they
get split up into like roots that can
form from a Tap Root and then roots that
are fibrous and a Tap Root basically
just means that the plant will make one
big long root that goes down in lots of
lots of roots will come off of that a
fibrous root system is kind of like it's
closer to the stem and it's it's they're
not as long they're kind of just lots
and lots but there's also many other
plants that don't even have a true root
system that have like kind of root like
structures and then when we get into
just like a regular root ball that we're
familiar with so like a house plant root
ball for example there's the primary
root but
these can get split up into other like
branching lateral roots that kind of
move away from the root into other parts
of the soil and then from there you can
have
um I guess root tears would be the next
option it's just like a single celled
little root hair that sits at just a
very short amount of distance from the
root itself and that helps kind of pull
up some more nutrients in the area
so let's talk about that Taproot for a
moment um since we are talking about the
roots specifically for our favorite
cannabis plant
um you know it's it comes up all the
time people will say this just kind of
off the cuff they will say
um you know they prefer to grow from
seed because they want to grow a plant
with a Tap Root because when we clone
cannabis plants the Clones when we plant
them don't have tap Roots
um uh is there a particular reason why
clones don't have tap roots and what is
the function of the Taproot in a seed
plant that we are missing out on when we
grow a clone
oh that's a really interesting question
so I guess when we talk about the types
of root systems that a plant can have
referring to like a developmental thing
so the plant when it's in a seed is
programmed to have a Taproot root system
when we clone we're actually taking
advantage of almost a wound healing
response instead so the plant has the
ability to make cells that wouldn't
normally be Roots turn into roots to
help it survive but that isn't
necessarily how it was developmentally
designed to do so when we go to the
Taproot when you grow from a seed that
Taproot goes as far down as possible to
get as deep as possible into the Earth
and
the advantage to like having a very long
Taproot is that if you can go like
meters and meters down into the soil and
then produce lateral roots from there
then you can access so much more of the
of the ground to get your nutrients from
and if you have like a really short Tap
Root then you're probably like if you
can only go four inches down you're only
able to access that much of the soil and
so when you grow from a clone I don't
think it truly matters in the long run
because we're usually growing in pots
and pots like even if you have a tap
root system you can only get to the
bottom of the pot and then you're going
to be branching out from there but from
a clones perspective like you wouldn't
have if you were growing out in like I
don't know a field you wouldn't have
access to that same depth of nutrients
it would be harder for you to get to
that makes sense I'm going to push on
this one more time one more question
um I I love the perspective that you
shared about how a clone rooting itself
is kind of like a recovery or a first
aid event because it's been damaged and
it's repurposing other dare I say stem
cells
um but no no different different cells
in the plant to create this this root
environment
um does the plant get stabilized and
kind of shake off that
um
that that damaged First Age first aid
kind of
um living bias and like become a
thriving plant or will a clone forever
um be hobbled by the fact that it wasn't
from seed
plants can River
uh well and if you think about it they
have to they don't have feet like we do
they can't just like Wander over so a
lot of their like responses they're
constantly adapting to a new environment
and if it was wildly damaged later one
damage event like say they got flooded
or something and then they can't recover
they wouldn't survive very well so like
any wound or anything like that you can
do usually as long as you treat it
properly and it comes back to a healthy
environment you should be totally able
to recover which is often why many many
different types of plants are
vegetatively propagated including like
potatoes and all sorts of other plants
um but the idea of a stem cell plants do
actually have the ability for so many of
their cells to become stem cells unlike
us where we just have this little tiny
amount of stem cells when we're born and
there's a couple of pockets of it of
stem cells in our body that can react in
certain ways plants almost any cell can
become a stem cell that will then be
able to be any other part of the plant
that's why tissue culture works so
brilliantly right on I'm glad that I
stumbled into that Brilliance I didn't I
didn't realize that was the case I was
trying to make a pun so good thank you
no it's perfect this is a stem cell but
it's also a stem cell right on right on
oh
um so let's talk a little bit about
um the the roots job of bringing in uh
nutrients so one of the things that we
talked about in the exit 8 show that I
found so interesting is all of the
different ways that Roots
um mechanize bringing in nutrition in
different ways and you know on shaping
fire we tend to focus on living Soil
Solutions but we'll definitely be
covering you know all other types of
substrate today especially since we're
talking about Roots but for this
question what are the forms of various
nutrients that Roots can't absorb
assuming that they are threatened in
thriving living soil environment because
I'm assuming that they're gonna they're
gonna absorb like you know uh like
minerals in one certain way and maybe
fungus in a different way and you get
well I think you understand what I'm
asking
okay so if I understand
asking correctly
um how do Roots take on different types
of nutrients in the soil is that right
so there there's a bunch of different
things when we're talking about I guess
all nutrients at the end of the day can
be broken down into nitrogen or
phosphorus ions or like like basically a
salt
happens either because the plant is able
to provide some sort of chemical or
enzymatic process that can break
something down right next to it or
because some bacteria or fungus next to
it was able to do the same thing and
they could take it up that way there is
some evidence that plants can take up
nutrients as slightly larger molecules
but I think this is very species
dependent I don't think all plants can
do this
um or at least I'm not familiar with
enough papers that have shown this to be
kind of a universal thing and then when
it comes to like bacteria or mycorrhizae
or those kind of things it's it's more
of a a conversation between the the
organism and the plant and that involves
some chemical signaling and some
invitations are sent and then the plant
is able to repurpose the structure of
the root to house it so it's not
necessarily that it's actually getting
into the cell
more like it's getting a special place
in the root to grow
um your answer uh is is seems to suggest
that you know another good reason that
if we're going to be growing in soil it
really behooves us to try to make a
thriving and varied
um you know Living Root Zone because if
the roots themselves are not necessarily
breaking these different uh nutritions
down and it's their partnership with
bacteria and other types of microbes all
those friends need to be there and and
the ways that you know all the ways that
we try to create a thriving root Zone
and not and not drown them with our
water is all important if the if the
root zone is going to be able to have
the buffet that we want them to have in
their living soil
I would agree yeah for sure and the more
vibrant that Community is the better
nutrition is available and not only that
a lot of the microbes that are found in
the soil provide other benefits aside
from nutrition like competition against
um pathogens for example if you have a
lot of healthy bacteria down there then
there's less room for uh an unhealthy
bacteria to show up it might just be
stimulating the plant to make little
immune compounds because they're there
and they don't react strongly to that
particular fungus but they're aware
fungus is there and they might be more
ready there's so many things that they
provide
um I know that you do a lot of
aeroponics and so this
um this may be an unfair question to ask
you specifically for living soil and I'm
not looking for us to like plug any
manufacturers but you know as somebody
who is constantly looking at ways to
create healthier and more thriving Roots
as you do in your research are there any
inoculants or particular teas or
anything that you would recommend for
living soil people to help support this
uh thriving rhizosphere
yeah I mean so for my research I'm
generally trying to avoid the
um the presence of bacteria as best as
possible because I'm really trying to
just get at the root but I do use
compost teas a lot when um when I'm
growing at home and I I usually I don't
know in places where you can get them
there's like a nettle horsetail bracken
fern tea that you can use a lot of them
have molasses bases which is really
helpful to get certain types of bacteria
and fungus to get growing there's like
so many good recipes online it'd be hard
to plug just one but if you if you go
and and have a look at some compost tea
recipes I think the simplest ones are
the best like a little bit of of soil
that's healthy plus some sugar sources
plus some plants is usually a good start
Plus in the one that you mentioned I
mean you've got the the the
um the silica from the horse tail and
the the growth hormones from the spring
Nettles I mean that's a pretty potent
mix you just uh suggested it is yeah
yeah I guess the other one I would say
too is um it depends on the stage that
you're adding it because I I will often
when I have very young plants I'll do
like a barley tea so you soak barley for
a little while and um all the different
growth factors that allow The Barley to
sprout are then present in the liquid so
you can either buzz it up or you can
take the liquid off and and put it on
your own seedlings and it it's thought
to help grow and I do it myself right on
good clue
so um you when you were back recently uh
back when you were here the first time
uh recently on episode 99 that show was
all about exudates
um which is a is a process that the
roots bring on uh nutrients now granted
that's an hour and a half episode that
we talked about exudates and I'm gonna
ask you to summarize it just in you know
in in a short answer and because I think
it's important that folks understand
that Roots do have this exudate
relationship because it's pretty badass
but I'll I'll you know my goal is maybe
hopefully to tease people with this so
that they understand kind of what you're
talking about for this episode but then
to encourage them to go back and listen
to episode 99 so will you just briefly
uh explain how um cannabis Roots uh work
with the exudate relationship
yeah so broadly speaking exudates our
um molecules that the plant root will
make that goes outside of the root and
it it's so it's made inside the root
it's it's exported outside the root and
while it while it's out there it can do
lots of different jobs it can provide
food for microbial communities it can
help to loosen up some nutrients like we
were just talking about breakdown
nutrients and things like that nearby it
can provide some protective efforts too
to prevent I don't know like they could
be antimicrobial or antifungicidal or
something like that
um and it they're they're just a huge
broad range of of molecules that do this
job
excellent so so uh go back and listen to
episode 99 for more so um so I'm really
curious we we've already talked about
how the um the roots uh take on
um uh nutrition and
um and I believe that mostly happens at
the root hair level would you explain to
us
um in in you know kind of both that
chemical and a mechanical way what's
actually happening there at the root
hair that allows the nutrition to come
on board inside of the root
sure I mean I think for the root hair
it still kind of comes across the way
that it would come across in a lot of
other
um cells so when we're talking about
transport from inside or sorry from
outside the in the soil environment into
the root all cells are wrapped up in
this nice little membrane that has
essentially you can think of them as
like little trap doors um for nutrients
to come into the root that are regulated
so you'd have to turn on a switch for
them to come in and that happens all all
cells are doing this all the time and
that is no different in a root hair cell
the big advantage to root hairs is its
increasing absorption so if you think of
like think of how big a root is and how
visible it is you could see it it's
usually depending on how long the
plant's been growing it can be super
thick
whereas these root hairs are super super
tiny and so while the main root can plow
through the soil at a pretty good clip
the little root hairs are meant to kind
of slide in between soil particles and
increase the surface area does that make
sense yeah it does
so that's kind of their primary purpose
is to is to increase the absorption rate
and when plants are trying to choose
what kind of doors they want on their
cells the root hairs will often have a
lot of like for my work I'm interested
in how Iron gets in and those root hairs
can have more iron doors on them so that
more iron can get in on those repairs
than they might in a regular size I like
that trapdoor analogy and so there's all
these different flavors and they only
open when they are looking for the
particular nutrient that approaches it
exactly like there's a like a secret
knock or something there is yeah yeah a
little handshake
so you know cannabis cultivators often
come into contact with the roots right
like sometimes just briefly when
transplanting but other times if the
plant is root Bound in a container
um you know we might be really
aggressive with the roots like grabbing
them and ripping them and thinking that
we're getting rid of tired roots that
were compacted and and most people say
oh I'm stimulating New Growth by pulling
these uh these uh you know roots that
were compacted off and giving it more
room to breathe how careful should we be
when handling the roots because on one
hand you know because I learned it from
my mentor the the ripping apart of the
roots like makes sense because that's
what I was taught but I also constantly
hear from soil biologists that that the
roots are very sensitive and we can put
the plant into shock so I'm assuming
that the the truth of the matter is
somewhere in that range
I would agree actually so
I don't think it's wrong to think that
you are stimulating growth because just
like we were talking about earlier with
the Clone and and how that's a wound
healing response that it makes more
Roots When you damage the roots that is
definitely something a plant will
respond to and it will make more so it's
more about like hoping you don't damage
it so much that the plant is overwhelmed
I think like roots are very sensitive so
as soon as you take them out of the pot
they're being exposed to light they
weren't expecting or touching them a lot
of those finer structures like the root
hairs that are so so small and fragile
like they're only a single cell thick so
like you're definitely destroying those
and it will definitely take the plant
some time to recover from that I think
it it depends on the type of plant that
you're working with well specifically
cannabis yeah but there's gonna be a
certain amount of cannabis plants that
are very sturdy but there might also be
more sensitive plants that maybe don't
grow as well you mean specific like what
we call strains or varieties not
different species entirely
yeah I mean I like I I grow a lot of
plants so I would say species too but if
we're talking strictly about cannabis
different cultivars are definitely going
to have
um different figure and so in a plant
that has a lot of vigor you're probably
okay to maybe manhandle the the pot a
little bit more
um but in a plant that's very sensitive
and doesn't grow that well it's going to
be trickier and I think most of the time
I would I would say that unless the
roots are dead or diseased I would try
and keep them intact as much as possible
you can break them up a little bit like
um like when you encounter particularly
with hard-boiled pots sometimes you see
the roots kind of run around in a big
circle yeah and so you can kind of try
and loosen them up so that they'll not
break them but like try and kind of
untangle them a little bit so they might
go somewhere else fluff them a little
bit
yeah exactly so that would be okay I
mean I I try and be as gentle as
possible with my root balls but yeah
it's gonna happen regardless I think
just the extent that it happens you
might have to be careful with some
cultivars over others would it be fair
to say that if we're growing from seed
and we have a Tap Root we definitely
shouldn't mess with that just you know
if we're gonna if we're gonna trim Roots
trim you know secondary Roots don't be
touching the Taproot
yeah I think that's probably fair I I
don't know enough about what happens if
the Taproot gets super damaged whether
it would produce a new Taproot and like
how that developmentally would occur but
I think it like because it does serve
this different function than the other
roots that if you damage it too much it
it will cause changes and I don't know
whether those changes would be good or
bad and I think it would be fair to
Intuit that um you know a damage to a
Taproot would put
um you know extra undue stress on the
plant that it would have to bounce back
from and since we're all dealing with a
timed growing cycle that uh none of us
want none of us want to cause that
slowdown in growth so for for our for
our plant um we should probably just
stay away from it
time thing if you have like a mother
plant that's meant to be in vegetative
growth for a very long time
and it'll never get flipped over into
flour
um you might have different choices to
make so for example it gets root bound
because it's growing so long and maybe
you don't have a bigger pot so you kind
of have to do some pruning above and
then some pruning below and like those
are choices you would have to make with
a with a mother plant and how much or
how little you do of it would probably
again depend on the cultivar when we're
dealing with like a plant that's about
to go into flower and it's only got a
certain amount of time that's where you
really don't want to damage the roots
too much because they don't have enough
time and all the time that it's going to
spend recovering is time that's not
necessarily going to be put towards
yield so in like a in a yield situation
absolutely you definitely don't want to
be you know making that plant suffer too
much awesome that's a great delineation
thank you so what biology determines if
the roots well you know how like when
you go to transplant when you when you
pull it out of the pot sometimes it's
got those like bright white like pearly
white teeth beautiful
um roots and then and and then sometimes
it'll be like you know somewhere between
a little more beige or gray and then
you've got roots that are just like you
know sad
um is is it just our guesstimate that
um that the white roots are the most
thriving is that the ideal or are lots
of different roots of different colors
perhaps just different kinds of roots
because when I see the bright white
Roots I'm all like hell yeah I'm doing
good and and when I see the beige ones
I'm like oh I'm not I'm not you know
treating this pot right in some way but
like I I really don't know I just made
that up
oh what an interesting question
okay so the roots like all of the root
is important I I totally agree I love
seeing those little white root tips and
in aeroponics sometimes they're a little
fuzzy because those little little hairs
they are adorable and they only occur
usually pretty close to the root tip um
because then they die off and then the
plant has other like that's where you
might see a lateral root form or
something passed there
um so the white tips are the actively
growing parts of the root which I think
is why we love them so much and we're
like Yay we've got a lot of white
growing areas but the rest of the roots
still super important and the Browning
isn't necessarily because of
um bad things so oftentimes what will
happen is different chemistry happens at
the tip of the root compared to the the
older root plants might put down for
example more tannins or protective
molecules that that will change the
color of the root but that's because the
function of the older root is different
if that kind of makes some sense too it
does yeah so when we see those kind of
Browner Roots at the at the you know
closer to the stem that's just because
the function has started shifting and so
the chemistry of the root has started
shifting
um and like it would be hard to pinpoint
exactly what is happening there for a
given cultivar but that's generally
what's happening the ones where it's
scary is when there is a
black root tip I guess like if that
black black or dark brown or or those
kind of colors are happening at the very
tip of the root particularly in cannabis
because its root tips are white I do
work with some plants that have a whole
bunch of different colors in there but
in cannabis specifically the white tip
um if that's starting to Brown or
anything like that you might have a
bacterial problem so yeah it just
depends on where it's happening I guess
so so let's say not quite as
um bad as that black tipped pathogen
version which sounds like a horror movie
to me
um uh is there is there any way for us
to identify Roots during transplanting
that we should shave off because you
know historically I would shave off a
bunch of those beige ones if I saw them
and now I know that I that was probably
not well thought because uh perhaps the
the plant is creating tannins in those
regions for
um you know Safety and Security reasons
and I just like cut them off is is there
any way for for us to recognize roots
that are are a damaged part of the
system that should be shaved off
I think you can kind of think about it
I guess the other part is
um there's a connection between the
roots and the shoots where like there's
usually certain routes that service
particular parts of the plant above so
it's really hard for us like looking in
the pot as we're trying to transplant to
be able to determine like oh this Branch
I cut off here are these roots here so
these ones can go so I think it is a bit
of guesswork
um but like if they're if they're like
particularly dry looking like they're
kind of shriveled
um and uh when a when a root is like
full of water they're kind of I don't
know what the best word to describe it
would be but they're almost like plump
you know like they they have they have
like kind of a juicy look and um if
they're on healthy or dead oftentimes
they'll be quite thin like a thread
almost and so maybe like the thready
ones you can get rid of a little bit
more easily but it is a lot of its
guests work and I don't have a firm
answer for you as to which part would be
I usually for myself I I look for as a
as we were just talking about kind of
like the Browner root tips that might be
experiencing some bacterial effects or
something like that but but there can be
good good bacterial effects too so I I
generally just try and do my best guess
right on I always had a better answer
well no that that is pretty good because
what I took from it is that if you see
roots that are particularly emaciated
and they visually look thin and like
they're not carrying water that
um perhaps those can be removed but
generally speaking we want everything in
the root Zone if we don't see like a
black or colorful tip on it so just uh
give give your roots a light fluff and
then go into the bigger pot and and just
don't think you have to Touch The Roots
When You're transplanting don't assume
that that's going to be part of your
transplanting process only do it if um
uh if you actually see visual problems I
I think that's a pretty fair statement
yeah and that's or at least that's what
I do and I know lots of people have
different philosophies and what the best
solution is but I think for getting your
plants to recover quickly from
transplant like as little damage as
possible and as as you say like if they
look emaciated and they're really sad
looking Roots like maybe trim those off
but otherwise a little fluffle do you
right on you know one of the one of the
interesting you said you know
everybody's got their own philosophy and
and you know that's true and there are
there are different ways to have
different philosophies within actual
science but I think when it comes to
cannabis we've all been taught so much
like Bro Science by our mentors and then
from friends that
um like if if anybody should be
decreasing the number of justifiable
philosophies it's it's our community
because we have so much bad information
to root out of our community first and
then once all that bad information is
gone then people can like find different
parts of of you know that the remaining
area to you know count as their
particular technique or philosophy but
um I don't know I kind of I kind of
think that that that we we haven't had
access to proper science scientists
analytics and research folks for the
last you know 40 years that um that you
know us all trying to kind of bring the
techniques all towards the center which
has actually got a scientific basis is
probably a pretty good set for all of us
oh I agree and I think um I think that
there's there's all these little habits
that we do that we don't really question
and those I I like to question myself
too
um and as you say there's a lot of myths
and legends about exactly what type of
thing you should do at what time and
things like that so I I think there's a
lot of tried and true methods that have
worked for people for a long time
um but I do agree that bringing things
around to like a scientific perspective
and not just doing it because someone
told you to do it
um which is kind of ironic can be giving
advice about this but you know like
think about it you know yeah so um I've
got two more questions before we go to
the break now in this in the third set
we're gonna be talking a lot about you
know the care and feeding of a thriving
root structure so that we can have the
best one available but
um but before we go to the set break I
want to talk about things that degrade
Ruth root growth and uh two two
different categories specifically are
there particular
amendments inputs or fertilizers that
can degrade root growth that we should
avoid in cannabis plants
oh interesting I think this is a this is
a more of a conversation of a mount or
like what the state is because this can
happen when you're building a soil but
it can also happen when you're feeding
fertilizer like if it's too I guess
quote unquote hot is the term that we
end up throwing around a little bit
um that can be a problem and most of the
time I would argue it's because
um particularly with fertilizers it's
probably because of pH or something like
that where it's like they're just the
poor little root is getting flooded and
I think it also happens more with
certain limiting nutrients like nitrogen
where the plant is less less able to
close the trapdoor for example nitrogen
is almost always like all the trapdoors
are open all the time because there's
not enough of it so if you flood your
root system with too much nitrogen
it builds up but the way that plants
convert what we feed them to a usable
form of nitrogen to them all the
intermediates between fertilizer and
usable nitrogen are toxic so they'll
start killing the cells off if there's
too much of it
um and I think
with soil if it's not well mixed it can
actually heat up in not just hot doesn't
like too much nutrients but as in like
temperature hot and obviously if your
root zone is like 60 70 80 degrees
you're going to have a hard time
surviving in those kind of conditions
too so I'd like your example about if if
we have uh too much fertilizer in a
particular place that it kind of um jams
the trap doors open and and kind of
force feeds the plant to its detriment
um that's the same description that
people
um use when describing you know bottled
salt nutrients about how it Force feeds
the plant is that what's happening like
at the root level is that the um the the
you know the synthetically prepared
um fertilizer is essentially breaking
down the doors and and going in through
the roots of more nutrition than the
root Zone would normally let in
yeah so especially with I think it's
more dangerous with
um with like synthetic or bottled
fertilizers because it's so concentrated
um and it's in such an available form
the plant doesn't have to do any work so
it just does flood into the root system
and as um as I was just mentioning it
like it's not so much that the nitrogen
itself is toxic it's that in order to be
able to turn it into something usable it
goes through a toxic stage so then the
Roots can't it's just too much they
can't do that process quick enough to
avoid all the toxic effects of that
process it actually can happen with
really rich composts too it just I think
at least in my personal opinion it's
harder to do because a lot of those
composts still need some breaking down
so it's a little bit slower but if you
dump like pure compost at the root zone
of a particularly sensitive plant that
isn't capable of taking it all up it'll
start to do similar things yeah right on
okay and then uh the last one is how
about pesticides because you know sure
we we apply the pest herbicides usually
fully or up top but we know that through
you know watering and just a regular
biology of the plants either the
pesticides will drip down to the soil or
the plant will take it in and move those
chemicals
um you know whether or not they be
synthetic or you know organic they're
going to move them around the plant
um are there any pesticides that we
would want to avoid because they too
degrade root growth
I mean I have a personal bias against
this because I don't generally like to
use pesticides I think that when you
apply I guess it depends very much on
the type of pesticide you're referring
to because a lot of them have toxic
effects if they're in too high of a
quantity and it actually can be both the
naturally sourced ones and also the
synthetically prepared ones like if you
put too much mint oil on your plants and
turn the lights on like those those poor
little guys are fried
um but with the pesticides like on
they're still able to take some up
through the foliar system but depending
on what mechanism the pesticide is
supposed to work by
um I don't know if it would degrade the
root particularly but it might have the
ability to affect the growth like if
it's acting like a growth regulator or
um or it's got a heavy metal component
to it or something like that I'm sure
that it can be taken out by the plant
and if it doesn't have a way to deal
with it and it's toxic in higher
quantities that will probably happen in
the plant just like it would in any
other system it's interesting we keep on
coming back to balance you know it's
like it's like hey you've got a lot of
different options for how to cultivate
your plant But whichever one you do do
it properly and not so much that you
knock your root system out of balance
yeah for sure and like I think
particularly with pesticides I don't
know if I would be like I'm not
personally aware of any pesticide that
if you watered it in at the amounts that
you would spray it it would cause a huge
amount of damage I think if you did that
you'd probably be killing it above as
well but it might affect the root
Community too like if you're adding an
antimicrobial or an antifungal agent to
the top and then it drips into the roots
I think you'd be affecting the root
Community more than you'd be affecting
the plant which of course does affect
the plant eventually yeah yeah for sure
I have to be careful with that myself
because one of my favorite
um uh well I I think of it as a
pesticide but really it's it's more
about
um discouraging pests
um I really like a a garlic fermented
plant juice on on the uh you know
sprayed foliar during
uh during veg because
um you know it no no like aphids is my
big problem where I live they just don't
want to live there they don't like they
don't like the experience for what you
know whatever smell taste reason and so
but but if if I put too much of that
onto the plant and it soaks down into
the substrate well garlic also has
antimicrobial
um uh aspects of it and and I don't want
that happening in the root Zone
absolutely yeah I think I think it as
you say it's about a balance so if you
if you just have to be careful
especially when you're trying to alter
something that's happening to the plant
in a way that doesn't affect the plant
too it just gets I don't know it's
sometimes it's subtle yeah well the more
we get into the cultivation specifics uh
it is more and more subtle right it's
like when you first start growing
cannabis it's like oh you know just put
the seed in the ground and it grows and
then at the end you got some weed but
then you like want more yield and better
weed and healthier plants and you want
to keep more floor plans and that's
where the subtleties come as as we get
you know more and more in love with this
uh way to express ourselves so right on
so let's go ahead and take our first
short break and be right back you are
listening to shaping fire and my guest
today is plant biologist Sarah Lane and
you know without these advertisers
shaping fire would not happen so please
support them and let them know you heard
about them on shaping fire
[Music]
as cannabis regulations become more
demanding and consumers become more
educated it is increasingly important to
avoid the use of chemical pesticides
when cultivating cannabis beneficial
insects have been used for decades by
the greenhouse vegetable and ornamental
plant industry and today many cannabis
cultivators are moving from sprays and
chemicals to beneficial insects
copert has the beneficial insects mites
and nematodes microbials sticky cards
and air distribution units you need to
partner with nature to defend your
garden
whether you manage Acres of canopy or
have a simple grow tent in your home
corporate is ready to help answer your
questions and help you transition away
from chemical sprays towards clean and
natural solutions
since 1967 corporate has assisted
growers in identifying pests and
devising reliable Solutions while
providing healthy insects and mites that
will protect your yield
since the 1990s covert has been a leader
in cannabis Pest and Disease Control
worldwide and have highly trained
Consultants to assist you in Canada and
the United States from coast to coast
with their Global Network of grower
support covert can help visit copper.com
choose your country and get detailed
information that's covert
k-o-p-p-e-r-t.com for the most
up-to-date cannabis related biological
control information you can also check
their Instagram at covert Canada
you know getting away from pesticides is
good for health and good for business
and culprit is ready to help visit
coppert.com today
[Music]
there are so many seed banks nowadays
that you really have options and who to
choose not only that if you pick the
wrong seed bank you could be in for a
really sketchy ride and that's only one
of the reasons I recommend Gas Lamp
seeds to my friends and listeners who
are looking for a seed bank you probably
already know Gas Lamp seeds as hembra
genetics hembra recently changed their
name to Gaslamp seeds
Gaslamp seeds is not just another seed
bank Gaslamp is a female operated
Boutique cannabis genetics provider that
only sells thoughtfully curated seeds
from the top names in cannabis breeding
with over 60 breeders and over a
thousand strains to choose from you will
certainly find something you'll love Gas
Lamp seeds has something for everyone
with over 650 feminized strains 300
regular varieties and over 200
autoflowers to choose from names you
know you can trust like compound
genetics Humboldt Seed Company Night Owl
in-house fast buds gnome automatics and
ethos
and we both know that there are other
seed banks who will take your money but
have no customer service I invited
Gaslamp to advertise on shaping fire
after hearing so many good stories about
them from my friends they have a Plus
customer service with Lightning Fast
Response times
in most cases Helene and Caitlin will
get your order out the same day you
place it most seed banks are simply not
this organized or interested in getting
your seeds to you so fast but Gas Lamp
seeds cares you even get free seeds with
every order
Helene and Caitlin get it they have been
in the Cannabis growing scene for over a
decade want some extra freebies use the
code shaping fire all one word at
checkout and they will give you an
additional set of Gaslamp provided
freebies that's an extra thirty dollars
in free seeds
buy seeds from good folks who will send
you great seeds reliably every time
visit
gaslampseeds.com today that's Gaslamp
seeds
[Music]
you've heard me talk about the
award-winning cannabis seeds that come
from the analytical breeding program of
Seth and Eric Crawford who founded
Oregon CBD seeds in fact Seth was a
guest on shaping fire in 2020 to talk
about triploid genetics
Seth and Eric are now releasing high THC
seeds for home Growers and Farms as grow
the revolution seeds at GTR seeds.com
their high THC seeds are extraordinary
in that they will start to flower at 16
and a half hours of daylight instead of
the typical 14 and a half hours of
daylight that means in most regions your
plants will start to flower outdoors in
the middle of July instead of the middle
of August which means these photo period
plants finish in September and not
October totally upending the photo
period Seed Market
Seth and Eric took their prized early
flowering CBG line and bred it to some
of the most desired verified genetics
out there including Sour Diesel triangle
Kush wedding cake chem dogs Skittles and
others these crosses all Express
powerful photo period terpene profiles
and THC giving you a great High GTR
seeds has a new thcv line with plants
like double Durbin and Gigantor that
boast one-to-one THC to thcv and people
want that thcv
GTR seeds are very consistent true
growing inbred f1s from stabilized
inbred parent lines these seeds are
nearly homogeneous and the plants should
all grow the same there is only one
phenotype in every pack available as
diploids and triploids Seth and Eric's
company is still family owned patient
and employee Centric and partially
powered by their two acres of solar
panels everyone can purchase these seeds
and the entire catalog of Oregon CBD
seeds at GTR seeds.com go to GTR
seeds.com today and choose something
revolutionary for your next indoor or
outdoor run welcome back you are
listening to shapingfire I am your host
shangolos and my guest today is plant
biologist Sarah Lane so during the first
set we looked at what exactly a route is
and the jobs that it does and some
things we want to avoid if we want a
thriving uh you know root Zone here in
the second set we're going to talk more
about the actual structure which is what
what the topic that was the Genesis of
me asking Sarah to come back right away
because during the exit 8 show she got
into this explanation about how
um the root structure is different in a
Coco choir and um Pete
non-soil or soilless
containers than it is in living soil and
oh I wanted to go down that path um but
we just didn't have time then and so
here we are today and we're going to go
down that in a lot of different ways so
so Sarah let's start at the top when we
when we use the phrase root structure
What specifically do we mean
I think like when I think of root
structure I think about
um the root ball itself the different
components that make up the root
structure and how that differs between
plants whether that be cultivar or
species or whatever and that's usually
like how the different components might
be arranged whether they're present or
absent
um all of that would be something I
would call Root structure
so in a typical cannabis plant what
would we expect the root structure to
look like in soil like is there you know
since since in nature it's in soil I'll
say that the the soil root structure is
the air quotes more natural one just for
the for the time being just okay let me
get away with that and uh and so what
what would we expect root structure to
look like in soil in the ground outside
okay
um well I mean we can stick with our
beautiful cannabis plant a nice big Tap
Root goes straight down as far as it
possibly can grow
um you can think of that like the
vertical axis I guess and then from that
all these lateral Roots start to grow
that kind of stick out from the main
root and they go sideways so they're
they're trying to like increase the
different places that the root can
access and then from there there might
be even more little branches and more
little branches and then at the growing
tip of the root there's a little tiny
Zone there where there's a bunch of
little root hairs that grow and they
don't live for a hugely long time
because that root is still moving places
and they so maybe like a couple of weeks
we can barely see with the naked eye and
we definitely can't see how thin they
are because they're a single cell wide
um but they they would be just in like a
little maybe I don't know a couple
centimeters long zone right there and
they would kind of bush out into the
into the soil
when I see diagrams of root structures
of different
um types of plants
um some of them go you know quickly
really deep and some
stay at the top and then some will throw
down like a Taproot and then and then
and then the rest will stay at the stop
at the top what is the architecture of
the the root system in an adult plant
are are they mostly up top where they
can support the plant from falling over
and you know get uh rain water or with a
cannabis plant are they all making this
Mad Dash for depth uh in order to create
stability that way and get you know
water that is in the soil or aquifer
um in in cannabis plants okay so we
talked about this a little bit earlier
like if it's a clone it might not get as
deep if we're talking about like in soil
uh because it doesn't necessarily have
that deep Tap Root to go driving down to
the bottom but in most cases like that
Tap Root it also anchors the plant as
well because I mean I don't know if
you've ever tried to get up some of
these weird little red carrot type weeds
in your garden you have to really Yank
on them like that tap Roots deep and
that plant is not falling over for the
most part so it does provide a lot of
Anchorage
um but I think like what we're talking
about diagrams and things like that that
we find like I think most of the time it
depends on species so for cannabis it's
it's mostly going to be on a tap root
system that's going straight down and
then it's there for water for Anchorage
for all these different things but then
all the lateral Roots Provide support
for whatever that purpose is so it's
kind of digging in there but also
increasing absorption the deeper The Tap
Root two the more likely it is to
survive things like dry out because it
can access that groundwater layer
whereas we find in a lot of plants and
here I'm not talking about cannabis
specifically but a lot of plants that
make surface Roots it's actually a very
nutrient Rich layer of the soil where
most of the organic matter sits so a lot
of the lateral Roots above are meant to
get nutrients specifically they're not
particularly good at getting water
because there's not a lot of water
usually in that layer
so earlier you mentioned that
um in um in container plants uh clearly
the Cannabis Tap Root cannot go as
deeply because it's going to be stopped
by the bottom of the pot
um other than a Tap Root that doesn't go
as deeply as it may like what other root
structure changes might we find in the
the lateral and other root structures
when they are in a container versus when
they are free-flowing in the ground
mostly I I think it would have to say
length I haven't really dissected a like
you know removed all the soil to have a
look but I would guess that because
um and I guess it does depend on the
type of pot too so for example we use uh
cloth sided pots and they're meant to be
sort of like self-pruning so we don't
get like running roots and so for us we
would end up probably seeing more and
I'm speculating here but I would expect
to see more shorter lateral roots that
are coming off that mean Taproot um and
and they probably wouldn't grow as much
but there's probably more branching and
by branching I mean like lateral and
then these little Roots Branch off of
that and some more Roots Branch off of
that kind of exactly the way a tree
looks on top but below
so what happens well you know what are
the effects of compaction on the root
structure
um you know we we talked in the first
set about
um how in a um
uh a pot bound plant how the The Roots
Run along the sides but I would think
that as a plant is getting more and more
root bound that there are other uh
changes uh that happen in the root Zone
to deal with that systemically
sometimes there's just not that much
soil and I mean I would expect the first
thing would be just like the soil
properties change so you don't have as
much water retention
um there's not as many
um like when we talk about things like
cation exchange and stuff like that
there might not be as many sites for
that to happen so that's basically the
way that soil acts like a little kitchen
cupboard if you will
um and there would be less kitchen
cupboards available for nutrients to be
retrieved from and so most of the time
when we have a super root bound plant
it's just there's not enough physical
space and soil to support that much
plant does that make sense yeah it's not
so much that the root architecture
itself may be changing although it might
it's more just it just can't support
that much root in that little space
and so then the systems will start
happening happening and efficiently and
it'll essentially just fall out of
balance and your plant will get sick in
one of many ways
yeah and it's usually like I think the
first thing I notice when when plants
are too root bound is like it's just
hard to keep them fed and watered you
have to water more often
um I've had a couple of plants that have
actually almost pushed through the
bottoms because I haven't had a chance
to get to them so the like they just
kind of push the pot out of the way
um but it it can get pretty bad and then
you end up with a root ball that just
can't sustain the amount of shoot growth
that you have
um and then and then the plant just ends
up getting super deficient and if we
wanted to relate that to something like
yield I think your yield would be
severely impacted because they just
can't put that much nutrients towards
the rest of the plant it's always a bad
scene when you find the plant that you
forgot to transplant and it's got all
the roots that are coming out of the
holes the drainage holes and you're all
like oh baby I'm so sorry I forgot I
didn't see you over there and and you
know sometimes you get lucky and it was
sitting on something else and so now
it's it's re-rooted itself in like the
pot under it or something you know yeah
which is which is always interesting but
yeah that's that's a bad day at the
office when you find that you've
neglected a plant that bad because you
know you're gonna have to cut those
roots and that's not going to be a good
day I've gotten pretty Adept at pulling
those roots out of holes partly because
of the way that I deal like my research
plants um I need them to kind of do that
so
um there's ways to untangle them very
carefully but uh but that does just go
to show you how efficient plants are at
seeking out nutrients like nothing in
this pot out we go we're going somewhere
and we don't know where it is but it
will find something somewhere to eat
yeah and you know that's a really good
point you know for for folks who are
home Growers who are you know growing
two or four or 15 plants where every
plant is important because they need to
yield their medicine for themselves
um you'll have a lot more time to kind
of you know wiggle the plant back and
forth and you know gingerly pull them up
and try to save as many of those roots
versus you know in a in a scaled
commercial or you know medical
environment where you've got you know a
hundred or a thousand plants where you
know you're just going to pull your your
knife and go you know cut cut and pull
it out and Transplant it and you know
that's that's a very different kind of
of of cultivation but it is interesting
how
um the same problem has to be solved
different ways depending on the variety
of cultivation that you're doing
absolutely yeah yeah and I think it's
it's something to mention too like like
if you have the time to try and save the
roots I think it helps we were talking
earlier about like how much root to lose
and that kind of stuff but the actively
growing roots are really the ones you
want to try and save so I do my absolute
best because those little Runners are
probably the most active as they're
trying to escape my poor little pot
situation
so so this next question is the one that
um that was that was spun off in in
episode 99 and the exudates which is
kind of the seed for this episode which
is
um you know Coco and Pete cultivation
systems have become like really popular
over the years and I and I think still
increasingly so and you know in the in
the beginning folks were using Coco
choir and Pete to supplement what we
generally think of is living soil as a
as an aeration and water retention
solution but nowadays people are just
using cocoa and Pete and they're not
even using
um you know the living soil aspect and
then they are then they are adding
nutrition into these cocoa and peat pots
with
um you know what whatever whatever kind
of fertilizer they choose from from
compost teas to to amendments to to
bottled stuff so there's there's a lot
of options with these these systems and
you had mentioned that a root structure
is going to be different in these types
of pots and and I'm super curious to
hear what the differences are
I guess that I guess when we think of
root structure we kind of have to back
up and realize that the root structure
is kind of dictated by the environment
and the needs of the plant
so like when we talk about whether
plants make a lot of lateral roots or
not like they're going to make lateral
Roots but how many depends on things
like nutrient availability or oxygen
presence absence that kind of thing
so in a soil that's very
mixed up there's like when you mix a
good soil like you it's going to be
quote unquote homogeneous to your eyes
you're going to make sure that like the
Pearl lights in there evenly there's not
a big Clump and stuff like that but on a
on like a microscopic level it's not
really there's little pockets and so
that's going to influence the plant
because it has to move towards Little
areas of nutrients
um in a system where the nutrients are
actually homogeneous when we're watering
it in and we're not necessarily
providing any other source the plant's
still going to be moving around in there
but it might it might need to act
differently
um because it doesn't have that many
different pockets in the in the soil
system and I think Hydroponics is the
most extreme of that because we can not
only can we really see the roots to look
at them
um but there there's just one place that
all of these nutrients are and they're
evenly available so I would expect to
see less branching and less root hairs
and that kind of thing that's
interesting so one of the uh one of the
things we talk about in the show a lot
is how in a in a living soil with a good
fungal environment that the fungus is um
you know creating channels for the water
to seep through and for the the roots to
find their ways through and it would be
my expectation that in cocoa and peat
systems
um because there is less
um
tiny particles of soil to fill in in
between that a cocoa and peat system
will have a lot more air pockets oh and
well I'm not don't want to dwell on the
air part but more like
um paths passages for the roots to
follow do you find that in cocoa and
peat systems the the roots are are
growing more willy-nilly because they
have so many more options instead of the
fewer options that you would find in a
living soil system
I guess it depends like I think I think
the more complex the soil system is the
more complex The Roots become because
they're just like I said they have to go
adventuring for all of the things that
they need and it's not all immediately
readily available I feel like with
aeration for example or like Pockets
like there there's probably other things
and whether you'd notice it if you just
like pulled the two root systems up like
you might notice that if you count up
the all the lateral roots or if you you
know measure the thickness of the root
it might might change but I think it
would be a lot of chemistry would change
too does that make sense yeah does that
answer your question yeah yeah
um and then um I'm gonna ask you a
similar question but with two different
uh varieties uh first will be you know a
hydroponic version where there is
um you know there is some kind of
cistern of water and you've got
nutrients there and the roots are
growing down into it and I guess this
would work for an earth box too where
the the the roots are sitting in the the
nutrient water
um how will the roots grow differently
in that kind of environment where they
really don't have to travel at all to
access the nutrition
I think they'd probably grow down more
um the one thing that I I've noticed the
most at least in my own research
um
is that the root hairs are missing
because they're so fragile
um and they might like if you took out a
microscope and did a little cross
section and did some fancy staining you
might still see like the starts of a
root hair or the types of cells that
could form a root hair but when you
actually look at roots that are grown in
Hydroponics especially because there's a
current and stuff like that it doesn't
really permit those super fragile
structures from showing up at least not
macroscopically like I can't see them
with my eyes
um whereas like other systems they
probably would be present because
they're not being disturbed as much do
you think that that impacts the thriving
nature of the plant or is it just like
equal and different
I I lean towards equal and different
because the purpose of a root hair is to
increase absorption and that's really
important when we talk about like that
super complex soil mixture we were just
discussing
um where you might need the extra
absorption because that little pocket of
of minerals is just a little too far
away for the the chemistry of the main
root to help and it just needs like a
little finger to go in there and collect
it
um whereas in a hydroponic system you're
readily changing the nutrients over
you're readily providing it with what it
needs and it doesn't necessarily like it
a regular root tip might be totally fine
for absorbing what's there I follow so
the last one I want to talk about is
aeroponics and
um you know there are certainly not very
many of us cultivating cannabis who have
got adult plants that are using
aeroponics however
um it's incredibly common for folks to
use aeroponic uh cloners at the
beginning of a plant's life
um so my question again is when the
plant is hanging but it is suspended and
it's not in it's not you know actually
submerged in the nutrient water it's
actually being sprayed with fine Mist
um how does that impact the root
structure
um like for me I use even finer Mist I
use fog and I notice quite a big
difference like like the plant just
doesn't need to go down as much
um and I don't have empirical evidence
that it's like particularly long or
short but for for my plants in
aeroponics I find they kind of they're
pretty bushy and those root hairs are
retained that's the big thing that I
noticed there because the fog is so
gentle it's just like a little air
current and you can actually see the the
root hairs come out but they also last
longer because they're not getting moved
around in the soil or like used up
um and so they do seem to increase
absorption it kind of makes sense when
you're dealing with a very gentle fog or
Mist because it's not it's not as evenly
distributed as a liquid would be because
it's relying on air currents to for
delivery
um so I think the root hairs they tend
to stay longer and they're more
important in um in aeroponics there I
think if you're spraying like because
you know like the grocery store high
pressure sure aeroponics that keeps your
lettuce wet yeah
um that mist might be enough to change
the root hairs depending on how fragile
they are and what you know again
cultivar species whatever differences
you want to talk about
um if it's being sprayed directly at the
root you might see less root hairs
um but if it's being sprayed into the
chamber to increase the humidity you
might you might again see more root
hairs something that's a big notice
noticeable difference for me yeah right
on the the the the root structure in fog
Panic cannabis plants is really
incredible
um it really looks unlike anything else
and you're right it does look like you
know this this this more compact
Shrubbery with with all the These Fine
uh fine hairs
um it does look like its own animal
um do you have any suggestions for folks
who are are starting their clones in an
arrow cloner but their plan is to move
them into a a cocoa Pete or a um a
living soil system because the the root
system that they have when they're being
moved it's not designed for that
environment maybe you'll tell me it
doesn't matter but I want to address
that one way or another
I think it does we uh we kind of
experienced similar issues when you're
transferring from tissue culture too
because it's a very specific environment
that the root has been growing in it's
got a certain weight to it it's got a
certain water content all these
different things that can happen at the
root surface that it can sense it's
going to be very different whether it's
gel or air or water or whatever you are
using compared to the soil
and so my my suggestion would be that
you know most of the times we fill a pot
and then we dig a little hole and we put
our plant in it
my general suggestion would be don't do
that fill a little bit and then just
kind of hold the plant up and sort of
like gently fill it in that way so it
can kind of retain that structure a bit
more you still have to be careful with
like large air pockets you're going to
have to gently press down but I I think
that that would probably preserve the
structure a little better than just kind
of smushing it in there don't jam it in
there let it let it hang of its own
accord and then fill it around it yeah
yeah I think that would
best way I think to preserve that very
delicate sort of structure and I don't
have again like this is speculation I
think it should provide the root some
support as you're filling it in
um and I think it would cause less
damage but it's still going to
experience some differences compared to
what it was growing in so you might
still see some damage
um just just because it's not as wet or
it's having to adjust the type of
nutrient acquisition it's doing like
those kind of things but hopefully that
way the root architecture is preserved
and I know that's something I do with
digiculture is I like I'll fill the pot
three quarters full and then I'll just
kind of try and like fill in around it
so that the roots kind of supported From
Below before I start squishing it down
all right so um
let's talk about
um uh comparing a couple of these
different
um uh substrates as far as microbial
life interaction goes so in soil most
cultivators are looking for complex
Micro Systems so that the plant thrives
and is pests free and has a complex
terpene profile
um and that happens because there is
this burgeoning community of life in the
root Zone in the rhizosphere
um
however in in
cocoa and Pete and in Hydroponics were
were pouring nutrition and in many cases
we're pouring microbes in
uh to the root Zone but uh because there
is not an established soil community
I I kind of get the idea that they're
kind of anything that we add is just
passing through
um because there isn't a system to
sustain life in those other
non-soil environments so um
how how does this impact the experience
of the roots to thrive and to bring
nutrition that the added microbes and
nutrition are not I guess I'll say
residents of the substrate but more that
were were pouring it in and it's there
for a little while and then they're gone
and then the roots are waiting for us as
the human to add more yes so I guess
I'll answer that in a couple parts first
supplementation of microbes
um it's it's sort of a spicy take but I
don't love the addition of that kind of
stuff because as you say it is very
transient and most of the times that
we're like when we talk about building a
living soil and we're adding like like
mycorrhizae or um like bacterial I think
bacterial is the easiest to get started
with and because they grow so quickly
and they have such a quick life cycle
people it might do better but most of
that is relying on the fact that it's
going to stay put in particular
mycorrhizae because like the mycorrhizal
structure that actually provides benefit
to the plant includes like hyphae which
are basically little fungal roots that
that need time to grow they're very
fragile they're even they're even as
thin maybe even thinner than a root hair
like they if you start moving them
around
um and this is something I don't know if
you've heard of no-till but it's one of
the main reasons why people try not to
till their soil because you're actually
disrupting all those little fungal Roots
um and I don't see that that's really
going to be something that can form
properly in something like Hydroponics
where there's current and in the same
way that the root hairs don't Farm I
would not expect to see fungal hyphae
form at least not to the extent where
they're helpful
bacteria a little different because
again they can they can still colonize
kind of on the surface of the plant root
but their main job in a in a soil system
is to help break down nutrients and some
of the stuff we were talking earlier
like provide protection and stuff and
they're just going to be more limited
um as far as like how that fits into I
think it's probably easier to get that
started in Pete but as you say when
we're watering it through and we're not
really providing for the bacterial or
mycorrhizal Community as well they're
not really getting set up there before
you're adding something different and
you're just pouring more stuff in there
does that answer your question yeah it
does and um it would make me think then
that um without the the constant access
to the resident microbes and nutrition
as you described it and then instead
um it's just going to be there when I
add it that
um you know you might so you might still
get perfectly fine cannabis plants but
there's some percentage of of thriving
or or in our case with the cannabis
plant specifically
um yield and uh
and terpene profile that you might
experience a little less in these
mediums where we have to
um add the nutrition through a cocopeat
or Hydro System whereas in living soils
it's there
um would you agree with that assessment
that those those plants will be
perfectly fine and people have great
success with them but but there's
there's some percentage that's more than
zero that would be benefited by the
living soil approach
I like I am I'm heavily biased towards
living soil I think it's like such a
such a fantastic like build an ecosystem
from the ground up and let your plant
live in it
um I think we've talked about this
before maybe on the last time I was here
where I certainly believe that there is
a shift like each growing method that
you use does something a little bit
different to your plants and it depends
when we're talking about like
um like terpene profiles and stuff like
that there definitely is a difference
when you when you grow in living soil
versus when you grow in Hydroponics when
you stress them out when you don't like
we we know we can influence these
terpene profiles depending on what we do
to the plant so I don't know if that
necessarily makes it better or worse but
when we talk about things like bacteria
and adding adding mycorrhizae
I think you really have to ask yourself
why you're adding it because when we're
going to Hydroponics and aeroponics
we're providing pretty much everything
the plant needs to put on weight as far
as yield goes like we're providing it
nitrogen and minerals and phosphorus and
you know all these little things to to
help it out it might not be as good at
defending itself from disease
um or something like that that might be
benefited by a living soil but like for
just making flowers grow it'll be
perfectly fine but that's why when
you're adding it to a hydroponic system
I don't know that it always is doing the
thing that people think it should be
doing if that makes sense yeah it does
make sense all right so to to wrap up
this second set I'd like to get you to
weigh in on
um
um pot variety
um plastic pots versus fabric pots
um you know a lot of people were happy
to move on from the plastic pots
um because you know a they they get hot
if you live somewhere hot because
they're black uh B you know they don't
breathe if that is an advantage uh see
it can get kind of Swampy in there if
you tend to over water or if you don't
have a good uh soil structure
um versus the the air pots which excuse
me the fabric pots and air pots I guess
where they they talk all the time about
how uh the roots are air pruned along
the side and um you know there can be
more oxygen exchange but I don't really
know that air pruning along the side of
a fabric pot
um or more air exchange with the pot are
necessarily good things I I don't I know
they claim them to be good things but I
don't know that to be true it does seem
that the plastic pots would be more akin
to to actually being grown in soil but I
don't know that so I would like to hear
you compare the two
okay well
um I guess for starters I do tend to use
air pots or or fabric pots
um but it's it's sort of a combination
so if we think about the whole oxygen
air thing we do actually need soil to be
aerated most of the beneficial microbes
that we're talking about today are
um they're requiring oxygen just like
everything else is and in on the
opposite hand we have a lot of bacteria
that are not healthy that grow in
anaerobic or Like Oxygen free areas so
when it comes to extra oxygen I'm I'm
all for that it sort of prevents I mean
there's still other husbandry things
that you would want to consider but in
my opinion it helps prevent things like
pythium and stuff like that from really
taking root
um and like air pruning and stuff like
that it changes the root structure I'm
not 100 sure if it's for the better or
if the worst but it does seem to do a
pretty good job of growing like mother
plants and stuff like that I will say
they are paint water because the water
just kind of leaks out the sides you
still have to have like a plastic saucer
underneath and they don't
there's definitely things that I don't
absolutely enjoy 100 about them when we
look at like a hard wall plastic pot
um I think you do like they're
definitely easier to water and they
definitely retain um they don't dry out
as as quickly I guess
um so you can put water in there it's
not evaporating out the sides um so that
the whole root ball it might be easier
to control for water moisture if you
don't water as often or something like
that
um and again I think there's other
husbandry issues that you that you'd
also have to look into as far as whether
that necessarily makes the growth of bad
bacteria easier or not that often has to
do with the type of soil you have too so
I don't know if it's directly relatable
but I feel more comfortable in in the in
the fabric pots and one way to get
around the miserable watering situation
is to use like drip emitters or
something like that where your soil is
more constantly wet which is actually
especially for living soil better
because a lot of the microbes need to be
wet constantly too so as far as living
soil goes my personal preference would
be fabric pots right on thank you that's
great analysis I use the fabric pots as
well and there was one thing that I
learned about them that that really
annoyed me I still continue to use them
but I I didn't like this fact figuring
it out
um I was I was talking with uh uh Josh
from dragonfly Earth medicine about them
and about how how I you know I I like
using fabric pots versus plastic pots so
that there's you know I'm using less
plastic and he had the audacity to point
out that even though we're using the
term fabric pots that nearly all of them
on the market are spun plastic and I
looked into it and damn it he's right
and so they're they're plastic pots just
in a different form and so
um that fact pissed me off and so I went
and I and I I intentionally purchased
actual hemp pots and they degraded and
fell apart in one season
damn the biology of it
um makes the spun plastic I guess at
least necessary for the time being until
we've got another material but um yeah
me thinking that air quotes fabric pots
were some kind of linen was like totally
wrong no and I think a lot of um I think
you're probably not alone because I
think a lot of us are trying to use less
plastic and that kind of stuff and I
don't necessarily think that fabric pots
will mean less plastic because it's
basically like wearing a polyester shirt
or something like that there's
definitely some plastic in there but as
you say of any of the natural fibers
tend to disintegrate very quickly
um so like felt or spun or whatever
you're you're gonna the the more natural
and less plastic you'd go the more often
you have to replace them which isn't
really a big deal I guess when you want
to like transplant into a field or
something you probably like if they
degrade in a couple of months of you
know watering they're probably okay but
what I hate though is the idea of my uh
spun plastic fabric pots that are
outside and once I learned that as they
degrade over the years they are very
likely shedding microplastics into my
Farm's ecosystem
and that was very disappointing to me
and so I don't have a solution for it
but I think that I think that it's
important for us all to be aware of of
the truth of it absolutely and I think
that goes to like like when we're
choosing things to have a preference
over like I think when you choose a
fabric pot because you aren't
necessarily saving the plastic
um and I don't think in the hard wall
plastic like especially because you're
putting acidic fertilizer and things
like that through you're breaking that
plastic down too so I it's it's a
trade-off more about is it providing you
the great right growing environment for
your method and then make your choice
based on that because fabric pots
certainly in my opinion anyway support
living soil better when you get them
going
um but I mean a hard wall plastic is
totally fine too right on cool all right
let's go ahead and take uh our second
short break and be right back you are
listening to shaping fire and my guest
today is plant biologist Sarah Lane
[Music]
online cannabis seed Distributors often
seem to be all the same but Multiverse
beans constantly Works to provide you
with cannabis seeds and a buying
experience that you won't find elsewhere
Multiverse beans Works directly with the
Breeders to secure as many packs of your
favorites as possible so that they have
your favorite beans long after others
have sold out some shops simply buy
breeder minimums but I get messages all
the time from breeders saying some
version of Multiverse has to buy my
entire run
at multiversebeans.com you can find rare
cannabis seeds from Night Owl seeds
including the dark owl sub label
Mephisto genetics Square One genetics
Robin Hood seeds and Ethos and so many
others
Multiverse also initiates projects with
breeders to secure exclusive packs that
you simply won't find elsewhere
Multiverse founder Paul lall sees
himself not only as a curator of the
best cannabis seeds available but also
as a collaborator with breeders trying
to bring novel crosses to the market
that his customers are asking for
Multiverse beans also creates exclusive
stickers for their popular seed
varieties that are available free only
when you order those seeds from
Multiverse check out their stickers like
the badass recent slap for Mothman by
gnome automatics on Instagram at
Multiverse beans and finally the
freebies as you'd expect Paul sends
quality freebies with every order and
when you spend at least 150 dollars
Multiverse allows you to choose your
freebies from their special selections
you can get a 10 discount off regularly
priced items when you use the discount
code shaping fire all one word at
checkout
sign up for their mailing list to be
eligible for their monthly seed giveaway
worth 250 dollars
so go to
multiversebeans.com now for a buying
experience you won't get anywhere else
[Music]
one of the challenges with buying
Autoflower seeds is that often you'll
have as many different phenos as you
will have seeds in a pack that can be
fun sure but so many varieties in one
pack is a sign of an immature seed line
that hasn't been worked enough
I prefer my auto flowers to be worked
enough that each Fino in the pack really
captures the aspects that the breeder
was intending
this is why I recommend gnome automatics
to my friends and listeners who grow
automatic flowering cannabis seeds
gnome automatic seeds are not just
crossed and released they are
painstakingly sifted again and again
tested in a wide range of conditions and
taken to a level of maturity that each
plant will be recognizable by its trades
traits that were hard earned so that you
can have your best growth cycle ever
the last 10 years gnome automatics
founder Dan Jimmy has become a trusted
breeder and he continues to pour His
passion of breeding cannabis into every
variety he releases for you to grow
check out the gnome automatics Instagram
at gnome underscore automatics to see
the impressive plants folks are growing
you can score gnome automatic seeds in
feminized or regular at your favorite
seed provider listed in the vendors
section of their website
commercial cannabis Farms across the
country love growing gnome automatics
because of their consistency from seed
to seed short grow times THC percentages
and colorful bag appeal Farms interested
in bulk seeds of more than a thousand
should reach out through
gnomeautomatics.com
while on the website be sure to check
out the gnome automatic shirts and other
merch section too
if you want reliable seeds hand built
from effort expert selection and
experience choose gnome automatics
[Music]
one of the reasons why no-till cannabis
growing is so valued by Farmers is
because the mycelium networks in the
soil remain established from year to
year and we know these fungal networks
are essential because they are the
nutrient super highways that extend far
and wide in the substrate to feed your
plants the trouble with growing in New
Living soils or Blended cocoa substrates
is that it takes most of the plant's
life just to create these mycelium
highways
dynomicoendomycorrhizal fungi inoculant
reduces that time and gets your plant
eating a wider array of nutrients faster
and it's three times the concentration
of the other popular brand in the U.S at
900 propagules per gram of two fungal
species selected specifically for
cannabis cultivation dynomica is the
result of 30 years of research and
trials at the volcani agriculture
Research Institute in Israel it has also
been vigorously trialed by cannabis and
food Growers across the U.S
dynamico is now available at Grow shops
and on Amazon in the United States I
love using dynamico to both speed up the
growth of the mycelium networks in the
soil but also as a biostimulant to make
clone cuttings more viral you can see
side by side showing the comparative
growth on their Instagram at dynomico
if you demand reliable growing results
and appreciate the importance of an
active root Zone in creating a thriving
plant I encourage you to check out
dynomico.com and use the store locator
to find out where you can get yours
that's d-y-n-o-m-y-c-o.com
shaping fire listeners can get 10 off
any size of dynomico on Amazon or
dynamico.com by using the discount code
shapingfire one word no caps whether you
are starting with new beds or pots or if
you want to add some Zing to tired soil
choose dynamico to maximize your plant's
potential
dynamico endomycorrhizal inoculant
welcome back you are listening to
shapingfire I am your host shangolos and
my guest today is plant biologist Sarah
Lane so here we are in set three for the
big finish what we're going to focus on
this set is is the you know the care and
feeding of a good and thriving root
system because you know it's one thing
for us to understand what a root
structure is and what the what the root
system is doing but we as cultivators we
want to make it as as healthy and happy
as we can so
um so Sarah let's talk about how much to
water
um what should our considerations be
across the various substrate systems we
have discussed today to make sure that
we're we're watering in a zone that is
enough for the root system but not
enough to drown it well that's a good
question so
I think the first and foremost things is
that Roots do not like to dry out so you
want to keep making sure that the soil
is wet and that the roots the root ball
itself is is nice and at least damp
obviously over watering is a problem
because the roots then can't breathe
they're kind of like drowning if you
will um and and that's a problem so but
it depends on the substrate of what this
looks like for example in Hydroponics
they're kind of always sitting in water
and there it's more important to make
sure that the the liquid is aerated
properly so it's not stagnant in
aeroponics this is almost never a
problem you just want to make sure that
the spray is happening often enough that
the roots are not drying out while
they're waiting because it's not usually
a constant thing and then in soils we
want to usually when I'm watering I lift
my pot up a little bit and as it starts
to get lighter and lighter you know that
the water is evaporating and then before
it has a chance to get too dry then you
water again and with living soil systems
it's even more important that it stays
damp so if the surface of the soil
starts to dry out too much it isn't that
healthy for that system so then I would
I would check probably daily or every
couple of days to make sure that the
that top layer is staying at least
damped to the touch
and another read that's another good
reason to use some kind of uh uh small
plant cover crop of some sort to uh keep
the top of the pot
um moist so it doesn't go hydrophobic
and push the water off and uh and and
helps the water get into the pot I would
think also that cover crops
um would be helpful because the roots of
the cover crop
um also interact with the roots of the
cannabis plant and
um you know they communicate and share
resources right
as a soil system
they keep her beneficial
the water in because it's not getting
lost and evaporating as much but also as
you say because those roots are are
providing like a little layer of of
support and networking if you are
careful about what you choose you can
also be contributing nitrogen for
example we often plant like micro Clover
or red clover in our pots because it
does kind of give back to the the system
as opposed to some cover crops where it
would also be using up nutrients I'm
forgetting the the vocabulary word for
it but um there are certain plants that
uh you can uh plant as a companion plant
that actually do does the other plant
harm
um are you aware of any plants where the
the roots of that plant actually are
combative against cannabis roots
I'm not 100 sure I know some like
classic I think what you're referring to
is a lilopathy yes um and there's like
definitely some plants that are just
like absolute no toxic but they're like
big trees like you never plant anything
under black walnut it's like a circle of
death but you're obviously not planting
that next to a cannabis tree I think if
you're worried about it sticking
strictly to things like like Clover
um and some of the like if you go to a
farm supply store they often have good
cover crops there and those plants
usually are compatible with a lot of
other plants I don't know anything off
the top of my head that I would want to
put in a pot that would do that but yeah
stick with the basics unless you're
choosing to research it first
essentially basically and like there's
lots of lots of Great opera like options
we do Marigold you can do
um like basil you can do like some some
types of herbs are pretty good in there
basil is really good basil and Marigold
both are good too because
um they can be planted in with your
cannabis plant but they also act as like
an insect trap because
um like everything loves basil so if you
plant a basil plant you're probably
getting the first signs of bugs will
show up there so they can be kind of
useful that way and of course like the
Clover is a really good one too I've
gotten into the habit of throwing
um different types of food producing
plants in my pots I I toured a farm
where they were growing potatoes under
their their plants outside in their in
in the kind of the duff berm that they
were doing out there at Green Source
Gardens and I thought that was such a
great idea but like you know we have to
be in containers where we are so so you
know I got strawberries grown in one I
got carrots grown in another like
culinary herbs in another and uh and you
know you get you get that wind from the
cover crop but also you know if you get
hungry out when you're working in the
field you have snacks so a little snack
that's great right on so um how
impactful is the pH of the water that
we're watering with on the root system
um I think that depends on the soil I I
it's so the pH of water
that's one of the things that
preferentially kicks off nutrients and
so the more acidic the water I think the
more nutrients you might kick off what
does kickoff mean
so I guess if we want to talk about the
soil as like essentially a kitchen
cupboard all these structures that you
see with your naked eye on the soil have
all these little charges on them that
that sort of collect all the nutrient
salts that you're adding whether that's
because a bacteria has broken it down or
not as I said earlier everything is
basically assault at the end of the day
um but it stays there until something
would prefer to be in its spot more and
that's usually acidity so it will it
will take its place on that soil
structure and because it takes the place
then that nutrient is free and it can go
back into the water does that make sense
it does
so then that once that ion is or salt is
free then the plant can use it and so
the plant actually does it itself it
makes acids to go out into the soil and
to kick off all the nutrients off the
soil so that it can take them up and if
you are watering in a like an acidic
like liquid even if it's just like water
itself or whether you've added like
citric acid or something like that
you're going to be doing the same thing
the plant is doing but you can do that
in excess where it would be too much
um but the soil kind of buffers itself
too so it's one of those things where on
a on a like a a big level I'm not sure
it's that impactful but that's what's
happening on a small scale
so
um so as far as like what we can learn
from this it sounds like you know unless
your water is uh making a significant
swing
um that uh the buffering of the soil and
if you're generally trying to stay near
neutral anyway
um the watering that you're doing is not
really all that impactful on the roots
on the pH level because it's the the
system is more or less going to
self-regulate so long as there isn't
something like really wild happening
yeah pretty much and I will I will put
the caveat in there that um Hydroponics
is a little bit different and I've heard
multiple opinions about whether to pH
your hydroponic feed or not I personally
do
um because it's hard to especially over
time it's hard to tell what
um the soil or whatever Medium you're
watering into has retained and so making
sure that your your nutrients are the
the pH they should be at before they go
in sort of helps if your soil is out of
whack
um but that's some people don't and they
seem to find it works fine so again it
might just be like like we were talking
about earlier all these things that we
do because someone else told us to do it
yeah totally um it might not matter in
the end right on let's talk about
temperature so there's a lot of
different variables that can impact the
temperature of the substrate in the
container this isn't something that we
need to worry about in soil because
geothermal takes care of any plants that
are actually in the ground but um you
know a a dark colored pots are are going
to attract and hold more of the sun's
heat
um we've got uh greenhouses and and
Tents outside that can uh get
exceptionally hot on on really hot days
even if we are I've got fans in them and
uh I run into this on my on my deck
because uh the the hours right before
the sun goes down my deck will get up to
you know 95 115 like way up there on a
hot day and and any plants that I have
on my deck will just will just cook I I
just imagine the the root zones just
like turning to Mush so um I'm sure that
there is a range though where
um you know the temperature of the root
zone is Optimum so would you kind of
talk about what temperature range makes
sense for the root Zone and I don't know
I guess I guess the only way we would
know on a hot day would be to actually
throw a probe in there yeah so I guess
the first part I would mention is so
it's kind of insulating
um and again this kind of goes back to
your growing method like if you're a
bare root ball hanging in Hydroponics
that's going to be way more important
um on on a deck or something like that
like I think the same range that you'd
expect the plant to grow in so like 30
or I guess I'm in Celsius
um I think like around like a mild
spring summer day would be fine
obviously if you're getting up to
really really hot summer days you're
gonna start seeing some effects but the
soil does buffer it it both hangs onto
heat but also protects it a little bit
and most of the time when we're looking
at I guess the second part is when we're
looking at heat stress on a plant most
of what's happening is water so the heat
is is causing them to photosynthesize
more
um they're losing more water because
that's a direct part of photosynthesis
is to lose water and because it's
happening at a faster rate in heat and
and they're also getting cooked at the
same time so their leaves are kind of
not happy it can put a lot of water
stress on a plant so that's why you
might see wilting or burning or those
kind of things and so if it's a hot day
I think the best way to keep the
insulating properties of the soil would
just be to water more because the water
is going to take up some time to to
properly heat up it's also going to be
providing for the fact that the leaves
are transpiring more and it's going to
keep the roots a little cooler on hot
days like this it's kind of generally
accepted that it's better to uh water
more times less water during a hot day
because
um you don't want to say oh it's a hot
day I'm going to water more and just go
with more volume because now not only is
the plant trying to take up water but
you've kind of like in you know
um flooded the substrate and and it's it
there's like almost too much water and
it has to it has to deal with moving the
water around at the same time it's
trying to take on water would you agree
with that best practice that you know
instead of doing your same two waterings
a day but you know make them larger in
volume instead you know do the do maybe
even less than you would on a normal day
but break it up into maybe four
waterings
I feel like there's a couple options
there because usually when I'm dealing
with plants that are outside that are
like it's a heat Dome or whatever I
water more in early morning when it's
not hot so that the plant can I guess if
you want to call it water balance like
then it's not already water stressed
when the heat hits
and then I probably would check more
because I I don't know if if you like if
it's best practices and people tend to
follow that rule I'm far be it for me to
go against that
um but I do think that it's less about
like the volume of water I think I think
especially in pots there's only so much
water that you can put in there per soil
amount but it evaporates really fast so
I would say that it's better to water
more frequently and then maybe you don't
have to add as much water but like in a
pot on the on a patio there's only so
much water that can fit in there and
it's not gonna be enough to keep it like
cool throughout the whole day
and and the amount of water is probably
going to also change about whether or
not you're in a hard-walled plastic or
if you are in a fabric pot too because
those fabric pots they just get all hot
and they they start to you know lose
water out the sides pretty fast
yeah then
soil there is
or if you're in in soil in the ground
like a good watering first thing in the
morning before it actually gets really
really hot you might have to check on it
part way through the day hard wall like
I was mentioning but yeah absolutely for
fabric putts because they evaporate out
the sides as well they're just not going
to retain as much as much water so yeah
and in which case like you're going to
be watering again in two hours anyway
you don't need to flood the part yeah
um right on
um let's talk a little bit about
um uh supplements you know there are
there are different types of fungal
supplements that are sold that people
say to
um you know uh mix into your soil so
that when you transplant a pot the The
Roots will interact with the um with the
supplemented uh fungi and will support
root growth you know essentially the the
the the the connection with the
um
between the root hair and the supplement
will wake up the supplement and and that
that fungal presence will will ease the
transition
um of the plant
um do you see that happening and and
does that kind of support make sense
an extent but it depends like we were
talking earlier about the system that
you're coming from and into so
it does take some time if we're talking
about like mycorrhizal inoculum or
something like that it does take time
for that process to happen because like
I was alluding to earlier it's a
conversation between this fungus that's
trying to help out and meets the plant
and the plant which has to prepare
itself to accept the fungus so it can be
helpful to get that going early
but it really only makes sense
especially for fungus I would say if
you're going to then put it into a pot
where it's not going to be disturbed or
into the garden where it's not going to
be disturbed and I also think it depends
on the health of the system you're
planting into like in a pot we have good
control over compost and stuff like that
but it's a real old Garden remedy to put
a little extra stuff in there when you
transplant into maybe not as Rich of a
soil or something like that to give it a
kick start and I would say if you're
doing that with inoculum too and you're
not confident that the health of the
soil you're planting into is is that
great then I'm sure that would give it a
little boost and with bacteria I think
bacteria are a little a little bit
a little bit more broad because they
again they don't they don't have those
like root type structures like the
hyphae um they don't have that hyphae
like the fungus do so they're more
likely to just kind of build up a little
film somewhere and that's probably
easier to water in in different systems
or more systems it might apply to more
systems but um I think there's there's
no harm in trying I just again some
systems are just not that set up to
support it afterwards in the first set
you you mentioned uh uh two or three
different simple teas that you like to
use
um for nutrition for the root Zone I was
curious whether or not you have any of
those simple recipes for beneficial
bacteria to improve the root growth
because you've mentioned beneficial
bacteria a couple different times as
playing you know an important role of
both helping the The Roots Thrive but
also Breaking Down nutrition for the
entirety of the root Zone
um I don't know if there is such a thing
I'm just kind of fishing here but but do
you have a beneficial bacteria prep that
can be uh poured into the pot and and
will help out
yeah I think um I think there's a bunch
of good recipes online but what we often
do um and what we do actually in
research about
um
uh beneficial bacteria and how it helps
the root is to take soil or compost
that's already full of all the microbes
you need and then put it into some very
well aerated water
um and then you can add a sugar source
of some kind depending I know people
talk a lot and this is also very I guess
veers into sort of compost literature
but you can get like green compost and
brown compost and those will have
different types of microbial communities
in them
um and so you can you can
be pretty confident that if you're
taking a sample from a healthy soil and
providing it food like a sugar source
that you're going to get a lot of
beneficial organisms including
beneficial bacteria so that's usually
what we do with like a good couple of
composts a little bit of molasses like I
was saying earlier
um and then some something for it to
nibble on like leaves or like I was
talking about earlier brackenfone and
stuff like that and depending on the
race ratio you're going to get different
stuff now are you talking about a brewed
compost tea in that and that uh point
because the the delineation I'm trying
to make is
um uh you know adding molasses to
um a a compost Brewer if you're going to
let it run for you know 36 hours or
something and so you're going to
incubate those microbes or in this case
bacteria that we want
um and then and then uh root drench that
into the pot that's one use of molasses
but then I also have been hearing folks
talk about oh I want to feed my microbes
and so they're they're pouring you know
molasses or a water molasses slurry into
the pot directly which that sounds super
scary and unbalancing to me versus in
the first example we're going to add
enough molasses that's going to feed the
the microbin bacteria communities and
then we're going to to pour it in the
pot which is going to decrease the I
don't know hotness if you will of the
molasses
I guess I guess like I
I just assumed we were talking about
culture
um which is my bad I should have I
should have clarified
um when I use compost tea my idea is
usually based off of um I know a lot of
people do this too that you're taking a
small amount of something and trying to
encourage growth of that something into
a supplement you can just water in
compost water and it will do just fine
and it might take a little longer but
remembering that a lot of these bacteria
and fungus like they eat the stuff
that's already in your soil so like
rather than add molasses you could
probably add Leaf litter or compost or
something like that to help them because
that's what they're eating at the end of
the day so when I'm talking about
molasses and aerated teas I'm definitely
talking about a brewing tea where you're
trying to grow microbes for watering in
later great I just wanted to make that
delineation really sharp since we talk
about both aerated compost teas and then
compost extracts right which won't be
aerated and I don't want anybody to get
those confused and just like you know
Freebase molasses into their pot you
know because because it happens
unfortunately I I and then and and then
and then they get a decent plant and
then now they swear by it right it's
like oh but that's that's dangerous so
oh yeah and like Superstition you you
know you have the things that make you
work and and like if if it worked for
you you're much less likely to not do
exactly what you just did because it did
already work for you and there isn't
really any harm in watering composting
because it's already got all these
nutrients if anything you're just
freeing up the loose nutrients that were
already free in the compost and watering
them through your soil column and then
and then you also have all those little
microbes that come with so if you don't
have an aerated compost set up
um for Brewing compost tees you can
certainly just take a couple of handfuls
of compost put it on top and water
through and it'll do the same thing it
might just take a little longer because
you haven't encouraged that the growth
of those microbes in the same way I
don't know about the sugar I tend to
agree with the like it might be it might
get things a little toasty in there yeah
right on so before I go to the the last
question
um of our chat um I want to just throw a
wide net here
um uh is there anything else that we
haven't talked about today that can be
done uh to support
um a healthy root life and root growth
um this is I just want to mop up any
other best practices that I may not have
known to ask you but you because
um because you are rudely uh you you you
might know so is there is there anything
else that you uh would suggest or
recommend
I think I think we've kind of covered a
lot of areas that I would talk about
with root health but I think one big one
is like trying to avoid disturbing the
root system and and really going for
some sort of balance because I feel like
we often just kind of manhandle them
they're this mysterious thing under
there that we don't really think about
and if you're gonna go for a healthy
plant you need both a healthy top half
and bottom half so being gentle with
them trying to trying to think about the
different things that you can do to
support them especially the watering
part
um we don't want stressed out roots so
making sure that you're keeping them wet
and able to do their job I think that's
a big one but I think I think all the
things we've talked about today are good
ways to try and promote root health but
at the end of the day it's up to the
plant and you can usually tell if the
top half is healthy the bottom half is
probably pretty good too right on it
does seem like you know we keep on
coming back to the thing that arcano's
plants like uh the most is balance and
consistency right if you can go slow and
steady you know do the same thing every
day and try to keep it a consistent
environment while that is so hard you
know based on our different bio regions
it is the name of the game absolutely
and especially I guess the other thing I
would mention is we focus very much
especially on a plant like cannabis
where we have an end yield that we're
really interested in that it's you still
have to respect the process of growing
it and making sure that the whole plant
is healthy because at the end of the day
that one little part of the plant you're
concerned about relies on all of the
rest of the plant to grow properly and
in the way that we want so don't neglect
your roots yeah amen right on all right
so for this this last question it's it's
fun it it is still a root question but
it's coming from a totally different
direction so
um all the way back like I don't know
four four or five years ago or so on a
shaping Fire episode 26 I interviewed
your neighbor up there in uh BC Natasha
Riz uh are you are you familiar with
Natasha I am oh quite a few nice dinners
together excellent well we like her too
and um and when we had her on the show
to talk about root ball medicine because
the Cannabis roots are filled with with
all sorts of cannabis
biochemicals I I'll guess I'll say that
do things like
reduce inflammation and and and other
things that we tend to use the tops of
the cannabis plant for and and there are
these biochemicals like there's
triterpenes in there and the one that
most people focus on is Friedland
f-r-i-e-d-e-l-i-n for anybody who that's
new but then there's also a whole bunch
of other ones which I could totally
butcher the names of but the point I
want to get to is that
um since that show I have had audience
folks from across the country reach out
to me and say hey we've started making
these tinctures and salves from the
Cannabis root Zone and we're getting
really good
um effects from them but we want to know
how to grow roots that have gotten more
of these various sterols and alkaloids
and try by terpenes and these these
these useful delicious medicinal
biochemicals and they ask me what can I
do for the plant so that so that my
roots are more rich with these these
these Target
um you know Biologicals and you know I
don't have an answer for that except to
say you know a thriving plant will
probably produce more of those like it
does more resin and more terpenes but
like I don't know like I just made I
just made that up I just given my best
educated guess right
um but um this is so similar to the kind
of research that you're doing I'm
wondering if you have a more educated
guess
I actually love this question I
I'm trying to use plants like plant
processes that the plant already
performs
um to try and
find things that are medicinal about it
um and this kind of
does exactly that so when we think of
the different types of molecules that we
find medicinal in a plant they often
have some sort of what we call a broadly
bioactivity which just means that it has
some sort of job that it can do in a
biological system and like a common
example of that might be like an
antibiotic like if we take it we get rid
of an infection hooray and it's usually
from something that is also trying to
fight off an infection so a lot of our
antibiotics might be from derived from a
bacteria that was trying to fight off
another bacteria we found what it worked
so we use it same with antifungals and
things like that so
my work is mostly trying to decide okay
if this is something that plants already
make these molecules for what if we
stress them out a little bit in this way
so for example if you wanted an
antibiotic then you maybe give it a
little bit of an infection or something
like that because then it might make
more of that antibiotic for you
um I don't know how this translates to
root medicine necessarily because a lot
of these things we don't fully
understand
um what they do like we know that when
we take them they have a lot of
medicinal aspects and especially with
cannabinoids they have so many different
things that they do for us that they've
like they've been all sorts of different
things that we have found out about them
but a lot of those aren't things that
plants do right like they don't like for
anti-seizure for example like plants
don't have seizures so we can't make
them have a seizure to make more of that
but for some of these things like that
molecule you're just talking about
if it has an anti-fungal activity or
something like that then then maybe a
plant that has a fungal um problem might
be good and then the other thing would
be we don't want plants that are too
stressed out though because it still
needs to have energy to fight off
whatever you're giving it
um so it might be something where you
can
um just expose it to any bacteria like
maybe a compost tea and maybe it has
some friends and maybe some not so
friendly bacteria in the compost tea and
maybe that will stimulate it to make a
little something extra and I'm I'm just
going to put the caveat that I'm not
telling you to go out and like try and
make your plant super sick right don't
be serum in them or something right yeah
please don't do that but there's ways
that we can stay with our own bodies
like um being exposed to outside and and
those kind of things or eating organic
foods that have things on them and those
kind of things like we know that um that
if we're too sterile our systems aren't
happy so maybe the suggestion would be
to just feed them some compost teas and
some of the stuff that we've been
talking about today
um so that the roots are not only
healthy but also are interacting with
other organisms and then maybe that will
stimulate more of a response just to
guess yeah yeah I like that guess um
while you were saying that I thought
maybe maybe we could get that from from
watering in some non-local
indigenous microorganisms right I mean
we talk about imos all the time and how
much we love them and how how helpful it
is to use localized ones well well maybe
if we were to to use some IMO from a
different environment since that will
have a whole bunch of strangers to this
environment maybe you can get a similar
uh defensive medicinal capability
um without having to go so far as to you
know actually cause damage to the root
Zone just just threaten it
yeah and like this might even be like we
we know that microbial communities are
pretty local and like even maybe local
to your garden versus like across the
street down the hall so maybe it's just
as simple as like if you live next to a
bunch of oak trees and your friend lives
next to a bunch of pine trees maybe you
just get some soil from there and water
it in right on cool well thanks thanks
for going down that theoretical line
with me just because
um you know you're you're you're my root
expert and I mean I know I'm gonna be
getting this question more and so at
least I've got you know more to say even
though we don't know exactly what it is
so thanks for that no problem and thank
you Sarah for joining us again you know
I'm so glad that we got a chance to uh
continue the conversation that we
started in episode 99 about Roots
because there really is so much there
and that really showed me how much I
take the The Roots themselves for
um for granted I talk a lot about the
rhizosphere in the root Zone and the
community and all that but specifically
The Roots I just kind of I just kind of
take them for granted and and the more
questions I asked last time we talked
the more I realized I didn't know so so
thank you so much for um for joining us
and sharing your you know good cheer and
expertise and um and and helping us uh
Rock a little more about what's going on
um underneath the surface in our pots so
my pleasure thank you so much for having
me again
right on dear listener so if you are
interested in uh reaching out uh to
Sarah Lane or just to kind of follow her
along she doesn't do a lot of social
media because she's focused most of her
time on the research but uh there are
there's one place that you can follow
along and that's at her Twitter and uh
her Twitter is
exudetrudely so that is
ex-u-d-e-t-t-e-r-o-o-t-l-y and and if
you have um a question uh that you have
not been able to find the answer for uh
out there on the Internet or an answer
that you actually believe
um saris does invite you to write to her
directly
um but make sure that you give her some
time to get back to you because remember
she is in a doctorate program right now
and and her email is s lane so that's
s-l-a-n-e at uvic.ca so that's u v i c e
dot c a you can find more episodes of
the shaping fire podcast And subscribe
to the show at shapingfire.com and
wherever you get your podcasts if you
enjoyed the show we'd really appreciate
it if you would leave a positive review
of the podcast wherever you download
your review will help others find the
show so they can enjoy it too on the
shaping Fair website you can also
subscribe to the newsletter for insights
into the latest Cannabis News exclusive
videos and giveaways on the shipping
fire website you also find transcripts
of today's podcast as well
be sure to follow on Instagram for all
original content not found on the
podcast that's at shapingfire and at
shangolos on Instagram be sure to check
out shapingfire YouTube channel for
exclusive interviews farm tours and
cannabis lectures does your company want
to reach our national audience of
cannabis enthusiasts email hotspot
shippingfire.com to find out how thanks
for listening to shapingfire I've been
your host shangolos
foreign