[Music]
as cannabis freedom spread around the US
and the world
new shiny and expensive brands are being
established to conduct the commerce of
the cannabis industry and even though
there's a huge amount of business risk
to opening a cannabis company the
likelihood that you might catch a case
and go to prison is greatly reduced
though we should pause for a moment to
remember that people are still very much
going to jail for the plant and that
needs to stop immediately everywhere but
in states with at least a medical
cannabis program you can usually run
your cannabis business within the
regulatory structure without getting
busted that was certainly not always the
case folks who have come to cannabis in
the last decade or so kind of always
have had the expectation that it would
be legal in the next few years but as
recently as the 1990s you could go to
very real prison for not a lot of weed
and there was no end in sight and yet
there have always been those who were
studying breeding conducting science and
inventing devices for the cultivation
and processing of cannabis plants this
global fellowship of botanical experts
developed specialty knowledge and traded
it amongst themselves while staying in
the shadows and just out of reach of the
muggles if you want to learn about
cannabis health business and technique
efficiently and with good cheer I
encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter will send you new podcast
episodes as they come out delivered
right to your inbox with commentary on a
couple of the most important news items
from the week and videos - don't rely on
social media to let you know when a new
episode is published sign up for the
updates to make sure you don't miss an
episode
also we're giving away very cool prizes
to folks who are signed up to receive
the newsletter there's nothing else you
need to do to win except receive that
newsletter so go to shaping feiyr.com to
sign up for the newsletter and be
entered into this month's and all future
newsletter prize drawings you are
listening to shaping fire and I'm your
host
Shango lows today my guess is frits
chess Fritz's founder of Eden labs maker
of some of the most advanced and relied
upon cannabis extraction technology we
won't really be talking tech with frits
today nor really about the modern Eden
labs company I invited frits to talk
about the early days
of selling extraction technology in the
back of High Times Magazine and what
hurdles he had to cross trying to
develop extraction tech and connect with
customers welcome to the show fritz
Thank You Shango glad to be here yeah so
glad that you share some of your
valuable time with us let's get right to
it so when you were first selling
ethanol extraction equipment it was in
the back of High Times Magazine and in
those days cannabis of course was still
very much illegal and yet and yet High
Times was exerting pressure against
prohibition simply by existing so I'm
curious to what degree did it feel like
you were getting away with something
illegal
being able to advertise your ethanol
extractors in the magazine well we
definitely felt like we were getting
away with something because here's how
it all happened
you know before before us and Eden labs
they way back in the 70s there was the
ISO 2 extractor it was made by a guy
named DJ Gould so I want to give him
some some props first of all but second
of all we studied what happened with him
and you know he was openly advertising
it as a way of extracting cannabis and
peyote buttons were two of his main
focuses and so the DEA shut him down
fairly quick and we talked to a lawyer
and basically he said you have to have a
disclaimer that that it's not for
illegal use so we turned that into a
tongue-in-cheek marketing pitch so the
picture in High Times showed our
original little coldfinger home unit and
up at the top it said warning not
intended for illegal use which was a
roundabout way of saying hey you can
make a coil with this thing yeah and
everybody got it and they started
selling pretty well right away and none
of this was my idea I had a friend
someone I'm still good friends with who
already was selling he he was the one
that developed the products for passing
the urine tests company called clear
choice and he approached me first he
asked me for one of these extract
because you know he knew I had one and I
made him one and then he said you know
if he can you make these I can sell them
and I'm like yeah I can make them and
and I was like you think there's a
market for herbal extractors and he said
well let's find out and so he had me
make 10 of them and he put that ad in
and you know there was no looking back
they immediately started selling really
well
yeah no surprise there I mean that
technology probably blew people's minds
that that it was gonna be so easy to to
extract oil do you remember how much the
original price point was I think that
little home unit sold for like a hundred
and fifty dollars back then and the one
unit we still make now that we came out
with shortly after the home you know we
call it the professional six litre you
know it started out at nine hundred
dollars it's it's thirty six hundred now
I mean glass glass and glass blowers
pricing has gone way way up and I never
really was marking it up quite enough
back then to begin with so so your buddy
comes to you and he says hey you've got
these extractors let's see if there's a
market forum why did you have the
extractor already I mean were you were
you making these in your garage like R&amp;D
style because you were doing your own
extractions or were you already in a
related business but you just weren't
selling to cannabis folk so what
actually started the company I mean I
was I was making various kinds of herbal
extracts and including cannabis but
basically just the super old-school
method of grinding some herb putting it
in a jar you know like a spaghetti jar
or something and with alcohol or vodka
and shaking it up and straining it off
in a funnel and you know cooking out the
alcohol I had like a crude still that I
used and so yeah I just made them for
myself and the reason I started making
extractors is because the one herb I
wanted to work with kava kava was
extremely difficult to extract it would
just not extract putting it in jars of
you know ethanol or vodka and so I came
up with this distillation method and and
that worked really well for the kava and
so there wouldn't even be in Eden labs
if it wasn't for kava kava because
cannabis was easy you know you just put
a jar with some alcohol and shake it up
and of course we didn't realize how easy
it was back then you know we were still
shaking it for days on end when really
all I had to do was pour it in there and
shake it up you know was pretty much
done so so what year are we talking
about here
1994 1994 right on so so you know High
Times Magazine has always been kind of
like you know counterculture bastion and
they provide a lot of cover for a lot of
folks with their own legal department
was was high times very open to you know
you know kind of sharing that umbrella
protection that was provided by their by
their legal team for a certain extent or
were they very much you know we're
giving you a place to market your mostly
illegal goods so you really owe us like
I guess I'm trying to get at you know
were they easy to work with back in the
day were they were they trying to
encourage your sales um well first of
all I didn't deal with high times it was
it was that friend Leigh the Dodd who he
was the one that marketed those through
high times so I was wholesaling him to
him I did have you know a web site very
early on I think by 96 I had a web site
and we were selling them here and there
but that was mostly kava industry in the
kava it really was a you know a hot herb
yeah in the mid in late 90s and so I was
mostly dealing with kava stuff Laith was
handling the cannabis but I think High
Times was pretty easy for him to get
along with because he was doing giant
full-page ads they they they like people
who are making their money but one thing
they wouldn't do is you know we kept
badgering them to do an article about
our extractors and they just wouldn't do
it and I think it was because a
liability and what happened with DJ gold
back in the 70s but eventually crap I
can't think of his name
Oh ed Rosenthal eventually Edie called
me outside you know of High Times having
nothing to do with High Times and he
what we call the four liter apothecary
in which we still sell and and then he
and I went over on the phone like you
know I taught him how to carbon filter
to get the green out and you know so ed
was using it that was in the 90s like
probably 96 so you know you must have
been pretty excited / startled when the
ad ran and then the order started coming
in work did were they like jumping out
of your workshop as as soon as the ad
ran well I mean the ad was in there
every month probably from 96 til Bush
got elected and I shut it down I said we
can't be advertising and had high times
with this new regime which actually you
know Michael Kennedy who owned High
Times I talked to him maybe five years
ago and a cannabis cup and he told me
that I did the right thing because a lot
of people you know got raided real quick
once they started that operation I
forget what it was yeah yeah I can't
think of the name but it was operation
something or other where they were
raiding everybody that was advertising
in High Times and so I feel like I got
out of there in the nick of time yeah
that sounds like a smart place so before
you got out I would have thought that
the you know those of you who were
advertising and High Times were kind of
like in a secret Club right because you
know there was pretty much nowhere else
in the country that you could get away
with advertising like that and all of
you were in it you know selling items
that were for example for tobacco use
only or or as year as yours was you know
definitely not for illegal cannabis
extraction it kind of I would think it
set up like a set a secret club of you
folks who were who were doing this did
you did was there camaraderie between
the advertisers who were who were
pulling this hustle or were you all just
kind of like working in your own worlds
well Lafe probably knew a lot more of
those people than I did I only knew one
guy and he was actually in Columbus Ohio
I lived at the time and he sold you know
glass pipes and bongs and he didn't pull
his ad and they came after him he barely
escaped and he went to Taiwan and he
didn't come back to lo bahama collected
so so so it's interesting that you'd say
okay we probably pulled our ad right as
the bush regime came in it's it's odd
though that they did not go to old
issues and find your ad and then raid
you that's that
did you ever get contacted at all by law
enforcement at any time um late Laith
had a he had something some kind of
inquiry from the DEA at one point
because someone got raided but you know
they didn't really give him a hard time
they just I don't remember you know was
back in the 90s I don't remember exactly
what they wanted to know but it was but
it was pretty innocuous I was kind of
surprised they didn't they didn't make
any big deal about it at all so you were
you were doing these other extractions
kava-kava and and other things were any
of your other extractions you know
potentially running into legal issue as
well like like you mentioned DJ gold was
doing peyote button extraction and we're
you know kava kava is legal even though
you know it certainly has got some I
don't know what's called medical
properties but were you extracting other
controlled substances as well or just
cannabis well yeah there were lots of
things I don't I don't really want to go
into all of that but you know let your
imagination run wild
sure sure where I was going with that
though is you know we imagine that there
is kind of like an international club of
people who are experts in their field
and and it sounds like at that time you
were probably an expert in the field
certainly on the forefront of it and I
wondered if other people from you know
who are developing their own extractors
are from other countries who are trying
to solve extraction problems was the you
know in an Internet
world this all became very very easy for
us right but in the in those days you
had to you know either write letters or
travel to each other did people reach
out to you because they wanted to
connect with you for your expertise oh
sure and you know and when it came to to
cannabis there was you know before Bush
when Clinton was still president I would
say that San Francisco was the epicenter
of the whole you know cannabis
processing and new cannabis innovation
and we put we put all kinds of
extractors and not the very first
dispensary that was Dennis Peron and his
didn't last too long but the very second
one was on Market Street in San
Francisco and you know that was the
second dispensary and we had you know an
older version of the ethanol extractor
distiller that we sell to this day and
my very first co2 unit that we ever
built he rented it for a little while
and we used it there and that was the
first time I'd ever put you know good
quality product and I you know in Ohio
basically I'd give people to give me
bags of leaf and you know obviously it
wasn't as good of quality is what came
out from primo buds coming down to the
bay from humble we're people even
thinking about doing whole plant
extractions at that point I mean in in
my mind and certainly I don't I don't go
back as far as you do but in my mind
you'll people have just been using trim
for extraction until just about you know
four or five years ago when when the
prices dropped and people realized how
much better extractions were from from
you know doing nug runs versus doing
trim runs where did you actually have
people back in the in the mid late 90s
who were doing full flower runs we did
full flower in the co2 unit at that at
that shop and on Market Street I don't
remember what the name of it was but
typically you know everybody was just
doing you know sometimes it wasn't even
trim it was just like fan leaves yeah
and you know obviously it was pretty low
quality stuff and nobody knew what wax
were and there was no analytics none of
that existed but I did figure out how to
carbon filter early on and you know at
least getting the chlorophyll out that
was a big innovation at that time
because I don't know if you've ever
smoked that old-school Jamaican hash oil
that was blackish green but who yeah
Matt you can imagine what that tasted
like yeah that stuff was really bitter
because there were so many fan leads
right so you're getting you're getting a
lot of other stuff actually it got my
attention when you said that you you
taught ed how to filter through carbon
to get rid of the chlorophyll that would
clean up a lot of people's product right
there well that was a major step right
there and you know it wasn't for some
years later that we realized that we
could drop waxes out just you know when
it came out of the coldfinger extractor
it was a tincture and you have to carbon
filter first get rid of chlorophyll for
some reason wax won't drop out when
they're still chlorophyll in there but
you know then we we figured out after a
while the you know part of it was us
figuring it out and there were other
people and we figured out we could just
put that in the freezer for a little
while and drop that wax out and really
bring out the flavor a lot better mm-hmm
so at this time you know you were
working with your business partner and
you were feeding him extractors to sell
through the magazine and but you were
also having these other extractors for
various other herbs were you you know
where you take were you going to trade
shows clearly they weren't cannabis
trade shows yet but did you go to
herbalist trade shows and and you were
bringing this gear out yeah the Natural
Products show which is in Anaheim every
March we've said we used to do that show
a lot so you probably know where I'm
going with this when you're at these
shows there are probably people who who
you know maybe they were doing lavender
for their business but at home they had
a little home grow what did you get
people coming up to you at the shows
with a nod nod wink wink could this be
used for other things and and you had to
be very careful with that yeah we were
pretty discreet about it probably not as
much when Clinton was president I didn't
worry about it too much
I mean obviously it was a lot more
careful than now but when when when Bush
got elected it was Don't Ask Don't Tell
I mean if if someone we it was real
typical back then for someone from
California to call up and just start
running their mouths basically say it's
legal here where you know we're licensed
we can we can do this and they'd start
talking about and I'd say now it's you
know I'm in Ohio it's federally illegal
you know if you were calling me up I'd
hint strongly I'd say like if you were
calling me up about extracting some
ginseng I'd be happy to talk to you but
I can't help you you know with the
cannabis right so I mean it was
basically like duh you know don't be
stupid you know maybe you want to call
me back and you know I'm pretty sure
some of them did but yeah it was
definitely a Don't Ask Don't Tell policy
till basically till after Obama got
elected and Holder had that press
conference in 2010 then then you know
the Pandora's Box opened sure that
reminds me a lot of back when I was in
college and we would go to head shops
and you know the signs would save for
tobacco use only and so you'd be asking
for something and you had to be very
careful what you asked the the employees
for because if you used any of their key
words they'd say sorry you have to go
you know and they'd get and they get
real shitty about it - yeah totally is
throw you out right cuz you're put that
you know they were you were putting them
at risk and pissing them off so so yeah
that's kind of interesting so people
think of those little glass bowls with
the stem off as a crack pipe but really
they were a hash oil pipe this you know
crack didn't come out to the early 80s
but there was always the hash oil pipes
in the head shops you know they they
weren't common but I had to tell people
to ask for the tobacco oil pipe and
which was a new phrase but most of the
head shops got it right away because
there'd always been the like I said that
nasty Jamaican hash oil that came around
you know starting way back in the 70s
and then there were a few people you
know making hash oil with DJ gold's
instruments so I'm trying to picture
this utensil that you're just
driving it was it was it kind of like a
glass spoon that you would light with a
butane lighter from the bottom so that
the flame did not actually come into
contact with the hash yeah so it was
more like a glass fishbowl with an open
hole in the top and a stem that came off
and so you drip the oil down in there
and then you'd hold a lighter to the
underside and smoke it you know the same
way people smoked crap exactly like I
said it's not really a crack pipe it was
it was an oil pipe that's where it all
started right on so so when you would go
to these trade shows and you were
selling to these these other types of
herbalists did you find that you started
selling these to people who were using
them for cannabis more than you were
selling them to people for regular herbs
I'm trying to get an idea of of how many
people may or how significant the number
of people who were buying your product
for its cannabis purpose versus you know
a traditional herbal purpose well one of
my original sponsors our backers was a
guy here in Seattle who you know he was
a big kava importer of course going back
to that and so he was in the natural
products industry and he was friends I'd
never met people like this you know
hippies that were multi-millionaire
businesspeople and and most of that
those those natural product companies or
herbal companies you know were started
with the proceeds from you know cannabis
importation so all of these guys were
super familiar and they all got high but
you know their businesses were selling
medicinal herbs and so yeah all his
friends bought these units and I'm
pretty sure they were mostly just doing
hash I with it but you know people were
kind of secretive back then and they
didn't know me so I didn't hear a whole
lot about it but yeah that was my
impression yeah that was actually a
pretty nice setup you had where you got
to build the machine which was your
passion and then and then have your your
friend be more the face of the company
which gave you an extra level of
security while you were still able to
you know not only make the profit
but have your hand and the cannabis
scene which you know even though it was
dangerous there it's also was a you know
kind of a rite of passage to be a bit of
an outlaw back in the day and that's
cool
yeah yeah everything you said is true
and getting back to to the culture and
you know people reaching out by the time
Bush got elected the whole epicenter
shifted to Vancouver and that same
friend had a condo in Vancouver so he
and I got kind of initiated into the the
VIP area upstairs above Blount Brothers
I don't know if anybody listening is
going to remember Blount Brothers but it
was a it was kind of an Amsterdam style
coffee shop in Vancouver back then and
you could smoke in there and they had
coffee and sandwiches and so upstairs
was kind of where you know the
Illuminati of the cannabis industry
often hung out and so I was meeting big
growers and exporters and importers and
people that were innovating you know
with extractions and stuff that was you
know the early 2000s or you know from
from basically from like 99 on and then
they got Stephen Harper and we got Obama
so everything shifted back to here yeah
right on so I'm gonna ask you more
questions about that that international
cannabis Illuminati but let's go ahead
and take our first short break and be
right back you're listening to shaping
fire and my guest today is fritz jest
founder of Eden labs now that the health
benefits of terpenes have become well
known in the cannabis industry people
everywhere are looking for the purest
terpenes and custom terpene blends true
terpenes isolated terpenes and
terpenoids
are tested to the most demanding
worldwide safety and stability standards
terpenes from true terpenes our
third-party tested non-gmo and food
grade their triple distilled making them
the purest terpenes available in the
world with over a thousand terpene
isolates strain profiles and Terp
flavors you can be sure that true
terpenes will have the perfect aromatics
for your manufacturing goals true
terpenes also offers custom blending so
that you can match your company's
marquee strains across all your product
categories while you can certainly
simply just order terpenes and go right
to
factoring true terpenes also offers a
wealth of manufacturing insight best
practices and a willingness to help you
break new ground with your product
formulations true terpenes has robust
and supportive customer service - so
your questions will get answered fast
and efficiently if you shop for turps
before you know how rare that is if you
are a cannabis product developer these
are the Terps that you want to add to
your oil or edible or capsule or
beverage true terpenes are simply the
best your money can buy don't try and
make a premium product with substandard
terms choose true terpenes for a
top-shelf experience go to shaping
feiyr.com
ford slash true terpenes to find out
more or click on the link in this week's
newsletter growing cannabis in
greenhouses is taking over the cannabis
industry an efficient and effective
blend of sunshine grown terpene profiles
and the controlled environment of indoor
greenhouses can be the best of both
worlds for many greenhouse operators
though building their greenhouse before
gaining insight into how cannabis
greenhouses differ from ornamental crops
can be the start of a world of hurt eric
Branstad and his team at greenhouse
advisory group have the experience and
technical know-how to help you avoid
these pitfalls Eric Branstad has been
helping cannabis growers find locations
design build and equip their greenhouses
for over a decade
first starting in Northern California
but expanding over the last five years
to helping clients throughout the world
he has an impeccable reputation for both
depth of knowledge and kindness and
communication you can hear Eric explains
some of the challenges facing cannabis
greenhouses and how to overcome them in
episode number 41 of the shaping fire
podcast no matter where I go in the
country good people with smart
backgrounds still are making the mistake
of building without knowing cannabis and
it causes them to burn through capital
and time fast
everyone has their filmed failure point
for some it is improper ventilation
planning for others it is surface
temperatures of the building or the
plants leaves or both some folks that
build their greenhouse from scratch make
really basic errors like placement of
the greenhouse on the property or not
understanding the natural environment
where the greenhouse sits
some have even built a decent greenhouse
but our inefficient in their deployment
of light deprivation techniques and
never really hit their target yields
it's great when you learn from your
mistakes but it's even better when you
learn from the mistakes of others when
you bring on green house advisory group
you will learn from the mistakes of
their many clients and you'll take
advantage of the best practices
developed by Eric Branstad over his
years of working with clients just like
you from location development to
choosing a builder and tricking out your
new green house or retrofitting or
rescuing your failing green house Eric
will help you through it
visit green house advisory group com to
learn more and connect with Eric and his
team that's green house Advisory Group
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire I'm your host Shango Louis
and our guest this week is fritz Ches
founder of Eden labs so before the break
we were talking about the early days of
Eden labs and advertising in High Times
Magazine and what it was like to be
selling an extractor that could be used
for cannabis during serious Prohibition
days well then things started
transitioning with the Obama
administration and and the laws started
loosening up Dennis Peron was running
the cannabis buyers club on market which
luckily I was able to check out there in
1996 and and and people were starting to
understand that cannabis had legitimate
medical uses and and things started to
loosen up at least for people who you
know we're HIV positive and for people
who wanted to do R&amp;D so so before the
break Fritz you were talking about how
above Blunt Brothers in Vancouver the
the International cannabis Illuminati
were able to get together and talk you
know safely and bluntly and and and
exchange information in ways that we
take for granted now due to the internet
but in those days you actually still had
to physically get together you know as
somebody who was and you know an
extraction engineer like yourself and
you're meeting these international
cannabis players did folks start to
consult you or you know try to recruit
you to for example go to Amsterdam and
build out machines
something were people trying to to
involve your expertise well there was a
lot of talk of me moving to Vancouver
and setting up an operation there and I
actually came very close to doing that I
think the only the only reason it didn't
happen because all of a sudden I got a a
giant project building multiple co2
extractors for some scientists down in
California and that just kind of kept me
in Ohio and then one thing led to
another I never did move to Vancouver
but yeah it was at one point it was all
arranged
I had growers that were gonna give me
trim I had a place to set up you know I
had blunt brothers that it was all gonna
move through so yeah I was I came very
close to moving to Vancouver just being
one of the earliest you know large-scale
actual makers it sounds like even though
you weren't actually making the oil
yourself it sounds like you still even
though you moved back to the US you were
still a very serious player you weren't
actually just doing the production you
were actually creating the means of
production though just because you moved
that act to the United States doesn't
mean that you gave up your hand on the
game no I was doing then what I'm doing
now is you know I run the R&amp;D department
at Eaton labs and that's kind of what I
was doing so I was always doing
extractions and trying new stuff but I
wasn't doing you know toll processing
for people so to speak so as kind of a
sidebar I want to talk about the
vocabulary that's been used historically
you know nowadays a lot of people like
to use the term eh Oh ethanol hash oil
but but a lot of people don't even know
what ethyl eh-oh is and so most of us
still use the shorthand for RSO Rick
Simpson oil just because people know
what that means and and even though Rick
Simpson wasn't the person who first did
these types of extractions he's
certainly one of the people who made it
more popular so so going back to the the
the early to mid-90s when you were
bringing these first extractors to
market what was the vocabulary people
were using to refer to a a clean
essentially a hash oil and and how did
you see if at all that vocabulary change
over the years well it was just simply
called hash oil and there weren't a lot
of options are a lot it you know there
weren't all the different manifestations
or varieties that you have now I mean
there was almost all alcohol extracts
that were carbon filtered and just put
in little vials and you know in the
early days the main market was deadheads
nobody else was interested in hash out
the deadhead community and though those
who traveled following the dead they
loved it
you know the BHO came along very soon
after I started doing the cold fingers
that was kind of really that was really
start I don't know who invented it but
the guys who popularized it was a
silicide fanatic is that were down out
of Olympia and they they developed the
easy method of growing shrooms and they
had the original you know BHO you know
blaster units that they they sold out of
high times but you know they didn't last
all that long because not only were they
advertising you know those things out of
high times but they were making mass
amounts of hash oil and growing many
many pounds of shrooms openly and they
got in a lot of trouble and they might
still be in prison I'm not sure that's
interesting that the first units that
were being sold were were open blasting
and and not closed-loop at all I mean my
god talk about a dangerous product in
the wrong hands jeez yeah and of course
there was there was them and then the
honey bee came out which I think oddly
is still around but the honey bee was
kind of the main instrument that people
started you know buying to do hash oil
you know you saw those and had shops way
back in the 90s so with it with the name
of that product being the honey bee it
kind of speaks back to my question about
vocabulary was was the term honey oil
being used to refer to the the ethanol
hash oil as well yeah it was and there
were people who argued that point way
back then because the honey oil was was
supposed to be really top notch
and honestly the the best hi show I ever
saw like way back in the day it was
crazy I knew this guy in college who got
on a plane flute in Nepal but tons of
hash oil stuffed it in condoms swallowed
him came back to campus you know you can
you know how he got him back out yeah
and then that stuff was all over campus
for like a month and it was this
beautiful pinkish red color and then I'm
pretty sure it was actually extracted
from high-quality hash probably with
ether which is you know an older method
that I don't think too many people do
anymore but that was the true that was
the true honey oil you weren't gonna
make a product like that extracting fan
leaves with ethanol yeah yeah that's for
sure and that that person who flew to
Nepal was probably a superhero on campus
there for a while well it obviously had
a big influence on me yeah when when you
can when you can get the the oil
straight and not have to smoke the plant
material as well it's a it's a really
different experience and it's
interesting too that you would mention
that the the oil kind of traveled with
deadhead family too I'm a I'm a deadhead
and followed they're in the you know the
mid-90s for a few years and that's the
only place that I ever saw it and so you
know when we toured you would run into
it in the parking lot pretty regularly
but where I went to school in
Indianapolis at Butler University it
only ever you you only ever really saw
it in Indianapolis in my circles anyway
was right after shows at Deer Creek
right so everybody would go to the shows
and and you'd buy some and then you'd
have it and then you know it was all
gone in two weeks but if but if you paid
attention like when the Dead came
through town you could get some of these
exotic things like like California kind
buds right right back in the back in
those days we were all smoked in Mexican
brick weed right but the stuff would
come from California and then eventually
became BC bud and out I mean that was
exotic stuff but it was cuz it was
traveling with heads right exactly
so probably I mean some of that hash oil
you might have gotten
dear Creek would be from guys I knew who
down in Athens at Ohio University and a
lot of that stuff would would get
unloaded at dead shows it at Buckeye
Lake yeah I've seen some good shows
there too yeah so do you think that it
traveled with the deadheads because the
parking lot market was so easy to work
in because the the heads were so happy
to buy it or because the extractors
themselves were dead heads yeah I think
it was a little bit of both but it just
seemed like the dead heads were hip to
it real early on and liked it and they
appreciated you know how high had got
them one of my tricks back in the early
days before anybody even knew what this
stuff was is I you know I'd put the oil
on the inside of a rolling paper and
roll up just a joint of you know Mexican
because that was what was around and you
know ten people would get high on that
Joe and they'd be just like what in the
world was that but they you know they
didn't even know what hash oil was and
you know they might want to get a little
vial of it but yeah back then I always
wondered why aren't people more into
extracts probably just sheer lack of
availability what was the price point
like on that stuff I think you know I
saw anywhere from twenty to fifty
dollars a gram back then and that would
have been you know just extracted from
trimmer leaf carbon filter ethanol
removed but you know obviously plenty of
parts per million but you know there
were no analytics and they'd just be in
the little glass files it's interesting
that the the price point has stayed
essentially the same and what has gotten
better is the quality but but the price
point is about the same it is yeah so um
let's see here so let's uh kind of as a
side note you know a lot of people when
they're talking about RS oh they'll talk
about how Rick Simpson popularized it
but that you really didn't want to use
his method because he encouraged the use
of naphtha and you were in the scene
before Rick was popularized and you're
in the scene after Rick was popularized
do you have anything to share about what
it was like to be there as the as Rick
and his method became popularized and
then and then people started to move
away from it because of the naphtha and
choosing ethanol you know if you you
were there so if you have any stories
I'd love to hear it yeah I have a short
story I mean he called me probably you
know 99 or 2000 or I don't know exactly
but about you know back around then and
I kind of admonished him for pushing the
snaps a thing and told him he should be
using ethanol and I'm not sure what
happened after that but it was you know
not too long after that that everybody
called ethanol extract RSO but to my
knowledge he was if you watched his
videos he was still promoting naphtha
not ethanol but I I don't know exactly
you know what the story was with him but
I you know Maya my knowledge was it was
always naphtha but somehow ethanol
extract it came our s so maybe you can
maybe you know more about it than I do
yeah I actually I actually don't I mean
all I know is just you know second
fourth fifth hand that you know the
naphtha was popularized because it was a
a good solvent and it was available and
you just had to make sure that you
purged it properly but then that that
skill and that equipment was so much
harder to get that people just naturally
moved to ethanol because it was easier
to get at but sure you know I I don't
know if that is accurate it just so much
safer right right exactly much safer so
to finish up on the kind of
international Illuminati thing had you I
mean other than going to Vancouver which
is certainly another country had you
started traveling internationally at
this point to meet with other you know
mines in Amsterdam to talk about
technology and processes
I never did go to Amsterdam now my
partner you know at the time that I've
talked about lathe he went to Amsterdam
on a number of occasions and of course
I've been friends with Donny wertshafter
I'm guessing you know who he is
oh yeah sure absolutely yeah so you know
he and I are both from Ohio and you know
he has that that permaculture preserved
down in Belize I've hung out down there
with him for like a month in the jungle
and you know I've known him from
environmental activism since I was you
know in my late 20s and so I the main
person I kept in touch with about what
was a scene was and where it was going
was Donnie because I just see him in
Columbus bouncing around town we had we
had all the same friends and he really I
mean he really does have a great rolodex
of international connections I mean he
would have to have that just to be able
to pull together a lot of the artifacts
that he keeps yeah of course yeah
nobody's more connected than Don yeah so
so right on so let's go ahead and take
our second break and then when we come
back let's talk about that you believe
that the changing of the guard and and
the the eventual decrease of prohibition
so yeah so we're gonna take our short
break and be right back you're listening
to shaping fire and my guest today is
fritz chest founder of Eden labs as a
listener of shaping fire you already
understand the importance of living soil
when growing cannabis when you have
active microbe communities in your
substrate you go way beyond simply
fertilizing with nitrogen phosphorus and
potassium having active microorganisms
in your substrate supports vigorous
plant growth throughout the plants root
zone making for higher yields and
thriving flowers mammoth pea is the
first organically derived microbial
inoculant
that focuses on your plants nutrient
cycling processes to release soil
phosphorus and other micronutrients from
they're bound forms making them more
available to the plant increased levels
of phosphorus will also keep internode
shorter and focus your plants energy on
bud production not only that but the
microbes act as a defense shield for the
plants rhizosphere
by out competing potentially harmful
pathogenic microbes pretty cool right
mammoth pee not only
the nutrients in your soil but it also
helps protect your plant from disease
mammoth Peas beneficial bacteria act
like microbial reactors
continually producing enzymes that
release nutrients mammoth pee was
developed at a u.s. university has been
extensively tested by Colorado growers
and independent laboratories mammoth pee
is proven to increase growth and enhance
blooming one of the great things about
supplementing with microorganisms is
that they won't compete with whatever
fertilizer program you're already
running simply dose on top of your
fertilizer schedule for increased
benefits to learn more and to find out
where you can buy mammoth pee near you
check out their website at WWF microbes
comm partner with microorganisms to
create beautiful thriving cannabis
mammoth pee did you know that shaping
fire has a fabulous YouTube channel with
content not found on the podcast when I
attend conventions or speak or moderate
panels I always record them and bring
the content home for you to watch the
Shango Losey youtube channel it has
world-class speakers including kevin
Jodrey of wonderland nursery talking
about breeding cannabis for the best
terpene profile nicholas Mahmood on
regenerative and polyculture cannabis
growing dr. Sunil a girl on the history
of cannabis medicine around the world
Ben Cassidy of true terpenes on using
terpenes for health in your everyday
life Reggie Godinho of steep hill on the
cannabis genome and Jeff Lowen Fell's on
the soil food web
there are several presentations from dr.
Ethan Russo on terpenes and the
endocannabinoid system and even my own
presentation on how to approach finding
your dream job in cannabis and why we
choose canvas business even though the
risks are so high as of today there are
over 100 videos that you can check out
for absolutely free go to youtube.com
forward slash Shango 'lose or click on
the link in this week's newsletter
welcome back you're listening to shaping
fire I'm your host Shengo Louis and our
guest this week is fritz Ches
founder of Eden labs so before the break
we were just coming up to the changing
of the vibe in the United States where
you know people were surviving the
Republican administration
everyone had scurried back underground
after the Clinton years but that you
know change was coming with the with the
Obama administration and Dennis Peron
was making massive changes in California
and people were starting to see cannabis
in a slightly different light than they
did with the reefer madness so so so
frits you know there there must have
been a point for you
after President Obama came into office
where you're all like okay things have
changed we can start to expand our
services and and change our messaging a
little bit to reach out to new people
what was that point for you well it
happened very suddenly and kind of
unexpectedly I mean Holder had that
press conference I think in 2010 where
he said we're gonna let States do what
they want to do and I certainly took
note of that but I had no idea how
significant that moment was but what
happened was Eden labs had had built a
fish oil extractor in particular it was
extracting you know omega-3 oils from
Greenland New Zealand muscles and these
two New Zealand brothers you know had
this company down in Orange County in
California and we had been setting up
that extractor and when we finished my
buddy Fred and I just decided to go to
Venice Beach for a few days and you know
party have fun and when we got up there
we were just shocked because it was you
know right after that press conference
but the response was dramatic I mean
they were giant billboards everywhere
with pot leaves on it people were just
smoking everywhere I mean everywhere you
walked around the boardwalk you could
smell it they had you know attractive
women in bikinis and rollerblades
selling medical marijuana cards you know
right there by Muscle Beach it was crazy
and back then my cell phone was the
phone number for Eden labs and it
literally when we got to Venice Beach my
phone just started ringing like crazy
and we've never looked back I mean
that's when it really took off was at
that moment so when so how fast so like
so holders talked so would you say that
with
a week your phone started to blow up was
it that fast um I would say it probably
even the next day it started to ring
more for that and we decided pretty
quick that it was okay to talk about it
now that you know what we're allowed to
do and say has always been an evolving
process but you know we quickly segwayed
away from the Don't Ask Don't Tell and
you know started start we it wasn't a
lot of direct marketing but certainly
they come to the website and they call
or email and we we talk about it openly
and and up until that point everybody
had just been buying our coldfinger
you know ethanol distiller extractors to
make oil but it
coinciding with holders press conference
was all of a sudden everybody wanted co2
extractors and we just you know we went
from building one two or three a year to
building you know three a month five a
month all right so that that brings up
two different questions for me the first
one is is that okay so if if you know
holder makes his statement and you are
immediately getting you know calls your
pivot was from talking about other herbs
and inferring cannabis did you pivot to
a medical at the time we would call it
medical marijuana language and you were
using medical marijuana language or were
you still not quite up you know still
not up to being that blunt about it
we're pretty blunt about it and we did
talk about it you know mostly in medical
terms for the most part I mean going by
you know Dennis you remember Dennis
pern's for sure state statement that
all all cannabis use is medical we kind
of went with that philosophy so in
addition to though your your idea that
you are you were safer because of
holders statement at this point you know
you're making some money and and you are
about to start to scale for real for the
what will become the you know commercial
cannabis industry were you you know did
you were you lawyer DUP at this point um
yes we we had a
had a great lawyer back then the best
and he unfortunately he he had like a
stroker and aneurysm in the middle of
the night probably 2011 and then he was
no longer with us but Ian was fantastic
and he had great ideas for how to
navigate all of this and it all worked
out just fine
we never nothing ever happened you know
for us to regret right on that's good
and you know it's nice too because the
reason why I wanted to ask that is
because you know it's it's always nice
for us to make decisions on our
intuition and how we think the politics
is going based on what the media is
telling us but at the same time have a
lawyer yeah yeah we had a great one yeah
excellent so so I want to shift gears a
little bit and talk a little bit about
the tech itself and so you know you had
the original coldfinger
back there in the in the early to mid
90s and is actually making me happy to
hear that it's like the same name you
know cuz you still have the cold finger
on your website right I'm sure that it's
evolved over the years but you know this
was this was like one of your original
kids if you will yeah I'd like to give
you the floor and just like here you
describe how the state of the art of
ethanol extraction has evolved from your
early days to where it is now and I know
that this might be a long answer but but
I would think that everybody would like
to hear it especially the the extractors
who are bothering to listen and you know
if you go over my head that's perfectly
cool but but you know if somebody were
to ask you from your from your early
coldfinger machines to the ethanol
extractors that you're selling now what
are the what are the main themes of
evolution in the technology that you've
developed well of course the big switch
was realizing how efficiently cannabis
extracted with ultra cold ethanol that
you know there's a very rapid extraction
and you know if you do it right with
cold you don't pull the wax you pull
very little or no chlorophyll depending
on you know what you're working with
none of us knew that back then I mean my
joke back then when it was you know
trying to make a cup of tea with cold
water you know I always believed
did you know chemists in general all
believe that you know the solvent needed
to at least be room temperature or warm
and you know it was it with a warmer the
it was the better it was going to work
and you know generally that's that's
true but in the case of cannabis it just
means you're going to pull a lot of wax
and chlorophyll so you know the original
extraction you're going back to the
Jamaica thing I always figured the way
they made that was they just throw a
bunch of cannabis and a big pot out in
the woods and and you know heat it with
a fire and within a bunch of rum and you
know I was in Jamaica a few years ago
and these guys confirm that that's how
they did it so going from that you know
the cold finger was able to distill
redistill the same ethanol through a
basket of Arab over and over again so
you got a much more concentrated batch
right out of the beginning and then you
could you could switch it out and put in
a collection vessel and then distill the
ethanol back out of it all in one
machine so that was pretty evolved for
the time and you know that's still a
very useful method I mean to this day we
have contracts making that kava kava for
people and that's still the best method
for that because it's very exhaustive
and kava is very difficult to extract
but obviously that's overkill for
cannabis and you know I laugh about how
long we went not realizing that you know
we'd have this little unit just
distilling and distilling for hours on
end and watching the drips come out of
the basket and wait til they ran clear
before we figured it was done and you
know in reality it was probably done in
the first 10 or 20 minutes and after
that we were just going hours and hours
wax in chlorophyll but you know we
eventually that was figured out and and
the very earliest that I knew of doing
anything cold was actually you know
there were guys up in Canada in that VIP
room at Blood Brothers but they talked
about doing it was it was never ethanol
it was cold isopropyl and and I did that
and it worked I just did not like the
idea of use and I
a propyl anymore than I liked the idea
of using naphtha so we were very close
to having this all figured out and like
you know 1999 but it was a you know we
thought you had to do it cold with
isopropyl not ethanol so we kind of
missed the boat and you know another 15
years went by or something like that so
obviously you know in the last couple
years the cold ethanol thing is really
caught on and so the way we do it now is
you know we kill a big chamber of
ethanol with a chiller or you can
jump-start it just throwing dry ice in
there and then we pump that and just
spray it over a bass it kind of like a
giant coffee maker and then recirculate
it for a little while and then pump it
off and you know we don't pull any we
don't pull any wax and if you're if
you're content to not grind it first you
won't pull any chlorophyll either but
that means you only get 30 pounds of
that basket if you grind it you can get
70 pounds and then you're gonna pull a
little bit of chlorophyll but you know
we have these a really efficient and you
know a lot of people listening or
familiar with the lenticular filters and
the plate filters and you can just pump
everything out of the extractor right
through that filter and it comes out you
know real pretty on the other side so
pull out a little chlorophyll is not a
problem the wax has always been the
problem once everybody realized they
wanted to get that out and you know
we're still trying to improve the tech
on that because coal cooling giant you
know hundred gallon or 500 gallon
chambers of ethanol down a minus 40 C or
colder that's time consuming it's very
expensive for the the chillers it's very
expensive on your electric bill so the
Holy Grail now is to just be able to do
this at room temperature ethanol you
don't have to put any cold or heat on it
and then be able to get that wax out
with some kind of refining system that's
a lot more efficient than having to
chill everything and we're working with
some of the biggest refining and
filtration companies that work in food
and chemical process we've got like four
different projects going at once right
now
and we're seeing promise with a few of
them but we we haven't really hit on
anything yet that's that's gonna
eliminate the need for those chillers so
it's interesting that you said that you
know back in the day things were being
done at room temperature and then things
got really cold but to make the cost
savings here you're trying to figure out
a way to move back to room temperature
but then filter after the fact my
question for you is when doing it at
room temperature you get a you get a
darker product that many have called you
know green lion or green dragon right
yeah and so and then and then that
evolved to you know using cold alcohol
in the freezer and and the the water in
the actual frozen flower material tends
to stay in the flower material when it's
all frozen and so you're adding you know
you know freezing temperatures alcohol
to actually frozen flower and and gonna
do you know a couple quick rinses off of
it and and then you end up with this
more of a this beautiful amber golden
tincture instead of the like kind of you
know what I now feel like is kind of the
scary and bitter green dragon kind of
material when when it moved when the
tincture pro or when the when the
extraction process moved to the cold did
that really get rid of a lot of the need
for the the carbon filter at the end
because there was so much less
chlorophyll in that product yeah
depending on how you do it now oh yeah
like you said if you can freeze the
cannabis along with getting the ethanol
cold that's an ideal way to do it but
now that people are scaling up to huge
volumes especially with hemp very few
people are actually freezing the
cannabis first they're just taking the
cannabis and they're getting the ethanol
cold so it's you know it still does a
much better job than you know warm or
room temperature ethanol but to avoid
chlorophyll completely with a and not
cool the cannabis you basically have to
not grind it just put whole buds in the
basket and then you know spray that
ethanol over it and that that still
comes out you know a nice golden color
how does using whole flower decrease
your yield I would think that a lot of
your trichomes would be tucked on the
interior of an unground flower
well it certainly washes all the
trichomes off which is you know 70 or 80
percent of it but there is that there's
those cannabinoids that are bound in a
matrix of cellulose and wax down in the
plant material and that's that's always
more stubborn to get out but the price
of cannabis has dropped and so abundant
that a lot of times people don't care
about good yields anymore they just want
good product yeah good product in an
efficient scalable manufacturing process
yeah so so I've got a question before
you that I get asked all the time you
know people ask me how how how much THC
or whole plant cannabinoids can ethanol
hold and I'm not really sure what to
tell them because you know when a
patient has talked to me and we're
talking about the opposite of scaling
here we're talking about a patient who's
at home who did their summer grow and
now they've got their you know ounce or
whatever a flower and and and they want
to make their tincture as potent as
possible and so you'll you'll you'll
take you know a half gallon of cold
alcohol and you're gonna pour it over
your flowers and you're gonna you know
you know shake that and then when you're
done patients are like well now I want
to use some more fresh flower and so
they they get more flesh fresh flower
and then they pour the already extracted
into ethanol over that and then they
always ask me how many times can we do
that at what point is the ethanol
saturated and so I'm not even sure if
I'm using the right vocabulary here but
but I think you know where I'm going can
you explain you explain how to think
about when you know that your ethanol is
saturated and you really should not soak
it
anymore and and that product is done so
with our code finger process where you
can just read to still clear alcohol
through the the material over and over
again you can make extremely
concentrated tinctures that you know
literally what chemists call bomb out
like it gets so saturated that it can't
stay in the solution anymore and it just
starts to fall to the bottom of the
extractor you can or if you put in a
bottle you'll see that it's all bombing
out and there's just piles of you know
resin or oil down on the bottom you're
never gonna get that from just pouring
cold ethanol over you know making tink
the typical way or the common way of
tink sharing just getting into herbal
tradition as you know whatever jar of
herb you have you pour ethanol in it
till you know it's an inch or two above
the plant material you shake it up and
that's supposed to be the extraction
right there if you know let's say in
with with cannabis you know doing that
method you've probably got you know an
eighty or ninety percent of the oil out
extraction if you if you take that
tincture and dump it over fresh material
again your yield is gonna be a lot less
the second time around I would think
it's gonna be more you know sixty
percent 70 percent maybe and that number
is going to keep going down so I would
say you know if your cannabis is very
abundant and you don't care you could do
it two or three times but you know each
time you do that you're gonna you're
gonna pull less of the cannabinoids
you're looking for in the terpenes from
that next batch and the batch after that
it's gonna keep dropping ten or twenty
percent I would think so in a perfect
world you'd love it you know this person
that we're talking about would want a
would want a solution where either they
do one wash and then they you know
distill off the alcohol and then they do
another wash and then they so that
essentially you're doing one to one for
your for your maximum yield or if
somebody is doing it more at scale your
cold fingers actually doing that whole
thing for you in a closed-loop
yeah it is I still think for people that
want really strong tinctures that the
cold fingers the best method and I know
people who have businesses that just do
that you know it's it's not a real
commonplace thing especially here in
Washington and they don't allow
alcohol-based tincture so there there's
no business but I I mean I just know
people who you know they might be gray
market you might say but they're using
cold fingers to extract cannabis and
then they they do a carbon filtration
drop the wax out and then just sell the
product like that and it's it's a very
nice product because if you do it right
you know you haven't if you're not
readest ihling at all back out and you
let the cold finger cool down before you
open it up after an extraction your
terpene profile is completely intact so
you're getting a full spectrum whole
plant extract and what the you know the
real tincture heads have noticed is that
different strains have a particular
taste but that's dependent on getting
all the wax in the chlorophyll aisle and
then that brings out the bouquet and you
know people that are really into it you
know they can they can smell a tincture
and have a good idea which strain that
is mm-hmm
so so this show is very much whole
plant-based and and so we we hold up
ethanol as essentially being the gold
standard for cannabis medicine right for
for rec you know there's a lot of other
things that people may prefer but but
for for a patient that we want to get
them the widest range of cannabinoids
with the widest spectrum of terpenes you
know ethanol seems to be the way to go
that said I'm curious to know from your
experience what are we still losing from
the plant when we do an ethanol
extraction I'm sure that there's
something that we're losing that we may
want what what might not make it through
the ethanol extraction process that's
valuable to us to patients so the
monoterpenes are going to evaporate off
very easily so when you when you
redistill or or flash off the ethanol
from a hash oil extraction you're going
to lose those mono
terpenes which are pretty important to
that you know entourage effect so the
method I was talking about earlier we
you do the coldfinger extraction let the
unit cool down so there's not going to
be a bunch of vapor coming off when you
open it up and then pour that off carbon
filter it and drop the wax out the
terpene profile will be intact but if
you're if you're distilling off the
ethanol you're gonna you know you'll
probably still have some sesqui terpenes
but you're going to lose monoterpenes so
just you know if you don't mind me
making a little pitch for our products
our modern-day commercial extractor
distillers that we do for cold ethanol
and all kinds of other things they can
be configured to do steam distilling so
you could steam distill your cannabis
first get your essential oils or
monoterpenes then you know spin the
water out with a centrifuge and put it
back in there and ethanol extract it
then refine out the chlorophyll and the
wax and add those terpenes back to it
and and you've got a very you know full
spectrum extract that has only the
things you want in it right on so I've
got a question about treat treating the
ethanol hash oil after the extraction
some people will say that ethanol
extraction can provide everything that
the the modern cannabis market is
looking for from the from the eh-oh -
dabs - viscous liquid for pens and and I
you know I'm not a professional
extractor so I don't know what after
extraction processes would need to be
done to do that but it seems that that
might be a little overstated what are
your thoughts it can f'n all do it all
or do we really need the the whole range
of of c8 a co2 and BHO for these
different products that that people are
enjoying in the modern cannabis market
generally speaking you know because the
main market now is vape pens and I
really think the best vape pens are
where you you know run a co2 unit and it
takes you know some talent to do that to
do make good co2 oil takes you know
Talent
artistic ability there's a lot of cruddy
co2 oil out there but if you if you do
the terpene pole which is you know they
jump out really early and you make that
Terp sauce and then put set that aside
you know drain it out or squirt it out
and then finish the extraction and
refine you know all the cannabinoids
down and add that early turk pullback
yeah that's that's the best way to make
a tasty full spectrum you know vape pen
product most of the the only good the
only good vape pen products that I've
had they were ethanol is where they they
short path the ethanol extract and get
it to like pure cannabinoids and then
you know they had the terpenes at added
back in whether they steam distilled it
or they bought terpenes from you know
Bennett true terpenes or something like
that but you know that's the only time
I've seen a good ethanol vape pen as you
know it distilled you know clear that's
like 95% cannabinoids with terpenes
added back in I mean most of the bait
pens I've seen that we're kind of less
refined ethanol extracts we're pretty
nasty tasting and then I've seen really
good ethanol shatter which is you know
basically you have to be able to see the
ethanol coming through the product and
and and when you see when it starts to
change color and get darker you pull
that away you only you know you want to
get the very first you know kind of like
the first press of olive oil you know is
the the best oil the virgin oil and kind
of like the Terp sauce with co2 but you
know with cold ethanol you needed to see
it passing through and what color it is
and you know while it's still a bright
pretty golden that's the stuff that can
be turned into shatter and it'll have a
real nice taste to it it's interesting
that you mentioned olive oil because
when you when you were talking earlier
about how using co2 extraction for the
vape pen market to do it properly it
takes more than just an understanding of
how the co2 extractor work it actually
takes
a death of knowledge and artistry and
who came to mind was our mutual friend
Jeff Church presently over at at puffin
farms and and he that you know they pay
they push this term EVF Oh extra virgin
flower oil yeah and and you know the
product that they make is is top of the
market right it doesn't taste like these
you know like these you know hot dog
water
you know soupy pens of distillate and
stuff it's got a it's got a depth of
flavor that you don't get anywhere just
like when you see you know any kind of
artisan put out a product and you're
like you're like damn this is this is
very much better than all the other
stuff I've ever had I think that idea of
a of a first pressing of an olive oil
versus you know a an extra version
cannabis oil is is apt yeah so yeah
props to Jeff and Sam back in the day
for they were the first people to figure
out - how do how to get a pure turf or
yeah pure terpene run with co2 and one
of the earliest dirt festivals you know
Jeff entered that product and it was a
pure terpene co2 and there were people
that wanted to disqualify him because
they said it can't be done that you're
you're lying you did something and we
pushed really hard and got that turned
around and they got the award and and
yeah they were the first to do it or the
first I'm aware of they were able to do
it and you know now it's I wouldn't call
it common now but there's certainly a
lot more people doing that but yeah Jeff
and Sam to my knowledge were the first
to figure it out I remember I remember
that year of the Terp Esteva land and
and and all the kind of drama around it
on awards day and Jeff's poor broken
heart right cuz like yeah you know Jeff
worked his ass off to develop this
technique and for them to say that
you're disqualified because what you did
isn't possible that's pretty that's
pretty groundbreaking yeah and from our
point of view in the very early co2 days
you know there were always those who
wanted to knock co2 especially you know
the BHO that you know it's kind of a
competition there and people would say I
co2 sucks it doesn't get
terpenes and then five or six years
later the insult is co2 is only Goods
returned yeah it's so so yeah clearly
co2 and the extractor people you know
the extraction artists if you will
themselves they've evolved a lot too
right yeah sure yeah yeah in there in
the early days you guys had to do a lot
of training of extraction teams just so
that they could use your proper your you
know extraction machines properly so
they didn't give you guys a bad name
because of the machine but nowadays that
you know that insight is a lot more
available so in that same idea as you
know the the evolution of it so so you
know each big evolution and technology
opens up new markets and creates new
products what do you see as a coming
evolution in extraction tech that will
create new market opportunities and you
don't it doesn't have to be ethanol
either I mean you're eating labs
produces an entire range of extraction
equipment from co2 to BHO to ethanol so
you know as the R&amp;D guy they're trying
to push the envelope what do you see in
coming down the pipe that that might
open up new doors and the industry for
new products so we actually figured this
out quite a few years ago but you know
for various reasons we didn't we didn't
push it too much at the time but we're
going to start promoting the concept of
adding a small amount of propane to co2
because it's it's kind of well what was
explained to me the guys who do the
large-scale short pathing mostly right
now they're using ethanol extracts and
you know the ethanol advantage to the
ethanol is you can just do such
large-scale you know quickly and
affordably but a lot of the the refiners
you know they they don't like the
ethanol because there's so many they
have to do many passes and there's
there's always problem
with different kinds of particulate that
are in there and ethanol that you know
they might have to do one or two passes
just to get residual ethanol out and so
what I'm told I'm not a short path guy
myself but I certainly have good friends
that are and they like they like
hydrocarbon extracts and they like co2
extracts as far as what they like to
refine with but you know the co2 they
believe is too slow of a process and the
hydrocarbon has you know the
flammability risks and the liability
risks and the regulatory risks so we
know that we can add a small amount of
propane to co2 and it will in in in the
extraction will be as fast as with just
pure hydrocarbon but it won't be
flammable there's not enough propane and
because the co2 represses that and you
know even if the system would delete
badly both gases stay mixed and settle
on the floor and we know for a fact that
you know with that can we can do this in
a way that it's not flammable and it's
it extracts us very very quickly and
efficiently and it's it's been requested
that you know we start pushing this and
bring this to market so it's it's the
next thing we're gonna push and I
already know that you know there's other
they're starting to be a buzz out there
you know we've got a couple competitors
that are also pushing that and you know
we know John McKay is mentioned it a few
times in public so we we don't know for
sure because you know these trends you
know take a momentum of their own but it
makes sense that this could become you
know a new method especially for people
who want to do refining right on well
thank you for sharing that you know it's
interesting I bet you that the idea of
mixing propane with co2 just kind of
blew a bunch of minds people like no way
I need to know more about that
and that's what keeps this exciting
right is that yeah is that you know the
people who are really into it who have
got a blend of engineering science and
you know passionate vision they
continually push this and and that's why
we find all these great new
technological solutions and with that so
thank you for spending some time with us
fritz you know I know that you're not
usually the guy who's out talking it's
usually AC Braddock from from from Eaton
labs but the fact that you were willing
to you know come out of your your your
laboratory and spend some time with us
to you know give us a taste of some of
the history from the early days up to
what you what you're seeing happening
right now is very kind of you so thank
you very much yeah thank you Shango it
was fun awesome if you want to find out
more about Eden labs you can go directly
to their website at Eden labs comm and
you can also follow their interesting
Instagram also at Eden labs if you want
to hear more about Eden labs and about
their co2 extractors and about how the
reputation and abilities of co2
extraction has changed you can go back
to shaping fire episode 19 where I
talked to em Labs AC Braddock about the
new expansions of the technology you can
find more episodes of the shaping fire
podcast and subscribe to the show at
shaping fire calm and on Apple iTunes
stitcher and Google Play if you enjoyed
the show we'd really appreciate it if
you'd leave a positive review of the
podcast wherever you download your
review will help others find the show so
they can enjoy it too on the shaping
fire website you can also subscribe to
the weekly newsletter for insights into
the latest cannabis news and product
reviews on the shaping fire website you
will also find transcripts of today's
podcast as well for information on me
and where I'll be speaking you can check
out Shango lowes.com does your company
want to reach our national audience of
cannabis enthusiasts email hotspot at
shaving feiyr.com to find out how thanks
for listening to shaping fire i've been
your host
Shango lowe's
[Music]