[Music]
we all love thc it consoles us when we
are hurt it soothes our pain when we are
injured it opens our mind and gives us
big thoughts and it makes us better
humans
when cbd cannabidiol entered our
awareness in the early 2000s cannabis
caregivers and patients quickly learned
of the incredible benefits that cbd had
on an array of ailments because it
interacted so effectively with the
endocannabinoid system
when i speak to patient groups around
the country there is usually someone in
the group who has some version of how
can cbd help so many medical problems
you talk about it like it's a magical
potion
and it's true that the list of physical
problems that cbd helps with seems
unrealistic but i tell folks that cbd
really only helps one thing
it supports and strengthens the
endocannabinoid system the healing
gained is because the endocannabinoid
system is the body's master regulator
for all the major systems
so if you help the master regulator you
keep your body more in balance and
lessen the impact of a wide range of
ailments simply because you have gassed
up the regulating mechanism and it can
now do its job more effectively
with the popularity of cbd new research
is now just beginning into several other
novel cannabinoids including cbg
cannabidirol and cbg2 acts system-wide
through the endocannabinoid system in
similar ways as cbd
cbg has many benefits for folks looking
to get relief and today we're going to
dig into the first scientific survey of
what ailments patients are using cbg to
relieve
if you want to learn about cannabis
health cultivation and technique
efficiently and with good cheer i
encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter we'll send you new podcast
episodes as they come out delivered
right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week and
videos too don't rely on social media to
let you know when a new episode is
published sign up for the updates to
make sure you don't miss an episode also
we are giving away very cool prizes to
folks who are signed up to receive the
newsletter
this month we are giving away the entire
vashon kush series from farmerfly
selections 10 lucky winners will receive
one randomized pack of these 10 new
vashon kush crosses
to learn more about what the crosses are
in the drop check out at farmer
underscore fly on instagram there's
nothing else you need to do to win
except receive the newsletter so go to
shapingfire.com to sign up for the
newsletter and be entered into this
month's and all future newsletter prize
drawings
you are listening to shaping fire and i
am your host shango lose
my guest today is dr ethan russo dr
ethan russo is a board certified
neurologist and former senior medical
advisor to gw pharmaceuticals he served
as study physician to gw pharmaceuticals
for three phase three clinical trials of
side effects he has held faculty
appointments in pharmaceutical sciences
at the university of montana in medicine
at the university of washington and as
visiting professor at the chinese
academy of sciences he has been
president of the international
cannabinoid research society and is
former chairman of the international
association for cannabinoid medicine
in 1995 he pursued a three-month
sabbatical doing ethno-botanical
research with indigenous people in peru
he is author of several books of
cannabis medicine and has published over
30 articles in neurology pain management
cannabis and ethnobotany
dr russo has joined us before on shaping
fire
episode 22 on treating traumatic brain
injury with cannabis and mushrooms and
episodes 11 and 27 about his famous
research papers on cannabinoids and
terpenoids
episode number 67 about treating
migraines with mushrooms and cannabis
recently on episode 80 to talk about his
new paper on cannabis hyperemesis
syndrome and of course the 10-part video
series shaping fire sessions on the
shaping fire youtube channel today we
offer dr russo's very first public
interview on the results of his
groundbreaking paper out this week
titled survey of patients employing
cannabidiol predominant cannabis
preparations perceived medical effects
adverse events and withdrawal symptoms
welcome to the show ethan
good to be back right on so
we're gonna talk mostly about this uh
new comprehensive survey that you and
your co-authors have published um but
before we do that um let's spend the
first set in talking specifically about
cbg so that everybody understands
a little more significantly the impact
of the survey when we get to it
so you know while cbg is only really
getting popular now when did we first
discover and isolate cannabigirl and
knew that it existed
well that goes clear back to 1964.
as with many other items pertinent to
cannabis and cannabinoid science
professor masholum was there
with his
partner yahil gayoni who
died
i think three years ago at about age 90.
but they isolated cannabidiol in 1964
from
hashish that
was seized
by the government and it was of lebanese
origin
but even then
as is so often the case professor
misholum was very prescient about what
might happen and he called canaba gerald
the missing link in the plant synthesis
of cannabinoid constituents
so he knew right away that this was sort
of the mother of of all cannabinoids um
was the precursor to the the rest
and that turned out to be absolutely
correct
so so what is the reason that he
determined it was the mother of
cannabinoids
well uh in looking at the chemistry it
seemed that other things would be
derived from it and i imagine that this
was based on the structure
but uh
certainly uh
i don't know how he did it but he turned
out to be right is in so many things
so
it was discovered um
uh dr mushulum realizes that this is a
significant discovery
and then all of a sudden they're like
there's this big period where there's
not a lot of research what do we
attribute that that to is that is that
directly related to prohibition or was
like nobody really interested
well combination of a couple of things
first was prohibition
uh by this time
cannabis was already illegal most places
and then more formally so
with a single convention treaty which
followed a few years later
but the main reason was all the
bandwidth was taken up by thc
and because in initial studies which
took place in 1969
they started giving cannabidirl to dogs
monkeys
mice and rats and didn't see any really
uh overt behavioral changes and so
uh it just didn't get any attention
until much later
so back in the days like that they would
have been giving them
um cbg isolate correct and not in the
company of other cannabinoids
yeah very likely uh of course there'd be
small amounts that might be present if
someone were using hashish or other
forms of cannabis but one of the quirks
um and that this could be another reason
that it wasn't studied so much
normally
cbg doesn't accumulate much
in
cannabis plants
it sort of is a high throat throughput
stop on the way to the other
cannabinoids
in other words as soon as it's made
most frequently the plant goes on to thc
or cbd
but
now with selective breeding that
situation is changing and we'll
get to that more later i'm sure
for sure we are and
when you so what do you mean um high
throughput stoppage i think is how you
put it
well uh again uh so there are enzymes
that result in the production of
cannabidiol or actually cannabidiolic
acid
which is what the plant makes before
decarboxylation
the loss of co2 molecule
but again normally it doesn't stop there
the more enzymes that will lead to
production of thc and cbd
and so
in most cannabis samples when they're
analyzed
you see either no cbg or very small
amounts well well under one percent
so one of the things that we know about
um you know the variety of cannabinoids
that have been researched is that they
they work on different receptors in
different ways which um
kind of suggests
what they might be used for um what are
the different actions and receptors that
cbg acts on and and is it similar to any
of the other cannabinoids
no it's it's really distinct i mean
there are some uh
some overlaps in terms of the things
that it seems to be good for which we'll
talk about later
but straight out of the shoot it's
important to mention
that cbg does not seem to work directly
on the cannabinoid receptors at least
not cb1 and cb2 which are normally
associated
with thc so it's true to say that it is
not intoxicating or doesn't produce a
high the way that thc does and again
early on that led to less interest now i
think it leads to more interest because
of all the benefits it can have
therapeutically
without the possible downside of
intoxication because
being high as you know is considered a
side effect according to the fda
but to answer your question it does work
on
adrenal receptors on alpha-2 adrenal
receptors and this may have something to
do with its effects on pain
um additionally it's an antagonist that
what's called the trip m8 receptor
which
makes it a good candidate for a number
of things
particularly
treatment of prostate cancer
but also overactive bladder
and a variety of other things
and then there are lots of other
activities where all of the um
all of it hasn't been worked out
you know again
its activity at cb1 and cb2 is much much
less
than thc
but uh beyond that um and all these
mechanisms aren't uh clear yet but um
back in 2008 giovanni abendino and his
colleagues discovered that cbg is very
powerful as an antibiotic against
gram-positive bacteria and that includes
mrsa
methicillin-resistant staphylococcus
aureus
which is associated with
hospital-acquired infections and
some years ago was responsible for a lot
of deaths
so
as far as the
excuse me
as far as the fact that we haven't
really had consistent access to cbg
until we've developed these more um
cbg dominant plans most folks that i
talk to kind of generally have the
belief that land races had wide-ranging
varieties of cannabinoids until they
became heavily bred for the thc market
and it is that breeding for thc that you
mentioned that bred the cbg out because
it was taking up space in the resin
gland that could be holding thc instead
um have you seen much evidence either
through your research or through your
work with breeders best that there were
cbg dominant land races prior to
us starting to breed it free thc heavily
uh great question i i don't know that we
know that um
what i can say
is that where people have been
growing with regenerative agriculture
real soil
uh
active mycorrhizae
natural bacteria in the soil they're
seeing a great greater diversity
of cannabinoid production including cbg
so in other words uh chemovars chemical
varieties that previously
were primarily thc or cbd seem to be
expressing
more different cannabinoids including
cbg when they're grown in this fashion
so
the premise of your question is a real
possibility
part of the problem is we don't know uh
it didn't have great analytical
capabilities going back uh to the early
70s when there were more land races
available and as i'm sure you're aware
a lot of those have been supplanted by
seeds from california and the
netherlands and so
it's getting harder to find some of the
old land races
but that's a great topic for future
research uh something i'd like to be
able to answer better in the future yeah
it is disappointing that so many of
those original land race populations
have um
um i don't know been infected by worked
over lines from from the west um
i do i do hope that people put more
effort into
saving those land races and as a side
note i find that very interesting too
that that you're finding the expression
of cvg and the other various
cannabinoids
is more prevalent in living soil and you
know from the other episodes we've done
it that would make sense too right if if
the if the
the plant has got a wider relationship
with the soil and the plant is
sharing exudates with the
microbe life in the rhizosphere allowing
a wider variety of life thus feeding the
plant from below
all those
you know delightful excretions in the
living soil it would make sense that
that the plant has got more raw material
to express itself more more wildly which
is you know why why plants that are
grown in soil have got a wider terpene
profile than than than otherwise that's
that's really interesting
so that it would make sense that if
folks who are growing intentionally for
cbg would want to strongly consider
soil all right that's interesting thank
you for that
um
so um cbg is often called a novel or
minor cannabinoid and in most cases that
seems to be synonymous with not studied
much right do those words novel or minor
cannabinoid have any relevance in
science
well novel is a misnomer uh minor really
refers to the fact that we usually don't
see a lot of it and again that's a
situation we'd like to change
i really think that cbg is the next big
thing
on and maybe in the future we're not
referring to it as a minor cannabinoid
um right so so
so there's a case to be made that really
the words novel and minor are or more of
a layman's terms and
and not actually all that legit all
right novel to me just means uh you know
i hadn't heard of that one so much yet
but again a situation that we need to
change yeah exactly
um
so i was surprised to read in your paper
that cbg actually often occurs or or
maybe not often but occurs elsewhere in
nature other than in cannabis would you
please teach us a bit about that
yeah not widely um clear back in 1979
there was an article that was published
in german
from a german group and they were
looking at uh
so-called south african daisy
helichrysum and braculigerum
and they found small amounts of both
cannabidiolic acid and cannabidirol in
the plant and it was mainly an
analytical article
but when you really dig it gets
interesting
because this plant and related
species in the genus
are were
sometimes smoked
by indigenous people in south africa
it's not a lot of detail about the
effects but presumably there was some
psychoactive effect and
you know uh
europeans would often look at this and
and claim that these things were smoked
as a tobacco substitute in other words
when people didn't have tobacco to smoke
they'd smoke these other things but i i
think that that's uh culturally myopic
let's say
um
i think that
my suspicion is that it had an
anti-anxiety effect on that's why it was
being smoked and we've got some
evidence for that now
but the amounts were small um
this was an article that i i knew of and
actually paid to have it translated into
english because i'm not a german reader
um
but again i didn't provide a lot of
detail about the uses
subsequently my colleague mark lewis
looked at some plants that we germinated
it was very hard to get seeds
but he really found only tiny amounts
and it's unlikely without a tremendous
amount of selective breeding that you
could get
significant concentrations
of these molecules from that species it
makes a lot more sense
to selectively breed cannabis where
we can do a lot better these days in
canada production
so in the second set we're going to talk
more about um you know what people are
reporting in the modern day
as human users of cannabis but before
your survey the largest survey of users
that has occurred
looking backwards we were looking at
animal studies primarily and there were
some suspicions of what we were going to
find uh the positive uses of it are
so would you would you do a review of uh
of what we
what i guess what we were suspecting
when we headed towards
studying human use because of what we've
learned from the animal studies
yeah again
so the early studies they just didn't
see a lot of overt behavioral changes
but then there was some work showing uh
benefit on pain reduction
uh there were studies that showed
decreasing of the intraocular pressure
much as thc can do
there were effects to reduce reddening
uh that were associated with
inflammation
um
uh
more interesting uh were some cytotoxic
effects in other words effects against
cancer
and
that was true in what's called
epithelioid carcinoma and then again
in prostate cancer
and breast cancer there was also a
prominent response
there was some rodent work done showing
an antidepressant effect
there was a reduction of cells called
keratinocytes
that are
present excessively in psoriasis so that
indicated a possible use there
and let's see what else um
oh an interesting one is um
cbg also works on another receptor a
nuclear receptor that affects gene
transcription called p part gamma
and uh in experiments that were done a
couple of years ago they were shown to
be a neuroprotective effect and
inflammation
um
and also effects on another um
agent called tumor necrosis factor alpha
that's involved in autoimmune disorders
so it opens up a lot of possibilities uh
finally there was a recent study just
this year
in gluoblastoma multiforme
um
showing uh
that basically cannabidire could kill
that kind of cell
um
so
again very promising particularly since
without giving anything away i can say
that cannabidiol is a very non-toxic
substance
likely we could give large amounts of it
and to be able to treat
cancer successfully without introducing
a lot of other toxicities in other words
side effects
it's going to be a real boon in the
future
because
currently available chemotherapy agents
are generally toxic in other words
you hope that you kill a cancer before
you kill too many of the patient's
normal cells and this is why uh standard
chemotherapy is associated with loss of
hair follicles and sloughing the gut and
cannabinoid and other cannabinoids
pretend to be
much safer as chemotherapeutic agents uh
so that part's very exciting i'm curious
what you mean using the the
the term that's relative uh you can give
much more cbg right um
for for many folks a a you know a
regular dose is going to be you know
somewhere between probably 10 and 20
milligrams maybe down to five but
probably 10 to 20.
so when you say
much more
what are you actually saying milligrams
wise
well you know with some of the
cannabinoids it may be necessary to have
hundreds of milligrams a day
um so far at least and i don't want
anyone pressing their luck but we've got
so little indication of toxicity from
the information we have it's very likely
that those kind of high doses could be
given without
the kinds of drawbacks that we find with
huge doses of thc
uh where certainly people can attain
them
but often they have to do it by
titrating upwards over a period of time
as much as two weeks um
so that that remains to be seen but from
what we know so far
uh my strong suspicion is that high
doses of cbg will be tolerable to people
um that might need uh higher doses to
treat uh cancer primarily
yeah i've worked with patients that are
taking as much as 250 a day
and um they certainly don't seem to have
any uh negative side effects uh unless
uh not having any anxiety is a side
effect
but um
so this last question before we go to
the break um it's a little personal but
i i think that it's called for um
regarding what you've just said about
the history of this as as a research
scientist who also
has worked in um you know a general
practice so that you are used to
interacting with real humans who are
really suffering and you're not just
um only in the lab where people are
sometimes less connected to the patient
um
how do you feel about the frustration of
having your hands tied for so long and
being able to
research something that you just stated
we've had really good ideas that is
going to help people for so long but no
one's really had the opportunity to
touch it and now
having that opportunity increasing i
mean i as someone who's a lifelong
researcher for you it must be somehow
like a frustrating opportunity
well i think frustration is my middle
name where cannabis comes
comes in because you know this has been
my life for 25 years um but frankly the
situation with prohibition on cannabis
gerald
is outrageous
it's scandalous and scientifically
untenable
this is not a drug of abuse
i'm certain that when drug abuse
liability studies are done they're just
not going to find a signal here
i could be that it's one of the
solutions to addiction but it won't be a
cause of addiction
um
so it's guilt by association it happens
to come from a plant that also happens
to make thc
uh which similarly shouldn't be
prohibited um so it is an outrageous
situation and the longer it goes on
the greater the
tragedy will be compounded
are you seeing that the ability to do
this kind of research has been eased i
mean you've told me just in passing
you've told me in passing that even
doing this survey is hard and you're
just asking questions what what is the
state of play as far as doing cbg
studies uh
well uh
you know
technically
it is cbg is a schedule one forbidden
substance and people could be arrested
for it under federal law
that has not changed um irrespective of
the fact that it's legal in many states
um
it would be possible for people to be
prosecuted just for having this stuff
so that hasn't changed and the
roadblocks to research
remain
essentially
no
no different substantially from what i
experienced back in the 90s
jeez so well that's the frustrating
opportunity right
yeah well another reason i've worked for
foreign companies for most of the past
25 years
yeah that makes sense well i'm excited
to hear what the what the survey shows
us but let's go ahead and get the first
commercial break out of the way you are
listening to shaping fire and my guest
today is canvas researcher and
neurologist dr ethan russo
[Music]
cannabis folks are innovators and
problem solvers and we like to make
money have you developed a tool
technique or plant that you want to
protect and monetize
you'll likely want legal representation
that is experienced accessible and
shares your values
plant and planet law represents a wide
variety of clients who choose to respect
the environment while pursuing their
business goals
have you invented a machine or gizmo
that you're bringing to market did you
discover a breakthrough environmentally
friendly pesticide or fertilizer
formulation that you're about to start
selling
have you bred a canvas plant with
attributes not found anywhere else
attorney dale hunt and his plant and
planet team have established genetic
patents in over 30 countries
working to help entrepreneurs scientists
throughout the life sciences plant and
planet represents environmentally
positive clients in cannabis and other
botanicals fungi water purification
clean energy emulsions and medical
applications
plant and planet helps people protect
what they've created
if you are an early stage company with
an established idea and are in the
process of fundraising often the
investors require intellectual property
protections happen at the same time
plant and planet can be your sole
representation or they can integrate
with your existing legal team and plug
in their specialties
plant and planet is made of scientists
lawyers with a real passion for cannabis
inventions and the environment they have
the scientific and legal depth to help
you establish patent protections for
your great idea
you don't have to go it alone
friendly qualified and honorable legal
representation is available to you
contact plant and planet law today to
start the conversation
email info at
plant and planet.com
that's plant and planet law
our clients make the planet better
for years organic cultivators have been
looking for a replacement for using peat
moss peat moss has long been the go-to
soil amendment for water retention and
container growing but organic growers
know that peat moss is an unsustainable
resource and the mining of peat bogs
destroys habitat and releases
sequestered carbon but peat moss works
so well that many have continued to use
it but now there's finally a
revolutionary replacement for peat moss
that shares the same benefits while also
being sustainable
pit moss sounds an axe like peat moss
but instead of being mined from fragile
ecosystems it actually is made from
upcycled organic paper and tree bark pit
moss is excellent at retaining water in
your substrate and creating air pockets
and tiny living environments for
microbes pit moss instantly increases
aeration nutrient absorption and water
conservation too
carefully and locally sourced pit moss
is the result of decades-long research
into the use of recycled paper fibers
pittmoss has the fluffy nature of peat
moss and handles exactly the same and
like peat moss pit moss is inert so it
won't change your ph
available in a range of preparations
including a nutrient enhanced blend a
coco coir blend and also as an organic
soil conditioner with no added nutrients
pitt moss is also available as an animal
bedding so go to pittmoss.com now to
learn more that's p i t t
m o s s dot com
growing healthier more sustainable
plants pit moss
[Music]
one of the reasons why no-till cannabis
growing is so valued by farmers is
because the mycelium networks in the
soil remain established from year to
year
and we know these fungal networks are
essential because they are the nutrient
super highways that extend far and wide
in the substrate to feed your plants
the trouble with growing in new living
soils or blended cocoa substrates is
that it takes most of the plant's life
just to create these mycelium highways
dinomyco-endomicrite fungi inoculant
reduces that time and gets your plant
eating a wider array of nutrients faster
and it's three times the concentration
of the other popular brand in the us at
900 propagules per gram of two fungal
species selected specifically for
cannabis cultivation
dynomica is the result of 30 years of
research and trials at the volcani
agriculture research institute in israel
it has also been vigorously trialled by
cannabis and food growers across the us
dynamico is now available at grow shops
and on amazon in the united states i
love using dynamico to both speed up the
growth of the mycelium networks in the
soil but also as a biostimulant to make
clone cuttings more virile you can see
side by side showing the comparative
growth on their instagram at dinomyco
if you demand reliable growing results
and appreciate the importance of an
active root zone in creating a thriving
plant i encourage you to check out
dinomyco.com and use the store locator
to find out where you can get yours
that's d-y-n-o-m-y-c-o
dot com
shaping fire listeners can get 10
percent off any size of dynamico on
amazon or dynamico.com by using the
discount code shaping fire one word no
cabs
whether you are starting with new beds
or pots or if you want to add some zing
to tired soil choose dinomico to
maximize your plant's potential
dynamico endomycorrhizal inoculant
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire i am your host shango los
and our guest this week is cannabis
researcher and neurologist dr ethan
russo so during this set we're going to
focus specifically on this survey
with a title that is
a mouthful so here it is the title of
the of the paper is survey of patients
employing cannabid girl predominant
cannabis preparations perceived medical
effects adverse effects and withdrawal
symptoms
so
uh you pretty much know what the agenda
is here in the second set
so um
so ethan i you've got um a handful of
co-authors on this study and you know
that everyone put in hard work so i'd
like us to take the opportunity to to
give them a nod if you would
sure well this was a real uh labor of
love on involved three universities as
well as credo science
it was my idea to do this
but i immediately wanted to enlist
the help of carrie cutler
on the department of psychology at
washington state university
who was fantastic in putting this
together
and really implementing the survey
which
we decided what to ask jointly but a lot
of that work was also informed uh by
michelle sexton at the university of
california san francisco
we also enlisted the aid of another
great researcher ziva cooper at ucla
and
grad student amanda steuber
who works with
kerry
was involved as well as my business
partner nisha whiteley of credo science
so i had the
great fortune to be involved with five
wonderful women in doing this study and
it all went very smoothly
from our
standpoint
um who funded this study
uh well
basically uh
essentially kerry and
the rest volunteered their time
you know uh same with us at credo
science uh we offered two gift cards as
an incentive to participation that cost
me personally a hundred bucks
the the the people who were recruited
you paid for the for the raffle
everybody was in
oh yes that's funny i assumed that since
this was being done in cooperation with
universities that that the way it always
happens is that the university foots the
bill for everything but i guess that's
an incorrect understanding on my part
well
it generally would be um
you know clearly
kerry and other people work through
grants but sometimes the grants offer
latitude and in how you spend your time
but
you know this was not uh funded by the
national institutes of health uh
directly or anything like that
all right well then uh let's move right
into the survey um um i'm just gonna
kind of like hand you the mic because um
so that you can go go through your notes
would you explain for us how the survey
was set up and operated
sure well first um the study was
exempted uh from what's called the
institutional review board they looked
at it and decided that we weren't going
to do anything that would
interfere with the anonymity of
participants or expose them to the legal
problems so we had
free reign to
take
take people through this
and we recruited people online with
listserv social media and some personal
contacts and
had
some help there
a survey was placed online
and there were certain things we wanted
to see
to avoid issues
we made it adults only age 21 or up
they had to be an american resident and
they had to and this was the important
part
they had to be using uh a cannabidiol
predominant product meaning at least 50
percent cbg
uh in the past six months
and then
we asked a bunch of questions and
uh analyzed those statistically
in terms of the demographics uh
166 people started but
127 completed and that's not unusual
people get bored or decide they don't
want to do it for some reason
it was about 34 males and 40 females uh
predominantly caucasian some diversity
there was a range of income in education
but unlike some surveys of medical use
of cannabis
where there are a lot of people who are
disabled or unemployed the majority of
the people who took part
were working
the first thing we examined was the use
patterns for the cannabis gerald
predominant
products
people had averaged taking these for a
little bit over nine months so it wasn't
oh you know i tried it once
and uh this is what happened we we
thought we had a better uh foundation of
information
when people were using flour they
averaged about three and a half grams of
cbg per week
and
for people using concentrates it was
about a gram of cbg concentrates per
week
then we wanted to know
why people took it in other words what
conditions were they
they treating
and actually they were probably boy
didn't count um
there must have been 40 or 50 things
that were mentioned and some people had
more than one
but the point being that over half 51.2
percent were using cbg for medical
purposes
only 6.3 percent characterized the use
as recreational and about 36.2 percent
uh called it both
on so this is a common situation
certainly one could argue that all use
has a medical basis
but that's how people judge this
themselves
the most common conditions that were
cited uh by the population involved uh
were anxiety 51.2
chronic pain which was 40.9
uh depression 33.1 percent
and insomnia difficulty sleeping and
30.7
and again that's this is all based on
127 people who completed the survey and
again
we're using cannabidiol predominant
products
the next thing we wanted to examine was
how did they compare cannabidirol with
conventional medicines that might be
used to treat the same conditions
well first of all
they seem to think that this worked
pretty well
majority of the conditions people said
that they were much or very much
improved as compared to prior to taking
canape gerald
the highest efficacy was
associated with endometriosis
on gynecological condition
on
66.7 percent
cited that as as being helpful then uh
one i didn't necessarily expect
inflammatory bowel disease 75
uh
in irritable bowel syndrome 82.4
so clearly people with
gastrointestinal issues
found this quite helpful
now what's really interesting to me was
not a single person thought that
conventional medicine was superior
to cbg for these various countries not a
single person
that's extreme
yeah it really makes you wonder and
i'm sure that some people probably think
oh you know
again it's a psychoactive effect they're
high
but they weren't high um
so it's not the usual
uh disclaimer that you sometimes
hear about in relation to thc they're
high and they don't care
that about their condition
anymore so that's clearly just not the
case
another measure of efficacy of a
medicine is what does it allow you to
stop in other words
were people discontinuing conventional
medicines
on there were a significant number of
people who
discontinued conventional medicine
because of the use of cbg
and this is particularly true for
antidepressant meds
the non-opioid analgesics so that would
include things like non-steroidal
anti-inflammatories
and also protein pump inhibitors
so you know they'd be used with
by people who had ulcers or that kind of
problem so again we've got the gut
um seemingly a lot of affinity there for
that kind of problem
um so
we're
again
one of the main reasons we did this is
finding out what it's good for
and frankly
you know we
we wanted to establish this because
i expect that cbg on cbg predominant
products eventually you're going to be
going into clinical trials and we have
to establish a pattern on number one of
what's it good for and number two
is it safe and
certainly that was one of the primary
reasons we wanted to do this this survey
to lay a foundation for future
more in-depth randomized controlled
trials that's an interesting idea
especially with how you described the
the legal environment for trying to do
this sort of research that if i
understand you correctly you kind of had
to do this study first
so that you can now go back to the well
and do a more complex deeper study
because without this study
um
you would not be able to get a heavier
duty study even approved
yeah certainly true so uh
i can relate a story um believe it or
not it was not that many years ago uh
that my my colleague donald abrams
wanted to do a study looking at
inhaled cannabidiol cbd
and the first reaction from the fda was
well we don't
have a record of uh human use in this
fashion
uh which really wasn't true cbd had been
extensively investigated as part of
of sativex nepiximals in clinical trials
on we we knew all we needed to know
about its safety for humans
but basically he had to put together
information showing that cbd was
extensively available in california and
elsewhere and that hundreds of thousands
of people were using it with no
major problems and then he was able to
proceed with the research
well you know you have to look at these
things and wonder what's going to happen
the next round with the next new
quote-unquote
cannabinoid and i really anticipated
that there would be pushback about
proposed cbg studies
um
normally uh say uh drugs really new a
new chemical entity something you
synthesize in the lab
the normal procedure is to test it in
animals and do advanced toxicology
studies where huge amounts are given to
rats and or dogs
and then
if there are no major problems you get
to give it to people well this is
cannabis again the amounts of cbg in the
past were probably low but
again we wanted to establish a pattern
of use
by humans uh without apparent problems
so that we hopefully will not face the
same kind of resistance
did you have a difficulty
finding you know the the 166 people who
started but then like the 127 that
finished
um you know as somebody who works
closely with cbg i know that finding you
know
cvg dominant products or flour that are
51 or more cbg that's very rare you know
that's that's not a common uh thing was
was it
what did you find as far as like being
able to recruit people who had access to
that was was that a challenge
uh well you know most of the people came
from the northwest this has really uh
been the year in the world where there's
been the most intensive uh cultivation
of cbg predominant varieties and the
greatest interest
in its therapeutic use um it didn't take
us forever to do this i think it was
just a few months
um so i was quite gratified with that
and
the other thing was we had very good
contacts
on trying to do this
you know
among others we sent this to our
colleagues that see the greatest number
of patients
for cannabis recommendations and a lot
of them are accessing cbg predominant
products and
um it it came together nicely
it's interesting that you mentioned that
it's um prevalent most in the pacific
northwest uh or for the interest it was
was there anything that came up in the
research that give you anything to
attribute that for i mean
my my only bet would be because the the
crawford brothers are in oregon and
that's my best bet well they've been the
prime movers for sure but uh there are
other braiders that have independently
bred cbg predominant varieties and
interest is increased
but yeah we in the northwest are really
at the center of uh interest in this
compound
interesting um
so i asked this question not as an
indictment simply as a neutral question
but um how should we weigh the
scientific validity of self-reporting in
this case right
i don't know a lot about um conducting
scientific research but self-reporting
sounds like something that should be at
least considered for for accuracy
but i know it counts as actual science
so so how can we think about that well
uh you know in the hierarchy of medical
proof a survey doesn't get a lot of
credence
however in this instance we had good
numbers we had specificity with
again not the idea that the one percent
cbg was present these were cbg
predominant uh
products being used
additionally we saw consistency in the
results
um
and
you know it would be different if this
were something that
people took because they liked it in
other words
where people could claim that well you
know people use regular cannabis because
they like thc and like being high that
just wasn't the case here
um
also we had consistency in the side
effects
you know we've talked about the good we
need to include
the bad such as it was but as it turned
out
there wasn't a lot to say
uh 44
of people in the survey reported no
adverse events in other words no
significant side effects
most common were things that might have
been
due to
thc that was in some of the preparations
so dry mouth sleepiness
increased appetite and dry eyes all of
which
could have been thc induced
interestingly although we were asking
about adverse events 10 percent reported
of
other side benefits
but when we look at
the list
it's not an extensive list
people were not
reporting anything
really
dangerous like paranoia or
hallucinations
and we also wanted to ask about
withdrawal say you've been taking this
for a while what happened when you
stopped but
84.3 percent reported no withdrawal
symptoms of any kind
um
there were
very very few uh who reported sleep
difficulties when they quit
as compared to non-cbd
predominant cannabis in other words
garden variety cannabis uh there were
very s
marked statistically significant
differences in other words
when people stopped they had many fewer
issues if any
as compared to other types of cannabis
so
it's clear again this isn't addictive
it's not getting people high
it's not producing significant
withdrawal
i have got a quick question about the
definition of withdrawal um
you know i i'm a i'm a regular cbg uh
user and it does a wonderful job
decreasing my anxiety and softening my
adhd
however when i haven't had it for a few
days some of the sharper edges of those
aspects of me come out and and and so
it's it's not that i've with that i'm
having withdrawal symptoms from
the the supplement it's because without
the supplement
um
my brain's a lot clankier right
what's a definitional difference between
withdrawal and just missing the cannabis
yeah well you've made you've asked the
exactly right question
there's a difference between withdrawal
and a recrudescence a reappearance of of
symptoms that were present before
so withdrawal would be
more the idea of something's worse than
it was before or something that wasn't
there at all before
um you know withdrawal uh
and other drugs uh
you know would also lead to craving
um we we didn't hear about uh craving to
speak of
or behavior
obsessive behavior
to reacquire the material the things
that one would associate with
say opioid addiction where people
unfortunately turn to crime to obtain it
nothing like that
and no pink elephants or things we
associate with alcohol
no dts etc
so um of the people i know you've
already given us the numbers of the
people who
thought that the
cannabis was more effective for their
ailment than the pharmaceutical
treatments that they were taking
was there any sense of how many people
you know they had an opportunity to have
cbg and they saw it worked and they were
not interested in the pharmaceutical but
then they couldn't find more because cbg
seems to still be spotty right in the
market yeah
i'm afraid we just don't have that kind
of information yet
um and again hopefully
supplies will
be available in the future and this
won't be a problem
um but
you know again from scientific point of
view we're looking at this as a
foundation towards much more
sophisticated
studies that are going to be
in the upper reaches of that hierarchy
of medical proof
basically
anything short of a randomized control
trial
with comparative placebo is not given a
lot of credence
by physicians or the food and drug
administration
so that's what we're going to need to
really uh prove if you will
that this is going to be a valuable
medicine well that's a beautiful
transition ethan thank you because
during the third set we're going to talk
about looking forward for the future of
cbg and how best we folks can use it so
let's go ahead and take our second short
break and be right back you are
listening to shaping fire and my guest
today is cannabis researcher neurologist
dr ethan russo
[Music]
as cannabis regulations become more
demanding and consumers become more
educated it is increasingly important to
avoid the use of chemical pesticides
when cultivating cannabis
beneficial insects have been used for
decades by the greenhouse vegetable and
ornamental plant industry and today many
cannabis cultivators are moving from
sprays and chemicals to beneficial
insects
covert biological systems has the
beneficial insects mites and nematodes
microbials sticky cards and air
distribution units you need to partner
with nature to defend your garden
whether you manage acres of canopy or
have a simple grow tent in your home
cobra is ready to help answer your
questions and help you transition away
from chemical sprays towards clean and
natural solutions
since 1967 culprit has assisted growers
in identifying pests and devising
reliable solutions while providing
healthy insects and mites that will
protect your yield since the 1990s cobot
has been a leader in cannabis pest and
disease control worldwide and have
highly trained consultants to assist you
in canada and the u.s from coast to
coast
no matter where you live covert
biological systems can help visit
cobert.com choose your country and get
detailed information that's covert
k-o-p-p-e-r-t
dot com
for the most up-to-date cannabis related
biological control information you can
also check out their instagram at covert
canada
you know getting away from pesticides is
good for health and good for business
and culprit is ready to help visit
cobert.com today
[Music]
for 20 years humboldt seed company has
been family owned and providing reliable
high-yielding seeds originating in
northern california while the current
trend is to slap one super male into a
line of hyped strains humboldt seed
company continues to breed with
precision and care by doing large sifts
and back crosses to emphasize the
absolute best traits that a line has to
offer this kind of breeding takes time
talent and space to work
no matter what kind of aroma you are
particularly into humboldt seed will
likely have something you'll love if you
love fruit you can choose from banana
mango apricot papaya blueberry blood
orange melon and lemons across their
various strains they have all gas glue
and classic sour diesel lines as well of
course there are the heritage california
strains like og kush jack hair and
headband and their award-winning
blueberry muffin is one that delights
just about everybody's palette
especially when concentrated
humboldt seed company is proud to bring
to market the infamous freak show
cultivar 2 which has a great thc high
but looks so much like a fern that some
folks can't even identify it as cannabis
it's a plant that really needs to be
seen to be believed
if you're looking for well-balanced cbd
seeds humboldt seed company can turn you
on to cbd strains that actually have
flavor like the dill and pepper terpenes
of willie g's lebanese land race
whether you are looking for regular
feminized or autoflowers humboldt seed
company has the gear to make this your
best growing cycle ever
visit
humboldtseedcompany.com today to check
out their line of vigorous genetics
download their catalog and find out
where you can pick them up you can also
check out their instagram at the
humboldt seed company to check out their
gorgeous flowers and the extraordinary
freak show plant
humboldt seed company let them know
shango sent ya
[Music]
with the national hemp program in flux
due to stringent thc testing
requirements brother seth and eric
crawford continue to release seeds to
hemp farmers that will be legal no
matter how you grow them or when you
test them
these new varieties from oregon cbd
seeds have substantial amounts of cbdv
cbgv cbcv and thcv while always staying
below the point three percent thc limit
and guaranteeing complying crops for
farmers every time
also these new varieties cannot be
pollinated by your neighbor's
uncontrolled pollen or a rogue male in
your own crop either
oregon cbd seeds are non-gmo certified
too
oregon cbd seeds was founded and funded
in 2015 by seth and eric maxing out
their personal credit cards without
outside investment they continue to
refuse outside investment that would
change their company culture
oregon cbd grows tons of fresh food on
their research farms for local food
banks literally tons of food
they also give away tens of thousands of
pounds of r d flour to patients
as their company began to succeed seth
and eric started donating money to the
cannabis medicine and hemp fiber cause 2
by giving millions of dollars to oregon
state university in order to establish
the world's leading cannabis genomics
research program
and they treat their employees right
oregon cbd pays for full health and
dental coverage for their employees a
401k program and their minimum starting
wage is 20 bucks an hour plus everyone
shares food from the farms
seth has been on shaping fire a few
times to talk about novel cannabinoids
you can check out episodes 25 and 37 on
cbd cultivars in the hemp market episode
66 on triploid cannabis genetics and the
very first shaping fire live episode 47
with seth and soil expert jeff lowenfels
talking about autoflowers
if you are a hemp farmer and you want to
grow reliable seeds that are sure to
thrive in past testing check out
oregon's
oregoncbdseeds.com to learn more about
buying seeds for the 2021 season that's
oregoncbdseeds.com
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire i am your host shango los
and our guest this week is cannabis
researcher and neurologist dr ethan
russo
so let's take a look forward you know
during the first set we got a better
understanding of what cbg is and a bit
about how it is functioning in the human
and then during the second set you know
we essentially talked to like 127 people
to find out how cbg is helping them live
better lives and get off of their
pharmaceuticals with uh you know
increased side effects so that's all
great
and we've already also talked about how
the
environment for research for cbg is
opening but there's still all these
hoops you've got to go through
i'm curious right now uh what show what
what areas are showing promise looking
forward um
because you know i know there are there
are you know you know college and
graduate students and citizen scientists
and others
who are constantly looking for the
promise in cannabinoids and and perhaps
we can either motivate them or direct
them in ways that are are most likely to
bear fruit so
the survey measured the prior use of the
participants and their continued need
for 13 different classes of medications
that they
appeared to be linked with cvg and you
talked about that a little bit already
saying that you know there are a lot of
people who um a uh
preferred it to their pharma and b
because they knew it they believed it
worked
what are the classes of these 13
different medications because it would
seem to point where we should look at
uh for for shorter term success
sure well you know once again that the
best signal were
for non-opioid pain relievers
uh with the opioids it wasn't a highly
statistically significant effect
um so it'd be a little different
from the claims that we hear associated
with say thc
predominant cannabis
but probably i think the most important
one here is antidepressants
so there was a p-value probability value
0.02
anything below
0.05 is considered statistically
significant for medical purposes
so that one's really interesting
but
i would say that considering the number
of
the big number of conditions that we saw
listed
um that there are probably many other
areas
um that beyond those uh where this would
be fruitful
um again we can go back to the basic
science
um and really see where the signals are
um so you know if the question would be
uh what is going to be promising for
future indications i think we have the
answers already
so
as far as like the the
how many people
what i'm going to is is market
attraction right because one of the
interesting aspects of of the paper is
that you know towards the end it's all
you know
there's there's accessibility and it's
potential future and pharmaceuticals but
really the fastest mover right now is
the cannabis market and people's
interests in
in cannabis with you know what we're
calling novel cannabinoids right so um
as far as the statistics go does this
look like something that is going to be
desired by everybody because on its face
to me it does
how did it bear out in the numbers
well again it's hard to say um
you know when
a new thing comes along there's always
somebody that's going to suggest we
should put it in the water i'm not going
to go that far
um
however um
i do see certain areas that are
preeminent here
um
as i'm sure you've
heard uh from your contacts
this seems to be a remarkable treatment
for anxiety
and what really distinguishes it
from other uh drugs is that it does this
without being overtly sedating
most anxiety agents are going to be
quite sedating
many are addictive
uh clearly cbg is not either of those
things
on i've also heard people
say something
to me that's very profound
in relation to its use and trending
anxiety and that is
its ability to allow them to compound
mentalize
what that means is
you know whatever was bothering them
they know it's there but they can put it
aside and concentrate on the tasks at
hand
in other words
just not let it pervasively interfere
with their functioning
um to me that's the definition
of a good drug for anxiety
um allowing people to function better
um i'd like to add a little color to
that as well and i i like the way that
that you put that uh
when i hear about that that same
attribute from patients they talk about
it being they feel like they've got an
increased capability that their their
their their life struggles or challenges
or pain have not decreased but somehow
they feel like they're able to handle it
like they um have the capability to meet
the
the difficulty of of the issue and
and in a way that's them being able to
compartmentalize it so that they can um
you know they can they can handle it
more
were there other varieties of anxiety
that you saw pop up
gee not
we we just
survey could not have that level of
detail i think that would come from
patient narratives
um and that's something we'll have to
supplement in the future
right on that that makes sense for for
folks that are listening and are curious
the other things that that i'm seeing
just from people taking them and
certainly not at a scientific level and
nearly only anecdotal
we're also seeing a decrease in uh
people ruminating either ruminating
first thing in the morning of all the
things that could potentially go wrong
or ruminating at night of all the things
that potentially did get wrong and
re-rethinking things
and um and for others that that
background anxiety that a lot of people
have well right there you may have put
your finger on how this has been good
for sleep because certainly nobody's
gonna get to sleep if they're running
through the all the bad stuff that
happened
during the day or all the bad stuff
they're facing tomorrow that's a sleep
killer we're finding that a lot of the
people who are sensitive to thc
and they don't really want to take it at
night because i don't understand the
mechanics behind this but some people
who will take as little as um you know
five or ten milligrams at night they
they describe a
hangover of sorts and
and they don't they don't care for it
and and we've found that a lot of the
people who switch over to the cbg since
it doesn't have the thc in the
preparation at significant numbers if
you're pulling it from hemp um they're
still getting to sleep because the
ruminatings get gone but they're not
using the thc so
that's a win
sure yeah so um what are your thoughts
so so you and i have talked actually
probably several times on this show
about
um about your interest in whole plant
compounds um
as a preference to
um
using lots of isolates
and and so
we know that you're you're you're
probably top choice would be to have a
plant that is bred and grown
specifically with a particular blend for
a certain set of ailments and then
creating a whole plant oil and then and
then giving that to the patient
um
however
the market has not developed the point
yet that those preparations really exist
um except for you know small pockets um
what are your thoughts on doing with cbg
what many people did you know five years
ago with cbd
where they would make a
a whole plant oil think of it as like an
rso or a fico or whatever you know
people say call it in there where they
live
but a they prepare a whole plant oil and
then they spike it with cbg isolate like
people used to spike cbd into a thc rso
um what are your thoughts on that whole
range of yeah
uh well you know certainly it's a
legitimate approach to treating a
disorder
we know that cbd
also has anti-anxiety properties the
difference being that the doses required
for cbd
are a lot higher than with cbg
it remains to be seen but it's a good
bet
that the combination is going to be more
effective and then there'd be other
components particularly terpenoids that
can contribute here
um so certainly uh the possibilities for
experimentation are great
um
and
it is a situation fortunately even in
development of a pharmaceutical from
cannabis uh that this kind of blending
is allowed as long as the material is
all cannabis derived that's a legitimate
approach
and we know this already because in fact
sativax or nubiximals which is approved
in 30 countries is actually a blend of
two different chemovars a thc
predominant chemivar and uh cbd
predominant chemoverse so the same kind
of approach could be used
with a cbg
predominant chemo var in combination
with something else to give the blend
that we wish
you know a few states especially the
ones that are still medical
are having
you know internal policy discussions
about whether or not
isolate that has been added to
cannabis products
should be
labeled as such so the kind of product
that we just talked about a an oil of a
whole plant oil if if it's been spiked
with either cbg or cbd or anything else
that
it should be noted on the package that
there was isolate added to it kind of
like a you know fortified with cbg kind
of thing what are your thoughts does it
matter do you think it should be on the
label and and if so why
yeah i believe in truth and advertising
um
unfortunately the industry is
not self-policed on quality control
isn't what it really needs to be and
um
i
would always worry about how it was
produced whether it was pure
uh whether it actually was synthetic
rather than
derive from cannabis
so all of these things are germane on
their things that i think the consumer
deserves to know
well that begs the question you know i i
did
a show a while back with uh uh greg
gerdeman about
synthetic cannabinoids um
both the you know the creation of
cannabinoids that we're familiar with
like thc and cbd in a synthetic manner
but also the kind of synthetic
cannabinoids that are used for testing
and research in the lab and don't really
have much use outside of the lab
but the way that you answered that
question
makes me super curious
does it matter if a cannabinoid in this
case cbg
is from the plant or if it is made
through a synthetic process in the end
it is the same molecule or no well it
it should be
but
sometimes
these syntheses will produce byproducts
that could be contaminants and
potentially toxic so that's always a
concern
also it has to be the right stereoisomer
in other words have the right
three-dimensional configuration
to have the same activity as the natural
compound from the plant
so these are all considerations
ideally
it will all need to be
cannabis derived
to produce a pharmaceutical that isn't
considered a combination drug and then
in specific states such as new york um
any additions have to be cannabis
derived that's part of the law there
so i think it is important and
[Music]
irrespective of what i think this is
going to be a requirement in certain
contexts
right on well that's interesting all
right so so let's let's finish this on
an upbeat positive note there ethan so
um
looking forward i know that you are very
attracted to cbg and you are already
looking at um your next work along the
same line of thought would you give us a
little idea of of what you're going to
be doing next
ah sure
uh well truth be told i'm associated
with a company called endura
pharmaceuticals out of vancouver british
columbia
and cbg pretends to be a big part of its
future
and this would be for two
indications that really weren't picked
up to any degree
in the survey
but these are all based on available
past science and specifically they are
treatment of cancer as we mentioned um
[Music]
there's certain cancers that when
they're metastatic we don't have any
current conventional drugs that are able
to treat them but
cbg seems to be
especially
promising
in treating prostate cancer and breast
cancer and those are
two of the most common
cancers that become metastatic
and then
hard or sometimes impossible to treat
so that's one area and the other one is
antibiotics
we're seeing phenomenal results from the
lab
in terms of cbg is a treatment for
infections including these antibiotic
resistant infections mrsa as i mentioned
but also
vancomycin resistant enterococcus which
is responsible
for a lot of hospital-acquired
infections and
a significant number of deaths
so
one of the exciting things about that is
so far from the lab
uh we don't have any indication that
these bacteria will develop resistance
uh to cannabinoid as they do to
conventional antibiotics
um so this this really may be
revolutionary
my hope is again that we've provided
a pattern of human use that indicates
safety
of these products which is going to
facilitate
um moving them into the clinic for these
specific indications i've got this huge
smile over here ethan because you know i
was i was wrapping up the show and i was
giving you kind of a phishing question
and and then you dropped on this
cannabis or excuse me uh cancer
and antibiotics these are both huge
applications that uh be you know because
they weren't part of the purview the
study i had not heard that they were
happening because they're happening in
private labs like you said
um that's uh that's very exciting uh is
there any public research that's
available like you know as somebody
who's interested in both cbg and uh
doing um support for for for cancer
patients are there any studies out there
that or or you know of taking place that
are going to come out where where we can
read more
uh
yeah the
study by abendino on canadiral
could be easily found on
national library of medicine pubmed
website
so and that
that's well established and there'll be
a lot more
lab
studies coming out
soon
and then
for cancer there are various studies
again if people would input on the pub
med
website cannabidirl and cancer
they'll see the various hits
but again that's just the beginning of
what we expect will be
quite uh
quite
number of
important studies yet to come fantastic
well we look forward to talking uh to
you about them here when they come out
ethan thank you so much for reaching out
to me and wanting to talk about this new
survey so that we can all get up to
speed as as this new uh cannabinoid
becomes more more common to use and more
common to defined
i'll thank you again for the opportunity
if you want to find out more about dr
ethan russo
you can check out any of the other three
four three episodes that uh we've had dr
ethan russo for the guest at that will
be on the page for uh this episode at
shapingfire.com also you can check out
dr russo's company credo science which
is cradle dash science dot com it's a
it's a it's a company that is delving
into some of the areas that dr russo has
found to be most attractive over his you
know over 25 years of studying the
cannabis plant and then finally if you
want to reach out to dr russo yourself
with a question or comment you can
always reach him at ethan
russo at comcast.net
and if you do um write to ethan just be
aware that you know he's he is still
researching and he's still publishing
and it may take him a while to get back
to you but he does try to get back to
everybody eventually
you can find more episodes of the
shaping fire podcast and subscribe to
the show at shapingfire.com and wherever
you get your podcasts if you enjoyed the
show we'd really appreciate it if you
would leave a positive review of the
podcast wherever you download your
review will help others find the show so
they can enjoy it too on the shaping
fire website you can also subscribe to
the newsletter for insights into the
latest cannabis news exclusive videos
and giveaways on the shaping fire
website you also find transcripts of
today's podcast as well be sure to
follow on instagram for all original
content not found on the podcast that's
at shaping fire and at changolos on
instagram be sure to check out the
shaping fire youtube channel for
exclusive interviews farm tours and
cannabis lectures
does your company want to reach our
national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hotspot
shippingfire.com to find out how thanks
for listening to shaping fire i've been
your host shango los
[Music]
you