[Music]
it is truly humbling to read or hear
about a human who totally defines an
area of life that their biography is
indistinguishable from a discipline that
their history is also the history of an
art
Dr Rafael mishulum is one such person
Dr michulum was a Titan of cannabis
research and his breakthroughs were
breakthroughs for all of us his setbacks
set all of cannabis science back and his
successes were to the benefit of all
Humanity
today's episode is unique on shaping
fire we don't do company profiles or
product profiles or cannabis personality
profiles we always focus on a topic and
then I curate a guest who is an expert
in that area
shaping fire is always in service of
Education instead of cannabis business
but today is different today we're going
to look back on the life's work of Dr
Rafael mashulum and in doing so you will
not only get an idea of the expansive
work and discoveries of Dr michulum but
at the same time you will get a really
engaging history of the last 60 years of
cannabis research even if you don't
fancy yourself someone who listens to
biographies you'll likely find that your
interest in cannabis medicine and the
history of our favorite plant is plenty
to engage you in the scientific work of
Dr Raphael mashulum who passed away last
week on March 9 2023 at the age of 92.
today's episode creates a portrait of a
man whose curiosity and unbreakable
stamina for research opened the doors
for all of us interested in cannabis
medicine and made whatever cannabis
normalization we are experiencing now
possible
if you want to learn about cannabis
Health business and technique
efficiently and with good cheer I
encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter we'll send you new podcast
episodes as they come out delivered
right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week and
videos too don't rely on social media to
let you know when a new episode is
published sign up for the updates to
make sure you don't miss an episode also
we are giving away very cool prizes to
folks who are signed up to receive the
newsletter there's nothing else you need
to do to win except receive that
newsletter so go to shapingfire.com to
sign up for the newsletter this week and
be entered into this month's and all
future newsletter prize drawings you are
listening to shapingfire and I'm your
host shangolos my guest today is Dr
Ethan Russo Ethan Russo is a board
certified neurologist and former senior
medical advisor to GW Pharmaceuticals he
served as study physician to GW
Pharmaceuticals for three phase three
clinical trials of satavex
he has held faculty appointments in
pharmaceutical Sciences at the
University of Montana in medicine at the
University of Washington and as visiting
professor at the Chinese Academy of
Sciences
he has been president of the
international cannabinoid research
society and his former chairman of the
International Association of four
cannabinoid medicines
in 1995 he pursued a three-month
sabbatical doing ethnobotanical research
with indigenous people in Peru
he is author of several books of
cannabis medicine and has published over
30 articles in neurology pain management
cannabis and ethnobotany
Dr Russo has joined us before on shaping
Fire episode 22 on treating traumatic
brain injury with cannabis and mushrooms
and episodes 11 and 27 about his famous
research papers on cannabinoids and
terpenoids and episode number 67 about
treating migraines with mushrooms and
cannabis episode 80 on cannabis
hyperemesis syndrome episode 83 on
kanaba girol CBG and of course the
shaping fire sessions on the shaping
fire YouTube channel
today Dr Russo joins us to talk about
the life's work of his good friend Dr
Raphael mashulum welcome back to shaping
fire Ethan
thanks
unfortunate that this has to come up due
to this event but I I hope that the
message that we impart today will be
valuable to people yeah I think so too I
think I think that making sure that this
story is uh preserved for people coming
up behind us is is important and it's uh
it's important to show the the respect
for Dr mashulum too so so thanks for
joining me today for this very special
topic I know you and Dr mishulum were
very close
um so to get us started for context
would you give us a little bit about
your relationship with him before we get
started looking at his career just so
people know from what perspective you're
you're speaking
uh sure so I knew of him by reputation a
long time before but we actually met for
the first time in 1999 at the
international cannabinoid research
society meeting in Acapulco Mexico
um so this is the first time we had to
the opportunity to meet one-on-one on
you know uh Chit Chat uh he recognized
my name as one that could be an Israeli
name
um and uh I knew that he had been born
to a Sephardic Jewish Family in Bulgaria
and pointed out to him that my father's
family had come from nearby in what is
now North Macedonia a town called
Monastery then currently called bitala
so there was an immediate Rapport there
also I was afforded uh some respect
beyond that which I had earned at that
time by virtue of being a physician who
was interested in cannabis in the
endocannabinoid system so that was a bit
of a rarity then
um and uh it it gave me a little bit of
an edge in people taking me seriously
so um I know that um you know I'm going
to ask you a lot of questions today
um kind of asking you what Dr mushulum
thought of this or that and I know it's
like like it's a hard thing to speak for
somebody else but you worked with him so
much over the years and and we're also
you know kind of social even even family
friends I think it's fair to say that um
you were pretty familiar with his
thoughts on both medicine and you know
the world writ large so so I know that
some of the questions are gonna will be
more challenging for others because it
kind of asks you to say what Dr michulum
thought
um so so I appreciate the extra effort
you need to put into that and I also
appreciate that
um you know you're speaking for somebody
else and so uh if if I come across
something that you're like you know uh I
don't I don't think I I would know what
he would have to say uh feel free to
just move me on sure it's a
responsibility but one I take on
willingly excellent good thank you so so
let's start um what initially inspired
Dr michulum to study cannabis and its
compounds and and how did he become
interested in the field
well I think he nicely explained this in
a resource I think all your listeners
would uh be a very find very worthwhile
to take an hour and see the film online
at YouTube called The Scientist so if
they enter the scientist and Raphael
mishulum they'll find this
but to answer your question uh it was
pretty clear to him he he seemed to be
the kind of person that uh wanted to do
something novel and important
um because of his good education he was
well aware of the fact that cannabis had
remained a mystery for at least 150
years
um for example uh morphine was isolated
from the Opium poppy Circa 1804
similarly cocaine was identified from
coca leaves in the 19th century but try
as they may scientists around the world
were unable to really get isolation of
the quote active ingredient unquote of
cannabis on the 19th century there was
some isolation of a red oil they called
cannabinol but it wasn't quite uh right
so he wanted to try to figure out what
cannabis had in it
and it just wasn't something that people
were paying attention to in the early
1960s
so that was it
um and it wasn't an easy thing to do
um you know there were some real
challenges that he faced
yeah I can imagine not only you know
you're describing how um how this you
know scientists around the world were
having a hard time isolating things but
of course it was all it was all you know
very much uh illegal internationally too
and comparatively it's relatively easy
to research cannabis during you know
this kind of creeping normalization that
we're experiencing right now uh a lot
different than when Dr michulum began
his research in the 1960s so so what
were those challenges that Dr Michelle
faced in his research due to the fact
that it was you know not only not legal
most places but it was also demonized
worldwide at the best of the United
States yes absolutely so at the time
um cannabis was by no means widespread
in Israel in fact early uh Supply uh
came from Lebanon uh the way I
understand it uh people on the Lebanese
side would come to the edge of the
border and and throw the parcel of
hashish over the barbed wire to someone
on the other side presumably with an
exchange of cash
um but there were seizures of hashish
and so that's where it got its Supply it
was initially from the police uh he tell
used to tell a very funny story about uh
uh getting help to uh go to the police
and uh requesting five kilos of hash
which he put in his briefcase and got on
a public bus
um and uh became quite a difference
apparently in route but at the time
people just didn't recognize the smell
he figured out subsequently uh that what
he had done was illegal on both sides
and that in future he had to go through
the police to get a supply of hashish
but basically from their first five
kilos of of hashish they used the latest
techniques to get a separation of
different components and
found isolated uh identified the
structure of THC and also synthesized it
in Novo that was in 1964. prior to that
in 1963
they had found cannabidiol so
cannabidiol was actually first
but shortly thereafter we can go through
a whole list of other discoveries that
came from those initial investigations
um before we move forward I have a side
question on uh him getting his uh
research supply of hash from the police
um you know I I have seen how
traditional hash is made in Lebanon and
and you describe them you know chucking
it over the fence
um I imagine that you know the hash that
was being gotten from the police was you
know was dirty and maybe had other you
know
items and hairs and straw from wherever
it was made or whatever did that really
matter with this kind of molecular
research because you're you're going to
do an isolation and just pull out the
parts anyway or or was that was it
harder to work with that kind of uh
product yeah no you're right it
absolutely had to be there'd be all
these impurities in one way or another
um you'd have to get through the crudity
of the initial material to get down to
the isolates of the compounds of
Interest so I have no doubt it was more
technically difficult
yeah I can believe that so so in 1963 Dr
michulum started researching
tetrahydrocannabinol AK THC specifically
would you explain how he suspected it
was present and the process by which he
discovered and isolated it
um yeah basically they use separation
columns but you know in terms of it was
well well known that uh hashish and
cannabis were psychoactive and it was a
matter of identifying which compound or
compounds were responsible and that
includes
um a series of steps of fractionation
and then fractionation again to get down
to the uh pure compound hopefully that
really is responsible for the activity
um you know at that time our testing
would have to be done in animals and
they use monkeys for better or worse for
a lot of the initial work
um but uh you know they they found so
many things that wasn't just THC uh also
in 1964 they isolated cannabigirol
um they published on that uh with his
his partner yahil gayoni
um and um even at the time I you know in
Reading Professor michulum's old work
I'm just struck with oppressions that he
had his predictions about things uh very
quickly they identified that
cannabigirol had to be the parent
compound
to THC and CBD
but that same year they identified the
acid cannabinoids which ultimately were
identified later as the the actual
parent compounds
um in the fresh plant before
decarboxylation on then in 66 they found
canaba chromine and then there were a
whole bunch of minors like cannabis
cyclol uh but they didn't stop there and
this is one of the things I would always
appreciated about Rafi was he was a
chemist
most chemists are happy to stay in their
Lane that was never enough for him he
always wanted to knew more what was the
biological function how can we figure
out what this does so by 1970 they had
tested all of these compounds and
basically found that
THC was mostly responsible and they made
an important distinction even today uh
you know some 60 years later almost
um people make the mistake of saying
that CBD or CBG or not psychoactive this
is absolutely wrong both of them are
what they should say is they're
non-intoxicating but Back in 1970
Professor mushroom knew that and he said
that these other substances were not
psychotomimetic which was a fancy way of
saying that they didn't make you crazy
when you took them
um and that was true throughout his
career
um again he did not confine himself to
the lab and was heavily involved in
clinical Pursuits with his discoveries
um you said that he discovered
um cannabidiol before THC when he
started looking at kanabit Isle was his
first thought that that might be uh the
substance that was taught causing
intoxication and it wasn't
yeah I I don't think so there had been
some prior work actually done in the
United States by uh German Refugee named
Lo
um and cannabidiol had been
um identified almost perfectly in 1940
um but they didn't nail down the actual
three-dimensional structure until
professor micholum in 1963
um so you know they're in science
they're often these incremental
developments and we'd have to say that
that was one of them
so from the timeline that you set up of
of the different Labs uh discovering the
different cannabinoids and and figuring
out their structure and isolating them
it sounds like
um you know this time between you know
1960 in the early 70s it was like bang
bang bang one cannabinoid after another
and you know that must have been not
only like an exciting time to be doing
this initial research to finally kind of
like crack the you know cannabis secret
um but also you know THC was something
that that people could immediately tell
there was going to be medicinal use for
what was the significance like both in
science but also perhaps in society writ
large
um what was the significance of the
discovery of THC and impact at that time
well I'd like to take this on a couple
of levels I mean the its first notoriety
came as an intoxicant
um certainly
um again being an extremely educated and
well-read person Professor Michelin was
very familiar with medicinal uses of
cannabis throughout the ages and I'm
sure that the wheels were turning with
him uh very uh very quickly but
um people have to understand how
earth-shattering
um these discoveries were for example
most uh most psychoactive drugs prior to
this time were alkaloids so they were
water-soluble substances the
cannabinoids were absolutely a different
kettle of fish because they were lipid
soluble and not alkaloids I mean you
know they had no nitrogen in them so
this really was a bit strange and it
made the material very hard to handle
um you know we usually dissolve things
in water and
um you know instead you have these lipid
soluble sticky substances they're
sticking onto the glassware and
everything else it's never been easy to
work with this stuff
um yeah
uh but and again he he quickly pivoted
into looking at uh clinical indications
and probably the first one that really
came to the four
um was uh the idea of cannabidiol as an
anti-convulsant uh so you know at this
time
um he was isolating these different
components from hashish and sharing them
with other scientists and uh there was a
great collaboration between the Israelis
and the Brazilian scientists
um uh doctors cunya and Carlini on 1980
they published the first clinical study
of cannabidiols and anticonvulsant
um in nine patients and very successful
and you know I would point out that
these were all people that had failed
treatment with available drugs at that
time time
now people may be really struck by the
fact that was 1980 we didn't get
approval of cannabidiol as an
anti-convulsant as epidiolics in this
country until 2018
um so there was this huge gap of time
that he was very uh surprised and
outraged by that this work had gone on
had shown such great promise and yet got
ignored for all that time
this might be as much of a question
about the scientific method as it is
about Dr mashulum but
um what about cannabidiol
um caused Dr mashulum to air quotes
suspect that cannabidiol was an
anti-convulsant was there something in
the nature or something that he had seen
and people who who used hashish or or
was it the the structure of the molecule
itself that he could look at and
envision how that would interact with
the human body no I'm really going to
attribute to his open-mindedness what I
mean by that was he was very aware of
historical
references to cannabis as an
anticonvulsant coming from the Arab
world
um and these dated back many centuries
um so there was a suspicion that hashish
could work as an anti-convulsant and
then it was a matter of seeing what
component or components might be
responsible
and why he honed in on cannabidiol
probably was because
um uh they were aware at that time that
it wouldn't be intoxicating
uh and uh so it would have an advantage
if it worked uh it wouldn't have the
liability that can be attached to THC
now we we still experience that
difference even today sure
um so
I talk with a lot of research scientists
uh on shaping fire and more or less they
fall into three different groups
scientists that study and intoxicating
substance
um but they they never touch it
themselves because they are they are not
the kind of person who enjoys
intoxicants and then in the middle
you've you've got scientists that you
know don't use whatever it is regularly
um but they have used it to understand
what the Human Experience is and then
you've got researchers that research
drugs and they like using them as well
um did Dr mishulum use cannabis or have
any personal appreciation for it uh I'm
gonna have to equivocate a bit
um he would tell a story of first human
experiences in in trying THC
um and it went something like this they
had invited friends and colleagues so to
a dinner party and his wife Dahlia was a
is a wonderful person
had made a cake
and there were portions of 10 milligrams
of THC I think that there were 10 people
involved
five didn't show any obvious effects
five did one an anxiety reaction the
others
felt something or felt different in ways
that you might imagine uh one
um it said nothing had happened but was
laughing outrageously every few minutes
and another one said nothing happened
but never stop talking so you can draw
your own conclusions what he didn't say
in relating this story was whether he
was one of the ten but I imagine he was
I can attest to the fact that he was not
a regular user of cannabis right on
thank you for that story that's great so
um another key cannabinoid that uh Dr
Michelle miscredited for and we haven't
brought up yet is is actually one of my
favorites uh anandamide and he
discovered it in 1992. would you tell us
about the discovery of anandamide and
what it meant for endocannabinoid
Science and kind of patient Health
generally sure yeah I think we just have
to back up a little bit to 2018.
um so at that time uh William Devane in
the lab of a Lynn how lat at St Louis
University
um had discovered a cannabinoid receptor
so and I'm going to back up a little
more prior to that time uh people had no
idea how THC worked the working theory
was that it somehow
disrupted the membranes of the neurons
and the way that alcohol ethanol does
um but there were synthetic cannabinoids
that were being made and these were
stereo selective that's a way of saying
that if the molecule had one
configuration in three-dimensional space
it it worked it was intoxicating however
if it didn't have the right one it
didn't work that implied that there must
be a receptor where the thing was
working
so the search was on for a cannabinoid
receptor and again that was found in
subsequently known to us now as CB1 the
uh the cannabinoid one receptor
um so uh after that there was an all
Hands-On deck search for endogenous
ligands that's a way of saying that
people were looking for molecules within
us endogenous cannabinoids now called
endocannabinoids that would bind with
this receptor
um but again it was super difficult
um the thing that set Professor mishulam
apart was he thought the endogenous
molecules rather than being peptides
um you know short amino acid molecules
rather would have to be a lipid
um to a lodge on this receptor
um so analogous to THC
um and then things get really
interesting because there they were in
Israel this is in the lab again with
William Devane and Lumiere hanouche um
his Associates at that time
and um they looked for these endogenous
cannabinoids in pig brains now again
that's anachronistic for sure
um I can tell you that Jerusalem where
the work was done is a very Kosher City
um but there was a place in Tel Aviv
that they could get the pig brains they
said each time they went back the price
went up but after painstaking work over
a couple of years they had a tiny
fraction of this material that they
identified chemically
um
as Erica Donal ethanolamide
then they had fun deciding what the
common name of the molecule should be
as it turned out William Devane was a
Sanskrit scholar
um and um he knew that the Sanskrit word
for Bliss was Ananda so they called it
anandamide which is a great name a
beautiful coinage
and they kept looking they found other
related molecules and in 1994 they
discovered another called two Erica
Donal glycerol less flashy name just 2ag
for short that was in 95 yeah uh but uh
then again didn't stop there they found
hundreds of related molecules that
seemingly didn't do a lot on their own
um but in putting these together in
different combinations by 1998 they
figured out that there was Synergy when
you had the main players uh with these
less active or inactive uh related
molecules uh hence the concept of the
Entourage effect was born in 1998.
so um so far we have discussed
um you know maybe even a dozen at least
10 different uh cannabinoids and you
know functioning aspects of the
endocannabinoid system that Dr mishulum
is credited for
um to round out this group is there is
there anything of significance
um any other cannabinoids or that that
he discovered that we should make sure
we mentioned at this time that we
haven't so far
well again just uh to make sure we do
justice to its work uh his discoveries
included CBD THC CBG CBC
um the acid cannabinoids cbna cbda cbga
cannabis cyclol and likely a few more
um that's a great answer I couldn't have
asked for anything better thank you
so so I know kind of like you know as we
as we wrap up the first set here you
know I I know the entirety of the first
set has been how you know we've been
talking about how Dr Michelle's research
you know um changed our understanding a
very specifically of cannabis and the
endocannabinoid system on a on a level
of perspective kind of like one level of
magnitude up like what impact did this
entire body of research have on both the
scientific I don't know acceptance and
interest in cannabis and in the
attraction of more scientists to dive in
because Dr michulum's research opened up
the area
yeah I in a word it affected it
profoundly
um what we see if you track the number
of Publications on cannabinoids and the
endocannabinoid system there was a huge
growth
um in the early 90s which has continued
for for some time you know once these
molecules particularly endocannabinoids
were identified it then was a matter of
experimenting them to see where they are
and what they do and the fascinating
thing in retrospect is every organ
system every type of physiological
function that was examined there was a
role for the endocannabinoid system
so again we had uh discovery of
cannabinoid compounds then the
endogenous cannabinoids uh they had to
figure out uh how they were made and
broken down the metabolic and catabolic
enzymes how they were regulated
um so you can see how there was this
expansion sort of a pyramid effect of
research opportunities and they were
pursued around the world now
unfortunately that is not extended to
Enlightenment on the political side
nor
did it totally break down the barriers
to research which still remain in this
country admittedly it's easier to study
cannabis now than it was then but it
still remains very difficult
yeah
um that is certainly the case I I can
imagine after Dr mashulum's
um you know earliest discoveries he
never
um he never wanted for funding though uh
during his career because he sounds like
he was an early celebrity and and I just
assumed that he was well funded at that
point is that is that accurate uh up to
a point but only after a certain point
his first uh application of the National
Institutes of Health which then is now
has been the main funder of biomedical
research domestically and
internationally
but his first application was turned
down with the explanation that nobody
uses cannabis here you know this is
Circa 1963.
um then the tune changed
um partly it was because of this
discovery but additionally there seemed
to be a political uh rationale
um something the effect that a senator's
son was busted for quote marijuana
unquote
um and wanted to know if it was going to
make him permanently crazy
um all of a sudden NIH was more
interested in cannabis and cannabinoids
and for the subsequent 40 years
Professor michulum had NIH funding
annually
it's a good story all right so so we're
going to take a short break and be right
back you are listening to shaping fire
and my guest today is Dr Ethan Russo
without these advertisers shaping
firewood not happen so please support
them and let them know you heard them on
shaping fire
[Music]
the cannabis seed Market is filled with
big name and hype breeders fighting to
get your attention and occasionally you
discover a breeder who is breeding
because it is the only thing they care
to do and they would be doing it even if
they never made a dime
that's my friend Craig hartsaw who makes
seeds as magnetic genetics
Craig comes from five generations of
farmers and is earning his master's
degree in Horticulture right now he's
been growing cannabis for 15 years and
been breeding for nine
he hasn't sold many seeds because he
really isn't a sales guy but I've
personally been growing his seeds for
years and I know I can always rely on
his seeds to germinate Thrive and smell
and taste great I suggested to Craig
that he should probably sell some seeds
and asked if he had enough stockpile to
bother much to my shock he was sitting
on five full menus in Cold Storage that
he produced in the last two years and
hadn't even tried to sell any of them he
was simply too busy breeding well we his
friends convinced him to make his damn
seeds available to the people and now
they are
for the first time anywhere you can now
buy magnetic genetic seeds at Neptune
seed bank and on strainley.io
Neptune seed bank has just picked up
magnetic genetics for a trial to gauge
your interest they are carrying three
strains from his Mean Mug prominence and
turpinato menus which are exclusive to
Neptune it's an easy way to score his
seeds you can pick up those menus plus
his hillbilly skunk and Candy breath
crosses and more on his profile page on
stranely.io
if you want very affordable seeds that
are exceptional quality with rare
terpene profiles from a good guy go to
neptuneseedbank.com or strainley.io
sometimes it is fun to buy the hype
thing from the brand you admire but when
you're ready to buy The Strain you'll
love from an obscure mad scientist
you're ready for magnetic genetics
magneticgenetics.org and on Instagram
magnetic genetics
one of the reasons why no-till cannabis
growing is so valued by Farmers is
because the mycelium networks in the
soil remain established from year to
year and we know these fungal networks
are essential because they are the
nutrient super highways that extend far
and wide in the substrate to feed your
plants the trouble with growing in New
Living soils or Blended cocoa substrates
is that it takes most of the plant's
life just to create these mycelium
highways
dynomico endometrizal fungi inoculant
reduces that time and gets your plant
eating a wider array of nutrients faster
and it's three times the concentration
of the other popular brand in the U.S at
900 propagules per gram of two fungal
species selected specifically for
cannabis cultivation dynomica is the
result of 30 years of research and
trials at the volcani agriculture
Research Institute in Israel it has also
been vigorously trialed by cannabis and
food Growers across the U.S
dynamico is now available at Grow shops
and on Amazon in the United States I
love using dynamico to both speed up the
growth of the mycelium networks in the
soil but also as a biostimulant to make
clone cuttings more viral you can see
side by side showing the comparative
growth on their Instagram at dynomico if
you demand reliable growing results and
appreciate the importance of an active
root Zone in creating a thriving plan I
encourage you to check out dynomico.com
and use the store locator to find out
where you can get yours that's
d-y-n-o-m-y-c-o.com
shaping fire listeners can get 10 off
any size of dynamico on Amazon or
dynamico.com by using the discount code
shapingfire one word no caps
whether you are starting with new beds
or pots or if you want to add some Zing
to tired soil choose dynamico to
maximize your plant's potential
dynamico endomicorizal inoculant
there are so many seed banks nowadays
that you really have options and who to
choose not only that if you pick the
wrong seed bank you could be in for a
really sketchy ride and that's only one
of the reasons I recommend Gas Lamp
seeds to my friends and listeners who
are looking for a seed bank you probably
already know Gas Lamp seeds as hembra
genetics hembra recently changed their
name to Gaslamp seeds Gas Lamp seeds is
not just another seed bank Gaslamp is a
female operated Boutique cannabis
genetics provider that only sells
thoughtfully curated seeds from the top
names in cannabis breeding with over 60
breeders and over a thousand strains to
choose from you will certainly find
something you'll love Gas Lamp seeds has
something for everyone with over 650
feminized strains 300 regular varieties
and over 200 autoflowers to choose from
names you know you can trust like
compound genetics Humboldt Seed Company
Night Owl in house fast buds gnome
automatics and ethos
and we both know that there are other
seed banks who will take your money but
have no customer service
I invited Gaslamp to advertise on
shaping fire after hearing so many good
stories about them from my friends they
have a Plus customer service with
Lightning Fast Response times
in most cases Helene and Caitlin will
get your order out the same day you
place it most seed banks are simply not
this organized or interested in getting
your seeds to you so fast but Gaslamp
seeds cares you even get free seeds with
every order
Helene and Caitlin get it they have been
in the Cannabis growing scene for over a
decade want some extra freebies use the
code shapingfire all one word at
checkout and they will give you an
additional set of Gaslamp provided
freebies that's an extra thirty dollars
in free seeds
buy seeds from good folks who will send
you great seeds reliably every time
visit
gaslampseeds.com today that's Gaslamp
seeds welcome back you are listening to
shapingfire I am your host shangolos and
my guest today is Dr Ethan Russo
so during the first set we talked you
know mostly about the the timeline of Dr
michillum's discoveries and clearly how
it impacted not only the the research of
cannabis itself as a drug but in a
larger form the endocannabinoid system
and then the impacts that it had on
medical research for humans as a whole
where I want to start out here in second
set is that you know how has Dr
mushroom's research impacted the
development of of cannabis-based
medicines
um and what potential therapeutic
applications have derived from his work
so far
um you know contemporarily
yeah that's a great question I mean the
first obvious ones are uh you know the
classic cannabinoids phytocannabinoids
from the plant so at this time uh in
terms of cannabis based medicines uh we
have synthetic THC as Marinol which has
never had big impact but
um satavex is an extract of two
different chemivers of cannabis one rich
in THC and one rich in CBD
and that's approved in 30 countries
around the world for treatment of
spasticity and multiple sclerosis but
not in the U.S in the U.S
for the last few years we have had uh 98
pure cannabidiol as epidiolics for
treatment of severe epilepsy syndromes
but again
um we're looking at Future developments
related to cannabigirol canaba chromine
and many others and uh I need to extend
the conversation to talk about the
semi-synthetic analogs that Professor
Michelin made and
perhaps we could run through those yeah
please do because I'm not sure what
those are
okay well uh you know chemists like to
take a molecule and see how it might be
quote improved unquote meaning different
meaning patentable or longer lasting or
more potent so a good example there
would be what's called hu-210 so the hu
medicines were all discovered by
Professor Michelin at Hebrew University
so that's where the hu uh derives so
hu-210
um was um
a dimethyl heptal derivative of THC so
instead of just a five carbon side chain
it was a seven carbon side chain with
two methyl groups on it and that made it
more potent and longer lasting so hu 210
um is something I believe on the order
of 50 to 100 times more potent than THC
and it's been a very important agent in
laboratory studies of the
endocannabinoid system but not a drug
for clinical use
it has appeared occasionally in
synthetic cannabinoids but it's not
something I would ever recommend anybody
taking I have a colleague who did and
spent the whole weekend
um with a very big experience
let's leave it at that I'll never tell
a closely related molecule with hu211
now this one actually got into the
clinics but wasn't approved and it's a
bit of a sad story this had the name
dexa nabinol
um
this was investigated by a now defunct
company called farmos an Israeli company
they developed this for treatment of
severe head injuries the idea being that
they would give this intravenously after
someone had a severe head injury and
hopefully it would help prevent damage
from the the head trauma
um however after this was licensed to
the company
um they never consulted Professor
Michelin again
um I think that they made a big mistake
in that because they again only use this
once
um after the onset of the head injury
and and not subsequently it worked in
phase two clinical trials but in phase
three nothing uh just didn't work
um
I wonder in retrospect whether they had
given uh administered it multiple times
the result could have been different
but that's probably a done deal at this
point and then there were a variety of
agency developed that yet could make it
to the clinics
um Professor Michelin was very active in
research on CB2 the non-psychoactive
receptor that's important in pain and
inflammation
he thought that one of the things the
endocannabinoid system
did was provide
protection from non-infectious insults
are
non-immunologic insults it developed a
medicine called hu308 which is very
active at the CB2 receptor but not
activated CB1 also wouldn't be
intoxicating and that's been
investigated for arthritic conditions
um and then more recently in 2018
he came out with uh
hu580
so what this is is they took the
cannabidiolic acid molecule which is
unstable cbda and they made it a methyl
Ester
what that means is they put this group
on it that made it shelf stable and it
could be a pro drug in other words when
taken into the body it would break down
spontaneously into cbda which in testing
has shown
um very powerful
activity on the serotonin 1A receptor
where CBD also works but it's somewhere
between a hundred and a thousand times
more potent so this may have application
and treating nausea of different causes
among other things I also might have a
role in treating anxiety
but that really hasn't gotten into the
clinic yet there's still
um could be could be developments there
so I have a um a two-part question it is
a it's a request for a vocabulary
clarification but then also I would like
you to explain its use in the lab and
here's here is what it is
um you began the answer talking about
the Cannabis analogs that Dr mishulum
had created and so when you said that
I'm like all right that sounds like
synthetic cannabinoids uh to me and
we've discussed uh both you and I and
then and then on other episodes about
how synthetic cannabinoids can be useful
in the lab but
um it's not as great when they get out
of the lab and people try to take them
as if they're from nature and they're
not but so you started by describing
these these analogs that Dr Michelin was
making and then you described these
agents that Dr michulum was making and
then you seem to contrast and say and
also synthetic cannabinoids where if he
made them it sounds like they're all
synthetic cannabinoids so so the first
part of the answer I'd like you to tease
those apart but then second for people
who have never thought about the use of
synthetic cannabinoids in in research in
the lab only but not actually used out
in the real world would you explain what
that that lab tool is for sure
uh so again of the ones I mentioned hu
210 was the only one that was a CB1
Agonist so you know would cause
intoxication so hu 210 and related drugs
in the lab would be used to look at
binding
um so say you had an unknown substance
you wanted to compare its activity to
something it could be compared to hu 210
as as one example whether your new
substance could displace hu 210 from the
receptor compete with it so it'd be a
measure of potency
um and you know you're correct I have
decried the use of high potency CB1
Agonist says potentially quite dangerous
but these other agents hu211 308 580
were all for entirely different purposes
and really would have no activity on the
CB1 receptor
I see so so it sounds like analog agent
and synthetic cannabinoids are probably
in the same bucket but we delineate
between them because some of them are
for you solely in the lab and and and
should not be used outside by for people
for either medicinal or recreational
reasons but then the other ones are also
synthetic but they're also promising as
as actual healthy medicines and so we we
just refer to them differently then
quite right okay great right cool thank
you
um so
uh well while Dr michulum's role was
clearly set in Pharmaceuticals right you
and I have spoken on this program often
about our our both of ours belief in
whole plant medicine whole plant
cannabis resin what were Dr mishulum's
personal thoughts about whole plant
medicine and using the whole resin
instead of isolating compounds and then
mix and matching them to make something
patentable since he worked in the
pharmaceutical realm but also his heart
was in pure medicine
uh and you know he straddled Both Worlds
um
part of uh the time that we work most
closely together was between
um 2003 and 2014 we were both uh working
actively uh with GW Pharmaceuticals
um they would have an annual research
meeting uh which uh he attended I
attended uh as an uh scientific senior
medical advisor at that time to the
company
um you know so we worked with people at
the company and also with other
cannabinoid scientists mainly European
and get together and talk about projects
and plans and a lot of what we know now
about cannabidiol cannabigirol and the
others came from that research
so he absolutely understood and aided
the development of these whole plant
medicines uh side effects and
epidialytics
um at the same time he was working on
the semi-synthetic analogues
um I would highlight a point of
difference perhaps uh he and I
um I'm not so sure he was absolutely
convinced
of the role of the terpenoids uh in
cannabis uh you may recall I pointed out
in 1998 he had coined the term with
Professor Ben Shabbat uh of the
Entourage effect initially applied to
endogenous cannabinoids the next year
the same pair published another article
and pointed out that the same thing
could apply to cannabis the idea that
plants might be better medicines than
their single components well I I already
felt that way and I really seized upon
this and although some people have
misattributed coining the term the
Entourage effect me I didn't I may have
popularized it through my efforts to
show the Synergy between terpenoids and
cannabinoids I think he needed a little
more convincing at the time in 1999 they
pointed out that this idea that plants
could be better medicine than single
compounds was a theory but in the
ensuing 24 years we've had a lot of
proof for that theory
so you know a good scientist
um is thinking about possibilities and
also retaining an air of skepticism I
think that's necessary sometimes you
have to play Devil's Advocate with your
colleagues or with yourself
well yeah because the whole point is
that we're hypothesizing we don't want
to go into it assuming we're right so we
have to we have to be our own doubles
Advocate sure yeah so much has changed
in cannabis research in the last decade
of Dr michulum's life like what was Dr
mashulum's opinion on the current state
of cannabis research and the potential
for new discoveries in the field
well I he never stopped working
um you know he continued throughout his
career to find new things to do uh We've
mentioned many of his accomplishments
but uh in more recent decades
um he worked uh with the late etai Bob
on
endocannabinoids and their role in
treating osteoporosis he did some
clinical work on cannabidiol for graph
versus host disease that affects
transplant patients
um and it it really never ended again
the more recent work on making the
methyl Esters of the acid cannabinoids
to make them more stable
and also the important work on the CB2
receptor done with Paul Parker who's at
the National Institutes of Health and
the idea that the endocannabinoid system
provided protection from non-infectious
insults so it never ended
um so the the wording of this question
is is kind of um I guess juvenile but uh
I think the point of it is good uh you
know as as
cannabinoid research expanded here in
the last you know 15 years or so did did
Dr michulum
was he at all annoyed that there were
people who were not approaching cannabis
medicine properly in some way because
there were so many people to it or was
he generally thinking that this was
badass that there were all these
different types of scientists looking
into it
ah
you know he was not prone to criticize
that often however he was quite uh
willing to decry the dearth of clinical
work
um that had gone on in in any number of
areas uh you know this is certainly
manifest by the fact that again here's a
bench scientist
um with uh uh a lifetime record of
accomplishment and when the
International Association for
cannabinoid medicines a clinical group
was begun in 2001 he was right there at
every meeting
um and um contributing
um and encouraging people to do more
work so that was another place that uh
we we got together uh all told I tallied
it up
um after word of his demise and he and I
were together at meetings or working
together and at least 14 different
countries
that actually must have been a pretty
heartfelt list that you worked on after
his passing last week you bet yeah
um to wrap up this set I was curious you
know we you told that great story about
about you know the cake but how did Dr
michulum view the use of cannabis for
recreational purposes like in society
um and and has his research affected his
stance over the years
um yeah a little bit of a tough one it's
not something he talked about a lot you
know my impression would be that he
thought that a lot of it was a
distraction
um and he was laser focused on clinical
applications
um for this system
um so he he wasn't a prohibitionist
um overtly in any kind of sense
um but I think
you know far more interesting to him was
how can we harness these substances uh
to treat disease
yeah I can see him being all listen I'm
trying to get the labs going I'm trying
to get funding and you guys getting
busted for illegal weed is in the news
that it's not helpful and so not not
that he's necessary so yeah right he was
he was never so overt about it but I I'm
sure he may have harbored internal
feelings of a similar nature yeah I can
follow that all right thank you so we're
going to take another short break and be
right back you're listening to shaping
fire and my guest today is Dr Ethan
Russo
[Music]
there are a lot of good people launching
new businesses in cannabis psilocybin
and other psychedelics and it's very
strange Time For Us in the same moment
that psilocybin mushrooms are illegal at
the federal level they are becoming
increasingly legal in States across the
country these businesses leading the way
into the future of plant medicines
require specialized legal representation
by attorneys who have depth not only in
litigation mergers and Acquisitions but
also in psychedelic and other plant
medicines
green light Law Group has been
empowering cannabis businesses since
2014 and as the market has Diversified
into psilocybin and other plant
medicines green light has been right
there evolving with their diverse
clients to provide legal expertise with
a high level of legal Acumen creative
strategy and precision that comes with
an intimate and specific understanding
of both business law and plant medicine
if you are a business owner trying to
navigate the layered local and National
Drug Laws on your own you are at risk of
fumbling these confusing and quickly
changing laws complicate everything
green light law group is ready to help
you when hit with a lawsuit or because
you were shafted by a vendor or business
partner or simply because you want to
stay legal and could use some
preventative guidance before cultivating
a controlled substance as an
entrepreneur
green light law group is a collection of
folks who care profoundly about their
work and I know this is true because I
know the folks from Green Light
there is a huge difference between a big
legal firm who has decided to start
representing a few drug companies versus
working with a collection of high
integrity passionate lawyers who are
personally interested in new plant
medicines and firmly believe in their
power to heal
contact Greenlight Law Group today and
learn more about the services they can
offer your industry-leading cannabis or
psychedelics company that's green light
Law Group at greenlightlawgroup.com
online cannabis seed Distributors often
seem to be all the same but Multiverse
beans constantly Works to provide you
with cannabis seeds and a buying
experience that you won't find elsewhere
Multiverse beans Works directly with the
Breeders to secure as many packs of your
favorites as possible so that they have
your favorite beans long after others
have sold out some shops simply buy
breeder minimums but I get messages all
the time from breeders saying some
version of Multiverse has to buy my
entire run
at multiversebeans.com you can find rare
cannabis seeds from Night Owl seeds
including the dark owl sub label
Mephisto genetics Square One genetics
Robin Hood seeds and Ethos and so many
others
Multiverse also initiates projects with
breeders to secure exclusive packs that
you simply won't find elsewhere
Multiverse founder Paul lall sees
himself not only as a curator of the
best cannabis seeds available but also
as a collaborator with breeders trying
to bring novel crosses to the market
that his customers are asking for
Multiverse beans also creates exclusive
stickers for their popular seed
varieties that are available free only
when you order those seeds from
Multiverse
check out their stickers like the badass
recent slap for Mothman by gnome
automatics on Instagram at Multiverse
beans and finally the freebies as you'd
expect Paul sends quality freebies with
every order and when you spend at least
150 dollars Multiverse allows you to
choose your freebies from their special
selections
you can get a 10 discount off regularly
priced items when you use the discount
code shaping fire all one word at
checkout
sign up for their mailing list to be
eligible for their monthly seed giveaway
worth 250 dollars so go to
multiversebeans.com now for a buying
experience you won't get anywhere else
[Music]
as cannabis regulations become more
demanding and consumers become more
educated it is increasingly important to
avoid the use of chemical pesticides
when cultivating cannabis beneficial
insects have been used for decades by
the greenhouse vegetable and ornamental
plant industry and today many cannabis
cultivators are moving from sprays and
chemicals to beneficial insects
copert has the beneficial insects mites
and nematodes microbials sticky cards
and air distribution units you need to
partner with nature to defend your
garden whether you manage Acres of
canopy or have a simple grow tent in
your home culprit is ready to help
answer your questions and help you
transition away from chemical sprays
towards clean and natural solutions
since 1967 corporate has assisted
growers in identifying pests and
devising reliable Solutions while
providing healthy insects and mites that
will protect your yield
since the 1990s covert has been a leader
in cannabis Pest and Disease Control
worldwide and have highly trained
Consultants to assist you in Canada and
the United States from coast to coast
with their Global Network of grower
support covert can help visit copper.com
choose your country and get detailed
information that's covert
k-o-p-p-e-r-t.com
for the most up-to-date cannabis related
biological control information you can
also check their Instagram at covert
Canada
you know getting away from pesticides is
good for health and good for business
and culprit is ready to help visit
covert.com today
welcome back you are listening to
shapingfire I am your host shangolos and
my guest today is Dr Ethan Russo
so Ethan how has Dr michulum's work
impacted the development of new drug
therapies Beyond cannabis I can imagine
that there are other areas of medicine
that are benefiting from his research
uh again
um
the
endocannabinoid system is ubiquitous it
is the major homeostatic regulator of
human physiology and that of all higher
animals
um so it's had a huge impact
unfortunately that has an extended
towards education of medical students on
the system and its importance
um so again you know this idea that
there were these lipid molecules rather
than water solid soluble molecules the
cannabinoids led to a real expansion
um you know the endocannabinoid system
isn't really confined to the two known
cannabinoid receptors it's become a much
broader concept and includes a number of
the trip receptors and even some of the
serotonin receptors particularly
serotonin 1A which I'm happy to say was
an extension of work that I did with
colleagues at the University of Montana
back in 2005.
um so it it's been an ever expanding
it's like the tendrils of the plant have
extended and all these areas of science
it's been an amazing thing to see
over the 30 years since the discovery of
the endocannabinoid system
you know that's one of the reasons why
some people are even skeptical or
suspicious of cannabis because they say
oh you people talk about it like it's a
Panacea it's like like as if it's going
to solve all these things and and that
only comes from people who don't
understand the endocannabinoid system
because that is the whole point it's
everywhere and so by working with
cannabinoids you can work on all these
different ailments and
um I don't I don't think that the
skepticism for that is going to be
overcome until more people are familiar
with how the endocannabinoid system
actually functions
quite right you know again it it's
important to say there really aren't a
lot of things that cannabis cures
however there are tremendous number of
things that cannabis treats effectively
at least as an adjunct if not directly
so what was
what did Dr Michelin feel was like the
most rewarding aspect of his uh career I
mean uh his his list of of recognitions
and awards are it's a long list but but
the list of what he achieved is
different than the achievements that he
himself was most proud of
well you know that's a hard one for me
to say
um he was not the kind of guy that uh
rested on his proverbial Laurels
um there was always more work to do so I
don't think it's something you dwell on
um you know when we look at this list of
accomplishments over the course of six
decades it's astounding but the obvious
pattern is the guy never quit working uh
or thinking about what's next
um so I to me it was a role model in
that regard
um you know it's to an extent if I can
compare myself it's the same thing when
I get a paper accepted for publication
I'm happy for a little while but
um thinking about what's next
um
the Restless mind syndrome while Dr
mishula was involved in cannabis policy
Creation in Israel much more than ever
in the United States
um what advice do you think Dr Michele
would give to U.S policy makers and
Regulators regarding the regulation of
cannabis and cannabis based medicines
I think it'd be really concise and that
would be to follow the science
um again I have no doubt that he had uh
pervasive uh skepticism about the
ability of politicians to incorporate
the kind of scientific knowledge that
was going on in this area
um but I I don't remember him wasting a
lot of time with criticism of that uh
there might be some remark in passing
but again
his concentration was always on
advancement of the science
um so so looking forward I mean clearly
Dr mishulum mentored so many and and he
even mentored so many people who never
met him right who who knew him through
his research and his interviews what
advice do you think that Dr Michelin
would give to Young researchers
interested in studying cannabis and its
compounds now
well I think the first thing he'd say
was expect to work hard
um it is a very deep and uh difficult
field I mean the thing that attracted me
when I really got into it Circa 1996 was
uh boy this is complex but it's all so
exciting
um and uh boy I became addicted to
cannabinoid knowledge very quickly and
led to a career change and that's
happened to plenty of other scientists
and Physicians
um but
um you know I have to really identify
his personal role uh in this because
um the thing that most people met or uh
corresponded with Dr Michelle and will
tell you was how availing he was of
um his time in helping them with
whatever question they posed to him
um so I've met hundreds of people not
just scientists who said you know I
wrote to him and I was shocked he got
back to me and you know or even we
talked on the phone or zoom and he gave
me all this time and people are just
blown away by that but that's the way he
was
um and she explained he didn't didn't
have a lot of hobbies but he was always
willing to talk about this
um so it's it's kind of an amazing set
of circumstances that Dr mishulum
you know even got to be a researcher his
his family was persecuted by the Nazis
his father was placed in a concentration
camp and survived and eventually Dr
mushroom found his way to Israel where
you know we all know his research
blossomed of course as a Jewish person
this would have been part of his culture
and his awareness of his entire life in
what ways do you think it influenced his
life choices or even research choices
that that his his he he grew up in
persecuted times
um yeah you know because we had so much
one-on-one time uh these were things I
got to talk to him about you know is his
early experiences and what they went
through in the war
um you know basically
um Bulgaria
um was occupied by the Nazis early on
um there was a certain uh well definite
level of of collaboration a very strange
situation uh developed um in that King
Boris in Bulgaria uh decided that they
would protect the Jews of Bulgaria to an
extent but they had invaded Macedonia
next door and basically allowed uh even
collaborated with the Nazis in
um in sending the Jews of Macedonia to
the death camps treblanca uh in most
instances
there went uh all of my family on my
father's side with the exception of my
grandfather
um so
um
you know it was a difficult situation as
you mentioned it is his father spent
time in a concentration camp but when it
burned down and he helped the people
that were victims of that they decided
to let him go
um but uh after the war Bulgaria became
a communist country that was again
increase in anti-Semitism and um that's
when he emigrated to Israel in 1949.
came out of this
um
again it's not something he dwelled upon
however I think that
um it probably caused him to take
nothing for granted uh in life he was an
extremely open-minded person
um he also wasn't tainted by politics
which is is so easy to have happen
um you know I can give a lot of examples
uh in in 1999 when I met Professor
Michelin I also met uh Professor
mahmudel Saleh from the University of
Mississippi
uh who was an Egyptian and I wondered
geez how are these guys going to get
along but in fact they've been
colleagues forever and um you know uh
the politics of their uh
their Nations never entered into their
relationship also when I went to do
research on cannabis in Morocco in 2002
I was delighted with how curious people
were about professor micheliner and the
reverence that they had for him so it
really transcended politics uh finally
uh Professor micholum had Palestinian
researchers in his lab
um you know and again there uh the
business was science it wasn't politics
it reminds me of of how you referred to
his his thought that he wasn't as
interested in the in the you know he he
thought that science should inform
regulations and policy I can imagine him
having that same idea about politics and
and race and how he interacted with
others where where it's like the science
was was the priority and and and it's
better for us to all be I'll be friends
and focus on the science than letting
the that the rest of the world into our
lab to to slow us down you bet yeah
so I'd like to finish this episode
um with um you know a bit of a personal
question for you I really appreciate
um the time that you've offered us
um and and sharing your your personal
stories of Dr michulum you know
obviously the two of you were such good
friends as to feel like family and uh
I'm curious what was Dr Michele's impact
on you as both a cannabis researcher but
also as a human being
uh well he was a role model in every
respect he was a very magnanimous and
magnetic guy uh very warm
um funny
uh you know I mentioned we had this
immediate Bond as fellow Sephardic Jew
um I considered him like my surrogate
Uncle he was 22 years older than me uh
he looked a little bit like my father
um you know for all I know we could have
been genetic cousins on some level
um because it was interchange during the
Ottoman era between it was a Bulgarian
Macedonia were all part of the Ottoman
Empire at that time but
um you know it was a great relationship
and uh I miss him I was really proud
um that he asked me to write the first
chapter of his last book in 2005
um he thought that they needed an
article on the history of cannabis and
that
should begin with one of the oldest
cannabis cultures in India and as it
happened I had this huge amount of data
it amassed with nowhere to go and here
he asked me to write a book chapter and
so I I was very pleased with that
also uh he provided me with what I think
is one of the best compliments I've ever
had in my life
um it was probably about 2008 we were at
a conference in London together and he
tried to introduce me to somebody
already knew uh your garage the
Swiss scientists and he said something
the effect that of I'd like you to meet
my friend Ethan Russo and then he said
he has many crazy ideas and I I left
like hell because if he knew Rafi that
was a great compliment and I certainly
took it as such
um yeah that's that's a beautiful story
and I can imagine that you know right
now in this this you know week or two
after his passing
um those types of thoughts are
are heavy you know on your heart as as
you you know look back and appreciate
your friendship so thank you Ethan for
um you know taking the time to discuss
uh Dr mashulum with us and sharing your
personal stories because
um you know as we all know over time
um you know history changes and and
people forget and it's very important to
um to record these people who mean so
much to us so so that we can remember
them as as as they were so thank you
Ethan amen
all right so uh you dear listener if you
would like to uh hear more from Dr Russo
and I think you do
um I've got a bunch of places for you to
check out
um at the top of the list is uh you can
go check out uh Dr Russo's company where
um he does research that's uh krato
science and that's a CREDO Dash
science.com
um you can also find uh
ethanrusso.org and if you go to the
library tab you can see all of Ethan's
papers there under that Tab and which is
really convenient if you want to um look
at his work without you know trying to
find out you know where the papers are
online and trying to get permissions to
download them and all that kind of stuff
Ethan's a big fan of of having as as
many of his papers available as possible
um if you would like to reach out to
Ethan directly he always offers his
email address which is Ethan Russo at
comcast.net and you know I just want to
say that Ethan you know I think yes it
gets back to everybody or at least tries
to get back to everybody but also
realize that he is inactive everyday
researcher still and so sometimes it
takes him a while to get back with folks
and um you know you might you might not
get the reply you want until he's you
know stuck in an airport somewhere for a
couple hours
um and then uh there's a great series on
the shaping fire YouTube channel uh the
Ethan Russo shaping fire sessions which
is a series of uh 10 short videos on an
array of topics that I thought were
being under under considered in cannabis
and so Ethan and I sat down in his front
room and he addressed those various
topics and then finally
um you know I don't think anybody has
appeared on shaping fire as much as
Ethan have has and there's I think
there's uh either six or seven just
fantastic episodes
um where Ethan shares his research on
you know a range of topics from uh
cannabis terpenes the endocannabinoid
systems psilocybin migraines I mean it's
all like really juicy stuff so I
recommend you go back and and check out
the the shaping fire catalog of episodes
um you get this easily searchable if you
just put Ethan Russo in and it'll pop
them all up for you
you can find more episodes of the
shaping fire podcast And subscribe to
the show at shapingfire.com and wherever
you get your podcasts if you enjoyed the
show we'd really appreciate it if you
would leave a positive review of the
podcast wherever you download your
review will help others find the show so
they can enjoy it too on the shapingfire
website you can also subscribe to the
newsletter for insights into the latest
Cannabis News exclusive videos and
giveaways on the shipping fire website
you also find transcripts of today's
podcast as well be sure to follow on
Instagram for all original content not
found on the podcast that's at
shapingfire and at shangolos on
Instagram be sure to check out
shapingfire YouTube channel for
exclusive interviews farm tours and
cannabis lectures does your company want
to reach our national audience of
cannabis enthusiasts email hotspot
shippingfire.com to find out how thanks
for listening to shapingfire I've been
your host shangolos
foreign