[Music]
the breeding of cannabis seeds is
elegant and thoughtful and inspired and
we've talked about that here before but
actually doing the work to bring those
seeds to market can be brutal
after you go through the work of
carefully crafting and breeding your
seed stock you still have to sort and
quality check thousands of seeds design
packaging and haven't manufactured
assemble the final product Rock the
social media to reach out and inspire
fans reach out to stores and online
retailers to carry your seeds travel all
across the country to attend shows pay
extra for everything because you're a
cannabis company and deal with thieves
and grifters and folks wanting to test
your seeds and this is all before you've
been paid even a dime for any of your
breeding talent any kind of startup is
hard I know
but a new cannabis seed startup is
usually a one-person job until the
company grows enough to hire help it's
grueling hours lots of travel and it
requires an incredible amount of
patience if you want to learn about
cannabis health business and technique
efficiently and with good cheer I
encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter we'll send you a new podcast
episode as they come out delivered right
to your inbox along with commentary and
a couple of the most important news
items from the week and videos too don't
rely on social media to let you know
what a new episode is published sign up
for the updates to make sure you don't
miss an episode
also we're giving away very cool prizes
to folks who are signed up to receive
the newsletter there's nothing else you
need to do to win except receive the
newsletter this month I'm really stoked
that give we're giving away several
newly released air vape X vaporizers
from air vape usa.com
go to shaping feiyr.com to sign up for
the newsletter before june 30th and be
entered into this month's and all future
newsletter prize drawings also remember
that we have a thriving youtube channel
too with original content separate from
what you hear on the podcast right now
we're featuring a series of interview
questions with Kevin Jo Durie of
Wonderland nursery we have nearly a
hundred videos that you will see nowhere
else so check it out at youtube-dot-com
forward-slash Angello's or just search
shaping fire on YouTube you are
listening to shaping fire and I'm your
to Shango Laos my guest today is Eric
Wimber Eric is founder breeder and head
of operations of dungeons vault genetics
his boutique cannabis seeds company is
sweeping the industry with a unique line
of pungent and potent cannabis strains
his strains have won over ten cannabis
cups in just the last two years
including first place just recently in
the 2018 Aloha Cup in Hawaii today we're
gonna talk about the seed game welcome
to the show Eric hey thanks for having
me I appreciate it well you know let's
let's go ahead and start right at the
beginning right because part of what we
want to talk about today is is the arc
that somebody who wants to start a seed
company would take from deciding that
they want to you know climb this hill
versus you know when they were starting
to win cups so so where did you learn
your skills did you have a have a mentor
or an internship how did you get into
the scene you know basically from the
time I was a young kid on I think I just
had a really a very piqued interest in
cannabis I was you know I was turned on
to it by a neighbor who he showed me
some killer herb and he was very into
High Times Magazine back he kind of
showed me that kind of got me going and
I really started focusing a lot of my
attention on to the different strains
and and all these different varieties of
you know canvassed around the world I
think it was until I hooked up with a
guy that introduced me to que estés from
granddaddy that I that I really took a
stance toward the breeding aspect I
thought about it before it was never
really something that I've considered I
always thought it was gonna be a lot
harder and I left that up for the pros
to do so it was kind of out of sight out
of mind but working with granddaddy it
kind of it kind of opened up the doors
it showed me you know what what people
were after I I knew I wanted to create
things that I wanted to smoke and I
figure if I'm putting things out that I
like to smoke other people would enjoy
it as well so that's sort of how it went
he he had some falling out with some
employees and so I was upgraded from a
seed rep and online you know sales guy
to full-blown breeder for kin and so
that that that sort of put a fire under
my ass and and really brought the light
on the whole suit
you Asian you know I think that's a good
thing to point out to that you started
at the bottom right you started doing
sales for somebody else there's a lot of
people who who want to get into well
every part of this industry they want to
start at the top right and it's like no
man you know a lot of people you start
at the bottom and you learn your skills
that way when you go ahead to start your
own business you've already done all the
jobs from you know sweeten sweeping the
floors all the way up and it gives you
better skills to run the company so so
when you were you know air quotes
breeding at at granddaddy what did that
actually involved were you doing big
sips or was this more like manufacturing
lines that were pre-existing I came on
board with literally absolutely nothing
we had we had all of our original clone
stock was stripped from us the guys who
were working with him out in Oakland and
NorCal they all literally left one day
they just every that everyone grabbed
their [ __ ] and left and just left him
high and dry so it was it was it was a
weird situation and he knew that he was
a you know we had a very popular brand
we were doing really well at attitude
seedbank
he needed some help so I basically
started over with everything I had we
had we had our GDP line which we were
most known for so I used a GDP male and
another male which was a Tahoe G times
granddaddy purp and that that was our
pretty much our our bread and butter and
that started the whole new line we did I
did I think 11 or 12 new strains for him
recreated the Candy Land which was lost
they they they lost that one completely
so what I redid it and again made it you
know sold out right on you know it's
kind of funny a lot of people say oh you
know somebody or other they got they got
a break right and it's like yeah this
you definitely got a break but you had
already been there for a long time slang
in somebody else's seeds and you just
happen to be there for the break right
and that's you know people say oh that's
luck well you know that's putting in
your time oh yeah no I start at the
bottom I was there was there were there
was uh years two three plus years of me
literally not getting paid anything but
seeds and then getting to you know I got
to keep
part of my sales but that sales are made
by me driving around all over the state
and you know hitting the hitting the
stores hard you know back when medical
days was going on so I was hitting up
every single store from Olympia to
Seattle and above there trying to sell
them seed so it was one of those things
like I had to put a lot of time and
effort in before I was even granted the
that the opportunity to breed for him
and even then that came with a lot of
you know there was a lot of things
attached to it you know and a lot of
drama and a lot of things that you might
not expect so I kind of had a not not a
shoe-in that's definitely not the word
to say but I kind of had we since we
already had a good thing going I it
couldn't have been
it couldn't worked out better is what
I'm getting at because we we had already
had the ball was already rolling whereas
if someone who was just getting started
it's gonna be a hell of a lot harder to
just pop up in the scene bag hi I'm a
new breeder take my stuff you know it's
you it takes a little bit to get
accepted yeah yeah yeah and it's funny
how much staying in cannabis is not
getting sucked into drama especially you
know in the seed scene right there's so
much drama in seeds that that a lot of
the work is actually not getting
yourself sucked into that politics very
much so I mean it's a I I might have a
little bit of a problem to keep in my
mouse at at times because it's hard you
you have so so many people that want to
give their opinion and say something
completely negative or off-topic and
just basically just talk [ __ ] so it's
it's it's it's one of those things you
can be the bigger person and say you
know I'm not gonna say am I gonna
respond
give them the pleasure of it you know or
you can just like you know what I'm
gonna go different route I'm just gonna
be the guy that sticks up for himself
and and I'll just say what's on my mind
cuz I don't really even I care of people
think of me obviously but I want them to
know that I'm not gonna just be a
pushover if you have something to say
I'll say something right back I treat
people with you know as much respect as
you'll give me and we can all be friends
but it's it's very very drama-filled
industry I tell you what it's like it's
like high school over again there's
clicks there's people that they shaking
your hand you're talking everything's
all good as you walk away it's [ __ ] that
guy it really it really it really just
depends but yeah it's it's a good thing
it's probably best to just stay out of
the drama just kind of
focus on your brand I should probably
take my own advice a bit more but yeah
it's it's it's really it's cutthroat
industry man really is yeah so so at
some point you're working over at
granddaddy and you had this idea like
you know what I want to grow the kind of
stuff I want to breed the kind of stuff
that I want to smoke did that would that
happen early on when you were still
selling or did that did that idea occur
to you once you had already started
breeding at Ken's
I think a little bit of both really
because it he knowing what we want to
achieve and and my own knowledge he he
only gave me the opportunity I was given
based on him seeing how I I treated the
weed how I talked about it he could see
I was passionate I had a lot of
knowledge in the in the in the strain
history of strains excuse me
so he was very into my opinion and what
I could come up with and so I think he
was as soon as I started talking to him
and showing him he just trusted me from
the jump and knew that there was gonna
be some good things that came from it
and sure enough they did so we had some
good things come a lot of a lot of
really popular strains some of the lines
like I said before we're totally sold
out on attitude and and continued to be
as long as we could produce the seeds
they were gone so it was it was good was
there some time that there was an
overlap between when you started
dungeons vault and were still over at
granddaddy or did you do was there a
clean break between the two oh it was
100% clean break I mean I don't want to
get into too much of the the Nitty
Gritty of what happened but at the same
time it's a it's it's it's all over the
internet about what happened I was
working with Ken we had a big falling
out and it is just like any other job I
called him up and said hey you know what
this is me putting my resignation and I
wish you the best but I'm out and that
was that was when I immediately broke
ties with them it was December of 2014
when that happened and literally the
idea was already sparked in my head of
dungeons of all genetic scientists the
name around you know back in like 2009
to actually it was red eye and ready red
eyed yeah he I had joked him about it
and so it was as soon as I broke away
from Ken the idea was just it was
already there and I
jumped with it immediately all right so
let's let's take us back to that day so
so you you've decided that you are on
your own feet now and dungeons fault is
is going to be real as of today because
you had just given your notice what were
the things that you determine were the
first things that you needed to get done
because because obviously you need you
needed to not only get the brand up and
running but you also needed to get
something out to be able to make some
money at the same time so what were your
task priorities at that point well it's
that's a very question because that
that's kind of where the where I had a
little bit of trouble at early on stages
me starting a company and this is
exactly what I was telling you about
earlier anybody can make seeds but you
come to the market with them and all of
a sudden it's who are you and how did
you get this and who you know where'd
you get your stuff and how did you breed
these there's a ton of questions to come
with it but what really happened was I I
literally knew immediately that you know
I mean I have I had leftover stock that
wasn't you know taken from me
when I gave can a ton of stuff to go
sell and that was part of the reason we
had a big breakup because I never ended
up getting paid for you know a very
large quantity of seeds were going out
to to Europe so I never got my pay on
that so that was kind of what started
the whole you know split up but I still
had stock left over from granddaddy days
so basically I rebranded and then that
was part of the reason people were
having troubled me because they're like
well you broke away from granddaddy but
used to have the same strains as
granddaddy and you stole them which in
all reality I never stole a thing I
worked strange for him I did the work I
did everything under my roof with my
money my lights everything so nothing
was stolen but it was just odd for
people to see me coming out with the
same exact ones that I'd already
released under granite II so the biggest
priority for me at that time was get new
strains that separates yourself from him
from you know the whole the split needs
to happen and be completely clean you
know and have your own line that can
that you're coming out with with your
own ideas your own strains you did and
with no one else's into it and that's
exactly what I did yeah I can see how
that would be you know both confusing
because because you're feeling legit you
weren't feeling guilty at all or that
you had done something wrong but but the
buying Publix all like hey man this is
kind of weird right so so as fast as you
could put those strains behind you and
have your own thing going the better so
so in those early days right well
actually let's let's start with the
ultra basic question where the name
comes up for dungeons of all genetics
cuz it's you know it's a pretty unique
thing you know it's not like you know
some kind of generic cannabis name like
there's so many of them where'd it come
no yeah no I don't know man I I swear
there's did for me
cannabis has been you know as some
people could say hallucinogens open the
doors for certain things for their art
or whatever well cannabis is made me a
very creative person I think really when
it comes down to names and even my stray
names or how I came up with dungeons of
all it's all it's all comes together
with me just sitting around and smoking
a joint or just thinking to myself about
how what sounds good or what sounds cool
let me say this right now I am NOT a
Dungeons &amp; Dragons fan I don't mind if
you if you play Dungeons &amp; Dragons
whether you were a child and played it
and loved it or you're into it as an
adult that's fine but I just that was
not my thing I never really rolled those
dice but dungeons and dungeons vault
genetics was something that came up like
I said back in that he was oh nine I was
online I was I was making a joke about
all these guys that were talking about
starting up a seed company I was like oh
this satis and you guys are all just
kind of started oh my might as well do
it too and I said I must start dungeons
of all genetics and it was literally a
joke like I was joking when I said it
but I really had thought about the name
I thought it was a cool name but I was
already working with Ken at granddaddy
and I had no no desire to leave at the
time you know everything was fine we
were doing great we were killing it so
that I had no no plan on leaving but
over time it just started making more
and more sense but that's literally it's
just I can't say a ton of thought went
into it just just enough to I thought
the name was cool and I just wanted to
really think about you know man I guess
really if you think about the done a
dungeon is a cool dark place where they
keep you know prisoners so nothing about
cannabis has to do with you know we
don't wanna think about being locked up
and that's not really what I was going
with but the dungeon is a place that's
you know it's it's locked up it's kept
it's it's under control you know so the
vault even even more so it's a locked up
vault it's in the dungeon it's kept away
it's to seek its
secret place whatever so those strange
those genetics are kept up and locked up
and now they're being released to the
community so that's kind of where I was
going with it
yeah right on that makes a lot of sense
and it's funny that it just started as
an online you know STONER joke but then
yeah day came that you needed a name or
like [ __ ] I guess I already have a
name let's just go with it exactly I
mean it really it was as simple as that
I said Wow well this couldn't work it's
funny that's how life works sometimes
some you you think about something or
you put an idea down on paper and and
you you might look at it a couple times
here never you don't really think that
it's going to actually be something that
happens and then all of a sudden it just
it's when the time's right things work
together but I always say things happen
for a reason and this this worked out
and it's worked out for the better so so
I've only seen your your seed packaging
for say like the last three seasons or
so and and the art were I mean it's but
it's pulled together right we'll talk
more about packaging itself in in a
couple minutes but like as far as like
the graphic design of your brand you
know you can tell when I see a pack of
seeds I can tell it's yours that your
stuff has all got a similar aesthetic to
it is that something that you developed
yourself or do you work closely with a
graphic designer who's helping you know
you kind of line all this stuff up a
little bit of both actually you know so
let me only answer a few different ways
so originally the dvg logo my shield
logo and the script logo that has become
so popular that's on every one of my
packaging on my clothing everything was
actually done by the breeder at bay
exclusives my buddy who Bay exclusive
seeds or Bay exclusive genetics out of
Oregon he he worked with me very closely
he's a good friend of mine he designed
the dvg logo for me and we kind of
talked about and he helped me get the
get that going so he did that logo for
me and then everything after that I
worked very closely with with a graphic
artist I have locally and then he does
all the print and excuse me but then did
my designer is actually 420 friendly
illustrations and he's the guy that's
been doing a lot of my art recently and
has helped with my citrus farmer logo
that dr. gonzo the full-metal-jacket and
he'll continue to help me with these
designs
he's an incredible artist with crazy
talent it's nice to that you can get
people that have gotten mad talent
freelance right cuz like you know yeah
when a company gets big enough sure you
can bring designers in-house but but
it's nice to be able to to work with
somebody who that you respect and
produces good work but not necessarily
have to pay them for all of their time
you can pay them for the time that you
need them yeah exactly I mean it good if
you had a full-time artist on deck that
was sitting there and always I mean I
would be paying so much stinking money
but what it really comes down to is each
design this guy does it's he's doing
he's doing a ton of work for other
people so when I need something done I
give him some notice in advance we sit
there we talk about what the concept is
and then we shoot back and forth ideas
and I swear it's like by the time it's
done it's like get out of my head you
you he literally it's so perfect and
it's so exactly what I wanted to
represent that I couldn't I couldn't ask
for a better artist really right not
good that's an awesome shout out so hey
let's go ahead and take our first short
break and be right back you're listening
to shaping fire and my guest today is
Eric Weber founder of dungeons of all
genetics as a listener of shaping fire
you already understand the importance of
living soil when growing cannabis when
you have active microbe communities in
your substrate you go way beyond simply
fertilizing with nitrogen phosphorus and
potassium having active microorganisms
in your substrate supports vigorous
plant growth throughout the plants root
zone making for higher yields and
thriving flowers mammoth pee is the
first organically derived microbial
inoculant that focuses on your plants
nutrient cycling processes to release
soil phosphorus and other micronutrients
from they're bound forms making them
more available to the plant increased
levels of phosphorus will also keep
internode shorter and focus your plants
energy on bud production not only that
but the microbes act as a defense shield
for the plants rhizosphere
by out competing potentially harmful
pathogenic microbes pretty cool right
mammoth pee not only unlocks the
nutrients in your soil but it also helps
protect your plant from disease mammoth
pees beneficial bacteria act like
microbial reactors continually producing
ends
that release nutrients mammoth pee was
developed at a u.s. university has been
extensively tested by Colorado growers
and independent laboratories mammoth pee
is proven to increase growth and enhance
blooming one of the great things about
supplementing with microorganisms is
that they won't compete with whatever
fertilizer program you're already
running simply dose on top of your
fertilizer schedule for increased
benefits to learn more and to find out
where you can buy mammoth pee near you
check out their website at wwlp.com
[Music]
incredible aussolas for a gathering of
the top minds in cannabis medicine field
experts will present their latest
findings and best practices in treating
a variety of conditions with cannabis
including epilepsy pain traumatic brain
injury cancer autism and more laboratory
professionals will share their
revolutionary technologies in
cannabinoid and terpenoid extraction
delivery methods and quality and safety
testing can med 2018 is October 22nd
through 24th at the Luskin Conference
Center at UCLA and while the final
speakers list is still coming together
the speakers who are already announced
give you plenty of reasons to get your
ticket today prepare yourself to learn
from 54 thought-leader presentations
focused on furthering the convergence of
medical cannabis research treatment and
product development speakers include the
father of cannabis research Raphael Mis
ulam Michael door chief medical
consultant for the Israeli Ministry of
Health will be there to the list of
esteemed speakers participating is long
and includes shaping fire guests
cannabis neuroscientist dr. Ethan
Rousseau and Kevin McKiernan of
medicinal genomics you can view all the
speakers at kin med events calm this
year's kin med features a special
education track on the application of
blockchain technology in the cannabis
market including cannabis banking seed
to sale tracking sequencing the cannabis
genome ICO financing and more if you are
a medical care provider be sure to
arrive a date early to participate in
the pre-conference CME course find out
more about that at
med events dot-com that's c-a-n-n-a me d
events calm 95% of attendees said can
med 2017 met or exceeded their
expectations that's a serious vote of
confidence that can med 2018 will be
well worth your time and resources so
don't delay visit can med events calm
today to reserve your seat and find out
more welcome back you're listening to
shaping fire I'm your host Shango Louis
and our guest this week is Erik Weber
founder of dungeons vault genetics so
you know during the first set we were
talking a lot about how dungeons vault
came into being and what your
motivations are around the brand and
everything but you know most of the time
when I see you Eric
you are working a booth at a cannabis
event somewhere and and you know part of
that is kind of like the Eric Wilbur
show right because you got a big
personality people are there because
like they follow you on Instagram and
they want to you know they want to see
you in the flesh
you know because because people are into
their cannabis and and so you seem like
you have to put out a hell of a lot of
energy when you're working I mean just
selling seeds itself working a booth
itself is exhausting but since you're
the guy that a lot of people are there
to see you seem to have to like work
double how grueling is that man it's I
tell you if you wouldn't think that just
standing there or even if I'm sitting
down just sitting there at an event to
sit there and tell people oh my god I'm
so so tired from the like you stood
there and talked to people and smoked
weed all day how [ __ ] bad is that
really it sounds pretty easy to me but
yeah really when you are talking to that
many people I mean I've never done a
count on how many people come through a
booth or even at those events but
there's enough there that by end of the
day I've barely left the booth enough to
go use a restroom or get myself
something to drink really quick or I
yeah that's that's really I don't get to
walk around very much my voice has gone
by end of the day or by end of the
weekend but I I i did i made this brand
by myself i do a lot of this stuff with
friends if you see people at the booth
they're usually friends of mine or guys
that i work with a tester who i've
become great friends with who
show up at these events and help me out
but for the most part I do everything
myself and I like to talk to the people
I like to be the one behind the booth
selling the seeds I'd like to do
everything I have my hands on everything
and know what's being said because I
want my company represented in a good
way and I want people to walk away
knowing that they had their questions
answered and Oran that they have all the
knowledge they needed when they made
that purchase I mean let's be real here
no matter how much money you make if you
spend any sort of amount of money on
seeds not only are you investing that
money that it's hard-earned money but
you are going to invest a lot of time
into those things so you want to know
anything that you want to know about
that strain should be answered at that
booth by a knowledgeable staff and if I
don't have someone there that I know can
they answer that question with 100%
confidence and I'll be right there
standing behind them helping anything I
can would you find that the kind of
questions that people ask you at the
booth are almost entirely about the the
seeds and cannabis botany and how to
grow them and verus those kind of
specifics or do you find that that
actually you know that's a lesser amount
of the questions and lots of people
actually want to like you know get
selfies with you and just talk shop or
or get you know tell you tell you how
much they love citrus farm or like like
how much of it is like people like
really needing to know that kind of
information it's it's a little bit it's
mixed because you have people that come
by you get you get the mom-and-pop that
have literally now that cannabis has
become so accepted they are finally
making their way to an event like wow
I've never done this before can you tell
me a little about your seeds or oh I
didn't even know they sold these things
or whether they've heard of them or not
they might come by excuse me and they
want to have a little conversation about
how you know you know seeds have become
so popular and how people are growing
them to the the novice farmer to the guy
that just yeah they do want advice they
want to know everything that's going on
with the strains and you know how I grow
what's my choice for nutrients all that
stuff and then yeah you got the people
that come by that are fans you know the
Instagram fans or people that are just
you know buddies and and people you've
seen at different shows and they come by
to say hello and and shake your hand or
you just stop by and smoke a joint but
that's that gets into the whole thing
you asked earlier I'm so busy at those
talking to people and trying to make
sure everything's flowing correctly that
I rarely have time to I mean even when
you came by last time I was trying I
could see you stand there I want to say
hi to you but I'm in the middle of a
conversation and how rude to just walk
away from a conversation and then ignore
that person so I have to do everything I
can to make sure everyone feels
respected and that they are being taken
care of and then I can step away and say
hello to someone or try and talk to some
people so at times it can be hard
because I've only got a couple of people
working my booth with me and sometimes I
would really rather be the one talking
yeah yeah I get that and and certainly
when I see you at events I know that
your job there is to sell you know and
and and and when and when you you know
you didn't have time for me immediately
I did a loop and I came back and you had
more time and you know we said hey then
but I think yeah I think it's important
for people who are you know who are who
are fans but not particularly planning
on buying that day they have to
understand that they need to like step
aside so that the person who's got you
know a hundred dollar bill in their hand
gets your attention because that's you
know that's that's why the whole thing
can continues because that sales gonna
happen you know yes yes and that's part
of the reason why I made these laminated
menus now so I can just when I'm talking
to someone I can see out the corner of
my eye that someone wants to talk to me
or someone wants to ask a question so I
can just very very politely hand them a
menu so they can see what's going on and
they can hopefully have a question
answer that I can continue to show this
other person the respect they deserve
and continue their conversation until
they walk away but yeah I agree with us
we can just try and shuttle the people
that want to talk aside and let the
people they're looking to buy and
another aisle that's that's what I
should be doing but you know it's it's
nice to talk to everyone he always sees
fans and friends from from every show so
it's cool so so I know that you know the
shows on the west coast are chill and
pretty easy but I'm assuming that you
spend a lot of time in the newer states
as well like you know Michigan for
example and you know how sketchy is it
going into some of these newer states
carrying you know not only all of your
product to sell at the event but also
like you know your personal stash
because I you know you're clearly not
going to be you know
you know have a medical card in all
these states and the laws are changing I
would think that with you know
everything that all that you know
everything you on the line that that
could get pretty sketched sometimes I
I've got a few stories from airports
that are pretty comical but ya know for
the most part they they really don't
seeds are really they don't care TSA and
and most of the people have made it very
clear that that's not something they're
concerned with so me traveling with
seeds so far hasn't been an issue I
would say once you start bringing you
know certain amounts of weed with you on
the plane or whatever you might want to
be careful but for the most part I kind
of leave all that [ __ ] behind and let
people know hey I'm traveling from other
states so the reason I don't have ten
jars with a quarter pound in each jar so
you can smell everything and make a
judgement on what you want to buy is
because a I don't want to go to jail for
this and it's just not it's just not
logical it's just there's really no way
to do it so unless I'm driving across
state lines and even then same thing I
can't be bringing weed across state
lines that way either so it's really
it's funny man you got to really build
your brand and let people know what you
got because if they're if they're
counting on smelling a jar to make their
third choice it's going to be hard for
them but yeah it's it's it's it's so far
for me going to the other States has
been incredible I mean Michigan honestly
one of my favorite places to go they I'm
so well-received there and I've got
nothing but love for Michigan those guys
show me so much support up there even
more so than any other state honestly I
think more than California more than
Oregon more than more than Colorado
Michigan has my back and is there's a
huge supporter of all things done she's
also big shout out to Michigan farmers
right on right on and and you know it's
funny too because you know so many of us
on the west coast between you know
having medical for almost 20 years
depending on where you are on the west
coast you know a lot of us have gotten
used to what it's like to be around
easily-accessible top shelf weed and and
you know feeling generally safe that
we're not gonna get in trouble but you
know I'm actually from Michigan so like
when I go home to visit my family and I
see friends from back in the day
and uh you know the fact that they now
have got you know more advanced medical
and they're getting you know cool
products out there to see it reflected
in their eyes being so recently out of
prohibition it reminds me to be grateful
that I live on the west coast and that
I've even taken some of this stuff for
granted at this point because I'm around
it every day but you know you go back
behind the prohibition curtain and
people are all like man I can't even
believe I can buy this stuff legally you
know ya know it's it's it's times of
changing it wasn't it wasn't long ago
that I was arrested for a possession of
marijuana charge here in Washington
State and I remember asking the state
trooper I said man you guys are crazy
when you're gonna just [ __ ] legalize
the stuff and he said 90 times soon
buddy
well that wasn't that long ago and here
we are so it's it's pretty funny so you
know we were talking about the the laws
around the seeds and and that the TSA
really doesn't care all that much and
you know people in the you know in the
olden days like five years ago you know
they didn't want to ship seeds into the
US and then people in the US didn't
really want to ship seeds from state to
state but now like lots of people are
mailing seeds and and you know a lot of
people I ask like why do you feel safe
doing that they're like oh our seeds are
you know for souvenir only which doesn't
seem like it'd be a hustle that would
necessarily stand up in court
like what do you what are the rules
around shipping and selling seeds are
you really at any risk it the great
question it is is very very strange
because you've got so many different
people with an opinion on on the
legalities of it and how you know like
how it all is playing out and you don't
even know what to think you know because
you got you got one person saying you
know it's its agricultural trash seeds
are not looked at as an item that is its
it shouldn't be it's not illegal you
know but then you got other people there
saying for instance at Kanak on this
last a couple few weeks ago the cannabis
Liquor Control Board came in and they
were saying that you know
sales in Washington state is illegal to
have seeds on my on my table was
essentially the same as having marijuana
displayed I mean very very strict when
it comes to the whole recreational side
of it because I think they're really
after the whole seed to sale thing and
they want to make sure that you know
they're getting theirs but it's very
weird because at the same time they're
telling me that it's illegal in this and
a blah blah blah but I've personally
been told and seen it written on paper
that seeds do not have THC in them and
therefore are not illegal in are like I
said rather considered trash and or a
souvenir or whatever you'd like to do
with it but seed sales I think has
increased so much because like you
mentioned before five years ago even
more than that maybe was you you if you
weren't ordering your seats from
attitude seed bank or from say herb ease
head shop or ever you were wherever you
were getting them from there was all of
our sources were overseas and then
unless you knew a private breeder here
in town you know you could get some
stuff but the the varieties and all the
hybrids and everything that this come
out is is over the top it's it's
absolutely crazy and I would say that we
are we are very lucky to have so many
talented people in one area that we can
actually get what we are getting because
now what why would you ever order seeds
from another country at this point I
mean what you're gonna have the people
get their seeds taken from customs and
then who's to say you're even getting
what's you're paying for I mean that's
that's really any seed bank you order
from but we have guys with great
reputations here so it's just why risk
it anywhere else
yeah totally we've got mad mad talent
here in the states now so before we go
to our second break I want to ask you
about you know you have got a really
rabid following you know your followers
are hardcore and and you know sometimes
things can get pretty rambunctious on
your Instagram for example right and you
know how does that play into you know
your your bigger work right cuz like you
know essentially that is part of your
tizen right and so you're participating
with people and yeah you're teaching
them about your product but also you
know you get you get like these jerks
who show up and then suddenly people
who's defending you and so like this
this this if this thing explodes on your
Instagram feed how do you you know how
do you what's your perspective on that
do you see that as just being like
healthy and fun or you do try to have
there not be much of it because because
we go when you've got what 84,000
followers and and everybody is
passionate it tends to happen often you
know what it's it's it's a yeah I kind
of got into this earlier with you but
it's it's it's weird because I want to
be the guy who's I'm not gonna turn my
cheek and get slapped again you know but
the same time I think there's there is a
point where you need to just kind of
step back and and and either defuse the
situation or just delete everything
entirely and I have done that I I mean
what the example you brought up there's
a few times where I can think of where
there was a post mate or there was
something said and it led into just some
hundred plus comments thing and yeah or
I've got attack people that follow me
attacking other people and then people
this trolling me hard and in all reality
what good is it none but it does get me
some some more people paying attention
to the page than other people next thing
you know I got I got more followers that
are looking at things so sometimes it
gets good it can be a curse and a
blessing but but I think for the most
part it's probably better to just keep
your nose out of that [ __ ] and just let
the let the troll pages and the meme
pages handle all the huge arguments and
you just kind of represent your brand
that's that's more of the line I'm
trying to take as of recently but at the
same time I'm I'm a very passionate
person I'm a very friendly guy but I'm
also someone who's got you know a little
bit of you know anger issues here and
there so I can easily lose my cool and
say things I don't mean or maybe I do
mean at the time but just say things
that might come across another person is
a real jerky thing to say but in all
reality I'm really just I'm not gonna
let people walk on me I I
I can appreciate the people that can you
know let's let's all just get along and
let's just all smoke a joint go hug a
tree there's nothing wrong with that but
at the same time sometimes people just
need to get put in their place and be
told that you know it don't it's just
your comment was unnecessary I don't
want to fricken hear it and then you got
my the followers that they will
literally go and I'm not telling them
not telling people to go do these things
and they will literally go and just
light a fire under someone's ass and
it's like oh my gosh I would you you had
I had no idea the outcome of what some
of these things are gonna do but it's
just it's it's comical at times but yeah
like I said if I see something for the
most part I don't leave that kind of
stuff up on my page I'll let it go for a
little bit I'll speak my mind I'll say I
need to say and then boom it's gone yeah
yeah you know I came up with a term for
that that I use with clients a lot I
call it a spectacle marketing right it's
it's it's you know it's something that
happens like like a master of this is a
Jonah to coma from dab stars right like
he does these big things that are just
like crazy and outrageous and and and
people all want to watch it because it's
like a house on fire or something right
and and he gets everybody excited he
milks it and then he just moves on to
the next thing right and sometimes these
these online fights can be the same
thing
you'd be like oh my god I can't believe
like so and you kind of follow the
thread throughout the day and then you
know solos nobody gets truly violent
with each other you know you can always
just delete it down the line and move on
exactly that's that's really what I've
tried to do because I think that
sometimes when I post something whether
it be drama related or on I'm calling
someone out for doing something stupid
or whatever maybe I want people to see
what I have to say but then it doesn't
need to just be a on going thing once
I've spoken my mind or I've said I want
to say and and enough people have
commented or seen it then they can go
tell their friends or whatever that what
they saw it's done at that point I mean
I I I don't think anyone should just be
allowed to be off you know let off the
hook for soft stuff they do or say if
you've said or done something that's
really faulty then own up to it and if
it's if you're gonna get caught out on
social media you know I mean then that's
it that's just that's how it is nowadays
so be ready so keep your nose clean and
don't say things you don't mean or or if
you're gonna say things you don't that
you do mean they get ready to back them
up
yeah totally so so it's it is funny so
so after the f9 yeah after the break
I wanted we're gonna talk more about
your particular strain lineage but but
one more question before we go to that
break you know I I have heard you talk
about testers a lot about you know the
kind of attributes that you like in a
tester and the kind of people that
deserve to receive test seeds and then
and then all the yahoos that just waste
your seeds and you never hear from them
again so you know there's there's
clearly a lot of people who are
listening today who would love to be a
tester for you or for somebody else
right you know what what do you see as
being the attributes of a good tester
and how should somebody approach a
breeder so that they get you know so
they start off on the right foot
I have literally gone about this in so
many ways that I don't even know I at
this point I'm gonna start doing face to
face interviews like I don't I'm joking
but I literally don't I don't know what
to do because I've tried it I've I've
literally done it this way where I look
at someone I say okay this guy's got X
amount of followers he obviously has
people checking out his page he grows
good weed he he's very he's very you
know he's on Instagram a lot he's spent
a lot of time on there and showing
people what he's doing so that's the
kind of person I would think would be my
ideal tester in and I say I think within
parenthesis because that's really that's
what I thought would be good then you
got guys that have a very very low
falling with you know hardly any
followers at all but they grow killer
bud and all they are trying to do is is
get their foot in the door so they can
hopefully one day you know be more are
like a permanent tester or be have some
sort of way to get into this industry
and if being someone's grower and and
helping them test strains and all of a
sudden you they've I've used ten of that
guy's photos on my page to advertise my
brand guess what he's probably made it
into a spot where I will always hit him
up maybe even invite him out for a cup
to come hang out and you know come meet
the guys and and really you know get get
more strains to grow out himself
whatever but
I'm looking to build relationships with
these people you know I don't want I
don't want some some girl or guy excuse
me
grown for me and me never even known who
they are just having some online persona
I want to know who you are I want to
engage with you I want to know how
they're growing I want to know what you
got going on and it seems to me that
there's too many people that are they're
so quick to jump in line oh I want to
test you all do this I'll do that all
they promise everything from the moon
and back and then they don't do what
they say they're going to do now there
are there are circumstances that happen
and you got a you know be understanding
because everybody doesn't have an easy
life there's things that pop up things
happen you know there's all sorts of
stuff out of our control but what I see
happening more times than not is is
people asking and or begging for seeds
and then they don't even do anything
with them they stay put them in their
stash or maybe they do grow them but
they don't ever tell me about it because
they just wanted something new so they
have something that sets them apart from
their their friend who's growing you
know something that everyone already has
right now yeah it's very loose yeah and
probably super hella frustrating too
yeah yeah so hey let's go ahead and take
that break we're gonna take a short
break and be right back you're listening
to shaping fire and my guest today is
Eric Weber founder of dungeons of all
genetics using pesticides when growing
cannabis has been common for a long time
nowadays though we know better we know
that most pesticides formulated for food
crops have never been tested for use
with cannabis they've been tested to be
eaten in tiny doses they have not been
tested to be inhaled and especially not
concentrated into a cannabis oil
chemical residues from pesticides are
not healthy for anyone but they are
especially dangerous for patients for
commercial cannabis growers this has
become very impactful cannabis
enthusiasts and patients have gotten
educated enough that they avoid growers
who used pesticides not only that but
states across the country have begun
making pesticide testing mandatory on
all licensed cannabis crops the time has
come to find a better way to fight
garden pests than covering your cannabis
and chemicals and there is a better way
let some good bugs fight your bad bugs
beneficial insects and predatory mites
have come a long way since we were
buying ladybugs online and putting them
in the grow room and just hoping for the
best natural enemies biocontrol
can help you solve pest issues without
using chemicals natural enemies founder
Shane young learned best practices from
working in the ornamental plant industry
and has fine-tuned those strategies
specifically for large cannabis crops
Shane works with commercial cannabis
clients across the country to ensure
that they keep their crop safe and pest
free without the use of chemicals
natural enemies has proven solutions for
spider mites a fits
thrips russet mites broad mites shore
flies
white fly and others - you can rely on
natural enemies for expertise and
excellent service for more information
go to shaping feiyr.com forward slash
natural enemies or simply click on their
banner in this week's newsletter if you
grow cannabis with sunshine you can
often feel limited by the seasonal cycle
you want to grow sustainably and save
money so you use as little electricity
as possible but if you haven't studied
or implemented light deprivation
techniques into your greenhouse you're
leaving a lot of money on the table by
incorporating light deprivation
solutions into your greenhouse you can
often add two or three additional
growing cycles to your year when you
pencil out the financial benefit of
those additional cycles you'll realize
why commercial scale light deprivation
technology is remaking the cannabis
industry what used to be done by pulling
tarps over hoop houses has been scaled
up over the last few years in such a way
that it's become mechanized easy and
affordable to even small-scale
commercial cannabis operations forever
flowering greenhouses is the industry
leader in light deprivation greenhouse
design and operation for the commercial
cannabis industry their team of
greenhouse experts have been in the
fields of Northern California for
decades and they're now building
greenhouses for commercial cannabis
companies across the country if you are
new to light dep and growing in
greenhouses i encourage you to go back
to shaping fire episode 13 with guest
eric Branstad of forever flowering I
talked with Eric about the importance of
intelligent greenhouse management as
well as the huge financial Ben
fit of incorporating light depth
techniques there are so many aspects of
utilizing a greenhouse that can go wrong
from temperature and airflow to light
DEP and workflow forever flowering will
help you produce crop after crop of
well-cared-for flowers they can help you
retrofit your existing greenhouse with
light depth and other modern systems at
a level that fits your budget if you're
just starting out forever flowering can
help you plan and build your new
greenhouse so that you get started on
the right foot the cannabis business has
enough risks without trying to go it
alone with your greenhouse contact
forever flowering greenhouses to partner
with folks who have an indisputable
reputation as knowledgeable and easy to
work with go to shaping feiyr.com /f FG
to find out more welcome back you're
listening to shaping fire I'm your host
Shango Louis and our guest this week is
Erik Weber founder of dungeons vault
genetics so you know up to this point
we've talked a lot about how someone
would start a seed company and and a lot
of the you know the goods and the bads
that you went through to get to where
you are I want to focus this last set
specifically on the gear that you put
out because it's it's fabulous I've
grown it myself I love you know actually
I love everything I've grown and you
know a lot of that I think has to do
with the fact that you really rely a lot
on this fabulous Grandpa's breath strain
as what seems like your dominant male
that you work with how did you find the
grandpa's breath and and you know where
did it where did your love affair with
that plant start so when I was still
working with granddaddy I had came to
Kin because everything with that brand
was obviously based on they've done the
GDP grandpa's granddaddy grandpa
anything like that it was all had to do
with the the marketing for that company
so I originally told him hey there's
this there's this clone going around
it's very held back it's not passed to
many people it's very exclusive and it
was the og cush breath and we're talking
we're talking back in like oh nine 2010
no excuse me it was a little bit after
that I'm wrong but either way it was it
was it was anyway yeah it was early on
in the in this in the stages of my
breeding that that this og KB started
getting
passed around I have friends in
California that looked after me and were
very good to me and and I'm not gonna
mention his name but he's a really good
dude he's very well known in the
cannabis industry and he he gave me
clones because he knew I that you know I
was good people I was gonna do anything
bad with them and he trusted me with him
so he gave it to me I used him I knew
what I was doing and og KB to me was
that was the best cookie it was it was
such a good smell it was it was very
rare and it was just one of those ones
that if you had it you you you had
something others didn't so I mean gage
green myself and maybe one or two other
people very few of us had that clone we
were the first to bring any of these
breath strains to the market I don't
care what anyone says I could argue till
night about you know his gage green with
their mindo breath and the grateful
breath and then I surely came after
Sheree was out with the Grandpa's breath
right after that and I knew from the
start of the mail when I when I first
crossed the og KB with the Tahoe GDP I
knew immediately once I found this mail
this thing was so just stout and it had
I mean it made the last mails that I
found when I was working for Andy looked
like nothing I mean they just really I
knew was gonna be good and then as I
continued forth my project I saw what
was coming out of it and everything that
I saw tested and grown out was
incredible so it was really just
something special and that's really why
it was used in everything because rather
than using too many strains and having a
bunch of stuff that I'm not certain is
going to be great
I found something special and I knew
that's what I was going to base
everything off of and so that's what I
did the the grandpa's breath has got
something for everybody too because you
know people have asked me before like
like I I really like the foul-mouth
right and so so people asked me to
describe the the Grandpa's breath and
I'm all like well you know it's it's
it's fuelie but it's got some floral in
there but but it's got some of those
like old-school alcohol esters like
skunk does and so people are like so and
essentially you know taste like and
smells like everything I'm like well
yeah I guess it kind of does you know
it's it's it's not one of these strains
that you're pigeon-holed into
um one descriptor it's not one thing
it's actually a lot of things and yeah
one of the cool things about F ones is
that you can put you you get to
experience you get to treasure hunt fee
knows still and and I enjoy that aspect
of it ya know I mean it's it's from what
I will say that I've noticed for sure
with this mail no matter what it's
touched you still get you still get
dominance from the from the female half
but that male brings so much frost and
so much kind of like almost like an
earthiness and berries is kind of what I
would describe because everything in
there you there's always kind of a gray
P musky berry thing going on in some of
the fee knows no matter which what you
grow but there's always going to be the
dominant you know a female phenotype
that comes in but yeah like you said
there's a little bit of something for
everybody because people like the purple
you get that the bag of pill is there
with every strain doesn't matter what
you choose and then the some people
there what's your biggest yield er
there's quite a few that actually yield
quite well and surprisingly because of
having the Girl Scout and then the OG
and GDP you don't think those three
strains together are gonna create
something that yields heavy but
surprisingly enough it does and it's
it's many growers who have tried my
strains out have reported back above
average yields even so once these once
these strains get dialed in and you know
what you're doing with them I mean they
can really be rewarding in so many
levels yeah it's probably a lot of fun
too for when you know once your seeds
started hitting the street and people
who you did not know personally so so
obviously your your friends and your
inner circle we're growing your gear but
when people start to report back beyond
your sphere of influence that they're
growing your stuff and really liking it
there's got to be a lot of self
satisfaction in knowing that other
people are digging on on your on your
baby you know
oh absolutely like my my first years in
with kin and all that stuff I was seeing
people bringing these samples to the
shows and hey this is your purple
champagne hey this is the this is the
grand OG this is this this is that and I
was super stoked I was I was I was half
what I was seen I felt pretty cool you
know it'll Pat on my own back you know
like I made that that's that's that's
really cool you know I was my it was a
dream and now it's come true
but what I've noticed now with this
grandpa's breath line it doesn't matter
what you bring by I am so impressed with
every single sample that gets brought to
my table
and I'm always so happy and so excited
to see the next one that someone has
because it's always been it's it's very
rewarding feeling but not only that it's
it's just cool because this is what I've
always want to do I've want to make
strange that I would be happy to smoke
and stuff that I mean to be sitting
there smoking on a strain that I created
and knowing that I'm not you know I'm
not just smoking it because I Korea I'm
smoking because I enjoy it and that's
something I would actually recommend to
other people to try not just not just
create a sale but because hey this is
good weed it's it's pretty good feeling
I gotta admit yeah I love it and every
single time I hear from someone that
they enjoy my strains it's just another
you know huge blessing because you know
I know I'm doing something right one of
the far-out things I think for being a
breeder versus a big you know commercial
production grower is that you're winning
cups cannabis cups but like you're not
winning them it's it's the people who
have bought your gear who are then
winning the cups and so you know your
work is winning the cup put together
with their work that must be a strange
feeling but what was it like the first
time that one of your strains won a cup
that someone else grew that that was
insane because it wasn't just one cup
this guy he goes by the name big worm
online he literally he makes incredible
oil but he was over in Massachusetts as
where he's based out of but um he he got
he placed at the secret cup for the east
coat or fur I don't remember rozat but
he placed a secret cup made it to the
finals and then with my citrus farmer
strain he literally swept the
competition I mean he won in one night
best overall highest Terps and best
shatter
I mean in one night and that was all
first place awards for citrus farmer and
then I got to smoke
the oil shortly thereafter and it I mean
absolutely burnt orange just absolute
dank it was so good and I talked about
feeling feeling really cool and having a
moment that's that was it for me I was
like that's that's awesome to know that
people are are that impressed with the
strain and it's coming out that that
good and people are really you know
positive reviews it it makes me feel
really good you know and in the end it
is also a business so I'm assuming that
once people started winning cups with
your gear that that really helped at the
box office to write because suddenly
people are all like wow I hadn't heard
of that strain they look it up and
suddenly they're on your IG and now
they're trying to totally connect with
you at a at an event or something to buy
the seeds that probably makes all the
difference in the world when when your
stuff starts winning awards oh yeah
tangey tangi with Crockett and DNA those
guys blew up with that strain I can't
say for certain that that's the first
orange train I've ever had orange
strains have been around for years and
years but they kind of they kind of
really set the standard for orange
trains right so when I was given my
skunk tangerine cut from organ and kid
that one is one that is so it's so held
back not very few people have that clone
so the amount of breeders working with
it is to me and archive seeds is the
only people that I have it as far as I'm
concerned I haven't seen anyone else
using it no one else is working with it
and it had such a strong smell it was
incredible and I knew right then and
there that that was going to be
something that as soon as people saw it
and smelt it and got to see what they're
gonna get from my seeds they were gonna
it was gonna be popular we released
citrus farmer at the Emerald cup in 2015
I believe and it sold out that weekend
so then it was not even let's see that
was December 2015 so I think yeah later
on in the year 2016 was when when citrus
farmer really blew up at one for war so
it won those three at secret cup for the
shatter and then the week after that it
won at a another event over in Maine or
on the East Coast for the flower at one
third place overall so it really started
making waves and even to the
des everyone that grows it has has left
back left me such positive feedback and
has really enjoyed it it's been very
well reviewed I know that like trying to
choose your your favorite strain is like
trying to you know choose a favorite
child or something but is there the art
is there a particular strain in in your
line that you feel especially warm to
like that like you know maybe it's maybe
it's the first cup or maybe it's
something that that you know was
especially difficult for you to run that
man it's such it's like you said it's
like trying to choose your favorite
child how do you say that you make sure
they're not looking when you say it but
I mean really it's it it's since they
can't hear me I would say that if I had
to choose overall if I'm left on an
island with one strand of smoke that's
so hard but I would say hot rod oh right
on yeah I mean my that or the ones that
are sold out my Swamp Thing or lost soul
anything oh gee Kim sour flavor anything
that's you cracked that jar and you can
smell it across the room that's that's
what I'm after so we have found so much
gas out of the hot rod that that really
was that that to me is probably my go-to
favorite but the Grandpa's breath man
very they're like right there I've been
smoking on grandmas but at the past two
days and I love that strain it works out
so well for me for sleep and for
everything it's just a very heavy
narcotic hi and I really enjoy it so but
hot rod just because the the taste the
Terps the smell overall everything about
it it's just it's really what I'm after
when I when it comes to what I choose
for my cannabis strain on a daily I like
the the fuel so it seems like you have I
mean everybody does you know limited
runs right but it's Ino yeah you have
really gone pro with with how you're
doing the limited runs and start for
anybody who did not who wasn't at
Emerald Cup this year this is pretty
much how it went down
you know you had you had these these
trials I mean I'm get sometimes telling
your story for you but you had these
trials that you weren't sure if you were
gonna go all the way with and so and so
like what 48 hours before Emerald cup
opens up you drop photos of these
crosses on an Instagram which like
freaks all your fans out everybody's
like oh my god and so
as as the morning first morning of
emerald cup and people are like sipping
on their coffee and like stretching and
stuff you've already got a line from the
front of your booth you know 45 people
you know deep and everybody else like
what that [ __ ] going on over there
right and and because I follow you on IG
I'm really uh well you know everybody
wants to get the limited-edition stuff
were you surprised at how successful the
marketing was for those limited editions
you have no idea like me and my buddy
that I drove down there with we sat
there over dinner and we're having a
drink one the night before I woke up or
maybe it was maybe it was that Thursday
night so we're gonna set up the next
morning one way or another we're sitting
there thinking we're like you know how
should we do this you know I mean do I
want to I mean do I want to just tell
people you know what I ended up doing
was I told people the how limited they
were how the fact that there's only so
many packs available and I and I what I
did was I actually opened it up to to
some people before the show so I made it
even more exclusive by offering people
if you can pay now and you want to pre
buy it
go right ahead you know send me the
money it'll be waiting for you and then
so I did that and I literally had so
many messages and so many people
automatically wanted to pay that I I
just was like wow I had no idea was
gonna blow up like this so as that
morning came that Saturday morning like
you mentioned there were so many people
already wait and there I wasn't even set
up yet and people were staying there
with cash out can i buy this can i buy
that I'm like I'm not even hold on one
sec let me get let me get this stuff out
and I'm I'm just setting up but it was
absolutely incredible and we took video
because I've never been that busy ever
at any show where I had that many people
waiting in line like I'm dropping the
next iPhone or something so so those
seeds that were all your limited
editions are do you think that you're
gonna move forward with all of those or
were those just you know fun things that
you figured on the side and you know you
just you just wanted to get them out but
you're not gonna move down the road with
them a lot of peace fine I mentioned
archive really he made a joke one time
we made a meme about it there was you
know it was like the breeders list you
know like what what that what that
really
some people say limited-edition means
totally untested you know high-priced
you know BS just some what's up breeder
wants to put something out real quick
that wasn't the case here what happened
was I had a run where I fully intended
on there being a hell of a lot more
seeds in there word that the the mail
just didn't put out as much pollen as I
was hoping it would have and overall I
think what what really happened was I
calculated my run days I'm telling
myself right here but let's just keep it
real with everybody I
I pulled I think a week early and so
some of the seeds weren't even as fully
developed as they should have been so I
was like oh [ __ ] so when it's all said
and done and I counted stuff there was
some where it was like I want this
strain release because this is too good
not to release it and after testing it
we knew that we had some killer stuff
but there was not as much numbers as I
normally would have so I was like you
know what I'm gonna put them up there
people that want them it's gonna be a
limited edition get them while they're
hot you know it's it's up to you if you
want them great if not no big deal and
sure enough I mean I they were very well
accepted and everybody was super stoked
to get in line and get some of them so I
would say that I would like all of them
to be something in my line that comes
back but at this point what I'm starting
to realize is and I don't think a lot of
people realize this either is I'm
working very exclusively you know on
certain things it's very it's it's I'm
doing things alone I don't have I don't
have a huge team I'm working with I'm
not I don't have a gigantic facility I'm
breathing out of so I don't have
unlimited numbers when it comes to these
things I don't have I don't have a
hundred different rooms to make all
these different strains so what it comes
down to is I do more or less kind of
boutique runs and boutique drops and and
now that's how it's gonna be like if you
if you're in if you're in that line you
get a hold of them then great because
that I really mean it they're limited as
in I might it might be another year or
two before I remake them so it's one of
those things like I've got so many great
ones that I've now released and have
become popular off of but now you know I
mean people are asking for certain ones
to come back and I've got so many other
ones I need to do and then trying to
stay relevant and make new strains it's
it's overwhelming at times and that's
another thing you asked about
people wanted to get into this industry
and how easy is it it's hard and you're
dead you're dedicating your life to
making seeds and then you got to test
those seeds and you got to grow those
seeds and you talk about six months down
the line before you can even do anything
with them well in those six months I've
got zero Gardens I'm cropping out either
so I'm not growing anything for smoking
it's literally just making seeds and
there's it's so it's it's how it's it's
very difficult at times to do everything
and have it all you know make sure you
got everything that people want and and
you know taking care of everything you
need to do it's it's it's tough
it probably frees you up to a certain
degree to that you're not having to
bring in product you know heavy
commercial production level of flowers
to you right because you know growing
flowers full-time is is a is an arduous
thing and you know you you specialize on
doing seeds you know like a ninja and I
and I find that across our industry
people who are specializing I mean you
know we all need to know something about
everything right because always hearts
fit in together right but but I think
that the people who are allowed to
really study their particular discipline
and they do it better than anybody they
reap the rewards because most everybody
else is just kind of like a dilettante
yeah no I totally agree and one thing
I'll say not not to I'm not trying to
toot my own horn here anything but I
have focused on trying to make strains
that I knew were gonna be great I
originally released I believe twelve
twelve strains or so or in my line from
the time I told you I left granddaddy on
at that first Emerald cup 2014 no excuse
me to I'm fifteen was when I first had
all my line fully released for everybody
there there was up at one point I told
people I said I'm not making any more
seeds I'm gonna I'm gonna let this line
ride for a while till I see everybody
has grown them I don't want to be a guy
that's got you know what someone comes
up to me what strain do you recommend
well I've got fifty you know here let me
totally try and pick one out for you
know let's have you grown any of my
stuff well I've got 12 to choose from
let's how do you do this one then come
back in two months let's try another one
like I really encourage people to let me
help you find something from my line
that I think you'd like and also just
just give it a try if you if you trust
in my
and you like what you tried before then
you will love all the other ones as well
so it's one of those things I really
want to be more of a more of an
exclusive breeder to where I don't have
150 strains in a few years I've been out
I've got my original line and I've just
now broken off into making a few more
and I've got more that are in testing
now but I've I'm not quick to jump to
market with you no more than I can chew
I want to be able to say that I've grown
and I've seen things grown and can give
you some solid feedback on everything
yeah right on right on
well Eric I know the time is valuable
and so I want to thank you for coming on
the show and you know I want to double
thank you too because I'm not and just
anybody would come on a show and talk
about you know how to build a business
because you know in a certain way you're
given out some of your special sauce
secrets for how you build dungeons vault
and you know that there's people out
there that you're inspiring during this
show who are now going to make seeds and
are therefore you know seeing themselves
as competitors but but you are so
comfortable in you know who you are and
your business that you were open to you
know to talk shop with me other than
just you know your own strain so I
appreciate you both taking your time and
and and talking about how you did it so
that the next generation can come up
behind you hey you know what thank you
very much for having me I really enjoyed
myself and to anybody out there looking
to get in the industry and/or do their
own seed breeding I encourage it just
know there that it's it's it like I said
it's a cutthroat business but that
doesn't mean you know don't try I say do
what you love and I love what I do and I
wouldn't have it any other way so if
anyone tells you not to do it just don't
talk to them anymore because they're
obviously not looking out for you so do
your thing and enjoy life and just do
let's all have fun here so awesome if
you want to find out more about dungeons
vault genetics you should definitely
check out Eric's Instagram page at
dungeons underscore vault underscore
genetics you can find more episodes of
the shaping fire podcast and subscribe
to the show at shaping fire calm and on
Apple iTunes stitcher and Google Play if
you enjoyed the show we'd really
appreciate it if you'd leave a positive
review of the podcast wherever you
download your review will help others
find the show so they can enjoy it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the weekly newsletter for
insights into the latest cannabis news
and product reviews on the shaping fire
website you will also find transcripts
of today's podcast as well for
information on me and where I'll be
speaking you can check out Shango
lowes.com does your company want to
reach our national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hotspot at shaping
fire calm to find out how thanks for
listening to shaping fire I've been your
host
Shango lows
[Music]