[Music]
fermenting has become wildly popular in
the last decade everywhere you look
people are drinking kombucha and water
kefir and other folks are making
fermented pickles and sauerkraut or
homemade yogurts in each of these
examples the goal is to make an
environment beneficial to microorganisms
so they thrive and multiply this is the
same thing that probiotic farmers are
trying to do instead of just trying to
jam the plant full of nutrients a
probiotic farmer is creating a soil
environment where life is abundant and
naturally creates the plants nutrition a
thriving plant comes from making healthy
soil not trying to force-feed @
nutrients Korean natural farming known
shorthand as KNF is next level probiotic
farming KNF ferments a wide variety of
naturally occurring substances from
plant and fruit juices to fish carcasses
and sea water in order to help
indigenous bacteria fungi nematodes and
protozoa to thrive and produce fertile
soils that don't require pesticides
herbicides or synthetic fertilizer
inputs in essence KNF takes the
principles found in making tasty to eat
kimchi and reapplies them to the farm
master chauhan ku invented Korean
natural farming method by blending
Korean farming and fermenting techniques
with those of natural farming teachers
he met while studying in Japan by 1992
he had begun an epic 21 part series in
modern agricultural magazine on his
newly established methods and in 1995 he
opened the natural farming life school
and research farm in Korea this school
is the source of these inventive
techniques that are taking the cannabis
world by storm seriously everybody in
probiotic cannabis growing is talking
about KNF right now if you want to learn
about cannabis health business and
technique efficiently and with good
cheer I encourage you to subscribe to
our newsletter every week you'll receive
a new podcast episode delivered right to
your inbox along with commentary on a
couple of the most important news items
from the week and videos too
don't rely on social media to let you
know when a new episode is published
sign up for the updates and make sure
you don't miss an episode
you are listening to shaping fire and
I'm your host
Shango 'lose my guest this week is Chris
Trump Chris Trump is a master natural
farmer certified by Master Choa of Korea
he's also studied microbial analysis
under dr. Elaine Ingraham many consider
Chris's YouTube videos explaining Korean
natural farming techniques to have been
the key to can s wildly increasing
popularity in the US it's also helpful
that chris is a certified kin of
educator who actually speaks english
today we'll be going over the central
ideas of KNF and discussing recipes for
korean farming's exceptionally alive
inputs
welcome to the show Chris thank I'm glad
to be here yeah I know your time is
valuable so thanks for appealing off a
little bit for us
so you know you know as I've already
mentioned to folks I am new to Korean
natural farming I've been in probiotics
for a while but but people have been
getting more and more excited about KNF
as the as the teaching finds its way you
know around the scene and so so let's
start like what do you see as the
difference between you know probiotic
farming and living soils versus the
specifics of Korean natural farming is
it is it simply a subset of probiotic
farming or do you see a kind of as an as
its own thing for some reason you know
it it's all it's all nature the best any
of this is really doing is working the
way nature already works and it's
optimum so if some of these doing
probiotic farming or living focusing on
living soil if they're doing it well you
know that's that's kind of it is very
similar Korea natural farming one of the
core principles is the idea of
indigenous microbes so where you might
buy bugs in a jug some some product made
where that somebody said it's really
good or they found success with those we
found may or may not persist in your
environment so depending on your
temperature or your moisture or just the
microbes that are already present you
might have a six month fall off with
some sort of purchased microorganism mix
and you might you might not that's not
I'm not saying that's always how it is
but with indigenous biology so if your
indigenous microorganism if you're
farming a acre of land and you go up the
hill and you collect something that
exists and the wild forest and bring it
down we're very confident that that will
persist in your soil because it's for
however many thousands of years or
whatever period of time that's been
undisturbed or gotten established it's
thrived in that environment so by moving
it you know downhill or a mile across
town it's still gonna like your rainfall
your temperature your barometric
pressure and the general soil mix for
the most part and even play well with
the microbes on your farm that makes a
lot of sense you know we talk a lot on
this show about bio regions and making
sure that you're growing you know this
the strains that work for where you live
if you're growing outdoors and this
seems to be a real obvious extension of
that you know it's like you know work
with the microbes that are comfortable
with your area and your weather instead
of you know necessarily recruiting bugs
in a bottle like you said to add them
and then just hope that they do good
where you happen to live that makes a
lot of sense and so so at the Etha at
the cornerstone of KNF would be simply
recruiting your volunteer microbes from
your neighborhood and then feeding them
what they want so that they are you know
motivated to stay and to increase yeah
and and that's not to say that bugs and
a bugs in the jug wouldn't help your
farm it just may be that you just got to
keep buying them whereas if you're yeah
if you're establishing something that
will persist you're basically building a
battery of health and vitality in your
soil that will be there year after year
right on so you mentioned that as one of
the key tenants of KNF would you would
you have any other key tenants of KNF
that you think are good to start with
you know the first time I spent a long
period of time with Johan new Master
Choa he we looked at her notes I sitting
next to my friend Pancho from Pedro he's
the head of Crazy Horse you know Neil
Young and Crazy Horse yeah yeah yeah
yeah he's the leaves Crazy Horse and
we're sitting there and we're looking at
her notes it's been a day or two of you
know getting into it Master Cho and his
daughter was there do young and we're
like every other words love you know
like this whole thing there's like
agriculture agriculture love agriculture
love and so that's taking me a bit or
initially it took me a bit as a
commercial farmer to be like okay what
does love have to do with agriculture
and but I would say as far as natural
farming goes it is a core tenant in that
it's it's a mindset or a position to
farm from where if you are caring for
things or treating them as you might a
child you know where it's like oh it's
just good enough but you're kind of like
no let me practice or learn to do this
well there's there's a result that is
has to do with this kind of invisible
component that is the farmers attention
and we have that I mean a culturally
we've seen that
over the years you have these same in
livestock you know the eye of the farmer
fattens the cow or the shadow of the
farmer makes the plants grow and it's
those are nods towards something that's
the invisible component and yeah so
there's there's that in there that's
kind of a deeper philosophical rabbit
trail but it is it is important in this
type of agriculture in the communication
of it I would think that just about
anybody who's attracted to either you
know just generally probiotic growing or
specifically KNF they've got to have
some of that in their heart though right
because you know generally people who
are you know ruthlessly corporate
growers they're growing out of bottles
and they are pushing nature to take from
nature to get nature to produce for them
versus all the farmers that I know who
are using probiotic growing techniques
are doing it because they're in love
with the plant they're in love with
their land they don't want to have you
know evil run off of their property
going into the streams I would say that
just you know farmers generally what
love in their hearts will find their way
to this kind of farming one you know
eventually yeah I would say so and and
that's not to say it's not this light
it's it's not to say it's not about
being profitable like it isn't there is
they aren't mutually exclusive to have a
care for what you're doing or
profitability if you can there's
definitely both you know as we toured
Korea one of the only things he would
ask master show with ask these farmers
doing that to farming is you know how
much money you making you know and
they're obviously caring for what they
do
I mean they have you know whether it's
pigs or crops just beautiful and Macke I
was pretty jealous when I saw persimmon
farm where it's just like they don't
live in fertilize in 11 years and they
just have it looks like 23 acres of a
tree that if you know mr. Miyagi had one
they
he would have you know it's like 23
acres of perfectly groomed beautifully
productive persimmons and they haven't
fertilized in 11 years but he asked them
how much money they make and they're by
and large the answers I heard they're
far more profitable than we are in the
US because some some of that has to do
with its family operations where they're
not paying workmen's comp you know
they're running these these things with
you know two people my husband and wife
and they're killing it on a couple acres
and but yeah it's anyways I just wanted
to clarify just because we're talking
about love doesn't mean it's not viable
to make a living on as a person or
family farm it's very much about
sustainability meaning that you don't
have to work a second job to sustain
your farming habit yeah that I think
that's a good thing for you to point out
too especially since a you know a great
deal of the audience for this show our
commercial cannabis growers right you
know we there are people who they want
to you know they're they may have the
heart and the love but at the end of the
day they need to make sure that what
they're growing has got high yield is is
developing a fantastic terpene profile
and that they're locking down as much
bag appeal as they can without going
indoors and and you know if people knew
that they they could use this techniques
but they would lose money well they sure
as heck wouldn't be as popular but but
you know we know darn well that using
probiotic and KNF techniques actually
just makes the plant thrive and then and
then also so your yields are going up
and and so is the quality of your
product so alright I think we've
probably hit that pretty well so um so
you know no-till is also becoming really
popular is would you consider no-till to
be an essential part of KNF as well
because you don't want to break up the
the community in the soil yeah it's
definitely in the same line if you're
with natural farming you're not you're
not telling
as a general rule if you're if you're
coming into a brand new area and it's
full of grass or some other you know
wild crop or weed you're probably gonna
have to deal with that in that first
season and so that's encouraged that
you're not beating your head against the
wall trying to grow around or through
the grass
that's super thick and beating out or
out competing you may need to tail or
Spade or do something the first time but
yeah that definitely because we're
counting on that that network that is
established of the fungal Network and
all these little organisms part of the
soil food web to grow the food so going
in and slam in the mall with equipment
at the end of every season is kind of
counterproductive when I was first
starting to read about KNF one of the
things that you know one of the one of
the explanations that really hit me was
about soil nutrient cycling and you
actually just hit it talking about that
persimmon farm and so I'm gonna set you
up and I'd like you to just kind of
explain it a little bit because you said
that that persimmon farm that you saw
had not fertilized in like 11 years and
and that's a perfect example because
normally the the trees get rid of the
leaves and and then they're up there
then they are in the soil and then they
rot and so the plant is self-fertilizing
can you go a little more in depth about
that yeah there's natural farming I
guess the the principle in nutrition is
the right amount at the right time means
that you can have far less quantity of
input than if you're just trying to
preload a whole growing cycles food in
the beginning so like that persimmon
farm I mean they use a lot of composting
you know or mulching so they mulch by
them but not not a ton of nice
they don't need to the rainfall is
sufficient yes it with depending on your
crop some crops need they really do need
nitrogen in their vegetative growth
cycle especially and so there is
nutrients available but like we we farm
750 acres of macadamia nuts with natural
farming in Hawaii organically and the
amount of nitrogen we use on our farm
now it's all grown with Korean natural
farming is homeopathic to put a
descriptive word to it compared to the
industry recommended nitrogen amounts
and the experts in our industry look at
in they're like well you'll you'll never
get yields with that amount of nitrogen
and now you know five years later
they're like so what are you doing will
you speak at our international
conference you know like because our
yields are increasing year after year
we're getting increased yields well our
entire island yields are in decline and
they're thinking while the trees are too
old we have the oldest trees on the
island on the farm and we're increasing
year after year with this tending to the
life of the soil so going back to the
person an example so since so since on
this show we are you know the our crew
our target crop is cannabis and and
since the persimmon tree you know to its
to its advantage you know the leaves
fall and it's already used the key
components to make the tree and then
when the and then in the fall they fall
and so they they then they rot at the
base of the tree and then they go into
the soil and so it's kind of self self
fertilizing since that's not the case
with cannabis plants essentially what
we're trying to do is to feed the
microorganisms that are in the soil and
kind of replace what would happen if we
just let the cannabis plants go through
their season and then degrade and die
you know after they seed the soil below
them so that they're ready to go in the
spring
again right so we're just trying to help
replace the nature since we are we pull
the plants out and we don't let them die
right there
yeah and you're going for maximum yields
in your your square footage so you're
you're trying to replace nature but
you're also I mean with like we use
specific sprays or or liquid nutrients
at each stage of say a cannabis plant so
cannabis plant loves about a thirty to
one
fungal the bacterial ratio so you're IMO
or you're tending of the microbial life
and your soil is going to be the huge
component to have healthy disease
resistant pest resistance even if
they're healthy and have good biology
microbiology going on in the soil and
but then there is because we're kind of
intensively farming there is the need to
apply nutrients your to get you know to
maximize yields in your space so
bringing in like a fish amino acid a
nitrogen source at the right time and
the right amount there's a big deal and
and that's not like ground upon and
natural farming it is it is about
maximizing yields but it's also
recognizing that the there's a cost to
fertilizer that affects your bottom line
and as a cannabis industry like in in
California they're kind of going through
a paradigm shift as they look look at
okay I'm not gonna get you know twenty
five hundred a pound anymore I got a I
gotta figure out a new normal which is
definitely sub but sub a thousand and
and find out what my bottom line is now
and it might mean that they have to look
at what they're paying for fertilizers
and and inputs and labor and and all
this stuff and and there's there's hope
you know this this doesn't have to be
breaking the bank to make highly
productive beautiful plan right on so
for those of you who are listening and
you're just like dying for us to get to
the techniques and you're less
interested in the in the background that
we're doing why make sure you stay to
the second set where we're gonna be
we're gonna be talking about the the
various amendments but for now we're
gonna take our first short break and be
right back you're listening to shaping
fire and my guest today is Korean
natural farming educator Chris Trump
using pesticides when growing cannabis
has been common for a long time nowadays
though we know better we know that most
pesticides formulated for food crops
have never been tested for use with
cannabis they've been tested to be eaten
in tiny doses they have not been tested
to be inhaled and especially not
concentrated into a cannabis oil
chemical residues from pesticides are
not healthy for anyone but they are
especially dangerous for patients for
commercial cannabis growers this has
become very impactful cannabis
enthusiasts and patients have gotten
educated enough that they avoid growers
who used pesticides not only that but
states across the country have begun
making pesticide testing mandatory on
all licensed cannabis crops the time has
come to find a better way to fight
garden pests than covering your cannabis
and chemicals and there is a better way
let some good bugs fight your bad bugs
beneficial insects and predatory mites
have come a long way since we were
buying ladybugs online and putting them
in the grow room and just hoping for the
best natural enemies biocontrol
can help you solve pest issues without
using chemicals natural enemies founder
shane young learned best practices from
working in the ornamental plant industry
and has fine-tuned those strategies
specifically for large cannabis crops
shane works with commercial cannabis
clients across the country to ensure
that they keep their crop safe and pest
free without the use of chemicals
natural enemies has proven solutions for
spider mites a fidex Russert mites broad
mites shore flies white fly and others
too you can rely on natural enemies for
expertise and excellent service
for more information go to shaping
feiyr.com forward slash natural enemies
or simply click on their banner in this
week's newsletter as a listener of
shaping fire you already understand the
importance of living soil when growing
cannabis when you have active microbe
communities in your substrate you go way
beyond simply fertilizing with nitrogen
phosphorus and potassium having active
microorganisms in your substrate
supports vigorous plant growth
throughout the plants root zone making
for higher yields and thriving flowers
mammoth pea is the first organically
derived microbial inoculant that focuses
on your plants nutrient cycling
processes to release soil phosphorus and
other micronutrients from they're bound
forms making them more available to the
plant increased levels of phosphorus
will also keep internode shorter and
focus your plants energy on bud
production not only that but the
microbes act as a defense shield for the
plants rhizosphere
by out competing potentially harmful
pathogenic microbes pretty cool right
mammoth pee not only unlocks the
nutrients in your soil but it also helps
protect your plant from disease mammoths
peas beneficial bacteria act like micro
bioreactors continually producing
enzymes that release nutrients mammoths
pea was developed at a u.s. university
has been extensively tested by colorado
growers and independent laboratories
mammoth pea is proven to increase growth
and enhance blooming one of the great
things about supplementing with
microorganisms is that they won't
compete with whatever fertilizer program
you're already running simply dose on
top of your fertilizer schedule for
increased benefits to learn more and to
find out where you can buy mammoth pee
near you check out their website at
that is throughout the literature is
this this bsj brown sugar
jaggery so so let's go ahead and talk a
little bit about that first before we
get into the different the different
things we're gonna do or do about it
what is this brown sugar jaggery
yeah it's um it's funny because as we as
we first were learning this as this kind
of first landed in Hawaii from Korea
there was a significant learning curve
not just from learning a new method but
just translation journey where not only
are we translating from Korean the
English we're translating from Korean
culture idioms and and indigenous plants
and products to English and American
mindset so that was that was a huge
process for and everybody involved so if
it if something hopefully that in the
education going forward people don't
have to go through that that painstaking
journey that we went through in the
beginning then they can learn from the
years of experience we've had since then
but brown sugar is used in Korean
natural farming on a lot of the
fermentation processes with fruits and
plants and was a vital component salt is
used but brown sugar and jaggery its
that was one thing in here in America
you go to Costco and you buy brown sugar
and really that's processed sugar with
some molasses added back in to make it
brown so it's white sugar and then they
browned it
with adding the molasses back in and so
when this when it was first communicated
whether we're talking about it's just
kind of the cheap unprocessed sugar you
can get in Korea or
these other Asian countries which is
just kind of lightly processed cane
sugar so it still has you know kind of
the natural molasses in it and so that
stuff kind of mainly what that's talking
about but if you can just get bound
sugar from Costco that works or if you
get some unprocessed sugar there's a
bunch of different types that are
available in the US where it's just kind
of you know sugar in the raw you don't
want to buy that they got a brand name
on that it's a really expensive but it's
it's the same concept it's just
unprocessed cane sugar or less punch
right on Ryan that makes a lot of sense
but the word jaggery it sounds so exotic
right yeah unprocessed sugar doesn't
doesn't have the same spin to it but but
at least at least you know it's the same
thing so all right so let's start at the
top of the list with these amendments um
I put them in an order of what Dilys to
me anyway seems like it's increasing
complexity and I've only made it through
the first few but my goal here is that
we can we can start with something that
sounds simple so that folks who are
listening or like oh you know I can do
that and then and then as we go through
this long second set they'll get
increasingly more complex like like
we'll probably lose some people at fish
immuno acids for example so so let's
start with maltose Oh soso break down
how people would use maltose and and why
yeah maltose is something used in Korean
fermentation in a bunch of different
ways and in the US that kind of
translates into are some of the things
we use for beer production maltose for
us as American farmers is super helpful
and not absolutely necessary so um it as
we looked at kind of translating these
concepts from Korean culture where some
things are super readily available and
everybody knows how to do
to us culture and what we have available
a lot of some of the maltose juice got
dropped in place of just getting
inexpensive beer rather than making your
own rice beer or rice wine which maltose
is used for so so it's interesting
because like you know when I first got
started I'm like alright you you you
sprout the barley and then and then you
you you crushed it and then you you
remove the foam from the top and I
continued to look for something that I
would then put that in no I didn't know
any better and I I just I just added it
to my my water that I was using to you
know my rent rain water that I was using
for the plants but are you saying that
that folks are not really using this as
much anymore because there are other KNF
techniques that you know cover that same
ground are you saying that people just
don't bother making it themselves
anymore yeah it's um so if you wanted to
make your own brown rice vinegar you
could go through this elaborate process
to make the brown rice vinegar and and
maltose is involved if you wanted to
make maca Lee which is Korean rice beer
which is really tasty and I highly
recommend going on that journey if that
interests you but yeah we've actually
just that's kind of been edited out of
the the journey for kind of an American
natural farmer for the most part it's
still cool and it still has a role if
you wanted to make it but you can do
natural farming without ever creating
your own maltose
yeah and it's something that I only
bothered to do once because as soon as I
got turned on to the second one we're
gonna talk about you know making lactic
acid bacteria from our rice water wash
that seemed to be the first one that
really hit and caused my plants to jump
so so would you explain
rice water wash and and how to ferment
it and why this matters to cannabis
plants yeah so a lot of what you can buy
in the store somebody's making you a
microbe amendment a lot of it is based
in the lactobacilli family of bacteria
which spans a bunch of little
subcategories and the idea in korean
natural farming la be lactic acid
bacteria is that you can culture it from
your area from the air and and make it
yourself in a really effective and
simple method and then have freshly
brewed kind of highly active lactic acid
bacteria from your environment to apply
on your farm and it's not super
expensive though milk isn't super cheap
it's it's pretty doable and accessible
for farmers and I think a lot of a lot
of the kind of probiotic cannabis
farmers probably started with the LAV so
when you go ahead and for the people who
have who have never created this I mean
it's not very complex would you walk
them through walk us all through a
recipe that they can kind of wrap their
heads around I mean obviously if
somebody really wants to get into this
stuff they're gonna follow up on the
episode that we're you know doing today
with some with some googling and you
know check you know to get something
that's line by line but but so people
can get their heads wrapped around it
would you explain how one would do it
sure yeah so um it's funny because I
grew up in Hawaii I was born raised in
Hawaii and the everybody knows to make
rice in Hawaii is it's just culture and
and coming to you know being involved in
mainland us some people like okay what
- its rice and so in the normal often
when you make rice you'll give it a
rinse first it's it's just kind of to
take some of the extra kind of dust off
your rice it not everybody does it that
way but but it makes it more you know it
makes it it makes it a little less Nikki
yeah so for this la be recipe you you
take your rice as if you were gonna make
yourself a pot of rice and you just fill
fill up some water in your dry right and
rinse it around and the rice the water
will become kind of milky and white and
you pour that off into a clean container
now one place people always are often
fail in this process is by having a
little soap scum left in the container
they just washed out for this so if you
have soap left in that jar where you
pour your rice wash water it won't go
properly it won't actually produce the
the bacterias will be inhibited by the
soap remaining in that jar so just make
sure real thorough rinse
protip there by go ahead and and take
that rice wash water set it on in a in a
cool and hopefully not direct sunlight
spot with a breathable lid like a piece
of paper towel or paper napkin
and let that sit for about anywhere from
one to three days generally it depending
on your temperature if it's really warm
where you are this might only take a day
if it's cooler you know in the fifties
it could take up to five days if you can
put it outside without it getting messed
with
that'd be great so if you have it under
a tree and protected from the rain and
the winds able to blow over it you're
gonna get all this all the good biology
micro microbes floating in there blows
the breeze that can jump in there but um
generally a lot of what's gonna be in
there is just you know what was in the
air when it got poured in and on your
hands even which you know use clean
hands when you make this and after about
two or three days it will change its
smell and this is ever-so-slight it's a
very slight alteration and smell so you
want to be smelling it regularly and all
of a sudden it'll have just a slightest
sweet smell to put a taste to a smell
but it's um it's just a little bit of a
hint of fermentation just just the
slightest change so if you sense just a
tiny change it's probably ready if it
smells at all rotten or super sour it
went too long you missed that sweet spot
and then you take that rice wash water
and you add it in a jar at a rate of one
part rice wash water to ten parts milk
if you can get whole milk that's great
and it can be stored by it doesn't have
to be organic it's if you if you're
gonna drink it yourself you know as a
you know health thing then you probably
go for the milk that you would want to
drink but if you're feeding if you're
putting it on soil I would just
encourage you to not spend a ton of
money on this and yeah add it one part
rice wash water to ten parts milk put it
in a cool and place out of direct
sunlight with a breathable lid again
like a paper towel you need a rubber
band put it around the lid and you leave
that and should be around five days two
to five days and you'll have a
separating of the
curds in the way just like Miss Muffet
ate when she sat on her tuffet and yeah
it's so the yellow serum or the clear
serum that forms in the jar is your whey
proteins and that's where all your LAV
activity is going to be and then the
curds is your casein protein so the two
proteins in milk will separate we do two
fermentation you you extract your curds
or strain them out you can let some of
the way I like to use something that's
fine as a t-shirt cloth if you use
something too thick like a strainer or
to pull like a strainer you're gonna get
a lot of cloudiness from the curds going
staying in your L AP serum and really
you want it to be clear so I like to use
something like a t-shirt and then yeah
you pull off your curds you can make
cheese with that or just eat them mix
them with some something and eat them
you can feed them to your livestock your
animals they'll love them and it's great
form and then that that liquid that
clear liquid that you have left you can
store in your fridge with a breathable
lid but that you can use on your plants
at a rate of one to a thousand so one
part lab2 a thousand parts water and
it's excellent for all kinds of things
there's a ton of applications of that
and the natural farming toolkit but
that's the the basic and as far as
adding it to your cannabis plants goes
there's a you know there's a lot of
different ways that you can use it but
that I would say that you know people
should know that they could both pour it
into their soil directly but it also
where it's really great as a foliar
right yeah yeah so it's at the rate of
one to a thousand it's really safe it's
not gonna cause shock or or you know any
any kind of over concentration issues
one of the things that I was curious
about is is they you know once you've
gotten to this point and it's in your
fridge and your ratio is one to a
and you know chances are that the the
LAV that you have made its gonna last
for a while but but I don't really know
how long and if there's a way that you
can extend the life of it so you're not
having to make it you know every couple
weeks what's your experience you know I
feel like in a fridge with a breathable
lid you have vitality for anywhere from
one to two months so don't feel like
about that you got to use it within the
week it's still real viable within a
couple months I wouldn't go beyond a
couple months I think that third month
that you're probably losing some of the
vitality you had initially but at that
temperature and a refrigerator it's
really everything's gonna slow down and
kind of just go to sleep or calm down a
lot of their processes and yeah so you
you're really gonna get a great storage
and a fridge if you have a store without
refrigeration you could mix it equal
mass with brown sugar so you can measure
that by weight or generally volume you
really want to put a ton of brown sugar
in so it's all the water is kind of tied
up in that and you can store that at
stores last I would say a month would be
the max on a non refrigerated kind of
ground sugar storage it's not
recommended to store with molasses some
people do that that's um that's not
really recommended in Korea natural
farming but you got to do what you can
with what you got
Yeah right yeah all right on so so so
let's move on to our next amendments
because rice water wash is great and you
know for people who are new to this it
is a you know I I can speak for myself
it is a it is a good confidence builder
right when you do that when you do that
as simple as it is
and and it goes right you're like all
right I'm ready to go what's next and
for me the next one that we're going to
talk about fermented fruit juice also
all over the internet as ffj this was
the first thing that I came across then
I'm like alright this is different what
is this and I and then I heard the term
Korean natural farming for the first
time so similar to like what we just did
with the rice water wash would you
explain fermented fruit juice and and
and then how how you choose your fruits
in and then how you do your ferment yeah
let me touch on if it's alright with you
Chango the some of the misconceptions
I've seen on the internet regarding ffj
so ffj is used in natural farming and
fairly limited kind of amount so we use
it for ripening promotion in fruit and a
few other inputs but in in the canvas
world that seemed to have been adopted
as a thing for fruits meaning bud
production and I think that that's a
little bit of a mistranslation of the of
the concepts in natural farming in it's
it's not so much intended for that
purpose believe it or not spj is
actually what you want for that and when
we can get into that next time I'm sure
fermented plant juice so fermented fruit
juice and then the second kind of
misnomer I've seen in just some of the
information on the internet is that you
just want to buy the best things you can
from the store to make your ffj with and
that all these tropical fruits were
using in Hawaii or these things are the
best when I can that's not really the
case what you want to get if you're
doing ffj is you want to find the things
that you can find wild in your
environment
so if
there goes on back to what you started
with right that you want to use the
microbes that you find in your
neighborhood so that they live where you
grow yeah there's there's some there's
some real benefit to getting the
beneficial bio chemicals that are in the
plants that thrive in your environment
and the plant growth hormones that are
fresh they're not something that was
picked green got ripe in the truck
coming across the world and has been
sitting and kind of calming down in all
its really vibrancy for weeks and before
it even gets to ferment in your
fermentation vessel and then it has none
of it yeasts and bacteria on its surface
that helped it grow because I was all
bleach washed off and so people get
these really funky green mold and stuff
forming on the top and that's mostly
because none of that by a Mike
none of those microbes that worked with
that plants for it to grow in in the
symbiotic way were present when they
began their fermentation so they're just
getting whatever was on their hands or
in their jar or which isn't really
sufficient or proper for this type of
fermentation that we're trying to
accomplish we really want a plan to
permit in its own microbiology where
microorganisms yeah so that's that's a
misnomer so ffj is a combination of
three ripe fruits so this could be
strawberries it could be it could be
even like things we don't normally eat
like oh man I can't think of off the top
of my head Pacific Northwest but it's
like rose hips if you're thinking about
north yeah Road hips are great yeah I
see all kinds of those yeah all rose
hips squash you know yeah there's
there's all kinds of anything that you
can think of that
to a ripe fruit even if it's wild and
kind of not really a normal thing you
would eat but say the birds eat it those
are all your your ripe fruits and so you
could harvest those with ssj you can use
up to three fruits and it's actually
recommended to use three varieties of
fruit so it's more anything like smile
biologically yeah and also just ripe
fruits have kind of they've they
processed to a different kind of profile
in in kind of what's going on in bio
chemicals and plant growth hormone and
all that stuff which is a you know is
it's not it's a part of it we don't
science is working hard to understand
all this going on there but um yeah so
three three different fruits you mix it
with equal weights brown sugar so if you
have five pounds of a variety of fruit
you get five pounds of brown sugar
generally if your fruits really dry
maybe your rose hips have almost no
moisture in it you could start with less
sugar four but generally the rule is one
to one sugar by weight you massage it
together break up your fruits chop it up
whatever so you kind of mash it you put
it in a jar this this mash that you've
just done you put it in the jar to
ferment for about five to seven days and
it'll separate you'll have liquid and
solids and it's really undergoes a cool
fermentation process that amount of
sugar is so that it doesn't run away now
when you go to store it so you strain it
off your solids can be strained out so
you just have your liquid left if you
use the less sugar then one to one or if
it seems like it's still really active
when storing you can add sugar you want
to kind of maximize the the sugar so
that all the water molecules are kind of
tied
and it stops fermenting because if you
have too much water it'll keep going
into alcohol and we don't want it to
become a strong alcohol we want it to
kind of stay in that minor fermentation
that it did just in that five to seven
days and then that you can store with a
breathable lid at room temperature and
that keeps for a long time that can keep
for six months really and be viable and
you use that on your farm at a rate of
one to five hundred when you're when
you're brewing up your fermented fruit
juice you're using a permeable top on
that well just like the rest of these
right like the cheesecloth or something
because you're you you both want to have
the air exchange and you want to invite
air bound you know yeasts and things
right yeah yeah and with sfj and fpj we
expect that we have a lot of our
microbes already in there but yeah we
want that that breathability that that
gas exchange that'll happen and because
the microbes will be using oxygen and
just like they they breathe you know one
of the things uh you know the first time
I tried to make this I used soar bot
stuff and you're right when when fruits
travel I mean I papaya cuz that's what
the literature was saying right but the
papaya has traveled a really long way
and in a lot of ways they try to
sterilize it as much as they can for
travel because they don't want it to rot
along the way so you're getting a
version of the fruit definitely not what
the locals where it was grown were
eating and a local friend of mine said
you know I explained to him my issue and
why my first ffj didn't work and he says
just go glean off the trees you know
whatever whatever's near your house
because it's it's not like you are
you're making this to eat and so you
necessarily need it to be palatable all
you need are the essential ingredients
of the fruit so so if you you know if
you or your neighbors got an old you
know plum tree and you know just just go
glean off
and especially if it's moving from ripe
to overripe so long as it hasn't started
producing alcohol man there's so much
biological activity in that thing it's
gonna make a great ffj yep yeah
that's ideal right on right on so so
we're seeing that we want to you know
the brewing part is easy and to get some
local fruits that are that are you know
we've got all of the the life stuff on
the outside of it and then and then make
sure that we add enough sugar and then I
was actually I'm actually surprised that
it lasts as long as it is just at room
temperature I actually went through mine
really fast because I figured that fruit
you know I always think of fruit being
unstable and it's going to go to alcohol
quickly but but it seems like if you if
you put enough sugar in you're gonna
slow it down and then at room
temperature like not on top of the
fridge like kombucha it'll it'll help it
sleep even more right yeah and and the
the thing that's actually causing it to
be shelf-stable is the amount of sugar
so if you added you know two parts water
to that so if you just dumped in a bunch
of water that would go off like crazy
and go from alcohol of the vinegar so
it's the the sugar is dry it actually
creates bonds with the water molecules
and the microbes that do fermentation
need water do any of their process so
bike this is the specific balance of
sugar or by total saturation of sugar
you've actually trapped all your your
water molecules in in chemical bonds
with sugar and and there's not a whole
lot of water available so you've created
kind of a desert environment for your
microbes so they all are just kind of
hanging around waiting for you to
reintroduce water which you do when you
add FPGA or ffj at a rate of 1 to 500
that makes so much more sense to me so
so even though the essential ingredients
are there for to continue on alcohol
because the sugar is out of balance with
the water the
microbes don't have the magic
combination to continue their party on
alcohol so they just hang out until you
add them to water and then you do you
know foliar or just add it to your sip
or whatever your whatever you're gonna
do with it
yep yeah and they they there are minor
alcohol is produced in that initial
fermentation so there is a little bit
but yeah that can't continue and use all
that sugar because they don't have the
water they do so the next one we're
gonna talk about fermented plant juice
this one is nice because you can you
know you can wildcraft you know the
plants that you want to use pretty much
year-round whereas you know if you're if
you're gonna glean you either need to do
it during fruit season or you need to
get a little more creative like with
rose hips or something so so why don't
we do the same process with fermented
plant juice please yeah fermented plant
juice is really similar to fermented
fruit juice except you don't use
multiple plants in one brew if I'm going
to use my FD J's and I want to use my
rhubarb spj at the same time I use my
dandelion fpj then I can just add you
know a half of each to make one to 500
and use it at that time but for storage
they stay separate and for the initial
brew process they stay separate so
that's that's specifically for for some
of the you know one might have a much
more delicate yeast and bacterial makeup
all over it that it's gonna do its
fermentation and and process it then
another one and I combined them for
fermentation you're gonna have you know
the dominant one or the stronger one
would take over and and you'd never even
have a representation or very small of
the you know the less dominant so yeah
you really you want to make these
separately and store them separately but
yeah with fpj you can use all kinds of
stuff
I used rhubarb here in Idaho last year
it was incredible there was tons of it
it was easy it tasted amazing and if I
wanted to you know bring in a new person
and make him taste our fertilizer you
know they were kind of floored by being
able to drink this incredibly tasting
that you know ferment we're using on
plants and so that was fun but you can
use anything so much is available and
what you're identifying as you look for
a plan for fbj is something that always
is thriving in your environment so you
want to look like for something that
nobody ever takes care of and it always
looks beautiful and green and lush and
the bugs don't even mess with it and so
find those plant you know um like where
I did we or oh yeah ice plants a good
one
also where I live we have tons of
horsetail right that was the first one I
tried cuz everyone said oh the silica in
it is is really great for for building
the strength of the cannabis plant sure
yeah or feels great um what are some
other examples of inputs like silica
that we think about wanting in cannabis
that we can get from other wild crafted
plants just just so people can kind of
get a simmer on the idea of like oh if I
want you know phosphorus I can use this
plant well that's something that's kind
of come out of the kind of general
thoughts online that isn't straight out
of natural farming from Korea that's
that's things that people have kind of
done and that's you know that's not
necessary that's not really something I
would say is wrong I think those are
really good start but that's not out of
the traditional natural farming kind of
process with if we wanted phosphorus or
potassium or calcium some of these
things there's inputs for that water
soluble calcium WCA or water soluble
calcium phosphate WC AP or wcp
so there are solutions for that in the
natural farming toolkit but I think that
that that idea of course sales is
actually it's a great thought process
but there's there's more to it there's
we want a new growth of some of these
plants we're identifying so that those
growing tips is where a plant puts a ton
of its energy they think of T cells and
plant growth hormone and and all this
stuff that that we associate with
potential energy and that's what plants
kind of jams all its energy into its new
growth or it's it's budding fruits so
green fruit is all categorized as fpj
material so if you take you know half
half-formed apples or you know green
plums that would be an FPGA you could
take rhubarb stalks and their leaves you
could take ice plant or ivy you can take
or you could take grass so you identify
some vibrant grasses you can make an
FPGA out of that so kind of sky's the
limit
dandelion we use dandelion we use
purslane all kinds of things that's
really interesting you just totally put
put my approach to this on its head
because we're not actually looking for
the specific input for example I use the
one of the silica in the horse tail
actually we want to get the microbial
level you know lifeforce one level of
magnitude down yeah that's pretty
heavy-duty yeah so so and it's there's
so little of this that we're using it
it's a whole system it's not it's not
just like extjs the one thing FPGA is a
food for the plants and the microbes and
it is
important and you are getting silica if
you're using horsetail you know that is
part of it but there's there's more to
it and it's that whole system that you
you're tending to the microbial life in
the soil on the plan itself and and yeah
so yeah it isn't just like identify a
phosphorus rich plant that's that's fine
and you can but but your there's a
bigger picture yeah your miss yeah
you're missing the love right it's kind
of its kind of a humility you're kind of
like okay there's actually some things
in natures that are beyond the NPK and
then the 23 minor minerals there's
something beyond this and we're
discovering that as we dig deeper and
understanding by the nutrients and these
you know bio chemicals were realizing
this is actually more complex than we
thought it was yeah that makes a lot of
sense into and to steal the line from
Jeff flow and fells this is like us
teaming with the nutrients right this is
us saying all right we don't necessarily
understand the life-force magic that
happens you know inside of the new
growth green you know the green new
growth on the edge of on the tip of the
plant but but we know that if we take it
and and if we fermented it a little bit
to encourage it to make more of it
whatever that you know unknown life
forces becomes multiplied and then our
cannabis plants are freakin stoked
something like that and and in the in
the process we're kind of saying and
we're just trying to partner with nature
we don't we're just trying to take
something that's vibrant and give it you
know into our commercial growing system
and benefit from what nature is already
doing well right on right on so let's
move on to fish amino acids I haven't
done this one yet and just that the fish
aspect of it has has caused me to
hesitate a little bit but but but but
please if you will explain you know what
the what the idea behind this is
and what the process looks like so this
is probably one of the best nitrogen
sources you can do you can get for
teaming with microbial life and and
using things that are really micronized
so all of natural farming these foliar
sprays and these inputs are highly
available and micronesia micronized is
nutrient TSA's is really it's a word
that's a thing where through
fermentation and the breakdown by
microorganisms of the components and
these things we're getting this this end
product this material that actually can
be absorbed by the plant itself without
the need for so like if you apply
chemical fertilizer or that to ever be
available to the plant it actually has
to be processed by some microorganism so
you know the people aqua pond or
hydroponic farmers they're always
bleaching and then they put in their
nutrients and as soon as they put in
their nutrients and the plant roots they
find that all the plant roots are
colonized by bacteria and they're like I
just leech why is there this bacteria
for them they're plants even to get
access to these liquid fertilizers
they're putting and they need those
bacteria and so for for us fish amino
acid is this is really amazing
fertilizer
there's fish hydrolysates and fish
emotions that you can buy and both of
those are good I think rolla say it's a
little better than emotion but really a
lot of those things they're they're
taking off the fats for a fish oil
product on the side you know so they're
double dipping in kind of productivity
or profitability of their product under
or they're taking off some other
byproducts of the fish and using it
elsewhere so you're not getting the
whole suite of what
like a fish has to offer whereas this
fish amino-acid this fermented whole
fish or or fish waste is the whole thing
and it's being highly micronized by
instead of us cooking it or doing these
other processes it's being fermented so
the breakdown is happening by
microorganisms yeah it's a great thing
in your plants if you actually make this
in the way that it's supposed to be made
your plants really react and they love
this stuff so well then let's talk about
how it's supposed to be made do you
really need to use the blue blue backed
fish as it says in the you know the the
you know the original treatise or can
you use it can you use whatever you want
is there something special about
blue-backed fish yeah so that blue back
fish for for the sake of kind of
translating that culturally and language
its deepwater fish they they've taken on
a different level of or a different
amount of the kind of minerals of the
ocean so farm-raised fish or pond fish
or river fish aren't gonna have quite
the same kind of mineral tied up in
their systems as deepwater fish are so
you're getting this kind of complexity
of nutrition for your plants that a deep
water fish has maybe more than a river
fish so that's that's kind of what
that's talking about so can I use what
fish I say say all I have is steel
header or tilapia can I use that and get
a fish fertilizer yeah you can and there
is there is something to this deep water
fish being recommended so just knowing
that okay I don't have the best source
but I have this tilapia that's what I
have available it's cheap and and
accessible um just know that there there
might be some benefit if you
you get you know that stuff coming off
the fishing vessels down at the Harbor
you might get some additional benefit
and that's that's why that's recommended
so up to you you got a autumn Italy
you're keen on your farm you get to make
the decisions you want to make and you
can you can do parts of this but the
year the natural farming has been
thought out very thoroughly and every
time I dig into the science I find it
sounded a really really good scientific
thought and theory and and truth so yes
so let's say okay so I've either I've
either gone down to the the the harbor
and and bought you know tuna or
something off a boat or or more
realistically the first time I try this
I'm probably gonna use something you
know less expensive like tilapia or
sardines something that if I screw it up
you know I won't feel it's quite so bad
about it so so now that I have my fish
how do you go about and stacking this
Fuhrman yeah well let me clarify real
quick if you go down and buy a fresh
tuna office off the fish make sure you
get the fillets off make yourself some
sashimi and enjoy that with your friends
and only use the bones that guts in the
head for or the carcass the guts in the
head for this fish amino acid don't let
me hear of anybody wasting a perfectly
good tuna fertilizer for yeah that that
would just be a tragedy so no and I was
thinking that it sounded really
expensive to use at a whole deepwater
fish but but with that with that
addition what actually might make a lot
more sense is to just go to your your
your local you know Japanese market
where they prepare and clean the fish
and just ask them say hey can I come
back at the end of the dragon yeah yeah
cuz I'm sure they'd be thrilled to give
it to you especially if they say you're
doing something like exotic like this
and be like oh yeah we'll hook you up
yeah this is what that is so yeah don't
don't confuse this this is cheap this is
supposed to be the the waste product
Emma and a lot of times
people are cooking with the head so you
might not even get the heads you might
only get the carcass in the gut and
that's fine some Asian cultures you're
not even good at that they're gonna
they're gonna cook with all of that but
um yeah I actually just recently for the
class I taught last November in Boise oh
yeah
I just asked our local sushi shop if if
they had any fish heads they got all
their tuna came pre filleted so I
couldn't get any tuna but I got all
their salmon heads and carcasses they
gave them a cooler of those to me and so
I I have fish amino-acid brewing in my
office that doesn't smell at all and I
share that that office I have two
offices where I work in that office is
shared with like six other people and
nobody even knows it's there and it's
basically rotting fish but it that's not
rotting it's aerobic Lee's fermenting
fish anyways here's the process XO so
you take your fish waste as we've
established not not the filets eat those
fish waste equal weights brown sugar you
sensing a theme here yeah get it okay
equal weights brown sugar a dash of IMO
four so I am very intentionally not
giving you a specific measurement you
don't have to have a super specific
measurement this is just a light
inoculum so just a handful of IMO for
for that fermentation that kind of
really skewing your your microbes for
folks who died when I mo for is we've
recently hit that yeah so that stuff
I've taken microbes out of my local
forests I've multiplied them out on
substrate it's a it's a four step
process so the number four just refers
to it's the fourth stage in the process
of taking it out of the forest and
getting it ready for my farm so it's
just indigenous inoculum so you could
take a handful of leaf litter out of
your local forest if you didn't have IMO
for
so you handful of inoculum whether it's
leaf litter out of your forest or i am a
poor IMO for is ideal and then just a
little bit of just a splash of Oh hm if
you have it
Oh HN is another natural farming ferment
I have a youtube video on how to make it
oriental herbal nutrient anyways don't
worry about those if you don't have
those you could still make this but I
would recommend going out to the forest
and getting some visible spider webby
mycelium and a handful and throwing it
in here but if you don't have that you
can still make it
so the basic process is equal waste
brown sugar and put it in a cooler and
leave it to ferment over time the
absolute earlier you would want to
extract that in the natural farming
recipe would be three months and
truthfully that's too soon it's not
going to be finished so best is a year
if you just throw it in a cooler you can
put a lid on it you don't you want to
whatever you do you want to set it up so
rats or some rodent can't get in and
ruin all your hard work but what I'll
usually do is stick a mesh over it and
throw a lid on it loosely so no rodents
can get in a little bit a little bit of
air can transfer airflow is positive but
sometimes it's hard to find a container
where it can both breathe and be closed
and protected but yeah then you leave it
for a year whether you'll have is you'll
have just the bones left over and you'll
have this like blackish liquid it'll be
straight liquid fish and it smells and
tastes like fish sauce that you buy at
the store for cooking it's really it's
really a positive smell and taste yes
I've tasted my Fisher miiniwaa acid I
I've made it with fresh tuna off the
coast of Hawaii and brown sugar and a
handful of IMO four that I made myself
and kept it nice and and
clean and the and a fresh cooler and and
then it came off and it's just a
beautiful if you can make food with it
you know this could be instead of making
plant fertilizer you just made fish
sauce for cooking but really it is it's
great
cheap fertilizer so how do you know if
it goes bad right like like like if it
starts to smell is that a good good
suggestion that something went a lot
wrong along the process yeah if you do
it if you do it according to this recipe
it really doesn't go bad um but if you
didn't have an inoculum you could have a
month period where it smells kind of
foul but that also probably means there
was something wrong with your ratio of
fish to sugar or something like that if
if you find if it seems like there's way
too much liquid you may need to add a
little extra sugar if you know that's
anyways you don't worry about that but
really it shouldn't smell and
something's probably gone wrong
but if you can get just even a handful
of soil from a wild environment could
could be all you need you just need some
kind of inoculum yeah right on good Wow
all right well this is clearly the the
longest segment of shaping fire that
we've ever done here at 50 minutes so
let's go ahead and take our second break
and we'll be right back you're listening
to shaping fire and my guest today is
Korean natural farming educator Chris
Trump while I certainly still enjoy
smoking joints I moved over to using
vaporizers about three years ago the
high was a little different than burning
the flower and in the end I decided I
preferred it for daily use especially
because I have asthma more importantly
though I could taste my flower so much
more it's hard to express to you how
significantly different cannabis with a
good terpene profile tastes when vaped
instead of burned I have brought my vape
with me to visit growers and they are
astonished by the clarity of taste and
they say they feel like they're tasting
their flower for the very
time the air vape vaporizer from air
vape usa.com is a great device to use on
the go or at home when you pick it up
and feel satisfying like a medical
device
it isn't flimsy like many vapes are I
like how the flower is inserted in the
top instead of the bottom so travels are
shorter path to my mouth with the
cannabis at the top I get a hit that
feels more substantial even though I'm
just inhaling vapor and not full bodied
smoke since I use this vape for flower
hash and concentrates I really like that
that digital control for the temperature
is right there on the front three clicks
of the button and it fires up to the
temperature I specify really quickly and
discreetly you know vape concentrates
are a milder experience than dabbing but
you still get the potency in your hit
also the taste is great as would be
expected with a low temp tab I love that
this vape gives quick little vibrations
when it gets to the right temperature
that way if I'm chatting or distracted
while it's heating up it lets me know
when it's ready if you are ready for a
nice pocket-sized vaporizer consider the
air vape the new air vape ex has just
come out and it's gorgeous and it
includes many updates you can find more
about the air vape vaporizer at air vape
usa.com if you grow cannabis with
sunshine you can often feel limited by
the seasonal cycle you want to grow
sustainably and save money so you use as
little electricity as possible but if
you haven't studied or implemented light
deprivation techniques into your
greenhouse you're leaving a lot of money
on the table by incorporating light
deprivation solutions into your
greenhouse you can often add two or
three additional growing cycles to your
year when you pencil out the financial
benefit of those additional cycles
you'll realize why commercial scale
light deprivation technology is remaking
the cannabis industry
what used to be done by pulling tarps
over hoop houses has been scaled up over
the last few years in such a way that
it's become mechanized easy and
affordable to even small-scale
commercial cannabis operations forever
flowering greenhouses is the industry
leader in light deprivation greenhouse
design in operation for the commercial
cannabis industry their team of
greenhouse experts have been in the
fields of Northern California for
decades and they're now building
greenhouses for commercial cannabis
companies across the country if you are
new to light dep and growing in
greenhouses i encourage you to go back
to shaping fire
13 with guests Eric Branstad of forever
flowering I talked with Eric about the
importance of intelligent greenhouse
management as well as the huge financial
benefit of incorporating light depth
techniques there are so many aspects of
utilizing a greenhouse that can go wrong
from temperature and airflow to light
DEP and workflow forever flowering will
help you produce crop after crop of
well-cared-for flowers they can help you
retrofit your existing greenhouse with
light depth and other modern systems at
a level that fits your budget if you're
just starting out forever flowering can
help you plan and build your new
greenhouse so that you get started on
the right foot the cannabis business has
enough risks without trying to go it
alone with your greenhouse contact
forever flowering greenhouses to partner
with folks who have an indisputable
reputation as knowledgeable and easy to
work with go to shaping feiyr.com
forward slash FFG to find out more
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire I'm your host Shango Lowe's
and our guest this week is Chris Trump
Korean natural farming educator so if
you're still with us after the second
set I appreciate you staying with us you
are either here for Chris Trump and
you're not a regular listener or if you
are a regular listener you just totally
got indoctrinated into Korean natural
farming so here on this last set we're
gonna talk about a couple different
topics and the first one we're gonna
start out with is one of my favorite
since I live on an island here and
that's fermented seawater and I got a
taker so when I first you know read this
I thought it was a typo or something how
do we go about fermenting seawater it's
it's really cool because it the it's
kind of philosophically and natural
farming the concept is we we we rose out
of the ocean ocean is the mother of life
and so you have all the ocean you know
mineral components and soil and human
blood is very similar and actually plant
blood quote unquote or cytoplasm is very
similar to seawater as well and actually
plant
um quote blood is very similar to
seawater diluted at a rate of one to
thirty and so in natural farming you'll
see sea water is used at a dilution rate
of one to thirty basically you're using
something very similar to plant blood
like so when we're at the hospital we
maybe got dehydrated or something we're
getting an IV of saline because it helps
us you know process stress or
dehydration and this is really actually
a quite similar concept fermented
seawater is giving some microbes access
to all those great minor minerals and
seawater along with some plant material
so fermented seawater is ocean water one
to thirty el ap one to seven hundred and
I think fpj one to three hundred um
somewhere in there sorry off the top of
my head but it's it's fermented for 24
hours you can ferment it longer or store
it in a vessel and it can just kind of
stay for mented seawater but if you're
raising animal and you want to kind of
cheaply better your pasture lands is a
great great thing to spray on grassland
it's also just something you can spray
on your crops somewhat regularly you
know weekly or every other week with a
great result and again almost no car so
the the ratios that you give for the
inputs those ratios are all to
freshwater right yep right on yep does
it matter and I'm assuming that with
most of these things we want to use
rainwater is probably best or perhaps
our Oh but we want to stay away from our
chlorinated tap water I would assume
yeah if you want to stay away from
chlorinated tap water ro is actually
really a
vacuum minerally speaking so it's like
distilled water and ro are fairly
similar and you want to be careful that
can be kind of shocking to plants
actually because it's so young stuff out
yeah it the water is so readily bonded
to so many things that it actually can
pass through your system and drom and a
little rather than you know and make it
back and have consequences yeah that's
interesting right on so so you you make
it in this that you put it together
fresh water with the with this salt
water the fpj and what was the third
ingredient la B Oh though I yeah that's
right baby
and and then how long do you let it
ferment how do you how do you know when
you're you're ready to go it's just 24
hours so you can go longer but yeah la B
is that thing we make with the rice wash
and the milk that serum and so your your
that's your fermenter your plant juice
is kind of like a nutrient and and this
came over hundreds of years of
observation of different things that
farmers did where basically they found
that if they took you know these minor
minerals and some plant component
through fermentation the leftover liquid
is gangbuster cool things to crops and
there was often done accidentally or you
know so like in Korea they make kimchi
and the kimchi water dumped out all
their plants wherever they dumped their
kimchi water went ballistic and where
the tastiest and sweetest and so they
found that though that mineral that
minor mineral allows plants to do
complex sugar making which we associate
with flavor yeah that makes sense and
the other thing you know not only does
the seawater have all of those those
micro minerals but it also has got
you know entirely different communities
of you know microbial activity and so
yeah and you you've you feed those guys
some some FPGA and wait which do you say
fermented fruit juice or the plant juice
goes into this plant you play oh yes
right so you give them that nutrient I
bet you they would multiply superfast
yeah and for those landlocked people if
you don't have a ocean water or you got
to drive eight hours to get some and
that's just not realistic
you could get some sea salt and put it
into water at a rate of 30 grams per
liter to make the basically that's sea
water 30 grams to one liter of fresh
water is now you have a bottle of
seawater and then you can dilute that
one to thirty or if you wanted to skip
the dilution step you put one gram per
one liter and then you have a solution
of one to thirty or it's a great excuse
to go on a beach vacation just bring
there you go bring back water with you
just do it fast because I'm sure that
those microbes don't like to hang out in
containers very long no you know sea
water seeps really nicely no in
landlocked places in Korea they actually
go and they'll get a tanker and they
fill these they have these underground
storage back and they just stow these
big old bat's and then that they need it
they pull it out oh great so let's talk
about water soluble minerals I mean we
talked about that a little bit earlier
when when you redirected me about the
silica that I from the horsetail I was
using and you you alluded to that that
you know there's actually something in
Korean natural farming for these these
minerals in case you want to you know
turn if you've got to turn up your
calcium if you've got to turn up your
phosphoric acid so why don't you break
down what water soluble minerals are in
KNF yeah there's there's a lot of
there's a lot of those and and some of
them are with with acid and rock and and
that's some some proprietary things that
master Cho does and that knowledge will
kind of trickle out over the next
several years
but the the basics and that are really
important are water soluble calcium
phosphate so that's kind of your
phosphorous water soluble calcium and
then water soluble potassium wsk so
those are WCA is the calcium that UCP is
sometimes used or WC AP for calcium
phosphate and then wsk for potassium
sorry I just rattled those off and then
to create them I have some videos on
phosphorus and calcium you can check out
on youtube but the basic recipe is that
you take eggshells or if you had access
to coral sand you could use that too but
eggshells you heat them in a pan until
they kind of they kind of cook past so
the organic matter kind of chars off and
you have just kind of the the calcium of
eggshells you throw them in brown rice
vinegar so now you have this highly
basic material this calcium rich
material and you throw it in an acid and
you get a chemical reaction where the
acid Yanks out all this calcium and you
take calcium now you have calcium in
solution or micronized through that
chemical process so you have a water
soluble calcium highly plant-available
and we use that as a rate of one to a
thousand and then for phosphorus we
taking bones so any any old butcher
bones or whatever you have you could
even go out to a ranch and get you know
Sun bleached bones out out on the range
and take them you throw them on the fire
you char them basically like you want to
make biochar so if you have a biochar
process already that's great but you
char them so they're past the organic
matter so they're just down you've kind
of you kind of charred off all the
organic matter and they're down to kind
of their mineral and so they're they're
kind of a solid black even some some
white on the edges turning to ash isn't
terrible but if it's all white its
on the ash it's really not good you want
to get it kind of at the point where
it's um even if it's some mash it's fine
even if it's some white but if you don't
want it to be brown where it's still got
a bunch of organic matter so I have I
show that in the video but it's it's
down to its mineral again you throw that
in a brown rice vinegar and it reacts
and Yanks out all that mineral and puts
it into solution and you can spray that
Fowley early and it's highly
plant-available so that helps you as the
specific stages and plant development
you know in in vegetative growth you're
going to want that calcium kind of kind
of banging in there in more so and then
in that changeover as it goes just
before it goes into flowering in natural
farming will encourage the use of the
water soluble calcium phosphate and and
then some more as it makes makes it free
for folks who have never done biochar
and the idea of of you know you charring
this stuff is new how long would you say
and I haven't actually done bone you
know if you're gonna say take a take a
small amount of bones and put it in a
like an old coffee can or something and
and and then cover it with foil and you
put it on the grill or something like
that how long would you say that it
would take for bone to reach this
mineral state we're shooting for you
know it's really gonna depend on what
your setup is if you're just doing it on
an open grill with an open fire you can
kind of watch it change so that might be
a way to do it initially but it kind of
if you're doing some kind of enclosed
thing it's gonna depend on your CV your
fire and how you set it up but on the
grill open flame it takes probably 30
minutes if you're just turning it with
some barbecue tongs or something right
on and that's what I
is going for is I I just wanted to hear
that 30 minutes so people understood
this is not like a five-hour thing this
is actually even though we made it sound
a little more exotic you know with the
bones it's it's actually you know not
not all that hard to do the recipe once
you have the bones I mean clearly the
eggshells are a lot easier to get yeah
yeah yeah so so to finish off the show
Chris I want to reward all of the hard
core Korean natural farming folks who
not only recommended you for the show
but also were like cheering me on for
having you on the show cuz you know
you're you are you were certainly a you
know I don't think you'd refer to
yourself as a celebrity but I can refer
to you as a celebrity in KNF so so I
want to invite you to go over my head
right I only know what to ask you based
on the little bit I've learned so far
and and the you know the questions that
people suggested me so so I'd like you
to go over my head and and talk about
something that that you're excited about
right now that will be you know a nice
reward to the KNF people who stayed with
us throughout the show and we're waiting
for you to like drop something you know
heavy over my head so so so please if
you would you know what what have you
been excited about recently that you
that you want to share
yeah there's um you know this this
journey and kmf is if it's deep because
it's really a pursuit of understanding
and partnering with nature which it's
the interconnectivity is mind boggling
and the science is just kind of
beginning to scratch the surface of how
things are interconnected one thing I'm
really enjoying something I'm kind of
pursuing and playing with is substrates
for growing out IMO and some of the best
media for that and what I found over the
years is that there's there's things
that certain microbes like better to
chew on than other things and so
in Korea they use a rice bran to grow to
do this I am a one through our IMO three
and four process and rice bran is rich
in fat in the u.s. they started doing
Mill Run because it was the kind of
comparable thing that was cheap and
readily available like a agricultural
by-product that was readily available
but as we've looked at it Mill Run is
way lower in fat content than a rice
bran so as far as fungal food
specifically fungi love facts so the the
cell wall of a plant is full of fats so
it's these these complex and tied up fat
chains but but cell walls are full of
them in like in plant cells so that
silica you know people are like oh
silica is great well why does silica why
is there so much and and my microbes
that that smaller you know bacteria is
really easy everybody's buying these
facilities and and stuff but these these
fungi these these microbes that tend to
have relationship with plants in a
unique way in their root structure
really require some of these I'm saying
that but these lipids and these these
things that we you know like silica
where was this kind of these complex
chains that are created and fungi get in
and they break apart these these fatty
acid chains and they use the acids and
the lipids and so what I found is that
the this the substrate are important so
in Hawaii I switched from using like
messing around with mill room and they
used a byproduct from our industry which
was kind of off grading macadamia nut
and I combine that with carbon
like a macadamia shell or wood chip or
sawdust and I found incredible fungal
growth and diversity could be fostered
in that kind of a substrate and so um
yeah I'd encourage you if you can find
rice bran or some of these other grains
that have their own decent fat profile
that might be cool to bring in to your
your material as you make your IMO three
as a food for your your bigger organisms
like a large Highfill diameter fungi you
know because they they are really
important in the whole process of
cultivating a soil food web in your in
your farm you know it makes sense to
write because Mill Run is going to be so
processed and and and the and the Rice's
you know it's got the full fat it would
make sense that that would be more of
what nature wants to respond to instead
of a thinned out processed product yeah
yeah it's it's it's fun it's a fun
journey just I kind of you know see how
we can cultivate what nature already
does yeah right on well Chris thank you
so much for coming on this show
especially for such a long episode and
and and not only you know teaching us
and sharing your experience but you know
you've been at this for a lot of years
so for you to be able to you know
capsulize it and give it context really
allows the rest of us who are new to
this to to jump in the deep end of the
pool a lot faster so thank you very much
yeah man pleasure so if you enjoyed this
episode be sure to follow Chris's
youtube channel and it doesn't have a
forward slash all you need to do though
is to just search Chris Trump and KNF er
actually I got it just by putting in
Chris Trump you can follow his Instagram
which you know it's a mix of both
growing and personal stuff and that's at
ford slash
soil steward on Instagram he's got a new
website up that is just being filled out
now so it's probably going to be
you know in a month or two but but that
you know you bookmark it for now that's
that natural farming dot CEO is his
website also Chris has got a class
coming up you can find it on Eventbrite
it's it's coming up in July of 2018 and
it's in Idaho so you know if you if you
if you were thinking you had to fly to
Hawaii you do not have to and so so you
can search that on Eventbrite and
finally I want to remind you again to
check out both the Korean natural
farming group on Facebook and also the
probiotic farmers Alliance group also on
Facebook
you can find more episodes of the
shaping fire podcast and subscribe to
the show at shape and fire calm and on
Apple iTunes stitcher and Google Play if
you enjoyed the show we'd really
appreciate it if you'd leave a positive
review of the podcast wherever you
download your review will help others
find the show so they can enjoy it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the weekly newsletter for
insights into the latest cannabis news
and product reviews on the shaping fire
website you will also find transcripts
of today's podcast as well for
information on me and where i'll be
speaking you can check out Shango lows
calm your company want to reach our
national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hot spot at shaping
feiyr.com to find out how thanks for
listening to shaping fire I've been your
host Shango lows
you