[Music]
i have been interested in the days right
before death my entire life
when i was a child my aunt started one
of the first hospices in the united
states
i grew up mowing the lawn of the small
house that acted as its office
my mom worked there for almost 20 years
in grant writing and development
my dad worked there too in public
outreach hospice
death and dying was a constant topic at
my house it wasn't dark or sad in any
way
it was just the service my family
provided in high school i was on the
debate team and we had an entire debate
season on the topic of euthanasia and
living wills
even though debate is a game i learned
the intricacies of what legally defines
life
and how the state and families play a
role beside the wishes of the patient
and now as an adult talking and teaching
about cannabis medicine
people come up to me right at the
grocery store and they got me and they
asked to talk to them in their car or
they stop me after public speeches
and very often they let me know they are
dying and they want to learn about
cannabis relief
i've learned to give an efficient dry
and to the point response
folks seem to appreciate that and off
they go to find some cannabis tincture
with an understanding of dosing and how
to use cannabis
this episode is important because dying
is not cool and there will be no
marketing or information
provided to cannabis folks who are dying
people who will die
soon and their families need one place
to get most of the information they may
need to get started down this path
all in one place that is what i'm trying
to do with this episode today
if you want to learn about cannabis
health business and technique
efficiently and with good cheer i
encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter
we'll send you new podcast episodes as
they come out delivered right to your
inbox along with commentary on a couple
of the most important news items from
the week and videos too
don't rely on social media to let you
know when a new episode is published
sign up for the updates to make sure you
don't miss an episode also we're giving
away very cool prizes to folks who are
signed up to receive the newsletter
there's nothing else you need to do to
win except receive that newsletter
so go to shapingfire.com to sign up for
the newsletter this week and be entered
into this month's and all future
newsletter prize drawings you are
listening to shaping fire and i'm your
host
shango los my guest today is dr sunil
agarwal
dr agarwal is co-founder of the ames
institute in seattle washington
a practice specializing in integrative
approaches to neurology
oncology transpersonal psychiatry and
palliative care
and incorporating cannabis ketamine and
other emerging therapies
dr agrawal is a fellow of the american
academy of
physical medicine rehabilitation board
certified in
physical medicine and rehabilitation and
hospice and palliative medicine
and the immediate past chair of the
integrative medicine special interest
group
at the american academy of hospice and
palliative medicine
he is clinical assistant professor at
the university of washington school of
medicine and a member of the humboldt
institute for interdisciplinary
marijuana research
he is also currently an associate
medical director of multi-care hospice
dr agrawal has been qualified as an
expert in cannabis and psilocybin
medical and religious use
in county state and federal courts his
education
associations and publishing are
extensive and can be found at
aimsinstitute.net
sunil has previously been a guest on
shaping fire episode 3 explaining the
geographical history of humans and
cannabis
today we're going to be discussing
integrating cannabis medicine into
end-of-life care
welcome to the show sunil welcome back
oh it's so great to be back
shango well let's get let's get right
into it and make clear what we're
actually talking about today because you
know
a lot of us have heard you know our
friends and family and even the news
talk about
end-of-life care but um except for the
idea that oh
that person's probably reaching the end
of life we don't
really have a real grasp on what that
might be so
when caregivers use the term end of life
care
what exactly are they saying
well end-of-life care is um
in in this in this country usually
happens in in hospice care
if most most people um you know when
they are facing
end of life means in hospice your
prognosis is
you have a medical condition which two
doctors certify
that you might have six months or less
to live
so it's a it's a it's a it's kind of a
care when you have you know that
somebody is near the end of life
and how how do you manage their care
such that you maximize the quality of
life uh with the time you have left
and that's that involves a whole range
of
of uh skill sets uh from the care from
the caregiver standpoint from the
medical system standpoint from the
family standpoint
um so you know that's and and that sort
of all falls under the umbrella of
end-of-life care
so how far away from death
does a patient have to be to to i don't
know qualify
for end-of-life care hospice treatment
because you know in a certain way we're
all terminal right
um but there's there's got to be a
window where it's it's it's so close
that that the strategy changes
yeah that's right i mean that's why
i mentioned hospice at the at the get-go
because this this really is
um how we build our system of care so
um hospice is sort of the most intensive
like um palliative that's another term i
want to let your listeners know about is
palliative care which
grew out of hospice it was the type of
care
palliative means to cover or to cloak
and so it's a medical specialty it's you
know where you're
working on symptom management really
high quality symptom management
supportive care
uh looking at physical emotional
psychological
spiritual suffering we call that total
pain
and so that type of care happens most
intensely a hundred percent
in hospice um it's like a palliative
intensive care in hospice
um where and that usually happens at a
patient's home
um and the team comes to them and also
is available by
by phone or you know telemedicine in
these days
so that's that's kind of um and that
that really is as a benefit that anybody
is eligible for
like i said if two doctors say that they
are potentially six months or less to
live no matter what
what medical condition that might be
sorry i was just going to say earlier
than that though now but people know
that even you know
patients need need some kind of
palliative care much earlier
than than in being a hospice care um
and and certainly anybody
you know you're right i mean we could
all benefit from greater quality of life
and better symptom management and
care for the total pain that we
experience in our lives
which is a very holistic model of care
and definitely that's
that's somebody something that anybody
can benefit no matter their age or
or illness status but um
the the medical field of palliative care
um has decided to focus its efforts
on patients with any anyone who has a
what we call a serious
uh or a life-threatening illness and so
that's at any stage of that illness
so that could be you know years before
somebody might um
you know reach and reach their death we
don't really know
but it is that patients can still be
eligible for that kind of care
even though they're not in hospice it's
just it just happens in a different way
it's interesting the that that
definition that you gave us for
palliative care
where it is care that is
more holistic and uh taking care of
the whole human instead of just let's
say the
the chemistry and mechanics of the body
when you describe that i thought to
myself well hell that's that's the kind
of
care that i wish i was getting from my
doctor my entire life
and it's just not how we how we do tend
to do things in the united states which
which is interesting um because you know
our general
fear of death in total
um you hit on palliative care and you
hit on
end of life care as far as definitions
go but since so many
people use the term terminal care um why
don't you hit on that too and then your
answer may be it's the same thing but
but but
specifically what do people mean about
terminal care
for folks who are listening and they're
they're trying to decipher
what their doctor is telling them sure i
mean terminal
if your terminal if you get a diagnosis
the doctor says you're terminally ill
that just means that you um have a
diagnosis of an illness that
um based on statistical tables um
you know will will lead to your death um
you know and that that there's a lot of
ranges of variable
variability in terms of you know two
years
one year or six months that's there's
like a lot of
um variation in that but like
for example uh an illness like uh
als or lou gehrig's disease um
people may live with that for many years
and the decline might be slow
that's where you know the patient might
slowly lose
muscle function and we don't we don't
have a cure for that right now although
there are some experimental approaches
out there that
might modify the disease but uh you know
so
there's there's another kind of
philosophy or school of thought where
people say well
we say the word terminal too quickly uh
in medicine and that
really it's kind of a um it's it's a
it can be a sort of um what do you call
it like a arrogance
because um we don't really know you know
there are there are definite examples of
spontaneous
remissions there are um you know there
are experimental approaches
and other types of things out there that
you know
uh there are people with stage four
cancer you know who are living
um for many many years now with certain
types of advancements that we have so
if somebody gets a diagnosis of stage
four cancer you know and they say well
that's
that's terminal they might not pursue
those other types of therapies that
you know have are showing effectiveness
for for survival or longevity
so that's why i'm a little i i'm
cautious with the term terminal
um because of the like i said it implies
a lot
more than we really know but it is
helpful to know the statistical tables
you know and doesn't necessarily mean
that they all apply to the
individual there's a lot of individual
variation and so that's that's where
that
comes from but we've we've kind of um um
i i think we still use it in in hospice
um so that's in hospice care you do
certify that somebody is
um you know we think we'll have six
months or less but then
what happens people still get ex let's
say they're living longer because then
now they're having better quality
of life and um and then the doctors have
to recertify the patient periodically oh
no they live longer than we thought so
let's
do we still think they're they're
terminal and then they have to go
through a process like that so
that that's it's kind of a it's a moving
target
um so just for the clarity of folks um
when we talk about terminal or not
terminal but let's use end of life care
in this case
we're not really looking for a solution
anymore right
because very often on this show we talk
about you know
taking large doses of cannabinoids to um
to fight cancer or you know other
um you know traditionally terminal
diseases but but really by the time
you're in end-of-life care
the goal really isn't to okay what are
the ways that we can
we can stop this it's really about how
can we make you
comfortable how can we make you mentally
present so that you can interact with
your family
how can we decrease your pain so you can
experience some joy
and maybe a little bit of
self-actualization um
before your last breaths but it's not
really about curing you anymore right
well you know people still uh
people can still have hope for that kind
of thing if they
we don't we don't want to um discourage
that you can still have that kind of
care uh you can see you can have the
care exactly as you describe the
impeccable a management of comfort
family support
psycho spiritual physical health and
healing
in terms of quality of life you know
improving your like you said your mental
acuity or just
physical comfort all the different
layers and then making sure that your
family is
also cared for and has support and we
usually accomplish this with not just
like one doctor or one nurse but really
like a whole team of
we call a multi-disciplinary team of
specialists like chaplains social
workers
you know integrative therapy um
acupuncture
providers or reiki or any you know
there's a there's very broad range of
specialties that get involved to to make
that
that kind of care um possible uh at the
end of life
but at the same time a patient might say
well you know i'm
i still want to take my ex
you know because even though that that
might
might be like an experimental therapy
you know to help a patient to see if
that'll um
improve their the length of time that
they have
or or slow the disease that's that's not
a
incompatible with that and patients
still have a right to
explore experimental treatments even
while they're on hospice
it's just generally the hospice the
medical
medicare which is usually most patients
in the hospice or medicare
they don't pay for that care they do let
you see a doctor
on the outside one doctor on the outside
like your old primary doctor or somebody
else so
so there there is a way to still have
hospice care
high quality of life care and still
explore the other aspects that you're
talking about but of course i'm
the we we we don't the end of life care
folks are focused on
how to make that quality of life as good
as possible so
so that um no matter what the patient is
doing um
you know that's that's the best possible
day and
and then also the people who live on
after the patient that they're they're
not racked with um
complicated grief or um you know
trauma from the um from from their loved
ones um
so right on so so just for the sake of
clarification because
of the particular audience that i have
you know you you said that the the
patient may still want to be taking
their ex
and it's a you know a a a it may be an
uh
you know not totally researched or
finished
um uh medicine or whatever when you say
x you meant like a variable
like whatever pharmaceutical that they
were getting good relief on you
are not referring to ecstasy mdma
correct oh yeah
yeah on another show you wouldn't have
to clarify that but on this show you do
so we work with a whole lot of different
entheogens so
although i mean certainly we can talk
about in theogens and and
and then pharmaceutical endogens like uh
mdma here
or the cogeners mdma is like similar to
um
you know uh something from sassafras
ceferol
and that um these are you know and and
and also has similar it's similar to
um masculine and it's been mescaline's
been used for
you know thousand years at least or more
in in in
different types of healing like holistic
healing that we're talking about so
there's definitely a uh like that we can
talk about that too
but i was referring to in that context
like if anybody wants to
sort of use i've had a lot of patients
in hospice that continue to use
different like supplements or natural
medicines um
that are you know they hope that have
anti-cancer activity for example
but at the same time they're receiving
high quality hospice care so
it's it's still possible to have that
hope of
of um having something to you know do
something about the disease process
uh but also being under the care of a
team that's
really focusing on your um comfort and
quality of life so
so while we're probably not gonna have
time to get into
the the mdma mimic that you just
suggested which is like
um uh mescaline and from a root
i know that there's a lot of people
whose ears just perked up like mine did
can you just give us a quick search term
for folks who want to look that up like
what what would they google to find out
more about this preparation you're
talking about
oh oh sassafras root yeah oh it's
sassafras okay
yeah that was that was just i was just
giving an example of
like you know it's a mdma was made
in german by german chemist in the 19th
early 1900's
but its chemical structure is very
similar to
um chemical that's been used in
natural medicine for a long time uh
sassafras oil
an ingredient in sassafras oil um so
that's all i was just sort of tying it
back to
back to a natural um cogener or
something in nature that it's very
similar to
and then i was also tying it to the
class of of um
compounds called phenylethylamines
phenylethylamines um
are are you know what mdma is like that
and
um and then there are naturally
occurring phenylethylamine
mescaline as your listeners might have
heard of so
i was i was just giving you some some
you threw mdma over there
and talked about anthogen so i wanted to
one of my interests is this class of
compounds and i think they're
they have a huge role to play in um in
end-of-life care and
and we're getting a lot of uh research
studies on that nowadays so
uh it's even more um compelling um
and um and i i'm i'm incorporating some
of that in my practice but we can talk
about that
later right on so because cannabis is
such a versatile healing herb you know
it's it's used for a wide range of
relief in all sorts of ways capsules and
vaped and tinctures and suppositories
and smoked
but you know as as a doctor you know
who still has um a very active clinical
life and you are seeing patients and
families all the time
i i imagine that even though there's a
wide range of
possible um uses for cannabis
that um that there are some that come
up more often what are these uses that
come up more often that you see
um when actually dealing with real life
patients
well cannabis is a widely
utilized um for managing the
pain managing fatigue
managing insomnia managing
like nausea and vomiting
the those are some of the uh did i
mention mood
i think i think though that that there's
like
a whole symptom cluster that
um you know cannabis can help patients
with and that's
that's exactly um what i have seen in my
practice and encourage
patients that um have access to cannabis
um who are
at um you know in in end-of-life care
settings
it's not it's not always easy to to make
that access thing happen i know we're
going to talk about that later
but when you do have access to cannabis
it can do a lot of work
to take care of these um really
difficult symptoms that
normally doctors would prescribe opioids
and benzodiazepines and some
pharmaceutical anti-nausea medicines to
treat
it is really interesting isn't it how
some of the some of the symptoms that
patients want relief for
are are some of the more basic things
that cannabis helps with like
nausea and pain and just general
muscle tension stress anxiety about
being sick
and and yet um you know once folks start
taking it for that they start to realize
all these other benefits like oh gosh my
my my ibs has gone away or my headaches
have gone away and
and and then suddenly now they're now
they're taking it for
a much wider range of symptoms than they
are originally taking it for
because once they have first-person
experience with it they're like oh my
god where's this been all my life
you got it that's right it's called i
call those side benefits as opposed to
side effects
so so um we're going to go to the we're
going to go to a break soon
and then we're going during the second
set we're going to talk much more
specifically about
using cannabis for end-of-life care but
yeah i want to before we go i want to
make sure
that we we talk about how this process
gets started you know
when cannabis comes up do you
find that it's normally you as the
doctor
who is mentioning it to the patient and
their family
or do you find that usually it's the
patient who has found out about it on
their own
and they are requesting this guidance
from you
well shingo i would say that the answer
to that question has shifted
quite a bit over the the last you know
i guess i've been i've been interacting
with patients
um you know as a professional medical
student or something for
almost 20 years so the situation
from the first half of my career
practice has shifted
where um to initially where i was
bringing it up more
to now where patients are already
already know about this and are bringing
it up for
for more specialized guidance so it's
it's it's really
um you know that now of course that
changes
in terms of demographics that you're
you're you're working with
um you know what is the age range the
patient what is their ethnic background
um what kind of setting are they in like
in a nursing home or
hospital or in a community setting so
it's really those variables and then now
i'm in a practice where
you know cannabis is very prominently um
featured on our
or you know on our materials and and
people know me for that kind of work so
it's um i end up getting patients who
already know about it and are
more like well yeah i know it can be
helpful i've tried it but i don't really
know how to
i need to kind of refine that or i need
more guidance so a lot of times patients
are bringing it up
well actually that's a that's a great uh
transition so our next set is going to
be all about
um refining and patient understanding of
how best to use
cannabis so that'll be great let's go
ahead and get this first commercial out
of the way
we're going to take a short break and be
right back you are listening to shaping
fire and my guest today is hospice and
palliative care specialist dr
sunil agrawal sometimes the topics i
want to share with you are far too brief
for an entire shaping fire episode
in those instances i post them to
instagram i
invite you to follow my two instagram
profiles and participate
online the shaping fire instagram has
follow-up posts to shaping fire episodes
growing and processing best practices
product trials and
of course gorgeous flower photos the
shango los
instagram follows my travels on cannabis
garden tours
my successes and failures in my own
garden insights and best practices from
personal grows
everywhere and always gorgeous flower
photos
on both profiles the emphasis is on
sharing what i've learned in a way that
you can replicate it in your own garden
your own hash lab or for your own
cannabinopathic health
so i encourage you to follow at shaping
fire and
at shango lows and join our online
community on instagram
[Music]
as a business owner you are incredibly
busy in reality you are responsible for
everything your company does
you've got so many responsibilities
every single day that often you just
don't have the time to really
dig into your marketing as deeply as
you'd like
you know there's more that you could do
to reach out to new customers and
encourage loyalty in the customers you
already have
but you certainly don't have the time
for it and you're not ready to hire
somebody full time for that role either
for you i recommend blunt branding at
blunt branding kirsten nelson and her
team are focused on improving your
bottom line
you know most marketing firms are
excited to make your logo
packaging and website very pretty but
they leave responsibility for improving
your bottom line up to you
they don't want that kind of
responsibility but that's pretty much
the most important part of marketing
right
kirsten and her team will help you
engage new customers funnel them to your
point of sale whether it be
online or a storefront and keep them
coming back to you and telling their
friends
now if you happen to be a new cannabis
company or an established company moving
from medical to adult use in your state
kirsten especially can help you not only
is she well reversed in marketing and
finance but she
totally gets cannabis whole plant
medicine terpenes heritage farmers
and the particular needs of startups
check out what she did recently for moon
time medicinals and humboldt at
moon time medicinals.com kirsten and her
team put together a whole brand package
for them
built their website and wrote their
sales materials no doubt this is a paid
commercial spot but that does not mean
they bought my opinion
i've worked with blunt branding on five
projects now for various of their
clients and
every single time they have done more
than they have promised and over
delivered on results
i love how they generate new revenue and
focus on that as the goal instead of
just making a pretty logo
similarly every single friend i have
referred them to has come back to thank
me
and that just does not happen every day
grab a pen and paper because the website
address is coming up
if you want someone to implement
marketing programs that feed your bottom
line
give blunt branding a call they will
share proven techniques to increase your
audience and generate sales
while using cutting edge technology
solutions in the background
that make all of this easy automatic and
trackable
go to shapingfire.com forward slash
blunt branding to find out more
you can also click the link in our
newsletter blunt branding
marketing that makes you money
[Music]
did you know that shaping fire has a
fabulous youtube channel with content
not found on the podcast when i attend
conventions or speak or moderate panels
i always record them and bring the
content home for you to watch
the shangolos youtube channel has
world-class speakers
including kevin jodry of wonderland
nursery talking about breeding cannabis
for the best terpene profile
nicholas mahmoud on regenerative and
polyculture cannabis growing
dr sunil agarwal on the history of
cannabis medicine around the world
ben cassidy of true terpenes on using
terpenes for health in your everyday
life
reggie gaudino of steep hill on the
cannabis genome and jeff lowenfeld on
the soil
food web there are several presentations
from dr ethan russo on terpenes and the
endocannabinoid system
and even my own presentation on how to
approach finding your dream job in
cannabis
and why we choose cannabis business even
though the risks are so high
as of today there are over 100 videos
that you can check out for absolutely
free
go to youtube.com forward slash
shangolos
or click on the link in this week's
newsletter
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire i'm your host shango los
and our guest this week is hospice and
palliative care specialist
dr sunil agarwal so you know
during the first set we kind of gave a
little background for folks who are
new to thinking about end of life care
so we know exactly
when it is what it is and uh you know
what it may take to get the to get the
topic started on cannabis medicine
um during this set we're going to talk a
lot more about the how
right as as sunil was talking about
before we went to break
um there's a lot of different ways to
use cannabis and not all of them
are appropriate for for each kind of
ailment
now before we get into those specifics i
want to point out that
there is no way that we are going to get
through
all of the different ailments and ways
that cannabis can help
um during this show or or during one of
any show
and so there's i want to refer you to a
handful of shaping fire episodes that we
already have out
that goes in depth into cannabis use
for particular ailments so here here
they are so uh
episode 22 you can learn about treating
brain injury with cannabis with dr ethan
russo
episode 36 is on breathing copd
and asthma and with cannabis with dr
robert
excuse me with robert littman episode 57
using cannabis for parkinson's with zoe
sigmund
episode 60 on decreasing chronic pain
with cannabis instead of using opioids
with dr eddie ray
uh episode 62 on um uh satisfying
sexually
with a chronic disease with uh counselor
and therapist
chris maxwell rose and then uh the
recent episode episode 67 on treating
migraines with cannabis with dr ethan
russo
so um so with that um sunil you know
most people think of using cannabis
medicine by
smoking a joint right just because
that's kind of what the picture that
they have in their head from culture
but really smoking's not usually the
proper
form for most patients both because
uh the dosing comes on so fast and also
most terminal or end-of-life patients
are are not usually a location that that
smoking
is um you know appropriate because
they're they're likely indoors and
perhaps
in some kind of an institutional setting
so so
what when when people ask you about well
well doc should i get some
cannabis flower to smoke what do you how
do you interpret that for them
yeah i also the other i i say the same
thing you just said
and also the fact that with smoking you
um it doesn't last as long it might
might be quick to come on which actually
can be nice and helpful
and for that reason i don't i try to if
a patient has the accessibility
to have vaporizers access dry flower
vaporizer or
or clean a clean oil that's vaporizable
without
pesticides or solvents um and you know
any excipients
so there are oils can be vaporized too
and and
inhalation is can be really effective
when you need relief like
now and you don't need that much
so you're fast acting and titratable you
know
as i'm sure your listeners know is
there's so many advantages of that route
but
the disadvantages are like you said
context environment that might not be
conducive to that
and also the uh the fact that um you
know your relief might not be as long
lasting because the onset
and and and fall-off is is short
so i just kind of educate patients about
that and that
if you do smoke you know the institute
of medicine
uh 99 their earlier report on cannabis
and in end of life care you know um they
said that
yeah hey you know the risks would be uh
outweighed by the
i mean the benefits will be updated with
the risk risks of smoking in patients
who are
terminal or end of life so we don't
really
i mean if a patient wants to do that and
and likes that and likes the flavor the
taste
you know um that approach and they have
a setting that's conducive to that i'm
not gonna
i'm not gonna you know stop that or get
because
that yeah there are risks like soot um
you know coughing
um and of course you mentioned the
respiratory sensitive individuals in
that earlier
show you had on copd um so those are the
those are the risks but if if they're
okay with those things or
and and i think i still think it's worth
supporting patients to do that it's a
very
old method of use and it might be part
of their tradition
it might be part of their um you know
the the sensual aspects of cannabis
and i i didn't get to mention that in
the last section that cannabis is also
useful for patients at end of life
on on improving you know their um
sense of being and well just overall
general
psycho-emotional spiritual wellness and
so anything that's going to help connect
them to
a tradition or a aroma that feels
you know comforting is is great so
that's that's all the big caveat i would
say
to patients about that i like how you
put point that out about the tradition
culture and the um i don't know the
emotional connection
with flower because it really is
different isn't it between people who
are learning about cannabis and starting
to use it for the first time at end of
life versus a lifelong user
of cannabis who is using it at end of
life i mean i have gone to so many
patient events where
you know you've got these these these
older
folks who've been smoking weed their
whole life and you know
they look so much more at ease and in
their realm when they've got a joint and
there's smoke in it and for me
as an asthmatic i'm like oh you know all
that combustion and all that heat
that's not you know for me um that in
that it
makes it harder to breathe and isn't
great but but you see these
you see these folks and like it's it's
been their release from anxiety and part
of their social world for so long
i discourage people to you know
try to have those people switch to you
know something else
just because they are you know dealing
with end-of-life care
because you don't want to take from them
something that they have been using
effectively their entire life you know
let
the the they're going to get the the
muscle relaxation the anti-anxiety the
increase in appetite you know they're
gonna get the basics whether or not
they're
you know smoking and combusting a joint
or
using a vaporizer but gosh you know
let them let them let them use it the
way that they want to
yeah exactly we our philosophies often
don't take away what people it's already
working for them
but maybe you can add to it or
supplement you know as long as it's safe
um so i i you know then i would educate
patients about the value of tinctures
you know
um or or suppositories or method or oral
edible route
the you know if they aren't um that that
they could add that in
and enhance the benefit that they're
getting
um so that that's sort of how i approach
that like it's
both and you know yeah possible and so
but before
we move on from smoking so i guess again
essentially the summary is is
if if there's no uh health reason for
the patient to
stop smoking and they love smoking
joints let them
you know go about their their way that
they always have
but if um if there are lung issues
um or or if they might be able to be
allowed to do this indoors
you know consider a flower vaporizer
which
um you know honestly i've heard from so
many patients
who they just close their door and they
vape in their room in an institution
that's federally funded and it's not
allowed but because
you know vaporization isn't smoke it
doesn't get the same kind of attention
from staff
and so um you know that's that and so
you know be aware of vaporization as an
option
um but don't think it's the only option
um just because somebody's sick
so so let's move on to capsules so um
you know
uh capsules are good for many patients
because of the ease of use right there's
there's no smell
it's it's discrete um it's it's very
easy
with the dexterity of the fingers you
know to just take a capsule versus
you know roll a joint or or you know
take tincture or things like that but um
but it's not so
good for some folks with like throat and
some stomach issues so
so please speak to your experience about
capsules
yeah you got it i mean a capsule can
basically people talk about um
encapsulating
in usually like cellulose capsules
um various extracts of cannabis
some people just use raw fla or heated
up flour
and ground up you know cannabis flour
or more commonly an oil extraction
like a coconut oil extraction or you
know a glycerin
um and then you and then your alcohol
extraction and then you
you just take take a chunk of that and
then fill it into a capsule
and there you have an encapsulated um
cannabis product which
um you know as you said by you it
bypasses it's not the lungs it's not the
oral mucosa
it goes straight to the stomach and in
the small intestine
it um you know absorbs the absorption is
more variable
but it's still it's longer lasting and
if you have if you take it with a fatty
meal
you know or oil drink sip some oil
it'll improve the absorption ability and
then it goes
has first pass effect through the liver
so you get more potent
and if you're working with a thc you get
11 hydroxy thc which is
more potent and you know you can have
several hours
of of effectiveness and you know all you
had to do was just swallow one capsule
so that's very convenient and um you
know i think
uh can can do a lot of um good for
patients
uh for for the symptom clusters and um
that we were talking about before so
yeah it's
it's very i i think you're right the
swallowing challenges are there
uh i've had some patients um i've heard
about patients that
just skip the uh who have feeding tubes
in um
and um i had a doctor teacher a doctor
who was a teacher of miami medical
school and she told me stories how they
would just
in the 80s uh somebody who hadn't used
cannabis for for nausea vomiting symptom
relief
but couldn't swallow so they would just
they made an oil
um and dripped it into the
opening of the uh food the feeding tube
yeah
so that's the you know sometimes you got
to just skip the entire upper
gut upper gi and go straight to the the
opening that patients use
yeah wow that's that's that's
extraordinary i've not heard of that
before
one of the interesting things about
capsules and you hit on it just a moment
ago
that there are there are some uh uh
stomach issues that you have to avoid it
because
even though cannabis is good for stomach
issues
the capsule itself is irritating for
lots of different types of patients and
so
it's weird to say that you know cannabis
is great for stomach issues and
digestive issues with it which it is
but a the method the capsule itself may
be the irritant
so you know patients patients and
caregivers
they'll get more sophisticated as as as
we go with this
um you mentioned a wide range of things
that could be in capsules
uh you know from um you know uh
just just uh flour that has been put
into a capsule
um and and then oils and then and then
whatever type of combinations that they
might purchase at a at a uh
at a recreational legal cannabis store
um
i think it's probably a good idea for us
to mention that if you
are interacting you know if you're using
uh
capsules that are homemade versus
capsules that are store-bought you're
going to want to make sure that you take
you know at least one of these capitals
maybe a few if they're if you think that
there might be a lot of variability to
them
and go ahead and drop them off at a a
cannabis
analytics lab hopefully you know if you
don't have one in your state you'll have
one soon
the point i'm trying to make is that
dosage is very relevant when it comes to
this because
you know one of the big aspects of
medical cannabis is repeatability of
results
you don't want to have a patient who is
taking
you know a particular dosage of a
cannabis
product consistently and then all of a
sudden they take the eighth or ninth
capsule
and and now they're over the moon high
because
um there's so much variability in it so
so i'm a big fan of people
you know making their own cannabis
medicine but
um would you agree that the the
repeatability of results
is essential when it comes to this type
of care
absolutely yeah if you if you can get to
a lab uh if that if you're in a state
where you have access as a patient or as
a consumer
um why not utilize it it's good to know
how much
you know at least the the potency no
there's other
testing for safety too you know if you
got it from some place and you're not
sure the pesticide content or heavy
metal
residue so those are also important for
safety purposes
and um and then potency is great too so
you can know
okay i'm i'm trying to i want to get
five milligrams of thc
and 25 milligrams of cbd or or i want to
have a high cthc low cbd
or you know i want to i want to some
places offer terpene testing
so those kind of things will give you a
chance to
to understand more about what your
responsiveness is and and what you might
need to adjust
to maximize the response you're looking
for so it's
it's very uh it's very helpful though i
it's hard
some places don't have it and sometimes
the testing is expensive
so um those are the draw the limitations
sure and and while we're talking about
limitations let's let's hit on the
limitations of capsules we've already
hit on the fact that
that the actual act of swallowing them
can be an impedement for
many patients but also the the putting
them together the actual
physical capping them up is is very
likely going to be something that
is going to be difficult for the patient
and gosh it's it's also very possible
that it's going to be difficult for the
family members too because making caps
is not the easiest thing
uh unless you've got you know very fully
functioning phalanges you know
and so there is a capsule making
machines you can get which we sometimes
patients benefit from
simplifying their lives you know it's
like an auto auto capper
absolutely and and you know for somebody
who is
uh uh working in end-of-life care and
it's not going to be immediate that
might be
that may make a lot of sense um the
thing
the biggest drawback for me when
recommending capsules to patients though
is the fact that you're you're kind of
uh
tied to the preset dosage that's in the
capsule
and i'm a big fan of uh
variability and dosing uh from day to
day
uh based on the patient's needs so they
can titrate themselves
and for this um tinctures become very
popular
what have you seen as far as like the
the benefits of a patient being able to
control
their dosage up or down based on their
day
oh let's yeah that's very
beneficial especially when you're um you
know
struggling with getting your regimen
right or you're in the early phases for
for patients who you know kind of
already know what their
what their sweet spot is what their um
you know about
amount of medicine that's going to
improve their um
whatever symptom or you know global
cluster
they're treating and then it's some
capsules you know can be a simple
sort of fix but if you haven't really
nailed that down there's nothing like
the tincture
um to really help to um kind of
play with okay let me half a milliliter
here there or quarter mil
um increments just to kind of see what
happens
and that's we call that auto titration
um it's
it was this it was a back in the day uh
when we were still
fighting where whether we can even you
know have medical marijuana and all
these
states that we have it now there was all
this you know
um there would be this the conservative
establishment would say oh well
gosh you know there's no there's no
single dose and that's that's terrible
like what kind of medicine is that
and um and then we'd go back and say
well no this is even this is called auto
titration you can actually
you would the patient can self-adjust
their dose based on what they what their
need is and how they respond because
there's so much
variability in you know each individual
patient's endocannabinoid tone their
absorption their
metabolism of different cannabinoids and
they're based on their their
genetic profile so it's um it's really a
it's a huge asset to to cannabis
medicine to have this
ability to safely you know
have little slight scales of sl you know
sliding joe sliding skills so to speak
it's interesting too how different
patients use that variability that
sliding scale
uh differently than each other for
example i have seen about the same
number of patients who
have a smaller dose of thc and a higher
dose of cbg and cbd
in the morning and and then maybe a
little bit more
by day time as their body is getting a
little more sore
and then by evening when they've already
you know visited with their family and
done whatever they have to
productive or whatever during the the
day and they get to the evening they
increase their dosage to decrease the
the stress on their body and just make
their body more inhabitable
whereas in that example where you start
slow and you increase the dosage
throughout the day
i've seen just as many patients go the
opposite way where they wake up
in a great amount of discomfort because
uh for many of them it's it's from you
know
sleeping or or being horizontal and not
sitting up or whatever and so they wake
up in a great deal of discomfort
and so they start the day heavily and
then and then they slow down
through the day and then and then they
increase again at night so they
they can increase their cannabinoid load
before they go to sleep
and it's that kind of variability which
a lot of patients
love about cannabis right because you
just not really offered these options
as a doctor in your situation where you
can really
go up and down and and give the patient
so much control
well that's fascinating shango that
you've been able to see that kind of uh
you know range of variable usage and
effectiveness that's just so
fantastic to hear so so
when you are explaining uh
uh um variability of dosage
individualized medicine and that the
patient's in control
for for for most patients throughout
their life
their relationship's been with the
doctors that the doctor tells you how
much to take
and you're not supposed to deviate from
that but we all know that we all pretty
much deviate from what the doctor tells
us and then we
often are not clean about that with our
doctor
because we because they're an authority
figure
how do you how do you go about
explaining to a patient that
they are in control of this medicine and
they can take as much or as little as
they want
how do you kind of get them past the
taboo that they
are in control and that they don't have
to do it the way
um the way that they're being told yeah
absolutely
i mean that i think um a lot of
what i've i'm coming from this
integrative medicine background
you know where um people are used to
you know having a little bit more
autonomy or a little more involvement in
their health care
um and so that that certain type of
consumer or patient
that that has already you know learned
to listen to their body and then to
to be more active in that pursuit and
cannabis is a traditional
plant medicine natural medicine and and
that's
you know people grew their own and and
made their own products for
thousands of years probably and um i
think it's just um
um you know just reminding people that
this is not um kryptonite
uh and that it's not gonna be like you
take too much and then you're gonna go
to the
you know fatal overdose and you know
something like that
like might happen if you're um you know
trying
um some other more higher risk profile
natural substances because there are
definitely you know if you
take too much datura or something like
that you know you can have a really
significant reaction or other types of
plant medicines that have value but but
also have a narrow window
so it's emphasizing the safety um you
know from the medical standpoint
is really important and it's we we're
fighting you know decades and decades
of of political um and you know
health political politicized public
health messaging
on the um you know uh extremely
severe dangers of cannabis so that even
one you know micro
fragment is enough to you know um
be so dangerous to society that somebody
needs to be put away
in jail and that that's just that that
kind of reinforces the
that fear and that cons that like let me
be very very cautious
the other thing i would say is that
there's been a kind of a proliferation
of para educators uh um
para health professional educators um
who who help
patients um with with dosing uh with
titration with kind of
feedback and so it's it's having
having somebody who you can kind of work
with
who can help kind of guide you in a more
you know
definitely you can still you're still in
control but it's still nice to have
a back and forth you know to to check
yourself with to get other ideas
other other suggestions of medicine or
product and so i i've
i've found valuable for patients um when
i can refer them to
um a company or an educator that's
you know doing that work and coming from
a patient advocacy standpoint where
they're trying to empower with education
so that's uh that's another way to kind
of be in the in in between ground it's
not just the doctor the patient it can
be
like a team of um with health educators
i i like that we keep on coming back to
this team approach
uh because you know while this is
becoming more and more popular
historically it's not really how
americans have interacted with the
medical establishment and
and i think that the the more examples
you give uh the more
apparent it is that this this level of
care that hospice patients are getting
is so much higher um that and it's so
effective that it would really be great
if if we all had that
um so so let's talk about this last
category of
methods for using cannabis medicine and
and that's suppositories and while you
know while he
always gets giggles when when i speak
about it publicly
um when push comes to shove
it it can it can cause so much
symptom relief that it brings patients
to tears because
they they've gone through all these
different um
pharmaceuticals and and they they didn't
reach the needs that they wanted
and so then everybody tells them they
should try you know cannabis medicine
and
and generally you know suppositories are
not the first things
suggested by friends you know so they go
through they go through smoking and
maybe they'll go through capsules and
maybe they'll go through tinctures and
then they're finally like what the hell
you know
none of this stuff is working for me but
it's supposed to work and it's working
for other people
but because of their particular health
issues you know these other methods are
not working
and so you can take an oil
and and make it into a suppository and
then
when you insert it rectally the the the
capsule
or the the the oil uh so some people use
like a
like a frozen um uh frozen oil
uh i don't know pill i guess i'd
consider it and
and then that melts and the the uh the
tissues on the walls of the rectum
will absorb the oil and
and the two biggest benefits that i find
that are unique to it is number one it
skips the stomach and
and whatever kind of problems could be
going on in the stomach
but also um you can take a higher dosage
of thc
as a suppository than you can otherwise
for
pain relief so how do you see it
actually
play out first person and i guess
suppositories are rare enough that you
that you may not have uh seen much of
this firsthand but
but uh but perhaps you have so what are
your thoughts
well i think it's really i think you've
pretty much said it all it's
we don't have as much you know like
pharmaco pharmacological data for a
pharmacokinetic is what it's called
where you know
you look at absorption and you kind of
calculate how much is in the bloodstream
as a function of how much you put into
the
into the suppository that data isn't is
there as much as
we have with other routes of
administration so it's there's a little
bit more of um
you know individualized or anecdotally
driven um recommendation pattern which
is fine
i think it's um it's just we just need
more learn to learn more i think
you know um like for example i think you
know the the absorbability of cbd might
be higher than thc or
actually i think the the thc we have
better data on than cbd let me put it
that way in terms of absorption from the
even the ability to absorb from the um
rectum
so and then the other there are other
issues with um
um whether you're placing it in the
right level
in in the rectum because there's there's
actually like um
some the blood supply and there there's
a there's there's a like a line of
tissue that separates
uh one one level of the rectum from
another and there might be some some
people
might need even deeper insertion for
better absorption but then
you know you really want to make sure
you don't have anything in there that's
going to
cause any any harm like it should really
just be a dissolving
um you know like bullet shaped type
like oil oil object so the suppositories
can be there's more of an art to it and
um
and i i think um i i think
you you it's sort of like uh smoking
where you do bypass a lot of the liver
effects
at the first stage so that's kind of
nice um
and but you also get the longevity of
effect of effect so that's also very
okay can be very helpful so i think it's
um
i have a less experience i have patients
that certainly use cannabis depositories
and and they're very happy with the
effect um i have we
prescribe other medicines by its
depository so it's not not a new
method to me it's just that we don't
have as much data on it with cannabis
it's really interesting helping patients
and their families
you know once they've decided that
suppositories are going to be their
solution
um it's amazing how much i've learned
about suppositories
just from trying to help uh families
figure out how to do it right you know
they're they're suppository kits online
on ebay that you can pick up and
it's really funny they look like um you
know they just they look like ice
make ice trays right and and people are
putting you know a little
a little squirt of cannabis oil from a
syringe and a little bit of shea butter
and a little bit of coconut oil in there
and then
tossing them in the freezer which is
like a really really basic
um recipe and um
and you know they get harder and then
once they take them out you know they've
got a few moments to um
introduce it to the body before it warms
up and gets
uh soft and of course that's always an
interesting experience for the patient
um to have something so chilly down
there but
but um it's interesting like i find that
more and more people are realizing that
a lot of um just regular old capsules
like you'd buy at the pharmacy just like
empty
you know number three capsules um
they as well will uh disintegrate in the
rectum
and it really doesn't have to you don't
really necessarily have to go down
this path of you know building your own
reinventing suppositories
um right but but you know it's a
it's a whole rabbit hole of its own you
know
yeah i i think it's um we need more data
um but i think i'm really happy to hear
that patients are making their own
products and
exploring it and um i think a lot of
folks are also
interested in this for disease
modification you know to get the night
higher number of milligrams to see if
that will help to
change the course of their cancer and i
just
i think it's harder we need more
information to find out exactly how much
is coming out of there
uh into the bloodstream so that we can
um you know help guide better
and i think there's gonna be we're gonna
find it's not it doesn't not everything
absorbs the same way
that um and that that you get in the you
know small intestine
so it's um it's going to be um
uh i don't know um hopefully somebody is
going to do that those studies
so so what what advice do you have for
folks who are going to use
different methods together so say
they're going to use
capsules and smoking or vaporizing and a
tincture
or or you know one of the others in
suppositories
um uh because you know in
taking these different ways you you have
issues with you know timing of when it
hits your body and also
having to do the math of your your
dosage
you've got a you know a lot of
experience with you know a variety of
medicines and stacking them right so so
so how do you teach that to patients
yeah it's
it's pretty much like a uh you want to
have
what we're talking with end of life
patients so a lot of there's a lot often
times a lot of symptom burden that's
just going to be there throughout the
day so
so it's useful to have a kind of a
workhorse you know something that's
giving you a steady state or more
you know long-acting effect and that's
like we talked about you know
tinctures or capsules um and
and then you can think of other methods
uh vaping
uh and even suppositories it's kind of a
shorter acting
like breakthrough or you know it's a
thing something that you can layer
on top of that longer acting workhorse
so i'd like to think of it that way to
help patients understand that there's
something you're going to kind of need
at the bait at the basal level and then
what else
do you need when when you need something
beyond that and that's
that that that's that's sort of a good
way to think about it yeah that's
that's a really good idea have have the
one be your central
solution and then have have these these
extras that you might add as
as needed um do you normally recommend
that patients
uh keep some sort of dosing journal too
yes that's very helpful especially when
you're trying to figure things out and
seeing what's working not working
and of course with the you know this is
a complex botanical medicine with
uh it's not just one active ingredient
so the more you also know about
you know what what percentage or
consistency or potency material you're
putting in your body
so by making note of that quantity
and time of day um will
you know and and if you have you know
you can put on the other on the columns
okay these are the symptoms i'm treating
and
and this is what it was before and this
is what it was after in terms of um
you know severity on a 1 to 10 scale for
example
so that that kind of data can be really
you can look at do that over like five
days and
get a lot of information and show that
to your
you know to whoever's helping you um
with with dosing
and and and you know because it can
become comp
it can become a lot but this is just
really to help
you know make sense of everything and
there's just so many products is the
problem too
so people kind of get overwhelmed and
and that's where
um you know starting with at least like
one you know that's one and then
and then another layer on top of it and
then keeping keeping notes
will help to um simplify
this and you know this is just just the
idea just to sort of dial us in so that
then
you know you can you know move on with
your life you know and
and do the things that you want to do
and yeah the other thing i didn't
mention in the
in the previous section about the
details on cannabis is
in end of life care you know
there may not be like a set dosing
pattern
just it might be like you know
people just are finding something that
helps them with their mood
and you know they they they just they
use that or they
they use it when they like to because um
you know their mood varies throughout
the day or their their
level of interaction with people changes
or they get they get fatigued after a
certain amount of time
or they use it for energy so sometimes
it can just be
a really like okay let me just have
these on hand
and i kind of know what they all do and
what they're all good for
and so let me just sort of mix and match
you know so that that's also another
like i don't want to like make it so
complicated and like
a program you know it should be a chance
to also have a spontaneous
um kind of empowerment toolkit yeah
excellent i like that an empowerment
toolkit yeah i like that
so um you know it's not uncommon to hear
from
a patient you know three months into
this process
that uh the cannabis just isn't working
like it used to anymore
and um and you know it's one of the
challenges with cannabis medicine that
over time
the human body can develop tolerance um
would you explain a little bit about uh
tolerance to cannabis and
and how you what kind of advice you give
your
um patients about uh manipulating their
doses or taking tolerance breaks
absolutely i mean i i've got my
colleague
dr dustin sulak in maine uh an amazing
osteopathic physician and cannabis
researcher and scholar
he has made such a nice um like websites
and patient literature and videos
about his um re-sensitization protocols
i just always refer my patients so
please go listen to dr schulack's
lectures or videos about this he has a
website healer.com
and so i i just have him do the
explanation but i mean
what he explained to people basically in
a bottom line is that that you know your
cb1 receptors even cb2 but all any
receptor which is the
um protein on the cells that um on the
surface of the cells like up nerve cells
for example that
um cannabis cannabinoids from cannabis
um you know bind to
and signal through to cause the
downstream effect of
modulating excitability whether it's
like um
you know overactive pain circuits
overactive
vomiting circuit or you know um boosting
up the activity of um
of a neurons that are involved in mood
or
or slowing down the activity of neurons
that are involved in
negative thoughts all that kind of
modulation that
is through those receptors you know
through tickling or binding to those
receptors
and you know if you just keep pushing
and pushing and pushing cannabinoids
um for a long period of time those
receptors can get desensitized
and that means that they just they don't
make as many of them
or um you know it's usually that like
they just kind of
come back into them into the cell
membrane rather than being
out there ready to receive signals so
it's a dynamic system so if you kind of
take a break from the
cannabinoid exposure or the holidays
all the different protocols that dr
schulack has advised you can really just
re-sensitize the whole system it can
kind of reboot nicely
so that's that's the that's the solution
there i mean and on the extreme
sometimes you take too much not only is
it not working it can actually make
things worse
there's there's something called the
cannabinoid hyperemesis syndrome
which is more rare but it does happen i
do see it in my practice and
i we we think that there's a you know
the body's like having an over
overactive immune response to all these
cannabinoids and
ends up making an antibody this is one
theory that kind of um might be blocking
the
um the receptors and and end up ending
up giving you more nausea and vomiting
rather than less
so that that's kind of the um everything
is in moderation so
so that's where i if uh if cannabis
isn't working as well it's also possible
that
um you know other therapies might be
helpful you know um cannabis is not a
complete medicine
it's certainly a holistic medicine it
can do a lot of things but there are
also other
other natural medicines out there and
other strategies um
that you know can can synergize with
cannabinoids so
that's the other thing i would say about
that so let's take that and go the other
direction with it
what kind of um interaction with
other drugs have you seen in your
practice
between um you know the pharmaceuticals
that there may be
and and um and then using cannabis
well the most common one that i see in
my type of practice
um is the combination of cannabinoids
and opioids
um and this is opioids from are derived
from opium poppy
like morphine a codeine
and and then derivatives from the bain
which is another ingredient anyway
that's
there's a whole class of opioids maybe
people heard about hydro
hydrocodone hydromorphone uh you know
dilaudid fentanyl the
the long list those medicines can be
helpful
for pain but if they're the only ones
you rely on they have
also significant problems with tolerance
um with um
dependency with the constipation um with
suppression of adrenal access with
long-term use
so if there's any way that you can make
the dosing of those
more effective like you know that you
take cannabinoids and layer that with
opioids
and the pain relief is synergistic or
greater or last longer
that's kind of the one of the drug
interactions that is very positive and
actually has been studied in clinical
trials and we know it's a real
phenomenon and it actually probably
makes opioids safer
because the blood level of the opioids
also comes down which
lowers the chance for having an overdose
so that's that's kind of a big one that
i i see a lot there's
there's many there's long tables of drug
interactions and
cannabinoids one of the ones that was
really pointed out with the introduction
of high dose cbd on the market
epidiolex that's the tincture of um
cannabis that is used in in seizure
disorders
uh fda approved for that um
they go on pretty high doses or they can
go on pretty high doses of
cbd like hundreds and hundreds of
milligrams per day
and at that level um it can impact your
ability to metabolize um other
anti-seizure medicines that your doctor
might have prescribed one of them is
called clobazam it's as well known or
our trade name is anfi
and if you take a lot of cbd um with on
fee the on sea levels become
more toxic in the body and so they have
to be monitored
more closely uh and that's that's been
shown in these studies and
you know that that does come up from
time to time i have patients who
who have seizure disorders who come to
see me for advice and they're they're
taking on feed so we always monitor the
blood levels of on fee while we're
titrating up cannabinoids
um so that you know we know that we're
in a safe range so that
it's it's kind of like on on one hand i
can count the sort of
some of the major issues in general
cannabinoids play well with others
from most medicines so um i think
it's it's just a matter of um
what can what can you mix it with
therapeutically i think there's a lot
more to talk about in terms of
what can you mix it with or what can it
help to reduce the amount of reliance on
i'm not a purist i think
it's nice to use other medicines if you
need them but maybe cannabis will help
to reduce the dose of those medicines
excellent fantastic well oh were you
done
yeah all right fantastic so um during
the set
third set we're going to talk about
trying to
use cannabis medicine in real life so
far we've talked a lot about
you know the theoreticals and the ideal
situation but after the set or after the
break we're gonna talk about
um you know resistance by the family and
resistance by the care facility which
which is its own thing to tackle
so um we will be right back you are
listening to shaping fire and my guest
today is hospice and palliative care
specialist
dr sunil agarwal
this message is for folks who grow
cannabis i'm talking to home growers
patients and commercial growers too i'm
probably talking to you
when you plan out your next growing
cycle be sure to check out
humboldt csi seeds at humboldtcsi.com
caleb and specta and his family have
lived in humboldt county for over 100
years
for the last 40 years three generations
of his family have cultivated
extraordinary sense of mia cannabis in
humboldt mendocino and trinity counties
because of his lineage and the
hard-earned experience that comes from
growing up
smoking and sifting large populations of
cannabis plants in northern california
the seeds you'll cop from csi will be
winning genetics
based on long time heavy hitters and
updated and resifted to bring out new
and exotic traits and better yields
go ahead and ask around caleb also known
as inspecta and pirates of the emerald
triangle is a breeder's breeder
he reaches way back and works with
significant strains
recreating them in new and interesting
ways that you'll love as a toker
and a grower as well as offering you
some surprises that will delight serious
seed traders and cultivators
humboldt csi goes a further step and
selfs
all these chemovars so you know all the
seeds will be female
these are not experimental feminized
seeds
humboldt csi releases some of the best
female seeds available
anywhere and it will show in your garden
folks grew quite a bit of csi humble gen
x last year here on vashon island
and everyone was pleased the patients
had beautiful
female plants and didn't have to cull
half of their garden as males
the folks growing for the fun of getting
high grew colorful flowers with
exceptional bag appeal and great highs
and breeders had seven out of seven
females in a pack
which gave them a lot of phenotypic
choices
take a moment right now and visit
humboldt csi.com
you'll find an up-to-date menu of both
feminized and regular lines
along with photos and descriptions
that's humboldt
csi
[Music]
pre-rolls have come a long way since the
early days of normalization
when you choose saints joints you are
smoking all flower
top shelf pre-rolls with terpenes that
will sculpt your high in a way that
dry old pre-rolls just can't whereas
most brands release pre-rolls as an
afterthought
for the last five years saints joints
has focused on their line of exotic
curated joints and while some companies
just chase the hype strains
saints joints goes deeper searching out
hard to find strains
unexpected crosses and nearly forgotten
land races and classics
and some hype ones too not only does a
joint from saints
smoke incredibly well they have
fine-tuned every step of the process
so you don't get runs in the paper the
joint is just the right density to have
a nice pull
and the joint stays lit even if you get
a bit chatty
saints joints boxes are works of art and
will spark conversation when you pull
them out at a party
saints award-winning boxes change with
every release
feature edgy outsider art and often
raise awareness of important issues like
equal rights saints boxes are so desired
then many collect them and display them
in their homes
ask your bud tender for saints joints
and have a premium
joint experience now if you are a
licensed cannabis cultivator i have an
extra message for you
saints is looking for partners in legal
cannabis states to expand the
availability
of the saints joints brand do you grow
exceptional canvas flower but are less
excited about all the effort
cost and risk of launching your own
brand
saints joints may be just the partner
you are looking for
already established in california
washington and oklahoma
and recognized by entrepreneur magazine
and green entrepreneur
as a cannabis industry leader the saints
joints brand will set you apart in your
home market
the best thing i can recommend is for
you to visit their instagram at
saints joints and look at their patented
drawer design
boxes become that brand everyone is
talking about
without having to build it from scratch
check out the instagram at
saints joints and then visit
saintsjoints.com to find out more
[Music]
in times like these when so many
cannabis companies are growing their
flower in gigantic warehouses and fields
using synthetic nutrients
it is good to know that there are
authentic california heritage growers
using natural farming techniques and
sunshine to cultivate cannabis flowers
for you
california has produced the best
cannabis in the world for generations
and the idea that massively scaled
industrial cannabis production
could produce the same quality as small
batch
lovingly cultivated flowers is just
silly
moontime medicinals is located in
humboldt county on the lush
south fork of the eel river watershed in
the epicenter of the american cannabis
heartland
moon time medicinals grows under bright
california sun in greenhouses
using only natural farming techniques
like hugelkultur
compost teas whole food fertilizers and
fermented plant juices
every part of their growing process
plays its own part in nature
and nothing synthetic is injected into
the process
the result is big beautiful cannabis
flowers
with wide-ranging terpene profiles that
taste
like great cannabis should if you live
in california
ask your bud tender for moon time
medicinals and visit
moon time medicinals on the web and
instagram
moon time medicinals is also available
as part of the redwood roots family
moon times whole flowers appear in
redwood roots curated joint packs
alongside other heritage cannabis
cultivators like
lady sativa farm ridgeline farms humble
redwood healing
and others moon time medicinals top
shelf cannabis grown in harmony with
nature
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire i'm your host shango los
and our guest this week is hospice and
palliative care specialist
dr sunil agarwal so sunil you know we've
talked a lot so far about you know
the why and the how of cannabis medicine
in kind of like an idealized environment
but we both
know that um when it gets down to the
moment of helping a patient
there are challenges and and hoops that
we have to jump through
to to make it work so um number one
on that list is usually resistance by
the family right because we've had
um you know what 70 plus years
of of um federal resistance to cannabis
medicine
and and it's and it's taboo and a lot of
people do not feel
comfortable having their parent or loved
one
using cannabis which they are unfamiliar
with
and may have have some you know societal
beliefs against i i figure you probably
run into that all the time because you
have such an integrative approach you
use a lot of stuff that people don't
even
know what it is and um so so how do you
normally uh approach a family do you do
you normally
um i guess this probably has a lot to do
with the the state of the patient but
i'm just going to kind of set it up for
you do you normally talk to the patient
first or the family first
when you know that cannabis is going to
be a helpful thing if used properly
how do you go about introducing it and
working with a family that that may be
resistant
now it's um the the first thing i
always try to do is to name
the what it is um
what the barrier is in this case and and
you know putting a name on it makes it a
little bit more um
you know like a tangible understandable
um contextualizes it
into the larger um social
fabric of of of a patient
and family's life um you know other
issues
in society uh where we face
discrimination based on you know age
gender race religion all the different
things that unfortunately we still
are are living with and and are trying
to systematically
address so and that that term is stigma
the the the issue of stigma which
is tied to shame and fear
and um ostracization that's that's what
you know stigma comes from this idea of
being marked
a stigmata a mark that that kind of
makes you
uh you know ostracized or socially
outcast
and so there's there's a stigma of
cannabis that
persists and that was you know
engineered um or
pushed pushed by the uh the government
for a long time
not that there wasn't um there's always
been
kind of in puritanical settings some
concern about substances that
change your ordinary state of mind and
so i think people
just need to understand that that's can
be done safely and appropriately and in
any accepted context that's safe
and healing and so i after you
talk about you say this is stigma that
you're facing and if a patient tells me
that they're
you know they'd love to try this but
their their loved one is really
like doesn't see it that way um or you
know they'll they'll put limits i've had
some
loved ones patients tell me oh well you
know my uh
my uh siblings older siblings somebody
who has a long
lifelong disability she has siblings
that's looked after else looked after
her but
one of the siblings is really in favor
of cannabis the other ones are not
and so they kind of like don't go as far
as they could go in terms of what could
help the patient
so things like that i i come across and
i always tell family i tell patients
listen i'm happy to have a
family meeting you know a conversation
with your family members
um to help them address their concerns
or questions that they have about this
it's
you know it's just it's it's stigma and
it's something that we should talk about
it's usually
grounded in some um ignorance uh or you
know lack of knowledge and then there
there is there's fear too
and the that's sort of the other angle
is that sometimes the fear is
sort of warranted you know in terms of
like actual
legal repercussions that can befall a
family or a patient that they're
concerned about and you know that's
where
you know and that's what the other
context around well what is
exactly the what are the legal issues
here what are the
you know what are the you know who's
making the rules and who's enforcing
those rules and
is there any way we can find medical
exemptions or exceptions or
you know utilizing that angle of of um
of medical care where you have to
advocate for a patient's rights or their
patients needs
um you know and if the laws and rules
are
impinging on on medicine then um
then you know what what can who which
social worker do we need to call which
lawyer do we need to call
who do we need to write a letter to um
you know how how can we
um you know
overcome that barrier so that that's
sort of how i
um family conversation identifying
stigma talking with the family
um inviting you know educating and then
um
you know if there are real barriers like
a legal or administrative barriers
trying to
address those with with them with the
team approach and
and medical and letters if needed it is
interesting
how you know even though the family is
coming to you
for expert advice how often they will
then try to um create the ground rules
for with
for within which you work so for example
um
you know it's it's not uncommon for a
family to say yeah we're okay with
cannabis medicine but only cbd and not
thc but they don't really understand
that thc even at low
uh doses that don't cause euphoria are
still
you know thc is generally going to be
part of a healing process when it comes
to cannabis medicine
yeah that's right that's those those
kind of the the cbd only
um like is a thc stigma is
is even more specific you know and and
and that's also requires
um the same approach uh
when you when you need to interact with
a family
and and and they say yeah let's do a
family meeting
um uh it is
it's hard right because you've got all
these different uh communication styles
of all these different people
and you might you know the patient
probably knows you decently
and and maybe the the spouse or maybe
the one
the one uh child who is kind of running
point for the family knows you pretty
well but then you've got all these new
people
in the room or on the zoom call or
whatever and they don't know you and
like you're like oh my gosh
how am i gonna communicate to this room
where
i've got all these varying people how do
you how do you deal with that
yeah well um these are these are
things that they teach us a little bit
about in in um in
hospice and palliative medicine training
fellowship training
and it's it's really just the the the
research shows that the more that
family members speak in meetings have an
opportunity to to actually be heard and
to
to to speak rather than being spoken to
um um improves their um
their satisfaction with the experience
you know so it's it's really more
about creating a venue a space
a platform for family members to listen
to each other
um and and to be heard about their
concerns so you know asking open-ended
questions
and um you know certainly leading the
meeting but giving a lot of space for
people to
kind of state their concerns and
and you know and then if there are
emotional aspects um in
in that in their concerns uh oftentimes
there are
um very strong emotional issues fear
like i was mentioning or
um you know the shame or um
the tied to stigma or whatever it might
be then you know naming those
naming those emotions like i can unders
i can hear your frustration i can hear
that you're worried
um and and that that helps to
improve the the communication name name
the concerns and you know start to
hopefully move towards
uh you know if if this is actually
something a patient needs and then being
the advocate for the patient as a doctor
and you know giving me advice that's
right
my recommendation and then you know
seeing what people say so that's
that's how that's how to approach those
it's
it's there's an art to that
i i would think that uh clinical doctors
that is one of the key
tools in their tool box is communication
skills because certainly uh somebody
who's interacting with family all the
time is going to
need a different version of
communication skills
than a uh you know a research doctor
right who who still needs to know how to
interact with people but it's a lot
different
dealing with the folks in a lab versus
family members who are dealing with a
end of
life patient
because they've got all their own
emotions are all on
like hyper then because they're they're
freaked out
and and and they're trying to review
their life's history with this person
and they're they're they got their own
taboos oh my gosh what a what a soup of
a mess
yeah you got it and and that's that is
our um
in my field um hospice and palliative
care
um communication is really one of the
critical skill sets that we
work on because it's very important to
um you know to deal with to to even
figure out what's going on with the
patient how you can better help their
their distress levels or or the family
or
sometimes i'm involved in helping them
um
you know develop the care goals like
whether they should go this way
take that treatment take this treatment
you know or focus more on
a fully palliative approach like trying
to sort that out
requires a lot of um ability to um
understand the various um competing um
you know interests that are involved in
trying to center the
what the patient's values are so it's it
is a um
it's is you know in general i would say
um when it comes to cannabis
discussions and talking about this
stigma if people
are are ready to sit down and talk about
it um or
we've already made huge progress i
remember
when um you know the state of washington
had no legal access to cannabis you know
until this
law passed i mean they had medical
marijuana but they didn't have uh adult
use and
you know the big campaign uh that the
aclu ran was
marijuana it's time for a conversation
you know and it was this this whole idea
hey we can sit down and talk about this
yeah you know we can sort of change some
of our
um preconceived notions and that that
was kind of a brilliant stroke and i
think the same thing is true in
in the individual context with the
family
it is often frustrating because even
when you have a
family that is totally into it and
they're you know they're modern they're
open-minded
and they're actually thinking about
what's best for the patient
then you've got resistance from the care
facility because
generally they accept federal money and
therefore
are beholden to federal laws i can
imagine
that as a you know integrative caregiver
um that running up against that barrier
causes you
unending amounts of frustration
oh well yeah i mean again as i mentioned
earlier in our podcast
i have seen i've seen a nice amount of
change
in the in the greater you know
healthcare environment um
residential care facility environment um
in the 20 years that
or so that i've been thinking about this
topic and and being in clinical settings
i would say
so i think um so and
and and so to to add to that like i've
had um
examples of where i've had um like
privately owned chains of um
assisted living or end of life
residential care facilities which have a
lot of older
population like um one one i'll just
name this
aegis living aegis he's just living
there they're a huge
they're in multiple states um they
um like i would say five years ago
or uh something like that worked out
a policy for um you know
allowing cannabis in their facility
uh and having having um uh
i've seen other facilities that are
privately owned also that allow their
nurses to handle
cannabis that patients bring in um you
know
their care staff if they're if they're
helped getting help with medicines
and so so i've kind of interacted with
clusters of facilities that
chose to not be beholden to some of the
federal rules even though their patients
might be on
you know medicare or receiving some
federal benefits
it's probably because they're you know
independent
um or largely independent um but you
know there's always still some overlap
there's always some federal regulations
state regulations
involved in all of these facilities you
know and so it's
it's just a matter of like well is it
enough to make a difference or are we
just using that as an excuse
you know um to to just sort of pump the
issue
so i've been i've been very heartened by
the fact that some of these facilities
develop their own internal policies in
general
they'll say no to smoking cannabis
they'll say you know non-smoked products
they'll say that the patient needs to
have a medical cannabis authorization
um and that things need to be labeled
and this and that so
um you know sometimes security around
the product so
um like i mean like a secure secure um
storage so that that's where i i think
i've seen some changes now
and then the other place that i
struggled a lot on this with was the
hospital
you know the hospital is really like the
the center of you know advanced
high-tech medical care
and lots of regulations on hospitals
um and you know many times patients
would sneak things in and just sort of
you know the hospital didn't want the
liability of saying okay well
you had a something happen to you and
it's a medicine that we did not give you
or authorized so
we we just don't want you on it and so
that kind of like
legal impasse prevented a lot of um
you know uh acceptance it's stigmatizing
environment to use cannabis and even
though when patients might be
hospitalized for
things where cannabis could actually
help their symptoms so i would you know
oftentimes prescribe like thc pills you
know the patients from the pharmacy so
as a way to
you know use some aspect of cannabis in
a legal in a legal framework
but but now i've seen um there are some
hospitals that are allowing cannabis in
their in their wards
not everywhere but it's changed um we
had patients at children's hospital
in the last couple years where um they
all
are allowing children to bring in
cannabis that their
parents are bringing in administering um
as long as they've had they've gone
through
some kind of approval process that they
have on the inside which goes through
their
pediatric attending doctor and some
regulatory
setup and you know it it changes the um
the stigma significantly the child now
you know and family members
don't have to hide it and and it's it's
um you know on
i've had some patients where they put it
on the white board you know their family
members are writing
like this is what we're doing and so
that's been kind of a changing
there is an opening there happening i
would say in the hospitals
and then i contacted the department of
health in washington and they had said
oh you know we don't have any
problems to patients using cannabis in
facilities like
it's not it's not anything that the
state of washington is
um limiting you know they they have
granted these rights to patients
and so anyway it's it's kind of a uh
there but
all of that said there are definitely
facilities that are still out there that
are
uh far more um tied into um federal
pools of money um and just say hey we
don't allow that here
and in those cases patients have to be
um
you know um discrete um this is probably
a good point for us to give a
loving shout out to nurses right because
there is no doubt
that nurses their creativity and
hearts and knowledge are there at the
center of these decisions between
the doctor and the family and sometimes
the gray market right
i mean so often i have come across
nurses who are like okay i've got a
patient who uses cannabis
at home they're in hospice but they're
moving into the facility now
and i'm trying to move their medicine
into the facility
what are the methods that are most
discreet and you know i i play that role
i can i can share with them it's it's
for them in the family to decide right
but
um nurses play such an important role in
making sure that the patient gets the
care that the patient wants oh that's
amen amen to nurses they have definitely
played a critical role um there's
one nurse who's been a huge leader in
the national
you know american nurses association's
largest organization of nurses
um her name is mary lynn mathery
and she has um you know been a huge
leader from
for decades on cannabis and medicine
starting
professional education doing her own
research about
her own master's research when she was
in graduate school about cannabis and
you know talking to doctors and how it's
important to have an open lines of
communication
so i just wanted to put shout out to
mary lynn because
and then of course many many nurses have
now come forth and started cannabis
nursing associations and
all across the country and um they've
really taken the mantle on
to advocate for patients and and to kind
of help them toe that line
yeah for family members who are
listening who are thinking about going
in this direction
with their with their family i highly
recommend
finding a nurse that is uh educated and
pro-cannabis
as an ally because you know you're not
going to do anything that's going to be
more effective
towards winning than than allying with a
good nurse
that's right yeah yeah so so sunil
before we wrap up here
you know i've heard you speak a number
of times and one of the things that i
really enjoy
is is when you get to the part of your
presentation where you talk about
humans having a right to use healing
plants
and you know certainly cannabis has been
you know taboo for many decades but
before that
you know it was 70 of the pharmacopoeia
we used it for everything
and and then it fell out of favor and
with the government because it was uh it
was you know
used as a scare tactic and and so now
everything's kind of a mess
and and it's and it's slowly coming back
but at the end
you know this is a plant that's
naturally occurring and
um you know i'd just like to you to
speak to the idea
that um that that that the plant is
naturally occurring
and and it's something that we should
have as an option
as a patient at any point in our life
well you you said it i amen i mean
there there's no i don't think there's
i i i i don't think there's much else to
say
it's just simply the fact that we are
i mean my area of interest is a human
environment relationship and
that's i came i came into medicine
having a background in
in geography a human environment
relationship and how it applies to
health and disease to
access the resources the therapeutic
resources the healing power of natural
landscapes and nature and you know all
this
critical ecology that that that we're
part of that determines
you know uh illness and and access to
health resources so it's
health health and the environment is
integral to
our um you know to who we are as humans
to our evolution
our connection to all other life on the
planet i mean it's a
it is a we we are cannabis and humans
are and all these these plants are
actually like
distant cousins on the evolutionary like
you know
tree of life so it it to me was always
very
um you know the the idea that you have a
natural right to
um you know the bounties or the
to natural plant resources um
is a very old concept in in in
law and you know i'm i don't know i
think it's called natural rights
um and the the idea that the state
that what is the compelling interest of
the state to
limit somebody's right to access um you
know natural resources
and that that's where you know that's a
social contract question
it's like well you know what limits are
are are there for
for example safety or resource
conservation so you know you might say
oh
you know if everybody took all the
firewood from this area
then the wood you know it collected as
much as they wanted then
then there'd be no none left for for
everyone's needs and
and so there has to be a limit or if you
say you know
i don't want people collecting this
particular um
rare um rare bird or
you know making these kind of endangered
species pets because
this this species at risk of extinction
there's this huge
you know global uh social
reason to to withhold um you know
trading an endangered species and
and conserving resources that are very
limited
um and that's that's you know that's
pretty much the limits that we play and
then and then i guess the other one
would be
um like how much verizon can you make
ricin
is a you know naturally occurring like
bioterrorism biotoxin which you can you
can grow from
from plants and so there's limits on
that for the safety
of of people's ability to you know be
free from bioterrorism attacks
so those are really the the idea that
there's these
plant medicines that are going to be so
dangerous for you
that you know uh so you're gonna abuse
them so much
and they're they're so unsafe and we
have to take them away from people
that's sort of the that's the sort of
overreach that infringes on that natural
right and
people have to really you know ask the
question is there
is there a compelling interest of the
government to limit this
um you know natural connection or you
know or to completely in the case of
cannabis or these other natural
medicines like
completely you know remove it from
entirely sever the relationship you know
like uh
legally speaking there's no legal
context there's no legal way that you
can um
have a connection with these these
natural um
medicinal plants um and and that's that
to me is
is is what it comes down to you know uh
do we really think that that's a that's
a valid um
reach of our of our government and is
there a compelling
and that that comes down to well what is
the argument they're making they're
saying it's very
unsafe and dangerous and i think that's
um
you know been proven wrong so uh and and
you know the fact that there's a long
traditional history of use
already um should have proven that
lauren a long time ago
and and i think that's um that's the
mess that you talked about you know that
we kind of took these political
um we took these allowed the government
to take these steps of overreach
um for naked racist political
you know economic interest purposes and
i'm sure some people along the way were
convinced that there was
oh some real danger here and we're doing
this to you know save the children to
protect our
future or to you know like like getting
rid of lead lead
lead paint and lead gasoline you know um
but this is not that
and that's that's really where um if we
don't have a historical context if we
don't have
uh knowledge of our traditions and we
don't have a
appreciation and reverence uh for
the uh right to access and be part
connected to nature
we're gonna we were gonna just kind of
give that up entirely and that's
that's really um you know i think that's
that's where i'm
one of the struggles that i'm very
passionate about and i appreciate you're
asking me and it's not you know cannabis
is one
but i'm also there's a whole family of
um psychoactive biota
um you know um anthogen natural
subsidement mushrooms and um
like ergot fungus that has a lysergic
acid in it
or you know we mentioned peyote which
has masculine in it
ayahuasca which you know is a has
a dmt in it and these are all substances
that
all these natural plants have chemicals
in them that are like our brains
neurotransmitters they're
you can call them neurotransmitter
analogues and so you know nature has
provided these amazing
um substances that that are you know fit
like
locks and keys in our in our body and
that's no surprise because we're all
evolutionarily connected so anyway it's
just kind of a i think we're we're
having a price
a crisis of connection to the world
and and to our own connection to the
natural world and
and a sense that the government is
uh has passed laws that have tried to
break that connection and that's where
we're
we're trying to get back on on footing
and and
and i think for as a doctor i can't i
think without these kind of without
addressing this problem we're never
going to be
we're never really going to achieve a
public health about uh
a a modicum of public health that that
we um we can
that's fantastic and so well put sunil
thank you so much well let me see i got
a couple things to thank you for of
course thank you for
sharing your incredibly valuable time
with us and thank you for sharing your
experience and also
you know just thank you on behalf of all
of the patients that you bring your
integrative approach to for you know
being willing to think outside the box
and uh to be able to open you know open
your heart and experience uh to with the
goal of decreasing
suffering you know it's it's always a
pleasure to interact with you because
um interacting with a doctor who is is
truly dedicated to helping the patient
instead of checking boxes
it always feels really good so so thank
you for sharing everything that you have
sunil
you're most welcome it's been a great
honor and pleasure to work
and to work with you i hope to we do
future episodes
fantastic so if you want to find out
more about dr
sunil agarwal you can go to the website
for his clinic and that's at
ames institute dot net that's a i
m s institute dot net and also
um i recommend that you go back and you
check out all the way back to
episode number three of shaping fire uh
sunil joined me he mentioned earlier
that uh he
was a was and is a geography buff but we
did this fantastic episode
on the geographical history of cannabis
medicine and
um if you're you know it doesn't matter
if you're just getting to know cannabis
medicine or
if you've been following cannabis for a
long time this
episode is just it's just great to give
you an idea
uh globally um how cannabis has evolved
in its relationship with humans and also
i want to remind you
of the six episodes that i mentioned
earlier in the show
um on the on on the various uh ailments
that you can find out very specific
dosing information
and you can find out all uh you can find
all of those shows either
where you downloaded this episode or at
the website
at shapingfire.com you can find more
episodes of the shaping fire podcast and
subscribe to the show at shapingfire.com
and wherever you get your podcasts
if you enjoyed the show we'd really
appreciate it if you would leave a
positive review of the podcast wherever
you download
your review will help others find the
show so they can enjoy it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the newsletter for insights
into the latest
cannabis news exclusive videos and
giveaways
on the shaping fire website you'll also
find transcripts of today's podcast as
well
be sure to follow on instagram for all
original content not found on the
podcast
that's at shaping fire and at shango
lose on instagram
be sure to check out shaping fire
youtube channel for exclusive interviews
farm tours and cannabis lectures
does your company want to reach our
national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts
email hotspot at shippingfire.com to
find out how
thanks for listening to shaping fire
i've been your host shango los