[Music]
humans have been burning cannabis since
our earliest relationship with it cave
evidence shows that early humans would
take whole cannabis plants and put them
on small fires and caves and essentially
Hot Box the cave and then they would
have a mystical experience and done with
the right intentions we still can
we love smoking cannabis because the
lungs provide a speedy and efficient way
to get cannabinoids into our blood and
into our brain that's why smoking comes
on faster than any other method hell yes
there are at least two strong reasons to
consider vaporizers though the first is
that not everyone has lungs of Steel and
the longer we smoke hot plant material
and tar the more impact our lungs take
over the years there are also folks who
have other respiratory diseases like
COPD where cannabis smoking can be used
as a medicine but smoking anything at
all is impossible
for asthmatics like myself and other
folks with respiratory issues vaporizers
create a fun and effective method for us
to be able to use cannabis
the second strong reason to consider
vaporizers is how much improved The
Taste can be to be able to enjoy
cannabis flour without all the burning
plant material getting in the way of the
terpene profile is a great thing many of
us love the intense flavors of Dab Oil
without the plant as contaminant vaping
flowers is similar in that we are
inhaling the resin of the flower without
taking in all the burnt plant
particulate and tar that gets in the way
of true flavor
you've likely heard me talk about
cannabis from an asthmatic perspective
before both here on the podcast and on
the shaping fire YouTube channel as well
on shaping Fire episode 36 on cannabis
and breathing with Robert Litman we
discussed how best to inhale cannabis to
preserve your lungs how to incorporate
cannabis into asthma and COPD care and
we address the long time myth that
holding your hits gets you higher
spoiler is hypoxia not THC that makes
you feel higher
today's episode is a blend of cannabis
medicine ideas and cannabis engineering
ideas if you want to learn about
cannabis Health cultivation and
technique efficiently and with good
cheer I encourage you to subscribe to
our newsletter we'll send you new
podcast episodes as they come out
delivered right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week and
videos too don't rely on social media to
let you know when a new episode is
published sign up for the updates to
make sure you don't miss an episode also
we are giving away very cool prizes to
folks who are signed up to receive the
newsletter there's nothing else you need
to do to win except receive that
newsletter so go to shapingfire.com to
sign up for the newsletter this week and
be entered into this month's and all
future newsletter prize drawings
you are listening to shapingfire and I'm
your host shangolos
my guest today is aerospace engineer
Mark Lewis Mark is a lifelong engineer
of systems machines and organizations he
has been an aerospace engineer for
Hughes space and Communications in Los
Angeles
looking for new challenges Mark joined
the Peace Corps and went into the
jungles of Fiji to teach science and
help with revitalizing schools there
this experience profoundly shaped his
views on the critical impact that
education plays in society which led him
to commit 15 years to improving K-12
education and becoming the Statewide
policy director for stem education in
Oregon
most recently though Mark Lewis is again
an engineer and inventor of Novel
vaporization devices for cannabis
products through his company Pearl Labs
his award-winning designs have been
honored by the 2022 course 77 Design
Awards and selected as the 2022 best
design vaporizer by Enigma
I discovered Mark through his first in
product class vaporizer invention called
the Neo the Neo can be used with any
pipe or bong or rig imagine lighting
your cannabis with a lighter like we
always have turning it upside down but
instead that lighter gives off really
intense radiant heat instead of flame
you just put his Vape later over your
flour or oil and it vaporizes there
isn't anything like it on the market
then I love mine but Mark is not here to
talk about his company at all today you
know I don't do company person or
product profiles on shaping fire we do
topics topics that you're interested in
so Marcus here is my science and
engineering expert to break down the
science and engineering behind modern
vaporizers without talking about his own
during the first set today we will
discuss why cannabis enthusiasts Vape
we'll talk about the advantages and
disadvantages and the differences
between burning cannabis flowers and oil
versus vaporizing them the second set is
devoted to engineering we will look at
the three families of vaporizer
technology that make up nearly all the
vaporizers available and then compare
and contrast them we will look at them
twice once for flower and once for oil
it's a big set with a lot of details you
will pretty much understand everything
you need to know about Vapes as a toker
after that the third set is short and we
focus specifically on the boiling point
myth that conflates evaporation and
boiling they are not the same and it
really impacts your experience with
vaporizers
welcome to shaping fire mark
so happy to be here Shango thanks for
having me on the show excellent all
right let's dive right into it you know
a lot of people
um feel kind of uh motivated and nearly
religious about their vaporizers once
they start using them but um you know a
lot of people don't understand the why
of vaporizers yet because in reality
vaporizers aren't used a ton in the
scene yet people are still mostly you
know lighting their cannabis with fire
and you know humans have been burning
cannabis with fire for thousands of
years to like great effect so let's
start by talking about the advantages uh
cannabis enthusiasts are after when they
start using a vape device instead of
combustion will you tell us a little bit
about those advantages yeah absolutely
well I think first and foremost there's
the health aspect right so anytime you
are actually combusting as the people on
the west coast and now the East Coast
know uh the detrimental effects of the
wildfires on their lungs and their eyes
you know smoke carries a lot of harmful
products in it the ash the soot the tars
and so first and foremost the process of
vaporization removes a lot of those or
almost all of those detrimental
compounds from what you're inhaling so
by and large they are healthier than
than smoking they're also more
efficacious there's been some research
studies uh about vaporizing flower
versus smoking it and how much is
bioavailable how much of the medicinals
and the active ingredients get absorbed
into your bloodstream it's it's much
higher than than smoking so there's the
bioavailability of the compounds which
is also very effective and then I think
the the smell is one of the things that
you know well personally I love the
smell of you know cannabis being
combusted uh but it's a little powerful
for some in it and it lingers because
the smells the smoke actually gets onto
your clothes or onto your into your room
so so the smell of a vapor vaporizers
um tends to be a quite a bit more
discreet
yeah and then if you're talking about
the vape pens the cartridges then those
are very very discreet and very
convenient for people to use it's really
been a benefit to cannabis uh portable
vaporizers that they became popular the
same time as nicotine vaporizers because
people are so used to people busting out
nicotine vaporizers that I can pull out
my travel vaporizer anywhere and unless
they're close enough to smell the exhale
they you know people around me have no
idea so that's been a real you know
Advantage for all of us who you know
attend events or or even just walk along
the street yeah that's a real Boon for
sure yeah um so let's let's talk about
um the the advantage also to people
who've got pre-existing conditions like
me you know I like like you know people
who listen to this show often know that
that I have very severe asthma and
because I have a respiratory condition I
have to be gentle on my lungs and you
know I still smoke joints but like I I
know after I've smoked a joint right
um yeah and like you know
um when when you go when I go to events
like you know Emerald cup or something
where you know you gotta puff tough the
whole weekend
um you know I really feel that
um for several days afterwards and and
for for many people with asthma or COPD
if we want to inhale our cannabis
um vaporizers are a uh fantastic option
um because it's so less harsh on our
lungs yeah absolutely yeah it's missing
all those Ash particles that that Lodge
into your your lungs um yeah and and
certainly the heavier tars and oils are
also removed from it so it's it's much
much easier on on your lungs you know
when people when people talk about like
the the the
unhealthy aspects of smoking almost
everybody just goes to cancer right but
it's it's interesting to hear you
delineate that you know the the the the
bits of smoke and the particles in the
smoke and um the tars and all of those
things on their own have their own kind
of impacts even if they don't eventually
lead to cancer
yeah for sure and and I try to really
avoid
um you know uh criticizing people who
who smoke because I I don't think there
should be any sort of judgment and
there's so much Social stigma around
smoking these days that I don't think
that's the reason why not to smoke I
think it's really you know from a health
and taste and and the bioavailability
for me you know I it's uh it's a much
more complex experience than smoking
yeah and and we'll get to it later but
it's also a different high too so it is
completely yeah um so but we also need
to be fair right because even though
vape's still uh even though Vapes are so
improved for people's lungs
um it's not without its challenges right
um it's still heated air we're still in
we're still inhaling superheated air
yeah by the time
um it well compared to smoke uh which
you know you can can reach temperatures
you're inhaling well right at the Embers
you're you're talking you know over a
thousand degrees uh at the Ember but uh
you know if you're smoking a joint
you're you're looking at five six
hundred degrees uh in your mouth and
with vaporizers you're you're well down
into you know the hundreds uh you know
into the low hundreds you know 180 200
degrees at the most I would think by the
time it enters your mouth I have not
done put a thermocouple in my mouth to
measure that paper but uh yeah it's I
don't experience that that uh lung
irritation from heat all right so then
so then maybe I'm misattributing you
know so like I talk about vaporizers a
lot with just like regular heads right
not usually with Scientists like you and
we so you know it's it's not uncommon
for somebody to say oh my gosh I've been
I've been hit getting my vape so much
that my lungs feel crispy all right so
what do you have any suggestion on what
uh what is the attribute of a vaporizer
that might make my lungs feel crispy
especially if it's a flower Vape like
you know my old school packs or
something
yeah to make your lungs feel crispy
you're well uh we're gonna get into I
think some of the the the
things that are happening out of at a
micro level but
um if you're really toasting your herbs
strongly you probably are
um uh changing the nature of the
terpenes and the cannabinoids into other
thicker oils that can reside then in
your lungs and have that heavy feel to
it and then certainly with cartridge
based
vaporizers the carrier oils make a big
difference and we think we know the
background around the ivali Scara a
couple of years ago with the vitamin E
acetate
um and that's exactly what was happening
right is is the carrier oils were were
impacting your lung experience
I think it's also fair if we're going to
be talking about the downsides of vaping
generally to talk about what a uh you
know plastic battery waste and trash
from packaging nightmare cartridges are
it's such a drag and you know
um for years I I mean I'm not sure if
cartridges have solved this yet but for
years I would have a little Ziploc with
you know partially
finished Vape cartridges that just had
all of this waste in there and I wasn't
even going to be able to get the oil out
anymore and it just seemed so wasteful
like like doob tubes right yeah for sure
yeah
um uh and then uh I guess we also have
to be careful about
um you know the terpenes for either oil
Vapes or for
um you know even I guess that would be
the only kind because people don't
really add Terps to flour I hope but
um you know we don't really there really
aren't a lot of studies on what it is
what it means to to vape
the amount of terpenes that are common
in an oil and
um you know terpenes are by their very
nature caustic and it'll it we won't
know until it's too late if it's
actually unhealthy to do that and um I'm
sure you've come across that a lot as as
you have done your research
yeah well I never recommend that people
add pure terpenes uh to
um anything that they're smoking or or
vaporizing uh because they are solvents
right so if you think about uh you know
limonene
um it's it's a wonderful solvent it
helps clean your hands it can get
stickers off it can do all sorts of
wonderful things
um but when you're when you experience
terpenes and and we've you know group
you grow up smelling flowers right your
entire life and the history of humanity
we've had a very rich interaction with
with terpenes in a very beneficial way
so in very small amounts
terpenes are phenomenal right so keeping
keeping as close to Nature as possible
is is kind of my rule right on so so
let's talk about that right because
um it's interesting because if we're
talking this idea of keeping it as close
to Nature and you know if if we humans
are you know a a thing of Nature and we
are a part of Nature and we are not
excluded from nature the way that we
have been using this natural plant with
cannabis for thousands of years have
been you know by fire you know going
into the you know pulling out the plant
and and going into the cave and putting
it on the fire and filling up the cave
with smoke and and you know then then
learning to you know craft little pipes
when we could control the fire better
and and then of course you know
eventually developing hash so we're so
we're able to store it better and and
not burn and combust as much of the
plant material
um and and you know so many of us love
that profound Good Taste of of
combusting you know quality herb that
has been grown and cured
um properly and and then yet at the same
time as we start to use vaporizers now
I'm enjoying the same plant in an
entirely different way
um that's giving me a different
experience of the terpenes and and we'll
we'll talk more about the the science
aspects of it later on
um but but it's it's it's an entirely
different taste where there's there's
almost a needed transition period when
somebody goes from flower to vaporizing
because it is so different would you
describe the difference
um in in taste experience I guess
between combusting and vaporizing the
same flour
wow
that's not hard
um well I I would concur I uh first and
foremost with the experience of and
rituals of uh consuming a nice joint or
or your pipe or your bong I think we
have
learned to
manage our experiences with those
devices and with combusting by
um
you know that we we get a certain
feedback that helps us can you know
manage our experience and when you're
shifting over to for example flower
vaporization
um the feedback that you're getting is
is much much different your lungs are
not experiencing that intense hypoxia
you know the the uh you know
constriction and the lack of oxygen
instead you're taking a deep breath
um of a vapor that is rich in uh the
cannabinoids as well as the terpenoids
and it's it's it feels gentler but that
can be deceptive as well because uh as I
mentioned earlier it can get you higher
so you have to you have to learn to
manage your feedback differently
with vaporizers than you do with with
our traditional modes of consumption I I
like that uh use of the word feedback
because I would say the number one
complaint that I've heard from people
who are just starting
um uh using non-cartridge vaporizers is
that like did I did I get a hit you know
because the the hits with a low temp
um you know handheld vaporizer I mean
heck even some of the desktop ones uh
it's it it feels
the inhale feels so much thinner
um and it's weird because so many people
who are developing vaporizers and then
because we people keep asking for them
we want vaporizers that will give us
clouds right right right and like in
like clouds are an aesthetic experience
uh of of both feeling a good hit like
like feedback you were talking about and
also the satisfaction of exhaling and
seeing this Cloud right which which
traditionally is is part of the
satisfaction from taking a bong rip
right totally
um so would you talk a little bit about
why
um you know why that hit is is thinner
and I guess you kind of already
addressed that because there's there's
not as much particular in there I guess
I would like you to talk to more like um
uh
are we missing anything from that
thinner Feeling Hit
I don't think so from my perspective I
think
um you again when when you have smoke
and it has the Ash and particulates and
stuff in there your lungs constrict and
so you get that intensity
um a feeling of of an of being a little
more intense because you're you're your
lungs are responding to uh these things
that you know are contaminants
um from its perspective uh whereas when
you're vaporizing flour uh then your
lungs are are not feeling that uh
intensity of invasion you're you're
getting things that it recognizes and
they're binding to the abioli and then
being moved into your uh into your
bloodstream and so
um so that's one aspect of it to the
clouds I think that is a learned
feedback that we are judging in our
experience based on these clouds but at
the same time your your lungs can only
absorb so many compounds at a time so
anything that you're exhaling with a
vaporizer you're exhaling those active
ingredients if you're seeing a cloud
that's kind of wasted byproducts because
you your lungs haven't taken them up and
and delivered them to your bloodstream
so that's that's another way of thinking
about it and at the same time there's
always been a a bit of theater in in
cannabis right and so we enjoy that as
part of the social aspects yeah that's
that's really true
um all right so uh if
all right I've got two sides of this
coin and so I'm gonna give you the coin
and then you can approach it however you
want all right on on one side of the
coin
um you know we're taking these uh these
these thinner hits I'll say
um and and you know you say sometimes
they they'll actually get us higher
right but then on the other side of that
coin are many people when they first
start vaping they feel like one hit is
not as satisfying for them and they
don't get as high and so they're all
like well you know I need to take like
you know two hits uh or three hits of my
my flower vaporizer to get the same
feedback as I would from my bong
um but then also some days you just go
and you have you know one hit of the
vaporizer and you've got this like
really like Speedy bright sativa kind of
high even potentially from you know a
non-equatorial plan right that something
that's that's more mercy and Rich so so
what I'd like you to kind of just speak
to is this idea of of the hits being
thinner and so we have to take more of
them and yet the misnomer in that that
like we actually can get get wicked high
wicked fast from vaporizers too like
like how like as somebody who studies
the technology and the and and the user
experience how do you kind of resolve
those because they're all true right
yeah they're all they're all true uh
yeah so for the same let's let's put
some boundaries on on before we go with
this
um so for the same amount of herb
um I will claim and I think research
backs me up on this that you will get
higher if you completely vaporize the
same amount of herb
um as smoking but it's over as you
mentioned over
far more hits I guess maybe you know
double or triple the hits so that's one
aspect of it
um
yeah and yet paradoxically it's it's
more effective so uh the where I'm
actually going is when you first load a
fresh Bowl
um with a vaporizer uh you we haven't
talked about decarbing it yet and
decarboxylation doesn't take place
immediately like it does with fire and
so your early pulls are going to
evaporate some of the thca without
necessarily converting it to THC and so
yes your first couple of poles are
probably going to feel a little thinner
and maybe not affect you but that third
fourth fifth sixth are going to be fully
decarbed and and a lot more intense
oh that's so obvious but I have never
thought of that before huh that's really
interesting so
so I hear that two different ways number
one I like it because if my first hits
are going to be offering me more thca
cbga cbda then my ladder hits that means
I'm going to get all these acid forms of
the plant which are healthy and good for
me yep but the longer it stays in the
vaporization chamber the heating chamber
the the cannabinoids will be changing to
the non-acid versions and so I'm getting
a perhaps a wider array of that and and
for for and for the listeners who are
not um familiar with
decarboxylation
essentially what you need to do to make
THC and intoxicant is that you have to
heat it to a certain point that changes
changes it from an acid to a non-acid
and you know when we normally smoke
bowls or
um smoke joints there's so much fire in
in that joint that it happens instantly
but as Mark was talking about earlier
we're not we're not burning at a
thousand degrees we're talking about
more like a couple hundred and so that
process doesn't happen instantly
um so then the second thing I'm thinking
not only am I happy about getting all
these acid forms of the cannabinoids on
the flip side if I'm dollar conscious
that's going to really annoy the hell
out of me because I could see that as
wasting cannabinoids because if I'm if
I'm money conscious and I'm trying to
get you know the most bang for my buck I
want to get high I actually will be
disappointed that I'm smoking THC a
um like the first hitter too so it
really it really is different um
consumer to Consumer yeah I think
um I I have never experienced
disappointment uh with flower
vaporization I'll just say Shango
um and uh your through vaporization and
again when we get into the mechanics of
of different kinds of modes of
vaporization
um you know we can see how they'll
behave differently but uh
often you unlike with fire when you're
combusting you've got a lot of side
stream you've got a lot of wastage and
with many vaporizers
um certainly the the more reputable ones
uh you're not heat actually heating the
Cannabis when you're not inhaling and so
the your bowl goes a lot lot longer and
from an efficiency standpoint you're the
over the overall amount of product that
you are going to be purchasing in a
month to manage your health and
well-being is likely to drop
significantly
I see so it's a it's a much more complex
algorithm that I was giving credit to
and also as far as like the wastage goes
um it's it's
uh it's always noticed how much smaller
the heating compartments are on uh
vaporizers as they are like from your
hand blown glass slides that can take
you know a thumb size gram nug in it
right and then you go over to your vape
and it's asking you to take like you
know one seventh of that or yeah one
tenth of that and then and then grind it
and then put it in there it it it
usually looks like a
opposity is I think that's the right use
of that word it looks like such a small
amount of weed um but then and then but
then you know still gets you high and so
it's it's confusing it's less weed it
gets you high but you need to take more
hits and you're getting a lot more thca
but over time you're you're wasting less
so it's actually budgetary smart yes
oh man all right so
um all right so let's let's wrap this up
so I wanted to start this first set with
um you know conversations about you know
the why of It kind of generally but um
no doubt I know I have invited an
engineer here so
um we're gonna go and take a commercial
break and then when we come back we're
gonna get into a more serious discussion
about uh the engineering behind
um the popular varieties of Vapes and go
through some uh oil vaping Solutions and
flower vaping Solutions and really get
into the mechanics of it so you are
listening to shaping fire and my guest
today is aerospace engineer Mark Lewis
and you know without these advertisers
shaping fire wouldn't happen so please
support them and let them know you heard
of them on shaping fire
[Music]
you've heard me talk about the
award-winning cannabis seeds that come
from the analytical breeding program of
Seth and Eric Crawford who founded
Oregon CBD seeds in fact Seth was a
guest on shaping fire in 2020 to talk
about triploid genetics Seth and Eric
are now releasing high THC seeds for
home Growers and Farms as grow the
revolution seeds at GTR seeds.com
their high THC seeds are extraordinary
in that they will start to flower at 16
and a half hours of daylight instead of
the typical 14 and a half hours of
daylight that means in most regions your
plants will start to flower outdoors in
the middle of July instead of the middle
of August which means these photo period
plants finish in September and not
October totally upending the photo
period Seed Market
Seth and Eric took their prized early
flowering CBG line and bred it to some
of the most desired verified genetics
out there including Sour Diesel triangle
Kush wedding cake chem dogs Skittles and
others these crosses all Express
powerful photo period terpene profiles
and THC giving you a great High GTR
seeds has a new thcv line with plants
like double Durbin and Gigantor that
boast one-to-one THC to thcv and people
want that thcv
GTR seeds are very consistent true
growing inbred f1s from stabilized
inbred parent lines these seeds are
nearly homogeneous and the plants should
all grow the same there is only one
phenotype in every pack available as
diploids and triploids Seth and Eric's
company is still family owned patient
and employee Centric and partially
powered by their two acres of solar
panels everyone can purchase these seeds
and the entire catalog of Oregon's CBD
seeds at GTR seeds.com go to GTR
seeds.com today and choose something
revolutionary for your next indoor or
outdoor run
oh
as cannabis regulations become more
demanding and consumers become more
educated it is increasingly important to
avoid the use of chemical pesticides
when cultivating cannabis beneficial
insects have been used for decades by
the greenhouse vegetable and ornamental
plant industry and today many cannabis
cultivators are moving from sprays and
chemicals to beneficial insects
copert has the beneficial insects mites
and nematodes microbials sticky cards
and air distribution units you need to
partner with nature to defend your
garden
whether you manage Acres of canopy or
have a simple grow tent in your home
culprit is ready to help answer your
questions and help you transition away
from chemical sprays towards clean and
natural solutions
since 1967 culprit has assisted growers
in identifying pests and devising
reliable Solutions while providing
healthy insects and mites that will
protect your yield
since the 1990s covert has been a leader
in cannabis Pest and Disease Control
worldwide and have highly trained
Consultants to assist you in Canada and
the United States from coast to coast
with their Global Network of grower
support covert can help visit copper.com
choose your country and get detailed
information that's culpert
k-o-p-p-e-r-t.com
for the most up-to-date cannabis related
biological control information you can
also check their Instagram at covert
Canada
you know getting away from pesticides is
good for health and good for business
and culprit is ready to help visit
covert.com today
[Music]
cannabis folks are innovators and
problem solvers and we like to make
money have you developed a tool
technique or plant that you want to
protect and monetize you'll likely want
legal representation that is experienced
accessible and shares your values plant
and Planet law represents a wide variety
of clients who choose to respect the
environment while pursuing their
business goals have you invented a
machine or Gizmo that you're bringing to
Market did you discover a breakthrough
environmentally friendly pesticide or
fertilizer formulation that you're about
to start selling have you bred a canvas
plant with attributes not found anywhere
else
attorney Dale Hunt and his plant and
Planet team have established genetic
patents in over 30 countries
working to help entrepreneurs scientists
throughout the life sciences plant and
plant it represents environmentally
positive clients in cannabis and other
Botanicals fungi water purification
clean energy emulsions and medical
applications
plant and Planet helps people protect
what they've created if you are an early
stage company with an established idea
and are in the process of fundraising
often the investors require intellectual
property Productions happen at the same
time
plant and planet can be your sole
representation or they can integrate
with your existing legal team and plug
in their Specialties plant and planet is
made of scientists lawyers with a real
passion for cannabis inventions and the
environment they have the scientific and
legal depth to help you establish patent
protections for your great idea
you don't have to go It Alone friendly
qualified and honorable legal
representation is available to you
contact plant and Planet law today to
start the conversation email info at
plant and planet.com that's plant and
Planet law our clients make the planet
better
welcome back you are listening to
shapingfire I am your host shangolos and
my guest today is aerospace engineer
Mark Lewis so during the first set we
talked about why we Vape what the in
cannabis enthusiasts experience is and
you know some of the some of the
challenges and work throughs for those
but we're going to get into more the
nitty-gritty of the engineering behind
um both flour and oil vaporizers now
both so that you can you know just be a
little deeper on this this very
important aspect of the you know
cannabis culture but also this should
help provide a bit of a you know a
Shopping Guide for you as you
um you know as you learn about the the
different types of vaporizers and and
you can figure out what what you might
be interested in uh should you decide to
pick one up so Mark you know you know
there's a lot of different approaches
designing vaporizers and there are so
many coming out on the market all the
time now
um and and we're going to talk about
flower Vapes and first and then vaping
oil second because because they really
are like different things so so let's
talk about flower Vapes so like do
flower Vapes fall neatly into a few
different categories so that we can kind
of bunch them up and talk about them or
is there so much for a variability
modeled a model that we have to like
take them one by one God help us
well not all vaporizers are created
equal for sure Shango um and when it
comes to flower vaporizers there are two
primary categories uh and those are
convection based vaporizers and
conduction based vaporizers now anyone
who stood around a campfire has also
experienced radiant heat before and
that's you know heat transfer at a
distance if you will and
um some vaporizers uh might include that
and that is certainly a an effect that
uh impacts sort of the the internal
working of of a vaporizer
to summarize you know just briefly the
differentiation between the two modes
um honestly I'm going to encourage you
to not be necessarily that brief right
like we don't necessarily need to do a
dissertation but this conduction versus
Convent convection thing that I think
that you're about to wade into like this
is key right so right so so so take your
time so that we can all pick up on this
because just the fact that conduction
and convection are so similar
immediately confuses people right out of
the gates and so so like so like take
your time because I think this is this
is a chunky bit
sure sure okay well you know in short
conduction is a heat transfer through
touch right so if you are a conduction
based vaporizer has an oven it has a
chamber uh either made of metal or
ceramic and you place your Herb in in
that and the vaporizer heats up that
oven
um and so your herb is being heated
through the from the walls of that
little oven of that chamber and that's
conduction so it's being heated largely
by touch
a convection-based vaporizer is sort of
like a convection oven or an air fryer
you're heating up the air and then that
is being
transported or pulled or pushed through
your herb
um and that hot air then extracts uh or
evaporates the various compounds
so conduction is actually your flower
touching the heating piece and
convection is
somewhere up the up the chamber the the
the air is being heated and then you're
sucking that hot heat towards the flower
and the heat is touching the flower
instead of the metal or the ceramic
right the air is flowing through the hot
air is flowing through and evaporating
the compounds the volatile compounds
okay and then the Third Kind was radiant
where
um there is there is uh some kind of
device that's that's uh itself just hot
and you're I'm putting it in in general
proximity but it's not it's it's neither
touching the flower nor far away right
okay
um so can you give us a little bit of
explanation on the conduction convection
timeline because you know I know that
generally speaking people consider one
better than the other but but I would
like you to just kind of
um explain the the beginning of
vaporizers design what was first and
then and then how they've kind of
evolved and and while not everybody
likes the same kind of vaporizers kind
of where the people are responding in
the market
yeah I think the earliest vaporizers
that I'm aware of are are certainly
um you know they played around in the
70s with with heat guns
um and uh you know just delivering the
hot air uh that evolved to some of the
whip-based
um vaporizers like the vapor Brothers
the early boxes with uh I still have my
vapor Robert's box man yeah and uh you
know Bert there he's he's a wizard he's
one of the grandfathers of of uh
vaporizers he's a really good guy
understands all of this
um those were were largely convection
based
um vaporizers so they were heating the
air and it was flowing through your herb
um now when it started to move to more
portable uh kind of devices it's a lot
easier to manufacture in small you know
compact designs uh to engineer a
conduction based vaporizer so to heat up
the oven throw your Herb in that oven
something on the market a cup some of
them ones like the packs
um is is largely a conduction based
vaporizer
and so how we want how we'll picture
that is that all of these various
vaporizers where it's got some kind of
little lid and uh you put your flower in
there and it's it's actually you know
touching it against
um steel or ceramic and then you're
putting the top back on
um they all kind of fall in the same
category no matter what they look like
uh there's a sizable portion
um but there's others on the markets
that are hybrids and and do a lot of the
heating of the air you know the crafty
and mighty by stores and Beckle
um they will you know keep the air but
there's also a conduction component to
their design so some of the heat you
know is transmitted up to the walls of
the chamber as well so they're both
introducing hot air as well as
conduction from the sides
um and trying to then get an even uh
vaporization of all the products that's
a good point for me to not be over
generalizing and and make it look like
they're these are really such
um
separated Solutions because because
you're right you know like everybody is
in is inventing and trying to find the
the technology blend that works best for
their product and and and so anybody
who's gonna buy one make sure you
understand the one that you want to get
directly and not you know just something
very general that you you know that you
read generally about conduction or
whatever right right
I'm all right I interrupted you please
continue
uh well I was going to say just to to
highlight some of the differences when
you actually have a hot
um hot material touching your herb you
have a danger of burning it right
because they have to compensate by
delivering a lot more thermal energy
through the walls in order to have it
then cook if you will the herb that's in
the middle of the chamber so you have a
much higher likelihood of over roasting
um your herb and getting that kind of
burnt popcorn taste that some people
complain about I do not care for the
toasty no no I'm a light roast kind of
guy
uh so so you so if if you're going to
get um you know more of an opportunity
of the toastiness with conduction
um uh you would not get that with
convection because the heated air is
coming in contact with your the entirety
of your flower mass at the same time
right uh correct um well it's it's
impacting the the wherever the inlet
side is it's getting a blast of the
heated air you know first that that
particular part of the herb is going to
get the heat blast first but then it's
going to be pulled through uh your herb
now in a convection based vaporizer you
can also pump up the power so much that
uh you do you know over roast it as well
so if you're up at combustion level
temperatures for that air it will
certainly combust on you
but most vaporizers try to avoid that
well you would really need to have your
temp like really cranked up at that you
would have to have it cranked up yeah
yeah all right so let's go back to your
timeline that you're giving us
um you know you gave you talked to us
about the Box Vapes and then the you
know the first I'll say real
breakthrough
um you know to the consumer Market Vape
of the packs
um and then and then things continue on
to Convention so please please pick it
up
uh yeah well I think a lot of the things
that you're seeing on the market now are
variations of a very similar approach
um a lot of vaporizers are trying to
um portray flexibility uh through
incorporation of different uh apps
um you know so that you can control the
the temperature settings
and we can talk about you know whether
or not they can actually do that or not
um most vaporizers uh are able to you
can set a particular setting and Vary
those with an app or directly through
the button control let's go ahead and
have that conversation now because I was
going to ask you that in two questions
anyway you know these these temp
controls and I know we're kind of like
talking about the entirety of the market
so that's not really fair but generally
speaking are these temp controls to be
believed because
um you know unless I'm paying a good
penny you know for a vape and you know
getting like a you know stores in Bickel
or something I'm pretty I'm pretty
suspicious of these these temperatures
that I'm being told that they're heating
at for anything that I'm paying under
200 bucks for
yeah I I think you're right to be
suspicious
um on that for a couple of reasons
um some don't actually use a
thermocouple you know a a a a sensor
that feeds back the actual temperature
and then moreover I think that the
biggest thing is well think about a
regular oven you heat it to 350 degrees
but as soon as you open the door to put
your cookies in
um then it drops a considerable amount
and the same with a vaporizer so as soon
it might heat it to a steady state but
as soon as you start pulling cool air in
that's going to vary the the actual
temperature of the airflow and the vapor
that you're experiencing now the good
side of the temperature settings that on
a particular vaporizer is that you will
probably get relative consistency from
one session to another regardless
of whether it's actually true so so that
can still be a very very beneficial kind
of attribute to a vaporizer so that you
can be able to dial in the experience
that you want from one session to
another
right on I buy that I think that makes a
lot of sense so so even though on some
of the Lesser
um expensive Vapes
the uh the temps maybe not be accurate
to you know the number that they say it
is
um but at least it's going to be same
from session to session so once you find
out you know where you like it
um it'll be able to hit that Mark
consistently yeah yeah that makes a lot
of sense I like that
um so let's talk about the the grinding
part right
um so you know historically a lot of
people don't um grind flour for a bowl
um uh many people will grind flour to
roll a joint though my mentor hated
Grinders and believed it always had to
be done by scissors
um but I think that was because
um he was always collecting seeds so I'm
not sure about that
um but but when it comes to you know
grinding you know every book that you
get with your vaporizer says to grind
the flower hour so you get a more even
experience will you speak to that
um yeah uh I really don't like Grinders
but it's true uh on on well there's pros
and cons let's just say yeah break it
down tell us let's break it down uh when
you actually grind your herb you are
changing the particle side and making
some uniform consistency in the uh when
you pack your material into your
vaporizer and so that can be very
beneficial to get Even Flow similar to
grinding coffee right you can't make
coffee with whole beans you know you
have to have to grind it and for
different coffee makers you grind it to
different sizes so it's a similar analog
for for flower vaporizers too
grinding will certainly give you that
consistency
of the of the pack if you will or the
puck as I call it because it comes out
as a puck once you've used it
but I don't really like the what happens
to my trichomes I don't want to go
chasing after Keef and then reintroduce
it to the bowl so I prefer actually to
chop my my herb directly in into the
chamber or to the Bowl when you say chop
do you mean like uh like finger
separation or scissors I actually just
use fingers to pluck small you know a
small size and then I I have a have a
tiny little sharp knife that that I poke
it with and and tease it around and and
get it to a fairly uniform consistency
so that's that's my method but everybody
has their own kind of method but I like
to keep my trichomes with the rest of my
herb yeah and and I guess some of that
also depends on what kind of a grinder
you're using right totally if you're not
using the kief attachment
um it stays with it the part about the
Grinders that I haven't really cared for
is is the smearing of all the trichomes
and absolutely and then like cleaning
cleaning them off of the grinder you
know if you know back back when I was
you know younger that seemed like a lot
of waste I mean it still seems like a
lot of waste but I have I have plenty of
weed now you know I'm like when I was
younger totally and um but uh for me the
the main advantage of the grind is to
get that
um nice even pull and to know that I am
not wasting the the trichomes that are
um on the interior of the little budlets
let's say that are in there
um am I correct in my assumption that
the the hot air
and the conductive walls of the oven
neither of those will vaporize
a trichome that is caught on the
interior of a dense Bud little piece
uh yes in general
um the it really depends on the size
right of of what you're dealing with
there
um
I would say that uh yes it's it's more
efficient to to actually grind your herb
and to be able to access those internal
trichomes I'll just leave it at that
yeah this is clearly personal preference
right right so so you you gave good
reasons why you're you know on your side
and and I did as well and you and I all
both have plenty of weed but somebody
else whose decision Matrix might be
slightly different well I want them to
be able to get the information they need
to totally totally I know lots of people
have opinions who who I need more than
just their opinion because I I want to I
want to kind of understand the whole
area so I can make my opinion right
right what I tend to do I mean again
this is my personal preferences you know
when you have those small nuggets you
are correct that the the internal
trichomesy don't immediately
um aren't accessible to to the hot air
um uh what I tend to do is is open the
chamber back up and crush it and then
release all of those things once once
you've hit it a couple times and it's
dry then it's dried and it will then
fall apart readily and you yeah and then
you've got your even distribution then
of particles and it's uh more efficient
right on the next thing I was going to
ask you was the recommendation that most
of these these companies have to stir
and uh and so you know usually somewhere
around I don't know hit four or five
they say oh pop pop it open and give it
a little stir and oh my God it just
kills me how often I see somebody using
a pen with ink on the end to do that and
I'm all like you're not even thinking
about what you're putting on your herb
dude but it's way too common but anyway
then they then they close it up and
continue on and um you know do you think
that stirring is is effective yeah yeah
definitely almost all vaporizers have
um
you know with the airflow going through
you're not going to get even heating of
of your herbs so stirring it just means
you're you're moving the sort of the
unspent particles around moving the oils
around so that they can be efficiently
vaporized so I I strongly encourage
stirring if you want to get the most out
of your herb if you're feeling kind of
lazy and and you have got a you know an
abundance of herb available then you
know whatever you want right on if
you're feeling if you're feeling lazy or
wealthy
um right so so at what point would you
recommend the stirring
um I usually stir when I when I taste
the toast for the first time but I also
suspect that I'm I'm one hit late at
that point
yeah uh it really is a personal
preference so you can stir every pole
which is a pain in the butt but
um yeah every three or four poles you
know
I've never tried Ever every pull I had
like that that sounds like so much work
but I should I should do it for the
experience for sure so that I can weigh
all this properly yeah I would never do
it every pull
[Laughter]
um you you know we talked on the first
set about how um you know Cloud hits are
different with Vapes and yet sometimes
you do pull clouds and sometimes you do
pull bigger flavorful hits even if there
is no cloud
and um in my experience whatever
cloudness I'm going to get from a
vaporizer is improved with stirring
what are your thoughts yeah I can see
that
yeah and again I think that once you're
into pull two or three you've
um
you know you you have decarbed you have
warmed the bowl you have removed any uh
of the residual
um sort of moisture in the herb and and
so they just it just becomes the whole
system becomes a lot more efficient you
know three or four poles in and so you
are going to get uh more you know bigger
clouds more easily at that point all
right so um so let's let's move on
unless you've got anything else to say
here let's move on to oil Vapes yeah
well let me talk just briefly about a
couple of couple of other things
um here one is that we haven't talked
about sort of the exhaust what happens
to the vapor after it's moved through
your herb and
um frequently another thing to look at
in a vaporizer is how much accumulates
you know in that Vapor pathway some some
vaporizers on the market said I'm not
going to call them out but you know
claim for an all glass pathway well
glass it actually is is a fairly
conductive material it tends to be cool
so we we have this perception that we
want to cool The Vapor well once we cool
The Vapor you've got those oils that are
then condensing in that pathway and the
way you can tell you know sort of how
efficient the vaporizer is is how much
Gunk you have to clean out and how often
so another sort of buying decision is to
look at you know just how much uh you
know what happens to the vapor after it
goes through the herb are you having to
frequently clean it well then that's not
really you're not getting the maximum
benefit from your vapor
so I wanted to say that and then one of
the other sort of controversies or
questions that are out there is is how
how much do you pack in your chamber you
know how do you press it down do you
crush it how dense do you do you pack it
in
um and my take on this from a sort of
Aeronautics science kind of direction is
that for convection base so the ones
that are using the hot air for a
convection based vaporizer Tamp it down
so press it down and compress it it's
similar to what you do with an espresso
shot you're removing any
um sort of easy channels for the air to
flow past your herb rather than through
it and air will always find the path of
least resistance so if you have those
channels and the larger buds in there
then it's going to flow past rather than
through your herbs so definitely
compress it down and it creates what's
known as back pressure which is similar
to a carb cap on a dab rig it lowers the
pressure
right there at the herb and it will
vaporize more efficiently wow I'm really
glad that you went back for that
um not only is that interesting but I do
it wrong you know I noticed that earlier
when you said um you know when you take
the puck out of your Vape right right
and I'm all like I'm like man I don't I
don't I don't have pucks it's just like
it just comes out as like slightly brown
ground up weed still you know and and in
my head I I wanted to leave a little
breathing room so that the hot air could
easily be be drawn through it but now I
understand from your analysis that that
I'm doing it exactly wrong because by my
leaving it somewhat loose in there even
though that does make it easier for the
stirring uh step that um
that I am Crea I'm allowing easy Vapor
paths that that will be preferred by the
physics of the inhalation when really I
want to press it down so that there's
all these multitude of variety of pads
that are being taken
for a convection based vaporizer so for
for a conduction based vaporizer or like
a dynavap which is the really Innovative
design right
um yeah they're look like I mean they
they replicate the the notion of smoking
so it's like a it's a smoke like
experience right but there are largely a
conduction based of you know vaporizer
in in that regard the metal heats up
right for for a for something like that
or the packs
um which many people have I would say a
looser pack is probably better because
you're heating from the walls so how
does the heat then transfer if it's
really dense the heat is not going to be
transported through your herb because
your herb itself is has low conductivity
wood and plants they don't conduct heat
very well
um whereas then the air that's moving
through there you want it to circulate
right and and the heat to then move into
the center of of that chamber so for a
conduction based vaporizer I would pack
it a little more loosely
you know it's interesting to to hit on
the dynavap one more time
um uh I I have owned one and the one I
have I've only ever used it with uh my
butane torch right and that's an
interesting experience to hear the
little crack sound and then and then
know that it's time to take your hit all
that's very interesting I'm not a super
big fan of using the Torches in general
though right
um but then my buddy Michael you know he
came over and he is like a total dynavap
like Fanboy like he well actually he
kind of is just like a vaporizing
scientist actually he you know until
until I met you he pretty much knew more
than anybody I knew about him and um and
so he got this uh he got this desktop
thing that dynavap has got where it's
like you plug it in and you can just
kind of put the pipe into it and and it
acts kind of like um
it transfers electric energy to it and
it's very convenient like an e-nail is
and then and then you just take it out
and you hit it and it's it's so much
more elegant and it's it's interesting
that it is a product that has multiple
um heating mechanisms because really
that's pretty uncommon to have multiple
heating mechanisms for one Vape system
yeah I I really am impressed with the
sort of the engineering background of of
the dynavap and what they're doing I I
believe that's an induction based
heating sort of block that you you drop
it in and so it uses induction to then
heat it up to the perfect temperature so
uh I think that's pretty fantastic
excellent all right are you ready to
move on to oil now sure all right so so
as kind of like a bridge Place let's
just give a little bit of a shout out to
those flower vaporizers who really
really want to be oil vaporizers too and
so so um you know they will they will
have like little Solutions like um you
know oh I've got a little cup and you
can you know you can take your oil and
put it in the cup and then drop it into
the flour chamber or
um or or you know we've we've got this
you know specialty screen or a sponge
you can put your oil in that and then
we'll put it into the flour vaporizer
and and you know those can
um that people can definitely find
Effectiveness with those but I think
that across the board it's really hard
to make one vaporizer that's best for
all solutions and and like if you only
if you're only going to buy one and you
need one that does both that's like
there are definitely some good Solutions
out there but um you know going all the
way back to the the original Pax like
little cup that was in there you know I
I got mine assuming that it was going to
be an oil vape and a flower Vape but
that little that that little cup just
it didn't really work out over time no
it didn't really work right yeah totally
so so what are your thoughts on on these
Vapes that try to straddle well I think
that when it comes to vaporization
um of an oil it's all about trying to
maximize your surface area and so when
we're dealing with flour it's great
because the flower fibers uh Wick the
oils and distribute them across the
across the fibers and it's pretty easy
so one way of experiencing oils or
concentrates would be to just drop it on
or mix it in with your with your flour
and and that can be a pretty effective
way of using the flour vaporizers to
experience oil but then you've got a mix
and you're not getting that Purity
um that a lot of people who dab are
seeking from from their extracts
and so the um just I'm gonna do a little
bit on the because I spent a couple of
years trying to find a solution to this
yeah with oils and most of the
vaporizers the flower vaporizes in the
market use a stainless steel kind of
Brillo pad if you will
um they it's just a bunch of stainless
steel wire that's been compressed into a
little you know shaped puck or disc that
then gets dropped into the the chamber
the challenge with that is that metal
will warm up and not reach the
vaporization temperatures very readily
so while it's warming up your thick oil
or concentrate your wax or shatter is
going to start melting and it's going to
travel along that along those wires and
oftentimes before you reach the
vaporization station temperatures it's
going to start flowing into the rest of
your unit and you're getting get that
Gunk everywhere
so no most most that try to do both are
are not very effective how many of us
have had that experience early in our
token career where we try to put you
know a ball of bubble hash or something
into our bong with uh with a screen and
and we're warming it up and as we're
warming it up we're seeing it like slide
down the slide on the glass and you're
like you're like I only got one hit off
of that and now it's all like now yeah
it's all inside of the bong oh yeah
that's disappointing but a similar I
mean that's exactly what's happening
inside the vaporizer and then you end up
having to clean it out and and that's no
fun nobody likes doing dishes yeah very
good point
um all right so let's talk more about
like oil vaping solutions that are
specifically leave for it let this
really isn't going to be a long show on
carts right but but let's do talk about
just
um the idea behind the carts and how
they function
um uh but carts could be like their own
show you know so right so if you would
just explain the mechanics of carts um
that'll be great yeah I mean basically
you have uh carts are are a very
interesting and efficient right um
they're very convenient uh the oil
basically is uh you know is in the
cartridge and then there's a heating
element
um oftentimes there's a wick or a
wicking mechanism to make sure that the
oil gets transferred to the to that
heating element
or to a hot ceramic that then uh locally
basically boils the oil
um locally and so that then uh that
Vapor then is transmitted and uh you
know through the mouthpiece and
aerosolized
um one thing I learned recently is that
uh part of the design of of many
cartridges is actually to introduce uh
an external they have little air holes
and that is to make sure that the vapor
is less dense
um and that it coalesces back into an
aerosol rather than staying in fine
particulate form and that was always
that fascinated me part of that is to
increase sort of the cloud production
but also to make it a little easier on
your lungs and to cool it a little bit
before it enters your lungs
um you know as as far you know we're
really going to focus on on non-cart
Vapes but but since we're right here I
think that it's important for us to say
you know whatever your preference is in
you know what you want in your Vape like
you know I'm a big fan of hash rosin
personally but I certainly have got
respected friends who like properly
purged BHO for flavor and you know
there's there's a wide range of of what
you can put in the Vape the only thing I
want to be clear on is to know your
Source because there is a lot of garbage
that can be put in the Vapes um and and
it was weird in the early days people
didn't really know what was best to put
in The Vape so people tried everything
from you know coconut oil to vegetable
glycerin all these different things and
and and God help us we made it through
and and so now we know mostly we we
don't want to be you know adding
non-cannabis
constituents
um but then
the ones in them in the licensed Market
are often so expensive for lots of
people that that they tend to buy them
cheaper in the unlicensed market and
then we're back to the problem of oh god
what the hell's in it right and so um
you know whatever whatever your oil
preference dear listener
um you know know your Source because we
want we don't want you to get you know
some kind of serious lung issue from uh
from using some sketchy stuff right and
and to for from a functionality
perspective you have to have something
added to the cannabis oil or it won't
flow well right so there's a a degree of
of flow that that enters into the design
and requires something to kind of cut or
thin the oil to make it function
properly
now one of the go ahead
is that always the case though because I
really thought that the the like the big
breakthrough in the last like 18 months
is people being able to press hash rosin
at a viscosity
um that they can put him in these these
new Vapes and not have to have any
adulterant at all to it and I I thought
that was true is that not accurate I I
don't know Shango okay yeah yeah I don't
I I haven't seen those designs yet
um and that's exciting if it is
um one of the cautions that I would say
for people with uh the cartridge based
vaporizers because at least I
experienced this
um and that is that throat burn
um that often happens and and it's easy
to think that that's temperature but I I
don't believe that that's what's really
happening
um any time that you drop let's say uh
if you've done in Chinese cooking or or
dropped you know hot oil onto or oil
onto a really hot pan that's like red
hot right uh you get
um a lot of
you convert those oils fairly rapidly
into other compounds that are thicker
and are
polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons you
know they become worse they become bad
[__] you know is is really what happens
there so anytime you're really putting
the oil in the presence of something
that's super hot it's going to alter the
chemical structures of those compounds
and so that's what I believe the throat
burn is due to
um
at least that's my my my armchair
science background on that I'll take it
and also damn if that's true that that
explains why so many people have turned
away from cartridges and gone to some of
these other Solutions
um like the puffco peak which we're
going to talk about in a second but but
before we do
um so do you consider an email vaping or
combustion
I would sell it's it's a form of
vaporization yeah right yeah and I was
wondering if it had to do with like the
temp because you know certainly we we do
we we do see smoke from it right and and
but we don't ever see fire
um and so I was kind of of this idea
myself because I've used an email for
years that that at my lower temperatures
is a vaporizer but at higher
temperatures it's combustion but that
might be like the most non-science thing
I've said today
well if you're experiencing again you
can alter the chemical composition
without it being combustion so at high
temperatures when you pass the smoke
point of an oil you start altering the
chemical composition and that can feel
like combustion right
um it's a it's a harsher effect and so
when your nail is is super hot
largely it will lead to that kind of uh
thing so there's been a lot of movement
to the to the cold start dabbing or low
temperature dabbing and enails have
certainly helped that quite a bit
to dial in the the temperatures more
precisely right on um so um so we're
gonna next let's talk about the the
puffco peak which um you know stands out
as being you know one of the most
cherished uh instruments
um you know in the oil Community you
know it's it's uh it's convenience and
and the fact that you you know you were
talking about the um
oh surface area right right and one of
the great things is that they've got
these you know their bowls are great and
they're pretty evenly heated throughout
it and so you've got a lot of space at
once that's in contact with the oil at
the same time
and and you know I also want to be clear
that you know puffco is not like a
sponsor or anything you know other
people like the focus uh Carta right so
like I'm talking more about the design
where it looks like a bong and and
you've got this this wide bowl and and
then it's heated and then when you put
your concentrate on there
um you're you're gonna get a a large
Vapor hit at once because of all the
surface area
um do you like how I'm explaining the
science behind that is that is that how
you see it too yeah yeah I have not had
a ton of experience with the puffco but
it's you know sexy AF right I mean it is
it is you know let's face it it hits all
the right uh notes I think for for being
a fantastic product and
um you know and it and it can really
deliver for those people who want that
experience so yeah it's pretty
revolutionary from an email perspective
and you know they got a lot of crap over
in in the early years because there
there were some models that went out
with some you know failing components
which they've they've I guess they've
figured out over the years because
I haven't heard people complete compare
complain about that anymore but um have
you ever seen the the the the the
specialty puffco Peak
um hand blown and and made glass
trophies that they use for Emerald cup
the last few years since they started
sponsoring them no I haven't oh my God
they're absolutely beautiful
um uh I wish I could plug the artist who
does such a great job on them or maybe
they change them from year to year but
anyway if uh that's great you know for
those who those who like puffcos and
they also like ostentatious pieces you
know you know search for the for the
emerald cup
um
Awards I've seen some great wood ones
online where people are making some
gorgeous Wood Pipes that uh that then
the Carter fits in and yeah yeah those
are gorgeous so you can have that
smoking like experience but then enjoy
your your extracts so this whole family
of uh of pipes like the puffco peak and
the Carta these all would fall into the
conduction category right because
um that that ceramic Bowl that's being
heated and then we're putting our Dab
Oil on it that is a direct application
of heat correct correct correct yeah
cool um do you have any do you have
anything else to say about that like
that that type of design before we move
forward no I think that well I I always
have something to say I suppose go ahead
yeah yeah I think
um again look at at the waste product
right so what's left in in the bowl when
you're done uh and that can tell you a
little bit about Clues to the to the
chemistry that's happening
um during the process of vaporization so
when you're left with you know dark uh
resiny
um substances uh then you you haven't
completely vaporized them and you may
have altered the chemistry just like
when uh in a cartridge that's near the
end of life the oil has changed from a
maybe a light honey to a really darker
uh blend because you've altered the oils
um and you're left with some of that
heavier kind of uh compounds in there
does that's interesting how what is left
um depending on what is left uh can say
something about your temperature choice
but it can also say something about
what's in the oil true
um so other other than the
the under combusted dark oil that you're
talking about what what else might we
find in remaining in the bowl
that we would want to be aware of
um well you're not having any plant
matter so what you've got are largely
just different oil compounds
um when you uh
when the changes happen to terpenes and
Dr strangen from Portland State
University has done some interesting
research on on dabs and sort of the
byproducts of of conventional dabbing
techniques this doesn't apply to low
temperature dabbing but for high
temperature dabs
there's you know a
but there's a great word pyrolytic but
literally means fire changed and
thermolytic is probably the more
accurate thing the the oils then break
down into those Benzene rings and these
other
um you know hydrocarbons that have been
shown to be present in in uh you know
cigarette smokes and be uh you know
cancer-causing compounds
so I'm not saying that that's what is in
there but there is a likelihood of of
finding those kinds of of compounds in
that remaining
goo goo yeah thank you I was trying to
think of the right thing it is goo it's
Gunk yeah it's gross um and it's a
really um good encouragement for us that
when we do get a new vaporizer to um
really spend some time getting to know
um the different temperature points so
that we can you know really find the
right temperature for how we like to
smoke so that we're we're not having
that much much
um you know uh residue and that we're
not tempted to smoke it once it's become
Gunk we wanna we wanna heat it properly
so uh we get to inhale it pre-gunk yeah
yeah definitely
um you know for anybody making a
selection of a of a vaporizer it really
comes down to your preferences right uh
you know how much do you value the
discreetness there's a time and a place
you know for a for a vape pen that's you
know nothing else is going to to
actually fill that that need for you and
then how much of an Enthusiast are you
are you concerned about preserving Terps
are you looking for the full kind of a
more relaxed ritualized experience which
some of those will give you or are you
looking for something that's a little
faster and if you actually I don't know
about you but I really don't want to
interact with my phone to then control
my control my vaporizer right interact
with my phone enough so it really it
does take you out of it does take you
out of being present but I also have to
capture the fact that I've never done
that yet so I I look forward to having
that there you go yeah so how much is
the technology
enhancing your experience or is your
technology getting in the way of your
experience is it is it becoming part of
the focus of your experience or not yeah
to me an ideal product kind of Fades
into the background and you don't have
to think about it too much right on well
said all right so uh let's bring an end
to this uh rather long set and go to our
commercial break uh you are listening to
shaping fire oh and let me make sure you
that you come back because because if
that was a long set for you you might be
like thinking about taking off but don't
go anywhere because we're talking about
something really important in the third
set we are talking about boiling point
myths and the difference between
evaporation versus boiling so make sure
you come back from that uh you are
listening to shaping fire and my guest
today is aerospace engineer Mark Lewis
[Music]
after you've caught up on the latest
shaping fire episodes do you sometimes
wish there was more cannabis education
available to learn well we got you
shaping fire has a fabulous YouTube
channel with content not found on the
podcast when I attend conventions to
speak or moderate panels I always record
them and bring the content home for you
to watch the shangolos YouTube channel
has world-class speakers including Zoe
sigmund's lecture understanding your
endocannabinoid system Kevin chaudry of
Wonderland Nursery talking about
breeding cannabis for the best terpene
profile Frenchie cannolis Lost Art of
the hashishan presentation Nicholas
Mahmoud on regenerative and polyculture
cannabis growing Dr Sunil Agarwal in the
history of cannabis medicine Around the
World Eric vlosky and Josh Rutherford on
solventless extraction and Jeff lone
Fells on the soil food web there are
several presentations from Dr Ethan
Russo on terpenes and the
endocannabinoid system too while there
be sure to check out the three 10-part
shaping fire session series one with
Kevin jodhri one with Dr Ethan Russo and
one with Jeff lowenfels and even my own
presentations on how to approach finding
your dream job in cannabis and why we
choose cannabis business even though the
risks are so high as of today there's
over 200 videos that you can check out
for free so go to youtube.com forward
slash shangolos or click on the link in
the newsletter
online cannabis seed Distributors often
seem to be all the same but Multiverse
beans constantly Works to provide you
with cannabis seeds and a buying
experience that you won't find elsewhere
Multiverse beans Works directly with the
Breeders to secure as many packs of your
favorites as possible so that they have
your favorite beans long after others
have sold out some shops simply buy
breeder minimums but I get messages all
the time from breeders saying some
version of Multiverse has to buy my
entire run
at multiversebeans.com you can find rare
cannabis seeds from Night Owl seeds
including the dark owl sub label
Mephisto genetics Square One genetics
Robin Hood seeds and Ethos and so many
others
Multiverse also initiates projects with
breeders to secure exclusive packs that
you simply won't find elsewhere
Multiverse founder Paul lall sees
himself not only as a curator of the
best cannabis seeds available but also
as a collaborator with breeders trying
to bring novel crosses to the market
that his customers are asking for
Multiverse beans also creates exclusive
stickers for their popular seed
varieties that are available free only
when you order those seeds from
Multiverse
check out their stickers like the badass
recent slap for Mothman by gnome
automatics on Instagram at Multiverse
beans and finally the freebies as you'd
expect Paul sends quality freebies with
every order and when you spend at least
150 dollars Multiverse allows you to
choose your freebies from their special
selections
you can get a 10 discount off regularly
priced items when you use the discount
code shaping fire all one word at
checkout
sign up for their mailing list to be
eligible for their monthly seed giveaway
worth 250 dollars
so go to
multiversebeans.com now for a buying
experience you won't get anywhere else
[Music]
sometimes the topics I want to share
with you are far too brief for an entire
shaping Fire episode in those instances
I post them to Instagram I invite you to
follow my two Instagram profiles and
participate online the shaping fire
Instagram has follow-up posts to
shapingfire episodes growing and
processing best practices product trials
and of course gorgeous flower photos the
shangolos Instagram follows my travels
on cannabis garden tours my successes
and failures in my own garden insights
and best practices from personal grows
everywhere and always gorgeous flower
photos on both profiles the emphasis is
on sharing what I've learned in a way
that you can replicate it in your own
garden your own hash lab or for your own
canabatopathic health so I encourage you
to follow at shapingfire and at
shangolos and join our online community
on Instagram
welcome back you are listening to
shapingfire I am your host shangolos and
my guest today is aerospace engineer
Mark Lewis so here's the big finish
during the first set we talked about why
we vape and what the customer
experiences the consumer experiences and
and why so many people are attracted to
vaping during the second set we went in
depth into the vaporizer Technologies as
as they are right now and a whole bunch
of strategies for for you know getting a
vape in your hands that fits your
smoking preferences because they really
are a personal device well here in set
three we're going to finish up with a
discussion of uh evaporation versus
boiling
um because you know uh if if the primary
physics that we want to have happen is
the cannabinoids and terpenes and the
rest of the resin components to be
vaporized and then inhaled into our
lungs it really does matter what their
volatility levels are are and whether
we're evaporating or boiling and in our
scene on Instagram or on Reddit you know
it's very common to see these little
charts that show all of the volatility
points for different terpenes and
cannabinoids and and we feel like that
empowers us
um but Mark you've written this great
blog on your website
um that explains how that belief is not
quite right and and then people are
using that information and the the
thermostats on our on our vaporizers in
in ways that aren't maybe getting the
results that they're looking for so so I
guess I guess let's let's slide into
this by by talking about these charts
that exist and and what their
limitations are that you see as as a
engineer
yeah yeah thanks Django I appreciate
that um the uh I'm fascinated by these
boiling point charts and when I first
saw them I was like oh that's really
cool and oh these vaporizers are are
saying that I can dial in you know a
particular terpene if I've you know if I
dilate it to 349 degrees Fahrenheit I
will get limonene you know because
that's the boiling point of limonene and
um you know that's just not true it's
the bottom line of that
um as you as you look deeper into it uh
you know those those may be the boiling
points
um boiling points are notoriously
difficult to actually measure so there's
boiling ranges uh most scientists use
boiling ranges rather than a particular
boiling point because it's pressure
dependent and and there's other aspects
of the purity of the sample and all of
these other things that that lead to
boiling or not boiling
um so there's that but that's not as
relevant as the other aspects here the
the great thing about the charts is that
it gives you some relative volatility of
the compound so by volatility how easy
is it to go from a liquid to a vapor so
something that's super volatile at room
temperature
will evaporate really rapidly think of
rubbing alcohol for example so that's a
pretty volatile compound whereas as
water is not a very volatile compound it
takes a little bit more work to get
those molecules into their into their
gaseous form so those boiling point
charts are are great to understand some
relative volatility but they're they
don't tell the entire story if you will
so so do they have any value to us as
people who are consuming cannabis with
vaporizers like like if there if there
might be some
you know maybe not inaccuracies in them
but some contextual things that are
missing
can they be useful to us at all how
could we use them to our benefit or or
is it is it is just not useful
no they're they are useful in
understanding sort of the relative
nature of these different compounds so
what we've got in cannabis uh is this
wonderful bouquet of of different
aromatics and flavonoids and
cannabinoids
um that are in this mixture and it's
helpful to maybe think about it as a
perfume and in that perfume there's
these top notes that are lighter they're
the citrusy notes they're you know
they're if you think about that in terms
of a perfume there's there's your top
notes your mid notes and your bass notes
now if you put on your cologne or your
perfume
um you know right away you're getting
those earlier notes as part of the
mixture
they're more dominant but you're still
getting the bass notes and those smells
as the perfume evaporates off of you
but the mixture later on an hour later
is going to maybe be less on the top
notes and more dominant with the mid
notes but your bass notes are still
there as well and then later on into the
evening you know a lot of your top notes
have all evaporated your midnotes
there's less of them and your base notes
then are the dominant smell that you
will smell and similarly that happens
more rapidly with vaporization
particularly flower vaporization is that
you are for a particular power setting
on your on your vaporizer
you are going to get a different mixture
of of those compounds and your second
pole will be slightly different your
third pull will be slightly different
your fourth pole will be more different
and throughout your session with a
particular Bowl
you're going to be left then at the end
with some of the heavier more difficult
to volatize
compounds but they'll still be present
you know that sounds fun but also
frustrating right because I I want all
of it at the same time but but my mind
suggests that the way that I would get
them all at the same time is if I am uh
using a really hot setting which would
then also give me a satisfying Cloud
perhaps but but what I'm doing is I'm
like wrecking probably the more volatile
ones in order to get the more base ones
and even though in my head I'm thinking
oh if I if I Scorch it at this higher
temperature I'll get i'll get all the
good stuff at once
that that isn't really how it plays out
is it
uh yes and no I mean if you if you crank
up the heat you're going to
volatize more rapidly right
um so you're going to get uh
you're it's still gonna happen in a
similar way your your your lighter
compounds are going to evaporate more
rapidly it's just going to be on a
compressed time scale and so the
benefits of of those who choose to do
low temperature vaporization is that it
spreads out that extraction if you will
over over time and so you're able to
taste and experience the subtleties
um you know in a different way again if
if I have a medical condition that I'm
treating uh and I and I need that rapid
onset then you know by all means Crank
It Up what would be the what would be
the temper that you would recommend
temperature you would recommend if
somebody's goal is to uh get as much as
they can out of it you know teaching
tasting you know uniform in you know
just a hit or two yeah well I I would
you know personally I'm I'm so you
wouldn't recommend that personally I
wouldn't recommend that I think you get
a lot more out of your cannabis through
a lower I I started out there Shango uh
when I first started exploring
vaporization and I wanted to you know
ratchet it up to that pre-combustion
point right so that I had that heavy
roast I I felt you know got the feedback
that was more familiar to me like
smoking
um and honestly I you know over the last
couple of years I consistently start
dialing it back farther and farther and
farther and it extends my session a
little bit but my enjoyment level goes
way up uh I don't approach with the bowl
there's a point in your bowl where you
start to experience a a bite and and
that's when I cash out and
uh if you're up in that pre-combustion
zone where you're at you know
temperatures around 400 or or greater
you're going to get to that bite a lot
faster and to me then I'm wasting
products because I didn't experience all
all of the joy that the rest of the
compounds were were offering me
um I think that that speaks to a really
important point and can probably be like
a theme for the show which is
um part of choosing to use a vaporizer
for your consumption involves
um having a different experience than
combustion because vaporizing is never
going to be combustion and so part of
becoming a regular vaporizer is is
learning to smoke in new ways for
example
um you know people who are fans of the
cold start where where you you warm up
the tool already loaded and and and the
the Dab Oil slowly increases and you're
and you're taking hits as it's warming
up working its way all the way up you
your your sesh has significantly
expanded in the time and also
um your every hit that you take is going
to be different but
that that evolution of the hits is
itself a a different experience and
enjoyable experience a connoisseurs
experience that you that you don't get
with with a joint yeah it's it's slowing
it down a little bit
um uh which I think we've lost a little
bit in in our cannabis consumption right
keep the foreplay in cannabis I love it
yeah well it it's uh leaning into I mean
we don't do shots of alcohol anymore
after college I mean maybe occasionally
but uh to me it's it's more like sipping
a fine cocktail or a whiskey rather than
you know slamming it back and not just
going after the end result again no
judgment because you know that that was
a large part of my life for a while
um and as we've talked about throughout
the show this whole show is about
personal preference right yeah
absolutely so we're not trying to judge
anybody no not at all not at all it's
just be open-minded to experiencing
cannabis differently and I think that's
what vaporization offers you is this you
know a really different way to enjoy
really high quality cannabis and uh I'm
blessed and you're blessed and others
out there are blessed to live in places
where they have really conscientious
cultivators who are creating these
amazing terp Rich uh varietals that I
think deserve to be experienced in their
fullest and for me flower vaporization
is a way for for me to taste and
experience that complexity that the
plant has to offer and and the high is
different than than combusting
well that you know that that's a really
great ending to the show there mark you
know I was going to ask you if if there
are any more boiling point myths that
you wanted to point out and so I am
because I don't you may you may have
something else that you want to bring to
the table before we wrap up but that was
that was beautiful uh do you have any
other boiling appointments that you want
to bring up before we end the show well
the well the only real thing is is that
um the mechanism is not really boiling
which is internal to a fluid it's it's
better to think about it as evaporation
and just a rapid evaporation rather than
than a boiling
I see so so the charts that point out
the boiling point they may be
scientifically accurate but but really
because evaporation starts before
boiling we're back to
um you pointing out that it really is
more of a range and it is a range that
every time we take a hit
um we're going to cool the the heating
element to some degree and so we're just
going to be whatever temperature we we
pick we're actually just going to be
kind of cycling up and down in that
General neighborhood yeah some devices
warm up faster and and compensate but
but largely yeah you're you're doing
that kind of cycling
um back and forth the boiling points
again give you the relative how how
you're going to experience uh that bowl
I guess
excellent well Mark thank you so much
for being a guest on shaping fire you
know um I've been a fan
um of vaporizers for years and you know
I but I've never actually like studied
them very hard and and as I said in the
introduction you know when I met you you
had the actual scientific answers for
for the questions that I had had for
years and and it was funny because you
know what our first phone call was over
an hour and um and I was like so excited
to hear you cross applying all this
vaporization
um all these vaporization questions I
had to to you know aeronautical
Aeronautical Engineering and and rocket
science I was all like oh I have finally
found my person for for The Vaping show
so
um so I really appreciate you
um you know uh coming over and hanging
out with us on shaping fire for a little
while and and um you know sharing your
expertise and also you know kind of
taking it out of the heady super science
vocabulary that you and I used on our
first phone call and and kind of put it
in layman's turns terms today so that we
could do a show that would be open to
everybody so so I I appreciate your
knowledge and your ability to make that
knowledge accessible to all sorts of
different kind of cannabis enthusiasts
well thank you so much Shango and thank
you for all that you have done over the
years to really educate consumers about
this wonderful plant and and other
plants that are out there
um it you've been a part of my own
educational journey and your guests have
been uh part of that journey and I just
want to do a shout out to all of those
people in the Cannabis space who are
helping to educate others and to
demythify this industry because the more
we can demythify it the more we can move
beyond the stigma and and start really
celebrating what the plant has to offer
us fabulous all right dear listener um
if you want to uh learn more from Mark
um I highly recommend that you check out
his website where he has got a handful
of blog entries that are very
interesting with all sorts of charts and
graphs including the one that we did
this last set primarily focused on on
Boiling Point myths which uh it goes
into far more detail than we did here
today and you can find the blog section
at his website which is pearlabs.com and
so it's spelled specially so it's p r r
l
l a b s.com it's kind of like a cat Purl
labs.com and there you will find
um you know his blog and and also the
vaporizers that he has
um engineered himself
um with all of this insight and uh I'm a
big fan of the uh the Neo that I talked
about in the introduction so at the very
least go check it out because a uh a
vaporizer that functions like a uh like
a handheld lighter is a pretty cool
thing to see
you can find more episodes of the
shaping fire podcast And subscribe to
the show at shapingfire.com and wherever
you get your podcasts if you enjoyed the
show we'd really appreciate it if you
would leave a positive review of the
podcast wherever you download your
review will help others find the show so
they can enjoy it too on the shaping
Fair website you can also subscribe to
the newsletter for insights into the
latest Cannabis News exclusive videos
and giveaways on the shipping fire
website you also find transcripts of
today's podcast as well
be sure to follow on Instagram for all
original content not found on the
podcast that's at shapingfire and at
changolos on Instagram be sure to check
out shapingfire YouTube channel for
exclusive interviews farm tours and
cannabis lectures does your company want
to reach our national audience of
cannabis enthusiasts email hotspot
shippingfire.com to find out how thanks
for listening to shapingfire I've been
your host shangolos
foreign