[Music]
up until last summer I really didn't
have much good to say about CBD
extracted from hemp I'm not a fan of CBD
isolate or spiking cannabis products
with it
CBD just doesn't work reliably for
patients on its own each of the plants
cannabinoids terpenoids flavonoids and
lipids are vital components that humans
require to achieve the healing that
comes with the entourage effect but last
summer something new occurred it was the
first season that plants were grown at a
commercial scale that were legally hemp
but they had all the medical marijuana
genetics this is a monumental difference
up until last summer good folks were
taking industrial hemp fiber plants and
extracting CBD the problem with CBD
isolate though is that the science does
not support its medical efficacy and the
only reason it exists is because of the
artificial market for isolated CBD
created due to federal prohibition of
the medicinal whole plant quality whole
plant medicine comes from whole medical
cannabis plants not from hemp fiber
plants while the two may share a Latin
name they are wildly different plants
due to years of hybridization the hemp
plants just don't have the terpene
profiles and other attributes found in
medical cannabis but CBD from hemp fiber
plants is federally legal enough that it
can be sold online so people grow the
fiber hemp plants extract the CBD and
are selling it rapidly last summer
though some farmers in the u.s.
approached CBD plant genetics from the
opposite direction and instead of
growing fiber plants they turned off the
allele that makes THC in medical
cannabis plants and grew truly medical
cannabis plants legally as hemp these
plans that normally would have been
highly regulated and sold in cannabis
stores were allowed to be grown in open
fields unsecured because with the THC
allele turned off they tested below 0.3%
THC which makes them legally a hemp
plant even though these are really
medical cannabis plants the evolution of
this hybrid plant moves us beyond the
simple vocabulary of describing a plant
as hemp
or medical cannabis there are now
medical cannabis plants that are
regulated as hemp without being the
fiber producing sort while confusing for
outsiders this evolution will again
remake the CBD market over the next five
years and for die-hard CBD enthusiasts
like me there's finally a scalable
low-cost method of providing CBD to
patients everywhere
the next major milestone will be the
inclusion of cultivars that have above
0.3% THC but we're not quite yet they're
federally if you want to learn about
cannabis health business end technique
efficiently and with good cheer I
encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter will send you new podcast
episodes as they come out delivered
right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week and
videos - don't rely on social media to
let you know when a new episode is
published sign up for the updates and
make sure you don't miss an episode
also we're giving away very cool prizes
to folks who are signed up to receive
the newsletter there's nothing else you
need to do to win except receive the
newsletter this month I'm really stoked
that we're giving away several newly
released air vape X vaporizers from air
vape usa.com go to shaping fire com to
sign up for the newsletter and be
entered into all future newsletter prize
drawings you are listening to shaping
fire and I'm your host Shango lows my
guest today is Seth Crawford
Seth is a deinstitutionalized academic
with a master's in public policy in a
PhD in sociology his focus has been on
the political economy of cannabis for
years now he has been consulted by
lawmakers and policy specialists for
better understanding of how the cannabis
economy works
he's now co-founder of Oregon's CBD a
company researching developing and
wholesaling high CBD cannabis seeds
today we're gonna talk about the
dramatic evolution occurring in CBD
genetics hey welcome to the show Seth
pleasure to be here thanks for having me
thanks so much for coming back so so
let's start at the very beginning you
know you and your brother Eric saw this
opportunity to produce CBD on the large
scale because there were so many
patients that were yearning for it and
yet to do it large scale you had to
figure out a way to make it legal to
grow in volume where you lived in
Oregon so so what did you and Eric see
in this opportunity that decided to push
you in this direction of producing CBD
from plants that are legally hemp we
have always really been looking forward
to the day of being able to grow enough
plants to do scientifically accurate
selection you know it's we've we're
hobby breeders for a decade before we
got into this full scale and there's
some really neat things that you can do
as a hobby breeder and people are doing
this all over the world and we love to
see it but there are a lot of things
that you just can't do with you know
four plants or six plants that really
emerges when you start growing thousands
at a time to do your selections that
that was that was one of the driving the
driving factors for us was just being
able to breed better plants yeah that
makes a lot of sense when you can do a
sift that's that huge you're just gonna
jump ahead of hobbyists like you were
saying you're only gonna do there their
patient max of four or 15 or whatever
it's going to be you know one of the
things I want to really drill on in this
part that's what sets you apart from a
lot of the other hemp from CBD producers
because I actually I do talk a lot of
trash about hemp derived CBD on this
show but but the weird thing is I always
have to make this caveat except for the
stuff that comes from oregon CBD seeds
right because you guys are going about
this a different way than nearly
everybody else in hemp and if I
understand it all correctly you know so
many of the hemp from CBD companies they
started with the fibrous version of hemp
and they are trying to breed in the
medicinal qualities of you know full
cannabinoid content medicinal terpenes
and you know in order to be able to pull
the entourage effect out of a fiber
plant and you know I have not seen a lot
of success in that however you guys came
from the other direction you guys
actually started with a legit
healing full-spectrum marijuana medical
marijuana plant and you decided to turn
off the THC allele and which as far as
I'm understanding from outside of the
CBD market that CBD hemp market that is
a wholly new approach so break that out
a little bit for us would you yeah that
that's accurate description of of what's
going on you know not only entourage
effect for individuals who would be
consuming the the final product but the
other thing that you end up missing out
from just a basic plant biology
perspective if you have no terpenes in
your plant you generally have more pests
you have more disease you have more
problems cannabis in in the in the long
term evolved many many different
different terpene combinations that
allow it to thrive in its natural
environment as the hand of humans has
started to select for those different
characteristics we've obviously
gravitated towards particular smells and
particular effects that go along with
with those terpenes whether it's for THC
in combination with THC or CBD or as
we'll talk about pretty soon CBG and
other cannabinoids so what we were
really really trying to do was to just
recreate that that like you said an
entourage effect but that beautiful
pallet that comes along with well bred
cannabis in Oregon we're lucky enough to
be surrounded by literally decades of
incredible breeding that has been done
by a number of different individuals and
put into the sort of the public well in
terms of cannabis varieties that
individuals have access to and we once
once we had figured out how to how to
essentially turn off the the THC
production it allowed us to then go back
to those wells and find those really
interesting to European combinations and
breed them back in to create new lines
and that's that was basically the the
essence of our business to begin with so
so what can you
tell us I mean I understand that there's
a certain part of where your genetics
come from that is proprietary but I'm
sure that there are people who are
listening like me who would just love to
hear what cultivar of medical cannabis
you started with and what you did to it
to turn off this THC allele because I'm
sure that that has raised flags for a
lot of GMO minded people in the audience
so so for those of us who really care
can you break that out a little bit yeah
there's there's really no secret we
didn't start with anything that was that
was miraculous or strange we started
just like most other I would say
small-scale breeders getting different
varieties from Europe mostly from Spain
and also natively sourced here in the in
the United States most of the varieties
you can see sort of the the history of
the emergence of CBD
many of the varieties were one-to-one so
these are type 2 cannabis plants that
have relatively equal parts THC and CBD
that was that was the starting block
that we we began with and really what it
comes down to with with all real
cannabis breeding the answer to get to
your solutions generally starts with
inbreeding we just do a lot of line
breeding inbreeding
specific plants selfing those and when
you self those plants you start to lock
in specific characteristics and say with
a one to one plant if you if you were to
self that you're going to end up with 25
percent of the resulting progeny as high
CBD plants 25 percent of the resulting
progeny will be high THC and the other
50% are roughly 50 percent are still
type twos so it the initial the initial
process was not at the time it may have
seen fairly revolutionary but in reality
it's really not and there are a number
of other people who are doing that as
well some of the the later advances that
we were able to achieve like
flowering type 3 high CBD plants and now
type 4 CPG plants that that I think is
that's definitely something that did set
us apart and it was it was mostly driven
by agricultural necessity we could
create really good plants identify them
clone them and run those clones and
fields and you have really good outcomes
but to to grow at a truly industrial
scale to make you know a an affordable
medicine for people that's actually
effective you really can't just grow
clones and that's when we started really
working on producing viable f1 hybrid
seeds using our are very inbred line and
recombining those was that was the goal
always to create a feminized and auto
flower seed or is that something that
you realized was going to be necessary
as you started interacting with your
agricultural clients and realizing oh my
god we need to make this easier you know
if for us it was out of necessity just
in terms of how we could maximize our
own production Eric and I have always
seen auto flowering plants as having a
very very interesting niche if if
managed properly and we've always been
curious about whether or not that would
end up leading to innovations on in
large-scale agriculture I think that it
does and I think what we're seeing right
now is not just on the CBD side but also
on for THC as long as you can get the
right terpene combination in those
flowers Auto flowers are fantastic for
large-scale production if it's if it's
going into an oil whether that's for cut
consumption or for a vape pen or you
know whatever else a myriad products are
on the market autos are incredibly
useful but it was it was mostly just
trying to develop initially and this is
back in 2016 it seems like forever ago
right now but in 2016 we were we were
trying to give ourselves as many options
as possible you know if you're trying to
grow early in the season you know your
best bet is probably an auto flowering
plant and if you're trying to grow you
know to maximize production you want to
have a plant that finishes early in the
season but it's still photo period
sensitive so we developed our early
lines to do that and if you have a long
enough growing season you can you know
potentially have a third crop with Auto
flowers as they tend to be a little bit
more robust and resistant to freezing I
think it's really interesting to
consider it because you know feminized
in Auto flower seeds in the you know
traditional heritage cannabis farmer
world they get a you know short shrift
right feminized and Otto flowers or
somehow seen as unnatural and a lot of
people have a lot of gripes with them
but when you when you talk to people
about their particular gripes it's
because you know they got some seeds
that had been you know bred into a
feminized and so now there's like hermes
and their stock and it seems that the
reasons why people don't like feminized
an auto flower has little to do with the
seed itself and everything to do with
how people have used them incorrectly
for their purpose whereas you're
designing these seeds specifically for
multi acre grows in an agricultural
setting where you're dealing with really
high volume and every plant has to be
the same and harvested you know either
at the same time or in known waves and I
think that's an important thing to point
out is that these are feminized and auto
flower seeds for a reason that has never
existed before that's exactly right
and a.22 and they're almost two separate
issues I mean the the complaints about
auto flowering plants especially for THC
production were legitimate I grew out of
flowering THC plants present at six 2007
shortly after they kind of emerged on
the market and they were terrible I mean
you could see the promise with them but
the terpene profile was awful
you know it left you just feeling like
you know you've been hit by a train and
not in a good way
they were they were they were not
sophisticated they did not have good
palates but the performance was
something that I just you know
immediately latched onto and said if you
can if you could make the flavor better
and increase the overall resin content
this has potential you know it took it
took a decade to get back to to that
need it before before we started
developing the newer versions of them
but in that interim time in the in that
10 years there was sort of a revolution
in and good terpenes being added into
those autoflowering THC plants as well
so have been have been working to
improve that was I think we're to the
point today where you can end up with
with fairly high quality plants that
come out of come out of the
autoflowering world with a feminized
feminized see your point is spot-on a
lot of a lot of breeders you know you
can't see me so I'm doing air quotes at
this point but some breeders who are
more interested in just selling seed
than necessarily creating good stable
lines they're not as careful with with
weeding out those from a frenetic traits
we're to the point with with our
breeding that we see one male and I
they're not males they're they're
they're definitely female plants but
they're male they have male phenotypes
so we've we've found one in 4,000 in our
fields and this is literally we're
talking about millions of plants that
have been grown in in Oregon and
elsewhere over the last two years using
our seed and it's it's a very consistent
rate we get one in 4,000 that have a
male phenotype we've screened them using
PCR doing the the genomics test from
medicinal genomics and they they're
female even though they have male
phenotypes the really interesting
background on that too is that if you
use one of those those phenotypic males
to pollinate other female plants you're
going to end up with
fifty percent that are phenotypically
male and fifty percent that are
phenotypically female so it's a it's a
strange a strange mutation that's going
on and I'm not really sure what's
happening I don't think anybody knows at
this point but uh an interesting feature
for sure but one in 4000 versus you know
having hermaphroditic traits built into
your plants we feel like that's a pretty
good ratio you know that's for us that's
one plant every two acres you end up
having to cut down see that's you know
that's actually epic will will that will
that you know typically male yet somehow
female plant be a risk to the rest of
the crop oh can there be any pollination
oh yeah yeah it'll definitely pollinate
and yet we recommend to farmers that you
basically walk your field you know it's
the old adage of the best fertilizers of
farmers footprints is definitely true in
this case you go out and you find those
as soon as they start flowering they're
very easy to spot they look just like a
male and you we cut them down and you
know even though that adds labor for the
farmer it kind of warms my heart right
because even though we are scaling up
and industrializing several aspects of
cannabis production there's still
something in it that the farmer has to
be in the in the field and be around the
plants and to give it that human touch
or at least awareness very much so very
much so in it you know it really draws
attention to the risk of pollen floating
around in the environment in the first
place you know that that one male plant
it's not going to pollinate your entire
crop and the chances of it you know
pollinating a neighbor are very slim but
you will end up with a twenty five to
thirty foot section of your field that
is just completely seated and seeds you
know obviously scattered throughout
wherever the wind was blowing we had a
fairly interesting I say interesting now
because it's been long enough that I'm
not completely emotionally scarred from
it anymore with interesting situation
back in 2016 we were trying to make
feminized seed doing a light deprivation
run in the middle of the summer and we
had a neighboring farmer that had
planted about 38 million male female MCS
just broadcast see it was the first his
first year growing and it ended up you
know it's a tremendous amount of males
that were out in this field and the the
pollen from that field destroyed farms
15 miles to the north 15 miles to the
south 15 miles to the west excuse me to
the east everybody to the West was fine
because that's the way that the wind was
blowing but that that one just
small-scale experiment ended up in the
the first major year of production for
Oregon recreational growers you know it
seeded a lot of crops it destroyed we
lost 15 million seeds in in in that
summer alone just due to contamination
we had to destroy them so pollen pollen
is a significant issue and it's
something that we have tried to be out
on the forefront in terms of providing
education of farmers to make sure that
they know just what the risks are and to
have good communication with their
neighbors but also question question the
veracity of seed makers with the claims
that they're making it's a the adage
about cannabis seeds being a seedy
business is very very true you know your
unfortunate neighbor seeding the whole
valley and you mentioned you know it
points out the importance of
communication what did your valley do
because your valleys full of hemp
farmers now from what I understand what
did you guys do to increase your
communication so that kind of malarkey
doesn't happen again well it's it's been
an up rode up rode up an uphill battle
to be perfectly honest most farmers are
are responsible about it and try to
communicate the Department of
Agriculture in Oregon makes available
the list of farm sites and the acreage
so we know where all the other hemp
farms are in the state and we have email
addresses and phone numbers and that
sort of thing to be able to communicate
with other farmers that that's the the
main thing that you have to do but at
the same time there are some especially
older traditional farmers
sort of thumbed their nose and just say
look I have a right to farm and we've
basically had to come back and say well
we do too and you're right the farm is
infringing on ours and if you pollinate
our crop with your your your grain crop
that's worth a dollar a pound we're
probably going to have to resort to
legal action and we don't want to do
that but the precedent needs to be set
that that people who pollinate others
are responsible for that so I why to
change hats for a minute before we go to
our first commercial you know up to this
point we've been talking a little bit
about specifically you know oregon CBD
seeds your company but but but a lot of
people know you as your you know
academic professor role where you
testify in front of the legislature and
are just you know a general CBD expert
right so I want you to put on that hat
for a minute so take off your your CEO
co-founder hat and put on your your
professor hat and and and and answer me
this how is what you are doing there and
the seeds that you are providing to your
your partners in Oregon how does that
compare to what is going on in the other
hemp hotspots in the country for example
Colorado because you know as I as I tell
people about what you're doing in Oregon
which you know when I toured your
facility you know it's mind-blowing
right is what's going on there if you if
you've been taking care of patients for
a long time and you think about it
you're like oh my god this is like the
Holy Grail you know low price high turps
high CBD not from fiber hemp oh my god
right but but at the same time there are
people also excited about their
breakthroughs in Colorado and other
places but but they seem to be of a
different tenor so stepping away from
the fact that you've got a company and
into your academic shoes how is what you
are doing compared to what's happening
elsewhere in the United States yeah
that's a it's a great question you know
and it's you know if we're gonna go to
the professor route it kind of gets to
the the point of the work that I was
doing before
my area of expertise was sort of social
networks a long-term organization of
capitalist societies you know these sort
of big picture you know 500 year or 500
year views on the development of
different social systems around
different technologies whether that's an
agricultural technology or markets and
you know that sort of thing and I bring
that to where we're at today with with
cannabis because it's it's an absolutely
exceptional time to be alive in
witnessing what's going on with this
particular market in good ways and in
bad ways we see the good as you just
described incredible access for for
patients and people who didn't even call
themselves and would never call
themselves patients or just people who
are a little bit older who have aches
and pains and they can take this what
amounts to a nutritional supplement and
end up having a higher quality of life I
mean it's it's D stigmatized to the
point where we're just constantly being
approached by people who are using these
compounds to to just have a have a
better time in in their their golden
years it's fantastic to see that the the
negatives are you know consolidation and
lack of diversity and all of the things
that you see happen in all the top elec
markets monopolistic markets we're
seeing that definitely emerge right now
but on the exciting the exciting set in
these different states Colorado Kentucky
North Carolina now is coming online in a
big way I mean there's we have 37 states
that have industrial hemp laws passed
allowing some form of production right
now Oregon Colorado and Kentucky are
definitely out in the forefront and the
the folks who were early adopters who
had some capital behind them have
finally gotten their their processing
centers up and running to a point where
they they can actually handle the amount
of material that is is being produced
and not only handle it but you know that
the demand is as more CBD has has
entered the market the demand has just
increased X
financially along with that so it's one
of those situations where the more
people know the more they're exposed to
it the greater the demand and it's
worked out really well for for everybody
in this in this industry
awesome innovations both on the product
side on the extraction side and the
scalability just being able to put good
good marketing plans together and how to
distribute this and get it
you know from point A to point B having
a more robust regulatory environment
where we it's no longer I think we're to
the point now with hemp at the federal
level that we we know that it's not just
going to go away it's it's only going to
continue to expand and that's given
given a lot of the people in the
industry a little bit more confidence
that the direction that we're going is a
good one and it's okay to continue to
invest your time and labor in this
because it's it's really just gonna go
up so as far as seed providers go now I
want to drill down very specifically to
this potentially difficult question so
so what makes Oregon CBD seeds great is
the uniqueness of your seeds and the
fact that you came from that the medical
cannabis side and then brought it under
the umbrella of hemp by Creative
hybridization is anybody else in the
country
been successful doing that I mean do you
have competitors that are doing putting
out these same kinds of seeds that they
have found their way to this same
solution or are you guys the only folks
in the country that are that that are
coming from the cannabis medicine side
and not from the fiber hemp direction oh
no there's there are definitely
definitely others who have been doing
the same thing and who've been doing it
just as long as us some good some good
breeders in Colorado we have good
breeders in Oregon as well they're the
the fun part is is there's there's
always somebody always somebody doing
something unique the thing that really
sets us apart was the creation of the
auto flowering plants and in addition to
that are the development of our early
flowering photo period sensitive
varieties so we are the only ones who
are doing that at this
and for us that's that's the major
technological innovation in addition to
having terpene rich very very high
content plants that was the major the
major innovation that has really pushed
a lot of the farmers in Colorado in
Kentucky in it in addition to Oregon
farmers in our direction are the three
hotspots of Oregon Colorado and Kentucky
are you guys all allowed to buy seeds
from each other or do you have to buy
seeds in state I know we are allowed to
ship anywhere in the United States it
has a section seven six zero six farm
bill compliant industrial hemp research
program so we ship to Kentucky we ship
to Colorado we ship Vermont Maine North
Carolina South Carolina we have some
clients in Florida that are coming
online later this year anywhere there's
a hemp program we can ship all right
awesome so so now with this first set as
talking about kind of where the the seed
technology is at the moment I think
let's wrap up this first sex I'm really
excited about the second set because
your season was insane and it was an it
was very enjoyable for me to watch it
from a state of way and and and watch
you go crazy and it'll be a good story
so so stick around folks we're gonna
take a short break and be right back you
are listening to shaping fire my guest
today is Seth Crawford of Oregon CVD we
humans are attracted to plants because
they offer us relief and are a whole lot
of fun sometimes though the best parts
are buried inside the plant and we need
to use specialty extraction technology
when it comes to cannabis it is
extraordinarily important to extract its
precious oils without changing them in
the process we want to preserve the
properties of the cannabinoids terpenes
and other constituents that all work
together since 1994 Eden labs has been
developing extraction technology and
processes to do just that
Eden labs was founded by a cannabis
loving engineer during the early days of
medical marijuana in California and the
expanded Eden team has been designing
and building industry-leading solutions
for cannabis extraction ever since
Eden labs flagship product is the newly
improved High Flow co2 extractor
as other extraction companies enter the
market it is the high flow from Eden
labs that everyone chases and tries to
compare themselves with not only that
but the improved automation software
allows data to be collected stored and
studied Eden labs can outfit your whole
lab Eden's coldfinger ethanol extractor
creates astonishing whole plant extracts
working alone or in tandem with an
initial stream distilling step to
isolate monoterpenes before extracting
the rest of the botanical constituents
Eden offers you many options including
vacuum distillation column distilling
stirred reactor units and accelerated
solvent recovery when you partner with
Eden labs your lab team is enrolled into
the Eden labs training program to boost
their understanding of Eden's best
practices to ensure that your outputs
are exactly what you require for your
application whether it be dab oil oil
for pen cartridges or edibles when you
work with Eden you're not just buying
the tech you are buying dedicated
customer support to help you attain your
business goals - you can hear Eden's CEO
AC Braddock talk about the company's
values during shaping fire episode 19
that was all about co2 extraction so
many of the new companies in the market
just smell opportunity slap an extractor
together and hire a marketing company
Eden Labs has been listening to feedback
from extractors and consumers for about
25 years now they care about both you
and your consumer partner with Eden labs
to extract astonishing cannabis oils and
terpenes that you will be proud of go to
shaping feiyr.com
Ford / Eden to find out more join me at
the upcoming kin met event in Los
Angeles for a gathering of the top minds
in cannabis medicine field experts will
present their latest findings and best
practices in treating a variety of
conditions with cannabis including
epilepsy pain traumatic brain injury
cancer autism and more laboratory
professionals will share their
revolutionary technologies in
cannabinoid and terpenoid extraction
delivery methods and quality and safety
testing can med 2018 is October 22nd
through 24th at the Luskin conference
center at you
CLA and while the final speakers list is
still coming together the speakers who
are already announced give you plenty of
reasons to get your ticket today prepare
yourself to learn from fifty four
thought leader presentations focused on
furthering the convergence of medical
cannabis research treatment and product
development speakers include the father
of cannabis research Raphael Mis ulam
Michael door chief medical consultant
for the Israeli Ministry of Health will
be there to the list of esteemed
speakers participating is long and
includes shaping fire guests cannabis
neuroscientist dr. Ethan Rousseau and
Kevin mckernon of medicinal genomics you
can view all the speakers at kin med
events calm this year's kin med features
a special education track on the
application of blockchain technology in
the cannabis market including cannabis
banking seed to sale tracking sequencing
the cannabis genome ICO financing and
more if you are a medical care provider
be sure to arrive a day early to
participate in the pre-conference CME
course find out more about that at kin
med events com that's c-a-n-n-a me D
events com
95% of attendees said kin med 2017 met
or exceeded their expectations that's a
serious vote of confidence that can med
2018 will be well worth your time and
resources shaping fire listeners can
save 20% off the ticket price price by
purchasing before June 21st and using
the discount code
Shango so don't delay visit kin med
events comm today to reserve your seat
and find out more welcome back you are
listening to shaping fire I'm your host
Shengo Louis and our guest this week is
Seth Crawford he's co-founder of oregon
CBD so now that we've got you all set up
at how you got to this summer there Seth
let's talk about this craziness that was
this summer so people have an idea of
the of the magnitude we're talking here
describe the number of fields that you
were running and then also the
associated fields like you know in your
area that were that were using your
seeds
uh yeah that's what we had five separate
locations various various acreages are
our main research and development field
was about forty forty thousand plants
planted on around thirty five acres
total number of seeds that went out for
the state of Oregon and to a couple
other states we were looking at about
two thousand acres worth last season a
substantial number of substantial number
of plants yes substantial number it's
really enjoyable to walk through that
much terpenes being given off to and so
and so you had your fields and you
provided your you know seed leadership
to other folks in your valley and and
we've already hit the story of the guy
pollinating the valley a couple years
ago but but what I'm kind of putting
together is that your local area you you
guys have kind of become the epicenter
of of hemp growing in Oregon and there's
there's some amount of partnership you
guys are kind of like a UH
an industry block of intention right
yeah I think that's an accurate
description although I'd also throw in
Southern Oregon as well southern
organism has long been a large cannabis
producing area and a lot of the the
recreational farmers have they started
out last year doing smaller plots but
are moving in this year to bigger plots
and it's really becoming a force unto
its own as well but here here in the
valley we're after after the great
pollination event of 2016 everybody's
sort of banded together to to try to
ensure that new farmers were educated
and that the other farmers had access to
not only feminized seed but good
information one of the the major
concerns that we've had is sort of
unsavory characters making claims about
seed that they sell last season you know
people were saying this is mostly
feminized and farmers would plant it and
it would be fifty percent female which
is not mostly feminized that happened on
a regular basis yet
seed sellers who were offering offering
varieties that were actually type 2
plants so equal parts CBD to THC and it
led to about 10% of the the state
failing their THC compliance tests so
everybody's trying to trying to watch
out not only for their own interests but
the the interests of the larger
industrial hemp community at large so
it's turned into a nice sort of
cooperative that everybody can
contribute to you know it just occurred
to me that that you know the the
compliance tests to make sure that the
the amount of THC in the plants are so
low those happen at the end of the
season and because your plants are high
CBD no THC your farms don't have the
same kind of hardcore security around
them that THC plants do and it's it's
funny and somehow ironic that there were
all of these one-to-one plants that were
being grown in fields just out next to
people's houses and and they were fine
and safe just because no one knew they
had THC in them even though those plants
are like every high schoolers dream to
go grab yeah exactly exactly and it's
scary to be to be perfectly honest it's
sad for the farmers that ended up buying
those seed they were they were built by
unscrupulous unscrupulous breeders but I
mean what you're saying is is completely
true the problem is is that if you're
over 1% so if you if you're over 0.3
percent THC you fail your compliance
test but if you're over 1% you get
turned into the local sheriff's and
that's that's a that's a significant
problem especially if you have 10 to 20
acres of those plants you you you the
numbers that you're talking about would
lead to a life sentence in prison
I think Jeff Sessions was just talking
about reinstituting the death penalty
for for people who were growing that
many cannabis plants so it's a laughing
matter to a certain extent because we
can say hey people did this and even
though it was it was unscrupulous people
who were misleading them the world
didn't in just because some THC was
grown outside without offense and
security it
the neat part you know the two downside
is is it's a it's a legitimate risk and
there's a lot of problems that can come
along with that yeah the thing that you
could you could pull a felony for what
is absolutely a technicality and seed
purchase that is scary as hell
yeah yeah and the the part that really
got us is that we knew that this was
going to happen we knew where the seed
source was coming from we knew that
there had been male THC plants that were
outdoors in a neighboring field and we
knew that the C crop had been
contaminated but because there is no
seed certification program there's no
you know you don't have to have any
verification that the seed is actually
type 3 industrial hemp is sort of a
free-for-all
then it's allowed some grifters to to
enter the marketplace they usually stick
around for one year and everybody
figures out that they don't know what
they're doing and they'll try to get
some quality seed but in the meantime
the lives are ruined crops are lost and
it just it's a black eye for the entire
industry
right on so it's this next part of the
interview that that kept me so excited
to have you back as soon as that you
could find time for us again and that is
that the the evolution of your business
model over the course of this last
summer so what I'd like you to do is to
- you know I understand that the the
major force of your business model was
that you were going to make and sell
feminized autoflowering high CBD nearly
zero THC seeds but as part of that you
need to have these research and
development fields and and so that you
can see how your plants are coming along
on how they work in real agricultural
environments so at the end of the season
you were going to have I think you said
maybe seven acres or something like that
of plant material that was R&amp;D but now
you've got all this flowers so so I'm
just kind of kind of set you up to tell
this story of what was your plan what
were your plans going to be for the
flower at the beginning of the season
and how did that evolve
over the course of the summer yeah
well you know this valley is we had
experienced the year before
sometimes there's pollen floating around
so we had basically just planned on
planting our field getting our research
crops in running the risk of getting
pollinated and having having a seeded
crop and basically the only option that
you have at that point is to turn it
into oil and sell it to extractors so
that that was essentially our plan going
into the season we just wanted to do our
field trials to to ensure that the
varieties that we are offering to
farmers for this this season actually
perform the way that we described so we
like to run our field trials to here
before and then then offer the seed once
it's been progeny tested we got to the
end of the season and you know we kept
checking the flowers and you know
there's no pollen yet you know have
another week goes by there's no there's
no pollen yet that I'm not seeing any
seeds forming you know and we finally
got basically about two weeks away from
two weeks away from from the initial
harvest and everything looked really
good there you know there were no seeds
in it and you know at that point you're
looking at you're looking at 35 acres of
unseeded just beautiful Turkey and rich
flowers it's as you got to experience
it's it's very hard to be able to
accurately describe the excitement that
one who's passionate about cannabis and
terpenes will have walking through it is
so there's so much joy in that
experience oh my god walking through and
smelling all the terpenes as the Sun is
hitting the flowers and they're all
calling out oh man it's yeah it's
otherworldly and it just it puts a smile
on my face to think about it and every
time we we send a farmer out the door
with with seed you know it's the one
thing that we generally leave them with
is just wait until August you know when
your field is in full bloom and it's you
don't have to harvest just yet it's a
it's a truly magical experience it's
it's transformational it's very cool
we got to that point in the season and
you know we'd we had had some some folks
come from Switzerland who really wanted
to get our flowers because you know they
came and they smell them early in the
season and Wow these are these are
tremendous but we you know knowing that
the risk of contamination I didn't want
to put us into a situation where we you
know we would get into a contract to
supply trimmed flowers or something like
that that's what they wanted and then
end up with a seeded crop and not be
able to follow through on it but once we
made it to that point in the season we
realized that okay
we're good we're gonna trim and dry as
as many of these acres as we possibly
can and send them internationally - to
Switzerland all right so let me hold you
right there cuz that's a big deal
number one how did the people in
Switzerland found find out about your
little farm in Oregon that's a great
question I'm I'm honestly not sure but
we're contacted pretty regularly the the
Swiss European sorry that the European
and Swiss hemp market for smokeable
flowers has has really just taken off in
the last couple years Switzerland has a
1% THC rule which gives you a little bit
of flexibility and in the oil content of
the plant and so they they've been
producing it in mostly in glass houses
for the last two years trying to meet
the demand and they saw Oregon as you
know sort of a hotbed of production and
started reaching out to different farms
throughout the state and most of the
farms that we're growing good material
we're all actually growing our seat so
the band as they say the roads all seem
to lead back to us and so they they
found us and and we got them some
flowers
so so one of the things that I picture
in my head is that as the summer goes
and as more people you know hear your
story and they hear the first podcast
that I did with you at the beginning of
the season
and you know in the hemp people just
start talking about what you guys are
doing that you're starting to get more
and more you know VIP contact from the
US and interested people from other
countries and and I can feel like this
brewing this attention and people making
contact with you and yearning for your
stuff is that how it was feeling for you
as well as you're like oh my god we're
we're riding this bowl of a product and
now everybody wants it very much so very
much so and that was that was true both
on you know our flower material and on
the the seed itself because the flower
material was I think it was excellent
the products that are coming out of it
were we're definitely things that I'm
proud of and I think everybody on our
crew is would say the same thing but
because it was an R&amp;D field you know we
were basically doing the trials for what
other farmers will be growing this
season and the the buzz was definitely
palpable so it led to not only the
demand I demand for the flower material
for the resulting trim and you know all
the other products that go along with
that but for the seed as well our our
harvest cease was was long arduous as
they always are for everybody but it
didn't stop I mean we went from we went
from our our flower harvest and trimming
and exporting to building out new
facilities in three separate counties to
make sure that we could we could meet
the exploding seed seed demand and you
know I want to take a quick second here
and mention you you've dropped out three
or four times it's been increasing as
the interview is gone so if you're
listening and you're like I keep on
losing you know like a second or two
it's because we're Seth lives way out
early in Oregon they are experiencing a
thunderstorm and so when the weather
gets bad they drop packets sometimes so
don't think that it's that it's your
phone or whatever we're just we're just
occasionally dropping packets from Seth
so so thanks for staying on the line
there Seth even though it's the
weather's getting crazy down there
so prom yeah sorry for the jobs yeah
well you know so so so I want to finish
up this great Switzerland stories so now
that you know the the Swiss folks found
you and they contacted you and they
wanted to buy your flower but you're
like I don't want to commit to the
flower because we think it's gonna get
seated over the summer now you're two
weeks out from harvest and you've got
all of this unseated sinsemilla high CBD
flower and you're like oh my god this
product this is the value of this
product just just shot up because it's
got great value in other countries so
how did that deal finish up because you
know I talked to you briefly during that
time and you were like oh my god we've
got it we got to hire all this new staff
and trimming machines and and and we
gotta figure how to package this and get
it to Switzerland so so tell that part
of the story because I found it pretty
engaging oh it was traumatic I don't
even want to revisit it yeah I mean just
a number of different growing pains and
in logistical details of you know
basically learning how to operate
large-scale machine
trimmers hiring a very large crew of
people to come in to do the finish
trimming with that packaging
I had never I'd never shipped quantities
that we were talking about we ended up
using FDA approved 55-gallon drums with
plastic liners we could fit about 30
pounds without without crushing the the
resulting product about 30 pounds in
each one of those and you could fit four
of those on a pallet and then shrink
wrapped them and off they go so it was
just non-stop deluge of trimming
packaging wrapping shipping and and in
going back into the field to then
harvest more and more and more and dry
and you know basically maximizing our
drying space and our throughput and just
have it there's no way that we could
have done what we did without the crew
that we had everybody was very devoted
to to the cause
and for a lot of people it was sort of a
mind-blowing experience you know
everybody is used to you think
industrial hemp and you definitely don't
think of the flowers that we were
pulling out of that field so it's it was
it was fun it was definitely uh
definitely a good experience for
everybody involved and this is one of
the times that you're really glad that
you're growing Otto flowers too so that
you can stagger the harvest because with
with regular photosensitive flowers
everything would have been ready just
about the same time so this is this is
the interesting part we did have Auto
flowering plants but the material that
we were trimming were their photo period
sensitive varieties but they have been
designed to flower very very early and
the other characteristic that we've been
able to put into these plants is that
you can stagger the harvest with them
and you get about a three week window
the first batch was finished the first
week of September the second batch was
done the second week of September and
then you know we were basically
harvesting until the rains hit after
that with the the later the later
maturing varieties but they they're all
within the same the same basic harvest
window and that's that's one of the
innovations that we've been able to that
we've been successful in breeding into
the lines that we've developed so we're
all familiar with seeing the the kinds
of machines that are used to harvest
fibrous hem what kind of you know
mechanizations can you use for
harvesting you know when you want to
preserve the flowers it's all done by
hand and the only mechanized part is the
trimmer that is correct yeah and it's
what we tell clients is a charity there
are a number of different options for
your finished product at the end of the
season you know you can you can flash
dry it and the terpenes will vaporize
and it's it's basically only useful for
isolate there is a market for that it's
although it's a lower value then the the
next best option is something like a low
temperature hop kiln that's operating
anywhere between 80 to 90 degrees and
just moving a tremendous amount of air
just getting that air movement to dry
those products retain a lot of the
heavier terpenes you lose your monitor
pians
but you still end up with a nice
synergistic potential medical product
that would be turned into oil that the
highest value is if you you treat it
just like a high-grade THC plant you
hang dry it slowly cure it and then you
know we went with the the mechanical
route on on on trimming just because the
cost of hand trimming would have been
prohibitive and not physically possible
to be perfectly honest with the quantity
that we were dealing with and also
probably not necessary honestly you know
hand trimming is certainly something
that changes the bag appeal but the at
at this point the audience that you were
serving were cigarette smokers in in
Switzerland which is certainly a
different crew than West Coast cannabis
connoisseurs exactly exactly yeah it was
it was I've never been a big fan of
machine trim but it did a decent job so
so um I gotta ask how did how did you
get all these pallets and and if you can
tell me how many pallets of these four
drums were there and how did you get
them Switzerland honestly I don't even
remember how many there were
that's a blur but there were a lot that
left our facility like like 100 though
right uh not not that many not yeah I
have no way to translate how 37 acres
into pallets right yeah yeah and in
different products as well so with the
with the pallets we would basically just
we had a shipping company that would
arrive and take the pallets directly to
the Portland Airport and they would they
would fly out to Zurich with a direct
flight the the company that was
purchasing it from us would take
possession at the Portland terminal so
it was no longer ours they were in legal
possession of it
so the off it went the
that that's that's one way of doing it
we also have these very large bags are
used for grass grass seed other other
seed crops grains called super sacks and
those can hold about anywhere between
250 to 300 pounds of trim material all
at one time and and they're basically
just a pallets worth of material that's
kind of the industry standard in terms
of shipping large quantities of material
to processors domestically but that's
that's also now going international as
well so this last question before we go
to break I hope that you don't deem it
unfair but I'm gonna set it up properly
but it's it could be a hard question and
I know you to be a very patient centric
dude both you and your brother have got
big hearts you you work with patients
you give advice to people for CBD you
like them to have strong
endocannabinoids systems and you are
very invested in your local cannabis
scene so you're you're the kind of
people that we want to see succeed and
when I visited the farm I had all these
visions of you know low price to
cannabis getting into the hands of
patients and I was excited for that and
yet somehow I was also excited for you
that you got this amazing buyer in
Switzerland and that was cool but all
this CBD was now leaving the United
States and yeah you had to have been
torn about that and I'd love to hear
about your decision yeah very very much
so you know the the largest influencer
of that was the fact that you know we
have this this Oregon market that we
could have sold directly into had it not
been prohibited by state law at the time
you could not sell cannabinoids or flour
product into the adult use market if it
was derived from industrial hemp and
that was just the strange quirk in in
the Department of Justice in the state
of Oregon in their interpretation of the
existing law it took us a whole year to
get that change we just are
our lobbying group for industrial have
farmers just got that passed in the last
legislative session in March so we hope
to be able to to sell products not just
CBD but also CVG and other novel
cannabinoids this weed is we're able to
isolate them into the Oregon market
first excellent but yes very bittersweet
yeah totally both sides of that too to
see all the potential and then realize
that it wasn't actually gonna make it
into local patience yeah bittersweet
well said alright let's go ahead and
take our second short break you are
listening to shaping fire my guest this
week is Seth Crawford of Oregon CBD
using pesticides when growing cannabis
has been common for a long time nowadays
though we know better we know that most
pesticides formulated for food crops
have never been tested for use with
cannabis they've been tested to be eaten
in tiny doses they have not been tested
to be inhaled and especially not
concentrated into a cannabis oil
chemical residues from pesticides are
not healthy for anyone but they are
especially dangerous for patients for
commercial cannabis growers this has
become very impactful cannabis
enthusiasts and patients have gotten
educated enough that they avoid growers
who used pesticides not only that but
states across the country have begun
making pesticide testing mandatory on
all licensed cannabis crops the time has
come to find a better way to fight
garden pests than covering your cannabis
and chemicals and there is a better way
let some good bugs fight your bad bugs
beneficial insects and predatory mites
have come a long way since we are buying
ladybugs online and putting them in the
grow room and just hoping for the best
natural enemies biocontrol can help you
solve pest issues without using
chemicals natural enemies founder shane
young learned best practices from
working in the ornamental plant industry
and has fine-tuned those strategies
specifically for large cannabis crops
shane works with commercial cannabis
clients across the country to ensure
that they keep their crop safe and pest
free without the use of chemicals
natural enemies has proven solutions for
spider mites athens thrips Russert mites
broad
nights sure flies white fly and others
too you can rely on natural enemies for
expertise and excellent service for more
information go to shaping feiyr.com
forward slash natural enemies or simply
click on their banner in this week's
newsletter if you own a cannabis company
you know that finding good business
partners vendors and allies is an
essential part of your role and building
your business in a new industry like
cannabis doesn't always make that easy
Canha khan is coming to Boston in
Detroit this summer and the halls will
be filled with every kind of ally you
need for a cannabis company technology
horticulture packaging marketing legal
Human Resources and media everything you
need for your business will be there and
your customers will be there too because
canikin is a premier cannabis business
and networking event with nationally
recognized speakers and the opportunity
to have serious conversations with your
business peers and investors reserving
yourself a boot that can ikonn can
unlock a lot of doors for you not only
do you get to network with all the
people who pass your booth but it is not
uncommon for canna con vendors to do a
million dollars in business during the
event canna con seattle e event in
february sold out well in advance so
reserve your booths now for detroit June
1st and 2nd and Boston July 27th and
28th attendee tickets are still
available for both events whether you
reserve a booth or attend just for a day
do not miss the opportunity to become a
serious player in your market visit
cannikin org for tickets booth
reservations and more information that's
Kanak on.org
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire I'm your host Shango Llosa
our guest this week is Seth Crawford
co-founder of Oregon's CBD so in this
last section we're going to talk a
little bit about legality and a lot
about the future of CBD derived hemp but
first of all I want to hit on the the
Reggie Godinho interview that we had
last week all about intellectual
property and cultivars because I know
that it excited you and engaged you in a
lot of very important ways
so I want to give you the floor so that
you can kind of speak to the topic last
week of of protecting these important
cultivars that you are developing yeah
it was an excellent interview I'd really
appreciate you just making the time and
and regi for making the time to have
that conversation I think it's an
incredibly important moment in time for
the entire cannabis industry having
moved from you know a system where each
individual breeder was doing their own
thing and generally in small small ways
but others doing it in larger ways
having having a new legal environment in
place as I think changed the the
calculations for a lot of people one of
the things that we have done is
basically what what Reggie was
advocating for and that is to
preemptively file patents to protect the
breeding technology breeding approach
that we use to create a lot of our
varieties at the end of the day whether
or not the US Patent Office will will
grant that is you know obviously
something that we're gonna have we're
going to do our best to make that happen
the way that we end up using it however
is a lot of people are concerned about
individuals or corporations holding
these patents and then excluding wide
swaths of certain types of plants or
chemo types or chirping profiles from
the general public that's something that
we're very concerned with as well it's
obviously not something that we would be
doing but you know it raises this this
this this really complicated issue for
people who are investing a significant
amount of time and energy and and money
into the development of unique cultivars
where chemo types or even just potential
breeding strategies like like we're
doing there needs to be some sort of way
to stop those bigger companies you know
the the one that's always raised is
Monsanto and soon to be called Monsanto
bear Bayer Monsanto or whatever but you
know two and a half billion dollars in
research every single year is a
substantial amount and that's not
something that we can compete with so
it's I think a lot
the folks that are sort of out in front
on this are are preemptively
trying to protect the work that they're
doing and there are others who are
trying to make sure that all of the
previous work is is accounted for it's
out in the public domain the interesting
interesting times to say the least but
it's it's it's something that I think
that a lot as Reggie Highline I think
cultivators and breeders would be very
wise to look into the potential for for
doing stuff like that yeah and you know
you know competing with their 2.6
billion dollar R&amp;D budget is only the
half of it right because their legal
budget is insane as well and you know
they may be able to develop the same
things as smaller cultivators are are
working on with that kind of R&amp;D budget
but also trying to defend your you know
chemo virus or cultivars or techniques
against somebody like Bayer Monsanto is
that that's its own problem that doesn't
even take place in the field that
happens in the courtroom and in briefs
and is just as ugly let's talk for a
second about one of your most valuable
strains I mean you've your whole line is
is is unique for their own reasons but
but I know that you are excited as well
as a lot of patients I know are excited
about your CVG strain so what would want
to talk a little bit about that and and
your hopes of protecting that so that
you can share it yeah it's first of all
CBD is phenomenal it's incredible in in
terms of its pain relief muscle spasms
spasticity as a topical it's great for
eczema and psoriasis it's it's one of
those compounds that you know once
you've tried it it it's it's kind of
mind-bending - to say the least that
it's uh it's just been tucked away for
so long inside of the cannabis genome
and it's now just just popping up so
we're really excited to be able to to
bring that to to the table for farmers
in 2019 the at this point it's not just
one variety I think we're at
there's between seven and nine
individual lines that we're working on
that have very different approaches and
different practical applications whether
it's for the production of field
production with harvests using combines
or terpene rich varieties that will be
hand harvested in the same way that a
lot of the the finest flowers are still
grown for THC production a number of
different options different flavors and
different characteristics we have some
that are a hundred to one
CBG to THC we have other varieties that
we've now developed that are over 300 to
CBG to THC which means that you can do
an oil extraction basic rough oil
extraction and still be below the point
3 percent THC limitation at the federal
level definitely some game-changing
things that are that are coming out and
will be available to farmers for for
2019 and you know CB G's since since
people don't spend a lot of time using
it on its own it doesn't have as much of
a rep as other parts of the plant and
and certainly when you come across CB g
it's not going to be in a whole plant
right most of the time it's it's because
it's extracted out but but the proof was
in the pudding when we visited your farm
in and and we we tried a dab of your CB
g rich strain and and we left your
sampling booth um you know I I thought I
know at first I didn't think i fel
anything and then I realized I was in a
really good mood and kind of felt like I
was walking on clouds but my associate I
brought with me
he's got lifelong pain and on that
particular day his leg was all flared up
and and he was uncomfortable in my car
and it was a drag and we got back out to
my car and we're driving away and he
like nudges me he's like dude I don't
hurt and my legs fine and I'm all like
I'm like oh that's nice he's like no you
don't understand and so that's when we
first started talking about how you know
we talked about CBD being 20 to one all
the time and how nice it is to be able
to get cannabidiol into folks with with
you know a low amount just trace amounts
of THC especially kids who don't want
be lethargic at school you know through
their parents of course but but with the
CBG you know you know 100 to 1 CVG and
that is an you know a powerful pain
reliever this opens up like a whole new
field of cannabis clinical medicine not
that they're gonna be giving them I mean
to be perfectly blunt I think that
America would be a better place I think
every every place in the world would be
better off if every adult had a CBG pen
a vape pen in their pocket like you
described it's it's not psychoactive but
it's also I describe it as being a
profound experience in the sense that it
provides a significant amount of mental
clarity if you are anxious or if you've
had too much caffeine or you know you're
just you're you're tense
it is a non psychoactive relaxer I mean
it just it calms people down in addition
to having all of those different pain
relieving properties it's I don't want
to you know you don't never want to be
making proclamations that are a little
bit of a reach but I do think that for a
lot of people who suffer from chronic
pain this is one of those amazing
substances that will help them not take
opiates and the more the more
cannabinoids that we have at our
disposal to be able to deal with things
like opiates the better off we're all
going to be but we are really looking
forward to seeing thousands of acres of
this in production and in the coming
years and so if you've got seed for
these strains coming out next year I
take it that you are following Reggie
gaudino strategy and defensively
patenting it in advance yeah we are it
the reason that we're not releasing it
to farm Rizzo is the for the same reason
that the varieties that you saw in the
field last year are the seed the test
crop for what farmers are growing this
season we do field trials to make sure
that we're doing accurate progeny
testing so that we can make the best
seed possible for farmers I don't know
of any other companies that do that
outside of you know
general agriculture and seed production
for other crops we basically just tried
to Mir that you know we've we've taken
our success and built a genomics lab
we're doing in-house testing we do these
these large-scale field trials to make
sure that the product that goes out is
going to perform exactly the way that we
say it is because we a know it really
well and B are telling the truth based
on on legitimate field applications of
the product so that's that's the goal
this season this summer is we're growing
out all of these different new creations
and finding out which one's work and
which ones don't
from a farming perspective right on yeah
cuz a lot of these seeds there's a big
difference between growing 25 plants in
your yard versus the growing 25 acres
agriculture is a whole different animal
and and to that point you know you need
a lot of seeds to be able to grow that
many plants and from what I saw when
when you had your announcements of seed
sales this year you had way more people
interested than you had seeds people
were showing up to your seed sale days
and essentially you know buying out your
whole run on that day and then and then
you know I've been watching your posts
about your new your seed manufacturing
structures so can you just give me a
little bit idea of how much you've
chosen to scale up and and if you think
that you're going to meet demand this
year I think we'll be able to meet well
that's probably a stretch I think we're
gonna be able to meet the demand for
this season but the crazy part is is
that people come out of the woodwork
between now and May first and and large
orders are definitely happening we went
from being able to produce you know
basically about 5 million seeds per year
to being able to produce 50 million per
year and this summer we're going to be
scaling out we have 500 lights between
our three main production facilities
we're scaling that up to 2,000 lights so
that we can produce every year we'll be
able to produce about a hundred million
so we're doing everything that we can to
make sure that this is a viable
large-scale agricultural crop for as
many farmers as we can possibly get into
into the farming it's weird too because
right that that's just producing those
seeds is like running an entirely
separate company I mean you're selling
seeds you've got all these seeds in your
R&amp;D fields your your your machine
trimming it and sending it to
Switzerland and oh yeah we've got these
you know four or five locations with 200
lights
producing like this this epic volume of
seeds that it's in a nut self sounds
like a hassle you do it all indoors
right so as you were complaining about
your neighbor that pollinated the whole
valley you and instead are doing it in
very tightly controlled areas with you
know vacuums that pull in inside and
everything right so that so that it's a
it's a very sealed up manufacturing
process exactly exactly you know the
nice part about what we're doing is you
know growing inside is the only way to
really ensure that that you're going to
have a quality product that's not
contaminated and you know we've talked
about this before but you know one one
male one legitimate male one pollen
grain from a male plant would destroy a
crop and we would have to to basically
get rid of get rid of all of those seeds
and we do that quality is the of the
utmost concern for us if if a farmer
ends up with one plant in their entire
field that is sampled by the Department
of Agriculture that has if it's a type 2
plant if it's a one to one that one
plant would make them fail their
compliance test so we we do everything
in our power to make the production side
sealed clean and and and not not
worrying about pollen contamination we
also flower in the in the winter that's
when we're making all of our seeds so
that we can miss that the large
potential plumes of outdoor pollen just
in case it's going on during the regular
harvest season but even after all of
that we still grow out you know these
test batches
do our PCR screen to make sure that
there are no y chromosomes in our gene
pool so when when farmers are getting
seed from us they can they can
reasonably assume that they're going to
perform as as we've claimed and we're
trying to back that up with it with
basically 21st 21st century science
being brought to bear on this ancient
awesome agricultural crop that we've all
been growing for generations so what do
you what do you see as being you know
looking forward to this summer what do
you see as being some of the the
interesting hot points like you know
last last summer you were super shocked
in a good way because you you didn't get
pollinated with somebody else's seeds
and therefore instead of having CBD rich
flour for extraction you actually had
CBD flower that was sensimilla without
seeds and so it was much more valuable
than you had planned
but it created a kink in your business
model what do you see as being potential
changes that could happen either for
your business model for the industry in
general
this coming summer to be determined you
really given up on forecasting it's just
it changes so dramatically and so
radically every season I know that for
us and for our company we've gone
through tremendous growth in the last in
the last year and we are trying to
devote ourselves fully to the process of
creating seed and doing good field
trials and I don't think that we're
going to be doing trim flower again this
season it was awesome one off last year
and it worked out but for us to be able
to focus on on the breeding and not just
CBG but but all the other minor
cannabinoids that that are basically
coming online is better testing is
emerging that's that's really where our
focus is and being able to create
varieties that will will succeed and
thrive in other areas we're doing a lot
of custom breeding projects right now
for say tropical areas different totally
different environments that we're not
accustomed to and we don't have
we don't necessarily have access to in
the summer for us to grow here so we've
had to build out climate-controlled
environments to replicate those those
you know low very high levels of
humidity very warm you know basically
try trying to do controlled experiments
to develop varieties that will work in
other other areas as well right on well
that's all really inspiring and and all
of us from from patients to product
manufacturers to entrepreneurs to
retailers we are all looking for your
success so that you can bring a wider
array of canvas products to the market
so keep on the good fight brother oh
thank you so much right on well thank
you too for being on the show Seth and
and send our best to your brother Eric
to who even though he wasn't with us
today is a big part of why Oregon Seabee
seeds is the success and and we look
forward to talking to you again at the
end of the season to find out one what
unexpected realities came across your
plate this year well thanks so much for
having me I really appreciate being here
you can reach Seth Crawford via his
website at oregon CBD seeds com and you
know even if you don't necessarily want
to reach out to talk to Seth I recommend
you go to the website just to enjoy the
reading of of their catalogue of seeds
if you're a nerd for this kind of thing
just reading the product descriptions
will cause you a lot of joy and also
it's fun to follow their instagram at
oregon CBD you can find more episodes of
the shaping fire podcast and subscribe
to the show at shaping fire calm and on
apple itunes stitcher and google play if
you enjoyed the show we'd really
appreciate it if you'd leave a positive
review of the podcast wherever you
download your review will help others
find the show so they can enjoy it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the weekly newsletter for
insights into the latest cannabis news
and product reviews on the shaping fire
website you will also find transcripts
of today's podcast as well for
information on me and where i'll be
speaking you can check out Shango
lowes.com
does your company want to reach our
national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hotspot at shaping
feiyr.com
to find out how thanks for listening to
shaping fire I've been your host Shango
lows
[Music]