[Music]
there is no doubt that after sheer
curiosity the most common reason people
become interested in cannabis is pain
pain is terrible
it interrupts our lives occupies our
minds and emotions and becomes the boss
of everything pain takes the last of our
will to do things limits our activities
and is emotionally crushing as it
repeats incessantly that things are out
of our control
and that we are living in a broken body
all the drugs commonly prescribed by
Western doctors offer little help cost a
great deal and in the end often leave us
craving and addicted physically which
just adds to our feeling of
powerlessness it doesn't matter if you
have carpal tunnel a broken back an
incurable disease are just too sore from
working in the garden
pain limits us and weighs on us
emotionally but prior to Prohibition the
American pharmacopoeia was filled with
uses for cannabis to fight a variety of
pain humans have been using cannabis for
pain and discomfort for generations and
it worked but now that prohibition is
unraveling we have access to cannabis
medicine like never before
it is incredibly safe far safer than
prescriptions and can be grown and
prepared at home if you want to learn
about cannabis health business and
technique efficiently and with good
cheer I encourage you to subscribe to
our newsletter will send you new podcast
episodes as they come out delivered
right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week and
videos - don't rely on social media to
let you know when a new episode is
published sign up for the updates - make
sure you don't miss an episode also we
give away very cool prizes to folks who
are sign up to receive the newsletter
there's nothing else you need to do to
win except receive that newsletter so go
to shaping feiyr.com to sign up for the
newsletter and be entered into this
month's and all future in newsletter
prize drawings if your company budgeted
thousands of dollars for cannabis can
mentions in 2020 which are all canceled
now I invite you to consider moving your
marketing investment to shaping fire for
only a fraction of what it would cost
you to attend just one convention you
can advertise for nearly a year on
shaping fire it has been a busy few
weeks as other companies have reached
out to shaping fire because their whole
year of customer outreach events were
just canceled and they are scrambling
for new ways to reach their customers
the audience for shaping fire is made up
of curious cannabis enthusiasts
entrepreneurs and home growers and you
can reach them for less than the price
of a postcard each email hotspot at
shaping fire calm to find out more you
are listening to shaping fire and I'm
your host
Shango lows today my guest is cannabis
pharmacologist a dear a doctor Rea PhD
is a National Institutes of Health
funded neuroscientist who has been
studying cannabis opioids and their
interaction for her entire career she
has a strong publication record in
chronic pain addiction and harm
reduction dr. Rey is currently an
assistant scientist at Legacy Research
Institute in Portland Oregon and holds a
joint faculty appointment at Washington
State University she is also co-founder
of smart cannabis a data-driven cannabis
consultancy focused on connecting all
humans with the best cannabis for their
needs they also produce one of America's
most respected cannabis competitions and
education events the cultivation classic
in Portland Oregon today we're going to
talk about transitioning from using
opioids to cannabis for treating pain
well welcome to the show 80 Thank You
Shango it's so great to be here I really
appreciate you sharing some of your
valuable time with us I know that even
during a pandemic you are busy busy busy
so thank you so much for joining us you
bet
so let's get right into it you know
since we're going to be talking a lot
about how opiates and cannabis moderate
the experience of pain I think we should
probably get all on the same page about
what pain
is and how we experience it biologically
so so let's start with that what's going
on physically in the brain that senses
pain sure pain is a very useful
phenomenon it is a feedback system that
our body uses to keep us alive if we
didn't have pain we wouldn't know that
we were encountering things in our
environment that are potentially
hazardous to our tissue into our lives
so a great example of this is people who
have a congenital insensitivity to pain
so that is you know they can walk over
coals and they can break their arm and
they can you know burn their hands and
have absolutely no idea and these
individuals end up living very short
lives because we actually need that
feedback from our environment to protect
our tissue in our lives so pain is the
phenomenon where our central nervous
system our brain registers noxious
information from our environment now
that's all well and good but there are a
lot of conditions under which that
system goes haywire so for instance you
know if you have an individual with an
amputee that individual can often end up
developing phantom limb pain that is
they have pain in the absence of the
biological thing that the pain is trying
to protect so that example tells us that
there's something more than just you
have nerves out in your fingertips and
in your arms and in your skin which are
transferring information about the
environment into the spinal cord and
that signal is being sent up to the
brain and the brain is putting together
a picture of what the environment is
like so it's more complex than you know
merely a sensory system that is
integrating information inside of our
brain the brain really has a powerful
role in constructing what the
environment and what the body is going
through so pain although it is a useful
thing
it also can really go haywire and there
a lot of those things that go wrong
happen at the level of the brain not
necessarily at the level of the tissue
that phantom limb example that you gave
I find extraordinarily interesting it
has been explained to me before that
that pain is it takes place in the brain
and you know I normally find that to be
kind of a semantic difference that's not
incredibly helpful to patients but but
it is very interesting when talking
about secession of pain with opiates and
cannabis and yet occasionally I'll come
across a healthcare worker who says no
describing that pain is in the brain is
very helpful to for patients because it
allows them to have an understanding
that they can manage their pain with
thought and perspective and with drugs
instead of they are a victim to their
hip or whatever right really complex
thing it really is and you're absolutely
true that pain does take place in the
brain and we have you know a whole
network of you know brain structures
that are involved in constructing that
picture for us and you know when I was
our early postdoc my first year as a
postdoc in Sydney I went to a talk that
was given by a number of folks who were
involved in clinical pain work and at
the time Australia was really cutting
edge in their view of pain because they
actually gave chronic pain its own
disease category like pain is a disease
chronic pain is a disease and that still
doesn't really have you know chronic
pain doesn't have that kind of
recognition here in North America and so
I'm at this talk as you know budding
pharmacologist and physiologist you know
my job was to measure neurotransmitter
release that was being released from
neurons and brain slices hard hard core
physiology and pharmacology you know
drugs in
acting with the brain receptors and then
you know change is happening in neuron
activity and I'm watching this talk and
I'm seeing these patients and I'm
hearing them describe their lives and
how they're able to have these
absolutely debilitating injuries and yet
they wake up every day and they say yeah
you know my pains at about an eighth
today you know sitting here in front of
you in this chair and you're like why
how how can you be physically
registering so much bodily sensation and
yet totally nonplussed just completely
fine with it and you know from from this
talk I really began to understand that
the cognitive component of coping with
pain walking with pain living beside
pain that ability resides wholly in our
brain that is totally within our control
and it really is you know a testament to
the the power of our thought the power
of our cognition and our attention what
we pay attention to grows and magnifies
and it's not that you necessarily turn
your attention away from the pain
although you know that is one coping
strategy there it's more shifting your
your attention to something else so you
know and as a pharmacologist I'm like
well what the heck am i doing you know
what is my better pain therapies make
better drugs and and you know all we
need is is meditation and coping
strategies and cognitive behavioral
therapy and biofeedback what okay I quit
so you're absolutely right you know pain
lives in the brain and we have an
enormous amount of power and control
over it if we can learn the tools to
harness it you know we'll talk a lot
more about cannabis as a distracting
later on but I want to double down on
your experience with the the mental the
powerful mental capabilities of pain
patients you know I'm very grateful that
I haven't had a lot of pain in my
except when I had an injury and rotated
my l5 and was in like a hysterical
amount of pain more than I'd ever been
in my life where I was just like
squirming on the doctor's table because
my mind was was just all I was all
bright and when I meet patients through
you know teaching about canvas medicine
and traveling forward and everything and
and I meet these folks and and like you
said they you know they're having an
eight day but they are presenting
themselves as calm cool and collected at
the talk or whatever and then you know
we get together kind of like on the side
and we sit next to each other and we
talk and and I'm trying to understand
the nature of their pain so I can make
some sort of recommendation to them
because that's what they're there for
and the more we talk about it
it brings them mentally away from their
I don't know let's say meditative life
where they're just they're focusing on
the doing nosov life and intentionally
distracting themselves from the pain but
as they describe it more in detail you
can see the the defense's coming down
and you know very often by the time
we're done understanding the nature of
their pain they are shaking and in tears
and the only thing that's changed is
that part of us doing you know what we
were there to do was they needed to let
down their guard and be vulnerable for a
moment and when they let down their
guard I got to truly see the pain
expressed through them and you know it's
very difficult as somebody who's trying
to help somebody to not get like like
sucked in to that experience of
compassion with them and start crying -
right I got to tell you working with
pain patients and getting to know them
and being one for a while and in a small
way really has given me a huge respect
for people who deal with chronic pain
every day ABB's
there's a couple of things in there that
I want to unpack one of which is that
attention right so when you're when
you're paying attention and you're
really digging in and looking at it and
describing it and putting words to it
I'm gonna talk about that and then I
also let's let's start there so in that
attention I worked with a fibromyalgia
patient once who told me you know I
noticed that on my worst pain days those
were the days I was taking my opioids
and I I couldn't tell if you know I was
taking the opioids because it was my
worst pain day or if my pain was worse
because I was spending so much time
thinking about should I take a half a
pill or should I take a whole pill today
so just the body scan the physical body
scan of looking for the pain that's what
makes the pain real right so she was
going through her process of waking up
in the morning and doing her body scan
and just by paying attention to it
that's what fed the need for her pain
relievers gosh so that makes total sense
and it's so sad to doing that
this morning right waking up and going
oh boy is it gonna be today and and
really going in and looking for it and
digging into those things you know and
if you're over 35 you can you can find
that within your body if you really want
to there's some spot that ails all of us
cuz you know that's what it's like to
have a body but the other component that
you talk about is that emotional
component of pain so my colleagues and I
Wash U and st. Louis we put out a paper
in the journal neuron last year and it
was in mice and and some of it was in
rats but what we demonstrated is that
the physical the bodily sensation of
pain and the emotional or affective
component of pain are inseparable they
are two symptoms of the same
that are being driven by this this
little network in the brain so you know
we have been going about treating pain
from the bodily you know sensation of it
for many decades you know that's the
whole reason that opioids exists as
you've been trying to anesthetize the
physical sensations of pain with this
drug but our work demonstrates that you
can't just ignore the emotional
component of pain because it is
literally wrapped up in the exact same
brain areas and the exact same
mechanisms that are happening with the
bodily sensations of pain and we see
this you know like roughly 80 plus
percent of patients with chronic pain
also experience some kind of mood
disorder like anxiety depression or both
so it's no surprise that you know people
who are in chronic pain also have
depression because that is literally the
manifestation of chronic pain it has
both a bodily component and an emotional
component so whatever we do to treat
pain chronic pain we have to think of
the organism holistically we have to
think of the emotional well-being as
well as the physical well-being of the
body well I really like the fact that
you are you focus so much on the
vocabulary of pain as well and it's it's
interesting people who are new to their
pain they often struggle to describe it
because you know luckily up to this
point in their life they haven't had to
describe it
whereas people who have had lifelong
pain you know they can they can describe
it on a number chart and they've got all
these different flavors of it it's like
it's they've got like a Crayola box
you know descriptors so so let's let's
talk about that for a moment because so
often people who are coming to cannabis
for pain one of the challenges that they
have is delineating between the types of
pain either for themselves like in their
pain Journal or to the doctor and we
know that there are different types of
pain right there's that there
a big difference between the the sharp
and stabby pain from a fresh fractured
fracture versus the kind of like
mind-boggling everywhere experience when
you're having a flare-up of rheumatoid
arthritis right so so I don't I don't
actually know anything about this part
of the process what do you use as a as I
guess a range of how to describe pain
well you know you're right in that no
one's pain is is like anyone else's
right so it seems important to think
about like is this throbbing is it
stabbing and in the clinic those kinds
of things are really useful from a
diagnosis perspective because you can
say AHA this is these kinds of
descriptors would indicate an
inflammatory condition which means we
need to treat it in this way versus oh
those kinds of district descriptors
indicate some kind of neuropathy so some
kind of damage to the nerves or some
kind of problem with the transmission of
the nerve signals so so those kinds of
pain are better treated with these
modalities so that kind of vocabulary is
really important in the clinic for
diagnosing a path forward for treatment
however on the other hand you know I
tend to make the argument that you know
once you've gotten past that initial you
know diagnosis stage and you know what
kind of pain you're dealing with you
know then it doesn't really matter
because it's all subjective it's all
only happening to you inside of your own
brain from your perspective and no one's
pain is similar you know you can have
two individuals who have the exact same
injury like a rib fracture right same
rib same spot and yet their descriptions
of the pain how much the pain bothers
them how that pain interferes with their
life it's all totally different and so
yes on the one hand
being able to have words for your
experience is really helpful and it's
also when you're in a community setting
and you're you're getting support from
other people who have the same kind of
ailment that you do it's really
validating to hear oh yes that's exactly
what I feel and it's so comforting to
know that another human being feels what
I feel but on the other hand it's
totally subjective and irrelevant
because all that matters is how you feel
and so if you're feeling bad in any way
whatever those bad words are then then
that's a starting point for how can we
start feeling better how can we shift
the attention the conversation the
treatment the therapy your day how can
we shift all of that so that whatever
descriptors you're using you start to
feel better let's follow up on that
because it is so common your I like your
example of the the same disc dislocated
rib in the same place and two people
will have different experiences of pain
it is so incredibly common that the
person who's experiencing more pain
whereas other people experience less
pain are written off as being a wuss
like they can't handle it later they're
immature they're being a baby about it
and I always think that invalidating
somebody else's pain is is not
legitimate and and certainly there are
situations where we want to encourage
someone to not focus on their pain which
is a different thing but but in
validating a patient having their pain
invalidated by friends family or even a
health practitioner is just wrong and I
just want to hear what you have to say
about that I mean to me like the perfect
example is like the hysterical woman
right how many hundreds of years you
know women do experience more chronic
pain and women have more you know
painful things that are associated with
childbirth and reproduction hormonal
imbalance and for many hundreds of years
that way
completely invalidated and we were seen
as the weaker sex and you know we were
shunned by you know psychotherapists and
you know the the it's that that to me is
like the most extreme extreme example of
totally invalidating someone else's
experience and I feel very grateful that
now we live in a time where you know we
are slowly being able to recognize that
each individual's reality has as much
value as anyone else's reality you know
I I'm really inspired by like my
undergrad you know students who come
through the laboratory and these are
like privileged white kids who go to a
private school and yet at the same time
they go oh I'm sorry I can't talk about
that that's a trigger for me you know
and everyone respects that like wow like
this is a next evolution in humanity
we're talking about here so so I I'm
really encouraged by you know this idea
that we're all coming to accept that if
this is real for you then it's real for
you right on so I imagine that you know
you know you know in a paint in a
chronic pain textbook in the school
there's a chapter on the different types
of pain and you know if there's there's
a there's a section on inflammation and
there's a section on nerve damage and
you know you study chronic pain
intensely and for years and so will you
give us a general understanding of the
different categories of chronic pain yes
certainly for me they fall into three
big buckets which to of what you
mentioned already you know the
inflammatory pain the neuropathic pain
so that is you know some kind of damage
or dysfunction in the nervous system
that is causing pain and then we have
this other weird one which is like this
mysterious you know sort of central pain
something like fibromyalgia where you
can't really pin down exactly what's
going wrong with any particular part of
the physical biology of the organism and
yet the organism is still reporting
that they're in severe pain so that
they're those are the three broad
categories that inflammatory the
neuropathic and then the centralized
pain and there there can be a lot of
transition from either inflammatory pain
to central pain or neuropathic pain to
central pain you know for instance where
you have an injury that totally resolves
you know there's some kind of you know
car accident or work-related injury the
injury is totally resolved and yet the
brain for potentially the rest of its
life still keeps registering some kind
of discomfort so there can be a
transition from one of those two types
to centralized pain there is also there
tends to be an inflammatory component to
even neuropathic pain especially in the
early days of the development of
neuropathic pain so for instance
chemotherapy induced neuropathy so
people who often survive cancer will you
know though beat their cancer but
they'll be stuck with this neuropathic
pain that was induced by the
chemotherapeutic drugs attacking the
central nervous system or nervous system
so when I say peripheral that's
everything outside of the brain and
spinal cord and central nervous system
is the brain and spinal cord itself so
you know chemo drugs will attack the
nerves throughout the body and leave the
cancer survivor' with this lifelong pain
but in the very early days of the
development of chemotherapy induced
neuropathy there is an inflammatory
component right those chemotherapeutic
drugs pull in the brain's immune system
or I'm sorry the body's immune system in
all of our processes that we have for
fighting off pathogens and the it
recruits our inflammatory processes to
start the damage to the nerves so
although yes you can sort of put things
roughly into these buckets of
inflammatory pain where you have all of
these you know the the body recruits
certain molecules to draw blood and draw
attention to you know some in
dating process or pathogen you get
swelling you know you know edema redness
soreness there's more fluid and joints
for instance so there's all of those
like that's a very molecular process
where there's just a whole lot of like
molecules you know flying around going
crazy doing their jobs hustling and
bustling to try and keep this organism
alive to the extent that it is you know
somewhat maladaptive you know we have so
much of the body trying to protect
itself that it is actually you know
really painful for the person who has
the body so you know that although you
can put you know in inflammation in its
own bucket there is largely an implement
and inflammatory component to
neuropathic pain and then either one of
those things can develop into a central
pain once the inflammation has gone away
once the nerve has totally regenerated
or you know whatever other neuropathic
thing might have happened alright good
so I'm gonna let's change directions a
little bit now that we have established
you know what what playing field we are
on with pain and that pain is
experienced in the brain let's talk
about opioids themselves and so we're
not gonna spend a whole lot of time
talking about the you know the
pharmacology of opioids because that's
that's not really what we're about I
think everybody who's here and listening
has already made the decision that that
they already want to move away from from
opioids so however if we're talking
about replacing opioids with cannabis we
certainly need to have an understanding
of what opioids do what their method of
action is so that later on in the show
we can compare that to cannabis so would
you give us an understanding of what
opioids are doing and why there is a
belief that that decreases pain yeah you
bet
you know I think that you're right
you know a lot of your listeners are
here and a lot of Americans and
Canadians and people all over the world
are interested in cannabis because it is
so obvious that you know opioids are
nasty drugs and that is true
you know we clearly have a huge overdose
epidemic on our hands however their
opioids are really good drugs under very
few conditions you know like the whole
reason they exist is because they are
profoundly good at turning off the
bodily sensations of pain they're
profoundly good it's sort of you know
somewhat anesthetizing the the body and
and not allowing it to experience the
physical you know sensations of pain so
they are really good at that because
they act in the brain itself to shut off
the sensations of pain that are coming
in through the spinal cord so if you can
imagine all of your nerves are like
little tiny highways of information and
all those highways are headed in one
direction and that is into the spinal
cord and that spinal cord it becomes
like this central hub like that's the
the main highway and all of the
information coming through those tiny
little you know arteries are coming
through this central highway of
information and then you know going into
the headquarters which is the brain and
so opioids shut off the sensation of
pain at the headquarters and so my
academic work has always been focused on
one particular brain area called the
periaqueductal gray and this really is
the brain's pain headquarters because it
is if you if you put an opioid directly
into the periaqueductal gray or the PA G
if you put an opioid there you shut off
pain throughout the entire body and if
you put opioids everywhere else but you
block them only in this brain area then
you don't get any pain relief at all and
so we know that this is a critical
component in you
the controlling or modulating the
sensation of pain throughout the entire
organism this tiny little brain area
it's fascinating what's really
interesting about this brain area also
is that it's where the body or the brain
develops tolerance to opioids as well so
again if you repeatedly give the brain
you know just this Phe region if you
repeatedly give it opioids it will
develop tolerance but if you block
opioids here but continue to give the
whole rest of the body opioids the
organism never develops tolerance so
this is a really critical brain region
and we'll talk more about it you know
when we get to the cannabinoid control
of our pain but opioids bind to
receptors in this brain region so you
can think of it as a lock and a key so
these locks these receptors are studying
the outside of our neurons so just
little padlocks you know waiting for
their keys to come floating by and those
keys the drugs the opioids themselves
come and they float along and they lock
into the binding sites on these proteins
and they turn on certain intracellular
signaling Cascades so these are
molecules that once they become
activated by the binding of the opioids
to these proteins they go off and they
do some other job they control
neurotransmitter release they turn on
genes you know they control other
proteins it's a whole very sophisticated
set of you know intracellular and you
know between cellular communications so
the sum total of all of those like you
know hundreds of thousands of millions
of little you know protein protein
interactions the sum total of that is
the organism not experiencing pain
because it has been shut off at the
level of the brain itself Wow eighty
that was awesome that was that was the
best explanation I have ever heard I I
don't know if you you know I mean I know
you've got a PhD and at some point you
probably had to teach classes you're
probably an awesome
well thank you I really enjoy being in
the classroom but you know I feel like
you know conversations like ours where
we get to talk to the label a person I I
think that's equally important yeah well
did it's a very that explanation was a
very nice balance of of using accurate
scientific let's say like how it
actually works while also using
vocabulary that we're all familiar with
so that you don't sound like a textbook
so that's great so so um so let's use
let's use me for a strawman for a minute
because that your description opioids
actually sound like they'd be really
effective right like like listening to
your description I'm like well hell
maybe these actually work you know am i
is this all this trash I've been talking
about opioids not justified and the
problem is actually more the abuse than
the fact that they don't work but in my
own personal experience and like I said
earlier I haven't had a lot of
experience with pain but but after I had
my ACL surgery after after a skiing
accident they gave me opioids to help
with the pain and I'm like you know as a
psycho not I'm really good I'm gonna get
to try something new you know and so I
used it and and my experience was is it
really did not do anything to help with
the pain but it made me feel like the
pain was maybe down the hallway and so
it kind of distanced me from the pain a
little bit
and I certainly found it to be a bit of
a fun distracted like it was it was a
novel mind state that was interesting
but after after the first day I'm like
you know I I don't really it's not
helping right and and mostly it made me
stupid for everything else I wanted to
do so is my experience typical or is my
experience you know more fringe I think
that it might be a little bit of both
you know when you asked the question
like hey you know edu made this sound
phenomenal and these are really powerful
drugs yes that's true however you have
to keep in mind that the PA G is not the
only place where these opioid receptors
live they live on lots of other brain
structures and they live in lots of
other important places in our bodies for
instance in the brainstem the area
that's like our old evolutionary lizard
brain the thing that keeps us you know
ticking automatically keeps our
breathing going that's that's the area
where you also have opioid receptors and
if they get hit over the head too hard
they will shut down your breathing and
that's how people die so respiratory
depression is you know essentially what
happens in an overdose people's
breathing rate slows down so much that
it stops entirely and that process is
controlled by the brainstem by the same
receptors so the same receptors that are
in your PA G turning off you know pain
for your whole body are also in your
brainstem controlling your breathing
rate and so it's not only those two
areas but you know like you said I
stopped taking these drugs after my ACL
tear because I felt stupid they were
making me dumb and the reason for that
is these receptors are also in your
prefrontal cortex all of your brain
regions that are used for making
decisions and you know like being a
functional human if you turn off all the
brain activity at the level of the
opioid receptor there then of course
you're gonna get some cognitive
impairment and this is something that we
unfortunately don't talk enough about
with the opioids you know like I was
testifying in the State House in
Jefferson City in Missouri one time and
you know one of the chairmen was asking
me well what about all the cognitive
impairment you know that comes from
cannabis and you know like people you
know driving Ojai and all of this stuff
that they were you know worried about
I'm like well no one ever talks about
like how many people in this courtroom
right now took an opioid before they got
in their car and drove 60 miles
get here you know like this this element
of cognitive impairment that you're
talking about is a very real side effect
of opioids so you know opioids would be
great drugs if they only acted on the
descending pain pathway but they have
all of these other unintended
consequences constipation respiratory
depression cognitive impairment
addiction because they're binding to
receptors that are not just in the
brain's pain pathway but they're binding
to the receptors indiscriminantly so you
know especially that last component the
addiction component opioids are better
than any other substance at totally
hijacking the brain regions that are
involved in reward and reinforcement so
those are very fundamental brain
processes where you know if something
activates this circuitry this reward
circuitry
you know the perception at the level of
the organism is ooh that was good I
should do that again
right so that's the reward and the
reinforcement is you know continuing to
engage in that behavior because of the
reward so opioids are particularly good
at hijacking those processes so that the
opioids feel better and over time become
more important than anything else that
activates that system naturally you know
the opioids become more important than
food opioids become more important than
lasting relationships opioids become
more important than you know what your
neighbors think of you opioids become
more important than your job so you know
that's where all of these unintended
consequences happen from pain control is
that you know the opioids aren't just
binding to the brains pain receptors
they're binding to all the receptors
that control all of these other very
important processes well now now you've
like totally unraveled all the all the
impressiveness I had earlier for it
because now it just sounds like a messy
drug totally it is it's a super messy
drug so before we go to our first
commercial break you know people started
turning against opioids or at least
in publicly in the media when people
started getting an understanding of the
the level of abuse in our country and
how quickly people were moving from
pharmaceuticals to street drugs because
they were more affordable and in many
places more accessible since you don't
need a prescription and you know so so
people realize that our country has got
a chronic addiction problem with opiates
but then that seems to have created an
environment where some in the medical
establishment have finally kind of taken
the risk of saying oh yeah and they
don't really work and you know you you
really have to dig for that it's not
usually something that's in the first
paragraph or the first couple paragraphs
with an article it's like down in like
paragraph ten right and they said oh and
by the way you know is it true that that
the medical establishment is starting to
kind of turn away from the efficacy of
opioids I think finally yes you know I
think for a very very very long time
there were you know like us fringe
weirdos you know scientists on the side
saying hey opioids cause hyperalgesia
that means they make pain worse you know
hey opioids actually you know like all
of these other negative side effects
they outweigh the benefits but you know
like our little fringe voices that are
you know clearly based on the evidence
that we've been collecting for a long
time our voices you know don't matter
much in the face of you know really hot
pharmaceutical reps and you know like
lobbyists with a lot of money and
doctors who don't have the time to
devote to you know being skeptical and
digging through the literature
themselves and they're relying on you
know the standard of practice from their
clinic and the recommendations of the
American Pain Society and
relying on these pharmaceutical reps to
give them the best tools to do their job
in the shortest amount of time possible
because they only have an average of 13
minutes with each patient so so yeah I
think for a long time you know we knew
that opioids weren't effective you know
over the long term that their side
effects outweighed their benefits we
knew that there were you know some
fundamental pharmacological problems
with them you know from the basic
neuroscientists knew that you know
oxycodone at the molecular level is no
different than heroin and yet you know
it took a crisis of this magnitude to
wake everybody up to the reality that it
doesn't matter you know if you're using
heroin or if you're using oxycodone the
results are the same your body becomes
physically dependent and you know you
you have to have some other strategy if
you want to have a sustainable and
healthy management of chronic pain over
the long term well that sounds like a
perfect place to end our first set thank
you 80 so we're gonna take a short break
and rewrite be right back you are
listening to shaping fire and my guest
today is cannabis pharmacologist a tea
ray in times like these when so many
cannabis companies are growing their
flower in gigantic warehouses and fields
using synthetic nutrients it is good to
know that there are authentic California
heritage growers using natural farming
techniques and sunshine to cultivate
cannabis flowers for you California has
produced the best cannabis in the world
for generations and the idea that
massively scaled industrial cannabis
production could produce the same
quality as small-batch lovingly
cultivated flowers is just silly moon
time medicinals is located in Humboldt
County on the lush South Fork of the eel
River watershed in the epicenter of the
American cannabis Heartland moon time
medicinals grows under bright California
Sun in greenhouses using only natural
farming techniques like google culture
compost teas whole food fertilisers and
fermented plant juices every part of
their growing process plays its own part
in nature and nothing synthetic is
injected into the process the result is
big beautiful cannabis flowers with
wide-ranging terpene profiles that taste
like grape cannabis should if you live
in California ask your bud tender for
moon time medicinals and visit moon time
medicinals on the web and instagram moon
time medicinals is also available as
part of the Redwood roots family moon
times whole flowers appear in Redwood
roots curated joint packs alongside
other heritage cannabis cultivators like
lady sativa farm Ridgeline farms humble
redwood healing and others moon time
medicinals top-shelf cannabis grown in
harmony with nature there are lots of
good seed makers out there every once in
a while someone becomes legendary the
Mendocino California cannabis breeder
called mandelbrot is one of these people
Mandelbrot was also known as Roz truth
and his cultivars are known as the
foundation for the Emerald triangles
world-famous gasoline scented terpene
profile back in the day when it was
really hard to find quality genetics and
education Mandelbrot was advocating for
organic growing techniques and providing
exceptional seeds that would sell out as
soon as they hit the shelves
Mandelbrot lived too short of life dying
in 2015 but while he was with us he
created several connoisseur level canvas
masterpieces like oil spill the truth
and royal cush no matter if you approach
growing cannabis more as a toker or a
breeder you will find something that
delights you in Mandelbrot selections
because while some strains are better to
grow or to smoke Mandelbrot's creations
excel in every category and that's why
people keep talking about them even
today emerald mountain legacy continues
the rasa truth tradition by preserving
these coveted genetics for future
generations unchanged as they were
originally created in the mid 2000s
emerald mountain legacy also creates
tasteful modern crosses to Mandelbrot's
classics these lines worked by
Mandelbrot's brother Ben furthers their
family's genetics and a spirit that
mammal brought himself would approve of
check out the emerald mountain legacy
Instagram and website to see photos of
these plants and learn more about
Mandelbrot and his infamous strains
emerald mountain legacy seeds are
available online from seed banks and
distributors including labyrinth seed
company the regenerative seed company
and pure sativa emerald mountain legacy
keeping Mandelbrot's legacy alive for 20
years Humboldt seed company has been
family-owned in providing reliable high
yielding seeds originating in Northern
California while the current trend is to
slap one super male into a line of hype
strains Humboldt seed company continues
to breed with precision and care by
doing large sips and back crosses to
emphasize the absolute best traits that
a line has to offer this kind of
breeding takes time talent and space to
work no matter what kind of aroma you
are particularly in to Humboldt seed
will likely have something you'll love
if you love fruit you can choose from
banana mango apricot papaya blueberry
blood orange melon and lemons across
their various strains they have all gas
glue and classic Sour Diesel lines as
well of course there are the heritage
California strains like og cush Jack
hair and headband and their
award-winning blueberry muffin is one
that delights just about everybody's
palate
especially when concentrated Humboldt
seed company is proud to bring to market
the infamous freakshow cultivar - which
has a great THC high but looks so much
like a fern that some folks can't even
identify it as cannabis it's a plant
that really needs to be seen to be
believed if you're looking for
well-balanced CBD seeds Humboldt seed
company can turn you on to CBD strains
that actually have flavor like the dill
and pepper terpenes of Willy G's
Lebanese landrace whether you are
looking for regular feminized or Auto
flowers Humboldt seed company has the
gear to make this your best growing
cycle ever visit Humboldt seed company
comm today to check out their line of
vigorous genetics download their
catalogue and find out where you can
pick them up you can also check out
their Instagram
at the Humboldt seed company to check
out their gorgeous flowers and the
extraordinary freak show plant Humboldt
seed company let him know Shengo Sencha
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire I'm your host
Shengo Louis and our guest this week is
cannabis pharmacologist a tier 8 so
during the first set we made sure that
we were all on the same page about what
pain is how it functions in the body and
what opiates are attempting to do in in
providing some relief but we're all here
because we want options other than
opioids and so that's what we're going
to go to in this set so so a tea I know
that you're you have an expertise in how
cannabinoids function in the brain and
specifically decreasing the experience
of pain and so I think that I just want
to start just by kind of like tossing
you the mic if you will and saying you
know what are the main methods or or
modes of operations that some of the
cannabinoids that we are familiar with
at this point are acting in the brain to
provide relief in different ways than
opioids yeah you bet
so let's start with how they're similar
so you know before the break we talked
about the mechanisms by which opioids
relieve pain so they bind to you know
this area of the brain that i've focused
on my entire career the phe
periaqueductal gray so opioids float
along and they bind to their receptors
like locks fitting or keys fitting into
their locks and cannabinoids work
especially Delta 9 THC THC works in the
exact same way
THC floats along into the PA G and binds
to its receptors studded along the
outside of these neurons and what's
really fascinating is that the MU opioid
receptor which is the primary pain
relieving target and the cb1 cannabinoid
receptor they are cousins
they're both g-protein coupled receptors
that's the kind of protein they are they
have an extremely similar structure and
an almost identical function so they're
both coupled the inside inside of the
cell they talked to the same sets of
messengers GI geo proteins so both of
the you can imagine you know on the left
hand and the right hand you have the
mute opioid and the cb1 cannabinoid
receptor both sitting there like locks
waiting for their keys to come along
when those keys bind the locks changed
shape a little bit and then release
their messengers and those messengers
are identical isn't that fascinating
yeah that's totally cool I had no idea
yeah same brain region same kind of
protein same second messaging system and
the result is also the same you know he
have you have a change in
neurotransmitter release and a change in
the descending control of pain and
that's really the primary way that Delta
9 THC relieves pain it's it's acting in
the exact same place by the exact same
way that opioids are working the
difference is everything else don't just
live in the Phe they live in lots of
other brain areas and in the brainstem
and you know inside you know the viscera
inside your you know your internal organ
cavity and cb1 cannabinoid receptors are
also everywhere else but what's really
fascinating is that somehow by
activating the cb1 receptor with Delta 9
THC yes you still get some activation of
the reward pathway just like the opioids
you know you have this that that's what
causes mirth and euphoria that's what is
rewarding and reinforcing about cannabis
its Delta 9 THC binding to cb1 receptors
in the brain's reward pathway however
the difference is that it doesn't hijack
the brain's reward pathway in the way
that opioids do it doesn't prioritize
cannabis or THC over everything else in
life it also doesn't bind to those
receptors in the brain stem which
control respiration that's why you know
you can't have a lethal overdose from
respiratory depression from THC is
because that's just not how it works
it doesn't it doesn't have anything to
do with respiration so so yeah that the
mechanisms fundamentally are identical
to how opioids work in terms of you know
turning off the pain signal at the level
of the Phe the brains pain headquarters
but the differences lie in everything
else the other really interesting thing
about the cb1 receptor in particular it
is that it is the most ubiquitously
expressed g-protein in the entire brain
what I mean by that is if you you know
we're to die all of these receptors
green and then zoom in and try and find
where they are they look like stars in
the sky they're literally everywhere
it's almost impossible to find a brain
tissue that doesn't have some level of
expression of the cb1 receptor and that
says less about you know what the brain
is doing in response to THC but it says
more about how important the cb1
receptor is in evolution how if it is if
it's on every single neuron in our brain
pretty much what is it doing there why
is it there and so you know the role
that that receptor plays in our everyday
function is huge you know we have
endogenous cannabinoids you know like
two AG and an and amide and a whole you
know set of cousins that are similar and
those little molecules have very
important jobs in regulating our brain
activity which regulates all of our
homeostatic processes all of the
processes that keep us alive our
metabolism our circadian rhythm our
responses to stress our ability to
relieve our own pain so the cb1 receptor
has an incredibly important role in all
of those homeostatic processes so for
whatever reason you know evolution has
set it
to where if you you know stimulate them
you opioid receptor you end up with some
pretty gnarly consequences and if you
stimulate the cb1 receptor you end up
with you know kind of a balance of what
could potentially be some you know risky
things but mostly innocuous things like
relieving pain and experiencing mirth
and euphoria well first of all it's it's
so nice to hear somebody actually used
the word mirth hi I haven't heard that
word in a long time I probably you know
only read it so I like that so so it's
it's remarkable how many of the same
plays I'll say that Delta 9 THC has
that's in common with the opioids and
somehow it's also equally as messy and
and not as targeted but it's the fact
that when Delta 9 THC is being messy
it's not causing all these other
freaking problems that opioids do and so
it's it's more it's more benignly messy
yeah and you know what's even crazier
about that Shango is it gets even
Messier and because it gets even Messier
it becomes even safer so what I mean by
that is you know we we are capable of
ingesting you know Delta 9 THC by itself
and that ends up not to be a very
enjoyable process unless you're like a
daily diver and that's your thing great
but that's that's very few people who
really enjoy totally overloading their
brains you know solely with dial to 9
THC for most human beings if they
consume THC by itself it ends up you
know especially once you get up and over
a certain dose it ends up not being
super fun and so part of the safety and
part of the tolerability of cannabis is
that Delta 9 THC isn't acting alone it's
being consumed with scores of other
biologically active molecules like
cannabidiol
all of the terpenes and all of these
flavonoids and alcohol or sorry
aldehydes and esters all of these other
molecules that are all working together
to make a really messy thing that you
know because you have all these
molecules which are competing for
binding sites some of them are
activating processes while others are
simultaneously turning things down what
you end up with is a really buffered
effect so if you could imagine you know
I I love music and I think about the
world from the perspective of audition
mostly and if you think about if you
have a tone a pure tone I want you to
imagine like B that gets really old
really fast it's not particularly
pleasant and that's like literally a
one-trick pony
right it has one job it does one thing
and that's what you know an opioid does
or that's what Delta 9 THC does by
itself is just one note but then if you
start adding in all these other tones
and layering it with all these other
things what you end up with is white
noise which is what we use to put babies
to sleep right so that buffered effect
when you have that principal component
in there doing its job very important
job relieving pain activating cb1
receptors in the PG but you add in all
these other molecules which are also
promiscuous then you end up with this
really buffered effect and the sum total
of all of those different molecules
doing their jobs at the same time is
that you have a very tolerable
experience so you know Ethan Ethan Bruce
oh very frequently you know has
championed the idea of the entourage
effect or the ensemble effect which is
that these molecules work better
together than they do in isolation and
you know from my perspective the
principal component driving the
entourage effect is just tolerability
you are able to reap the medical
benefits of cannabis because it is sim
Limor tolerable not necessarily that
it's more effective but that it is more
tolerable and that tolerability comes
from this buffered effect of all of
these molecules acting at once that's
great all right so we let's go let's
circle around and go back to the top of
the slide again so you just took us on
this explanatory trip of Delta 9 THC and
how it works on pain but as I often tell
patients we have to start over now and
talk about cannabidiol because it's not
just that cannabis helps pain it's that
cannabis helps pain in multiple
different ways and we really have to
treat them independently so so let's go
back to the top of the slide and and and
and would you go through the same
process with cannabidiol CBD sure
so CBD is a lot more complicated so
there are at least 14 plus known
mechanisms of action of CBD in the
central nervous system so delta 9 it's
pretty straightforward it is a you know
partial agonist at the cb1 receptor and
that's that's largely it but cannabidiol
especially it you know a range of doses
does lots of different things you know
is it's actually a partial allosteric
modulator a pam at both the MU and delta
opioid receptors so what that does is
you know it puts the receptor in a
position where is more receptive to the
endogenous opioids that are there so
just like our body produces in an amide
in to EEG our body also produces
endorphins and kathleen's and lots of
other peptides that naturally act at our
body's opioid receptors so cannabidiol
binds to the mule opioid receptor the
primary pain relieving target in the
brain to make it more receptive and
activatable by its endogenous peptides
like the endogenous opioids so that's at
least one mechanism of action that CBD
could pretend
we be having in the central nervous
system however I think that the the more
profound and direct effect that CBD is
having is it is a profoundly
anti-inflammatory agent as is THC as our
lots of the other molecules that are
found in the cannabis plant so this is
especially why when we have patients who
are suffering from some kind of
inflammatory condition
cannabidiol alone or in combination
especially in combination with you know
these other molecules from the plant
it's profoundly effective because it is
directly acting at those
anti-inflammatory you know pathways so
you know I myself have seen you know the
knuckles of patients with rheumatoid
arthritis and literally their only thing
that they engage in is putting a topical
on their knuckles you know every couple
of hours every single day and you know
you don't have to be a Rheumatologist to
look at someone's hands ago oh wow yeah
you look better so so I think that you
know especially for patients who have an
inflammatory component to their pain and
we talked earlier about how even
neuropathic patients you know people
with neuropathic pain often there is an
inflammatory component to neuropathic
pain so wherever you have any kind of
inflammatory you know thing going on
cannabidiol is going to be an ally you
know especially if you're consuming it
in a whole plant preparation you know I
I tend to refer to type three and hemp
cannabis as the you know nature's
multivitamin for inflammation you know
it truly is you know so much better to
take 12 active ingredients that are
fighting inflammation from 12 different
pathways than just one ibuprofen that
does you know anti-inflammation from one
pathway alone because you know they're
just in inflammation there are lots of
different kinds of processes and lots of
different kinds of molecules involved so
you know if you imagine a construction
site you have all of all of these people
who are buzzing around you know and from
a 30,000 foot view you you have a bunch
of construction workers
but when you really dive down in there
you've got the welding guy you've got
the plumber you've got the electrician
you've got the concrete person you have
the engineer you know and so all of
these people yeah they have different
roles but they're all contributing to
this this main effect so it's the same
thing with inflammation yeah the the the
main effect is inflammation but there
are all these different molecules
involved in that process and so if
you're able to you know knock out every
one of those rolls that's contributing
to inflammation you know then then
you're clearly going to have a better
outcome than if you're only going after
the electrician
all right let's let's talk about a
minute about how fast this CBD works
because there are two different ways of
thinking about CBD helping pain the
first is that you know I've got a you
know whole plant CBD tincture in front
of me and I take it and what will the
cannabinoids do for me right now in this
moment and you know lasting for the next
you know three hours shall we say which
is usual efficacy for CBD or any
cannabinoid but then there's this that
then there's this the second mode which
is people are taking CBD to simply
supplement their endocannabinoid system
and strengthen it because a properly
functioning endocannabinoid system
itself turns down the volume of pain and
you know helps with the homeostasis of
all these different key body functions
that when they come back into balance
our experience and likelihood of pain is
decreased but that's something you know
the building up of an endocannabinoid
system is something where you need to be
taking whole plants CBD for a few weeks
before it's really starting to to work
on the endocannabinoid system as a whole
so would you tease out the differences
in the patient experience of taking CBD
about whether or not the patient can
take whole plant CBD now and get
benefits now versus taking CBD now but
will taking it every day for the benefit
of my endocannabinoid system in the
future to decrease my pain man Shango
we're gonna need another 90 minutes
first of all I want to say that I really
like to have evidence-based
conversations and frankly there's very
little evidence that CBD does anything
acutely especially at the common doses
that people typically take you know
they're like oh I have my you know like
whatever five milligrams in my soda in
the morning every day that that that
probably does nothing except make
someone feel better
via the placebo effect or the
expectation that it's going to do
something which I am not at all
knocking I love a drug that does
absolutely nothing except make you feel
better
so there's that component we are taking
this thing empowering ourselves taking
our health into our own hands expecting
it to help us expecting it to make us
feel better and lo and behold it does
that's because our brain is profoundly
powerful at creating that experience for
ourselves so I think that that's
probably the most immediate benefit that
someone could get acutely from taking
any dose of cannabidiol is that the
knowing that they're taking care of
themselves and you know there could be
some underlying pharmacology that is
actually doing that especially you know
in a within a certain dose range or
after you know taking it by a certain
you know inhalation route particularly
but the the reality is that we don't
have the clinical studies to tell us
what are the acute pain relieving or any
other the you know medical benefits of
cannabidiol
we definitely have evidence to suggest
that over time there is some bio
accumulation of CBD in the in the brain
and in the body
cannabinoids are very lipophilic so
they're stored in the tissue and our fat
tissue really well and you know it does
after a certain level of accumulation it
ends up with like this slow release so
you know we see this with Dravet
patients with you know a Padilla's CBD
and you know with the FDA clinical
trials we see that you know there there
is a profound benefit medical benefit of
you know daily consumption of you know
pretty high doses of CBD you know the
doses that are given to these kids are
pretty whopping and it would be quite
expensive to try and recapitulate that
on your own and there are definitely
more efficient and cost-effective ways
to go about it but but yes I think that
that that latter part of your hypothesis
that maintaining a healthy
endocannabinoid system is by far the
best way to set you're all set yourself
up for success for any health condition
pain included the the other thing that
you know we didn't mention was again
going back to this affective component
of pain so CBD is psychoactive so you
know you hear all the time like oh CB
he's not a psychoactive anything that
changes the brain chemistry and the the
physiology of the brain is psychoactive
so we know that CBD is psychoactive
because it shuts off seizures it acts in
the brain to change the physiology of
the brain to create a beneficial effect
so CBD is psychoactive in that aspect
and one of its other psychoactive
properties is that again under certain
conditions at certain doses it relieves
anxiety it provides positive affective
positive emotional support we also see
this in the opioid world because there's
a researcher at Mount Sinai in New York
Yasmin Hurd who's been studying CBD for
a very long time and her work
demonstrates that in people CBD
profoundly reduces anxiety and that that
reduction in anxiety is also associate
with a reduction in craving for opioids
so addiction one of the one of the
primary drivers for drug seeking
behavior when someone is in recovery
when they have been physically dependent
on a substance and they're trying to
come out of it one of the primary drug
seeking you know craving triggers is
negative emotions you feel crappy and
that feeling is a trigger for seeking
drugs so the the affective or emotional
support that comes from you know
chronically ingesting CBD I don't think
we can underestimate I think it's going
to be very difficult to measure but you
know given what we know from these
little bits and pieces from the
literature that we do have I think that
it is why is to say that you know having
a rich endocannabinoid system a
supplemented endocannabinoid system if
that's what you need that will provide
both you know that bodily sensation
support that you need as well as the
effective support that you need that's
great so so what I think it's important
to hit this one more time because I I
really was caught off-guard and pleased
that you said that taking CBD now who
does not have an acute effect meaning it
will help you now and actually your your
example of taking five milligrams of CBD
in your morning soda crack me up because
I'm often telling people you know you
got to be really careful about how
you're taking your cannabinoids because
you know your your CBD gummies filled
with crap sugar and artificial coloring
is probably doing worse for you than the
CBD that you're trying to get through it
but I think that it's important for us
to understand that taking cannabidiol is
a
a long-term commitment and that if you
want to get relief from it you've got a
you know you can't just take it when
you're feeling bad it's important to
take it every day on a regular schedule
and heck if you can take it everyday
small doses two or three times a day
that's even better because you will
metabolize more of it but the the the
overall idea that yes take cannabidiol
to help your endocannabinoid system but
also don't forget that you should be
doing the lifestyle changes that are
necessary so that you ease off the
trauma that you're giving your
endocannabinoid system so that you don't
have to take CBD forever you know a lot
of people they start taking CBD and they
get these great effects and then they're
like oh I'm feeling so much better and
then they get off of it and then they
feel like crap again I'm gonna like oh
my god am I gonna have to take CBD the
rest of my life and I said and I say you
know you don't necessarily have to but
you're probably gonna have to start
exercising and getting proper sleep and
not drinking coffee and then and then
they're all like screwed that I'll buy
CBD you know you're absolutely right in
that you know CBD is far more like a
micronutrient than it is a drug so you
know we think of taking a drug I'm going
to take this I'm going to feel better
right and especially in America that is
our expectation that is why we have a
health care system built around Commerce
give me the thing make me feel better
now that is that is our culture of
medicine and that is not how CBD works
CBD works more like you know omega-3s
and it's actually not that dissimilar
from omega-3s structurally so you know
we don't take fish oil when we have a
headache right so we're not expecting
fish oil to like miraculously make us
feel better in 30 to 90 minutes
it's a nutrient and it's a part of our
lifestyle where if we're deficient in
some way if we don't have the diet or we
don't have the lifestyle to provide us
that kind of nutrient by some other
means
we have to supplement it by taking fish
oil it's the exact same thing with
cannabidiol if you're not stimulating
your own endogenous cannabinoids system
through like you said exercise sleep a
balanced diet acupuncture all these
other things that mimic the
endocannabinoid system support the
endocannabinoid system without the plant
derived cannabinoids if you're not doing
those things then clearly yeah you've
got to make up for it by taking CBD as a
micronutrient on a very regular basis
and if you're going to be taking it on a
regular basis it's going to be expensive
so you might as well find out how to
take it in a way that's economical so
you know there's tons of products out
there that are orally ingested you know
like you can eat something or drink
something that has cannabidiol in it and
the the sad fact is that only about 5%
of what you swallow ends up making it
into your bloodstream CBD has terrible
oral bioavailability that means if you
put it in your mouths and you swallow it
hardly any of it is getting to your
brain and the rest to your body
something like the lungs you know you've
got about 50% bioavailability so if you
look at you know how much does it cost
you to you know vaporize a kilo of hemp
flour versus how much does it cost you
to you know ingest 300 milligrams or
rather 300 grams of CBD if we're talking
like a 30%
you know cannabinoid content you know
like that's a lot of oil that's really
expensive so you know thinking about
more efficient ways to utilize that
micronutrient to support your
endocannabinoid system you know is a
good thing unless you are also using it
in combination with all these lifestyle
factors and then like you said you won't
need to use it forever let's tease out
one bit about using CBD orally because I
agree with you up to a point and the
point is you know a lot of these oral
solutions and we'll talk more about this
during the third set but a lot of these
oral
solutions like like capsules and various
edibles that I have got CBD added to
them you eat them and for that CBD to
become accessible to the human they have
to go through your gut and you
eventually through your liver and you
know it takes time plus you're getting
all the other you know random sugars
along the way so you know it's a long
road to go in contrast I find that
patients get good results with an whole
plant ethanol extracted tincture because
when they are put putting it in their
mouth whether sublingually or not the
ethanol acts as such an effective
carrier for cannabinoids
that the CBD is actually making the jump
through the mucosal membranes and the
tongue and the cheek and the esophagus
and by the time you know any remaining
fluid of the tincture gets down to the
small intestine it's already been soaked
in other places so what what what do you
think about that delineation Shango
thank you so much because there are so
many products out there that are labeled
as a tincture which are you know is a
cannabinoid which is an oil in an oil
and that's not the same thing as it
cannabinoid suspended in a solvent like
ethanol and you're absolutely right if
you have some kind of oil in order and
if or if you have two bottles of
tincture let's say one of them is oil
and one of them is ethanol either way
your best bet at getting those
cannabinoids into your blood is right in
your mouth and so if you're going to use
an oil-based you know quote-unquote
teacher then you have to use it more
like a topical you have to put it under
your tongue and you have to use your
tongue to rub it in you have to rub it
in under your gums into your cheeks you
have to actually it really is more of a
topical than it is a you know orally
ingested product and you're right that
with the ethanol there might
some chance of enhanced permeability
right there in the buccal tissue the
tissue on the side of your cheek right
in the sublingual tissue you've got a
ton of blood vessels in there wouldn't
it be great if you could just take the
cannabinoids and shove them right into
all those blood vessels inside your
mouth yeah that's the idea
so oral bioavailability typically refers
to when a drug is swallowed that's you
know clinically what we talk about when
we're looking at an oral preparation
that's a preparation that's swallowed
which is kind of different than a
preparation that is absorbed in the
mouth which is you know a far more
efficient way to take cannabidiol
fantastic all right so we will pick up
that topic again in the third set when
we was talking about dosing and methods
but there's one more thing I want to hit
on before we go to our second commercial
break and and I know that you are very
evidence-based and so you may not have a
lot to say about Canaveral but I do want
to talk about CBG because I was lucky
enough to get my hands on a high CBG no
THC plant material about a year and a
half ago that was part of a Rd seed grow
in Oregon and that's yeah yeah yeah all
right well we might as well I was not I
wasn't gonna out him but yeah this is
this is the this is the stuff developed
by Seth and Eric Crawford at oregon CBD
there in oregon and it's fantastic stuff
so i was able to get some of this
because they know that i work a lot with
patients and that i run a lot of dosing
trials because i think that one of the
biggest challenges with patients using
cannabinoids is that everyone's using
totally uncontrolled dosing and they're
just taking some right and and one of
the things that is important about any
kind of medicine is repeatable results
anyway so what i got this material and I
did ethanol extractions and we
a bunch of tinctures and I'll say RSO so
people know what I'm talking about
but really we're talk about full extract
cannabis oil and and so we did a bunch
of dosing trials here on Vashon Island
with with pain patients and because it
was said and in some you know casual
early CBG studies that it was really
great for neuromuscular pain and I'm
like alright well you know CBG is gonna
be the hot novel cannabinoid let's find
out how to actually take this stuff so
that when I talk to people I actually
have my own first-hand knowledge great
so we we you know I make make this
questionnaire and I and I and I take the
tinctures in the RSO we cap a bunch of
it up and we give it to a lot of
patients and and absolutely
we got positive response from people
regarding their pain and it tends to act
like a non intoxicating Delta 9 THC as
far as the patient experience but where
I'm going with it is is this next part
the part that was really startling was
that everyone said that it put them in a
better mood and so you know I teased
that out with folks and it was
decreasing people's anxiety about having
pain at all and and when you tease that
out more this is how I explained it now
to folks is that you know people turn to
cannabis for anxiety and pain but but
THC tends to slather you know I mean I
understand that that generally we're
looking for doses of THC that you don't
actually feel right that don't cause
intoxication but but at this point few
people take it that way right most
people think you're not a little high it
doesn't work so so based on people's
actual experiences you know Delta 9 THC
slathers a little bit of intoxication
over your anxiety and pain and you know
does decrease your pain and acts as a
distractin but but you know involves
some intoxication and then the CBD it
doesn't work for today but it's
work for next month if you take it for
you know every day for the next month
CBG is a different category it actually
makes the patients feel like they are
capable of handling their day or their
pain with with the resources and
abilities they have in front of them
and the patients said you know like my
pain is the same as yesterday but I feel
like I can just fricking handle it more
because of the change in attitude and so
they're all like I think that I'm having
some pain relief but I can tell you one
thing I can cope with my pain a lot
better and I love CBG for pain relief
and then with that week we kind of did a
the secondary you know trial of people
who had extreme daily background anxiety
and performance anxiety and they took to
it like a duck to water they were like
oh my gosh this stops my ruminating and
and and you know a fear of social
situations and these things this is all
a big setup to ask you as somebody who
studies you know the pharmacological
aspect of these cannabinoids have you
seen any either
you know legitimate peer-reviewed
evidence for what I'm describing or even
some significant anecdotal or or heck
since you know how these mechanisms work
I could do you imagine you might go oh
there aren't any studies but from what
are you described I bet you ABC is
happening so I'm just gonna hand that
that whole explanation to you on a big
platter and say what do you think yeah
so we'll start with the evidence that we
do have which is preclinical so in petri
dishes and animals and CBG is you know
kind of like cannabidiol it is
non-intoxicating and it is psychoactive
it is you know very similar to CBD we
don't it is not nearly as deeply studied
as cannabidiol so we don't know exactly
you know all the mechanisms of action
which proteins it's interacting with but
in general you know it is anti oxidative
and anti inflammatory you know it looks
like it's doing good things and not bad
things to the brain
so you know at a very fundamental
molecular level there does seem to be
some kind of basis that this could be a
profoundly therapeutic molecule because
it looks like it does a lot of good
things without causing impairment you
know with that said the anecdote that
you just told me is the deepest and most
wide anecdote that I have ever heard
about CBG because to date it has been
nigh impossible to get enough of it to
actually give to a human being at a dose
that would do something so you know this
is changing now because you know I think
now we have this year will be really the
first time that we have large commercial
operations which are growing type four
CBG dominant cultivars and we'll have
the opportunity to do this you know sort
of real-world scientific experiment and
of putting this stuff in our bodies and
watching what happens so I do think that
there is some fundamental basis for it
to be a profoundly therapeutic molecule
but we also you know again we we don't
have any evidence to look at either the
acute or the chronic chronic effects for
either effective support or you know
pain relief the other thing I will say
and I you know like I always lean on
this because it's so true and I don't
mean on it in a in a negative way to
downplay the power of pharmacology I
clearly in the cannabis pharmacologist
but I also equally believe in the power
of the brain and what we know about all
drugs any drug is the newer it is the
more profound the placebo effect is so
you're you know small test cases that
you do with your your patients on Vashon
do they know what they're getting do
they know that it contains CBG well they
they knew at the beginning of the study
that it was a new novel cannabinoid
called CBG but they did not know what
the effects were supposed to be mm-hmm
yeah so you know and I certain and I
certainly didn't prime them for this
anxiety stuff which I wasn't even
looking for myself right think about you
know like what ails people generally and
if you're a chronic pain patient
both about that bodily sensation of pain
as well as you know like we talked about
earlier that affective component of pain
which is inseparable from the bodily
suffering so you know III approach this
you know from like you said you know I
really appreciate the evidence and it
wouldn't it be lovely if we could do you
know double-blind placebo-controlled
crossover clinical trials with this
stuff yeah that'd be great as a matter
of measure matter of fact you know dr.
Ethan Russo happens to live on the same
island that I do and I actually told him
what I was doing and I described it to
him and and and and he kind of raised
his eyebrow because he's he's you know
he's like that well that he says you're
using this term study he says this is
this isn't really a study you know
you're just kind of giving it to people
and asking them questions that I'm like
yeah study and so you know yeah there
was no there is no double-blinded in
this or peer-reviewed NIST to this right
but I totally understand
you know dosing protocols I want to
recommend to people now which was the
actual point for sure and I also want to
say that everything we know about
cannabis started from anecdotes you know
20 years ago patients were coming into
their doctors offices and saying hey Doc
when I smoke a joint before bed I don't
need to use my dilaudid or you know like
I've noticed that since I started
smoking cannabis I used half as many
opioids and those anecdotes all
collected into community to find
evidence and that community to find
evidence grew to a point where we were
able to you know do more closely
controlled experimental trials and so
all of this stuff has value heuristic
value if nothing else in that it allows
us to go down a line of questioning well
huh isn't that interesting that you know
these chronic pain patients who
experience anxiety have this you know
what looks to be a very profound
therapeutic effect why don't we dig into
that a little deeper so I think there's
a ton of value in this
you know both from a you know cellular
molecular level there's rationale there
and there's definitely rationale to
listen to the people and when what
they're saying is real and it's worth
looking into a lot of my scientist
friends when I talk with them say we're
at emerald cup or something and which
which pulls cannabis researchers and
scientists and doctors from all over the
world and we get together you know a lot
of them talk a lot of trash about
citizen scientists right essentially
what I'm doing and they're like yeah we
understand what you're doing but there
doesn't have a lot of value to it and
and I'm actually a big proponent for
citizen science that that like let's all
work at home on our own and and
especially since cannabis is federally
illegal and and getting the research
approved is so difficult let's let's
start doing this research on our own and
then as it becomes more commonplace in
the population
when legit research scientists go to
divine their studies look like well you
know I've heard this thing anecdotally
let's go ahead up and and fire up the
funding machine and get the university
to do this study but that wouldn't have
necessarily been indicated without
regular nobody's doing it on their own
first for sure and the other component
to that is that you know when we do
clinical trials we have a very long list
of exclusion criteria you know you have
to be pretty neurotypical and you have
to have a pretty narrow range of
conditions and you can't have abused
drugs in the past and you can't have it
this and you have to be this you have to
be a certain age so we have a very
lengthy list of exclusion criteria which
means that we're self selecting yeah
that drug might work in this population
that you have you know developed a
rigorous exclusion criteria for and it
only works for them but what about
everybody else what about all these
other people who lie all over the place
on the neurotypical spectrum you know
and who have all of these other
comorbidities and who have all of these
you know traumatic childhoods
you know so that that's also a really
great thing about you know a large but
messy data set is that if you do have an
effect which is profound
you're gonna detect it in both
populations you know if a drug really
works it should work for everybody no
matter what their you know neuro typer
or background or underlying conditions
rather than you know some drug that only
works for this very very narrowly
defined you know like population of
people I want to hit on one other thing
about you know you mentioned that last
summer was the first summer that
cannabic girolle was in commercial you
know acre acres and acres of it were
grown with with those Oregon CVD seeds
all over the country and I was very
excited because while I got my sample
for these tests almost two years ago now
I was all like alright great I'll do
this stuff now and then at the end of
the summer 2019 there'll be all these
whole plant oils coming to market and I
can send people to purchase them and
it'll be like this new new arrow in the
quiver and I'll be damned I was very
disappointed to see that the vast
majority of the people who grew CVG they
ended up making single my molecule
isolate out of it and using it to spike
edibles and things like that and as
you've mentioned several times during
this episode so far you know these
cannabinoids especially the novel ones
are they work their best in the presence
of other cannabinoids and so I feel like
you know CBG grown in volume at acres
was made it was extracted into isolate
for the monetary value and ease of
integrating into products and yet again
patients lose out because what they
really needed to do was turn all that
stuff into a whole plant full extract
ethanol oil put it in capsules and give
it to people so that
is actually effective yeah I mean like
you're right but you're also like
fighting economic you're fighting
commercial this this is not new for me
or this show and you know like what is
best for the patients is not necessarily
the same you know but I am encouraged
because you know this is you know one
more frontier that we get to go down
what happens when we have that full
cannabis extract what happens when we
have it you know in large doses and
capsules what happens if we you know can
somehow vaporize that flower you know I
don't I don't know a lot about the
phenotype of that flower I've never had
a chance to encounter it myself or even
look at a certificate of analysis but
you know I I could imagine how it could
potentially be at least right now and in
this stage a relatively low yielding
plant in terms of you know what is that
cannabinoid per gram but I don't know so
so maybe that's the thing too maybe we
need to get it you know hybridized into
these like really oil-rich you know
rather than just biomass producing
plants these oil producing plants maybe
that'll help you know popularize it so I
I'm excited because I do think that this
is a really interesting molecule and we
have a long way to go with it
very good so last thing before we go to
commercial are there any other
cannabinoids or constituents of cannabis
that you see coming down the line that
we should look out for for dealing with
pain I mean there's there's there's a
slew of cannabinoids but there's almost
no research on the vast majority of them
but but what what do you anything you
want to flag for us to make sure that we
keep an eye out for the future yeah I
think there are two big ones and you
know if you are a nerd for the
literature like I am they've been there
all along and it shouldn't be a huge
surprise but there the evidence is like
profound like beta carrier filing is a
full agonist
at the cb2 receptor so it's not a
cannabinoid per se but it is a
cannabinoid in that it is a full agonist
at a cannabinoid receptor so baby
finally you know is profoundly
anti-inflammatory has tons of
therapeutic potential and it's abundant
so I think that you know this one in
particular could be playing a really
important role in pain relief especially
because of the mechanisms of pain and
inflammation in particular
so at basal conditions when you have a
normal healthy organism the cb2 receptor
is pretty silent there's not much of it
around so much so that for a long time
even at the International cannabinoid
Research Society ICRS that's the the
main professional scientific society in
the cannabis and cannabinoid sphere ICRS
you know still to this day there's a
little bit of debate about is the cb2
receptor even present in the brain and
that's because under normal conditions
no it's not it's there's no need for it
but when you have chronic drug exposure
chronic stress chronic inflammation you
know any kind of insult to the organism
these things bloom like crazy expression
of the CBT receptor goes up you know
under any kind of you know insult or
injury and so particularly in those
conditions if you have all those
receptors sitting around waiting further
you know little key to come float in and
activate it may be beta carry ethylene
could be a good you know component to
introduce so it's not a particularly
sexy one because it's everywhere but it
is it is you know it has a lot of
promise the other one that there are
some preclinical evidence for is
tetrahydrocannabinol
so that one especially in combination
with other cannabinoids does look like
there's a large amount of promise I
think it's a few years behind Canaveral
and I definitely don't know anyone who's
you know trying to cultivate THC V
dominant plants but certainly there's
some like semi synthetic folks out there
working with yeast who are trying to
produce this you know at scale
and I think th CV has a lot of promise
as well I also think and again this
one's like not super sexy because it's
so obvious
th CA so you know the acid form the non
decarboxylated version of THC
this thing's profoundly
anti-inflammatory but again it goes back
to that sort of micronutrient territory
where if you have you know low but
consistent ingestion or somehow you know
putting the non-intoxicating THC into
your body and supporting the
endocannabinoids system you know that
way as from a micronutrient perspective
that also has a lot of promise you know
there are tons of patient stories out
there people who have been you know
preparing their own non-intoxicating
sort of cannabinoid rich you know hemp
seed elixirs for many years and you know
it seems to be at least anecdotally that
you know that has that has worked for
them to manage you know chronic chronic
diseases so those are some of the big
ones you know the acid form of THC the
the non decarboxylated form beta carry a
fine lean and THC B fantastic thank you
ad we're gonna go ahead and take that
last short break and be right back you
are listening to shaping fire and my
guest today is cannabis pharmacologist
ad ray pre-rolls have come a long way
since the early days of normalization
when you choose Saints joints you are
smoking all flour top-shelf pre-rolls
with terpenes that will sculpt your high
in a way that dry old pre-rolls just
can't whereas most brands release
pre-rolls as an afterthought for the
last five years
Saints joints has focused on their line
of exotic curated joints and while some
companies just chase the hype strains
Saints joints goes deeper searching out
hard-to-find strains unexpected crosses
and nearly forgotten land races and
classics and some hype ones too not only
does a joint from Saints Smoke
incredibly well they have fine-tuned
every step of the process so you don't
get runs in the paper the joint is just
the right dent
need to have a nice pole and the joint
stays lit even if you get a bit chatty
saint's joints boxes are works of art
and will spark conversation when you
pull them out at a party Saints award
winning boxes change with every release
feature edgy outsider art and often
raise awareness of important issues like
equal rights Saints boxes are so desired
then many collect them and display them
in their homes ask your bud tenor for
Saints joints and have a premium joint
experience now if you are licensed
cannabis cultivator I have an extra
message for you Saints is looking for
partners in legal cannabis States to
expand the availability of the Saints
joints brand do you grow exceptional
canvas flower but are less excited about
all the effort cost and risk of
launching your own brand Saints joints
may be just the partner you are looking
for already established in California
Washington and Oklahoma and recognized
by Entrepreneur Magazine and green
entrepreneur as a cannabis industry
leader the Saints joints brand will set
you apart in your home market the best
thing I can recommend is for you to
visit their Instagram at Saints joints
and look at their patented drawer design
boxes become that brand everyone is
talking about without having to build it
from scratch
check out the Instagram at Saints joints
and then visit Saints joints calm to
find out more this message is for folks
who grow cannabis I'm talking to home
growers patients and commercial growers
too I'm probably talking to you when you
plan out your next growing cycle be sure
to check out Humble CSI seeds at
Humboldt CSI dot-com Caleb Inspectah and
his family have lived in Humboldt County
for over a hundred years for the last 40
years
three generations of his family have
cultivated extraordinary sensimilla
cannabis in Humboldt Mendocino and
Trinity counties because of his lineage
and the hard earned experience that
comes from growing up smoking and
sifting large populations of cannabis
plants in Northern California the seeds
you'll cop from CSI will be winning
genetics based on longtime heavy hitters
and
updated Andrus if today bring out new
and exotic traits and better yields go
ahead and ask around caleb also known as
Inspectah and Pirates of the Emerald
triangle is a breeders breeder he
reaches way back and works with
significant strains recreating them in
new and interesting ways that you'll
love is a toker
and a grower as well as offering you
some surprises that will delight serious
seed traders and cultivators Humboldt
CSI goes as further step and selfs all
these chemo VARs so you know all the
seeds will be female these are not
experimental feminized seeds Humboldt
CSI releases some of the best female
seeds available anywhere and it will
show in your garden folks grew quite a
bit of CSI humble gen-x last year here
on Vashon Island and everyone was
pleased the patients had beautiful
female plants and didn't have to call
half of their garden as males the folks
growing for the fun of getting high grew
colorful flowers with exceptional bagged
appeal and great highs and breeders had
seven out of seven females in a pack
which gave them a lot of phenotypic
choices take a moment right now and
visit Humboldt CSI comm you'll find an
up-to-date menu of both feminized and
regular lines along with photos and
descriptions
that's Humboldt CSI comm did you know
that shaping fire has a fabulous youtube
channel with content not found on the
podcast when I attend conventions or
speak or moderate panels I always record
them and bring the content home for you
to watch the Shango lows YouTube channel
it has world-class speakers including
kevin Jodrey of wonderland nursery
talking about breeding cannabis for the
best terpene profile nicholas Mahmood on
regenerative and polyculture cannabis
growing dr. Sunil Agarwal on the history
of cannabis medicine around the world
Ben Cassidy of true terpenes on using
terpenes for health in your everyday
life
Reggie Godinho of steep hill on the
cannabis genome and Jeff Lowen Fell's on
the soil food web
there are several presentations from dr.
Ethan Russo on terpenes and the
endocannabinoid system and even my own
presentation on how to approach finding
your dream job in cannabis and why we
choose cannabis business even though the
risks are so high as of today there are
over
100 videos that you can check out for
absolutely free go to youtube.com
forward slash Shango lohse or click on
the link in this week's newsletter
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire I'm your host
Shango Lowe's and our guest this week is
cannabis pharmacologist ad rate so here
we are in the third set and we want to
go through dosing and methods of taking
in your cannabinoids because now that
you perhaps have these ideas that you
that you might want to replace your
opiates with cannabis one of the hardest
things is figuring out what the hell to
do next so so we're going to go through
a couple of the different common methods
for ingesting or taking in cannabinoids
and and and we'll kind of riff on each
of those so that we can we can all kind
of learn together so so a tea I know
from watching your other presentations
that you are not particularly a fan of
smoking and I mean for for medicinal
right we all love to smoke smoke that
but actually as far as it being
medicinally effective would you explain
why that's that's what you teach yeah so
I mean that that the basis for that is
purely from poly aromatic hydrocarbons
from things that are potential
carcinogens you know putting burnt plant
material inside of your body is less
healthy than not putting burnt plant
material inside your body however that
being said I am I've always been a firm
believer that the best kind of medicine
is the one you will take
so if smoking cannabis feels like
medicine to you and it is the the the
path of least resistance to getting
medicine into your body then you're
better off with the medicine than
without it for a lot of people smoking
simply doesn't feel like medicine it was
never part of their culture it was
always frowned upon there's some fear
and shame and there's a lot of war on
drugs stuff happening there
and smoking simply is not going to work
for them the benefits of smoking are
really the benefits of inhalation which
is an immediate onset here you have an
activated molecule and Delta 9 THC in
particular has to be decarboxylated it
has to be converted from it's a civ acid
inactive form to its you know
decarboxylated active form so THC a has
to be converted into THC so to do that
you have to apply heat and the easiest
you know way for thousands of years to
apply heat to the cannabis plant is to
set it on fire so the the benefit of
smoking is that you have an activated
THC which goes directly into your
freshly oxygenated blood supply which
goes directly up to your brain which is
exactly why it has an immediate effect
and for someone who is experiencing for
instance breakthrough cancer pain
nothing is going to help better than to
have an immediate relief of that pain so
anything that can you know literally
instantaneously shut off the pain that's
amazing and so if smoking does that for
you great there are other ways of
inhaling the cannabinoids that don't
involve you know the burnt plant
material that you know can potentially
cause other health effects and when I
say other health effects you know there
are known side effects of smoking
cannabis although we have yet to see any
you know sort of cancer or lung cancer
come out of chronically smoking cannabis
like we see with you know chronic
tobacco smoking clearly causes cancer
that's gnarly but what we do see are you
know COPD chronic inflammatory you know
respiratory issues we see you know
coughing we see phlegm production so
it's not to say that smoking is totally
unsafe but it's also not totally safe so
there's still other ways of reaping the
benefits of inhaled cannabinoids without
exposing yourselves to all of those
that the toxins and the irritants that
lead to all of those other you know
inflammatory conditions I'll go ahead
and add to that to that for a lot of
people I mean your example of cancer
related pain and the immediate secession
of pain is spot on and yet there are a
lot of patients who are taking either
THC for other types of pain or or maybe
they're looking for CBD where smoking it
has that very fat fast effect it fills
your lungs it's instantly in your brain
and you go up fast that's not
necessarily what everybody who is
fighting say for example inflammatory
pain is looking for taking say a
tincture or something or a topical where
the cannabinoids enter the body at a
slower rate so instead of going up and
getting this peak and then slowly coming
down you instead have this slow the slow
pathway up and then the slow pathway
down it'll tend to you know last for
longer and allow you to be more
productive right it's go so many pain
patients they still have got to go to
work and and and it's hard to titrate or
control your dosage when you're smoking
and so people are like oh I'm gonna
smoke and then they're like [__] now I
can't go to work so I'm freaking baked
you know and so for those for those
folks they should definitely be aware
that in addition to not scorching your
lungs you know some of these other
options that we're gonna talk about may
be better for you because they are going
to be less intoxicating right and so
they're I think for all of these methods
of administration there are really three
major components that we can talk about
right where you're managing impairment
you're also talking about the onset of
the effect how quickly it works as well
as the duration of the effect how long
it works so you know one other element
of you know pain relief is you know a
lot of chronic pain patients have a lot
of trouble sleeping they
a difficulty falling asleep because
they're in pain they have difficulty
staying asleep because their pain wakes
them up in the middle of the night and
so just from a sleep management
perspective smoking is probably not the
best idea because the the peak the onset
might be you know almost immediate but
the duration of that effect is really
not very much you know two to three
hours if you're lucky so you really do
for something like you know where you
need a long-term effect you know
something that's going to get you
through a good six hours smoking isn't
going to be the best for you because you
need something with a longer duration
you know just as a little side note one
of these days somebody's gonna figure
out a good way to do time Early's whole
plant capsules and they're just gonna
crush the market because you know some
people use and you know enteric capsules
which help a little bit but most of the
time to make something time released you
have to over process to the point that
it's not whole plant anymore but your
description is point right on point
because so many pain patients they'll
they will they will take whatever
cannabis they they're gonna take in the
evening and then by you know 2:00 2:30
in the morning
their pain is waking them back up again
and so they have to have strategies to
have a second dose on their nightstand
which then occasionally in some people
with some cultivars make them feel a
little groggy in the morning but but at
some point or worse where sometimes - it
can cause tachycardia right so you know
what I mean by that is a racing heart so
ironically you're trying to go to sleep
and yet you you know inadvertently
consume a little bit too much THC causes
this like sympathetic nervous system
reaction where your brain interprets you
know a fast paced heartbeat as paranoia
and anxiety yeah I hate that and and
also I guess it's worthwhile to point
out at least at least my understanding
is that the tachycardia is actually most
likely attributed to a particular
terpene in the
and not THC directly and so if you use
cannabis and you do get the racing heart
which is something that I hate there are
you know you need to try enough to find
out what the terpene is for you and
those plants and then and then avoid
those plants and I would say that this
is kind of the cutting edge of
understanding you know using whole
flower and there's there's not a lot of
research on it but I think there will be
soon I think you're right - but I do
think that you know the the patients who
use dronabinol which is the synthetic
form of THC you know they also
experience this so I think that there
probably is some interaction between you
know just like all of our cannabinoids
and terpenoids and ingesting it by any
means you've got to find that personal
therapeutic window right you've got to
take enough of the stuff to get your
good effect without taking so much that
you get a bad effect yeah I totally
agree with you all right so that's
smoking let's talk well we've already
talked quite a bit about tincture but
let's talk about tincture so you know a
lot of people like tincture is because
they feel much more in control right
with with smoking you know it's really
hard to control how much you're actually
going to take and with you know things
like capsules you're kind of beholden to
whatever they put in the capsule but
with tinctures this is very much
individualized medicine you're able to
say okay you know this this lab tested
tincture I know the potency of it and so
I'm gonna slowly increase my my dosage
over the next few days and then I'm
gonna find my sweet spot and then I know
it's going to be you know X amount of a
dropper or X amount of you know drops
themselves so that you can get
repeatable results and for me and that's
why I generally you know recommend
tinctures for people because of the
patient control yeah I love tinctures
for several reasons one of them is that
you know like you said it does feel like
medicine too
you know like for a lot of people my
grandparents age you know I'm lucky
enough that my grandmother is still
alive
and you know like there's absolutely no
way like she would even use something
that looked like inhaler to inhale
cannabinoids but a tincture like that
feels like medicine medicine to her so
she'll actually use it and you know you
can't benefit from a medicine that you
are opposed to using so there's that
component the easily titratable easily
do scible reliable results those are all
amazing the other thing that I like
about some of these teachers is that you
know depending on the formulation it can
act as somewhat of a hybrid between a
product that's available both
immediately in your mouth and if you
swallow some of it and it does get all
the way through the liver then you have
you know like a two-for-one where you
have the immediate onset you know from
some of the THC to you know produce some
sedation whereas you have that sort of
slow release effect from the from the
liver and the you know converting
delta-9 into other you know metabolites
that gives you this more prolonged slow
release effect so you have both
immediate onset in the long duration
which is you know really not achievable
through any other product one of the
things that I find very liberating about
tinctures is that even though there are
certainly you know artisan and craft
ways to make a good ethanol tincture
that is going to be potentially better
than you know a novice tincture maker I
like the fact that it is a process
that's available to everyone right
anybody can grow their own cannabis
plants in their yard they can take the
flower they can pour you know Everclear
ethanol over the top you know shake it
for 90 seconds strain it through a
coffee filter and guess what you just
made your own tincture and sure there's
there's you know there's fancier ways to
go about it by like freezing everything
first and all that kind of stuff but
essentially if you just pour ethanol
over your flower and strain it you have
made tincture
and depending on what state you live in
many many state cannabis labs will will
allow patients to get things tested and
so you can find out how strong what you
made is as well and I think that that
kind of I don't know I guess I'll call
it egalitarian mm-hmm pharmacology is
something that's it's it's very
attractive to me because I I do not
support the ivory tower medicine idea I
mean I guess we already established that
with the whole citizen scientist thing
but tinker's are great because you can
have control of your own health by
growing your own plant making your own
tincture and and now you are
self-sufficient and it's wildly less
expensive than purchasing it either
licensed or unlicensed totally I and I
the word that I use for this is
empowerment and I think that you know
it's it's beyond just the not being
reliant upon someone else but there's
like when you see a project through from
beginning to end and I see this with my
trainees and my students all the time
you have investment in it when you you
know pop that seed when you drop that
clone in the soil when you are tending
to that plant when you are you know
looking for signs of maturity when you
are harvesting it with your own hands
you know you have a lot invested in
yourself and all of those you know that
that whole process is supportive of your
health you know like that is you taking
your own health into your hands and you
know we see this all the time in the
pink clinic you know those people who
are able to you know take control of
their own lives and decide I am going to
do this for myself those aren't the
people we see in the pain clinic because
they don't have any pain because they
have figured it out for themselves so
you know like this this this you know
being invested in it has has sort of a
holistic support you know from a human
level
in addition to you also as a by-product
are not reliant upon some you know like
commerce or pharmaceutical company or
something so yeah I love that idea of
this pharmaceutical at Galit Arianism
okay let's talk about edibles because a
lot of people use edibles and swear by
them for their pain and pretty much you
know will express that they can't live
without them but edibles are are a
complex medicine and they've got pros
and cons so so let's start there what
are your general impressions of the
efficacy of edibles and and when you do
recommend edibles what do you recommend
people try yeah so let's start with the
pros so clearly we have something that's
really easily doable just like we have
with tinctures you know it's pretty easy
even if you have something that is you
know more than the dose that you would
prefer it can often be really easy to
divide that dose you know I am NOT a
five milligram gummy person like two and
a half is just fine thank you so you
know that that's the benefit is that you
have something that is easily doable
which means that a patient knows what to
expect there's some consistency in that
effect which is huge so I love that
about edibles is that it's easy to dose
and easy to divide doses the other thing
that I really like is the duration you
know because we're putting the
cannabinoids through the liver you are
you know recruiting the liver to prolong
the effects of the medicine and often
that can be extremely therapeutic if
you've got to get all the way through a
workday if you've got to get all the way
through a night of sleep you need a
slow-release formula you know something
that wears off in two to three hours is
not going to work for you so I like it
for the ability to dose and the ability
to last for a long time and that I could
see why patients would totally swear by
that because those are really important
components of medicine and and also you
know we talked about earlier about the
smoking while certainly the the power of
edibles
is is not to be scoffed at it's nice
because you don't go up as fast as you
do with smoking and so if you're looking
for pain relief and the anti
inflammation without the stony aspect of
it
edibles can often be a good choice they
can as long as you stay within your own
therapeutic window so you know we talked
briefly about that before how you've got
to take enough of it to feel something
but you can't take so much that you
start to experience negative effects and
unfortunately with edibles the
likelihood of experiencing a negative
effect it can be pretty high so if we
look at the data that came out of
Colorado
you know when legalization first came
around we saw that the vast majority of
people who came into the emergency
departments after ingesting cannabis you
know they're having an acute psychotic
episode or they think they're gonna die
there's you know some kind of THC
overdose the vast majority of those
cases are edibles and part of the reason
for that is that in when you ingest
cannabis delta-9 is converted you know
Delta 9 THC is converted into 11 hydroxy
THC which is far more potent and it
lasts for a very long time so you know
inhaling five milligrams of THC is not
at all the same thing as swallowing five
milligrams of THC because your liver
converts it into something that's more
powerful and lasts longer the other
thing about the liver is that you know
everyone's liver is different you know
the different effects of edibles say far
more about the differences in our livers
than they do about the difference in
manufacturing processes or the
differences in the products themselves
you know the the enzymes within our
liver that you know metabolize drugs and
and dump things into our bloodstream and
protect us from toxins all of those
enzymes are proteins and those proteins
are encoded by our DNA and our DNA is
different you know drug metabolism is
affected by other drugs that you're
taking other medications that you're
taking it's affected by your diet
affected by your exercise and your other
lifestyle components so you know that
for all of those reasons you know the
effects of an edible are not only you
know variable between people but also
variable within one person so although
yes it might be really easily to dose
and it might last a long time there's
also some degree of risk there because
you're you're allowing your liver to
produce a very potent molecule and it
you could experience different effects
you know from day to day because of the
other you know sort of lifestyle factors
and this is such a challenge for for
pain patients who are new to cannabis
because you know what we're kind of
teasing apart is actually a really
complex situation right where the that
the patient wants the cannabinoids and
so they take inedible because they
they're approachable and they're pretty
easy to get in in legal states anyway
and but then if you take it and you take
too much your your will call it over
Medicaid itself not only is it way more
intense because it's become 11 hydroxy
but because your body is processing it
more slowly your bad experience lasts
longer - right like if you if you smoke
too much pot it's like oh alright well
you know I'm gonna go and sit in nature
and I'll be pretty good in about 45
minutes I just gonna go away and while
you know it's gonna go away with an
edible - that could easily be 2 and a
half hours easily you're like damn and
so that will often scare people away
from cannabis medicine when it really
had nothing to do with the inherent
value of cannabis medicine it had to do
with using edibles properly for pain
takes some pre education and then an
awareness to start at a low amount
absolutely and this this outage the
start low and go slow apply
absolutely the most to any product that
is ingested swallowed so you know it is
incredibly important to start you know
really really low and when we're working
with our chronic pain patients in
Philadelphia I have a collaboration with
Thomas Jefferson University and the
Rothman orthopaedic Institute when we're
working with our chronic pain patients
you know we're advising them if they're
gonna use an edible product a swallow'd
product to start at one milligram of THC
because there there really are some
individuals out there who are
hypersensitive to THC you know there's a
lot of variability some people can
tolerate an entire 100 milligram edible
you know to themselves and other
people's you know spin out into you know
total paranoia and psychosis at one
milligram so you know it's far more
conservative and it's it's you know
better to not take enough than it is to
take too much because you can always
take more but you can never take less
especially with inedible and you know
while we're talking about liberation
medicine let's let's talk about ego and
being cool I want to make sure I point
out to patients that there's a certain
vibe within the cannabis scene that
taking more THC is cool and if you take
less you are somehow less than or a wuss
or you know have got baby lungs or you
know there's a lot of different ways
that people with high tolerances can
kind of dis people who take a small
amount but I want to encourage folks to
you know if if taking two point five
milligrams of THC which which most
people don't feel it at two point five
milligrams it's a it's a nice steady you
know three times a day anti-inflammatory
dose but you don't get intoxicated and
and I'll mention sometimes you know two
point five milligrams and someone in the
group I'm talking with will totally
scoff and they're like them all I take
you know twenty five milligrams
you know six times a day and I'm like
I'm glad that you found
something that worked for you but you
know there are a lot of people myself
included if I took 25 milligrams like
I'm gonna have a bad day oh yeah like
like my you know I'm gonna you know you
know I don't know if I can call it so
far psychosis but I need to go lay down
and I'm going to be scared for a few
hours and I hate it and so like you know
individualized medicine is very modern
and it's important for pain patients to
remember that you need to start low and
you need to increase it slowly and
comparing your dosage to anybody else
should not matter at all you've got
different number of you know you know
Canada cannabinoid receivers in your
body you your body is gonna process it
at a different rate there really is not
you know any kind of hard and fast
comparisons patients to patients you
might be able to get guidance from other
patients but understand that guidance
and then start at 1 milligram right so I
I love that you're bringing this up and
and I don't know at least from my
patients that I'm working with you know
like we we are seeing a whole lot of
people that are entirely cannabis naive
so luckily you know they're not bringing
that kind of thinking we're that kind of
for lack of a better word much ease
moment to the table you know it's
entirely novel for them and they're just
looking to their doctors for help so you
know fortunately you know we can start
working with people with all of those
factors that you mentioned you know your
individual experience and the beautiful
thing about this plant is that it is
dynamic enough that there is something
for pretty much everyone and I love the
idea of we're all unified in our process
but not necessarily in our dose or our
amount so our process is always the same
we start somewhere
and we either have a good time and we
can keep going or we have a bad time and
we have to back off and
the magnitude at which we increase or
the magnitude at which we decrease our
consumption or our frequency may vary
but that's the process right and this is
something that we don't talk about in
you know all of the rest of allopathic
medicine very much you know that this is
true for lots of other drugs that people
go to the doctors for you know like some
people go for anxiety medication or a
tricyclic antidepressant and the doctor
tries you on one thing and it didn't
work so you switch to a different drug
and then you have to up the dose and
then it was too much so then you back
down the dose but the difference between
allopathic pharmaceuticals and cannabis
is that instead of your doctor telling
you you're having a bad time let's do
something different you have to pay
attention to yourself and look at your
journal and say that didn't work for me
I need to do something different which
for some people can be incredibly
empowering and it can make all the
difference in the world in their health
but for other people who are really
accustomed to having their hands you
know truly held by a healthcare
professional and putting all of their
trust and getting all 100% of their
guidance about their health from you
know a person in a white coat that can
be really intimidating to have to say
like oh jeez I have to like figure out
all of this stuff by myself like this is
really overwhelming and I feel for that
person it is absolutely true it is work
to try and find a place to start and
then you know fine-tune your own process
in accordance to your own body and your
own lifestyle needs so it can be a
process but it can also be an incredibly
rewarding process and bully for anybody
in the audience who's new to cannabis
who is trying to you know transition
from opioids to cannabis who is saying
okay I need to get a good education
first right because it's it's sad how
much of the licensed market cannabis
packaging and marketing is intended to
confuse
the buyer of what it actually is maybe
trying to sound like a product of higher
quality than it is or making claims that
are untrue and so when you when you take
your health into your own hands
and you do your research in advance you
are really doing yourself a service for
sure and that can be really hard you
know like it's very difficult to know
who to trust you know like this is on
the label that it relieves pain and then
it improves cognition or whatever it is
whatever it's on the label oh it was
formulated by a PhD therefore it's a
good product you know like that all of
those things can be kind of deceiving
and it's I I do feel for people who are
you know just embarking on this journey
because it is a lot of homework and it
is a lot of time that not a lot of
people you know have the luxury of
navigating I've heard you use the term
science washing before and I and I got a
chuckle out of that and and you're
comparing it to like green washing right
things that are are faking being
environmental right and there's so much
like there's so many cannabis products
that are faking having a scientific
basis to them not cannabis itself which
has a scientific basis but that
particular method may not like be in
line with the science exactly like if
you have a vaporizer pen that has you
know sleep in its you know branding or
or its effects you know like I think
that your listeners are would benefit
from you know applying some scientific
thinking to that you know how do you
know that it's good for sleep where did
you get your information how many people
tried it for how many people did it work
you know like where did the formula come
from so you know like I I love the idea
of everyone being a little bit more
skeptical you know and and especially
when it comes to this kind of stuff you
know we we have been relying on the
pharmaceutical industry to you
we trusted them to provide us with safe
medicine for a long time and it didn't
happen you know like we were extremely
misled by the pharmaceutical industry
when it came to the opioids and I think
it would behoove all of us to think a
little bit more critically and
skeptically about you know any kind of
claim that appears on some packaging so
I realize we've kind of set ourself up
right we've just spent this show
recommending that people try cannabis
instead of opioids and now we just said
you know there the market is full of
lies and you can't trust what's on the
shelves and the damn thing is is that
they're both true and and the best thing
that I recommend to people is you you
know do your research on you know the
dosing protocol that you want to do for
yourself and then do some research
beyond just talking to a budtender on
the product that you're gonna buy but
then also you know humans have been
using cannabis and you know smoking it
and making cannabis tinctures for for
thousands and thousands of years the new
cool hot fancy thing is not necessarily
better and if you're just starting out
and you don't have a very good [__]
detector when it comes to cannabis
products I would always recommend to
start with something that is more simple
than more fancy you know everybody was
all excited when water-soluble CBD
became available and they're like oh we
can put in all these beverages than I'm
gonna like what use does water soluble
isolate have because I don't think it's
healthy to take isolate and you have to
over process it even more to make it
water soluble and and so you know maybe
maybe that makes me you know less cool
it certainly got rid of any soda
advertisers I would have gotten on the
show but I think that sometimes it's
it's a you know better if you stick with
the basics yeah and you know I many
times before I have said
that you know we did phase 1 clinical
trials on cannabis 5,000 years ago in
China it's safe for most people you know
and now the question is is it effective
and I do think that we have a lot of
evidence to demonstrate that you know
cannabis is both a safe and effective
pain reliever for most people with
chronic pain we can't say that about
opioids we do know that it does work for
some people you know a very small
proportion of people it works over the
long term there are people who have been
on you know opioids for decades and it
you know it's effective for them but
it's far the risk of you know physical
dependence and the risk of overdose and
the risk of you know constipation
cognitive impairment and all these other
things it's greater than the you know
pain relief that results from engaging
with opioids where these two start to
interact is largely at a point where you
know patients all often get to a point
where their opioids are becoming more
difficult to obtain and when you have a
person who's physically dependent upon
an opioid they're kind of stuck they
need something to be introduced into
their body to feel normal and so a lot
of people have been using cannabis in
combination with their opioids
especially initially and you know my
work in academia has been supporting
this approach for a very long time
because we know you know at a very
fundamental mammalian level when you
have these compounds in your body at the
same time they produce synergistic pain
relief that means a greater than
additive effect it's not two plus two
equals full or it's two plus two equals
in so when you have something like that
when you have a seven instead of a four
then you can back off on the doses of
each of those components so that you can
achieve the same level of pain relief
you had before at a much smaller dose
anything anything we can do to reduce
the dose of an opioid required to elicit
pain relief that is a really
thing and you know nothing no other no
single other drug no other law no
prescription drug monitoring program no
abuse deterrent formulation of a
pharmaceutical no other intervention has
reduced the number of opioid overdose
deaths as much as legalizing cannabis
has reduced opioid deaths so you know
we're about to go into the how-to of
actually doing the transition because I
know you've given this a lot of thought
but before we go there there's one more
thing I want to hit on on the edibles
tip and that is you and I mentioned in
passing that that you know many folks
they just stopped at two point five
milligrams because that gets that takes
care of their pain and maybe if they
want to feel like a little jocular with
it they'll go up to five milligrams and
so they're getting some of the other
attributes of pain relief as well but
then you've got these people who have
got long-term chronic pain and they're
taking 100 milligram brownies and and
they're both pain patients like like I
know there's several different variables
at play
so I'll just toss it to you like that
and say like what's up with that well
one of the one of the fundamental things
there is tolerance which is you know
both a tool and a hindrance so in order
to reap the benefits of THC in cannabis
you you do have to have some degree of
tolerance so that you can widen your own
personal therapeutic window you can
widen the dose range at which you feel
something but you you can still fall
below the threshold of feeling bad
things so staying in that therapeutic
window is easier if you have some
tolerance to THC it's it's more
tolerable you have a wider window of
good effects the problem comes in and
this is something that you know we would
be wise not to repeat with the opioids
right it with with opioids no no doctor
ever told their patient hey this stuff
can produce physical dependence to
manage your physical dependence you
should monitor your tolerance if you
find yourself taking more
or more frequently take a break switch
to something else for a couple of days
allow your body to reset and come back
to it that could have saved thousands of
people's lives but we never had that
conversation but with our opioid
consuming patients this is one thing
that we can we have the opportunity to
do right with cannabis we can have that
exact conversation this is a substance
that you can develop physical dependence
it's rewarding you could you know
develop some kind of cannabis use
disorder or hyperemesis or some other
dysregulation in your endocannabinoid
system it's prudent to take a break from
time to time not only to allow your body
to resent eyes but if you are able to
take those periodic tolerance breaks
you're able to reset eyes to a point
where you don't need a hundred
milligrams in order to feel that effect
that you felt on Friday night you know
it is a far more economical approach to
take tolerance breaks reduce the amount
that is required to elicit that same
effect for pain patients who have pain
every day the and who have transition to
cannabis what do you tell them to do on
those tolerance break days because you
know so many of the pain patients I
talked to the idea of taking a tolerance
break and experiencing 48 hours of their
pain straight just makes them cry and
and they they want to avoid that at all
costs yeah I mean like to be quite frank
I don't tell them anything because
people are very resourceful in figuring
out what's gonna work best for them a
lot of people you know turn to other
kinds of pain therapies
anti-inflammatories you know the
non-steroidal ones you know some of them
might take an opioid for a couple of
days because I mean like the risk with
opioids is over the long term where they
where they increase risk where they lose
their efficacy is when you take them
chronically but if you're only taking
you know opioids for two days that's
exactly what they were designed for
short-term use so some of them switch
back to opioids some of them you know
just you know rely on meditation and
cognitive sort of
techniques there in fact digital health
technologies and apps that people can
download to you know sort of go through
practices daily to cognitively manage
their pain so you know I know
unfortunately I don't need to have those
conversations frankly at all because
people are very resourceful in figuring
out how can I just get through a couple
of days and it's different for everyone
it just makes me sad when when they
don't want to go back to the opiate
because maybe they had a challenge with
it before and then they are on cannabis
and they know they need to take of the
break so either a they resist taking a
tolerance break because they are afraid
of those days off or as I see so common
they just turn to alcohol and so they're
sloshed for two days and then they come
back and I just wish there were more
options I do too and you know what I
feel like this is going to be you know I
I would hope that as this you know
chronic pain management with cannabis
becomes more mainstream that we will
have more of our best and brightest
minds in clinical practice and in
scientific development that we will have
some answers for people all right so
let's get down to the brass tacks of
actually transitioning so you know going
cold turkey on opioids can be not only
difficult but dangerous and there are
definitely advantages of doing kind of
like a measured transition but I know
you've developed this out in detail so
so why don't you tell us your
recommendations eighty-four for transit
for the actual transition time the
process again is very different for
every patient and also just because
you're on an opioid doesn't mean that
you're on the same opioid as anyone else
who is going to the same pain clinic
so there are short-acting opioids and
longer-acting opioid drugs which all
have their different profiles in terms
of how rapidly you can taper off of them
so again this is where the personalized
component is critical you know we've
been attempting to develop
opioid tapering protocol for a number of
years and we make some observations one
of which is if we tell a patient
absolutely nothing by the three-month
mark they have just sort of figured out
how to take half as many opioids or get
off of them entirely on their own so
again this kind of comes back to the
self empowering component where you know
people are perfectly capable of figuring
things out for themselves you know like
if if you need some strategies
specifically for doing that what we
found is that a lot of patients just
start by eliminating one of their daily
doses so a really common one that people
eliminate is the one right before bed so
if they switch to some kind of ingested
or swallowed preparation of cannabis
right before bed they no longer need
their overnight dose of their opioids so
that's probably the most common one to
skip the dose of the opioid that's taken
right before bed and then often a lot of
patients wake up feeling refreshed
having slept through the whole night
without having that heavy sort of
sedation and the almost a hangover from
the heavier narcotics and just that that
cognitive state alone is able to get
them through the day so that they're
able to walk beside their pain and you
know live in the presence of the pain
rather than trying to totally numb it
with their next dose of their opioid so
those are those are my practical ones
and then I would also you know again
advocate for the personalized component
which is do what is right for you you
know a lot of patients will do just fine
on you know like one or two doses of
their opioid every day a lot of people
can you know decide that they don't want
to be reliant on this anymore and
they're willing to you know have a
little bit you know because the thing
about cannabis is that it doesn't
profoundly eliminate the pain the way
that an opioid does but it certainly
profoundly improves the quality of life
so for some people the physical
sensation of the pain is so intense that
they just can't ever get away from it
they're always going to be consuming
Oh Pio it's not fine if that's what your
body needs in order for you to have a
high quality of life then shoot for that
but that's that's really what it boils
down to is figuring out what your own
personal priorities are and utilizing
cannabis in combination with and
eventually you know for some people
potentially in substitution for the
opioids I think that patients who are
going through that transition they
really need to they really could I'm
doing need and should I'm like oh these
are not good words it is described to me
often by patients that they think it's
going to be worse than it is and that
the transition becomes easier for even
very simple things like you know part of
part of taking Delta 9 THC is it can
cause a you know a little bit of
cascading forgetfulness that the kind of
thing where we joke as cannabis people
like Oh
forgot where my car keys were right just
basic stuff like that and so many
patients there they're so used to taking
their opioids on a schedule and that if
they aren't on their schedule they're
afraid that their pain will flare up but
then they start incorporating cannabis
alongside the opioids and a little bit
of the pain relief kicks in that's
natural but also a little bit of that
that forgetfulness comes involved as
well and they actually forget that
they're in pain or they forget to take
their dose and they realized oh my gosh
you know I've naturally started
replacing the opioids opioids just
because of the nature of cannabis mm-hmm
yeah that's that's absolutely true I
think that's been reflected in some of
our anecdotes that we hear in the clinic
you know and and again like this this is
like to each their own you know for for
a lot of our patients you know more than
half of our patients don't experience
any impairment whatsoever and for those
that do experience some impairment they
either doesn't affect their day or
they're more willing to deal with the
impairment than they are to deal with
their opioid side-effects
well this is all fantastic 80 thank you
so much for taking your time - well
actually a lot more time than we had we
had planned on we actually got on a roll
this is a lot of really great
information but but I thank you so much
for sharing you know the caring that you
have for patience and your in-depth
scientific research because I think that
you know there's so much in our scene
which is you know anecdotal evidence and
people sharing only what worked for them
and then a whole bunch of kind of like
myth and taboo left over from from the
reefer madness days and I think that you
know people like you doing the real
research and then you know interacting
with patients and then coming out and
sharing the reality of what they can do
to save themselves is really important
well Shango it's an honor and a
privilege to do this work and I feel I'm
very strongly about sharing the work as
widely as possible so thank you so much
for the opportunity to share it with
your audience
wonderful so if you want to find out
more about 80 there's a couple different
ways to do it first of all I recommend
that if you like the kind of information
we talked about today and you would like
to hear it
with pictures I recommend that you go to
the the YouTube channel for cultivation
classic it is a it's a fantastic event
in the Portland area and on the
cultivation classic YouTube channel
there is a recording of 80s 2017
presentation on beyond opioids and so
you'll hear a lot of the stuff that you
learned today over again
but there's also a bunch of stuff she
covered there that we did not cover and
it's got pictures so that's great
also 80 did a great talk at the Cato
Institute on harm reduction for opioids
and you can find that on the Cato
Institute website at Cato org that's C
ATO dot o-r-g and then finally if you
want to reach out to a
Rey herself or find more about find out
more about her work and her company you
can go to smart cannabis dot life
so that would be
www.smartmartialartsmanchester.com or
insights into the latest cannabis news
and product reviews on the shaping fire
website you will also find transcripts
of today's podcast as well for
information on me and where i'll be
speaking you can check out Shango
lowes.com does your company want to
reach our national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hotspot at shaping
fire calm to find out how thanks for
listening to shaping fire i've been your
host
Shango lows
you