[Music]
today is another episode where i will be
learning right alongside of you when i
started cultivating i thought soil was
mostly inert and it was like a computer
insert npk and out came cannabis flowers
over time though i have been humbled by
how little i knew and i'm grateful for
all the regenerative cultivation
pathfinders who constantly teach me what
they have learned so that i can grow
better flowers in a way that most honors
the earth so i can be part of the
solution and less part of the problem
one thing i have learned again and again
is that the soil is its own universe it
is infinitely complex
a truly regenerative cultivator doesn't
see the soil as something apart from the
earth and separate a regenerative grower
sees the soil in their hands as the
earth itself
as regenerative cultivators we are
constantly completing cycles closing
loops and acting in service to the earth
and that's an important aspect being in
service to the earth really focuses our
attention on how we can help the earth
heal from the damage we have done as
humans and how to work in partnership
with the earth to grow the best damn
cannabis possible
if you want to learn about cannabis
health cultivation and technique
efficiently and with good cheer i
encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter we'll send you new podcast
episodes as they come out delivered
right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple most important
news items from the week and videos too
don't rely on social media to let you
know when a new episode is published
sign up for the updates to make sure you
don't miss an episode
also we are giving away very cool prizes
to folks who are signed up to receive
the newsletter this month our friends at
magical butter are awarding our winner a
fantastic four pack gummy bundle
including a magical butter countertop
extraction machine filter press a d-carb
box gummy mixes and gummy molds too a
432 value
sign up for the magical butter
newsletter now at
magicalbutter.com and to win go to
shapingfire.com to sign up for the
newsletter and be entered into this
month's and all future newsletter prize
drawings
you are listening to shaping fire and
i'm your host shango los
my guest today is kawatamak via
guatemakia is a highly respected and
sought-after regenerative soil educator
he is a friend of the microbes student
of their ancient wisdom and teacher of
their ways he has years of experience
working with effective microorganisms
and creating custom soil blends specific
to the needs of the plants he's working
with
he does work in bioremediation of land
and waterways and teaches school kids
these practices he also teaches
indigenous agricultural practices today
we're going to talk about biochar
during the first set we're going to get
a good understanding of what biochar is
during the second set we're going to
learn how to make biochar and in the
third set we learned best practices for
using biochar in your garden of any size
welcome to the show kawatamak thank you
so let's get right into it we've all
probably seen biochar and seen folks
making biochar but let's all start with
a basic understanding of what biochar
actually is
when we take wood and burn it in hopes
of making biochar what is it exactly
that we're hoping to make
what we're trying to do is we're hoping
to
create and leave behind just the carbon
structure of the biomass
that we're
uh burning
and by doing that by just keeping the
skeleton the carbon of the of the of the
biomass this is going to then contribute
so many benefits to the biology of the
soil as we consider life we consider
things need water but we also must
consider how important carbon is as well
and that's what we're going to have when
we made good biochar is a good high
percentage of carbon
um
remaining from the burn
i like that idea that um we're trying to
get ourselves down to the skeleton how
you put that we're kind of like burning
off the fat
um what are the aspects of the wood that
we're trying to
remove
so that we can get to the carbon core
we're gonna we're gonna um burn off all
of the volatile gases from the biomass
and these volatile gases is what's going
to contribute to the fire but as the
heat pressure increases as
this heat pressure is then going to
extract or if you can imagine squeeze
out the volatile gases from the biomass
and hopes of just leaving us those
skeletal remains the carbon
so in a way
we are kind of refining carbon in a way
we're we're taking this beginning
material of wood
and we're getting rid of everything that
we don't necessarily want to use as a
fertilizer and purifying it into
i guess a specialty
carbon exactly and
um
within the structure of that carbon it's
gonna be formed into a shape which is
very similar to a beehive
and that honeycomb structure is then
gonna be
home for
many beneficial microorganisms
nematodes
water nutrients but i think most of all
we got to remember is these bones or
these carbon remains also have
electrical information
about that plant in which it grew in and
this becomes a major contributing factor
in the regenerating growth of the new
successors of that plant
all right i'm gonna i'm gonna bring us
back to the electrical information
in a minute i want to start with your
first point there on um on honeycomb the
honeycomb structure
so um and this may be too vague of a
question but i'm going to give it a shot
anyway
is there any explanation
for why when we burn wood we're left
with the honeycomb i mean it's such a
it's such a unique shape and it's so
detailed um do we know why after we burn
it it looks like that
yeah it's the pattern and the energy in
which drove the force of that plant to
transport water and nutrients up and
down
so you know i call it skeletal remains
but it can also be looked at as veins
but it's the pattern and structure of
that particular um
a plant or tree and this is this becomes
very important because each structure
within each plant and tree is going to
be created differently and it's in the
diversity of those structures which
allow
many different kinds of microorganisms
to then call that carbon home
so each unique structure will foster a
unique set of life forms all right
that's that's totally cool i was not
expecting that badass answer all right
let's let's dig into that a little bit
so first of all um i really like the
idea that um it is showing the
vein structure
of the plant because it
you know this is to my fault as i learn
about plant biology i learned more and
more that that my my understanding that
it's kind of uniform within the plant
and there's just you know
the flesh of the plant and then the
outside is just a real misunderstanding
of what's going on in the interior
botany of the plant and i don't think
i've ever thought about that until now
because i've i've seen what biochar
looks like up close and it is so
detailed and and you know you've got
you've got pits here and elongated bits
there and and and if you're telling me
that that the burning reveals the guts
of the plant this is telling me that the
inside of the living plant is far far
more complex than i am imagining as a
cultivator
we're just scratching the surface on
this thing you know we've
looked at the plant in so many different
ways
but now as we're looking at
the electrical influences that shape the
plant
and we get into this fourth phase water
we realize how electric these things are
and anything electric is going to need
conductivity and just like we see
mycelium growing differently and
threading differently these patterns in
nature they repeat themselves because
they work
so we're finding these patterns and how
they relate to not just mycelium or
plant growth but your own human body
there's so many patterns within
everything
that it's just become so ex and this is
what makes the work so exciting because
i'm just a farmer i'm not a scientist
never have been but the excitement of
watching patterns and shapes
you can see the relations and how
they all come together mm-hmm
so let's let's let's tie into the
electrical info because now you've hit
on it twice and i gotta admit like i
i've gotta know that there is our
electrical impulses in
plants as there are through all of
nature but to
hear you
talk so quickly about the uh the
electrical info or the electrical
history of the plant i i must admit i
don't exactly even know what you mean by
that so so break that out a little bit
for us okay so if we think of like a
forest and how that grows
and how important the fire is to that
forest to continue to grow and stay
healthy so it's not overran with
invasives
we can see where that fire as it comes
through and burns and leaves behind its
skeletal structure
that that new plant that grows the new
seed that grows is always stronger than
the original plant
now
when we think of storing information in
carbon this is nothing new all of our
phones and computers all use carbon that
we call silica
and
the basis of loading information onto
the silica so we can access it when we
need information we can just whip our
phones out and get it we've never
contributed or related that to the
forest itself
when we leave behind the carbon
structure of the parent grandparent
plants that have burned and their carbon
is in the soil their successors can do
the same thing they can tap into that
carbon they can know the relationships
their parents and grandparents had
meaning trees
and how those symbiotic relationships
worked because it's in the carbon
structure of the char
and this is what makes the forest
so intelligent
and evolves the way that it does because
it stores information and even now we
realize there's microorganisms these
electron microbes that can join together
create a force that can influence a
lightning strike into an area
you can see where the forest fire is not
random
but more of a specific we need to create
memory here the microbes somehow decide
influence a lightning strike to
carbonize
because this is how the planet has done
it for so long so these patterns are
nothing new they've always have happen
we mimic them as we develop computers
and software even as we talk biochar we
would
have we're used to doing this with
farmers and conservationists and groups
like that but now we're getting the
semiconductor industry in the workshops
because they're looking for other carbon
sources besides silica to create
computers
and things like cannabis
and hemp are testing at 200 percent more
semiconductor potential than other
materials
this is why we're now seeing the
computer guys at the workshops asking
questions about the electrical side of
things
where
the sky's the limit with carbon
and we're just scratching the surface
the idea that biochar could be
you know a natural hard drive for nature
is like you know truly mind-blowing
right um
so
it
how literally should we take this idea
let's say that we've got a hugelkultur
we're throwing biochar in it and then
we're growing our cannabis plants on top
and the roots are going down and they
come in contact with the biochar and up
until our conversation i've been just
imagining that moment is about two
things it's about
the nutrition fertilization for my plant
coming in contact with the biochar
because it loves that um
that pyrogenic carbon um but but then
and then also it is touching the bio the
roots of my cannabis plant are touching
the biochar which is a home of microbes
and so it's providing them a variety of
shelter too so that's cool but but now
you've added something else which is
this this carbon from the now deceased
and biochard plant
that there are at a very simplistic
level data points that are stored in
this carbon
if we want to get a little more poetic
about it maybe it's like the story of
the tree that is being passed on to my
cannabis plant like like
like i i guess i don't even know what
i'm asking here how literally should we
take this fact that there's information
going from the tree
to my cannabis plant okay so we know
that plants could communicate through
terpenes and when the plants have more
information when they have learned a
great deal of information from being
under the stars growing under the sun
being in contact with carbon that
information then transfers into what we
know as terpenes
now
when we test cannabis that's grown and
this is what i love about the legal
industry now we us as the old farmers
everyone we always knew we had flavorful
herb but now we're to have the terpene
test
and we can see those terpenes are
getting higher and higher with the more
carbon or more information we're able to
work with that plant and this is what
makes it so exciting and when we send
this stuff into extract
where typically the capture of the oils
under
normal organic farming they were about
four percent of the capturing uh oil out
of biomass and extraction
we've got the number up to seven percent
there's way more information or what the
bosses say oil there's way more oil now
in the flower and then aside from that
we've doubled and tripled the terpene
scores which for me that's the most
important number i'm looking at because
then that is telling me that we are
working with the plant closely together
and that plant is going to have more
information to then share with the human
who's going to consume it
and that's why when we smoke the good
herb with the good flavor you're going
to ask yourself who grew this where did
it grow
if you don't know the name you want to
know the name of it and the parent of
that plant
so when we're growing cannabis we've
taken cannabis from a
it's it you know from a very um
money driven industry but there's
cultures where
this is exactly how the cannabis plant
was raised the more
the cultivator grows and becomes a
better person as they work with the
plant the plant knows the intention and
that information or what we call
terpenes is starting to increase
and this is why special growers not just
with cannabis whether you're doing
farm food or grapes wine there's certain
things where you can do the same inputs
but if the heart of the farmer is not in
the position of continuing to want to
grow and make
and improve himself
then that information becomes limited so
the ultimate goal when we grow these
plants is really about
how we can become better humans but then
at the same time the information in
which those are gonna people are to
consume those plants
you have got to hope that that's the
same thing that's going to happen when
they take on the information so for me
information is translates and into
terpenes and into more oil so there's of
close relation we just have somehow
missed the mark because we get i mean
when you're doubling your oil production
they start counting the stacks of cash
they're not thinking about what we just
talked about but me who always wants to
improve myself i realize man that is can
only be done with a close relationship
to the plant
to the soil and to the people who are
going to consume that plant
envisioning who they are
and carrying that with you as you work
out there in the field that's the
information the plan needs it's also an
indictment of large-scale
automated growing too because the more
large the more you scale and the more
you automate
the less the interaction
less interaction the farmer has with the
plant and you know it's no joke that
highly automated commercial flower is
gonna have lower terpene profiles than
than slower than smaller scale deeply
loved plants
and um
you know and and and your argument is
that you know
if the farmer's not involved and the
terpenes uh percentages are lower
um it is very true that the cultivator
is communicating less with the actual
toker and that's a really interesting
idea
yeah and um yeah those are the kind of
things where
as we strive to grow the best we have to
realize we're also trying to grow our
best self
and it's so closely related to
how those things go hand in hand right
on so so let's talk about this specialty
carbon that we are um
uh that we're trying to refine out of
the wood
so so um you know they call it pyrogenic
carbon of course but but why why is this
carbon so uh effective and so uh well
hell it's also expensive right if you
buy it what's so special about pyrogenic
carbon compared to other carbon sources
that we could feed our plants
um so what we're going to look at is
how the carbon is going to react within
the soil and there's so many soil types
people have around the country
some people you know they use a lot of
water some don't
it just seems like the carbon is allows
for that forgiving factor
and
let's be real when people are learning
to grow or they're
trying to increase something
uh terpenes or something they always
want to use more of the formula
so i'm finding like with the biochar
it has such a forgiveness factor on not
only the water that we're using the
ingredients that we're using
but when we wanted to go too much it it
seems to be a buffer and and keep our ph
in a range that's going to be favorable
for the plant
um
and then that being said when our plants
are growing we don't realize our soil is
like a battery and if we're draining
from
the battery it's gonna have less and
less energy to supply the plant
especially as the plant develops and
grows bigger
um so the char allows for
the energy to be kept up in the soil but
also calculating as the plant gets
bigger all of the sunlight hitting the
leaves are making sugars pump out of the
roots
what's happening are you calculating all
those sugar productions or are you just
calculating your drops when it comes to
soil health
so when i have the bio char and i'm
getting the sugar production
that's exactly what i want when it comes
to growing microbes so it seems to just
allow the microorganism development to
thrive much
more efficiently i mean with permanent
housing come on who wouldn't thrive you
know hard it has hard permanent housing
it has water it has food electricity
that's everything you need to live so
these are the kind of things that we
have to consider when
we're developing soil in your
description of it it sounds like
pyrogenic carbon is kind of like a a
a flexible knowing athletic carbon like
good for any soil in the country can
change and mold itself to what you need
it to be it sounds like it's
it's kind of like a um you know super
carbon you know or something it's it's
it's the
it's a it's a carbon goal that is just
going to simply outperform our other
usual sources
definitely and you mentioned the cost
you know the cost is like super high
right now but what fascinates me is
the usda just came off of a program
where they're giving away char free
every farmer in the country i was
talking about this the whole time we got
very little cannabis people to sign up
but tons of hazelnut farmers but here's
what's happening
the um
usda is understanding how
we're developing food with no carbon
it's like
making houses without a building code
so by them supplying the carbon free to
the farmers they're going to be able to
continue to collect data
and then they're going to send out
portable um biochar units so that the
farms can collect by their own biomass
and convert on site so my point is the
agencies now are seeing the value of
char and trying to get it in the hands
of people now so now it's up to the
people to do their homework to figure
out okay is were they just talking this
good thing to sell us biochar or is it
something good for the soil so when i
see the usda now getting involved i mean
if you're doing something other than
cannabis you know about
the the food production issues we have
for that for for our areas especially
low-income areas
this is why they're trying to chart
everybody so we can have sustainable
food so it's just not for
driving your cannabis up to a certain
level
but it's really about developing soil
for long-term
investment and we have major players now
giving it to people free well right on
it's too bad that um that uh we didn't
have this conversation before the usda
biochar program
was completed because this would have
been a great plug to get more cannabis
people involved hopefully they'll do it
again
yeah and shingle for sure when um next
time if it happens i'll contact you as
soon as i get the info so we can
continue to support um community use
yeah yeah i'd love to support you i
would love to support that message okay
so let's let's circle back around to the
advantages of the biochar now that we've
got a better idea of you know what it
physically is
so um
when people ask you what the advantages
to their cannabis plant is
what do you tell them
it's going to improve the immune system
of that plant
which then is going to help fight off a
lot of diseases and pests
so i mean it's just like a healthy
person so i'm always trying to encourage
them that
by having a healthy plant you're going
to be able to avoid many things um down
the road that cause
failure in our crops
so it's it's not that the biochar itself
is necessarily changing the plant it's
that the biochar is you know providing
homes for
the microbes so that there's a buffet of
nutrition in the soil and that it is uh
good at holding water and so the plant
is less likely to dry out and the
in the um
rhizosphere is less likely to have the
microbes cyst up it's it's a is it kind
of essentially a soil regulator and it's
through that regulation that the plant
is going to have better color and better
structure and better pest resistance
yes but also keep it in mind like each
cannabis plant is going to have specific
microbes that they're partnering with
that you know we call the endophytes now
and if we don't make a home for these
microbes to go
in and out of the plant
and keep going through the loop
then that's really what is going to
drive that the healthy soil and the
healthy plant is fostering the microbes
in which that plant really wants to
partner with and you know we can drop in
inputs from all kinds of a beautiful
creations but essentially what i'm
thinking is
the plant does want to partner with a
lot of the beautiful natural farming
drops we're doing
but it also has like a special group of
partners it already has inside of it it
carried from seed
and
allowing for those little guys to
continue to live whether in the plant or
out of the plant in my char
no
just no i know that i have the a team
for each plant because each plant has
their own different one i have the a
team supported and that gives me a way
better chance of success
right on all right so um
uh before we go to break i would like to
hit on the water retention we've already
mentioned it a couple times but
a lot of people i know this is the first
reason why they go to biochar because
you know
many of us especially
container farmers right a little less so
folks who are directly in the ground but
definitely for container farmers
we do this um this whiplash thing where
um the the the container goes from
too dry and the microbes are cysting up
and the soil is getting hydrophobic
to suddenly we're trying to make up for
it and we are
um making the soil too wet then
and then so now it's too wet and it's
waterlogged and we're we're um
um we're choking everything out from
oxygen and then we let that dry out and
then then oh my gosh then then in a
couple weeks we were too dry again and
the swinging back and forth we keep on
hampering our microbes
and
people say well that hasn't happened
since i've i've i've started using
biochar so so talk to us a little bit
about the water retentive capabilities
and water
equalizing abilities of biochar
yeah so in a lot of applications where
we're using the biochar and this is
anywhere between five to fifteen percent
we're able to cut that water down in
half and just like you mentioned the way
the water um
enters into the soil or pot and then
respires back out it's all it makes all
the difference on how that plant grows
but with the char since all that those
little pieces are holding water
it's distributed back to the system
seems to be much much slower and it's
just much better for the plant
and we've we've seen
some operations they're doing about two
gallons a day
on full grown plants do fine and even
better
after char was applied at um one gallon
per day and this is mixed into the rows
or if they
another another section they did they
just dug out maybe about 10 gallons of
soil mix the char into there and then
put it back into the hole and planted
the cannabis plant and you couldn't tell
the difference
physically from the plants where the
char was tilled in or the plants where
the char was just put into the hole they
physically
looked the same and same amount of water
the only difference was when they went
to lab
the um char with the the rose with the
char in the row
scored higher
but um
plants still physically looked really
good from
from the lesser amount of char
right on so so if it makes your water go
further and it holds your water
longer and it um
it's almost like um
over time it gives the soil its own slow
drip of water instead of a flood
definitely and then when you think of
like below
all that where all the all the water's
leaching down into when you have um the
micronized char headed further down into
the soil system it starts to
aggregate the soil differently the
biofilms are different and all of these
contribute to water holding capacities
when you have these um things going for
you that micronized biochar is probably
at the core of why biochar regenerates
uh abused and old soil right
yeah it's one of my favorites they have
yeah because you can also put those in
drip lines they don't clog up it's so
micronized yeah oh wow and yeah and it
just keeps sinking deeper and deeper
through the soil
um it's definitely more costly
to use that very fine activated they
have even activated carbon style but the
results are so quick and they can
integrate into many systems whether
you're doing hydroponic or or soil
so these are always like the one quick
shot if they allow me to do anything to
their system well pump into some very
fine micronized char and the electrical
charge back to their soil always
translates into plants praying that then
that's where you get more and more work
when people see their plants lift
that's when they're become more
receptive and it doesn't take long when
you add the char there is just something
about the healthy glow of a praying
cannabis plant to make you believe in
the strategy you're using isn't there
it's just it i think i think it makes
every cultivator glow with pride
no that's really how we know right i
mean when you come to work the next day
after a drop
and they're doing that i call it plant
yoga
though because the cells are just so
hydrated they're reaching
you can just it looks like they're
stretching it's a yoga
and
it's nothing better than to come to work
in the morning and see him doing that
hell yeah that's beautiful all right so
we're gonna take our first of two short
breaks and be right back when we come
back uh in set two we're going to talk
about um uh choosing wood for making
biochar and how to make biochar and uh
and some best practices uh you are
listening to shaping fire and my guest
today is kawamok via
without these advertisers shaping fire
would not happen so please support them
and let them know you heard them on
shaping fire
for years organic cultivators have been
looking for a peat moss replacement peat
moss has long been the go-to soil
amendment for water retention and
container growing but organic growers
are recognizing now that peat moss is an
unsustainable resource and the mining of
peat bogs destroys wetland habitats and
releases sequestered carbon but peat
moss works so well that many have
continued to use it now there is finally
a revolutionary replacement for peat
moss that provides better benefits while
being a sustainable choice
pit moss sounds an axe like peat moss
but instead of being mined from fragile
ecosystems is actually made from
upcycled organic paper and cardboard
headed for landfills
pit moss is excellent at retaining water
in your substrate and creating air
pockets and tiny living environments for
microbes pit moss instantly increases
aeration nutrient absorption and water
conservation too
carefully and locally sourced pit moss
is the result of decades-long research
into the use of recycled paper fibers
pit moss is lightweight and easy to use
and pin moss is inert so it won't change
your ph
available in a range of preparations
including a nutrient enhanced blend and
an organic soil conditioner with no
added nutrients pit moss is also
available as an animal bedding for
horses chickens and small animals
you can say 15 percent with the discount
code shaping fire one word no caps when
shopping on
pitmoss.com so go to pittmoss.com now to
learn more that's p i t t
m o s s dot com
growing healthier stronger more
sustainable plants
pit moss
there are so many seed banks nowadays
that you really have options in who to
choose not only that if you pick the
wrong seed bank you could be in for a
really sketchy ride and that's only one
of the reasons i recommend hembra
genetics collection to my friends and
listeners who are looking for a seed
bank that's hembra spelled h-e-m-b-r-a
hembra is not just another seed bank
hembra is a woman-operated boutique
cannabis genetics provider that only
sells thoughtfully curated seeds from
the top names in cannabis breeding with
over 50 breeders and over 500 strains to
choose from you will certainly find
something you'll love
hemorrhage genetics has something for
everyone with over 350 feminized strains
200 regular varieties and over 100 auto
flowers to choose from
names you know you can trust like
humboldt seed company night owl
cannerado in-house genetics fast buds
and gnome automatics
we both know that there are other seed
banks who will take your money but have
no customer service
i invited hembra to advertise on shaping
fire after hearing so many good stories
about them from my friends
they have a plus customer service with
lightning fast response times
in most cases helene and caitlin will
get your order out the same day you
place it and you'll usually receive your
seeds in just a few days
most seed banks are simply not this
organized or interested in getting your
seeds to you this fast but hembra cares
you even get free seeds with every order
helene and caitlin get it they have been
in the cannabis growing scene for over a
decade
so save a few bucks by using this
discount code too use the code shaping
fire all one word at checkout to save 10
off your order
buy seeds from good folks who will get
you great seeds reliably every time
visit hembra genetics.com today that's
hembra genetics
[Music]
as cannabis regulations become more
demanding and consumers become more
educated it is increasingly important to
avoid the use of chemical pesticides
when cultivating cannabis
beneficial insects have been used for
decades by the greenhouse vegetable and
ornamental plant industry and today many
cannabis cultivators are moving from
sprays and chemicals to beneficial
insects
covert has the beneficial insects mites
and nematodes microbials sticky cards
and air distribution units you need to
partner with nature to defend your
garden
whether you manage acres of canopy or
have a simple grow tent in your home
copert is ready to help answer your
questions and help you transition away
from chemical sprays towards clean and
natural solutions
since 1967 culprit has assisted growers
in identifying pests and devising
reliable solutions while providing
healthy insects and mites that will
protect your yield
since the 1990s cobra has been a leader
in cannabis pest and disease control
worldwide and have highly trained
consultants to assist you in canada and
the united states from coast to coast
with their global network of growers
support cobert can help
visit copert.com choose your country and
get detailed information that's covert
k-o-p-p-e-r-t
dot com
for the most up-to-date cannabis related
biological control information you can
also check their instagram at covert
canada
you know getting away from pesticides is
good for health and good for business
and culprit is ready to help
visit cobert.com today
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire i am your host shango los
and my guest today is quatermakia so
before the break we were talking about
what exactly biochar was
and the advantages to the plant to the
rhizosphere uh in the soil and you know
pretty much the the the earth itself
and certainly the now uh uh microbes
having homes are definitely stoked too
but um this set we're gonna talk more
about actually how to make biochar
because as we talked about in the first
set
if you're gonna buy biochar
um it's actually quite expensive and um
it's really not that hard to make and
and like many things in our cultivation
scene
um you know
thing you know it's time or money right
you can save a lot of money if you make
your own ferments instead of buying your
own fertilizers and in the same way
if you've got enough time um if you make
your own biochar you can have a super
powerful ally to your cultivation
without actually having to pay your
hard-earned money for it so so let's
start by talking about what kind of wood
we should use now during the first set
you said that
you know these different types of woods
they have got
different
botanicals
[Music]
setups inside of the plant inside of the
tree inside of the shrub whatever we're
gonna make the biochar out of and those
provide different types of homes for
different microbes so that's great but i
i would believe that you know over the
years you have tried to make biochar out
of lots of different types of wood and
and you've got to have some of your
favorites and for good reason so so talk
to us about what you think through when
you're choosing the wood you're going to
use for a biochar burn
okay so as i mentioned before one of my
favorite personal plants it's the
cannabis and implant um first of all
because in our industry nobody does
anything with the stems
and being that they're 200 more
conductive than other chars that just
allows for
more more electricity in my soil
and um
i get to close the loop too in our
industry by bringing that in into uh
like we're doing at a veggie farm here
at the island where i live i'll grab the
cannabis stocks from the producers on
the island and then bring them to the
veggie farm over at topaz farm where
we'll use it to grow vegetables
but uh my second favorite would be
blackberry
blackberry if you think of the inside
pulpy material inside of that blackberry
when it chars all of that pulp turns
into this beautiful
crystallization that is easily
micronized at that point
and who doesn't have a lot of blackberry
up here in the pacific northwest yeah
right yeah yeah so that one's been super
cool but i love doing like the hardwoods
too any of the hardwoods are gonna just
get so hot
and burn at a temperature where you're
just gonna be able to add in other
materials to them because the hardwoods
are burning so hot i can maybe add in
other kinds of wood i'm maybe not too
crazy about but because of the high heat
it's going to give me a different matrix
of honeycomb structure
and that's what really excites me um is
the matrix of the honeycomb
but really it's
i love to see what people bring
we opened up at our farm for the
community just to drop off their biomass
just so we can convert as much as
possible
and i was finding like the the apple
prunings
just made an amazing char as well so
it's a whole discovery
i learned off of grapevines those were
the first
conversion piles that we did out in napa
and when they would rotate the vineyards
they usually would take them to the
dumps but we started turning them into
biochar
and
just incredible incredible char coming
from the grapevines i gotta admit i'm
really surprised that you are are
talking about let alone preferring what
i think of as soft plants like um like
the cannabis and hemp stocks and the
blackberry versus hardwoods i really
thought that that the answer to the
question was you were just going to tell
me a varieties of of trees that you
liked um i'm really surprised that and
and we'll talk more in detail about how
you know like how to manage the biochar
burn in a couple minutes but i'm really
surprised that that those soft
fleshed plants can be used at all
um because they're so soft i would
assume that they would just like burn
right up
yeah but let's think for a minute
shingle if we're doing some cannabis
breeding
and i'm working with this plant trying
to look for specific trait
the plant knows what i'm looking for
maybe it couldn't get there on that
on that journey but the seeds that come
out of it if i don't put those skeletons
of that plant back into the soil
it i just seemed like it would take
longer to achieve
the characteristics in which i'm looking
for
so by adding the bones in of
the pla the last breeding
cycles
i think shortens the duration of what
you're looking for
because the information then can get
passed to the new seed where it's parent
information can to say hey you know that
farmer that's growing us he's looking
for these specific terpenes if by chance
you can grow them
let's let's increase that and this is
the strange way of the cannabis plant
but you can see where if there's any
legs to it at all
you can really quicken and improve and
become more targeted
in the cannabinoid
research you're doing by adding in the
old plants so that's why i like to use
not only my old cannabis that i've
worked with but cannabis from other
farms too because it essentially is
cannabis and it's going to be talking to
the new cannabis
just something i think is special about
that relation well yeah definitely
something special i gotta i gotta tell
you you know i
i wouldn't i don't necessarily consider
myself especially spiritual i mean i
meditate and all but but
compared to the kind of ideas that that
you're
laying out uh you know these are these
are mostly new to me i say um humbly um
[Music]
this idea that you are bringing forth
that
um the
if the plants are holders of data and
stories and and how to repair the soil
and if when we
burn them into biochar it is
um
refining the carbon down to its basics
and that carbon is holding memory just
like the carbon silica holds memory in
our iphones
and if this is
you know feeding the memories back into
the earth
it really
creates a whole different
motivation and intention for all of us
as humans
to
take all of our
natural wastes our organic waste and
turn it all in the biochar and put it
back into the earth because like duh why
wouldn't we
and you know that that whole that whole
package of idea right there is all brand
new to me
yeah and i kind of like to picture as
you know we have computer programmers
right and they are loading software on
computer to run specific apps
if you think about what you're doing
when you're making char
you're a nature programmer
and that char can be in the soil for
hundreds
thousands of years it can have that
information
and we'll get into it a little bit later
but
there's other ways you can load
information onto the char too
where the reality of you are really a
co-creator and program in nature
becomes the reality you can create the
chart specifically
from the good healthy blocks of the
vineyard that you have
then create char with that information
that you can put into the less
healthier blocks
and continue to co-create and regenerate
soil that way
right on that's awesome all right so um
so we've talked about um your favorite
types of wood and why we want to use
different types of woods because they
make different types of housing
structures and then they carry different
kinds of information
how about the worst to use are there any
are there any types of woods that you
have come across where you're like okay
most all of them are great but this one
is really not going to get you where you
want to go is there any wood that we
should avoid
no but you do want to avoid using wet
wood you can buy a moisture meter i
think they're about 40.
you want to use wood that's between a 15
and 22 percent moisture
any biomass within that range
it's gonna combust beautifully
the only problem you'll have is when
you're using wood that's wet that'll you
make a lot of smoke if temperature may
not go up
and making the biota in the pacific
northwest because we re it rains so much
this is very important because you don't
want to make char and create a bunch of
smoke if char is made correctly
you can use that smoke to drive the
combustion
so moisture meter will
keep you from all wood is good you just
got to make sure it's dry all right so
for for all of us cultivators who cut
corners
um i happen to be one often
unfortunately
and we don't have moisture meters
clearly a freshly cut tree is going to
have the highest percentage of moisture
whatever that may be
i do have a fireplace though right and
so i am very used to the idea of taking
down a tree
and bucking it
and then putting it in piles and then
it'll be good
the next year
can you give us like like i don't know
just like a a rule of thumb or some
guesses for us
about how long after we take down a tree
before it would be good for
um for making biochar is i mean is is it
the same strategy as as
you know making effective firewood or or
is it faster than that
yeah so if we had our trees stacked from
our cuttings from the spring they should
be dry enough to burn in the fall okay
um a lot of times too if we make the
piles but throw a tarp on the top
they'll release enough water so we can
burn like if i cut piles in the fall
but threw a tarp on them
by springtime
they wouldn't have taken in all the rain
water and released their water it'd be
good to use
but there's always a chance where if i
wanted to do a burn and i had some
material that was kind of wet but if i
had
three quarters percent of that pile was
really dry
you could integrate and mix
the two
and get a full combustion from from the
material all right so there's certain
little tricks you can do sometimes
mixing really dry
with wetter material or how you stack it
or even with some of the kiln
technologies where you can use stuff a
little bit wetter
but typically if it snaps
you know the rounds that snap you're
good to go
all right there needs to be a uh some
kind of a
a saying there if it snaps it caps or if
it snaps it you know
something to make a bumper sticker out
of um so
um i'm assuming that there's probably a
good conversation to be had right here
about moving wood you know how
they say don't move firewood from one
part of your state to the other because
you're moving all sorts of um
uh insects or or non-indigenous bugs
that you might be helping spread around
your state
i'm guessing that's probably the same
when you're making biochar i can imagine
people collecting wood at place a
and then moving it to place b to turn
into biochar where it's more convenient
for them um
we probably shouldn't do that should we
yeah there's times where that can be uh
very dangerous ecological wise
um but i mean there's times where some
biomass can be moved you have to look at
how it's collected where it's stacked
you know try not to put like a blanket
rule on this thing where we have to
sequester carbon we have there's that's
a fact
and so we have to figure out the
materials that we can and cannot use and
there's methods where we can employ that
convert the biomass right on site
so there's many ways we can get the
conversion done but maybe not just with
one particular tool
so
all of us who are natural farmers are
very much into imo um
indigenous microorganisms the
microorganisms that are in your locale
in your neighborhood they're your
neighbors and so let's do what we can to
beef them up and use them in your local
gardening
and i can imagine that same kind of idea
might go for uh the the trees and other
plants that we use to make biochar where
if if if we're saying like you did in
the first set that our trees are holding
you know
memories if you will of how to beat a
particular pest that it beat several
years ago
and you know it's still cellular
knowledge for the plant
that that it might make sense to
focus on making biochar with the kinds
of plants
and even source them locally because
locally sourced plants are going to
provide a biochar that has got
memory of your area what do you think of
that
that's what that's the direction it's
going all the conservation agencies now
employing the prescription burns that
they call them um forestry groups that
are doing in place conversions this is
exactly why
because you can't import those goodies
they're created on site and must be left
on site
it's happening 100 all right cool
all right so let's start let's start
going through
um a process of
uh making uh biochar now i've seen
biochar i mean there may be many ways
but i've only seen two i've seen people
who dig a hole in the ground
that's pretty deep and has got pretty
steep sides and they throw everything
inside of that and they burn it and then
i see people who are using
um
like uh what do you call those things
like um
metal metal things that are round
kilns
sure kilns kills
drums that's what i was looking for kill
kills is a pretty sexy name i just met
like i just meant like like oil drum
looking things so uh so so what
what are
what which do you prefer and does it
matter
okay
when it comes to making char
most people on farms are just doing
burn piles
you know and they're burning their waste
so what we try to encourage them to do
instead of just burning their waste if
they employed a different burn technique
to their traditional burn piles they can
be left with char the method in which
we're teaching them is referred to as
the conservation method
the conservation method is simply when
you light that pile of biomass and these
biome you have to check your at your
local regulations for maximum pile size
but what you're going to do instead of
lighting throwing a bunch of gas and
lagging that pile on fire what you want
to do is torch the top
you want to put smaller material and
create a type of a bird's nest if you
will
bird's nest where it when you light that
fire if you light it from the top at
that bird's nest
when that little bird's nest starts to
burn and combust
it's going to excite the biomass just
below it
and as it heats up and
and excites that biomass the gases are
going to come out of the wood and fuel
that little light on top
now
as that little light on top is burning
its smoke is going to you'll notice
smoke start going into the top of that
toplet fire
smoke is actually
um combustible and we don't realize that
when we make our fires but by lighting
at the top and allowing the smoke to
come back into the flame it's gonna
drive that top fire even hotter so the
more smoke that's coming out it's
actually the fuel for that fire at the
top and this is what's so cool about is
because you don't no longer have those
particulates going up into the air but
coming into the flame front for
combustion you could reduce the
particulates from these burn piles where
you've seen them at the farm smoking out
all the neighborhood
but if that smoke is going into the
flame front driving the combustion that
chocolate fire is going to get bigger
and bigger and heat that pile up so that
the volatile gases get released from the
fire
killing and combusting all the smoke
this is where the practice of the ark
comes in a conservation burn as that
fire burns that pile down you're going
to notice the white little ash on the
top of the material
that's the part where you want to
extinguish the fire
so that you don't turn the carbon into
ash the ash is basically oxidized carbon
but you do want to get the gases out so
learning when to pull the trigger on
that fire
takes some practice there's a ton of
really cool videos on youtube where
people are
using conservation burn with different
size piles and materials but you'll be
able to notice when they cool that fire
down and this is the part where the
natural farmers you guys are going to
love because
when that fire carbon is in flux and in
heat it basically has a memory that's
neutralized and is pretty much waiting
to receive new information the hotter i
drive the carbon the more i erase the
old memory from that now you say well
you said v has a lot of good memory why
do you want to erase it
well this case there are times where i
want to erase some memory from carbon to
load it up with new memory and the new
memory is essentially
all of the great ferments that i've been
creating and these ferments can be from
your healthiest plants or like i
mentioned your healthiest parts of the
soil
if you can record
that information of healthy soil in a
liquid t form added to your water at the
cooling process you're going to then add
more memory to that carbon and this is
where you get even more exciting because
you are essentially programming the
carbon now when they discovered the
terra preda pits which means um black
earth the biochar pits in 1960 um
cornell university went down to the
amazon to look at these
carbon pits that were 10 to 15 feet of
biochar but alongside them were japanese
scientists and the japanese scientists
did tests on the biochar that is still
in america we don't do and they not only
looked at its physical properties but
they're very interested in its
electromagnetic properties and in
particular its potential to cast out
what we know as far infrared far
infrared has the ability to have
microorganisms self-divine we know that
as mitosis
it's a type of uh of a thermal type of a
heat but at the same time it's also a
vibration it's like hearing your
favorite songs while you're working and
this just gets the microbes cooking and
going but when the japanese scientists
left the um left amazon in the 1960s
they came back and they started playing
with what we know today as bio ceramics
and these are simply ceramics silica
quartz
like the quartz crystal that you you
guys sit around your house or you know
quartz crystal will grind those down and
fire them at 2000 degrees to erase the
memory but then cool it they'll cool it
with the em effective microbes and they
create this amazing bio ceramic so japan
has been playing with many forms of bio
ceramic whether they're mineral
influenced or in dr higa's case with em
microbial influence but their physical
ability to cast electromagnetic
frequency in the far infrared at about
12 to 15 inches away from the bag
lets you know like we are we know
nothing about
uh there's so much more to learn so when
we create our car our our carbon and our
biochar and we keep in mind that the
principles that adding in these
high-power microbial teas are then going
to create a physical and electromagnetic
property to the char i hope a grad
student will pick up on
testing different electromagnetic
potentials of char created under
different um imo recipes
and different consortias that could
potentially increase the regeneration
capacity of soil
all right so much in what you just said
so
i'm going to go all the way back to the
conservation pile
but i want to tell folks that anybody
who was just turned on by this idea of
bio ceramics um i uh i had the
opportunity of hearing quaterma talk
about
bio ceramics uh in the past and it it
sounded unreasonable to me and so i
looked it up and the stuff really exists
and it is very effective and some of the
trials that they have done
just putting bioceramics near other
products that you know improved their
like improved taste of wine and things
like this is like truly amazing you know
oh so we're not we're not gonna we're
not gonna go down that path today but um
it is it is an amazing truth that that
you might want to google bio ceramics so
with that said let's let's go all the
way back to the conservation piles and
um i found it interesting that what you
know we're going to take our burn pile
and we're actually really going to just
make a a small fire at the top of the
burn pile
instead of just like torching the hell
out of the entire burn pile at the same
time because what we want to do is
create this physical nature of the pile
where the fire at the top is going to be
pulling oxygen up through
the
burn pile and so it's going to be
creating heat and hot more and more heat
in the burn pile but really burning from
the top so so really the burn pile
itself becomes a fuel source for this
smaller fire
that's at the top
and and then you said well that you know
it when you're done that's also where
you are going to extinguish your fire
before it turns to ash
with water so that you're left with the
biochar instead of just you know
powdered ash
and and then you said
take a look on youtube
for
videos so that you can get a visual
representation
of what we want the biochar pile to look
like when we put it out like like at
what point do we put it out now now that
is probably really good advice to turn
people to youtube to to learn that what
that looks like but if you had to
describe it to us without the video
what would you tell us to look for to
know when to stop that burn pile and we
know we've got biochar and so we don't
get ash
the pile should be collapsed all the way
down you should have at least 90 percent
of the charcoal
i should start seeing a little bit of
white ash coming in
sometimes i use mixed woods so there's
going to be some pieces that still are
burning
but um they're not going to have enough
time to convert or i'll lose a bunch of
the small pieces so looking at what to
separate what to cool i'll even pull off
some of the bigger pieces sometimes with
the rake and then move them to the next
pile because we'll have several piles
going and then at that point once i see
that pile has collapsed most of it has
turned white the the um
the fire should be
very little if any coming up at all
that's the point where i want to cool it
down
um and that's the part where i hit it
with water all right fabulous okay so so
one more thing about the burn pile
before before i move on to holes and
trash cans and that is um this converts
conservation style burn pile i'm really
surprised that we're making biochar with
it because
again and i have very limited experience
in biochar when i was reading about it
it was saying that one of the
key aspects of making biochar is that
you're making it in a limited oxygen
environment and that is why people make
it in holes and in um
um
oil drums or other kinds of drums
because when you pack that space
full of wood and then you burn it
there is an interesting
[Music]
biological reaction happening in play
because the area is small and and
the wood cannot the fire cannot get all
of the oxygen it wants to have and so it
burns slightly different i um somebody
commented online that that their wood
can't get or the fire can't get oxygen
drunk right which while i don't know
what that means scientifically it sounds
really cool um so so
so what can you tell me about the
importance of limiting oxygen
when making biochar and why doesn't that
really apply to the conservation pile
style
you'll make a better char for sure the
more oxygen you can limit into it but
the reality is
farmers aren't going to use drums you
can't get big farms to dig all these
holes and the amount of man-hours to
process the char and pits
it's really not feasible for a lot of
farms so the first conservation burn
method i described to you is going to be
the crudest way to make char
but that's the way a lot of big farms
are already burning anyway polluting the
sky
can convert piles
now if you want to make higher quality
char you then are going to move to the
drum technologies where you can get more
oxygen absent from the process and not
to mention you'll capture a lot more
char doing it in oxygen deprived
environments than doing conservation
burn
but the conservation burn is just an
open invite for many farmers who are
already doing the practice to say hey
well let me try this out and typically
once they see the results from that char
naturally you want to make better char
in your next run so that's where the pit
and the drums and the kiln technologies
start to come into play but the
conservation burn is my my gateway
carbon uh entry point all right to get
farmers to use fantastic good
explanation all right so so so we've
gone through the gateway and if we if
we've got a bigger farm you know we're
starting to make our piles and we're all
like biochar hell yeah this is great or
you're a smaller farmer right you're
you're a craft hobbyist you're a home
grower you know where where
we love our cannabis and we want it to
be high-end and
um i mean hell i've got i've got such a
small property it would it would take me
a whole summer to put together that much
biomass because you know i don't have a
big-ass farm so so let's talk about like
you know level two of
of using a a drum so would you describe
how to do a drum process
so typically with the drum we have um
one drum in which your feed stock that
you want to make the char with go
you put all your material into one drum
with holes in that container and then
that drum typically goes into another
drum and on the outside of in between
the drums are going to fill with biomass
and different wood materials
that then get combusted
and as the fire burns it draws out the
volatile gases from the interior drum
leaving you behind with the um with pure
carbon
typically a lot of people use this
method they can get very smoky but you
create very good char this way but just
takes a super long time
yeah you got to find two different sizes
of drums i mean yeah even that sounds
like a pain in the ass all right so so
like let's let's imagine that you have
found these two metal drums one bigger
than the other slightly um you said
they've got holes drilled in them where
are we drilling the holes you're going
to put them on to the side and then down
on the bottom so you can get a nice
draft coming up from from the bottom of
the of the drum so
so like you know a handful of drilled
holes in the sides but then a whole
bunch at the bottom because the idea is
that it's sucking in
the oxygen at the bottom
correct but you also got to make sure
you have enough holes to release the
volatile gases as well
so it's
to me i think this is probably my least
favorite way to make char
because of all the
complications involved of
making sure my holes are the right size
sometimes they put too many in but
that's the only draw you have
so it just seems like it's
it's a it's a tougher learning um
learning curve with with that particular
style the pitch char would be you know
my second favorite all right let's let's
talk about that
break it down
so the pitch are you're going to dig
yourself a hole into the ground and you
kind of want to cone out the shapes if
you look
on your on your pit that you make so you
can have a little a little edge around
the outside of that pit so air can come
in and out of the pit but the trick is
when you light that pit you want to
stack your wood above the ground
so you're about a foot and a half above
that ground level and same thing light
at the top if you light your pit chart
at the top your combustion rates gonna
be
super quick but the best part about the
char pit is you can once you get the
fire up and going and burning i can keep
adding biomass to that pit and as i'm
adding the biomass to the burn pile it's
suffocating the coals underneath
you can create a lot of char pretty
quick it's a beautiful slow kind of a
burn
but you can just keep stacking into the
hole as to where conservation burn
you're limited to the pile you can't
keep adding to it
the pitch are you can keep adding
biomass and create quite a bit of
biomass in a short amount of time and
the quality is just so beautiful and
because you've got so much uh wood
material burning and the hole is deep
and and
and
i guess you'd be limiting the oxygen
right so so you've got the wood that's
got this slow and steady burn because
it's not allowed to get like all out of
control because the oxygen is limited so
so there is our advantage to limiting
the oxygen is so that we get a a slow
and low long char instead of uh here's a
bunch of oxygen and just have it go ape
and and then like just burn to ash
yeah and that's exactly how they feel
too when you're burning those things the
conservation burn is like mad and just
roaring but i mean you know in a
vineyard when they got 20 foot piles
where they usually take all day for
three and four days even sometimes to
burn
that aggressive high temperature burn is
nice because it's only three hours yeah
but the pitch are
super nice super slow good quality and
it's even once you get the fire nice i
can even throw in a little bit wetter
wood
because it's just going to combust all
within the heat so i can
convert more biomass
you know that's probably not favorable
because of that nice calm high heat from
all right hr so so you know it scaling
up like making more biochar once you're
already kind of sold and successful
um is easier than probably doing it the
very first time when you've got to learn
how to do it so so if if if we are for
this example let's say that we're we're
just talking about a home cultivator
let's say that they're just like doing
20 plants or something
and um they want to produce biochar for
the summer um how big and how deep of a
hole
um
is reasonable
like you know i've seen lots of
different holes i mean i see some people
who are using freaking backhoes for them
and then i see like nick risden who just
spent an afternoon digging a freaking
hole that he can stand up in and making
biochar and that and not using the big
old backhoe so like like give us a
little idea of of what this hole is like
and i'd like you to talk about that ring
around the top that you said that helps
bring in oxygen because i didn't i
didn't follow that okay so um man i got
people making the pits as small as like
a barbecue pit oh you know the weber
size
so you people even making it in practice
it in the weber they can make small
piles and get the skill down
and then you know get it figured out
on a small scale but it doesn't need to
be big at all
they can be
just the size of a weber and that's
great for a small cultivator but what
i'm saying about the sides
instead of having the sides of when you
dig your hole being straight down into
the floor
if you can kind of angle that to the
floor
so you're kind of at a um 45 and it
opens up if you look at something called
a tiki khan kiln you'll see the shape of
the tiki khan kiln or what's referred to
as the oregon kiln and how it's kind of
vertically shaped that's the slant size
that we need um
for for that type of burn i understand
what you're saying so so even though we
are making these slanted sides we're not
filling up these slanted sides with
material we're actually just still
stacking up our biochar kind of as a
center column
and and these sides that are at 45
degrees are not filled with wood and
that just allows some oxygen to get down
into our hole correct all right that's
going to be airflow yep got it all right
so does this 45 degrees go all the way
to our bottom or is it just like you
know the top third no it goes from top
to bottom okay so so all right so so
that tells me that like in my head i was
imagining building a pit that's like you
know up to my neck right
that that would take out that would be a
big because because you'd have
to go 45 degrees all the way down to
five or six feet of depth and that's a
really big hole nah just even think of
campfire and it's actually cool because
your family would love if you made a new
campfire spot out there it doesn't need
to be bigger than campfire size but just
the way you describe how you're going to
stack your wood that's going to be the
trick you don't fill the thing up but
you make that center column style all
right so like a three by three hole is
probably all i need for my whole year
especially especially if i'm going to be
adding
more
material as it's burning yeah you're
right plenty of char all right um
this hole and and we've got we've we
started the fire at the top and um it's
you know it's it's it's it's
decreasing the amount of oxygen in the
in the deeper parts of the hole uh and
yet we're still getting good air flow
you know a little bit of airflow from
the 45 degree walls and it's clocking
along and we're throwing in some
additional biochar occasionally um uh
are we are we just leaving the top open
or are we covering it at all
um to extinguish
no no while it's burning
yeah so the trick is
you wanna and it's even referred to as a
flame on the cap
you wanna make sure you keep a flame on
the cap of that pit
because if that flame is what's going to
do all your conversion
and that flame is actually going to keep
oxygen out of your carbon as well
so
keeping if you look at flame cap kilns
or flame cap
pits you'll see how they maintain it
with the the flame on top
and that's gonna be your key
so you may need to add in different size
materials at different times of the
combustion to maintain that ring all the
way around the top that ring of fire on
the top
and
that's going to be your converting um
feedstock into into biochar why doesn't
the flame that that that cap flame why
doesn't it work its way all the way down
so that i've got this like total pyre
as it's releasing gases from the wood
and meeting the oxygen that's our
combustion point there
so it doesn't never oxygen doesn't make
its way down into the carbon for
oxidation
yeah wow this is a real badass skill to
learn
it's so much fun
all right so um
all right so i do want to go back to the
like while we didn't really dig the drum
version i do want to ask one question
that's uh burning good pun um in my mind
and and that is you said that we've got
the two different sizes of drum and
we've got uh burning material in the
center but we've also got wood material
between the two uh layers of drum
um
is the
like are are both the interior and are
both sets of wood going to be used as
biochar or is only one of those sets of
wood going to become bio char good
question only one the one in the
interior drum on the inside
the uh so what's the stuff on the
outside for it that's the that's the
heat that's gonna then excite the
volatile gases from the interior drum
and get it to release
um
without actually being exposed to the
fire all right cool that's good enough
and and you know since it really does
make sense that the vast majority of us
are probably either going to dig a hole
or do a conservation burn we're not
going to go in to do the uh drum within
drum version anymore and and you know if
if we have excited you know listeners to
like go find out more you and i have
done our job right um but as far as as
far as getting you to teach it um i
think that people generally understand
what the drum version would be like and
if they want to explore that there's um
you know
there's there's lots of youtube videos
online all right so let's talk about uh
the end process so um it's been going
for a while we've got this very
successful burn
um uh and and um we have decided it's
time to um put it out because the
material is starting it has has
collapsed and some of the smaller stuff
is starting to get a little ashy
and we want to put it out um
do we just like put water on it how do
we put it out
yeah so we're extinguishing with water
and keeping a rake handy you'll have to
water down the pile and kind of rake the
coals around because they there's just
layers and layers of charcoal under
there
and the bottom layer will stay hot even
though it appears like it's out so
keeping a rake as you're cooling that
char down
it's going to allow that fire to go out
and maintain the carbon
but if you don't put that thing out
right you know you'll come the next day
and everything will turn to ash even
though you thought for sure the fire had
went out oh you'd be so sad yeah i'm
gonna do it all over again
lots of water and all that water gets
soaked back into the char too so it's
not like you're wasting any water at all
right so so the water is definitely uh
you know you you can't use too much
correct the
char is very hydrophobic at first so
it's nice to actually give it a nice
soaking
that water then is going to start to
attract the life forms that you need to
charge up that char or get it inhabited
so the cooling part
is super important and so then we just
leave it in the hole overnight and we
walk away
or you can pull it out if it's cool put
it in storage containers
um
but typically people just leave it until
the next day all right so next day
we look in our hole we've got all this
biochar we're we're going like hell yeah
guadamuck totally hooked me up um i'm so
glad i know this skill and so like now
now what do we do with it um we'll we'll
talk more in the next set about like
when do we want big pieces and when do
we want little pieces but what i'm more
asking you is storage like like what
what do i actually do with that stuff do
i do i go stack it do i do i put it in
some kind of a bin like like how do we
keep this stuff until we're ready to use
it
now you can keep that thing in a pile
outside um
near you know anywhere near soil and the
soils and microbes are going to start
being attracted to it
um so i kind of like to leave it out and
open like that it doesn't sound like we
have to protect it then no no you want
things to come to it oh right you know
yeah so it's usually going to house good
things
um yeah it actually is kind of becoming
it's attracting imo at that point 100
right right on all right okay cool so
let's wrap up this set here and when we
come back we'll start talking about how
to use this stuff uh what a great
episode all right so we're going to take
our second of two short breaks and be
right back you are listening to shaping
fire and my guest today is koatta mcvea
hell yeah
a fully functioning greenhouse grows
extraordinary cannabis flowers that have
exceptional bag appeal great terpene
profiles and exceptional yield
but as we have discussed many times on
shaping fire a greenhouse is only as
good as the environment you create for
the plants inside
biotherm has been on the forefront of
developing and installing highly
efficient greenhouse solutions since
1980.
whether new construction major upgrades
or a retrofit biotherm's cultivation
climate solutions are tailored to each
grower's specifications
they even have root zone heating mats
that attach to a home hot water heater
for growing areas 500 square feet or
smaller
the atmosphere of the growing
environment directly affects the health
and productivity of your crop
biotherm offers heating cooling
dehumidification and co2 enrichment to
optimize the air your plants breathe and
optimize plant growth by enhancing the
elements within the cultivation space
biotherm's dissolved oxygen irrigation
solutions will improve the vitality of
your water and the efficiency of your
hydro delivery system when you implement
biotherm's systemic innovation you'll
experience increased yields improved
plant vigor and increased resistance to
disease and pests
biotherm offers free phone and email
support for everything they sell and
will help you troubleshoot and diagnose
issues to get your equipment back online
the explosion of greenhouse cultivation
has crowded the field with novice
consultants selling unproven gadgets
when you choose biotherm to regulate
your greenhouse environment you know
you're relying on their over 40 years of
experience designing installing and
supporting mission critical greenhouse
technology
your plants deserve nothing less than
biotherm visit
biothermsolutions.com today to learn
more and request a quote
one of the challenges with buying
autoflower seeds is that often you'll
have as many different phenos as you
will have seeds in a pack that can be
fun sure but so many varieties in one
pack is a sign of an immature seed line
that hasn't been worked enough
i prefer my autoflowers to be worked
enough that each pheno in the pack
really captures the aspects that the
breeder was intending
this is why i recommend gnome automatics
to my friends and listeners who grow
automatic flowering cannabis seeds
gnome automatic seeds are not just
crossed and released they are
painstakingly sifted again and again
tested in a wide range of conditions and
taken to a level of maturity that each
plant will be recognizable by its traits
traits that were hard earned so that you
can have your best growth cycle ever
gnome automatics became a trusted and
loved brand in cannabis over the last 10
years as mandalorian genetics and
recently changed their name to gnome
automatics
the only thing that has changed is the
name founder dan jimmy continues to pour
his passion of breeding cannabis into
every variety he releases for you to
grow
check out the gnome automatics instagram
at gnome underscore automatics to see
the impressive plants folks are growing
you can score gnome automatic seeds in
feminized or regular at your favorite
seed provider listed in the vendors
section of their website
farms interested in bulk seeds of more
than a thousand should reach out through
the website too
while on the website be sure to check
out the gnome automatic shirts and other
merch section
if you want reliable seeds hand built
from effort expert selection and
experience choose gnome automatics
once you've discovered the benefits of
using cannabis it's a very small step to
start making your own edibles gummies
lotions tinctures and concentrated oils
at home
magical butter has been helping cannabis
consumers become self-sufficient for
over a decade with the easy to use
magical butter countertop botanical
extractor you can create high quality
cannabis products to your exact
specifications at a fraction of the cost
of store-bought edibles
i talk a lot on this show about the
importance of home growing so you don't
have to rely on others to feel healthy
well the magical butter machine can
empower your personal health by putting
you in control of how you use cannabis
in your daily life
i've been making my own butters and oils
on the stove for years and i much prefer
the ease of using the magical butter
machine i just set it and walk away with
the simple touch of a button the magical
butter machine grinds heats stirs and
steeps your herbal extract all at the
correct time interval and temperature
for the perfect infusion every time
as a result you achieve your desired
infusion easily safely and consistently
check out the magical butter instagram
to see the machine in action and don't
feel like you have to go it alone there
is a huge community on facebook called
magical butter users united sharing
recipes and best practices so you can
learn at your own pace from others who
are already doing it successfully
now is the time to get your own magical
butter machine and save money while
enjoying cannabis
use the discount code shaping fire one
word no caps to get ten percent off
visit
magicalbutter.com today
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire i am your host shango los
and my guest today is guadamac guatemala
all right so here in the third set we
have this beautiful biochar that we have
already made made during set two
and what are we gonna do with it you
know quatermark already told us that we
don't have to keep it safe
it's great to lay it out it's going to
start attracting
microbes from your neighborhood which is
exactly what we want to do with it and
and now we want to use it now granted um
you know in the audience there's lots of
different sizes of gardens right we've
got we've got people who are doing huge
ass huge cultures and then we've got
folks who are using huge ass containers
you know 100 300 gallons and then you've
got like a bunches of people who are
using containers that are like sub 20
gallons and then then then you've got
people who are you know maybe want to
throw some in their house plants too
right because like this stuff sounds
like such magic
i'm gonna want to put it in my like
simple ornamentals right so so let's
let's let's
let's start at the top you know i'm
imagine when you're done with um with a
burn
that that you are seeing these different
sizes and you are starting to think
about what's going to be used for what
can you kind of walk us through your
thought process when you're looking at
this this pile of various sizes
yeah so before i was really anxious to
crush it on make it all the same size
but later on i started to realize how
good it was to have different sizes in
my soil
um
so i kind of leave i do crush a little
bit but i leave it mainly in its raw
form it falls apart pretty good as we
handle it
[Music]
so um
let's say that we're doing a huge let's
start at the biggest size um
[Music]
are you satisfied just for putting your
your big ass pieces your branches or
whatever in there or do you want to have
a variety of sizes in every growing
environment
um
just based on the size that you're into
like like you know small medium small
medium or in large pieces but scaled to
whatever you're growing in
yeah hugo mounds are one of those
recipients where they can actually take
any size and we actually the pieces i
mentioned that don't quite burn
but you can tell they've been charged
just and need more time they're actually
some of the best in the hugo mound
so for the hugo mounds i find them the
most forgiving for all the different
sizes it's when we get into the pots and
containers where i try to stay towards
the smaller
pieces of char
so those those big thick pieces that
didn't fully get charged up they you
know there's they still got hard centers
um we should we shouldn't feel bad about
that that that is going to bring its own
set of advantages to the party and we
certainly shouldn't like ignore it or
not include it um it's just going to be
helping in a different way
yeah it's going to be half google and
half biochar but still contributing to
the system and these are the pieces
where typically we don't know what to do
with them they're not quite char and
they're still kind of woody so the
mounds just take them and do wonderful
things with them all right cool um
when
we are putting the biochar into
assuming that we have dug into the
ground a little bit because like i know
that some people just make hugel mounds
and they don't dig in but but i'm
picturing some amount of digging into
the ground
um
what ratio of the biochar do we want to
have in that hole
you want to go anywhere between 5 and 15
depends on how much you have okay so is
this a a situation where up to 15
more is better
no
um
yeah no not at all
um so
so
how how should we decide whether or not
we want to do use five percent or
fifteen percent like if i have enough to
do fifteen percent should i always do
fifteen percent and stop at that or are
there ever any times where like no
because i'm using this other thing i
should only use five
no i'm just mostly charged so expensive
people don't have it in abundance like
that all right well let's let's say that
like you've made your own right so
you're biochar rich
um you know we would our we would want
to use 15
it sounds like
yeah 15
allows
for
like sometimes if you go too much char
there's this weird little adjustment
period
depending on the kind of char that you
have soil types i just found like 15
on the max
just allows for
good soil development
and not robbing from the host and allows
me and like i'm always planting as soon
as i use the char some people some
people don't do that and especially like
google mountains you know i think if we
use the right biology
i always plant in my hugo mounds as soon
as we create them and a lot of people
this they say no you can't do that
so these are the kind of things where i
found 15 allows me to develop the
ecology i need for that first season and
just keeps me in a good position for
food production for that year or
medicine right on you know i've heard
that often myself people say oh i i just
built this huge culture so we're not
gonna use it this year we're gonna use
it next year but then i've had like a
lot of friends who like build their
hugel culture and they're all like well
you know sure it'll be better next year
but like let's plan it this year and
like get it going and get it primed and
then they grow these like insane plants
that are just incredible and they're
like uh see you know it's gonna be even
better last year but i'm glad i'm glad i
used it this year so so you are
definitely of on team user google call
or use your hugelkultur with biochar
like as soon as you make it
yeah and that's because of the microbes
that i enlist to help me on that if i
was relying on the natural breakdown
microbes they could lock out a lot of
things from my from my garden but since
i'm an em bokachi guy i use a lot of k f
stuff
i know a lot of the drops i'm doing
they're going right in and plus we got
you know foliage uh
treatments that you know on arsenal so
these things allow
for my plant to uptake
and for biology to break down without
growing thermophilic or these other
pathways with all of the wood in the in
the soil could potentially take it right
on that makes a lot of sense so
since you are
um an effective farmer using effective
microorganisms um you're you're actually
using a lot of the playbook of our
natural farming that helps get your
hugel culture up to speed super fast
and same concept too like with char
you're going to read on char where
they're like don't use it raw but with
that same concept if i'm feeding my char
raw
the same way i'm doing my mounds and
those first three four five waterings
are a nice tea that i know have been bio
or bio available for my plant i don't
have to wait before the charging period
it's all being created naturally and
since the ems are just essentially
feeding the imo's for the area
i'm really drawing them into the char i
could do a lot of things where they tell
you you can't do it with raw char but
because of the partnership with specific
microbes and and those goodies
you're able to get away with a lot of
things what i i don't think i understand
what raw char is versus r not raw char
so raw char is what they're going to
describe if you just burnt the biomass
you got the honeycomb structure you
cooled it there's really nobody living
in there yet
so when they say raw char and i you
picture the honeycomb structure as
apartment buildings you gotta move in
things to those apartment buildings and
once the microorganisms have moved in
they consider that charged char all
right all right so yeah all right so um
what do you find as being best practices
for
uh charging your char i can imagine that
you know earlier we talked about just
leaving your biochar out and it'll
naturally gather imo and that's badass
um i can imagine that um
that's you know spraying an imo solution
on it that you have prior made that that
sounds like a probably a pretty
reasonable thing like what else we got
so
molasses is going to attract in the
goodies right add a little bit of
molasses to your water when you water
and then just straining out compost get
a bag of compost make a fill it with a
sock you do the tea bag extraction and
getting those goodies from the compost
because it's already bio-available
you're going to know your plants have
the goodies that they need and then all
of that's going to move into the
honeycomb structure of the char and we
just want to spray it on right we don't
want to dip the biochar into
the compost water or anything because
that wouldn't be an application if you
were just made biochar and you want to
use it like right now and mix with soil
that would do that's what we would call
raw or if you wanted the top dress with
the char you have your gardens already
up and going but you still want to add
char you can add char to the surface but
then water in with a compost tea and
then that will begin to get the char
part of the system i can imagine that if
you're gonna top dress with a biochar
um you're gonna want to
also top that
with soil or compost because isn't
biochar it's most effective when it is
kept
moist right so so having it on the top
where it's wet dry wet dry every day as
it gets as it gets watered
um it's going to be harder for microbes
to establish i can imagine and so but if
you if you cap it with some compost well
then now it's under the compost and it's
going to stay moist all the time
yeah but evaporation is going to come up
through the top so if you are on top it
still does get some moisture but
scratching that thing right into this on
the surface gets it down gets it down
into the playing field
so um keeping that in mind but if you've
got slugs and things like that that are
eating your plants
leaving the bigger chunks on the top and
around the plant they don't like to
crawl up it's scratchy yeah it's very
scratchy so there's times where we'll
top dress but big chunk
around the base of the plants to keep
crawly things off of them man biochar is
like a like a
do everything member of your garden
100 um all right so let's talk about uh
containers now um we i have an idea of
how much to use at up to 15 percent five
to fifteen percent in our hugels is
are those numbers you know about the
same for containers or do we do we need
to adapt for some reason
um every soil type's going to be
different but typically i'll run between
three percent and a 10 for container
gardening
but i'm also watering during my growing
cycle
with
like you can take that char that you
have and make extracts too with that
thing so you get just the dust particles
so there's a lot of times where
it seems like you have less at the
initial start but if you're continually
adding in
with your drops
your plants are going to love it but
you're building up the carbon the
electricity um energy of that soil so
keep it in mind add it in all not just a
one-time drop go micronized on that go
top dress on it but always think about
your soil is draining the plants growing
bigger the energy is going somewhere so
you're going to have to recharge that
and carbon's going to be that recharger
all right all right now let's talk about
really small pots so let's talk about my
small ornamentals like my my flowering
plants that i'm not going to smoke on my
deck right stuff that's stuff that's
there to you know look pretty for me my
doll is and stuff like that um uh you
know is it is it the same same kind of
thing three to three to five percent and
five percent typically you're good at
the house plant they don't need there's
not a lot happening right you might have
like a crazy house plant but you get
them to flower some stuff like you you
haven't seen them throw flower before
they'll flower right up when you when
you charm up and it's like wow i didn't
even know you made a flower well that
that now that sounds like an advantage
for us in the pacific northwest right
yeah i got a lot of flowering plants
that don't like to live here
so um all right so so let's talk about
getting them getting the biochar small
and then this micronizing right so so
you you were very clear with us that
it's good to have biochar pieces in a
variety of sizes
so that it can be host to
a variety of types of microbes and you
know just play more like a more variety
of roles in in the substrate so that's
great but let's say that we do want to
get it small like maybe we want small
pieces to top dress so that we're
discouraging slugs or maybe we want to
get it small because we want to put a
little bit in you know a favorite house
plant of ours
or
you know maybe we want to get it small
because we want to put it in the bag
with our compost tea um how do we make
biochar smaller
no fancy technology man we we get a
bucket sometimes and just mash it up in
the bucket in two weeks like with a
hammer
you know with a shovel that the tips of
your shovels can break that thing down
um sometimes we'll put it in between
um pie boards four by pie boards and
then as you drive your machines around
the farm you can crush it in between
there back and forth uh-huh and then
i've seen some of my friends their wives
don't like it but they'll put it in the
driveway and just drive over it for a
while yeah
it slowly just crushes through your
day-to-day activities and
yes so there's really no fancy way to
all right there's no trick to it
i get it cement mixer my friend did a
cement mixer where he put in trailer
hitch balls and let that thing run for a
while and that broke it up kind of nice
so
so like for me i've got access to lots
of uh burlap coffee bags right and so i
can see me taking it and putting it in
the in in that and then honestly just
kind of hitting it with a hammer um just
because like at small scale that might
be what works for me beautiful i love
that all right all right so um okay so
oh micronizing so like you're describing
this micronizing and that's really small
now are we as cultivators making it at
micronized um size or are we just
putting it in and then nature is
breaking it down to micronized
or both and as we bang it around it's
it's like glass right so every time you
move it it breaks down smaller and
smaller which i advise you to wear a
mask when handling the the char because
you're going to breathe it in
but um
nature 2 is going to break it down small
and
these are the parts where
as you're watering you're scratching the
surface you're moving things around the
char is going to work its way down into
the soil
i kind of cannabis has such a short life
cycle
i have i prefer to break it pieces of
that down if i'm watering in my compost
teas
um
i definitely love to add the chard with
almost all of my drops
simply because it's that insurance
when we're out there in the cultivation
doing cultivation you always are at that
point where you
want to give the plants all that you can
and
i think every farmer can relate to this
it's and i call it the hire me or fire
me drops where you know you know the
plants are telling you give me this give
me that and you're thinking in my head
like oh my gosh we're really pushing you
girls
should i do this but then when you make
the drop
and
it works out and you know you have the
insurance from the char
these are the parts where they're gonna
hire you but i've seen people do the
same drops without the char
and trash plants
they didn't have the buffer you get
fired
so
this allows the insurance for
the um
the cultivator yeah to cover you cover
up your screw-ups and make it yeah
100 yeah the end result is the plants
just they use all that electricity and
it just turns into yoga plant yoga plant
yoga fabulous so so why don't you why
don't you kind of like um bring us home
here quite a mug with um you know
here at the end of the show
um
i have heard you speak before and you
have spoken a lot about the interaction
you know the electricity the interaction
between
the biochar and the microbes and you
know you are a very um like systemic
thinker right you're you're constantly
thinking about the relationships between
all the different
um players um who are in the rhizosphere
and i think that as natural growers the
more and more we're thinking about soil
as a
you know as a community that we are
supporting
and less of
less as the soil being like this npk
eating robot
um i think that we become more allies
with the soil instead of
you know
domination of the soil and um you know
we are adding something that sounds like
it is
um
you know a very potent
cause of growth and i would expect that
if we take
you know the simple communities if we
haven't been using biochar and we start
using it i can imagine that there will
be
a new environment in our soil for
all of the microbes and for our plant
and then eventually us to smoke like
everybody wins will you kind of like
speak to this idea
of of of what it means to add this
electrically
gifted biochar to
our soils and and and
what might be experienced by the soil
okay
so i'm very fascinated with conservation
work
and
ecology
and what i find out is places around the
world
where there's the most
macro life the most diversity plant life
where there's most diversity living
and they look at the soil
it's always has a high carbon content
and it's loaded with char
so this tells me that
when it happens micro at the micro level
and you can see it at the macro
something must be going on
it becomes like nature's playground of
life there's just so many
relationships happening
i have to ask myself what role did
carbon play in that
and then when i think further back is to
even how our whole planet started
you can see where that carbon
relationship
is hand-in-hand with water
so we're only here for a short time on
this planet you know
and it seems
if there's something we can do to
co-create life
and foster life
and leave our permanent mark through
carbon
that's the real investment
money comes and goes
but to say that this investment we're
making today is going to be here in a
thousand years
how many things can you say that for
and when you take on and have the
realization like
dude i'm making a difference for a
thousand years
you stand different
you walk different
you feel like you got a purpose
and it makes it an even playing field
because all of this
i picked up which is barely a ged
education i sucked at school
straight gangster from the streets
but when i learned to work with the
plant
and the plant taught me about soil
look how i end up on shows on your show
talking about things the homies would
never believe i picked up on
so not only does it create life on the
planet but it seems like it creates life
within yourself
and something about being on this rock
especially in these times right and you
feel like man i can do some good
especially when we've done so much wrong
i'm grabbing it with both hands
oh yeah so i feel like that life force
that's even within me
it must
transfer over into life around me
and these are the kind of things where
people feel like we
can do something we can't wait around
for someone to come in
and do this work
it's like this is what we're born to do
all of us in some way is born to
co-create whether we're creating soil
over creating art you gotta believe it
influences each other and this is gonna
be the key
it's not a financial thing
it's not a money thing
you can't eat none of that
but the soil and the next
thousand years i can affect positively
and even spreading the word if just one
person starts to make char who's
listening to this
and starts to program nature and finally
starts to realize wow
i could really do something
watch what happens to that community
because if it transforms a little area
into
so much life
what does it do to an area where things
aren't going so well
when you add the carbon and the microbes
to an area watch it change pick a spot
don't tell nobody
pick a spot a neighborhood and start
adding this to a spot
come and visit that spot add regularly
watch what happens to that spot
birds show up butterflies show up
hell people with a picnic basket might
even end up there who you never saw a
picnic there before
because something happens when you
change the soil
that somehow changes the macro and we're
part of that
macro thing
so i hope that this was
able to
make you feel like you or have already
been doing something so much of your
natural farmers man it's like you don't
realize what role we're playing here
but i hope this continues to inspire
not just to create but to share with
each other how we're doing these things
to share with the younger generation
because that's the ones who need it the
most
wow well i definitely feel inspired i
feel all juiced up so um
i don't think we'll we might as well
leave it there that's beautiful
quarterback i'm i'm so honored to have
you on the show and you know this is our
first conversation i i
appreciate your friendship and i look
forward to interacting with you more and
you know i guess for now thank you for
being a guest here on shaping fire and i
look forward to meeting you again in
person
thank you shangri-los for having me
pleasure to talk to you and our first
conversation be recorded i've been a big
fan of you for so long i remember seeing
that emerald cup a couple years back
and wanted to go talk to you we were so
busy so this is great well i'm really
i'm really glad that we had this
opportunity today so thank you okay
blessings brother right on so uh if you
would like to uh continue learning more
from guatemala um there is only one
place to do that there is one center of
that and that is at his instagram
account um you know when i was asking
quarterback why or um you know where he
wanted me to turn people on to
um you know he's like oh just my
instagram i'm like well you know you got
do you have a you know a website or
anything he's like no man i don't have
anything to sell
he's like i'm just i'm just here to
teach and that like felt so good because
you know nothing against the people who
come on my show to teach about a topic
but then also you know make a living
because we all have to make a living but
gotta me i gotta admit it it's um it's
refreshing to
have somebody who has dedicated their
life just to just education so with that
um his fantastic instagram to follow is
bokashi for you so um it's uh it's b o k
a s h i
and then the number four
and then the letter u so at bokashi for
you and you can follow along on
quatermarks uh education
of folks and adventures and you know
you'll you'll have found out about
things like the usda biochar program
that we didn't uh know about so um so
that's the place you want to go to
follow up you can find more episodes of
the shaping fire podcast and subscribe
to the show at shapingfire.com and
wherever you get your podcasts if you
enjoyed the show we'd really appreciate
it if you leave a positive review of the
podcast wherever you download your
review will help others find the show so
they can enjoy it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the newsletter for insights
into the latest cannabis news exclusive
videos and giveaways on the shaping fire
website you also find transcripts of
today's podcast as well
be sure to follow on instagram for all
original content not found on the
podcast that's at shaping fire and at
shangolos on instagram be sure to check
out shaping fire youtube channel for
exclusive interviews farm tours and
cannabis lectures
does your company want to reach our
national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hotspot at
shippingfire.com to find out how thanks
for listening to shaping fire i've been
your host shango lose
[Music]
you