[Music]
one thing that the Internet has not been
very good at yet is providing quality
information there's a lot of information
and if you dig through it read it all
and educate yourself you can eventually
become a good judge of informations
quality too but if any topic is new to
you good luck getting good clean
information without reading all of the
information available in becoming an
expert yourself this applies especially
to cannabis and that aspect of cannabis
legalization is such a drag patients are
literally dying while trying to learn
about accurate cannabis dosing and
watching videos on how to make feek Oh
other patients are trying to figure out
how to make full plant tinctures and
every tincture recipe is different and
most of them are poorly written and some
are straight-up ineffective fake new
sites and other media sources that are
not really fake but rather just repeat
dumb analysis are everywhere people with
no expertise write about cannabis policy
without any real context and certainly
there is enough snark and ridicule in
the comments everywhere to be
disheartening today we're going to talk
to one source of cannabis information
online that is well researched peer
rated and technologically advanced you
are listening to shaping fire and I'm
your host Shango Lohse today's guess is
back Simon founder and CEO of green
flower media green flower works with the
top cannabis experts in the world to
create reliable programming to educate
patients cannabis enthusiasts business
owners and policymakers green flowers
cannabis health summit and cannabis
entrepreneur summit are the most highly
attended cannabis education events ever
to take place online prior to launching
green flower max produce programming and
outreach for Deepak Chopra rebranded the
company and led technological
innovations he's a down-to-earth
communicator is a profound understanding
of technology and how we learn as humans
I've spoken at the green flower cannabis
entrepreneurs summit as well as recorded
a show with them on how best to set up
cannabis clubs in your local area my new
program seven mistakes made by new
cannabis entrepreneurs debuts next week
on January third at five pm
this showing is free and then will be
added to the green flower library you
can find out more about that event at
shaping fire calm ford / green flower
some call green flower the netflix of
cannabis we will discuss that with max
today welcome to the show max thanks
Shengo i'm glad to be here with you my
friend i'm glad you could make the time
so so let's start by giving folks a
little context about where you're coming
from because you know i understand that
you helped Deepak Chopra develop his
video outreach program but tell us a
little bit about that and how it
informed your vision for what green
flower media was to become yeah it's
it's hard to even embrace this now but
over a decade ago I was the director of
consumer products for the Chopra Center
which is Deepak Chopra's Wellness Center
and just to paint a picture if you will
at that time this was way before
meditation yoga Ayurveda mind-body
medicine was deemed acceptable and
popular and in fact it was it has an
eerie coincidence or an eerie similarity
to the cannabis space because in that
world people saw meditation and yoga as
something that people only on the fringe
did that there was no science to it that
it was going to kind of disrupt your
life you know there was all these
stigmas attached to it and over the
course of you know was the seven years
that that I was there and the team that
we built we really did some unbelievable
things two distinct eyes meditation in
my body medicine in yoga and to really
get the message out to tens of millions
of people through you know online
campaigns and the meditation challenge
that now is I just heard has been taken
by a half a million people this year at
the Chopra Center and it was a really
fascinating experience to take something
that was so fringe and really integrated
into mainstream and so you know in
cannabis it feels just like this unusual
path that I've already walked
for but this time it's with something I
have an even deeper relationship with
because I've been a cannabis user for
decades and I also you know in a funny
way I think that it's cannabis is even
bigger than mind-body medicine because I
always say you know I I taught some of
the biggest stars and celebrities in the
world how to meditate and when you would
teach these people you would always say
to them look you have to do this every
day for 21 days for it you to really
start to notice some benefit because you
know if anybody's ever meditated before
you know like the first time you stood
under meditate you feel like oh so I'm
just going to sit here for 20 minutes
and let my mind drive me freaking nuts
and and it takes a little bit to like
get the hang of it and you know use the
tools and work through it and with
cannabis it's like you know I put an
arthritis arthritis cream on my
grandfather's hands and in 30 minutes
all of a sudden he could move his
fingers again you know I gave my mother
who hadn't slept in three decades a
little bit of a you know a chew and she
slept through the night that same night
and so you know when you combine the
fact that I think this plant has the
capacity to impact hundreds of millions
of people in so many different ways and
that it's so quickly effective I just
feel really excited about the path that
we're on so yeah I have this kind of
funny background of taking things that
have been highly stigmatized and yet
also highly effective and helping them
come to come into the mainstream it's
kind of funny how all the puzzle pieces
fit together so elegantly when you look
backwards isn't it because it's like you
know looking back we can see you know
the kind of programs you put together at
the Chopra also then with the marriage
of the technology that you were learning
and managing their it pretty much gave
you a full skill set to do exactly what
you're doing now in the cannabis space I
mean I think you know on some level the
universe is always conspiring in our
favor if we're paying attention it just
takes people being willing to take some
risks and for me you know I see cannabis
as a health and wellness movement and so
that have that background but I also see
cannabis as something that needs really
good education to
change the stigma and for what we've you
know really done at green flower it's
about changing stigma to me is about to
core things one it's about knowledge
because people are just misinformed and
once you start to learn about anything
you quickly realize the truth right so
that happened with meditation and I
think that's happening with cannabis now
and and in cannabis it's just such a
diverse rich topic full of so much
fascinating knowledge so that's one part
to changing stigma is just doing a
better and better job of education and
then the second part of that is people
is the the more credible the more
high-level the more authoritative the
more celebrity you bring into something
the more it starts to change public
persona and change the perception of
what this thing is and so you know when
I was at Chopra I had this just
unusually long list of people that I
dealt with of celebrities that were sick
you know celebrities business moguls you
know high level people and you realize
that people are just people no matter
how big of a star they are no matter
where they come from they're just people
and and when you treat people like
regular people then it gets better and
better and you can kind of allow that
relationship to become more and more
comfortable and I think with cannabis
it's again it's the same darn thing
where people might be highly stigmatized
but I'm getting into bigger and bigger
circles right now more and more
celebrity-driven affluent driven people
that are using cannabis because they're
not sleeping or because they got cancer
or because they have pain or whatever
else it is and so you know I'm very
proud to have people like Eugene Monroe
who's become such an industry advocate
who is a major part of green flower and
people like Steve DeAngelo who's you
know been an activist for so long to be
a part of green flower and I feel like
we can just keep doing those two things
education and people education and
people then I'm convinced that within 10
years it'll be the same thing that
happened to Chopra will have cannabis
shops on every corner and tens of
millions of people will be benefiting
from the plant
in a more public way and you know i
think it's a it's a really interesting
interesting thing to be doing now with
the background that i have it really is
amazing the reach that green flower
media has put together in such a well
feels like to me a short period of time
the first time i heard about your
company was kung going into the cannabis
health summit that you had I don't know
maybe maybe was year and a half two
years ago now and the funny thing was is
you know I'm knee-deep in the cannabis
industry but i didn't i didn't get
contacted directly i actually heard
about it from a non cannabis aunt who
sent me a newsletter that you all put
out and said oh look at this great
Canada's health summit it might be
something that you would be interested
in Shango and you know what she was
totally right and so and I was stoked
that you had all these you know amazing
cannabis health experts that were all
going to be streaming for free and I'm
like oh man I'm gonna sign up for this
so I sign up for it and over the course
of the weekend I probably caught heck I
probably caught eight speakers or so and
then and then you know and then after
that you did the cannabis entrepreneur
summit which I was very grateful to have
been invited to so so my question for
you is that you know when you put
together one of these summits it's like
two days it's all the top minds in
cannabis and these are really busy
people I can imagine getting all these
folks together over one weekend was like
herding cats did you find it challenging
to pull everybody together at the same
place well here's the thing about
experts and this is something I've
learned after being in the kind of
experts business for a decade because
after I left Chopra I started a company
that trained over 8,000 thought leaders
on how to build digital marketing
systems to get their knowledge and their
wisdom out into the world and so I have
this kind of deep vast experience with
network with experts and what I've
learned is that when somebody acquires
enough knowledge to feel like they have
something of value to share what people
are really looking for most is two
things they're looking for a platform
right we want
be able to reach more people and
secondly we're looking for ways to
enhance our visibility and credibility
in greater ways and so it actually
wasn't terribly difficult to get people
together because we knew that with our
marketing channels and the strategies
that we put in place in the background
that my team has I have been a
remarkable team or 13 people deep now of
you know true experts in kind of digital
publishing that our reach was going to
be huge and then with the other part of
my team that works with people on
content we knew that we could help
people become better speakers better
presenters and that the production
quality of what we were going to do
because my for example my executive
producer was 30 years at Marvel and
Disney and Fox and spotlight
entertainment and so between our
production and our marketing we could
invite people into something that was of
true value and true benefit to them and
do it in a way that that really lifted
up their credibility and helped him get
their message out and so actually the
hardest thing was not getting people
together the hardest thing was deciding
who we want it because we are
perpetually being contacted by so many
people around the world that think
they're experts or or or maybe our
experts but not at the level we
necessarily want them to be at and so
the hardest parts actually the filtering
right because everybody wants to
participate because they they can smell
a good thing well especially with how
big your reach was you know I didn't
actually hear the follow up what was the
public response to this sort of large
free online event because you know I had
never heard of anything like this
happening in Canada this before did
people respond to it other than you know
my aunt and I so we had 28,000 people
tuned in to the first cannabis health
summit which by the way was just in
January of 2016 so no my gosh I said it
was two years ago I'll tell you guys
right right right we had twenty eight
thousand twenty one thousand three
hundred people from I don't remember
exactly but I think goes from like 55
countries or some some unbelievable
diversity of people and
and the cannabis entrepreneur summit had
ten thousand eight hundred people attend
that particular event and it really did
help put us on the map if you will in
terms of people seeing what we could do
and it was cool again I don't know the
exact numbers but I want to say that
between those two events people watch
something like 2.5 million minutes of
content over those two days or over
those two events I mean and it's been
very exciting you know speaking of
retweet we also have started live
streaming just individual classes every
week on green flower people can go and
they can sign up to watch any live class
basically we're doing multiple live
streams a week and we also just recently
pulled those stats and have had 3.9
million minutes of livestream class
content watch this year as well so it's
been it's been phenomenal to see the
level of engagement in reach and I think
it comes back to the fact that there's
very few places where people can go to
learn about the plant right now and
especially learn from the most credible
experts and so we've just built a really
nice ecosystem we also built our own
technology platform to run the whole
thing so that it's got a nice user
experience so it's a it's a cool thing
we're doing and I think it's really
providing a service that people are
really grateful for you know especially
as we get bigger and bigger yeah that's
a lot of minutes I can imagine that it's
probably the most dense cannabis
education event that there's ever been I
mean that many people learning about
cannabis cannabis medicine and cannabis
business all at the same time it's
actually pretty astonishing so thanks
max we're going to take our first short
break and be right back today's guest is
max Simon of green flower media and you
are listening to shaping fire if you
like podcasts like shaping fire chances
are that you will like audio books too
pretty much audio books are like
podcasts except with less stuttering
better production quality and more
targeted topics yeah I know I make audio
books sound better than a podcast and
you know maybe they are but I get you I
like podcasts too I like to
learn from people talking to me while
I'm doing something else like you know
driving or cleaning my house or making
dinner or even being at work whatever
here's the thing audible.com has an
offer I want to tell you about right now
they are offering a trial of their
audiobook service for absolutely free
you can go to shaping fire calm /a
dab'll and you will get a free audiobook
straight up you can listen to it on your
mobile device on your computer or you
can download it and listen to it you
know pretty much anywhere it's really
simple you know of course they really
want you to subscribe to their service
forever and enjoy more and more audio
books but as cannabis users you also
know how this goes the first one is free
they're going to hit off said that but
it's pretty great you know I listened
recently to smoke signals by martin lee
from project CBD org Martin's book is a
classic of cannabis advocacy he explains
the history of cannabis in America THC
and CBD cannabis science and why
cannabis policy in America has gotten so
jacked you know if you consider yourself
a cannabis person this book really is a
must talking cannabis we all sound
radical just because we're talking about
weed but if you learn the history and
science of cannabis suddenly you become
smart and trustworthy to people the book
was really incredible and there's no
doubt that Martin Lee is the real deal
you can get the book for free just for
doing the trial you know if you don't
want to listen to a cannabis book that's
cool too there's everything else there's
sci-fi and history biography hell you
can even listen to a book about card
counting in blackjack whatever it's all
pretty rad so here's the deal your first
book is free it's easy to sign up it's
easy to quit but they do do a pretty
good job making me want to stay every
month just check it out go to shaping
fire calm /a dab'll to find out more
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire i'm your host Shango lowes
and our guest this week is max Simon
founder and CEO of green
our media so before the break we were
talking about you know just how many
people that you're reaching now with
green flower and how behind it is the
structure of technology and experienced
people and you know one of the things
that occurs to me is that you know over
the time that that I've been following
green flower it does feel like you have
changed the direction or the business
model at least once and you know so many
entrepreneurs they're either they're
either you know poo-pooed by their
friends for changing or they themselves
a more changing the direction of their
company but I've always thought that you
know it's important to be sensitive to
what your audience wants would you share
for a little bit you know what your
experience has been over the the Ark of
green flower so far and and how the
business model has evolved yeah
absolutely um so I should start by
saying that I'm a huge subscriber and
student of what's called the Lean
Startup model by a guy named Eric Ries
and the Lean Startup model basically has
a philosophy which says that when you're
building a new business you should be
testing everything and you know instead
of being concerned about it quite
frankly even what your customers think
or what your team things or what your
investors think or whatever it is that
that everything is an experiment and
that in the beginning you should
experiment as much as possible and so I
say that because our first experiment
was more of what I would call a
traditional media company and and the
reason I even entered the cannabis space
as an entrepreneur if you will is
because I saw huge massive void and that
void was no high-quality cannabis
content that demonstrated the other side
of the stigma right and that that
basically the way I looked at it is the
vast majority of material that was out
there wasn't portraying cannabis
properly and so when you start thinking
about businesses we thought well we
could reach you know zillions of people
and the business model would be based
upon a media company that reaches a lot
of people which is ie an advertising
model right there there's there's
different business models for media
companies and so we started going down
that path and the premise behind a media
company like that is you produce as much
content as you can you get as many
eyeballs as you can and then you sell
advertisements well while we were
getting a lot of eyeballs and we were
getting a lot of traction with the tribe
if you will we were barely selling any
advertisements and it was starting to
get pretty scary because we just were
not couldn't see a path in sight to be
able to sustain the kind of impact that
I am here on this planet to make for
better or worse and the kind of person
that is a hundred percent driven by
global impact and and by big massive
global impact and so you know when I
looked at green flower originally I was
thinking well for that to get to that
level you know it takes basically we
take a lot of money yeah and so when the
business model was quite frankly failing
I mean I that's how one could say like
we were generating a little bit of
income but but nowhere near the kind of
numbers that I knew was necessary to
create a business that would sustain
itself we had to really look deep in
hard and this is where you know the
funny thing about my past re converges
because in media there's there's really
only two models when it comes down to it
there's there's an ad model which is
based upon publishing free content and
then there's a premium model which is
based upon producing content that people
are willing to buy and I actually have
had a much deeper background in premium
but I just didn't start there and so we
just pivoted we pivoted to being a
premium content business if you will
that was based upon creating content
people were willing to pay for and
that's a different kind of content it's
more educational it's more how-to it's
much deeper it's its content that's
designed to provide specific value to
somebody based upon a problem or a
desire that they
have and it was the greatest decision we
could have made because one there was
very few people doing this and if they
were they weren't doing it well but also
it was Twite friend quite frankly just
much more in our sweet spot as well from
our experience and our depth and really
were able to carve out this kind of
beautiful niche that is working very
well both in the financial side but also
in terms of you know where we feel most
comfortable playing yeah I believe that
about the place where you feel most
comfortable playing too because one of
the challenges with advertising as a
model for media companies is you know
you're always aware of what your
advertisers want and yet I know you to
be somebody who's very service oriented
to humans I can imagine that a premium
model where the audience is helping pay
for the content is way more you know
emotionally effective for you because
that way your loyalties are not split
between advertisers and the audience
it's everything you that you can do for
the audience to create value for them is
is what you you know was what you're
supposed to be doing i can see that
fitting a lot better and the nice thing
about it for for us as well is that it
really does allow us to use our tribe as
i call it or our audience if you will to
guide the direction of where we go right
because a premium content model if i was
to get really granular for a moment it's
really actually just about solving
problems for people that they believe
are valuable enough to pay for and and
so when you start moving into premium
content it's just saying how do we
create increasingly more valuable
content and we do that by asking people
you know we at this point we've got tens
of thousands of data points because of
our technology about what are the issues
people are struggling with so you know
for example one of our most popular
classes was about cannabis and
creativity and that was because people
were really struggling to find a way to
use cannabis to enhance their creativity
without making them anxious and and I
wouldn't have thought that right that
was a that
something that I wouldn't have known
unless our audience told us like hey
here's a problem I'm having a lot of
people that are creative we're either
getting really anxious or they weren't
finding the right way of doing it to
enhance the the way they think about
stuff and it just kind of was a
surprising data point for us but because
our model is based upon creating more
and more valuable content for the people
that are paying for it you know it's
become a nice kind of self-perpetuating
loop to design stuff that's really
valuable to them I think that makes a
really good case to for listening to
your customer base for everybody who's
listening who's an entrepreneur that you
can get really great insight if you're
making sure you read the emails that are
coming in your email box from your
customers they they can show you roads
that you had not considered yourself and
you have to ask I mean it's really
uncomfortable to ask people for what
what to do not even went to two but what
what to do better you know I mean really
that's at the end of the day that's what
it is it's like how do we serve you
better what are we not what are we not
doing that you'd like us to do what are
we doing wrong and it's it's a very
uncomfortable experience because you
know everybody wants to have all the
answers but again that's also very much
a Lean Startup principle is you want to
be constantly trying stuff and then
reviewing how people responded to it so
yeah it's it's necessary i think quite
frankly well while we're talking about
uncomfortable things about being an
entrepreneur and running a start-up
let's talk about raising money real
quick you know entrepreneurs are often
really shy to the fact that they have to
raise money and I know that you've
raised money successfully for a few
businesses what advice do you have for
cannabis entrepreneurs who are raising
their own capital so actually just to
clarify this is the first business that
I had I've had to raise real money for
em you know I've raised you know a few
hundred thousand dollars here and there
for other stuff but but you know friends
and family and my network wasn't that
difficult this was the first business
where I had to fully go out and hit the
road and go pitch and do that whole
thing and holy smokes I tell everybody i
know these days that it's them it was
the deepest
and still continues to be the deepest
and most profound learning curve I've
ever gone on in my professional career
so i'll start by saying raising money is
definitely not for the faint at heart
and I've I failed more times than I've
ever failed at anything in my entire
career so far at raising money and
that's been really humbling so that's
the first thing I would say is is it you
have to be really prepared to deal with
rejection in a way that um I just I just
wasn't I mean I wasn't thinking it was
going to be this hard so that's the
first thing I'm saying the second thing
I would say is that I've learned some
really fascinating things about
investors in this last period we've now
raised a few million dollars and one of
the things that I've learned is that
people always think that you need to go
and pitch an investor and that you know
they're basically they're the prize in
some level psychologically what's
happening for people is I need your
money you know I need to impress you
you're the person that that that's the
prize here and you know the greatest
thing I've learned in this process is
that if you have that attitude you're
done it's just not going to work that
you have to come up with the ways of
thinking about yourself and your
business and what you're doing and the
energy that you cultivate and the story
you tell and the way you approach people
so that you're the prize and that that
you're giving them an opportunity to get
into playing with you because if they
feel like you're chasing them you're
never going to close a deal but if they
feel like they're going to miss
something by not chasing you that's when
people start to actually write checks
and so I mean I could talk to you for
literally days on the investment thing
but that's the single most important
lesson that I've learned is you have to
psychologically turn the tables to
making you the prize even if you're just
starting out that makes a lot of sense
because you're removing that duality
that that I'm negotiating with you and
your the other and
dead your you're stepping across a line
and you know embracing what it is they
want for themselves so now you're on the
same side and I'm sure that the the
capital conversation becomes way way
easier at that point uh-huh I'd like to
say any part of its easy it's I think
that raising money is arguably the most
difficult business task on the planet
but you know speaking to the startup
side of things the reason why I love
business actually has nothing to do with
money I'm not a very money driven person
even though I think it's very important
to focus on money I'm driven buying
business by two things primarily one is
impact as I said many times before I
think that's my number one motivation as
I feel like before here on this earth
we're here to do something that
contributes so that's my number one
drive but the second is the leadership
opportunity or you could say it is a
leadership challenge and raising money
is is so far been the single greatest
leadership challenge I've had to take on
in business thus far and if you can
frame it that way I hear most people I
hate raising money that's the worst and
it could be really hard but it's an
amazing leadership challenge to step
into and I have learned more about the
psychology of desire and persuasion and
urgency by becoming better and better
raising money than any single activity
I've done in the history of my career
thank you for that max we're going to
take another short break and be right
back today's guest is max Simon of green
flower media and you are listening to
shaping fire businesses everywhere are
constantly striving to reach out to
people through advertising we all know
though that trying to reach a cannabis
audience with a quality message is
actually pretty difficult that's why
many people choose to advertise on the
shaping fire podcast advertising on this
show allows us time to talk about your
product service or brand in a way that
really lets people know what sets your
company apart from the others bold
people who own companies know that
getting in a relationship with their
customers is
essential and that is what we offer we
will explain your service or product and
what sets it apart as desirable and will
help our audience get in contact with
you it's really pretty simple
advertising does not have to be all
whiz-bang smoke and mirrors nowadays I
find that people prefer just to be
spoken to calmly accurately and with
good intentions if you want to make your
own commercial spot you can totally do
that too because our podcast is young
but growing at an exceptionally fast
rate if you become an advertiser on the
shaping fire podcast now you're going to
pay a fraction of the cost we will be
asking for in just a few months and yet
everyone listening both now and to the
back catalogue of interviews in the
future will hear about your company
again and again for years it's a great
deal for you pay a small amount now
because the show is new but take
advantage of the huge listening audience
we will have forever do yourself a solid
and contact us today for raids on
podcast and newsletter advertising email
hot spot at shaping fire calm to find
out more welcome back you are listening
to shaping fire i'm your host Shango
lowes and our guest this week is max
Simon founder and CEO of green flower
media so so far we've been talking a
whole lot about the nature of a cannabis
start up and running a business with
integrity and you know just trying to
build a company in this very unusual
cannabis industry but I want to talk
more specifically now about the content
because at the heart of it you are a
publishing company and and you are
trying to find content that people want
to hear as you as you mentioned in the
last set you know your goal is to find
out problems that people have and try to
solve it for them so so let's talk about
some of your free events that are coming
up in the new year so that folks can get
an idea of the kind of content you are
producing what's coming up for green
flower media so we have learned that
there's basically four areas in this
cannabis movement where people have a
strong desire to learn so one area
is the health vertical and that camp
encapsulate everything from how do I use
this for my specific ailment how do I
treat other people or recommend this to
other people you know what's the
difference between cannabinoids and
terpenes or how do I use them to my
benefit you know that there's about a
zillion things that people want and need
to know about cannabis and health so we
have a tremendous diversity of classes
in those places I would say so far
that's probably been our strongest place
because well because it look and a lot
of our health background a lot of people
on the team of a very strong health
background including myself um so
classes like cannabis and pregnancy
coming up you know about whether it's
safe or not and we have cannabis and
Alzheimer's in cannabis and opiate pain
and all you know just some really
interesting classes there with with
famous doctors and mind-body medicine
practitioners and all sorts of
interesting people the second vertical
is the industry vertical and that's all
about starting or building or succeeding
in this cannabis industry you know we
have classes with you coming out Shango
and we have classes around investing we
have classes around compliance in
classes around protecting your cannabis
brand and classes around building a
cannabis brand you know those there's a
pretty diverse range of really
fascinating topics coming out there
steno Steve D'Angelo's doing a whole
thing about what he's learned from
building the world's largest cannabis
brand essentially and we have that whole
sector vertical then we have the science
vertical which is all about the biology
and chemistry and ways to work with the
plant so I'm really thrilled that we've
developed some amazing partnerships in
that area like the cannabis science
conference where that entire conference
will actually be made available to our
insiders which is our membership program
and the Emerald scientific conference as
well as another one that we've partnered
with where their entire three-day
conference will be included to our
insider portal and
includes everything from extraction to
the ways of working with the plant and
growing the plant and genetics and and
that whole kind of amazingly rich
category of content and then finally we
have what we call our DIY vertical which
is all about basically cooking growing
making your own products and tinctures
and that kind of thing it's working with
the plant and we have a whole slew of
really interesting classes and that one
as well growing indoor and outdoor and
working with some of the real legends in
the cultivation space we won't name them
for now until it comes out but but
really you know the legends in the space
that have been doing this for decades so
all of that content is really we have a
really interesting model where because
our number one desire is impact we
always live stream these classes first
for free so every week multiple times a
week people can tune in to the website
and they can register for these classes
for free and they can watch in real time
and if that's all that happens then
that's amazing and we have right now you
know thousands and thousands of people
every week that are tuning in but then
we also have this ability for people to
basically unlock the entire library for
you know it's just 18 bucks a month and
and so you know we have a lot of cool
stuff coming up cool and since we're
tantalizing folks I want to give you the
URL right now and we'll say us again at
the end of the show but you know if you
want to attend some of these free online
events you can go to shaping fire calm
forward slash green flower to sign up
for those and you know because of the
nature of podcasts that they that their
online forever if you are listening to
the show in the future you can still go
to shaping fire calm green flower and
it'll be a constantly refreshed list so
it's always going to be evergreen so max
you know as far as finding these topics
you know you professed earlier that you
paid a lot of attention to your audience
so that you knew what the kind of
problems you can solve for them
what is your what do you find us your
best way to get feedback from your
audience which is you know tens and tens
of thousands of people deep now yeah
we're over 75,000 now actually um and
you know I think it goes back to just
the idea of making it a muscle so for us
at least you'll find once you register
for any of these classes the moment you
register we say hey tell us what you
want to know and and so in our
technology it's now built in every class
we're gathering people's questions and
in many cases we're actually answering
them live like right on the spot during
the class and so that's one way that we
do it what we're also you know we have a
certain set of values of how we operate
here at green flower and one of those
values is to be open and curious and for
us what that means is that you know
we're human and people often times
forget companies are like made up of
actual just real people and and as a
team of people we make mistakes
sometimes or we do something wrong or we
you know find ourselves having made a
decision that wasn't the right thing and
we're just always trying to be to
communicate that we're very open and
curious with everybody to tell us you
know if they have feedback or if they
have some kind of guidance that will
help us so I think one of its just kind
of tactical you know ask ask more ask
more frequently asked in every way that
you can but then the other way is is a
value set that's really served served us
and certainly served me in my life many
times is just being kind of humble
enough to say you know to tell us if
there's something else we can do to make
this better for you how did how did that
play into the development of the
cannabis health challenge I've been
seeing new advertising for that all over
the place right now that's so that's a
funny thing where I'll just say first
we're really excited about this cannabis
health challenge which basically what
we're doing is it's an online challenge
that for ten days we're going to release
a daily video that will teach and
educate people about how to use cannabis
responsibly and perform three
health enhancing activities so there's
cannabis and fitness cannabis and food
and cannabis and reflection and we're
going to be kind of guiding people
through it as a community and it's gonna
be so cool well there's a lot of really
you know amazing people taking part in
it you was one of them but that that's
one of those things while speaking of
our values so we have other value that
says break new ground and for us this
was actually just a very strong gut
decision of my mind particularly because
I'm a I'm a very very active healthy
person and cannabis has become a
substantial part of that and so you know
I have I live out here in Ojai
California this beautiful mountain town
and we have these gorgeous outdoor
trails and about three days a week I'll
go for a pretty long trail run with
cannabis and I had go on these trail
runs and I just kept getting this
message over and over again I'm running
on this trail and puffing away you gotta
do a health pounds you've got to do it
because I used to do stuff like this
with Chopra and I did stuff like some
other companies these beats online
challenges and so it was just a gut
instinct to say let's let's do this as a
community and see if we can really
inspire our cannabis community to come
together and really prove to ourselves
and others that can if it can be a true
life enhancing activity so um it's been
really exciting to see the response so
far and you know I'm excited for
everybody to take part of that and again
they can find that through that URL that
you mentioned before in terms of how
they can register for that so max before
we go you know I wanted to talk about
this this tagline that I'm hearing about
green flower media in the press I'm
reading folks refer to your new
subscription service as the netflix of
cannabis and those are some pretty big
boots to fill do you think the tagline
fits for what green flower media has
become well so yes and no i mean the the
thing that that the reason why they're
calling us that is because we have this
program called green flower insider and
as an insider what it means is that
every single live class that we do which
is multiple times a week
gets added to this ever growing library
and for you know it's 18 bucks a month
people can watch unlimited cannabis
classes including every new one that
comes in and so in that way we're just
like Netflix because we have this you
know ever growing library of really
credible cannabis education in cannabis
classes and cannabis material that
people can can enjoy anytime they want
and you know can binge watch as much as
they want um where it where we differ is
that are our content is really more like
classes you know and in that regard we
have a different model which is more
like a Linda calm or au Domini or a
creative live because we're actually
teaching people and so for for most of
the cases you know if you were to go to
a cannabis seminar or a cannabis event
you know you'd have to spend hundreds
and hundreds of dollars or sometimes
thousands of dollars to go and listen to
these people speak to learn and we have
those same thousands and thousands of
dollars of education but it's just 18
bucks a month and so we love that that
people are seeing how big what it is
that we're doing but because we're so
education focused and value driven and
Netflix is more of an entertainment
platform it kind of works but it also it
doesn't you know and we kind of see
ourselves more as we would compare
ourselves more like a Linda calm of
cannabis more than a Netflix but
certainly the fact that that we unlock
every class in our library keeping both
less than the price of a pizza is
something that people have been really
excited about yeah well i certainly get
the excitement I feel it too it's you
know even though I spend most of my time
interviewing folks and getting to learn
about exactly what I want to learn in
cannabis it's always nice to see what
the new addition is to the library so
that you know in the evening when I mean
dinner or something I can watch and
learn something that I didn't already
know well max thank you so much for all
the work that you're doing to educate
folks on cannabis and kind of like
raising the torch and I really
appreciate you taking some time out of
your busy schedule to be on the show
today it's an honor to be here with you
and I'm really glad to participate in
this kind of amazing thing that you're
building as well max Simon is founder
and CEO of green flower media to find
out more about green flower media's free
online events as well as their cannabis
video subscription service you can go to
shaping fire calm ford / green flower
you can find more episodes of the
shaping fire podcast and subscribe to
the show at shaping fire calm and on
Apple iTunes stitcher and Google Play if
you enjoyed the show we'd really
appreciate it if you'd leave a positive
review of the podcast wherever you
download your review will help others
find the show so they can enjoy it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the weekly newsletter for
insights into the latest cannabis news
and product reviews on the shaping fire
website you will also find transcripts
of today's podcast as well for
information on me and where i'll be
speaking you can check out Shango Lohse
com does your company want to reach our
national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hot spot at shaping
fire calm to find out how thanks for
listening to shaping fire I've been your
host Shango lowes
[Music]