[Music]
one of the most difficult aspects of
cannabis cultivation is learning how to
use light at an expert level the Sun is
pretty much always the same and reliable
and that's one of the reasons I prefer
greenhouse growing
however most artificial light sources
traditionally used for cannabis
certainly got the job done even though
they were inefficient and gave off a ton
of heat but the application of light to
plants whether it be from sunshine or
electricity actually is just one part of
the skill set a cannabis cultivators
needs to understand in order to perfect
their craft if you want to learn about
cannabis health business and technique
efficiently and with good cheer I
encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter will send you new podcast
episodes as they come out delivered
right to your inbox along with
commentary and a couple of the most
important news items from the week and
videos - don't rely on social media to
let you know when a new episode is
published sign up for the updates - make
sure you don't miss an episode also we
give away very cool prizes to folks who
are signed up to receive the newsletter
there's nothing else you need to do to
win except receive that newsletter so go
to shaping fire com to sign up and be
entered into this month's and all future
newsletter prize drawings you are
listening to shaping fire and I'm your
host Shango lows today my guest is
former NASA lighting engineer Robert
Solaire robert Solar has worked at the
Kennedy Space Center where he helped
design and build the cultivation module
and the first LED light for the use on
the International Space Station
additionally he served as a subject
matter expert for NASA's circadian
lighting system he holds a master's
degree from the lighting Research Center
at Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute and
has begun a PhD in behavioral
neuroscience where he received a
fellowship from the National Science
Foundation for investigation in
circadian lighting paradigms Robert is
presently vice president of biological
technologies and research at BIOS
lighting on today's show we're going to
talk about some of the key threshold
points in the relationship between the
light spectrum and cannabis plants that
impact all cultivators clear up some
botanical myths that persist in cannabis
cultivation and talk a bit about how
working under artificial lights impacts
the lives of professional indoor
cultivators welcome to the show Robert
yeah thanks for having me awesome man I
know that you you're a busy guy and I
appreciate that you take some of that
valuable time and share it with us and I
really appreciate that you've got you
know the NASA space station in your
background because it's an interest of
mine having worked on the space shuttle
program and the space station myself and
I just generally think it's really cool
still and so before we go into a lot of
the more light and botanical questions
I've got for you today
would you just tell us about the grow-op
in the space station yeah I worked on a
a project called Abers which is an
advanced biological research system that
grew Rabbid OPS's so I was on the team
that worked on that my role is the LED
lighting expert so you know it wasn't
probably as sexy or or anything that
that this audience cares too much about
but there's a rabid OPS's is pretty cool
because it's almost like the white mouse
of a you know laboratory experiment so a
lot of experiments a lot of fundamental
science is done with the rabbit offices
so it's kind of kind of groundbreaking
research for growing you know plants in
outer space and that's kind of evolved
into you know growing you know flowers
on space station growing vegetables and
herbs on space station so things that
are good for us both nutritionally and
and psychologically so you know when I
think about the space station I'm
thinking about everything being
incredibly compact how large is the
growing area and were you finding that
you were having to devise smaller
versions of the technologies just to get
him on the station oh absolutely and and
that's exactly what NASA loved about LED
specifically was that it was small it
was you know you could put it in pretty
much any form factor you you wanted it
was rugged so when it goes up on a
rocket or Soyuz rocket it's it's going
to last it's not made of glass or
anything it's very rugged so but the the
team that we had was
it was basically the space flight
experiment team so astronaut I'm not
sorry astronaut you know scientists
would come from all over the world and
and basically to fly their science on
space station they would come to us and
we would basically develop the hardware
and shrink it down to what's called a
mid-deck Locker size box where that
experiment would run so basically you
have you know minimal space to to have
all your HVAC your cooling your nutrient
deployment your lights everything was
all kind of in a really really
compressed space and astronauts would be
able to open it up kind of check on
everything so when we're camera based it
was all very high-tech I'm trying to get
as much science we can autonomously yeah
so yeah and as compact as you could
imagine and of course lightweight cuz I
think things cost about $10,000 a pound
to send into space so weight is huge if
you sure sure you know I I think most of
us who picture plants growing in space
from either movies or or just you know
imagination we imagine there being you
know like a table somewhere and it's got
it's got green plants growing out of it
that are just kind of like in the air
and sharing air with the astronauts is
that how it is or is everything all like
super sealed behind plastic because
everybody all the environments are
separate oh yeah they want they you
don't want any cross-pollination you you
everything is an experiment so it's
really not designed for you know
life-support at this point so it's
really just it wants to have its closed
environment it's gasketed off so
whatever is going on in recirculating in
in this one environment doesn't doesn't
commingle with you know any of the other
you know hundreds of experiments that
are going on at the exact same time I'd
assume that you guys are probably
running some kind of you know Rock will
substrate and feeding liquid nutrition
rather than
any kind of living soil which would have
a ton of variables is that true oh yeah
so it's uh it is so the nutrition system
is all kind of predetermined some of the
stuff that was that's recently done is
in these little pods these soil pods
where all the nutrients is already
contained in inside that and then you
have to syringe in water because as you
know water in microgravity doesn't
doesn't go where you want it to go I
goes everywhere so you have to have a
very specific delivery system to make
sure that's getting into so everything
is very well contained in order for it
to work right on so um you also worked
on the the grow lab in Antarctica didn't
you yeah that's right so I said they
were looking in it was the McMurdo Sound
station grow facility they were looking
to to kind of see if they could go into
LED technology so we did this probably
about eight years ago growing the the
fresh fruits and vegetables that are on
there down there in Antarctica so pretty
cool pretty cool stuff yeah that's
really great and and I'm sure they're
thrilled to do anything to get fresh
fruits and vegetables there since
everything's shipped in like a couple
times a year probably get really really
tired or whatever their version of MREs
are that's right yeah yeah it was really
important from a from a psychological
mental stability standpoint to see
something growing to see kind of some
semblance of like what's what's normal
in most people's perception yeah I mean
go ahead you know I I just think that we
talked a lot about space and I think
there's one thing that's really
fascinating about space is you know we
look at the spectrum of light and kind
of going back to the what we're what
we're gonna be talking about but you
know plants are hyper efficient to to
red light and and we now know kinda it's
a balance of red and blue but one of the
first discoveries about kind of
phototropism is that you know if you
grow plants in space under only red
light
plants grow in every single direction
they don't have any up or down they just
kind of they just grow outward if you
will and so just adding a little bit of
blue light gives them some orientation
so that they'll actually grow up towards
the light because otherwise they have
really no understanding there's no
gravity there's no buoyancy to kind of
tell them what's up and down in fact
blue light tells them which way to go
and I think that that's a really
interesting story as we kind of think
about you know how we deliver blue light
I'm here on earth and in more normal
cultivations yeah and and maybe even
strategically how it could be used you
know maybe and I don't know this to be
true I'm just positing here but like you
know maybe red light will give you a
shorter bushier plant that's growing out
whether we're we're as feeding it more
blue light will make it more erect is I
don't know if that's true but but I bet
you there's lots of people researching
that right now that's right yeah I mean
it's it's actually kind of the opposite
blue light is kind of the the natural
signal for for more light availability
so when you're depleted a blue light
plants will actually grow out longer and
stemi err to try to in search for kind
of more light availability and so so
it's actually a blue depleted light will
will create a longer stem ear kind of
lanky looking plant so so that's
generally why a lot of the strategies
are around kind of a blue enriched early
in the early stages of plant growth
right on so let's go ahead and make our
transition to the the stuff that I asked
you to come and join us with because
well you know you are an LED specialist
for both you know your company BIOS and
formerly for NASA the things that that
I've heard you interview about which I'm
most interested is actually the
relationship between the vel light no
matter its source and the plant as a
living organism and you know this time
of year a lot of people have got
transition concerns from taking their
plants from
indoors and moving them outdoors and so
a lot of us are talking about light
cycles so let's go ahead and start there
that let's go ahead and start there so
indoors the lights are weaker than the
sunshine but the day is usually longer
before because most folks have their
lights on 18 6 or 24 0 to help get them
established and getting growing before
they go outside yet so often when the
plants go outside into the more intense
sunshine but you know this time of year
depending on where you are in the
country it's about 15 9 they start to
flower for a lot of people and we know
there's clearly a relationship between
the day length the light intensity and
flowering but you know for so many of us
we try to figure out where that
threshold is to cause flowering so we
can better manage our cultivation so
somewhere in there between like taking a
plant from 18:6
and bringing it out died outside 215 9
somewhere in there there is the
threshold where oh now your plants you
brought outside are going to go into
flower versus oh your your plants
transitioned outside without flowering
can you kind of like teach us a bit
about that so that we can make better
cultivation management decisions yeah
yeah I mean it comes down to exactly
what you're saying I mean the I think
the interaction with light intensity is
is an interesting one but I you know the
evidence points that photo period really
drives you know all of that kind of
seasonal cue of when to start flowering
so you know plants are basically gonna
strategize around taking all the energy
from the summer months they see a long
day they think of it as a summer month
well then when you shorten that period
that photo period it's thinking it's
going to interpretate interpret that
information as okay now the seasons have
changed and this is fall and this is the
time where I'm going to take all the
energy that I've created that I've
harvested from the summer months and
convert it into flowers so it really is
that transition from a long day to a
short day so as long as what you see so
if 15-9 is what you get outside
and that was compared to you know
eighteen six as you said before that
that might elicit a flowering event if
it was 59 inside and 59 outside it won't
so I think that when you you know if you
think about how you want to do this when
you convert from inside to outside think
about what that photo period is going to
be when you take it outside and do you
want to you know elicit flowering at
that time or not and if you don't you
want to basically set that time period
inside to be similar to a photo period
that you're going to see outside well
the million-dollar question of course is
what is the similar right
so if eighteen six to fifteen nine is
very much going to be a precipitous drop
to cause flowering how close to fifteen
nine would you say we want to get to be
sure that we're not going to lose our
clones but by suddenly kicking them off
well so so what you I mean what you want
to do is you really want to make sure
that you you hit it all the way right so
usually what people do is a twelve
twelve so you know it's it's a it's a
relative difference but I think they if
you really want to do it if you would
really want to initiate flowering it's a
twelve twelve is what you kind of want
to shift over to but I do think you know
there's gonna be something really
interesting so there's you know hacks
that get you all over the place but I
think that what I've seen at least in
the literature is that you know
different strains come from different
regions and their seasonality czar
different so what's going to change
initiate the the flowering response for
one species might be different than
another species so I think that really
there are ways to you know if you want
to elicit flowering 12/12 going to do it
if you want to kind of play with the the
different thresholds I think that that's
that's something that's really
interesting to see how those impacts how
those photo period effects are going to
change you know the
product that you that you put out I
think the idea of where the cultivar is
from is a really interesting idea the
equatorial strains of cannabis may well
you know have different lighting
responses than the you know the
mountainous ones or the Danny Valley
ones alright let me ask you the question
in a slightly different way though
because normally for most of us who are
coming outside right now we're not
trying to cause them to flower as we
take them outside because really we're
gonna let the we're gonna let the
natural world yeah we're gonna let them
do it and you know depending on where we
live in the country and the you know the
cultivar it'll all start kicking in
around you know mid ish of August right
so for most of us worked were taken you
know 12 18 inch plants outside now and
we want them to veg for another couple
months and and double or triple in size
or more before it flowers so so you know
I tell people you know if you can try to
have your flowers at 59 before you take
them outside and the problem is is like
who most nobody does that because a lot
of people they'll start there they'll
pop their seeds or start their clones at
24 0 or many people at 18 6 but then the
time from when they start their plants
at 18 6 and suddenly they're going
outside at 15 9 you know it's hard to
step down that far I mean for myself I
try to step them down you know about a
half hour a week so that after after
I've had them inside for you know a
month or six weeks I've brought it down
two or three hours but every time I drop
it down a half hour I'm like concerned
that I'm gonna accidentally flower them
indoors so with with overlooking that
whole challenge where do you think it's
best for us to to to play with our
particular cultivars do you think that
they think that it's going to be more
effective for us to you know start the
plants on a shorter day or do a step
down or maybe instead of taking them out
at 59 maybe we take them out at at 17
seven and like your like at two hours
isn't gonna matter so so like where
we're in that variable process are the
ones that you think we're most likely to
find success you know jiggering with
yeah I I mean I really do think that as
I mentioned before some of these species
may be a little bit more sensitive than
others so so how you you know I there's
not one answer that's gonna cover all of
them but really what I would say is to
try to match so start with a shorter
photo period indoors is the way that I
would absolutely do it because if you
step it down as you said you know those
little steps might initiate a flowering
event and if that's not the outcome that
you want then you've just you know kind
of ruined your whole crop so so what I
would do is I would absolutely keep the
photo period as closely matched to that
the time that you expect to go outdoors
so you're suggesting maybe just kind of
like get off the myth that's normally
for you know traditional prohibition-era
indoor growers where they're like oh
24:18 six twelve twelve right because
because you know when you're when you're
running lights you can your god right
you can do anything you want
whereas if if the plan is to go outside
maybe just pop pop your seeds or make
your clones at 16-hour days and even
though you're running your lights a
little less long you will make up for
that in having clear-headed knowledge
that when you go outside your plants are
gonna be safe that's right
that that would be my that would be my
recommendation and and the reality is
you know the energy expenditure is
pretty much the same I think that you
know you know I'll speak only on LED
lighting LED lighting could could hit
those light levels too because you still
want to hit the DL is the your daily
average light intensity the integral of
the light over the photo period so you
want to in order to go to that that
sixteen eight you're going to have to
use higher light levels in order to
still get the the growth that you want
meaning intensity of light yeah all
right got it
I'm so so most of these you know with
with some of the old you know hyper
sodium metal halides you know you you
get what you get
there's no there's no ideas of dimmers
or any way to reduce lights or you know
do anything like that but with LEDs you
have infinite dim ability capabilities
some of these things are pushing out you
know 1750 micromoles per second so it's
you know these things are getting really
impressive in light output so you could
you can crank up the light levels your
energy expenditure is gonna be pretty
much the same because you know you're
using the same amount of energy over a
shorter period of time all right so this
plays in right into a question this is
probably the question I'm most excited
about asking you today and it's about
the 24 hour light cycle and it's it's
always interesting to watch folks who
are who are growing outdoors versus
indoors and how we were taught by our
mentors and then nowadays when when
indoors and outdoors and people are
going back and forth because it's it's
generally safer to grow in both in you
know both environments there's kind of a
clash of myth and and what people were
learned and one of the most watched
videos on the shaping fire YouTube
channel is an interview I did just a
quick one I did with dr. Karuna Chow ray
explaining that the 24 hour light cycle
is not beneficial for plants because
without a dark period microbes in the
soil will starve because it's during
this dark period that the plants feed
the microbes in the rhizosphere with
their exited so you know they push them
down through the roots this was the
first time I really considered the
give-and-take between the plants and the
microbes and for so many people they run
especially in hydro they'll just run
their plants 24 hours to have the plants
grow faster and for many people they
actually can sneak another cycle in
their year because the plants grow about
20% faster with a 24 hour light cycle
and no break but
dr. calorie was very clear like you know
you are growing plants faster but you
are growing plants that are weaker
because you don't have strong microbes
and this back and forth before the
plants don't work as well but again Mike
my talk with her was only about eight
minutes so so does this sound like this
make sense to you that the plants need
this dark period and and if so what do
you see happening to benefit the plant
during the dark that is so essential
yeah so I'm a light nerd but I'm also a
circadian nerd which means that there
needs to be a 24-hour cycle and plants
respond to a 24-hour cycle which means
that it has to be both light and dark so
you know cell respiration occurs in
darkness a lot of beneficial things
occur during darkness so I think that
there's a lot of things that we probably
don't know you know I'm I'm not a plant
physiologist I'm a you know a lighting
scientist but so you know the the idea
of having a light and dark period is
going to drive the circadian rhythm of
that plan so so I think wholeheartedly
that we need to really a respect that
that dark period and if it's two hours
at a minimum I would like to at least
see the idea of 24 zero going to at
least 20 to two and again as I kind of
mentioned before there's infinite
expandability with with the newer LED
lighting technologies that that could
allow for the same kind of grow rates
because you could just have higher light
outputs and still have some sort of a
dark period now I think the idea of the
of you know microbial interactions is
really interesting but I think that
there is going to be a lot more going on
in that plant that's dictated by that
light dark cycle that is really you know
it always comes back to what what nature
is doing right
there's not too many environments that
are 24 zero and so so plants have
evolved around a an environment that's
both light and dark and so the better we
could do with that the better off your
plants going to be as a result I think
that my testament would be that that you
should strive to do that as much as you
possibly can
that's interesting that actually even
expands what I when I feel like I want
to continue to look into which is not
you're saying that yeah this is probably
all true with the microbes in the
rhizosphere that makes sense but also
there are unique botanical I don't know
housekeeping that happens during the
dark period that the plant needs itself
it's not like a like a you know just a
photosynthesis machine and you just turn
it on and it runs infinitely it to needs
to take out the garbage and do cell you
know transpiration and and these other
things that it does during the dark
period yeah I mean there's there's some
species of plant that will you know
co-evolved with its predators and will
change its nutritional content over the
course of the day so that it you know
quote-unquote tastes yuckier to plants
are to disease yeah and then there are
plants that will Co evolve with their
their pollinators so that they'll you
know emit some odors to to kind of
attract pollinators at a very specific
time and so there's all these things
that happen over the course of the day
biologically speaking and without a dark
period that plants gonna have no
reference for when the day starts and
when the day ends so I think that we're
probably gonna find out that there's
some interesting things that that are
happening as a result I think that
historically though the you know it's
always been one parameter so you get
longer hours you get more light and get
better growth but if you were to
compress that same amount of light from
24 hours into you know a shorter photo
period and just increase the intensity
of
lights I think you're gonna get a better
response right on that makes a lot of
sense so so let's move on to a different
line of thought but still talking about
light and dark period so so indoor
cultivators are very careful not to let
light hit their plants during the dark
period and for some that means simply
not entering the grow room for others it
means duct-taping any holes in their
indoor tents and for outdoor folks it
means not turning on the floodlights off
the back of the house at night right but
how do we know how much light leakage
will actually impact a crop where's the
threshold of where the interruption will
cause you know the plants biological
confusion yeah that's a that's a great
question I mean you know I don't I don't
know that there's a real threshold I
gather that it's actually not that not
that low it's not like you know the you
know a small incandescent light it's
gonna really do a whole lot you know the
the likely light leakage if it's minimal
coming through the cracks is gonna be
that much but I do think that you know
general practice to make the night
environment as dark as possible is a
good thing I don't think that there'll
be biological confusion but it may you
know halt cell respiration it may help
halt some of the nighttime activities
which are gonna be vital to to the
success of that crop so if we were to
think about which would be worse like
you know the the intensity of the
interruption of dark or the length of
the interruption of dark I want to know
if you have anything to say about that
so in comparison say walking into your
like let's say you know your
sister-in-law is in town and she walks
into your grow room and turns on the
light and during the dark period and
suddenly now there's you know there's
all these bulbs that are on and she's
like oh I'm this is not the room I'm
supposed to be on and so she turns off
the light so it was short maybe 10 12
seconds but it was
whole bunch of you know shop lights that
may have come on versus say a tent
that's got a handful of like pinprick
holes in it right so you got this tiny
tiny amount but it's in your living room
so it's constant right so so are they
both potentially troublesome or really
does because perhaps some hormone or
something needs to build up in the plant
this short burst really isn't gonna do
anything and it's more what happens over
the longer term it you know it's both
so the said the plant will acclimate so
if the dark period is you know that
constant day you know that content like
threshold low threshold day-in day-out
it's gonna acclimate to that as being
kind of the standard for what nighttime
is as opposed to the bright light may
may alter it for that one night and you
know maybe it will it'll actually shift
the clock to to maybe like a
quote-unquote different time zone for
the next day but after about two or
three days it's gonna come right back to
it so that single event is probably in
in both cases neither one's really that
bad it's really just kind of if you you
know if you do something where you got a
lot of light for a long period of time
it's is it going to have a detrimental
impact I guess that's probably not a
very satisfactory answer so if I if I
have to pick one I think that the the
short bursts of lots of light for one
period of time is going to have a longer
lasting impact than kind of the little
like really dim light constantly right
on and actually getting to that you said
something I found very fascinating the
idea that if you've got a small dribble
of light coming into your growing area
whether it be indoor or outdoor that so
long as it's you know a low amount that
that could become if you will the new
normal it reminds me of what you know
shooting photography and you set the
white balance on a camera no it's like
hey
that this is what light is today camera
right and so if you do have a tent in
your living room and you're a patient
and you're you know you're just doing
what you can to grow your medicine and
if you have an imperfect tent if you've
got a low level of light that goes in
there regularly your plants are just
gonna go okay this is what night's gonna
be for us so let's do our night stuff
when it gets to this point that's right
that's right now that's super
interesting Robert yeah I want to make
sure that that that doesn't mean like oh
you could just kind of crank on the the
ambient lights as long as you're doing
the standard practices to make that that
environment pretty dark that's that's
kind of what you what you want to do it
doesn't give you freedom to to just keep
the lights on I'm around your plants you
definitely want to try to make it as
dark as you possibly can but but given
that and it'll absolutely know what the
threshold is it'll acclimate to that
that low light level I've never heard
anybody say anything about the light
cycle and how it may impact plants
during a full moon right I mean I
understand a little bit about the the
biodynamic stuff from from those folks
about you know full moons but as far as
there being you know air quotes all of
this light during a bright night is that
I mean we experienced it you know as
human animals as a bright night and
because we can see and that makes us
feel safer but does a bright moon night
really impact the plants at all no no
not at all that's that's way below
threshold you know that's like Oh point
zero zero one Lux on a full moon you
know there is really what we're talking
about I mean even you go outside and you
see street lights there is evidence of
you know trees that are right next to
that street light will have a
significant impact but the ones that are
you know kind of some distance away
those light levels just kind of think
about that light level that's not
impacting that's below the threshold of
what of what that plant is seeing and of
course back to the
original point when it sees that every
single day it acclimates and goes
alright yeah this is this is my
nighttime scheme right on I follow this
alright good so one more question before
we go to our first commercial break you
know some indoor growers use a green
headlamp to work during the dark periods
and other growers are like no that's
totally [__] that like if you even
if you use green lamp it is interrupting
the the dark period so so you're the
scientists is is using a green headlight
lamp legitimate tech or is that a myth
well so what a green headlamp will do is
if you're trying to assess the plant and
see how they're doing they're going to
reflect that green better so you could
get a sense of what's going on with a
lot less light so it has to be a really
really dim green light if it's a super
bright green light and you know you're
you're absolutely getting giving them
that bright burst of light at a time
that could actually throw off their
their circadian rhythms and their night
phase so I think that it is a good idea
as long as if you're not blasting those
headlights and the main reason is
because you're you're using the spectral
reflectance of that plant the fact that
it's reflecting a lot of that green
light it's using a lot of it but it's
reflecting the most of it back and
you'll if what you're trying to do is
see the plant you know assess an issue
and then go away you want to use as
little of it as you possibly can to make
sure you can do that to do it good
enough and then go about you know go
about your other business so it's not a
fail-safe it's not going to not
interrupt that plan it absolutely can do
that but the green light helps you see
that plant a little bit better using the
least amount of light you possibly can
all right that's interesting all right
so let me see if I can break that down
to two rules of thumb for everybody so
would it be correct if I were to say
if you're going to use any light green
is a good choice but you want to use a
small amount of it as you can and only
use it in a small area like with a
headlamp in contrast to I've even seen
people using green flood lamps in their
grow at night so that they can you know
clean and and things like that whereas
that that's a terrible idea because the
intensity is more and longer Green is
not a magical color spectrum that
doesn't interrupt sleep that's right
that's absolutely right yep right on
cool well thank you very much for that
Robin we're gonna go ahead and take our
first short break and be right back you
are listening to shaping fire and my
guest today is lighting scientist Robert
solare there are lots of good seed
makers out there every once in a while
someone becomes legendary the Mendocino
California cannabis breeder called
mandelbrot is one of these people
Mandelbrot was also known as Roz truth
and his cultivars are known as the
foundation for the Emerald triangles
world-famous gasoline scented terpene
profile back in the day when it was
really hard to find quality genetics and
education Mandelbrot was advocating for
organic growing techniques and providing
exceptional seeds that would sell out as
soon as they hit the shelves
Mandelbrot lived too short of life dying
in 2015 but while he was with us he
created several connoisseur level
cannabis masterpieces like oil spill the
truth and royal cush no matter if you
approach growing cannabis more as a
toker or a breeder you will find
something that delights you in
Mandelbrot selections because while some
strains are better to grow or to smoke
Mandelbrot's creations excel in every
category and that's why people keep
talking about them even today emerald
mountain legacy continues the Roz Truth
tradition by preserving these coveted
genetics for future generations
unchanged as they were originally
created in the mid 2000s emerald
mountain legacy also creates tasteful
modern crosses to Mandelbrot's classics
these lines worked by Mandelbrot's
brother ben furthers their family's
genetics and a spirit that man
himself would approve of checkout the
emerald mountain legacy Instagram and
website to see photos of these plants
and learn more about Mandelbrot and his
infamous strains emerald mountain legacy
seeds are available online from seed
banks and distributors including
labyrinth seed company the regenerative
seed company and pure sativa emerald
mountain legacy keeping mammal brats
legacy alive pre-rolls have come a long
way since the early days of
normalization
when you choose Saints joints you are
smoking all flour top-shelf pre-rolls
with terpenes that will sculpt your high
in a way that dry old pre-rolls just
can't whereas most brands release
pre-rolls as an afterthought for the
last 5 years
Saints joints has focused on their line
of exotic curated joints and while some
companies just chased the hyped strains
Saints joints goes deeper searching out
hard-to-find strains unexpected crosses
and nearly forgotten land races and
classics and some hype ones too not only
does a joint from Saints Smoke
incredibly well they have fine-tuned
every step of the process so you don't
get runs in the paper the joint is just
the right density to have a nice pull
and the joint stays lit even if you get
a bit chatty Saints joints boxes are
works of art and will spark conversation
when you pull them out at a party Saints
award winning boxes change with every
release feature edgy outsider art and
often raise awareness of important
issues like equal rights Saints boxes
are so desired then many collect them
and display them in their homes ask your
bud tenor for Saints joints and have a
premium joint experience now if you are
licensed cannabis cultivator I have an
extra message for you Saints is looking
for partners in legal cannabis States to
expand the availability of the Saints
joints brand do you grow exceptional
canvas flower but are less excited about
all the effort cost and risk of
launching your own brand Saints joints
may be just the partner you are looking
for already established in California
Washington and Oklahoma
and recognized by Entrepreneur Magazine
and green entrepreneur as a cannabis
industry leader the Saints joints brand
will set you apart in your home market
the best thing I can recommend is for
you to visit their Instagram at Saints
joints and look at their patented drawer
design boxes become that brand everyone
is talking about without having to build
it from scratch
check out the Instagram at Saints joints
and then visit Saints joints calm to
find out more if you listen to shaping
fire and you grow your own cannabis
chances are high that you are very
particular about the inputs you use for
growing people like us painstakingly
self-educate on cannabis nutrients and
techniques so we can cultivate the best
tasting and cleanest flowers possible
and when we go to purchase those
nutrients we want to be sure that our
supplier shares our values and is
providing exceptional quality this is
why I recommend build a soil calm to my
friends who care about quality build a
soil empowers organic growers to do
their best work by sourcing and shipping
only the finest cannabis growing
supplies from organic inputs soils soil
testing and pots to Lights growing tents
sprayers and cover crops build a soil
founder Jeremy Silva doesn't just stock
his store with what's available he goes
deep to personally vet each product for
quality and determine that there isn't a
better version of the product that he
could be selling because of this arduous
process you know that your options on
build a soil calm have been carefully
curated to create the results you are
looking for not only that but the build
a soil way is a philosophy that will
permeate your interaction with the
company from website design to pricing
and shipping to after purchase support
Jeremy and his team always strive to do
their best and give you the best
customer service in the business
checkout build a soil dot-com today for
top tier quality cultivation supplies
and a friends and family buying
experience and check out their
educational videos and extra
social media while you're there to
quality organic growing supplies at
build a soil calm welcome back you are
listening to shaping fire I am your host
Shango Llosa our guest this week is
lighting scientist Robert Solaire so
Robert you know during an interview with
soil educator Jeff Lowen Fell's he
suggested that sunlight has a very
powerful effect on the soil microbes and
soil life generally it isn't just the
plants that's taking up the light it's
actually the soil and you know
everything that's living in it that is
also taking in the light and and he
continued to say that this is one of the
reasons why indoor cultivation pales
when compared to outdoor generally
because the Sun is so much more intense
that it has I don't know deeper reach
into the soil I guess I'll say so you
know what is it in sunshine that
provides you know life to the soil and
how difficult is that to attain nowadays
with lights indoors yeah I you know I
would think any of those benefits you
know could come from the the penetration
but I would probably stand to the guest
that it has a lot more to do with the
spectrum so you know indoor lighting has
the opportunity you know to do whatever
but but for energy efficiency it's
always putting all the energy at least
the energy-efficient ones LEDs
specifically will put all the energy in
the PAR region from 400 to 700
nanometers you know the Sun puts out
stuff you know from 300 nanometers you
know on up so there's stuff in the UV
there's stuff too and the infrared
spaces and the interaction of those
things with sunlight and daylight is is
probably pretty and profound so I would
probably stand to guess that that it has
more to do with the the idea of you know
it could be a circadian component of
temperature but probably also you know
the far Reds
and the ultraviolets that come from that
that solar exposure that that's going to
have the impact on microbes and I would
probably say that that doesn't mean that
interior lighting is inferior it just
means that we got to get smarter about
how we do interior lighting because we
could absolutely recreate any of those
spectrums we could create far reds we
can create UVA UVB so it really just
comes around to playing around and
really getting into the research of what
we could do to to kind of find out what
those what those benefits are yeah
that's interesting and and you know it's
it's taking me a long time to come
around this idea that it really depends
on what you want for your output I mean
there's crappy outdoor and there's
crappy indoor right and I've had good
indoor and I've had good outdoor but in
the end it's it's what you're actually
looking to produce and if and if you can
find a combination of you know a
appropriately efficient indoor light
that can sustain the proper you know
microbe life and also give the plant
what it needs you may not need the
entirety of the sunshine spectrum but
there's no there's no doubt that when
you're outside that you know there's
there's all the spectrum you need and
more for your plans so there there's
some kind of combination between you
know the the knowledge of which parts of
the spectrum helps sustain microbe wife
and the rhizosphere and along the the
top layers that the light can penetrate
and also you know I guess just bang for
your buck right like if the goal is to
produce a you know a good tasting
good-looking plant that thrives and
resists pests we mean we may be able to
do that without the entire spectrum of
the Sun that's right and and I and you
hit on a good point there is that you
know as someone who you know makes
lights you know you could make light
with all these things but it's gonna
cost you a lot more
to have that that capability and you
know you're gonna give up efficiency so
so really if you wanted UV light for
your soil you know get like a
supplemental UV light UV LED light or a
fluorescent tube and put it on the soil
and test it out and see what what you
get out of it I think that there are
things you could do kind of add-on
features that you could you could throw
on to test stuff out and really kind of
see what what is gonna work for your
individual grow I think that's probably
the most important thing is to for us
all kind of be scientists with what
we're doing well I appreciate you saying
that I mean this show is very in favor
of citizen scientists and it's funny
because sometimes I'll have you know
either guests on the show or scientists
all meet at conventions or whatever and
they really don't like the you know the
regular folk mess and messin with the
science and they're like God you just
you know just read the white papers and
do what we say you know but especially
when it comes to cannabis when for so
long all of us growers were on our own
because you know good educated folks
like you were you know we're not
available to us right and so I
appreciate the fact that you know you
encouraged us to experiment as well in
speaking of experimenting you know I was
in in preparation for this interview I
went and I watched all your your prior
interviews that I could find and during
an in one of your interviews you
mentioned that you have some secret
sauce on using light to improve cloning
success and and during that interview
the interviews blew they blue right over
it but I'm like oh that's totally what I
want the part of it I wanted to hear so
so will you share that with us like how
can we better our-our cloning success
with something about lights well I think
that it's I think that most people kind
of have an idea of what's going on and
it's really kind of meeting the blue
light thresholds you know people will
talk about you know they'll just use
metal halide or they'll use cool white
fluorescent to do this
and really it's a matter of making sure
that you meet the blue light threshold
because if you don't we talked about
this early on if you don't have enough
blue light the the plants will basically
feel like they're their star they're in
shade or something until the old long
gate trying to get more blue light until
they meet the threshold and so so it's
really important to get a light that has
that blue light that meets that blue
light threshold it's usually about kind
of rule of thumb is about 30 micro moles
per meter squared of blue light is
what's required so if you're trying to
put out you know 300 or 400 micro moles
per meter squared that means you're
gonna probably want about 8 to 10% of
blue light and so this is kind of where
a lot of this stuff if you had high
pressure sodium high pressure sodium
only puts out about 5% blue light so
this is kind of where some of the the
ideas have stemmed from but if you if
you figure out that threshold which is
generally about 30 micro moles a blue
light now you can really kind of
maximize that spectrum for efficiency
and so once you maximize the efficiency
then you're gonna get tremendous yields
because you could you could really kind
of create something that has that
spectrum meeting the threshold but but
putting all the energy in the high
efficiency photosynthetically active
region you would not be able to do this
with with either the traditional lights
of hph HBS or metal halide right you're
gonna need some sort of led to do this
nowadays right yeah yeah you know there
are manufacturers that'll talk about you
know they've got a special high-pressure
sodium or something that has or you know
more optimized for for growing but the
reality is the spectrum the spectral
power distribution of these things the
way that they put energy is pretty much
the same HB s versus a different HPS
metal halide versus different metal
halide it's really only LED that has
this almost infinite might well I would
say it is absolutely infinite modularity
of and configuration of what spectrum
you could possibly have so for a cloning
area you could have exactly the right
spectrum that you need for a vegetation
area exactly what you the right spectrum
that you need for flowering just the
right spectrum that you need and they
all really kind of stems from a very
specific blue light threshold it's all
kind of the same so the reason why HBS
works out well in a you know in the
flowering room is because the light
levels are so high if you're giving you
know 600 plus micro moles per meter
squared
if 5% is blue you're still hitting that
threshold of 30 micro moles of blue so
that's that's why it still works there
if you were to use lower light levels
than that then you actually start seeing
morphological effects and not good ones
bad ones they start getting lanky or
leggy if you will mm-hmm so I know that
I'm about to suggest a really janky hack
but I've seen it and so I'm probably
gonna ask you you know I've seen people
have HPS lights and they that they read
something that they needed to increase
their blue and so they took those you
know they like the lighting the blue
lighting gels from like a rot you know
like a stagecraft like like going to see
a band or something and and and they
will put one of those you know over that
and they're like look I just cover it up
20% of my light with blue I just got a
bunch more blue it is is that science no
so you you know if you didn't get 30
micro moles of blue without the filter
the filter just removed it subtracts it
doesn't add anything oh it's the
opposite direction even so
so yeah it's it shifted or its removes
the a lot of the red component out there
but your light levels have just dropped
significantly so I'd love to find
someone where that actually worked but
that that's not gonna work that is that
is that is not a good idea right on well
you know how it is with bro sign
right I mean it's kind of its kind of
the the other side of the coin just
being a citizen scientist right it's
like you know trying a bunch of stuff is
great but then also you know a lot of
the stuff that had been handed down from
us from our you know from our mentors
doesn't pan out long term yeah for sure
so I know a lot of your work with light
involves humans and and it was actually
really interesting to listen to your
interviews about you know human
Lighting's and circadian rhythms and
then also then to hear you talk about
the same thing in plants so I thought
that was pretty cool but you know
cultivation employees spend a lot of
time under a wide range of lights from
you know from classic HPS and metal
halide to LED and you know now even some
folks are spending for the plasma lights
so what impact does working under these
sorts of artificial lights have on the
humans that work below them and I'm
assuming that we can't just group them
all in one category so like go category
by category if you will because lots of
cultivators listen to this show and I
think they'd be curious to know what the
lights they work under maybe doing to
their to their human yeah well I would
say that generally speaking from from a
human circadian standpoint I guess that
most people are very well educated on
this but you know there's a lot of talk
about blue light and its effect on honor
sleep but basically there is a newly
discovered photoreceptor that drives our
circadian rhythms and and really what
the problem is is not so much the these
grow environments but the regular dim
lit office environment so we really kind
of need to have brighter days and darker
nights and in the built environment if
you're in a gross space and in and
you're getting you know what it'd call
it you know six seven hundred micro
moles per meter squared that's a ton of
light you know you don't need to be
convinced the fact that that is a ton of
light so
as if you are working a day shift in
those spaces and you're getting a ton of
that light that is a fantastic way to
get the dose that you need of light for
your day now if you're on a ship work
schedule where you're going in after
hours that light could absolutely
destroy your sleep if that's a time that
you're supposed it'd not be getting you
know just like we talked about before
plants could get altered their growth
could get altered that could completely
throw off your circadian rhythms making
it really hard to to to sleep that night
but also the next three or four nights
afterwards as a result of it it's kind
of like that will be enough light to
shift you to another time zone up to
three hours later so so that is
something that could dramatically impact
your sleep so if you're getting that
light exposure what I would actually
recommend which is pretty simple if
you're doing it after hours there are
blue blocking glasses that exist you can
buy them anywhere and actually we got
some friends at a true dark that makes
make some really good ones that block
out all the blue light that would be a
really good approach to to protecting
yourself from getting too much of that
daytime exposure at a time that you
don't want to get it right on so let me
unpack that a little bit so so I think
you're saying that if if you're under
all that light during your regular day
daytime let's say 9:00 to 5:00 shift
you're actually winning because you're
getting a ton of light you know you will
not need a seasonal effectiveness
disorder light box like you're getting
all that at work and you're getting it
at the right time in relationship to
your sleep cycle so that when you go to
sleep you'll be good to go to sleep yeah
and and and then but if you if your
second shift in the afternoon and you're
still hoping to sleep at night you're
kind of jacked because it's going to
shift you off by 3 hours and disturb
your night
let's say you're working the night shift
if you work the night shift and you're
sleeping during the daytime so your
whole life is upside down will you be in
good shape again because again you while
you might be on an artificial sleep
cycle that's not in jive with the planet
you're actually set resetting your own
circadian rhythm to night shift and
you'd actually be okay again yeah so
that that's a that's a great question
and it's it's it's the quandary that has
plagued pretty much all shift work in
all industries which is you know that's
great we could totally do that and in
this case you'll absolutely shift now
the problem is what happens when you
like live your normal life on your off
days and stuff like that yeah because
now maybe you're aligned with that that
night shift but then you go out and
normal life has a regular Sun that goes
at a different time so now the Sun is
the thing that completely throws off
your schedule so so again it could be
the exact same thing you wear those
glasses when you go out in the Sun to
try to to try to minimize the disruption
that the the solar cycle is going to
have on you but really from a health and
wellness standpoint what you want to do
is try to create that same pattern same
wakeup in sleep times over and over
again and unfortunately for some people
that means you're you're kind of looking
like a vampire on your off days so the
the protection mechanism in all
scenarios is to have some sort of blue
blocking glasses to try to to try to
make it to that light exposure at the
wrong time doesn't doesn't throw your
sleep cycles off kilter while we're
talking about glasses and the eyes you
know I don't spend a ton of time under
cultivation lights but I know when I go
and I get tours and stuff and the tour
goes especially long that when I leave
sometimes my eyes feel tired like
they've been worked too much and and I'm
curious what
you know being under intense light like
that as a full-time job might degrade
the eyes are these are these spectrums
that were growing under potentially
dangerous for the eyes or is it just
that I'm not used to that intensity and
so when I go in it for a little while it
tires my my eyes out yeah it's so I
think that the the bigger thing is it's
not the intensity it's not the spectrum
it's really kind of more the the
gradient or the contrast it's you have a
lot of bright and dark and your eyes are
constantly trying to adjust to those if
you think about being outside you know
it's usually you're either usually
either shaded or you're you know in this
bright you know ubiquitously bright
space so it's nothing about the it's not
nothing about the intensity and
something really about the spectrum
that's that's particularly harmful ful
what's causing this fatigue is Scott
that your eyes are constantly going from
a bright spot to a dark spot and it's
trying to acclimate to these multiple
locations and and there's a little bit
of you know your eyes aren't acclimated
to to that so there's a little bit of
that but we know from the visual science
standpoint that high contrast ratios
like you know it's just like when you
when you watch it when you're watching
TV at night and all the lights are off
it it could be you know kind of glaring
and off-putting but you just put a
little bit of ambient light on and it
makes that screen a lot more comfortable
to see a lot of it has to do with the
contrast ratios of light and dark that
you see so if I understand that right
what you're suggesting is that actually
it's the might like bite my pupils are
tired that muscle or whatever it is that
meant that mechanism in my eyes it's
it's it's opening and closing so much so
it's closing when I'm directly under the
light but then it's opening so when I go
away from the light for a minute to take
something off of a shelf and bring it
back to the light now it's back under so
it's it's at that back and forth that's
making my eyes tired that's right and
that that's super cool well like there's
a con
you know there's actually a lot more
fatigue on the cones itself because it's
called lateral inhibition which is the
contrast it amplifies a signal when it's
contrasted against darkness so it's it
you're you're really giving your your
cones and your eye a rollercoaster of
emotion so it's a combination of that
and the pupil your irises are kind of
going going back and forth so we talked
about the the true dark glasses for
people you know to help with their
circadian cicle what what kind of a
recommendation do you have for people
who work under lights and so they have
this experience of going back and forth
from the bright environment to the
darker environment and so they're their
pupils are potentially getting tired at
work is there is there a hack for them
yeah I mean it should be just glasses I
mean you want so with like the same kind
of thing are we trying to cut out the
blue or is it a different kind of
glasses now and like the method 7s or
something I'm I'm not sure if I know the
method sevens
what are those deal oh so they're just
often used for for folks and not only to
to darken the eyes but from what I
understand about the technology it's
it's it's taking out particular
spectrums the only the time that I
experience it most is when I'm trying to
take photography in aggro and I get
those those black bars on the
photographs and so I had not used the
method seven glasses I actually do use
the method seven lens on my camera so it
sounds like we may have waded into an
area that that um yeah but I think that
what's interesting those black bars are
actually just a it's the DC ripple on
your electrical current that interferes
with with the camera exposure usually
I've seen on like iPhones and all you
have to do is kind of change the
aperture exposure and it'll it'll kind
of wipe out I think iPhones really kind
of
fix that in software recently but that's
that's actually a really really
interesting phenomenon on ripple current
in your lighting system it it's nothing
wrong with anything that's going on but
it's it's a it's just a conflict between
the two electrical devices but I would
say back to the main question is what
you do to try to if you're going on that
back and forth is really just try to
have overall intensity glasses if you
can
I don't think trying to filter out any
spectrum so that blue light is going to
is what drives your your what's called a
sustained pupil constriction so you
probably don't want to have like a blue
blocking glass because you know while
that keeps your eye open it's also you
know letting a lot of that that light
come in so so that's not good you really
just want to lower the light level so
what you're seeing in your office and
what you're seeing in the grow space are
close to the same so most most standard
off-the-shelf glasses will cut ninety
percent of the light level and that's
probably what you want to do there would
then even though it certainly would
increase the the price of the operation
just for the for this for the scientific
basis would it would it then also make
sense to let's say that you're in a
warehouse and you've got you know
there's some part of it that is the
artificial lighting for grows would it
also make sense to pick up the you know
the ambient lighting of the entire space
so there's less contrast just like your
example watching television in the dark
is not like the greatest idea of like
perhaps the whole warehouse shouldn't be
black except for the grow area yeah I
mean that that is that's a great idea as
well to to try to minimize those
contrast ratios I mean I know this is a
a non grow example but like in in
buildings at least well designed ones
they'll actually put if you have windows
put light on the on the walls in between
those windows to try to make sure that
that says Brooke that wall in between
the bright windows is as bright as it
can be to minimize that contrast ratio
well that's interesting you know it's
it's a I bet you it's only a matter of
time before we start to see you know
OSHA regulations around how bright the
ambient environment in cultivation
warehouses have got to be just for the
health of the employees yeah yeah I
think that's that's interesting I mean I
would say because we also do some work
with the Department of Energy that they
would probably suggest that the glasses
is probably the better solution then
wasting all the extra electricity yeah
yeah all right cool well let's go ahead
and take our second short break we'll be
right back you are listening to shaping
fire and my guest today is lighting
scientist Robert solare in times like
these when so many cannabis companies
are growing their flower in gigantic
warehouses and fields using synthetic
nutrients it is good to know that there
are authentic California heritage
growers using natural farming techniques
and sunshine to cultivate cannabis
flowers for you California has produced
the best cannabis in the world for
generations and the idea that massively
scaled industrial cannabis production
could produce the same quality as small
batch lovingly cultivated flowers is
just silly moon time medicinals is
located in Humboldt County on the lush
South Fork of the eel River watershed in
the epicenter of the American cannabis
heartland moon time medicinals
grows under bright california sun in
greenhouses using only natural farming
techniques like google culture compost
teas whole food fertilizers and
fermented plant juices every part of
their growing process plays its own part
in nature and nothing synthetic is
injected into the process the result is
big beautiful cannabis flowers with
wide-ranging terpene profiles that taste
like great cannabis should if you live
in California ask your bud tender for
moon time Madison
and visit moon time medicinals on the
web and instagram moon time medicinals
is also available as part of the Redwood
roots family moon times whole flowers
appear in Redwood roots curated joint
packs alongside other heritage cannabis
cultivators like ladies sativa farm
Ridgeline farms humble redwood healing
and others moon time medicinals
top-shelf cannabis grown in harmony with
nature one of the reasons why no-till
cannabis growing is so valued by farmers
is because the mycelium networks in the
soil remain established from year to
year and we know these fungal networks
are essential because they are the
nutrient super highways that extend far
and wide in the substrate to feed your
plants
the trouble with growing in new soils or
blended cocoa substrates is that it
takes most of the plants life just to
create these mycelium highways Dino
Michael endo mycorrhizal fungi inoculant
reduces that time and gets your plant
eating a wider array of nutrients faster
and it's three times the concentration
of the current leading brand in the u.s.
at 900 propagules per gram of to fungal
species selected specifically for
cannabis cultivation this new product
called Dino my co is the result of 30
years of research and trials at the
volcanic a Greek ultra Research
Institute in Israel it has also been
vigorously trialed by cannabis and food
growers across the u.s. since the
product first arrived here last year you
may have already even heard about
dynamite go by its original name
dynamite
now Dino myko is available at grow shops
and online in the United States for the
first time I love using dynamite go to
both speed up the growth of mycelium
networks in the soil but also as a bio
stimulant to make clone cuttings more
virile you can see side by sides showing
the comparative growth on their
Instagram at Dino myco if you demand
reliable growing results and appreciate
the importance of an active root zone in
creating a thriving plant I encourage
you to check out Dino myko at Dino my
cocom and find out where you can get
yours that's dy n oh my co.com
whether you are starting with new beds
or pots or if you want to add some zing
to tired soil choose dynamite go to
maximize your plants potential Dino my
co endo mycorrhizal inoculant growing
cannabis in greenhouses is taking over
the cannabis industry an efficient and
effective blend of sunshine grown
terpene profiles and the controlled
environment of indoor greenhouses can be
the best of both worlds for many
greenhouse operators though building
their greenhouse before gaining insight
into how cannabis greenhouses differ
from ornamental crops can be the start
of a world of hurt Eric Branstad and his
team at greenhouse advisory group have
the experience and technical know-how to
help you avoid these pitfalls Eric
Branstad has been helping cannabis
growers find locations design build and
equip their greenhouses for over a
decade first starting in Northern
California but expanding over the last
five years to helping clients throughout
the world he has an impeccable
reputation for both depth of knowledge
and kindness and communication you can
hear Eric explains some of the
challenges facing cannabis greenhouses
and how to overcome them in episode
number forty one of the shaping fire
podcast no matter where I go in the
country good people with smart
backgrounds still are making the mistake
of building without knowing cannabis and
it causes them to burn through capital
and time fast
everyone has their fill and failure
point for some it is improper
ventilation planning for others it is
surface temperatures of the building or
the plants leaves or both some folks
that build our greenhouse from scratch
make really basic errors like placement
of the greenhouse on the property or not
understanding the natural environment
where the greenhouse sits
some have even built a decent greenhouse
but are inefficient in their deployment
of light deprivation techniques and
never really hit their target yields
it's great when you learn from your
mistakes but it's even better when you
learn from the mistakes of others when
you bring on greenhouse advisory group
you will learn from the mistakes of
their many clients and you'll take
advantage of the best practices
developed by Eric Branstad over his
years of working with clients just like
you from location development to
choosing a builder and
freaking out your new greenhouse or
retrofitting or rescuing your failing
greenhouse Eric will help you through it
visit greenhouse advisory group comm to
learn more and connect with Eric and his
team that's green house advisory group
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire I'm your host Shango losan
our guest this week is lighting
scientists Robert solare so Robert one
of the things that I've heard you say a
couple times on your other interviews is
that you know people and plants see
light differently and that seems like
the kind of phrase that you like kind of
throw out there but that there's a whole
hell of a lot behind it and so I just
want to go on a little fishing
expedition with this phrase that you use
often what do you mean by plants and
humans seeing the light differently oh
yeah I mean so I guess anyone who's
familiar with early day LED light will
show you know it's a purple light right
so or pink light and it's just comprised
of blue in red well that's because
plants which are green reflecting sea
blue and red most efficiently and people
actually see green most efficiently so
on a high level so there are things that
are what people see which are kind of
Luxor or lumens that's how we see light
this is how we quantify how bright
something is well plants which use ppfd
see things differently but I think that
it's even more complicated than that
because when we talk about say comparing
different light fixtures like a
high-pressure sodium light fixture or a
metal halide or an LED the way that
those spectral compositions are will see
them maybe like we could have a metal
halide that looks like we'll call it a
5000 Kelvin color which is very cool
white light and we could get an LED that
matches it and so they look they could
look the same to us but the plants
actually will look at those lights and
they're very very different and so the
it's all about these spectral
power distribution of how that all works
out that that is really what you want to
think about when you're deciding what
kind of LED light or whatever kind of
lighting technology you have to that's
gonna work best for your grow so when
you look at hyper sodium that doesn't
mean you need an LED replacement that
looks the same that means you you know
you might get better performance out of
something that doesn't look the same
same goes true with the with the metal
halide is that what the plant sees and
what we see are fundamentally different
and so we can't look at a light and say
oh that's gonna perform you know really
well or really poorly just because what
my eye sees and this is really true as
we start getting into the infinite
possibilities that LED light provides
for us so if we can't use our eyes to
judge the spectrum and while that makes
like intellectual sense to me you know
I've been in plenty of grow rooms where
the cultivator has told me that you know
that there but for example like bulbs
get tired over time right and they'll
tell me oh the bulbs getting tired I can
tell because the spectrum is different
and while you know I certainly defer to
their experience and it's their grow
room is that enough of a salty subtlety
and change of an old bulb changing
spectrum that they'll actually be able
to see with this technology we have that
our eyes so with the older technology
absolutely a metal halide will change
and changes color once it gets
quote-unquote tired and that's a visible
change that it's a direction we can see
that is a visible change in those
changes will so a new metal halide
versus old metal halide will get a
little bit of a shift but that's not
nearly as significant as what its gonna
have versus an LED light spectrum and so
what it comes down to is really kind of
understanding the buckets of light that
they have how much percentage of blue
light you have how much percentage of
red light you have and so when you're
thinking of
you got to think about it in those terms
and it all comes back to kind of hitting
this threshold of you know a certain
number of blue and this is really kind
of what drives most of the morphological
effects is I need you know again rule of
thumb about 30 micro moles as my minimum
of blue light so when I measure light
and weight think about how much light
I'm gonna put out there you know if I
have 20% blue light you know that's
probably gonna do good enough if I have
5% blue light that's probably gonna be
pushing the boundaries of what I'm gonna
get and so as I mentioned before hyper
sodium has low amounts of blue
metal-halide has you know higher amounts
of blue fluorescents will have higher
amounts of blue an LED could be
absolutely anything it really depends on
what you what you're trying to do and
LED is is much more of an engineered
light source an engineered solution to
try to bring the benefits of those other
technologies but in a very targeted way
that's giving the light on the plant the
right spectrum that it needs at the
right time and and just trying to to
tailor that spectrum to what the plant
needs and at the basically benefit of
energy efficiency all right so let's
take this back one one step so if if
there are limits to the usability of our
eyes to determine spectrum for those of
us who are not lighting nerds what are
the tools that a cultivator would use to
measure these light attributes that the
that the eyes cannot handle so if you
know you've got these deep you know
you've got buckets and you've got
intensity what are the tools of the
trade if you will for those of us who
don't spend a lot of time with lights
yeah so I mean it's it's pretty simple
if you have high pressure sodium there
are rules of thumbs metal halide is
about 15% blue high pressure sodium is
about 5% blue and so just think
about it like that and then if you're
thinking about you know what LEDs gonna
do to replace either one of those think
about what's gonna have a similar blue
light percentage as those two things
five or 15% and that's what you want to
match and so when you go to any credible
LED lighting manufacturer that's the
number that you want to have they should
have published on there the percentage
of blue light on their specification
sheet and that's what you need to think
about is if you're thinking about it for
a for a flower space where you're gonna
have high pressure sodium normally you
want to have at least 5% blue which the
majority of them all do and if you want
to have something that is for a metal
halide or a cool for fluorescent space
you want to make sure that you're north
of 15% so you actually took that in a
different direction that I thought I
thought you I didn't realize that you
know I mean I I knew that the lights
were sold with full spec sheets I mean I
get that part but I actually thought you
were gonna say oh we use these hand-held
technologies to to measure the the
buckets of you know the spectrum and
then we go back and we just adjust our
lights but what I'm kind of getting the
idea is is that this the spectrum is
going on most lights the spectrum is
going to come hardwired and so you want
to buy the spectrum from from from the
jump from from day one it isn't like
you're gonna buy your light and then
tune your spectrum for what you
personally like in your grow that's
that's right I mean there are ways that
you could do it again you're gonna pay
through the nose for it
you know those meters that that can do
it are you know a couple thousand
dollars for a meter that that could tell
you what the spectrum is and then you
don't really know what to do with it
afterwards really it comes down to very
simply saying okay if this is I just
need to meet a minute
minimum criteria so that things don't
get weird in my grow and so it's just a
matter of looking at the spec sheet and
usually what I've seen is that every LED
light has kind of hit the threshold of
what the minimum needs is minimum needs
are for either one you might come across
one that you know doesn't have enough of
the the blue light content but by and
large they almost all do nowadays
hmm well it's that's nice that way it's
a lot harder to screw up that's for sure
yeah so um so as you and I talked about
before before we got going today you
know I do a lot of work with patients
and and you know while while a lot of
folks are you know focused on commercial
cultivation my pate my passion will
still always be with like these little
home growers trying to give them self
relief and it is incredibly common for
them to have these like like these
little plastic greenhouses or hoop
houses where they've they you know taken
some kind of skeleton of wood and they
wrap it around in plastic and you know
you know I know from interviewing Eric
Branstad the greenhouse specialist that
you know at the very least we want to
use four year or horticultural plastic
but a lot of people are you still using
plastic sheeting you know just from Home
Depot if thinking that well it keeps the
plants dry
would you tell it to just a little bit
about what what the different plastics
will do to the light when it hits our
plants and maybe even more importantly
how we will experience that in the
plants that were growing for our
medicine yeah sue that's that's a really
good question so generally speaking
plastics or design plastics don't do
well with UV and we kind of talked
earlier one of the one of the key
benefits of sunlight is the UV that's
going on to the
their stuff that's happening out there
in the in the non-visual region so a
horticultural grade lighting is going to
is going to do better I'm sorry a
horticultural grade plastic is going to
do better it's going to understand that
those far ends of the spectrum are
important and try to allow them through
the cheaper plastics are not and they
are not going to consider what those
ends of the spectrum are going to do for
for the plant and generally they're
going to be not the best outdoor rated
and what will happen you'll notice that
they'll start yellowing over time
they'll start becoming very brittle and
so that yellowing is going to take a lot
of the blue out of the spectrum it'll
drop the overall intensity but it's
going to take out all the UV all the
blue light is the yellowing is the
yellowing in the plastic or in the
plants the I'm sorry yeah the yellowing
is in the plastic okay please continue
yeah so the plastic we yellow and that
that means it's attenuating more of the
UV it's attenuating more of the blue
light and so it's so now the plants not
getting things that are vital for it's
for normal growth right on then I would
strongly advise to get a horticultural
grade plastic I love it that's that is
the the decision rule that I was looking
for there because you know how it is
like when you're working with you know
any kind of a home grower whether it's
cannabis or vegetables there are so many
variables and so many people don't have
complete knowledge that you go and you
see and you're like okay they've got
they've got the they have non
horticultural plastic and they're their
plants are not doing well but it could
also because they screwed up some other
variable right sure so it's good to hear
without any question that not only does
it make a difference but it makes a big
enough difference where you know it's
definitely worth spring in for the extra
money to get the proper plastic that's
right yeah all right so hey before we
before we wrap up here I want to I want
to ask you one question specifically
about LED
so you know you know even though you're
an LED expert you know I really wanted
to have you on the show today more
because you are a lighting and and
horticulture scientist and at the same
time you know there's a big competition
in our scene between LEDs and and the
traditional light mediums and you know
they're they're kind of like street
gangs like they do not play soft really
people get get angry if they are
dedicated to HPS and and you do and put
out any kind of LED content and then on
the flip the LED people i'll find
themselves you know much more
sophisticated and educated and they talk
all this trash about the HPS people and
I'm all like hey man I have had really
kick-ass flowers of both but I do know
that LED has kind of just kind of come
into its own right there there's a lot
of flowers over the last 20 well I'll
say 12 years that that I've had from LED
that just just didn't rock my world
right and so as as somebody who you know
does LED engineering and you know but
also understands the fundamentals and
and why people choose HP s what are your
thoughts on the threshold point like
have we passed that threshold point now
where LEDs have gotten to the point with
spectrum and intensity efficiency of
electrical usage and and price come
competition where even the most hardcore
HPS people should start to like like you
know at least read some websites about
the LED stuff because we've passed this
threshold because you know I have now
had LED flower that is fabulous and and
while there's this whole secondary thing
about electrical usage in in my mind I'm
looking forward to the day where we can
have solar-powered indoor right and I
and I know we got we got a while we got
a you know there's there's some
technologies that need to get developed
but um you know I prefer growing
outdoors because the sunshine is free
but the day will come where we can do
solar powered in
and so then so then it's all going to be
on the technology and it's going to
decrease the question of efficiency will
be out the door so with that very
significant and yet potentially
convoluted setup where do you see that
threshold point is and have we passed it
yeah so the threshold point really was
can LED lighting serve as a thousand
watt HPS replacement and I think until
just very recently the answer has been
no and so what I think that the majority
of people who have kind of been
naysayers of LED have either been burned
from generations past or they've just
kind of heard about it or they've
they've kind of got this stigma that it
just can't put out the the output and
anyone who's who said that say five
years ago were a one hundred and one
hundred percent correct I think that the
lighting industry did them well some
people in the LED lighting industry did
themselves just gave themselves a black
eye by trying to say it was a thousand
watt HPS replacement by you know putting
a meter directly underneath it and going
see you get the same light levels but no
one's thinking about what happens at ten
degrees from underneath that light
source but now they have reached that
threshold where they can and and it has
been you know not everyone could do it
it's a it's a thermal exercise to try to
get all that heat out so so there's a
fundamental difference between how
traditional lights work like high
pressure sodium versus LED high pressure
sodium it you know it has a certain
amount of efficiency and whatever else
is waste heat is is heat and it radiates
that heat LEDs are different because
what is waste heat is actually conducted
away sorry do I need to go over that
again
did you hear my phone ring just now uh
no no I did okay
I call it no no we got it okay I'm so
and what happens is when when that he is
conducted away it takes a certain amount
of a thermal like device in order to get
that heat away but what I could say very
certainly is that LED has been able to
to hit that threshold and go over that
hurdle of really truly being a thousand
watt high pressure sodium replacement so
there's you know you know I have a
company and and my company does it but
we're not the only one so there are you
know kind of these Tier one
manufacturers that can absolutely hit
these thresholds and if you you know if
you were a naysayer you know you're a
smart man but the time has come for LEDs
to kind of hit hit that threshold and I
would say if you're looking for a very
specific threshold if it could get over
1600 micromoles per per second
preferably 1750 micromoles per second
that is going to be something that
you're going to have a really good
experience with fantastic that is a
great answer so Robert our time is done
thank you so much for all of this
interesting information and some of the
you know atypical insights that we don't
usually hear when you know people are
either talking about strictly the botany
or strictly the light technology your
your ability to kind of weave those two
together to provide some some answers
that straddle both disciplines was
really enjoyable so thank you very much
yeah thanks for having me I really had a
good time
excellent so if you want to find out
more about the kinds of lights that
Robert helps developed you can check
that out at BIOS lighting com you can
find more episodes of the shaping fire
podcast and subscribe to the show at
shaping fire calm and on Apple iTunes
stitcher and Google Play if you enjoyed
the show we'd really appreciate it if
you'd leave a positive review of the
podcast wherever you download your
review will help other
find the show so they can enjoy it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the weekly newsletter for
insights into the latest cannabis news
and product reviews on the shaping fire
website you will also find transcripts
of today's podcast as well for
information on me and where I'll be
speaking you can check out Shango lows
calm as your company want to reach our
national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hotspot at shaping
fire calm to find out how thanks for
listening to shaping fire I've been your
host
Shango lows
[Music]