[Music]
it's really something isn't it how
people are talking about psychedelic
mushrooms like simply everywhere now and
sure many of us had lots of mushrooms in
our subculture is growing up and it's
nothing new but we're talking about
mushrooms being discussed on CNN and
daytime talk shows it really is
something some folks are talking about
micro doing and others are talking about
macro doing but everyone seems to feel
much more free to discuss mushroom use
and benefits nowadays it's very common
for the media to talk about the
importance of using mushrooms in a
clinical setting or for psychologists to
suggest the importance of having a guide
or trip sitter because of this there is
a creeping assumption that everyone
should have a psychedelic safety coach
involved with their
self-discovery I'm not of that opinion
certainly some folks should definitely
seek these types of support and it is
very good that they exist but the vast
number of people don't actually need a
guide there are records of human beings
using psychedelics for over 9,000 years
our species has a long and positive
relationship with the psilocybin
mushroom and if you follow some simple
but important best practices you or you
and your friends can engage engage in
psychedelic exploration safely and on
your own that's our topic for today
taking psychedelics without a trip
sitter if you want to learn about
cannabis Health cultivation and
technique efficiently and with good
cheer I encourage you to subscribe to
our newsletter we'll send you new
podcast episodes as they come out
delivered right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week and
videos too don't rely on social media to
let you know when a new episode is
published sign up for the updates to
make sure you don't miss an episode also
we're giving away very cool prizes to
folks who are signed up to receive the
newsletter so go to shaping fire.com to
sign up for the newsletter and be
entered into this month's and all future
newsletter prize drawings you are
listening to shaping fire and I'm your
host Shango Los welcome to episode
117 my guest today is Daniel shankin as
the founder and director of Tam
integration Daniel offers radically
accessible and inclusive support and
education for people who are wanting to
transform heal and grow Tam's
integration circles and online
conferences enjoy a worldwide audience
and much Acclaim he also leads the
year-long Mount Tam psychedelic
integration coaching program training
emerging leaders the facilitation of
transformational Engagement I know
Daniel as having incredible insights
about psychedelic integration the use of
psychedelics and a keen sense of the
importance of psychedelics as both
Recreation and for self-discovery I came
across his social media channels and
started getting some really good
perspective from him then Daniel Morford
from Heart Rock Mountain cannabis
introduced us and we quickly chose a
date to pull together this episode for
you during the first set today we will
consider the differences between having
a trip sitter or guide and going it
alone or with friends and then we will
discuss best practices for going into
your psychedelic trip with good mindset
and setting in the second set we'll
offer some tips on preparing for your
trip locations and things to do while
you're high and during the third set we
will discuss psychedelic integration
what that is and how to make sure that
you're able to bring your lessons in
healing from psychedelics back into your
daily life there are two important notes
about today's episode first I recently
upgraded the shaping fire studio so all
the episodes will sound even better than
they already do alas I thought that I
had all the settings dialed in and
tested but I did not at some point
before we recorded I hit the gain and
threw it off significantly because of
that my voice was recorded too boldly
and now Clips a great deal throughout
the entire episode Daniel's voice sounds
perfect though but I don't sound so well
our shaping fire sound engineer did an
excellent job making my voice listenable
but yeah you'll hear my voice sound
crappy this episode after 171 podcast
episodes of being my own sound
technician I was bound to make an error
sometime and and that is today we have
adjusted the gain and taped it in place
now so we shouldn't run into this again
so thanks for your patience with the
sound of my voice today second neither
Daniel or I are doctors and we certainly
are not your therapist this information
is offered to add to your own res
research and discussions with your
doctors please don't take today's
episode as permission or instruction
similarly consult your local laws about
any plans you may have when considering
psilocybon therapy shaping fire has a
global audience and you are responsible
for understanding the laws in your
specific area welcome to shaping fire
Daniel thank you so much for having me
it's great to be here I really
appreciate you joining us I know your
time is valuable and uh I've been
excited about doing this episode for a
while now before we get into it let's go
ahead and repeat some of the disclaimers
that uh I already mentioned in the
introduction because we want to make
sure that we're all on the same page uh
my dear listener um we are not your
doctor or your therapist and we don't
know your personal situation so we're
going to be speaking in generalities so
don't be taking our insights as you know
permission to do something at all um we
encourage you to do your own homework
talk to your own doctor talk to your own
spiritual leader and and be aware of the
legality wherever you live because I I
know that you know the audience is all
around the world at this point but here
in the United States um you know the
psychedelics we're going to be talking
about today are are schedule one drugs
in most places or everywhere so you know
be really aware about the laws in your
particular area so okay so with that so
Daniel I want to start with um uh kind
of the kind of the opposite of what the
episode is about today you know today's
episode is is primarily Focus focusing
on uh people who choose to do
psychedelics either by themselves or
with friends and not using a counselor
or a facilitator involved but I want to
make sure right off the bat that that we
make sure people know that that we're
not saying don't use a facilitator for
for many people and for many goals using
a f facilitator is exceptionally helpful
maybe even vital to their healing
process so um you know you are a trainer
of psychedelic facilitators so so let's
start out with that question what are
some of the good reasons to um to engage
a psychedelic facilitator um when
someone uh chooses to do psychedelic
healing well you well you might want a
certain level of care right you might
want a certain level of safety and care
that maybe isn't available with just um
friends or family or by yourself you
might also
want uh when I say safety I I mean of
course like physical safety we don't
want you running off into traffic but
maybe you want a uh like a psychological
or emotional safety uh as we know uh
psychedelics can
really occasion
catharsis right people um have emotional
releases they might have old memories
resurface and that might not be the kind
of thing that you feel comfortable
talking about with just like your buddy
um but when you're with somebody who
you've worked with for some time you've
built up kind of a therapeutic
relationship and a certain amount of of
Rapport and you've already started to
kind of like open the doors to the stuff
that's you know in your closet uh it
might uh do you really well to go deeper
into those places and that can allow a
lot of
kind of stuff to come up and to be
released and to be processed and to have
somebody who's trained who knows how to
hold space for that and knows how to
reflect back and sort of guide you into
like a proactive Direction uh can really
come in handy for sure we don't want to
be in this situation where all of our
walls are down and we're being very
vulnerable and we're ready to do work on
something that's really important to us
but we happen to be with somebody who
isn't the sort of friend that we want to
share those kind of intimate details
with because um you know if if we're
approaching these psychedelic um
modalities to heal sometimes the healing
looks like you know bringing up our our
some pretty sensitive Secrets yeah it
can be messy yeah
and um and that and it can even make
things go weird like I don't know if
you've ever I'm sure your audience knows
what it's like to sit on an
uncomfortable secret right or to kind of
have stuff that wants to come out and
wants to be seen but you don't feel safe
and maybe there's shame or maybe there's
anxiety or whatever it is and you can't
share it and things can go sideways like
think people are like what's wrong with
you what's going on and like the whole
vibe gets weirder and weirder and
weirder um so that can happen right if
you're holding things back on the flip
side I've talked to folks
who have a lot of experience with like
let's just MDMA let's talk about MDMA
for example and they've partied with it
they've gone to shows they've gone to
concerts they've gone to you know good
times with their friends in front of the
fire and it was just always a chill and
a sweet
time and then they decided hey maybe I
want to do some more work I'm already
familiar with this molecule I know how
it acts and then you take them out of
the one setting and you so we should
probably talk a lot about set and
setting tonight so you take them out of
this kind of friendly recreational
setting and you put them in a
therapeutic setting where the space is
there for them and it's an entirely
different medicine and then all of a
sudden this person can access things
that again have been wanting to be seen
and you know uh things that have wanted
wanting to be acknowledged and loved for
years and years and years it can finally
come out because the space and the
setting is there for them excellent and
yes we will be we will be talking a lot
about um set and setting here just in a
little bit
the other thing I want to hit before we
move on about the good reasons just some
of the good reasons to use a facilitator
is that um a lot of people who are drawn
to psychedelics have you know pretty
serious pre-existing issues that they're
trying to sort out whether it be you
know schizophrenia or anxiety or
psychosis or or a history of things that
if you're going to try to go on a
healing path such as this um it can get
complex and perhaps even mentally
dangerous quickly and so you might want
to have someone trained in these areas
present instead of putting that weight
of helping you in a crisis situation on
your friends or just yourself so I'm
sure there's a host of those as well
there's that and then also you know we
have the Renaissance happening right the
psychelic come up is is going on and
what this means is that there are a
whole lot of new people who may have
never considered psyched before right
and so I'm guessing you know from from
what I know about you and your audience
and you know our mutual friend um Daniel
yeah Daniel har rocks shout out Daniel
heart rocks um we've kind of grown up
like like these are heads who have grown
up with psychedelic people and
psychedelic friends and like you know if
if I needed a friend of mine to sit for
me like I can call somebody who's who
I've known for sometime for years and i'
be like hey you know I just I kind of
want to do this thing is it cool can you
just like make sure I have tea and the
music's playing and like I I feel safe
and stuff and my buddy will be like cool
that sounds awesome will you do that for
me next month right because we've been
through it but then you've got folks who
are don't have that don't have that kind
of community they're coming from like
you know middle class wherever they're
coming from n9o FES they're coming from
straight lace family life and they're
like I don't know anybody I don't have I
don't have any Community like
that and so they kind of need some of
that you know and a facilitator can kind
of fill that role and also kind of like
guide them into like the world of
psychedelics like the world view of
psychedelics right on so uh my dear
audience um we are in favor of using a
facilitator when it's called for but
what we're going to focus on today is um
when you choose to do psychedelics
without um a clinician or a facilitator
because you know um we are in favor of
facilitators but often you know
sometimes the price is very high um
getting into the thousands of dollars
and sometimes folks don't want to take a
psychedelic in a clinical environment
and they they're not able to find a
facilitator that does something not in a
clinical environment um or perhaps they
don't want to have the facilitator's
energy U mingling with themselves during
during the trip and so that there there
you know there are good reasons to want
a facilitator and there's also good
reasons to choose to not use a
facilitator um this little beginning of
the show the point is just to tell you
that even though the show is about um
going it alone or with friends this does
not mean that we are uh discouraging the
other so I think we hit that pretty well
oh do you want to say something else on
that Daniel um yeah and I also
again you said the disclaimer I just I
want to use the term sort of harm
reduction right and education and um
benefit maximization right this is
offered in the spirit of harm reduction
um you know this is and this is one
strange man's opinion so I I definitely
suggest you know checking um you know
like doing your homework and things like
that um I'm going to show up for you all
the best I can and and I'm excited about
this because this could we can use this
is like a resource in the future about
like sort of a friends and family or
solo guide to this sort of work that is
that is exactly the goal the the the
shaping fire episodes are always quite
Evergreen um so that they people can
continue to use them over time and you
know sometimes we're talking about you
know um you know a handbook of growing
cannabis or using cannabis or making
medicine and today we're talking about
psychedelics so let's get right into it
by talking about mindset and setting
which you have already brought up um
it's pretty much the Cornerstone of drug
usage and um I'd like to start with the
first part mindset um what are the some
of the factors in um coming to the
Psychedelic experience with a good
mindset we'll talk about setting in a
couple minutes but let's let's focus on
mindset first what what what what do we
want to bring to the Psychedelic
experience for good for their best
practice results well can I take a step
back and talk a little about bit about
the history of set and setting for sure
go for it so there was a time like way
back in the 50s um when there were
researchers who studied LSD as um
something that mimicked the experience
of having psychosis right they were like
oh wow this molecule creates Psy a
psychosis like experience for people and
so if we give it to them they'll be
psychotic for eight hours and we can
study that and sure enough they would
give it to people and they would they
would give it to people and they would
go psychotic for eight hours and then
they were shocked to meet like the
hippies of hate Street who had you know
their velvet couches and their Paisley
shirts and their music and lava lamps
and what have you and that their
willingness to dance and to be groovy
and those people weren't going psychotic
they were having mystical experiences of
love and Oneness M and it was confusing
and what the researchers realized is
that this is dependent these molecules
are dependent on set and setting like
Advil for example works the same if you
take it on the mountain or in the beach
or in an office or on a plane and a
train you know with a goat in a boat
right yeah so they kind of decided oh it
probably just works like that it just
works the same but what they found is
that if you put somebody in a hospital
and you strap them to a gurnie and you
put them under bright lights and you
tell them they're going to go psychotic
and then you ask them really probing
questions with the clipboard for eight
hours they guess what you get a
psychotic person I might do that without
I might go psychotic in that situation
without drugs exactly yeah right and so
there has been this um exploration about
what are optimal set and settings for
particular results for particular people
and like you were saying um that might
freak me out even without drugs certain
sets certain settings
and certain sets are better for some
people certain settings are better for
other people right so there's no one
size fits all and so this journey you
know hopefully if we're talking about um
healthy use perhaps over time right and
that maybe we're going slow maybe we're
starting with low dosages and and so on
and so forth but back to set say back to
mindset um you're going to bring
yourself with you into a psychedelic
experience right so you're bringing you
right um and what they they call
psychedelics um for the most part right
the the true psychedelics non-specific
amplifiers and what non-specific
amplifier means is that it brings up the
stuff that's already there in a lot of
ways right and sometimes it smooth you
know sometimes it does add that love and
connectivity and that's really nice too
um but people say oh it made me anxious
or it made me afraid well not really
like you have that in you already it was
bringing that up it made me feel like I
was garbage and I wasn't worth loving
well no you've been carrying that around
for decades now you get a chance to look
at it so educating people at least about
that is a big deal so people are not so
and of course people forget it of all
the time but um if you can sit with
people and kind of um coach them on
recognizing that that's one of the
things that can possibly happen that's
important so they're not so surprised
when they come face to face with their
own stuff their own shadow perhaps
what's also important to recognize is
not only are you dealing with stuff that
is potentially very very old but your
recent environment and experiences play
a part so if you have been
watching a lot of election news you know
you've been watching a lot of like
fear-based news before your trip that's
not going to help um if you've been
watching horror movies that's not going
to help um although if you
watch um the Lord of the Rings trilogy
that actually might help right the
hero's journey right so you're tuning
yourself you're tuning yourself into
like archetypal forces so you know a
good good things that people often do to
get ready is not only they they do
various diets and so they might limit
their food they might eat cleaner food
so that you don't have to process the
food on the journey and deal with that
whole thing um you might read more um
higher higher Vibe literature whatever
that means for you I was talking to um a
student yesterday and she was um telling
me that she really like she there's a
graveyard near her house that has a stat
statue of Jesus in The Garden of
Gethsemane and she reads the Bible and
she listens to George Harrison and
that's like she knows that works for her
right and I'm not you know I don't have
opinions on other people's religion so
just just that's just religious beliefs
that's her story and it's nice right
because it is certainly it's it's really
high Vibe for her it puts her in a place
of faith it puts her in a place of love
and connectivity and for other people
that might be um Tibetan bows right or
or throat chanting or um um you know
vdic chanting or devotional chanting or
things like that but you know if we
start to turn down um the ordinary and
the mundane and we start to turn up the
um the vibrations that we want to
resonate with you know higher vibration
things that are in alignment with our
intentions that usually goes pretty well
for people right and this brings us to
intention perhaps can still table it if
you have more questions about s setting
um well just one thing I want to add too
I love I love the idea of of create you
know um creating a mental environment
that that you think is going to work for
the the kind of work you want to do um
but I also generally like to point out
to people to to be doing the Psychedelic
because you want to um over the course
of my life I have certainly seen people
be peer pressured into doing
psychedelics because the rest of the
group was and to to make sure that
you're doing it for for the right
reasons that are that are your own in
addition to you know removing the uh
immediate um stressors that we were
talking about right oh right so yeah
turn your phone off give yourself a dope
and bean break from your phone for sure
um but when we talk about mindset one of
the key tools for mindset is um having a
personal intention right so like you
were saying man um know why you're doing
it like do it because you want to and
know why you want to like I'm doing this
to heal this I'm doing this to look at
that I'm doing this to come become more
in alignment with um my romantic partner
I'm doing this to become more in
alignment with the Divine you know what
whatever it is and then what I usually
recommend to people is um whatever that
intention is is uh try to wrate it out
sort of in like Mantra form and what I
mean by that is is like short and sweet
right you wouldn't want something oh and
I kind of want this and maybe I want
that and the other
thing you want something like short and
sweet that is going to kind of cut
through the noise right so that you can
focus your mind on it in a psychedelic
state right some of our our most
well-known mantras in the west are
psychedelically inspired things like be
here now right by ramas everybody knows
be here now that's a psychedelic
intention um Let It Be by the Beatles
right there's a story that says that the
mother Mary that is referenced and let
it be was Maria Sabina the curandera
from Mexico right let it be and then of
course we all know Dr Bronner is all one
or none right so these sorts of like
short sweet like poignant like cut
through the noise um intentions that we
can use as an anchor that will root us
in our minds when everything is swirling
and if folks are hearing this and going
ah
I'm not going to do this woooo stuff I'm
just going to take the drug and go for
it I want to encourage you that that
these types of intentional setups they
actually do work and while to many
people this kind of um internal
awareness of intention might be
dismissible in this realm that you're
about to play in um it it is it is
essential and uh by by creating this
intention you truly give Direct ction to
your mind and spirit of the direction
that you want to go and having an
intention and and giving your um Mind
and Spirit a direction to go in is going
to be far more effective in most cases
than just going into it without an
intention and just kind of like riding
the Bronco whatever random Direction it
goes in um we're talking about best
practices today and having intention is
truly a corner Stone best practice oh
yeah I mean do people can do what they
want um you know if somebody thinks that
what we're saying is woo woo I'm I'm
surprised that they're still listening
yeah um and I'm not I'm not really here
to I'm not I'm not trying to sell it you
right right it's known you know you guys
and what I would even suggest um my
friends are try it both ways you know
it's like run run an experiment you know
and see how it goes report back I'd love
to hear
you know do it a couple of different
ways come to our we've got integration
circles where people can come and talk
about this stuff every week let me know
how it goes right on the last thing I
want to touch on here in mindset um uh
well good mindset anyway is um uh I
think it's pretty important to have
faith in the in your drugs if if if your
um if your psychedelic comes from a
sketchy source and you're not sure what
you're taking um uh that can come up at
the worst times right as the Psychedelic
is coming on and you suddenly feel like
it's brewing and it's about to come on
and and then suddenly you get this hit
of adrenaline because now you're second
guessing your source and of course any
kind of drug even if they're not
psychedelics you should know your Source
but with psychedelics since it's such um
a momentous experience be sure to have
faith in the quality and cleanliness of
the Psychedelic that you're using um
because not only are there there it's
important for your personal health but
it's also important for your mindset you
can just kind of like check that box of
safety off that that that that you don't
have to worry about the veracity of of
of the of the Psychedelic that you're
taking this is an interesting point yeah
so test your drugs kids right go to
dance safe you can you can get drug
tests you can get test kits um I think
if you go to my link Tree on Instagram
like I think um
with a roll kit like I'm an affiliate
for roll kit you can you can get test
kits there too um but we want to get as
much
sketchiness out of the thing as we out
of the situation as we possibly can
right for those of us who kind of grew
up under the kind of the shadow of the
drug war right we knew that there was a
lot of stigma there was a lot of fear uh
we were all we were worried about
getting caught we were worried about
what would happen if people knew um
there was all of this anxiety around
that and also that ends up internalizing
as self-judgment oh am I doing something
wrong and maybe on some level we get off
on doing something that's a little taboo
but on another level like it gets in
there and I don't know if any of you
have had the chance to take psychedelics
in Colorado since it's been
decriminalized but it's kind of a whole
different thing because that kind of
worry and those belief systems that are
kind of cultural and we've been carrying
them around in our in our uh subculture
for some time that's starting to get
cleaned up and people are starting to be
able to have Freer experiences where
they are not worried about being caught
or being judged or things like that um
but but part of that means is that you
potentially have an opportunity to
cultivate relationships with people in a
new way where it's not surreptitious and
it's not under a bridge and and um you
know I got Pals who are on Instagram
saying hey please come learn how to
micro do I'll give you a month's Supply
right it's it's wild they're in Colorado
and so like that's hopefully going to
become more and more of the norm where
people can
feel um free and confident and peaceful
around the fact that they are exercising
their cognitive Liberty right on so um I
I want to TCH on briefly some of the
factors that would constitute like maybe
a challenging mindset like I already
mentioned one earlier the feeling of
being pressured like you're being peer
pressured to do it because you know your
other people in your life are doing it
and and they're kind of dragging you
into it when you're not ready um what
might be another you know one or two
mindsets that are challenging that you
might caution folks to take a take a
psychedelics during that period of their
life well are are you fighting with your
girl
um did you just lose your job um do you
not
have um housing do you not have safe
housing um did your electricity get
turned off um have you not been eating
well um these kinds of things yeah right
so you know if that you would want
there's like a maslo hierarchy so you
you definitely want like your basic
safety needs taken care of right so that
kind of thing uh you would want your
relationships uh you know um relatively
speaking to be in a fairly good spot you
know you'd want a certain amount of
space in your work life right you
wouldn't want to have
to um be on the phone right up until you
took the medicine and then be on the
phone right as it wears down right that
would be stressful especially if it's a
stressful thing yeah going on at work um
so these kinds of pressure right so it's
interesting because your podcast is
called shaping fire and I'm really
interested in um the idea of shape right
from like a sematic perspective right so
you you famili do you think your people
are familiar with the term sematic sure
but but not everybody so go right ahead
and fill it in so sematic is a Greek
term it means the living body in its
wholeness
and so it means that we're this holistic
organism this Mind Body nervous system
thing entity right personality um whole
this whole thing and this whole thing is
a whole thing um and it is expressed
through the body right so so one of the
ideas of of of sematic kind of theory
philosophy is that your entire your
body is a representation of your entire
history right everything that has
happened to you is smudged on your body
like clay in some ways so the way that
you walk the way that you hold yourself
the way that you react under stress and
pressure right this has been developed
over years right through um through your
experience right and the way people work
in the world and then what's interesting
is that once you're shaped um you then
shape the world that way and then you
shape your own experience
because let's say somebody feels like
they're not worthy of love like they
have that deep belief I'm not worthy of
love I don't deserve it there isn't
enough love out there for me well you
can imagine how somebody who believes
that deep in their soul since they were
like 5 years old might walk through the
world and hold themselves in their body
it's going to be very different like you
could put two people in somebody who is
like I'm definitely worthy of love like
I'm full of love I've love to give I'm
open to receive love I know it's it's
the best stuff in the world I love my
friends I love my family they love me I
know it and you put those two people
next to each other and you tell them
just stand neutral you can tell who's
who it'd be obvious right and so then
the way those people move through the
world is going to be
different right and so the person who
doesn't believe they're worthy of Love
is going to act in ways that reinforce
that and the person who believes that
they are worthy of Love is going to act
in ways that reinforces that and then
they're going to get more of what
they've been getting because they keep
doing what they're
doing um and so what we are trying to do
is what was the question how did I get
to this I love talking about this
shaping fire we're shaping
ourselves um what was your I'm sorry we
had started on um the the factors that
constitute a a challenging mindset a
time that you maybe wouldn't want to do
psychedelics right so
relatively like hopefully we're in in
decent relationships relatively speaking
right and we're able to kind of show up
in a way that is present and available
to receive the medicine right and I'm
still trying to figure out what that has
to do with shape but we are going to
start to be able to see our shape in a
new way right and if we are constantly
tense and stressed right we're going to
wear that and we're going to have to
spend time kind of like unwinding that
whereas like maybe if you've been doing
some yoga you've been opening up your
body you've been taking care of it like
like the B the the the body set is as
important as the mindset I guess is what
I'm trying to get at and
so yeah so when we're looking at
challenging experiences sometimes we do
need a reset I guess is what I'm getting
at right so sometimes people like I've
tried everything I'm in a bad place and
I something's got to change and
something's got to change now yeah like
sometimes people have to come to
psychedelics like that but hopefully you
can still carve out enough space right
that's another sematic word space so
that you can embody the space in its
fullness and be present for it be open
and not have to worry about the
pressures of the world shaping you in
such a way that you can't you can't
stand up straight in the open right on
so so that was the mindset and we we've
been talking about the Cornerstone of
psychedelic usage which is mindset and
settings so so now um let's talk a
little bit about setting which is um you
know often a little easier to make um uh
good than the mindset part so um since
you are the educator in this area let's
why don't we I'll I'll start by sending
giving you a general question here what
are some of the factors in uh
establishing a good setting for doing
psychedelics
it should probably be sweet right let's
just let's start let's
let's radiate out from the word
sweet right um it should be sweet and
nice and comfortable and safe right and
not too over rot although sometimes
people depending on the molecule
sometimes people like over rot you know
it's like we know what like the LSD
hippies of the 60s how they decorated
their spaces right they liked a lot of
stuff that was very vibrant and alive
and that's kind of fun sometimes it's a
little bubble gummy for some people but
sometimes it's really fun right and then
you know sometimes for depending on the
molecule sometimes psilocybin people
spend most of their time just inside
right like with their eyes closed right
they're journeying inward it makes um
it's less of an issue um one thing we do
know for sure it should be neat and
clean right um so we want something
that's neat and clean and you know has a
ceremonial energy to it in some ways
depending on whatever that means for you
um you know a sense of perhaps
sacredness right so you might want to
think about again like where is your
head at and what are you trying to
create like if you create more of a
temple atmosphere you might have more of
a temple
experience right if you just sort of a
very um clean minimal kind of experience
well there's maybe not a lot for the
mind to project onto and it encourages
the mind to go inside but some of the
things that I might say is you decorate
it however you want and you talk to you
know you talk to your friends about that
and you know maybe you want a picture of
your kids maybe you want a picture of
your parents maybe you want a picture of
yourself as a kid depending on what you
want to work on maybe you want people
who are inspiring to
you um but you know what is kind of
important is that it's a
container right you kind of don't really
want strangers wandering
in right you want it to be neat and
clean and in many cases simple uh in
many cases ceremonial and you want to
kind of be sure that you're not going to
be bothered because that can be
um unpleasant yeah an intrusive
unexpected person suddenly can can
really change the direction uh not only
because we might have to some for a
moment try to present ourselves as you
know sober and regular when we're
actually having you know a pretty heavy
duty breakthrough moment and suddenly we
have to fake it for somebody that can
that can get messy um especially if that
person will be bothered if they figure
out that we're on psychedelics so you
know being being in a in a good location
a safe location that feels safe is
pretty essential and and I would also
include some of the the biological needs
too you know a source of water a
bathroom somewhere where there's not
going to be any threats um and some of
the other things that I've recommended
to people include a notepad and a pen
art supplies you know soft blankets to
soothe your nervous system um Tri trippy
items and and um sometimes movies that
are are your favorite um for me I have
always been very focused on nature I'm
not really an indoor psychedelics person
I'm a I'm a get outside where I know
that there's not going anybody around
and then you know start looking at bugs
in my celium and the weird the sun
glistening off the waves and and things
like that but everybody has their own um
their own style of of what you know
creates that that vessel or that that
safe space for them and and it's it is
really worth thinking about it in
advance and writing yourself some notes
and kind of like you're planning a
vacation for yourself so that when you
do um when when you do take take the
Psychedelic it's it's it's like oh
somebody who really cares about me
planned this experience for me and the
person who cares about you is
yourself yes and I do want to just note
that it might be different to depending
on your
dosage right so people might micro do
and then just go about their daily life
right right because it's it's sub
perceptual and then there is things that
slightly up from there you know is maybe
sometimes called the hro do where people
are taking maybe you know a little bit
more than a micro do to kind of make the
you know the leaves Shimmer a little but
they're not their cognition isn't
impaired that much or M sometimes it's
called a museum dose right this kind of
dose where you you would feel
comfortable going to a museum right
maybe a little bit maybe you take a
little bit more to go to a concert right
or maybe depending on how you roll maybe
you're taking quite a bit more to go to
a concert and then maybe we're going
towards something approaching
heroic right where being out in public
um wouldn't do it all right and maybe
you could be in a campground and nature
or things like that but you would
probably really want someone to look out
for you a bit right like if you're in
depend again depending on dosage and
this is why General wisdom says start
low and go slow yeah right so it's like
okay I know that like if I do like I can
pretty much manage I can make a fire not
burn myself on this amount of this but
you know if I'm really going to melt
down you know maybe somebody wants to
watch me if there's
um a river rushing by you know because I
might need them to tell me that like I'm
not a fish
yeah this might not be the best time to
go for a swim my friend why don't we
come on back over here for a little bit
and look at the water or whatever yeah
and this is also this brings us to you
know regardless of you
know you know it's hard to do this by
yourself but if you're going to do this
with with other people having some
ground rules and agreements you know
that's also good that when we're talking
about containers right is sort of like
ethical and relational containers of you
know we're all going to we're all
agreeing that we're staying in this area
whether we're staying in this house or
we're staying in this backyard we're
staying in this campsite we're staying
here for this time you know we're we're
going to agree that for this time we're
going to keep our clothes on you know or
not depending on how you party right but
you know you know we're not nobody's
going to uh um you know this nobody's
going to try and sleep with anybody
nobody's going to cause any physical
harm to anybody one one of the popular
ones in with my friends is no one's
going to turn on their phone or make a
phone call yeah occasionally we will
need to use our phones because you're
you're you're trying to tell a story and
you really need some data point that
might be on your phone you know like
what was that place called or whatever
or I want to show you this picture or
whatever which could all be fun but for
goodness sakes you know don't Place
calls or answer calls
yeah
yeah yeah so that kind of thing MH um
all right so um let's go ahead and take
our first break and and when we come
back we're going to talk a little bit
more about um preparing um yourself um
uh physically and mentally um uh in
advance of the Psychedelic experience so
um you are listening to shaping fire and
my guest today is psychedelic
integration coach Daniel shankin now
without these advertisers shaping fire
would not happen so please support them
and let them know that you heard them on
shaping
[Music]
fire fish poop brand fertilizer is an
allnatural fish poop concentrate with
nothing added real fish poop is
extraordinarily complex not only are you
adding the nitrogen phosphorus and
pottassium your plants need to build
mass transport nutrients and enhance
flavor but fish waste is also packed
with biological activity and
micronutrients
when you add fish poop to your
irrigation water you are adding life
force probiotics and active microbes
these microorganisms include a wealth of
various bacteria and protoo which
further enhance nutrient availability
for the plants because plants are
limited by the absence of any essential
micronutrient these Trace nutrients are
the difference between having a decent
garden and having a garden that makes
you feel really proud of your efforts
fish poop is a naturally complete
solution that fills in the cracks in
your fertilizer program to ensure you
offer your garden a broad base of
nutrients not all fish poop is created
equally most products with added fish
waste don't reveal their sources or lab
results fish poop brand fish poop
however generates their own fish waste
as a byproduct of their organic
aquaponic cannabis farm where they raise
ornamental koi and tilapia you are even
invited to tour their Farm in person or
on their YouTube channel to look for
your self this sort of transparency is
wildly rare in the fertilizer Market the
folks behind fish poop are also lifelong
medical cannabis producers who have deep
Connections in the community donate more
product than they sell and support
cannabis prisoner veteran and patient
collectives and Charities to get your
bottle of pure fish poop go to fish
poop.com and to see their entire line of
cannabis products go to ounce of
hope.com that's fish poop brand fish
[Music]
poop one of the challenges with buying
Autoflower seeds is that often you'll
have as many different fenos as you will
have seeds in a pack that can be fun
sure but so many varieties in one pack
is a sign of an immature seedline that
hasn't been worked enough I prefer my
autof flowers to be worked enough that
each feno in the pack really captures
the aspects that the breeder was
intending this is why I recommend gnome
automatics to my friends and listeners
who grow Auto itic flowering cannabis
seeds gnome automatic seeds are not just
crossed and released they are
painstakingly sifted again and again
tested in a wide range of conditions and
taken to a level of maturity that each
plant will be recognizable by its traits
traits that were hard-earned so that you
can have your best grow cycle ever over
the last 10 years gnome automatics
founder Dan Jimmy has become a trusted
breeder and he continues to pour His
passion of breeding cannabis into every
variety he releases for you to grow
check out the gnome automatics Instagram
_ automatics to see the impressive
plants folks are growing you can score
gnome automatic seeds in feminized or
regular at your favorite seed provider
listed in the vendor section of their
website commercial cannabis Farms across
the country love growing gnome
automatics because of their consistency
from seed to seed short grow times THC
percentages and color bag appeal Farms
interested in bulk seeds of more than a
thousand should reach out through gnome
automatics.com
while on the website be sure to check
out the gnome automatic shirts and other
merch section too if you want reliable
seeds handbuilt from effort expert
selection and experience choose gnome
[Music]
automatics businesses everywhere are
striving to reach people through
advertising we all know though that
trying to reach a cannabis audience with
a quality message is pretty difficult
that's why many people choose to
advertise on the shaping fire podcast
advertising on this show allows us time
to talk about your product service a
brand in a way that really lets people
know what sets your company apart from
others bold people who own companies
know that getting into relationship with
their customers is essential and that is
what we offer we will explain your
service or product what sets it apart as
desirable and help our audience get in
contact with you it's pretty simple
really advertising does not have to be
all whizbang smoke and mirrors nowadays
I find that people prefer just to be
spoken to calmly accurately and with
good intentions if you want to make your
own commercial spot well you can do that
too during these pandemic days
conventions and cannabis events are
pretty poorly attended but podcast
listening is
skyrocketing with a commercial on
shaping fire you'll reach your customers
in the privacy of their headphones right
now and will continue to reach new
listeners as they explore the shaping
fire back catalog of episodes again and
again for
years a spot on shaping fire costs less
than a printed postcard per person and
the shaping fire audience is full of
smart cannabis enthusiasts cultivators
and entrepreneurs who are always curious
to learn
do yourself a solid and contact us today
for rates on podcast and Instagram
advertising email hotspot shaping
fire.com to find out
more welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire I am your host Shango Los
and my guest today is psychedelic
integration coach Daniel shankin so
during the first set we talked a lot
about um the mindset and the setting uh
things that you definitely want to to
consider uh in advance um you know we
have t we talked a lot during the first
set about how planning in advance is
really a way to improve the likelihood
that you'll have a a good and valuable
and meaningful healing psychedelic
experience and and and we're going to be
talking a lot about that again here in
second set but in a little different
sort of detail so um let's start uh
Daniel by I I want to um uh hit on
something that you
touched on briefly but I want to I want
to drive it home a little bit more um
the the physicality of it um you had
mentioned that you know bringing a good
calm body to the Psychedelic experience
can be really helpful and I totally
agree um but I also want to illustrate
that a little bit more um for example um
you know there are depending on which
molecule that you take most of them will
encourage your body to void itself and
so one thing that um um people that I've
worked with including myself have found
value in over the years is uh to take a
little psyllium husk uh the morning the
the day before in the morning so that um
whatever you may have eaten that is
heavy you know maybe you had some steak
or a burger or you know jalapeno poppers
or something like that that can sit in
your gut and and sometimes um during the
digestion um that that can take your
attention can come away from the work
that you're trying to do and start
thinking about like the functioning of
your body and so um uh you know make
sure you're really hydrated as well
because so I you know very often when
we're having a psychedelic experience we
will actually
forget to drink water which is one of
the good reasons to um to do psyched dos
with friends because everybody can kind
of help babysit each other to make sure
that you are are um you know getting
getting enough water and and such so um
in addition to the yoga and the two
things that I just mentioned Daniel do
you have any other physical things to
kind of round out that that that group
of
ideas I mean that's pretty good I mean
you could also kind of just refrain from
eating jalapeno poppers for a couple of
days ahead of time that could
work um you might want to oh I was once
working with a guy who had his first
psychedelic experience uh on a camping
trip you know and he had a friend with
him and they had an RV and when he came
back he said to me in all
seriousness good set and setting starts
with clean
socks right because he had been out in
the woods and he the clothes he was
wearing was were filthy and it he really
felt it you know something that you
might not notice as if you are just
drinking a couple of beers becomes very
obvious on you know 3 to five grams of
mushrooms it is interesting how
messiness and filth and anything that's
gross is going to be usually really
gross um and I'm I'm not sure why and it
certainly isn't you know for everybody
there are certainly um uh people who can
get really curious about messy gross
things as well but for whatever reason
um the people I've interacted with and
myself um we generally want to be
comfortable and clean and orderly and
you know just generally happy of body
and spirit yeah well being curious about
gross stuff and being covered in gross
stuff are definitely two different
things yeah that's a good point and you
know we
could we could make all kinds of kind of
cosmic High woo ideas about why that is
but you know it's it's pretty much
so let's talk a little bit about um the
kind of preparations to make
additionally um if you're going to do
this experience with friends and for me
I'm I'm very grateful that when I got
turned on to psychedelics in college um
it was in a peer group of people and so
you know most of my first experiences
were you know three to seven people and
and we had a u a big Forest next to my
uh University and and and off we would
go and we would have these fantastic
days and come back and exhausted and
dirty and take showers and then you know
kind of have this Afterglow period in
the evening um the the first the first
thing with friends that I'll get us
started with is to um you know kind of
work with everybody to compare your
plans and your locations because if you
all get together on on the day of your
experience and um you have different
intentions um either a um some people
might have some hard feelings about it
which isn't a great way to go into an
experience or which can sometimes be
equally as as detrimental um your your
original fellowship if you will of
people who are going to um be together
people want to do different things and
so they split off and so your your group
of six comes off into a a three a two
and a one and um that's going to be a
very different experience than if
everybody has a shared plan um uh
another one is uh and and I'm hoping
maybe you speak to this a little bit
Daniel is um we always had like an
emergency signal or word and and not
emergency meaning like there's danger it
it was it was um usually a signal or
word that meant I I I could there is a
moment that I really could use you to
pull your [__] together for a moment so
we can talk about something that's like
somewhat relevant or serious for a
moment like can can I get your attention
and um you know I I've never really
found a really good way to talk about
that with people to to to delineate
between like a safe word for an
emergency and a signal that I need your
attention um H How would how would you
go about that with folks I like that
that's really
interesting um and before we get to that
because I'm going to think about that in
the background while I mention this all
right um there's been a phenomenon
recently right so you grew up with your
friends and they were your friends and
you did psychedelics with your friends
and that's that works cuz they're your
friends um so recently more and more
people are coming into the Psychedelic
space and they're not even kids they're
grown-ups right so they're adults you
know they're not teenagers or college
kids or whatever they're they're these
adults and there was a and they're
interested and they're curious and
they're excited about this also then
there was a
pandemic right which means that people
were kind of isolated
and it also meant that people were
becoming friendly with people from all
over the place on Zoom that they didn't
actually know right and then they think
because they've had you know a half a
dozen Zoom whatevers with these people
um that they're Soul
family and they get together and they
take psychedelics together and they
realize really quickly that they're
not and and so you know people kind of
take for
granted um real relationship and real
connection you know the ability to kind
of like smell somebody you know to know
what your friends smell like to kind of
be there when you are weird together at
a restaurant you know like like all of
these kinds of things that are really um
intimate relationship things that are
missing because you just log in with
somebody for an hour or something and
you're on like a group signal chat with
them group WhatsApp group right and
that's different than being in an
intimate psychedelic space with people
so you want to actually be careful
perhaps about like who you're doing this
with like are these really your friends
like is is there a container are there
agreements do you have a plan like and
that can help create an intentionality
that can help build that Bond MH right
but to do it kind of
off the cuff and loose and pretend do
like a pretend ceremony because what I
see sometimes is people like oh I've
been to ceremonies I know how they work
and like it was good but you know we're
we're just going to be chill and we
don't actually need to have the group
agreements and we don't need to kind of
ring the bell and set the circle or
whatever it is because we I've done that
before you have to do it you have to do
it every time yeah right like it's it's
a practice it would be like I don't need
to breathe today I breathed yesterday
MH and so you know keeping in mind you
know are your friends really your
friends like are you setting the stage
properly and do you have the agreements
so as far as this thing where you're
having um safe words and things like
that I mean this comes back to like do
you do you know your people because I
sort of feel like um
with my friends who are really my
friends I can communicate an awful lot
with a cough a pause or a side
eye right like if I need something like
I can just you know I can kind of look
out of the corner of my eye at my buddy
and go
like you know and he'll be like hey Dan
you know let me show you something over
here in the kitchen yeah you know and
then and then we can have a thing but
you know I like the idea that like
just introducing that is a great idea
and I think the really the theme Here is
uh making things explicit right we all
have a very transpar yeah yeah clear
transparent explicit we all have a lot
of assumptions about how the thing is
supposed to go and you know are they the
same assumptions yeah and you know as we
have talked about where you know your
ceremony is your ceremony that you
designed and and and and and your
environment is your environment the same
thing would be the safe word or the
signal and and since I have some
experience with this I I will also take
it a step further and say um in my
experience we have found that safe words
are easily forgotten and sometimes a
safe hand signal is more easily
remembered and and one of the ones that
that I used to use back when I was a
young man was we decided that thumbs up
was not a good one because we we did
thumbs up often just to be happy and
thumbs down well that's not really good
CU that that kind of sets off your
adrenaline and so what we would do is we
would actually do like um uh horizontal
um thumbs pointed out and we just put
like the sides of our hands together and
it it's kind of a fun hand motion to
make and anybody in the group who saw it
knew exactly what this hand motion meant
and um a good example it where where I
was not trying to well actually it
wasn't me who was giving the sign but in
in this is my story um uh we want to get
attention and we want people to pay
attention but we don't necessarily want
to give people the idea that there's
something dangerous and and maybe
influence their trip and and a good
example was that um one of our friends
stepped on was barefoot and she stepped
on some
glass and she needed just some basic
first aid and and um it was something
that we could provide within our group
um because you know we were we were all
kind of outdoorsy people right so we we
we all had our 10 Essentials with us
when we were out in the forest but but
we we wanted to come together to heal
our friend we didn't want our other
friends to drift off in the forest and
we kind of wanted to work together to
apply the first aid right cuz you know
when you're on psychedelics things are a
little odd to think through and so so
she gave us the hands signal and we're
all like came together we're like hey
what's up you know and then she showed
us and we were all kind of like a moment
like oh blood which and so but then we
all just kind of sat down together and
we we you know went through the steps we
we cleaned the wound we bandaged it we
chatted with her so she understood that
this was not the end of her good trip
and things were still fine and she was
safe and we were with her and we were
going to slightly change our plan about
how far we were going to walk so so she
didn't feel you know but it was all as
soon as we all saw the hand motion we
all understood that oh we all need to
come together for like a little meeting
and um and I I recommend that people
include that when when they're working
with a group I dig it yeah I dig it and
what you're reminding me of actually is
is Disney World oh
um there's a there's a non Seer this
should be good it's um so what they have
now like I I I haven't been to
Disneyland in in for since I was a
little guy um but now they had to give
you like these uh wristbands with
microchips in them right and to like get
on the rides and to get in everything
you just kind of swipe your wristband
and then what they realize is like like
if the wristband works right like it it
flashes green it's like okay you paid
for your meal green if the wristband
isn't working or like you're go trying
to go somewhere you're not supposed to
go it flashes blue I believe
because red is too dangerous oh like
they don't want people they feel like
they decided that red would harsh
people's mellow too much yeah I I dck
that yeah and um I just I think it's
really funny that you know you don't
want the hand signal to be too alerting
int you know alarming alarming yeah
that's a better word yeah we just want
your attention yeah yeah I mean it's
like sure we know how to like bandage a
simple wound this is the most natural
thing we're just friends taking care of
friends and that's an attitude that you
know if there's any you know guides
listening as well that you know we want
to take an attitude of like this is the
most natural thing things are okay we're
just folks hanging out and honestly it
ended up being a very beautiful
experience I mean uh the there were five
of us on this day and um it
was the five of us working together to
heal one of the five of us and all kind
of gently speaking with each other and
and doing the first aid and and and
giving her healing like conversation at
the same time it probably was healing
things in us at the same time as we were
giving her first aid like healing Us in
the sense of we're doing a psychedelic
experience to heal emotional wounds or
whatever um us coming together I'm sure
we were all you know getting getting
good stuff out of that I mean to the
point that I remember it now like what
years later right yeah yeah I mean just
to know like like the experience of of
competence and
care right of like I can we can do this
we are people who take care of each
other and love one another and we show
up for each other and do what needs to
be done you know because like it's a
it's a little thing it's a little
Band-Aid but you know on the right
molecule like that's an Epic Quest you
know even though we're saying oh yeah
it's chill cool like you know we make
things big in our minds yeah and you
know healing our
friends you know is it's a big deal like
it's it's the most it's the biggest deal
there can be really yeah um it's it's
like at the core of Being Human yeah um
one of the other things that tends to
happen is um you know very often people
will get separated um One Way or Another
and um you know it's it's it's it's kind
of a tossup with who the people that
you're doing it with because we all have
cell phones and so if we get separated
it is easy to go grab your cell phone
and say hey I lost you where are you
right but at the same time um I've been
with people where everyone's decided we
want to turn off our cell phones so that
people who might harsh our Vibe don't
call us and interrupt what we've got
going down right and so um uh in in the
situations when we don't have the phone
um I I usually work with folks and say
hey if you get separated from the group
um we will meet at this whatever
location and and when we realize you're
not there um we will all head to that
location and then we will continue our
experience from that location um I'm
sure this has come across your plate
many times um it's a story as old as
time um I'm serious U can we do history
again yeah do it do it so should we do
kind of modern psychedelic history or
archaic tribal history
archaic sounds more fun let's go there
all right we'll start there so um when
you go through places like the Alti
mountains and Siberia and just places
where there are vast fields and steps
and hills and mountains you often come
across big stones that are vertical like
just plopped in the middle of a field
right these kind of like obelisque Kon
kind of things and you know the the
scholars believe like this is how people
oriented right like if you needed to
meet Nomad like you're a nomad right in
in the Siberian mountains right and you
need to meet people we're like okay on
the solstice I'll meet you over three
Hills at that stone yeah at the stone
that looks like a horse or whatever yeah
and so people were have been orienting
themselves um forever right to try and
find their place in space right which is
good cuz again you know like
so our
minds we're we're taking our minds out
into space right we're we're
intentionally disorienting ourselves
right and this is one of the reasons why
having a good intention is key right
we're talking about that Mantra
intention you can think of that Mantra
intention kind of like a stone in a
field like I'm lost in the in in Siberia
where's my stone right and then to have
something like that for the group is it
only stands to reason um I don't know if
you've ever have you ever um seen a dead
show at the Spectrum not at the Spectrum
um so back in the day um there was a
Rocky statue at the Spectrum in Philly
right there was the movie Rocky the
boxer yeah sure and they you know they
made a statue for him in the movie but
then the statue also existed in real
life and so they put it at the Spectrum
for a while which is you know a Philly
place where the dead would play mhm and
so that's where we'd meet our friends if
you get lost we'll meet you at the Rocky
statue that's great and so we would not
you know it's natural in our bodies you
know it's natural in our community
Spirit to say you know we say it to kids
you know if you get lost this is you
know meet me here by this thing you know
find an adult find another mom and tell
her to take you to this place right and
so you know that that's is the most
natural thing in the world that we have
been doing for thousands of years is
picking meeting
places a corar to that that um you know
really applies differently in different
situations is um letting somebody know
what's going on who isn't going to be
with y'all so you know if if you're if
you're going to do a psychedelic and
stay around the house well you know that
may not be as important but if you're
going out in the forest right or I live
on an island so you know it is not
uncommon for people to decide that that
we're going to get in a boat and go to
one of the Lesser populated Islands near
me in the Puget Sound or which is you
know much more of a trip um pun intended
and um that if you are doing anything
where you're going to be leaving home
and and and it is a good thing to let
somebody know who's not going with you
that y'all are doing this and and and
even if you're sure nothing's really
going to go wrong where where that
person would need to know there's almost
always somebody in the group who is a
little uncomfortable with some aspect
and they're they're just happy to know
that there is somebody who's not with
the you know four or six or whatever of
you um on the outside who isn't um you
know tripping or isn't experiencing the
Psychedelic sometimes people need to
have a sober person on the outside that
they can call if they if they start to
kind of slide off and and start to
potentially have a a troubling
experience so you know they can be they
can be used in lots of different ways
but I'm a strong proponent of of having
there be a you know a phone a friend out
there just so there's somebody who isn't
on a psychedelic in case they are
needed yeah that's great and again you
know back to the idea of sitters that
person might even be with you in the
house mhm like they might be they might
be traveling with you at the concert you
know there there is you know the idea of
sort of like the mom you know you know
the the the the the denm mother of sorts
and you know it could be not to gender
anybody but you know it it could be
whatever but you know somebody who is
there and they are you know making tea
and they're sort of there if you need
them and does everybody have a blanket
and okay it's hard for you guys to pick
the music right now I will do that and
that sort of thing yeah the way you just
described it sounded really nice
actually I I might actually like that in
my regular
life yeah yeah um and you know it
doesn't mean that the that the person
needs to you know be right there because
very often when people are having a
psychedelic experience it becomes very
intimate and they really only want the
people who are high there um but it's
you know if you're going to have
somebody it's it's perfectly fine that
they're in another room reading or
something and if and if you need them
they they're there and if not maybe they
just like go through the room you know
every half hour and just like make sure
everybody's doing good you know it
really just depends on on everybody's
Comfort level you can really design this
however you want this is this is your
adventure this is your experience and
and all Daniel and I are doing are are
pointing out a whole bunch of best
practices that work for lots of
different kinds of people um yeah
sometimes I like to think of a sitter as
kind of like
um Alfred from
Batman like you're I like that yeah
you're in the dark right you're like you
imagine you're laying there with your
eyes closed right you're in the dark um
saving the universe and then you come
out of the dark and you open your eyes
and he's there and he said would you
like some tea
sir and the thing is he's been there
like if you follow the history of Alfred
like Alfred used to go on missions with
Batman he would like he was the driver
for a while oh you know he knows how it
goes like you know he can he can um
stitch up like you're saying like Alfred
one of the things Alfred does is he
stitches up Batman right fixes his
wounds and offers him counsel you know
if he needs
it so I've got two more topics before we
go to Commercial and and one is um there
are some classic foods and beverages
that just seem to work well with
psychedelic experience for so you know
water coconut water fruit is almost
always fun especially like bright citrus
fruit oh my goodness gracious what what
are some in your experience that are are
you know loow hanging fruit for being a
good U good thing to have along yeah I
like a nice fruit plate M um I I
generally
like yeah I like a nice fruit plate and
and so often berries and citrus and I I
like berries a lot you know they're
they're bite-sized um you have to check
because not everybody likes every Berry
um I like dark chocolate a lot I think
dark chocolate is great um I like
cashews personally quite a bit so you
know the I I really
like um the
presentation as well so you know there's
there's a difference between having just
a plastic bin of berries like over by
the sink versus like taking a really
nice plate and AR making a mandala of
treats honestly if you could spend your
entire trip making that mandala of
snacks Well it Well actually we were
talking about preparation yeah sure it's
a really nice preparation activity
because it's creative and it's nurturing
and it's focused right and it's
intentional so you're starting off your
journey by okay like I'm here to I'm
taking care of my future self yeah and
you know I'm just kind of bringing my
attention you know whatever I was doing
in the world now I'm creating this kind
of little work of art this little edible
work of art and there's okay there's the
chocolate and then you know maybe
there's olives I don't know some people
like that you know sometimes it's it's
nice to have something that's like a
little in congruous mhm well because
then you can hit all the flavors here's
my sweet here's my Citrus here's my
salty Olive whatever
yeah that kind of thing um um you know
mushrooms seem to like uh well you know
you might have like a drinking chocolate
as well like cacao could be nice um you
know you you'd want to know if that
would disturb somebody's stomach but um
Cacao is nice ginger tea is really nice
crystallized ginger is really
nice um you know you certainly don't
want to have to do much prep MH not in
the moment exactly you want to you want
to do it well in advance yeah yeah and
also you know with most psychedelics
most psychedelics in the short term are
appetite suppressants too and so um you
know when when you're you know going up
and up that's not usually when you're
going to get hungry after you have you
know some time you you might get a
little snacky which is what we're kind
of talking about here but um it while
it's not never it is atypical my
experience that when you're in the in
the throws of a psychedelic experience
that you'll be very hungry now when you
come down you will often be hungry and I
think it's a good idea to plan in
advance what your you know and end of
trip meal is going to be like so so at
least you know where the food's going to
come from um because when you're when
you're coming down you might be tired
and you might be feeling glowy um you
might not want to be making you know
like serious food decisions that time so
maybe maybe you already have it or or
maybe you have a plan that oh at the end
we're going to order delivered food from
our favorite place or whatever um like
most everything we've been talking about
you can do it however you want um but
it's good to plan this out ahead of time
especially if it's one of your first
times so that the whole thing just goes
well for you right and and people do you
you want to be mindful that and this
goes with setting I'll go back to
setting as well that what is appetizing
to you in your regular life might not be
good point um whereas you know you might
be a person like uh U psychedelics have
have minted many
vegetarians you know who were who were
very comfortable just eating whatever
and then they tried to eat whatever and
it wasn't working for them
anymore um they was like oh that's
that's not that's not it um so you know
in general one of the really cool things
about psychedelics that I think a lot of
people don't recognize you know with all
the stigma and stuff is that in many
cases they make people kind of more
wholesome in a lot of ways right they
make people Kinder and more gentle and
more
attentive um and perhaps wanting to um
have fun in simpler ways right eat simp
foods not always of course but you know
that that's one of the things and you
know on that note well going back to
setting is sometimes the things that
people think are trippy when they're
sober are not trippy when they're trippy
also true yeah like you know like like
sometimes there'll be like you know
cheap plastic crap with flashing lights
in it is not as interesting as like a
smooth gray rock yeah
well it's odd too because very often you
see the plastic and you're like this is
an unreal thing you know it's it's it
you just don't really know how you're
going to um interpret things and I don't
know I I think that there are reasons
why people tend towards um natural
things when they're on
psychedelics yeah yeah yeah I mean there
is a really there's a cool book called
psychedelic prayers by Timothy ly he um
had I think like seven copies of the Dao
de ching and a vial of acid and I think
he was in India he fled the country and
he read the da ching and he took the
acid and he wrote psychelic prayers and
one of the things that it talks about in
there are the things that are nice to
have
around you know and he um I'm seeing if
I have it nearby uh we can put it in the
show notes I I don't have it nearby but
you know something like handwoven cloth
right uncarved wood right raw
rocks right he said in in his poem he
says bread bread cheese and
wine right um anything that is over 500
years old right when you have like like
an ancient artifact that can be really
fun yeah um and then of course he ends
by saying of course it's best to be
secluded in nature
right um but just simp
natural things you know can go a long
way
yeah
handmade right things that have care in
them you can see that's an interesting
thing it's like one of those superpowers
you know in the shows that sometimes
there's a superhero and they can touch a
thing and they know it's history right
yes like a Tripper knows if there's care
in a
thing so the last thing I want to touch
on here is is just the preparation of
the drug itself um I think it's always
good um whether you're on your own or
with a group to be really clear well in
advance on what your dosages and to
pre-make it so that you're not debating
on your dosage or preparing it right
there at the last moment because you
know some of these molecules they you
know you really have to do it with care
and slowly if you're going to be making
a capsule or you know you want to be
clear if you're going to do it with
friends are we going to make a tea or
are we going to you know eat the
mushroom fruit itself um I I I
discourage people from leaving that to
the last
minute yeah I mean
I am cautious about answering this too
much because I don't want it to seem
like too much advice about like that
kind of
stuff but you know test kits are
available scales are
available you know um Guy aroid is
available
right you know there are many reference
materials so that you can know what a
thing is supposed to do right you can
decide based on the effects that you
want that some things lean more towards
one thing or lead towards another right
guidel dosage guidelines are online
right
so yeah right on so let's go ahead and
take our second break uh we'll be right
back my friends you are listening to
shaping fire and my guest today is
psychedelic integration coach Daniel
shankin
[Music]
this message is for folks who grow
cannabis I'm talking to homeg Growers
patients and Commercial Growers too I'm
probably talking to you when you plan
out your next growing cycle be sure to
check out Humbolt CSI seeds at Humbolt
csi.com Caleb inspecta and his family
have lived in Humble County for over a
100 years for the last 40 years three
generations of his family have
cultivated extraordinary sensome Mia
cannabis in Humble mesino and Trinity
counties because of his lineage and the
hard-earned experience that comes from
growing up smoking and sifting large
populations of cannabis plants in
Northern California the seeds you'll cop
from CSI will be winning genetics based
on longtime Heavy Hitters and updated
and rifted to bring out new and exotic
traits and better yields go ahead and
ask around Caleb also known as inspecta
and pirates of the Emerald Triangle is a
breeders breeder he reaches way back and
works with significant strength
recreating them in new and interesting
ways that you'll love as a toker and a
grower as well as offering you some
surprises that will Delight serious seed
Traders and cultivators humble CSI goes
a further step and selfs all these
kimars so you know all the seeds will be
female these are not experimental
feminized seeds humbold CSI releases
some of the best female seeds available
anywhere and it will show in your garden
folks grew quite a bit of CSI humble Gen
X last year here on Vashon Island and
everyone was pleased the patients had
beautiful female plants and didn't have
to call half of their Garden as males
the folks growing for the fun of getting
high grew colorful flowers with
exceptional bag appeal and great highs
and breeders had seven out of seven
females in a pack which gave them a lot
of phenotypic choices take a moment
right now and visit humbl csi.com you'll
find an up-to-date menu of both
feminized and regular lines along with
photos and descriptions that's humbl
csi.com
[Music]
after you've caught up on the latest
shaping fire episodes do you sometimes
wish there was more cannabis education
available to learn well we got you
shaping fire has a fabulous YouTube
channel with content not found on the
podcast when I attend conventions to
speak or moderate panels I always record
them and bring the content home for you
to watch the Shango Los YouTube channel
has worldclass speakers including Zoe
sigman's lecture understanding your end
cannabinoid system Kevin jodry of
Wonderland Nursery talking about
breeding cannabis for the best turine
profile Frenchie canoli's Lost Art of
the hashian presentation Nicholas mmud
on regenerative and polyculture cannabis
growing Dr seil agrawal on the history
of cannabis medicine Around the World
Eric voski and Josh Rutherford on
solventless extraction and Jeff
lowenfels on the soil food web there are
several presentations from Dr Ethan
Russo on tpin and the endoc canabo
system too while there be sure to check
out the three 10-part shaping fire
session series one with Kevin jodry one
with Dr Ethan Russo and one with Jeff
lowenfels and even my own presentations
on how to approach finding your dream
job in cannabis and why we choose
cannabis business even though the risks
are so high as of today there's over 200
videos that you can check out for free
so go to
youtube.com/ Shango or click on the link
in the
[Music]
newsletter sometimes the topics I want
to share with you are far too brief for
an entire shap Fire episode in those
instances I post them to Instagram I
invite you to follow my two Instagram
profiles and participate online the
shaping fire Instagram has follow-up
posts to shaping fire episodes growing
and processing best practices product
trials and of course gorgeous flower
photos the Shango Los Instagram follows
my travels on cannabis garden tours my
successes and failures in my own garden
insights and best practices from
personal grows everywhere and always
gorgeous flower photos on both profiles
the emphasis is on sharing what I've
learned in a way that you can replicate
it in your own garden your own hash laab
or for your own canopic health so I
encourage you to follow shaping fire and
Shango and join our online community on
Instagram welcome back you are listening
to shaping fire and I am your host
Shango Los and my guest today is
psychedelic integration coach Daniel
shankin so my friends here we are at the
final set and we are going to talk about
integration integration is actually the
first reason why I became interested in
your teaching because integration is a
part of the process that I am least
familiar with and by watching your um
your Tik Tok and Instagram accounts um I
started really getting a good sense of
the integration I was doing right and
the integration I could be improving on
and the quality of the advice that I was
offering to others has absolutely
increased since um since I started uh
listening to your insights so so let's
that's amazing to hear thank you oh good
excellent so so let's start with with
just asking you to kind of give us an
umbrella integration um is is is
probably a pretty vague term for most
folks and so why don't we start with
that like what is integration and what
are we looking to get out of it right
okay so and we can look at this from a
lot of different levels like depending
on how we view who and what we are
but on a most basic level you might say
Hey you learn some stuff you learn some
stuff about yourself you got some
messages we we like to call them
downloads these days
sometimes and maybe marching
orders and so it was like okay maybe you
should start doing this be nicer to
people say you're sorry clean your room
and maybe you should stop doing this
smoking drinking too much whatever and
and maybe on the long term you want to
kind of move move towards this in your
life you want to become a chef you have
to go to culinary school right and so
figuring out how to get those done like
what might what is it like to genuinely
be kinder to people what is it like to
be more humble and say you're sorry when
you mess up even though sometimes it
feels like you might die if you have to
say you're sorry that it's the most
vulnerable thing in the world what might
it be like to quit drinking when that's
what you know right and that's how you
interact with people and then what does
it take to actually get yourself to and
through culinary school right all of
these kinds of dreams and upgrades that
are available and what is it going to
take to kind of make this happen right
so that's part of
integration um and what often happens is
people start off with good intentions
and then it drops off life gets in the
way they don't have any accountability
they don't have anything anybody um to
support them right we just kind of
forget our lessons yeah we can forget
our lessons and then you know what
happens when we forget our
lessons is our Vibe
drops right so also this is my favorite
I really like integration of
transcendence and mystical experience so
this is what keeps me coming back is I
have these
experiences of bliss Oneness connection
God love all of that stuff right and I
like that and I like that feeling and I
can feel speaking about shapes like
being in that kind of ecstatic con
connected State shapes us in a certain
way right we get shaped by Bliss and joy
and the spiritual experience which is
awesome and then perhaps we vibrate in a
certain way or we show up for the world
in a certain way um depending on whether
or not you know whatever you think of
Vibes but we show up different and we
feel amazing and we want to hold on to
that
but then the thing is is that that
starts to downgrade too and it starts to
downgrade because we stop practicing
humility we stop practicing kindness we
stop practicing truth and we drink too
much and we eat the wrong stuff right so
it's like the
lessons kind of correlate the doing and
the being we start to see a connection
if I want to be the person that I want
to be it means I have to do the things
that I know I'm supposed to do yeah
ain't ain't that the rub
yeah and you know if you want to stay
connected to one one of the things I I
say to people like if you want to Stay
Connected To Source you have to serve
the
source right and so there's that um
integration might also mean that there
are kind of parts of you that you
haven't been embodying or living right
maybe kind humility Parts but like
sometimes we discover that there are
that we maybe are a more creative person
that we gave ourselves credit for for
and so there's like again this kind of
integration of uh being our our full
potential like letting our full
potential really have a chance instead
of just squashing it down and saying it
doesn't matter and and putting it away
there might also be
um like integrate like healing might
have to happen right we might need to
heal from like some really difficult
stuff we might have uh repressed
memories come up of abuse or something
like that and we have to kind of
integrate our own personal history in a
new way so that we can uh be a whole
healed healthy person so we can look at
it from like a lot of different angles
and depending on who you are and what
you're going through at any particular
time in your Soul's Journey it might
mean different
things so um let's say that uh you know
somebody just had this psychedelic
experience and they want to do
integration because they want to really
embra embrace the lessons that they
learned and you know if this person
already has a therapist you know chances
are very likely that they will do this
integration with the therapist they
already have but lots of people who are
doing psychedelics don't actually have a
relationship pre-existing with the
therapist what kind of advice do you
have for those
people um well get one if you can afford
one mhm um and it's of course cool if
you find you know there's an increasing
amount of therapists who are willing to
talk about psychedelics with you so
that's cool um you
can find an integration Circle you can
find an integration coach or an
integration Circle um an integration
circle is kind of halfway between like a
meditation group and a support group MH
right so it's like it it it kind of
might look like a support group on the
outside but um it doesn't necessarily
mean anybody's broken or wounded or
anything you know I mean we all are but
it's not it's not like a Survivor type
support group you necessarily it's it's
a slightly different vibe you know
people are just kind of like really
growing right so it's it's got that kind
of thing to it um as well as healing in
some cases and that is a place where you
can talk about you know what's important
to you and what you got out of your
experience and how you want to keep it
going with a group of people who are you
know semi-regular
and you kind of form a relationship with
folks and sometimes you know we have
three a week um you know on our on our
website they're all on zoom and then
depending where you live in the world
there might be one in
person um you know it just so happens
that I have a uh an online a little mean
online course on how to make your own
you can you can start your own
integration Circle then it's not rocket
science um so you know some Community
Support is a big deal
um some of it you have to do on your own
of course like nobody can nobody cannot
drink for you MH right right you know
nobody can journal for nobody can
journal and meditate for you you have to
do that on your own so
[Music]
um yeah I I don't know if that answers
your question sure it does and and and
the next question would be um I know
that there are some independently minded
people who are listening and and um you
know people who have got you know always
seeking autonomy like I am and and we're
thinking oh well I can just do that on
my own and um you know I just I have
this belief without any real evidence
that that doing integration with others
um who are not U who have got a
different perspective and are are a
little more objective and especially if
they've got therapy training
that it just seems to be more effective
to do
integration um along with someone else
if if if only to have someone to bounce
stuff off of what are your thoughts
about that yeah you can't we can't see
ourselves like you can't see your own
eye you know what I mean like you just
we just can't and because because I'm in
the Skinner box right so so me looking
me observing myself is is incredibly
subjective so so we need it it's help
for us to have somebody who's looking at
us on the outside is that the
idea um yeah yeah you you you're
strategies of evasion are highly
sophisticated yes they are I'll say that
once say that for those of you in the
back your strategies of evasion are
highly
sophisticated right and so there there
you know you one would I I don't want to
say need but I will you know we need to
have a little bit of willingness and a
little bit of humility sometimes and to
recognize that we are relational beings
and you've just been talking this whole
time about oh I I did the psychedelics
with my friend and it friends and it's
good to have a group it's good to have a
group right like you could meet you know
what would it be like if you and your
your party people said okay like we're
going to meet once a week at the same
time right for an intentional meeting
much like that intention that you all
brought to fixing your friend's foot
right we're going to meet for 4 weeks
before our journey for an hour and a
half uh we're going to have a a
conference call or we're going to meet
at the coffee shop or whatever we're
going to get on Zoom and we're going to
wrap about what we want and we're going
to talk about we're going to listen to
the shaping fire podcast and we're going
to make our own checklist we're going to
set it up and we're going to talk about
our hopes and our dreams and our desires
we're going to be vulnerable with each
other right and then after the trip
we're going to meet for four to 6 weeks
for an hour and a half and we're going
to talk talk about how our experience is
unfolding and we're going to hold each
other accountable and we're going to
focus on what's important we're going to
reflect back what we saw from each other
in our Journeys and we're going to see
what we learned about ourselves and each
other and we're going to be there if
somebody is confused about something and
offer them um support and and good and
good um Fellowship without again laying
our trips on each other or offering each
other a lot of advice but just kind of
recognizing that we're growing together
like how would that change the journey
if it was it would wildly improve it
hearing you describe it I'm like man
I've never done that I want to sign up
for that like like that level of
integration would really expand the
healing that any particular psychedelic
experience
has right and right and I say it and
it's almost like duh right yeah yeah it
is but but honestly I you know I don't
know about how psychedelics are done in
the rest of the world but you know i'
I've been involved with the Psychedelic
world for you know 35 years and
integration is not historically a part
of the you know every person's
psychedelic experience yeah and my God
it should
be yeah yeah yeah for sure and it's
almost like keep in mind that you know
in Peru like the iasa people of Peru
shapo tribes and such don't really do
integration circles they live very
different
lives you know what I mean like they
live like a slower paced life right
their society in a lot of ways was built
off of people doing iasa like if you
were a tri if you if you and your
friends had the wherewithal to start a
society based on your Journeys together
like what would that Society look like
and then that's what you have right in
Peru in many ways um so so it's built
into some cultures it's not built into
our culture and and you know
vulnerability and Community is not
necessarily built into our cultures at
least not like a vulnerable kind of
community thing right like it's it's
more like it's more external you know
it's exoteric and in a lot of ways um
you know still built around like what
what the individual can get out of it on
a real mechanical level if if somebody
wants to do integration with a a
professional um what would you recommend
they look for like what are the
attributes and what are the things that
they should think of when choosing who
to work with I mean you've you've taught
so many so many facilitators and
integration specialist you probably have
got you know a good a good list of uh
best practices for choosing one right
well I mean you should start with me
right reach out to me um you know you
would probably want somebody who was
very familiar with the territory so you
know I don't have an advanced
degree you know I I I don't I don't like
I don't like traditional schooling you
know I've uh taught and trained many
people with Advanced degrees um but you
know I as soon as I got out of college I
just I found a yoga mat and I hung out
in yoga studios and meditation halls and
stuff like that and that's kind of where
I did a lot of my
training um so you have to decide like
is
the degree important like to what extent
is the degree important and to what
extent is the experience important and
if you can get both that's great yeah
you know especially if there's rightness
of fit so you want to be working with
somebody who you feel seen and not
judged and held by right then and
they're clever right so um so you want
to be that's what you're kind of looking
for you know if somebody is kind of just
out of school and they've you know
they've done a little bit of aamine
training maybe maybe not mhm you know um
but you know you can vet people you can
ask people stuff um and you know in the
realm of social media you know there's
there's people out there sort of like
you know blabbing about how smart they
are all the time and maybe you find one
that resonates with you I think that's
the very important part is is to find
somebody who's got a communication style
that that I feel blends with my own
because we're going to be talking about
but intimate and subtle and um you know
I think subtle is the right word things
and I I want somebody where we're
already kind of speaking the same
language so that we can get to the core
of the matters uh
swiftly
effectively yeah right so somebody is
one of the best compliments I've gotten
was
disarming right which almost sounds kind
of you know I I almost had would be like
wait what do you mean and they were like
well you just you make me want to like
put down my weapons my defense my
defensive structures you know I can I
can drop my defenses and and be myself
and I was like oh okay that's nice you
know you want to feel like you can take
your armor
off so now that we've been talking with
integration uh about integration a
little bit because I I've been learning
as you've been talking um I think that I
would probably summarize it like if I
were if I were to be talking with
somebody else later on today about
integration
I think I would describe it as um so we
learn lessons when we're on
psychedelics and we you know those of us
who have done psychedelics we've all had
the experience of of forgetting our
lessons and leaving them behind in the
Psychedelic experience and so what um an
integration coach or or similar will do
is help you bring those lessons from the
Psychedelic psychedelic experience and
help to integrate them into your non
psychedelic everyday life so that the
good things that you have discovered
during the Psychedelic experience you
actually get to use those to improve
your life instead of just having a
psychedelic experience and having these
thoughts and then H and then having them
slip away is that a is that a fair
assessment yeah yeah that's a that's a
great place to be with all that right on
well thank you for explaining that so um
so let's w up there Daniel so um I'm
going to put you on the spot a little
bit but in a in a way that you're
probably very used to yeah lightning
round um so so what would be your what
would be your last advice for somebody
who has never done psychedelics before
they have found a good source for the
Psychedelic of choice that they want to
use and they're just trying to like rev
up The Moxy or the gumption they know
they want to do it they they have it
they're they're good to go but it sounds
like it sounds like you know taking the
step off of a cliff or something to them
and and and and they don't know what
it's going to be like and and so they've
got a little hesitation maybe they've
even maybe they've even had the
Psychedelic in their pocket for months
and they haven't like taken the next
step um what what would be your advice
for them to to to help them in this next
step oh I don't I don't know um I don't
I don't love this question um well if
you don't love the question maybe speak
to that and we'll learn from that well
it's you know it's it's not for me to to
you you you you you can lead a horse to
water right like it's not for me to push
somebody off um you know to push
somebody into the
pool right I mean I would just be really
curious if if I was coaching them right
so it's I if I was coaching them it's
it's not a performance coaching it's not
like um Glen Gary Glenn Ross you know
there not coffees for closers right this
is this is what we call development
coaching and so I just want to hear
about your
anxiety right I just want to know what's
coming up for you and what is holding
you back because it's entirely possible
it's highly probable that that
trepidation that you're feeling has has
served you really well throughout your
life M right like that trepidation there
may have been times when that
trepidation was the difference between
life and
death right and so I want to honor like
I deeply honor people's
hesitancy right it's it's a it's a
display as far as I'm concerned it's a
display of wisdom and discernment and so
I you know I I bow to your trepidation
and I want you to know that it is safe
and acceptable for you to be hesitant
and
anxious right and like let's learn more
about that um how has it served you in
the past right what is its aim how is it
held in the body um what is it make
possible for you does it limit you from
things sometimes right it's like what
can we learn about our this is their
shape right coming back to it the your
person is showing up and that's their
shape right they're bracing perhaps I'm
just picturing in my head you know as I
picture this person who's hesitant I'm
picturing like a musculature like a
tension almost as if they're bracing for
impact right I'm picturing like like oh
like I'm hand like if somebody would be
handing them the mushroom and they're
like ah right and their hands go out
like they're pushing away like oh like I
like it's I fear I'm not safe it's
dangerous right and so there's that
tension there and that's their shape and
they can't do anything else they can't
not do that
that's the thing that has been keeping
them in as good a shape as they are
right and so let's explore it let's
learn about it let's see if there are
other ways to practice being in a
different shape that is more in line
with your higher intentions and value
and
purpose well I really like how you took
the question that you weren't a big fan
of and and turned it into a powerful and
liberating answer so I appreciate that
in you Daniel and I also appreciate um
that a couple of the different questions
I've asked you today um you kind of you
kind of shook off and as being not the
right question if you will and and kind
of uh working with me to mold it so the
right things could be shared so I
appreciate that level of assertiveness
in our conversation today and um so so
thank you for your time and and thank
you very much for sharing your breath of
experience and
um your your your gentle self right I
think that a lot of people who are
approaching this it can be a pretty
bombastic um topic area for a lot of
people but your approach is uh so
accepting and uh genuine and um and
soothing that um uh I appreciate that
you you brought that to us and and
shared that with us today yeah man
thanks for letting me you know share the
message I think this is really important
work um I also really think the work
that you're doing is really important
work and um yeah it's an honor to
collaborate with you and um you know I'm
I'm deeply grateful that we we got
connected in such a a sweet and divine
way yes thanks for holding space man
yeah thank do really well right on thank
you so my friends if if you would like
to know more about uh Daniel and his
insights and his teaching and his
business um there's a couple great
places for you to go um the first place
to go is on Instagram and that's where I
got turned on to Daniel and that's at
Tam integration so that's
TM integration and you know you can
absolutely enjoy his social media Clips
but there is also his uh his link tree
there on the profile and you can you
know find everything all the different
ways to connect with Daniel allinone
place um the second place is on uh his
website which is again t
integration.com and you can uh you know
on on on Instagram and on Tik Tok you
will you will get you know one flavor of
Daniel but on on on the website you can
find out more details about his his
staff and the services they offer and
how they can be helpful um to you in
your integration or um or training or
coaching uh there's a there's a wide
range of good things for you to check
out there on the website Tam
integration.com
and um and and finally um Daniel wanted
me to point out that there is right now
A A psilocybin bundle of educational
services available um special right now
at Tam integration.com for SL siloc
cybin Das bundle so thank you my friends
for joining us and you've been listening
to shaping fire you can find more
episodes of the shaping fire podcast And
subscribe to the show at shaping
fire.com
and wherever you get your podcasts if
you enjoyed the show we'd really
appreciate it if you would leave a
positive review of the podcast wherever
you download your review will help
others find the show so they can enjoy
it too on the shaping fire website you
can also subscribe to the newsletter for
insights into the latest Cannabis News
exclusive videos and giveaways on the
shaping fire website you'll also find
transcripts of today's podcast as well
be sure to follow on Instagram for all
original content not found on the
podcast that's @ shaping fire and @
Shango on Instagram be sure to check out
shaping fire YouTube channel for
exclusive interviews farm tours and
cannabis lectures does your company want
to reach our national audience of
cannabis enthusiasts email hotspot
shaping fire.com to find out how thanks
for listening to shaping fire I've been
your host Shango
[Music]
Los e