I remember back when I was younger we
would get high and lay on the grass and
talk about how cool it would be to move
to California and grow marijuana
California was the promised land of
getting high on beaches drenched in
sunshine we had no idea how to make that
reality happen but we all knew that
being a marijuana farmer in Humboldt
County was pretty much the gold standard
of life goals most of the cannabis in
the Midwest was all moldy brick weed
from Mexico every now and then someone
would come back from a trip to
California we would all gather around to
see the big dense and fragrant flowers
that were called kind bud
putting California flower next to him
Mexican brick weed you'd not even know
they were the same plant and just like
that the kind bud was smoked and it was
gone and after a while it seemed like
myth again that flowers like that even
existed but we knew they existed because
we saw them in High Times Magazine these
ornate colorful and perfect flowers were
pretty much unattainable to us we
considered flowers from California with
reverence the idea of California was
more than just the gorgeous but itself
though it was the small clandestine
farmers in love with the land and making
it work it was these back to the land
folks giving up the city and growing
their own food and subsisting on income
from weed crops you know they may have
been modest income small farmers but
they were happy and they were high and
they had community the thing about that
fantasy of California we held in our
imagination was that it was actually
pretty true
while the DEA certainly played a role
and there was a general fear of
outsiders when I have talked to
old-timers in Garberville or Mendocino
or wherever they describe a world quite
like the one we always imagined it to be
now though those farmers are being
threatened by the potential
consolidation of production into huge
farms leading to the end of the small
family cannabis farm but this is in no
way a done deal though small farmers in
California can stand up and demand that
their voice be heard and influence the
implementation of proposition 64 so
their culture can pre preserved instead
of obliterated by corporatism and it
isn't only just on them all of us as
cannabis enthusiasts can speak up that
we don't want only mass-produce flour we
want artisan flour too and we want to
preserve California's cannabis heritage
today's episode is part 2 of 2 in our
series on the impacts and opportunities
of Proposition 64 in California if you
missed last week's episode with Amanda
Ryman of the drug policy Alliance you
can go back and hear our discussion
about new business opportunities now
that proposition 64 is passed
today's show is about what comes next
for small cannabis farmers in California
my guest today is Hezekiah Allen
executive director of the California
Growers Association Hezekiah grew up off
the grid in Humboldt County in exactly
the kind of community my friends and I
used to dream of living in he lived off
the land in cannabis was his agriculture
he realized that his community of
farmers in the Emerald triangle of
Northern California could use someone
dedicated to representing their
interests and so he progressed locally
from executive director of the Emerald
Growers Association to become the leader
of the now more statewide oriented
California Growers Association he now
speaks for cannabis farmers and
especially for small farmers with
California policymakers today we're
going to talk about the impact of
Proposition 64 on small cannabis farmers
and the actions necessary to preserve
artisan cannabis agriculture in
California
welcome to the show Hezekiah it's great
to be here thanks for having me well
thank you for making the time so you
know going into the election there was a
great deal of fear by a lot of folks
about the outcome of Proposition 64 and
and for some folks especially people who
think business wise simply not knowing
how the election was going to turn out
made business decisions really difficult
now that we're on the far side of the
election and we know that Proposition 64
is passed what are you hearing from
farmers and families in the Emerald
triangle region of Northern California
about how they feel now you know I in a
single word I think uncertainty is is
the overarching
here certainly going into the election
there was a lot of uncertainty about how
the legal adult use regulated market
would play out but I think coming out of
the election you know and this is a bit
of a curveball for for everyone coming
out of the election there's also
significantly increased uncertainty at
the federal level and so you know
exactly how this is going to play out
and what implementation is going to look
like was riddled with uncertainty to
begin with and now that conversation is
is even a bit more uncertain so folks
folks aren't quite sure what to think
you know of course my job and the reason
I moved down here to Sacramento to work
on this issue is to try to stay really
at the cutting edge of that conversation
to try to cut through some of that
uncertainty and and right now I don't
have a huge amount of solid feedback to
give to members so we're all sort of
looking at what passed looking at
current law and speculating as to what
may happen at the federal level but
certainly you know it's anything but
celebratory there there for folks who
have criminal convictions or who are
facing charges or are in jail
those folks are stoked and everybody is
100% in alignment that they should be
out of jail and those charges should be
dropped from the business side a really
really tremendous amount of uncertainty
you know that must be really frustrating
for you as somebody who grew up in the
Emerald Triangle area and as their
representative down in Sacramento for
them to turn to you for sage advice and
insight but for you to you know maybe
not really know anything more than we
knew before the elections since the
rulemaking hasn't really started yet as
somebody who you know represents people
who are not only our constituents but
like these are this is your family and
people you grew up and your loved ones
there must be a certain amount of
frustration kind of packed into that -
yeah you know and this is certainly the
frustration that we felt ahead of the
election you know the the Association
largest Association of cannabis
businesses in California with probably
close to about 900 members at the time
of this
you know we felt that frustration ahead
of time there is a lot of policy in prop
64 there is a lot of statute that was
passed last year by the legislature and
part of our concern and part of why we
were never never able to get to a
support position on prop 64 is because
of the immensity of it and because of
how many aspects of it are a bit unclear
and the disparities or disagreements
with current law and trying to figure
out which provisions will be preeminent
you know which ones will actually govern
the industry and and yeah it is a bit
frustrating I mean I guess the saving
grace and you know a bit of irony and in
describing it as a silver lining but the
silver lining is there still plenty of
things growers can be working on from
water permits to labor law to tax law
you know there's plenty of things that
folks who are currently operating in the
underground or gray medical market
there's plenty of things they can be
working on so there's not a shortage of
compliance tasks for the growers to be
doing but it is certainly frustrating to
have frankly more answers than we did
the day before there excuse me more
questions than we did the day before the
answer before the election answers are
hard to come by and questions are
plentiful yeah and you're probably
trying to hand out more patients than
anything to everybody
you know I think it surprised a lot of
folks that the voting returns from the
triangle counties actually came back in
favor of the proposition now even though
I read over the weekend that Mendocino
County very literally passed it by one
vote did it surprise you that the
counties ended up voting in favor of it
no I you know I think I think at this
point in 2016 it was pretty much a
foregone conclusion from our perspective
that it would pass we saw a lot of
people that took a YES on adult use no
on Prop 64 position I you know I would
estimate and some of our initial post
post-election surveys indicate that you
know public support was probably closer
to 65 or 70 percent
and the fact that we saw numbers in the
mid-50s throughout the state it reflects
the fact that there there was a
significant YES on adult use voting bloc
know on 64 so we were pretty pretty
confident that it was going to be
successful this time all of all of the
numbers indicated such and and there was
no good reason to believe they weren't
gonna pull a majority in in most
counties the the map looks a lot like we
expected it to frankly you know there's
that schism that there was before the
election the the YES on adult use no on
sixty-four folks it was it was hard
because people who are family and
friends and and have done business
together and medical providers you know
it there was this subtle cut in between
the community and the closer got to the
election and and more of it got turned
up and up and up on social media it was
it was pretty rough there right at the
end and I think that probably everybody
is just happy to have the damn election
over so we can deal with the reality of
it instead of everybody trying to
convince each other and hate on each
other about whichever side they were on
yeah I'd certainly think that's an
accurate observation and you know I
think one thing that was particularly
acute for our community in part of the
cannabis culture in California is is one
of sort of escaping from the system
right my parents went back to the land
to get away from all of this and so our
culture is very much a outsiders culture
and for a lot of our members this was
the first election cycle that they've
gone through and actually had a real
tangible emotional stake in it and so
you know for for me and for folks who
work in in politics election fever is a
pretty well-known thing you know you get
you get really really worked up an
intense and passionate in the weeks
leading up to the election and then you
wake up the next day and you sort of see
how long the hangover lasts and so for a
lot of people experiencing that
phenomenon for the first time it got
particularly nasty you know boycotts of
businesses that were voting
no and just just you know frankly a lot
more divisive than it needed to be and
you know the beautiful thing is now that
that cycle has concluded farmers know
about cycles now they understand okay so
that was harvest and now we're tilling
the soil and starting over and so to be
able to have gone through the cycle made
it through the fever and frankly to have
emerged more unified and stronger than
we went into it I think is a pretty
significant accomplishment yeah I would
definitely agree with you there and you
know it's it's too bad that it happened
right there during harvest time as well
it must have been really distracting
from everybody trying to trying to get
the harvest in yeah you know I actually
think we saw a bit of relief there right
around the third week of October when
the rains hit we saw a lot of the social
media at least from my perspective cool
off and you know everyone had more
pressing concerns the vote-by-mail
ballots had already been mailed and you
know as it was back to the farm which is
where most growers want to be spending
their time so it actually worked out
pretty well with the weather and the
conditions and sort of gave us a bit of
relief right in the lead-up the
immediate lead-up to the election there
right on well before we go to commercial
I want to ask you one cultural question
about harvest over there in the Humboldt
area you know I I heard once that there
are so many growers in the area that the
businesses that sell high price tag
things like cars and stuff they actually
advertise harvest sale so it's like
you've made your harvest and then you've
sold it down the line and now you've got
your big yearly income do do you see
that happening do businesses really
target market harvesters because there's
so many growers in the region yeah
absolutely and you know the only thing
that I'll correct in that sort of
understanding of the situation is this
is not a phenomenon that's limited to
the triangle tri-county region I mean
this is something we see statewide from
Calaveras Tuolumne out in the foothills
Nevada County Sierra County Santa Cruz I
mean the the one of one of
things from an academic perspective that
I'm most excited about as this
marketplace emerges into regulation is
wrapping our minds and imaginations
around the scope and the scale of our
outdoor harvest it is truly an epic
agricultural feat that we managed to get
all of this labor-intensive high-value
delicate by some standards perishable
product out of the ground onto the wires
and into the turkey bags in such a short
amount of time so I am thoroughly
excited about having better
understanding of that but yeah you know
we definitely see that in in many ways
all of rural California is operating on
a harvest cycle and of course you know a
lot of other agriculture has that same
cycle so it's not completely unheard of
but it's it's really undeniable that
that the cannabis harvest is a major
driving force in in regional economies
up and down the state awesome thank you
for that little bit of culture injection
there Hezekiah we're gonna take our
first short break and be right back you
are listening to shaping fire using
pesticides when growing cannabis has
been common for a long time nowadays
though we know better we know that most
pesticides formulated for food crops
have never been tested for use with
cannabis they've been tested to be eaten
in tiny doses they have not been tested
to be inhaled and especially not
concentrated into a cannabis oil
chemical residues from pesticides are
not healthy for anyone but they are
especially dangerous for patients for
commercial cannabis growers this has
become very impactful cannabis
enthusiasts and patients have gotten
educated enough that they avoid growers
who used pesticides not only that but
states across the country have begun
making pesticide testing mandatory on
all licensed cannabis crops the time has
come to find a better way to fight
garden pests than covering your cannabis
and chemicals and there is a better way
let some good bugs fight your bad bugs
beneficial insects and predatory mites
have come a long way since we were
buying ladybugs online and putting them
in the grow room and just hoping for the
best natural enemies bio control
can help you solve pest issues without
using chemicals natural enemies founder
Shane young learned best practices from
working in the ornamental plant industry
and has fine-tuned those strategies
specifically for large cannabis crops
Shane works with commercial cannabis
clients across the country to ensure
that they keep their crop safe and pest
free without the use of chemicals
natural enemies has proven solutions for
spider mites a fits
thrips Russert mites broad mites shore
flies white fly and others - you can
rely on natural enemies for expertise
and excellent service for more
information go to shaping feiyr.com
forward slash natural enemies or simply
click on their banner in this week's
newsletter welcome back you are
listening to shaping fire I am your host
Shengo louse and our guest this week is
Hezekiah Allen executive director of the
California growers association so
Hezekiah before the break we were
talking about the lack of certainty on
growers parts about what's gonna happen
next and you know there are a lot of
lobbyist groups who will be trying to
influence policy making in Sacramento do
you think the artisan farmers throughout
California the smaller folks will you
know have a voice in the rulemaking
certainly if I have anything to do about
it they will you know that that is very
much the purpose for which the
California Growers Association was
organized our our general highest level
metric of success will be how many
independent growers are successful in
the regulated marketplace you know
oftentimes economists will boil things
down to how big is a market what is the
gross productivity of this marketplace
but from our perspective we want to go a
layer deeper and we care greatly about
what that ownership pattern looks like
and so transitioning not just from what
is the gross value gross productivity of
the market but how many people how many
businesses are enjoying the benefits of
productivity and you know that's that's
a I think a very relevant and salient
message in in sort of the greater
political be it national or global as
we're looking at this economic reality
that you know there's more wealth in the
world today than there ever has been in
the world and yet absolute and relative
poverty are off the charts not only are
we offering this new and amazing
alternative medicine we're also bringing
this very different culture that
incubated outside of that economic
development you know the post-war years
nineteen fifty was not that long ago and
we had a very different wealth
distribution both nationally and
globally then and so our industry grew
up outside of the consolidation and to
be able to bring that back in such a
culturally stimulating exciting this is
a product that people care about it's in
the headlines to be able to bring that
to the conversation in you know early on
in the 21st century I think has
implications not just for our
marketplace but for the broader academic
study of economics in general and you
know certainly at this point we're
pushing a thousand members we'd love to
double that again this calendar year you
know we look around the state we're
estimating about fifty thousand growers
total probably about thirty thousand of
them would eventually seek a license and
we'd love to see five or ten thousand of
them licensed in year one and so we
certainly I think it's fair to say that
the existing rowers in the state not
only have a voice but are one of the
preeminent voices in Sacramento and
we're gonna continue growing our
membership and growing our influence
accordingly
that is such both an honorable and a
really difficult fight because you know
capitalism just generally moves towards
consolidation so that economies of scale
can be taken advantage of and prices
generally come down and profits are made
but of course what you're suggesting is
that you know it's it's better to have
more small business
then fewer gargantuan businesses and you
know that's where a lot of people's
heart is but pushing back on those
economic forces is a real challenge yeah
it is and you know where I grew up very
few things were easy you know every
harvest came at in spite of at the time
a paramilitary war on drugs you know
Bush Senior sent the National Guard out
a couple times so we you know we grew up
on the front lines of this thing and our
culture was really tempered by that most
extreme manifestation of prohibition and
and you know this is this is the place
that our culture is coming from and and
you know it's it's certainly present in
other states Washington Colorado Alaska
Oregon you know you you had these
experiences but the center of gravity
and the the there are so many people and
and businesses and farms coming from
that place here that you know frankly
it's about time that we start
questioning some of those basic tenets
of economics and what better community
of businesses to do it than ours I mean
change has to be financed at the end of
the day you know there's no way that we
can win a revolution of economics of
sustainability of Labor of any of these
things that our culture is marked by
there's no way we can win that fight
without a financial commercial base and
we're in a very unique position of
having that and that's why it's so
important to permit and license those
businesses so that this message that we
carry continues to have voice and
continues to have momentum and and I do
think at the end of the day if we stop
and take the time to ask ourselves is
this economic system working for us as
people as families as neighborhoods the
answer frankly is no and we do need to
start doing some things differently we
can look to a handful of states in the
farm belt just to add a quick aside to
it there
there's about 11 states in the nation
that currently restrict the corporate
ownership of agriculture and those 11
states from a Human Development Index
standard they have some of the longest
lifespans lowest infant mortality
everything is so much better than the
states around them that have allowed for
the financial sector to gut agriculture
there's something really really special
a special kind of value that small farms
bring to our communities and building on
that value not just from a cultural
perspective but also from an economic
perspective it really needs to be the
foundation of our 21st century and you
know the last point I'll make on this
subject it's it's very uncommon for me
to cite a World Trade Organization paper
1,013 the World Trade Organization
teamed up with the United Nations
Commission on Trade and Development and
they released a report called wake up
before it's too late
small farms are the only way to feed the
world and it really called into question
the entire driving thesis behind the
industrial agricultural revolution and
so at this point there really is a
global movement picking up steam to put
agricultural productivity back in the
hands of family farms one of the biggest
challenges of course to that and one of
the reasons the obama administration
didn't take this one on is because of
the entrenched interests of agribusiness
these are these are giants of global
commerce but they don't exist in our
marketplace and so we have this very
unique opportunity to move quickly with
a different type of regulations and you
know that's precisely what we've been
doing and what we intend to continue
doing as executive director of the
California Growers Association you know
you have got I think at least two really
nice advantages as far as as getting
your base involved number one like you
said it's a it's an industry that grew
up outside of the consolidation world
in the gray area and so you all have you
know you've been to war together already
you you've had the war on drugs come to
your neighborhood and it and it bonded
people and it really let people get to
know each other and so you're not a
hodgepodge of folks that are put
together you're already a prepared
communicative folks who you know have
each other's phone numbers and email
addresses right but also as far as you
know income distribution which is what
you've been talking about you know
having the big conversation and message
of Bernie Sanders in the election got
people thinking about whether or not
consolidation and big business helped
them as individual people and I think
that having having both your people
already know each other and the fact
that that message was pushed so heavily
during this particular election can only
help the California Growers Association
yeah and you know frankly we saw it from
I think the Trump campaign is well well
a lot of folks on the coast particularly
our beautiful Pacific Northwest out here
I think we were triggered by some of the
more racist misogynist xenophobic things
that the incoming president said but for
academics who have now had the
opportunity to take the time to go
through speeches and to do quantitative
analyses whether or not it's lip service
the incoming president spent a lot of
time talking about the damage that free
trade agreements the damage that this
particular neoliberal breed of economic
development has done to the heartland
and so well it's easier to find the
affinity with the with the senator
Sanders campaign I think that there's
also a commonality in in folks who who
voted for the incoming administration
and well of course we talked about the
uncertainty at the beginning we have no
idea how this administration
particularly the incoming Attorney
General is going to respond and react to
cannabis laws throughout the country
there is an underlying majority and I
think growing majority that big is not
better and and that's the fundamental
question that we need to ask ourselves I
mean we went through it in two thousand
six seven eight with the too-big-to-fail
era and and the way to not end up in
that situation again is to prevent that
level of consolidation so I actually
think that it's a it's a populist it's a
resurgent populist message that is
bridging partisan divides it's unifying
campaigns and frankly I think that the
Clinton campaign was unsuccessful
because they didn't have a meaningful
answer to this question and I really
think that over the next 10 to 20 years
this will be the defining question how
is this policy going to impact the
middle class is this going to create
more small business owners and you know
we need to get into some of those
definitions what is a small business I'm
sorry grossing 2.5 million is not small
from my perspective you know and and
this is one of those important areas
where current state law for the medical
regs to find small business very
differently than prop 64 does prop 64
defines a micro business as being four
times larger than what current law
defines the micro business as so there's
a real slant and bias toward larger
businesses and prop 64 and that
ultimately was why we weren't able to
support it is because it prefers fewer
bigger businesses over more smaller
businesses thanks for that Hezekiah
we're gonna take another short break and
be right back you are listening to
shaping fire businesses everywhere are
constantly striving to reach out to
people through advertising we all know
though that trying to reach a cannabis
audience with a quality message is
pretty difficult that's why many people
choose to advertise on the shaping fire
podcast advertising on this show allows
us time to talk about your product
service or brand in a way that really
lets pee
we'll know what sets your company apart
from others bold people who own
companies know that getting in a
relationship with their customers is
essential that is what we offer we will
explain your service or product and what
sets it apart as desirable and help our
audience get in contact with you it's
pretty simple really
advertising does not have to be all
whiz-bang smoke and mirrors nowadays I
find that people prefer just to be
spoken to calmly accurately and with
good intentions if you want to make your
own commercial spot you can do that too
because the podcast is young but growing
at an exceptionally fast rate if you
become an advertiser on the shaping fire
podcast now you are going to pay a
fraction of the cost we'll be asking for
in just a few months and yet everyone
listening both now and to the back
catalog of interviews later will hear
about your company again and again for
years it's a great deal for you pay a
small amount now because the show is new
but take advantage of the huge listening
audience we will have forever do
yourself a solid and contact us today
for rates on podcast and newsletter
advertising email hotspot at shaping
fire calm
to find out more welcome back you are
listening to shaping fire I am your host
Shengo Louis and our guest this week is
Hezekiah Allen executive director of the
California growers association so
Hezekiah on the last episode of shaping
fire Amanda Ryman of the drug policy
Alliance was on the show and she said
that the new law very much protects
medical in California but she also said
that the bigger medical players who can
afford the costs of compliance in adult
use with the new law will very likely
migrate to the commercial market now you
know I've been a business strategist my
whole life and to me that suggests to me
a future where the medical market slowly
gets drained of its major players and
therefore major funding and it gets
smaller and weaker until the commercial
lobbyists who you know are dying to
inhale that medical market find a way to
say oh the medical market is irrelevant
and they try to shut them out how do you
see it playing out at this
well you know I think that this idea
that prop 64 protects the medical
marketplace is a bit more of campaign
rhetoric than actual policy work and so
California was obviously the first to
pass a medical law back in 96 we have a
two decade long tradition of medical
cannabis it is compassionate use and
compassionate commerce are very much the
foundation of our cannabis industry and
marketplace be it regulated medical
unregulated adult use or out-of-state
sales which of course you know
California is a a large exporter of
cannabis as well but that culture really
threads the needle between all of those
marketplaces and so the initiative would
not have been politically viable if it
was perceived to undermine that
marketplace so the campaign ran very
very heavily on this point that you know
medical is protected this is separate
that's not true just to put it simply
every everything around town in
Sacramento here in the legislature the
regulatory agencies everyone's pulling
their hair out trying to figure out how
we're going to fold these marketplaces
together what rules and regs apply to
both I think that before we knew the
outcome of the presidential election
there was a pretty firm consensus that
California would emerge with a single
regulated marketplace now I think
everyone is sort of on alert that the
federal government may decide to impose
a distinction on the states something to
the effect of will respect States
medical programs but we won't respect
States adult use programs and so that
uncertainty asserting certainly clouded
the conversation but the truth of the
matter is at the end of the day at least
up until the consumer purchases the
cannabis there is likely to be one
unified supply chain a grower is not
going to be a medical grow
or an adult use grower they're simply
going to grow cannabis pesticide
regulations are not going to differ if
it's not safe for a patient it's not
safe for an adult consumer those types
of things are going to be unified and
that was always the intent and so this
is this is one of those places where
policy and politics don't always match
and you know it was a necessary
political goal to to insulate and to
carve out medical but from an
implementation bureaucratic who's going
to give you a license it's going to be
the same office there's not going to be
two offices and two bureaus and two
directors so I think it's important to
distinguish how politics and policy
differ in this regard yeah I think
that's a good point I've got a couple
more questions about economies of scale
here and how you see it playing out so
you know the economies of scale will
continue to favor the large commercial
growers as they start to create more
profits because they can you know
essentially by things like supplies and
labor and bulk so do you think that the
Emerald triangle Appalachian region that
will eventually be created will be
enough to support the higher prices that
artisan farmers were will likely have to
charge since they're smaller and can't
take advantage of buying things in such
mega bulk well so this goes back to that
that initial question is bigger actually
better you know there's been a lot of
work done on the high cost of low prices
and understanding that those economies
of scale are not actually reduced costs
they just externalize more of their
costs and society ends up bearing those
costs whether it you know for
traditional agriculture that comes in
the form of farm subsidies or for the
oil industry it comes in the form of
unmitigated or unrestored environmental
damages but those costs still exists in
fact if you want to get really technical
about it products grown agriculture in
particular large scale grows are
probably more expensive the consumer is
seeing a reduced cost but
the overall social cost is not reduced
and so we need to do a better job of
doing true cost accounting but you know
that's all well in good academic
conceptual feel good stuff let's talk
about nuts and bolts on the ground this
is one of the biggest distinctions
between prop 64 and the medical regs the
medical regs limit any single license
holder to one acre per lot and four
acres cumulative prop 64 blows it wide
open and allows a licensee to grow as
much as they want frankly we don't think
anyone needs to grow more than an acre
and it's very much our intent this year
in 2017 to ask everyone in the state who
needs to grow more than an acre raise
your hand come to the legislature and
tell us why tell us what the public
benefit of you doing that is you're
going to ask the state for some level of
limited liability through a corporate
charter that's not a free pass corporate
charters shouldn't be handed out so
easily demonstrate how you will promote
good jobs not minimum-wage jobs good
jobs demonstrate how you will protect
California's scarce water and why going
big is going to allow you to improve
those metrics and at the end of the day
the truth is they want these small farms
are more resource efficient they create
better jobs and so it really is a
question of how we look at efficiency
are those cost savings real or are they
just externalized and secondly what are
the secondary benefits and the
multiplier effects of inhibiting those
large growths and I'll just say at the
end of at the end of this conversation
there is a clear consensus that the
lieutenant governor's Blue Ribbon
Commission reports States very
succinctly it is appropriate and wise
for the state of California to limit the
size and power both economic and
political of any single entity in the
cannabis marketplace I think that if you
had to make that argument anywhere in
the
you are the best place to make that
argument where the ideas of of social
socially conscious business and you know
in triple bottom-line profit really you
know people are interested to know that
okay that so the company's making money
the shareholders are making money but
what impact is it having on the
community and and let's not forget that
that there's humans in all these
companies so so I think that if you you
know if you had to make that argument
anywhere I'm glad that you're making it
in California you know and strangely we
find ourselves drawing on some very
unexpected bodies of policy North Dakota
for example has what I think is probably
the most robust restrictions on
corporate ownerships of Agriculture
you know there's several states through
the farm belt there that right around
the the turn of the last century when
you know the the railroad barons were
and disrupted and and that last major
wave of antitrust regulations went into
place you know you see you see some
similar provisions in states that you
really wouldn't expect this from so so
they're actually there there are some
some other states out there that we're
drawing from but I certainly agree that
you know if we're going to if California
is going to lead like we so oftentimes
projects that we do which quick tangent
I'm not convinced that California is
exactly the trendsetter nationally
anymore um but but we certainly identify
as such and if we're going to lead in
terms of those values we're going to
need to be bold and courageous and I
think this is a perfect opportunity to
do just that right on well said so for
this last question you know I really try
to do my best to decrease fear whenever
possible decrease fear and suffering in
people whenever I have the opportunity
and you know there's a lot of people who
are still afraid of Proposition 64
because it's passed and they don't know
what the rulemaking is going to be and
as you have already mentioned you know a
lot a lot of more weird as
ingredients are going to be going into
the sausage before the rulemaking comes
out on the other side so so take a
moment what advice would you give
fearful artists and growers who've been
doing this for generations who are
afraid of what comes next what balm can
you offer them that might help them get
through just living through the
rulemaking process you know we really
focus on basic core values at cow
growers and we try to boil things down
to the most simplest of terms and and
the two things that I can offer are
really the outcomes are going to be
better if we have a hand in shaping them
and the more organized we are and the
more we work together the more influence
we'll have so you know I'm not trying to
veil the fact that this is a bit
self-serving in that of course I want
the organization to have more members
but the reason the organization needs
more members is not so that you know I
can go on a fancy vacation it's so that
we can have more influence we we really
are focusing our resources pooling
resources together to ensure the
outcomes are as best as possible and
secondly courage what I can say with
certainty is that the clock is not going
to go backwards on this one we are
moving forward into a regulated future
and we need to have the courage to
embrace that the sooner folks get on the
train the easier it's going to be five
years from now it's going to be really
hard to make the transition from
unregulated to regulated so beyond to
have the courage to be on the first wave
have the courage to jump in and go for
it know that there are hundreds if not
thousands of other like-minded
businesses throughout the state that are
going through this together with you and
really at the end of the day we're going
to have the courage to work together to
put our values
first and like you mentioned a minute
ago we value our profitability but we
also value the places we do business and
we value the people we do business with
and I all I can say is that if we put
our values first we work together to
advance them with courage the world is
going to be a better place than if we
didn't and I you know I I some wake up
every morning and I give thanks for the
challenge and the opportunity and let's
be intentional let's bring this amazing
healing culture wisdom that is cannabis
let's bring it to the regulated
marketplace and let's heal not just
people and patients and consumers let's
also heal the economics and the politics
so that's what I got it's not going to
get any easier let's do this together
let's have the courage to do it and
let's put our values first well that's a
great call to action thank you for that
and this has just been a great interview
thanks for taking the time to be on the
show I know that you're probably even
more busy now that Prop 64 is passed and
you were before the election so thanks
so much for taking the time and being on
the show my pleasure thank you very much
Hezekiah Allen is executive director of
the California Growers Association you
can find their website at Cal growers
association dot org and you can find out
more about Hezekiah Allen at his website
Hezekiah Allen calm and that's a cheesy
eki aah al l en com you can find more
episodes of the shaping fire podcast and
subscribe to the show at shaping fire
calm and on Apple iTunes stitcher and
Google Play if you enjoyed the show we'd
really appreciate it if you'd leave a
positive review of the podcast wherever
you download your review will help
others find the show so they can enjoy
it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the weekly newsletter for
insights into the latest cannabis news
and product reviews on the shaping fire
website you will also find transcripts
of today's podcast as well for
information on me--and where i'll be
speaking you can check out Shango
lowes.com
does your company want to reach our
national audience of cannabis and
email hotspot at shaping feiyr.com to
find out how thanks for listening to
shaping fire I've been your host
Shango lows
[Music]