[Music]
there are over 100 cannabinoids found in
cannabis and more continue to be
discovered each one has a personality
each has particular uses and when they
all work together they are at their best
Federal canabo prohibition influences
the Cannabis Market in ways that pervert
it to the detriment of everybody even
though Delta 8 THC is widespread
throughout the country and many profess
that it was made by the US farm bill it
is not actually a legal canabo its
illegality is just not enforced but
that's not what we're covering during
today's show if you'd like to hear
expert legal analysis on that topic
check out the new video clip from last
week's Kos science Delta 8 webinar on
the shaping fire YouTube channel with
attorney Lauren Ruck during the webinar
highlights you'll find there she
explains in detail the legal standing of
Delta 8 and clarifies many of the
misconceptions and consider consider
subscribing to the Kratos science
newsletter to find out about their
upcoming cannabis science webinars links
to all of these are on the shaping fire
website page for this episode today's
episode is about the Delta 8 molecule
itself how it functions how it doesn't
function and why How It's Made is so
important if you want to learn about
cannabis Health cultivation and
technique efficiently and with good
cheer I encourage you to subscribe to
our newsletter we'll send you new
podcast episodes as they come out
delivered right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week and
videos too don't rely on social media to
let you know when a new episode is
published sign up for the updates to
make sure you don't miss an episode also
we're giving away very cool prizes to
folks who are signed up to receive the
newsletter there's nothing else you need
to do to win except receive that
newsletter so go to shaping fire.com to
sign up for the newsletter this week and
be entered into this month's an all
future newsletter prize
drawings welcome to episode 110 you are
listening to shaping fire and I am your
host Shango Los my guest today is Dr
Ethan Russo Ethan Russo is a board
certified neurologist and former senior
medical adviser to GW Pharmaceuticals he
served as study physician to GW
Pharmaceuticals for three phase three
clinical trials of satx he has held
faculty appointments in pharmaceutical
Sciences at the University of Montana in
medicine at the University of Washington
and as visiting professor at the Chinese
Academy of Sciences he has been
president of the international canab
research society and is former chairman
of the International Association for
cannaboid medicines in 1995 he pursued a
thre Monon sabatical doing
ethnobotanical research with indigenous
people in Peru he is author of several
books of cannabis medicine and has
published over 30 articles in neurology
pain management cannabis and
ethnobotany Dr Russo has joined us
several times on shaping Fire episode 22
on treating traumatic brain injury with
cannabis and mushroom rooms episodes 11
and 27 about his famous research papers
on canabo and terpenoids episode number
67 about treating migraines with
mushrooms and cannabis episode 80 on
cannabis hyperemesis syndrome episode 83
on canabal CBG episode 103 regarding the
life's work of Dr rapael mulam and of
course the shaping fire sessions on
shaping fires YouTube channel during the
first set today we will take a look at
the molecular nature of Delta 8 THC and
its historical milestones in the second
set we will learn about how Delta 8 is
synthesized and how that creates
complications for use of this
cannabinoid and during the third set we
will explore some of the Lesser
discussed attributes of Delta 8
including its propensity to cause failed
drug tests and cannabinoid hyperemesis
syndrome welcome back to shaping fire
Ethan that's nice to be here you know I
had another first this morning while
setting up here in my office Studio of
usually I can leave a window cracked
facing the water for you know the good
saltwater smells but today I had to
close it because the sea lions have
decided to have a party on the beach
below my house and you know you can just
hear them honking away and um I did a
little test and uh you could actually
hear them and I thought well that would
that would give people a little bit of
sense of place but but also probably not
appropriate and and this isn't the first
time that animals have played a role one
of your shaping fire episodes you may
recall that 5 years ago I we were
recording and I had to ask you to hold
for a moment because my neighbors cows
had found their way into my yard and
were eating um all of uh my my tulips
and so you were kind to wait for a
minute while I shoed them out of the
yard yeah the animals uh want their
voices heard totally and and this
Island's definitely theirs as as much of
or maybe even more than ours so anyway
so um thank you for being here Ethan and
U let's get started right off at the top
you know so many people refer to uh
Delta 8 tetrahydro canabidol as you know
d8 Delta 8 everybody wants to shorten it
and everyone just kind of like assumes
they you know other people know what it
is but but since this is a this is a
good uh you know primer on what's going
on with Delta 8 in the Canabis scine I
think we should start there so would you
please describe what Delta 8 is
chemically
sure so this is a normal
Trace uh compound found in cannabis it
differs from the more expected Delta 9
THC only in the fact that a double bond
in one of the Rings is in a different
position um
interestingly apparently the plant
doesn't have any enzymes to make this
but it appears in Trace Amounts even in
fresh
material um and certainly under the
influence of heat uh it may uh appear in
Greater concentrations so it is a
natural
component uh and it is more stable to
heat than Delta 9 is so that that that
one caveat confuses me because if if if
the plant doesn't have a way to make it
are you suggesting that
a um there is enough heat that is that
happens during harvesting that some
amount of canabo is is uh synthesized
into delta8 or are you saying that we
just haven't figured out yet how the
plant makes Delta 8 because if it's
there it's there yeah I think it's the
ladder uh I'm not sure how it's doing it
but plants are very resourceful and it
may have some trick that doesn't in
evolve uh the customary enzymes right on
all right well that that's really
interesting it's always great when there
are uh when we get to point out new
research that's uh looking to be done
for all the folks moving into the
industry you know so um so Delta 9 is
the form of THC that you know we're so
familiar with and and humans love so
much how is delta 8 different from Delta
chemically uh again you know if we look
at the molecular weight it's the same uh
in terms of most reactions uh it's going
to be the same it does differ in its
Affinity uh for the CB1 receptor the
psychoactive receptor and the brain and
so it is not quite as potent but
basically most of its activity would be
similar rather than distinct from Delta
9 UM um and there's a very involved
experiment going on now hasn't quite
been completed by Ryan vandre at Johns
Hopkins we have some preliminary results
on it but they haven't gotten through
the full contingent of um subjects for
that study so we will learn more but
they're more similarities than
differences that really surprises me
because um you know most people that I
have spoken with say that you know
they'll they'll they'll struggle to
describe what Delta 8 feels like to them
but they're always describing it as uh
feeling different than Delta 9 which we
will often you know we will describe as
a euphoric right and and and so um and
it sounds like we'll get more to the
bottom of this after this new study but
but in its Essence are you saying that
that we're finding that Delta 8 actually
feels pretty similar to Delta 9 except
cep that it's more like at a 60%
potency uh that would be a a really
reasonable way to characterize it yes
all right um that surprises me right um
so um so it may have a a a reduced but
similar euphoric effect as Delta 9 does
um let's talk a bit about the similar
medical applications you know not only
do we love the experience of of taking
in Delta 9 THC but but it also has got L
heralded medical benefits of being an
anti-inflammatory and an analgesic and
and an animedic meaning you know anti
nausea along with a whole bunch of other
things um does Delta 8 have any of those
similar medical applications or or maybe
we don't know yet quite likely but again
there could be differences there's only
been one uh real clinical study uh Del
done with Delta 8 and that was cleared
back in
1995 uh so this is a study by Abraham
off and
mulam uh they use pure delta8 THC so not
what people commonly have access to here
uh we should say they use this in
relatively high doses to uh children
that had uh blood cancers you know
mainly leukemia and the like um and this
was given to counteract nause and
vomiting associated with the
chemotherapy that they were getting and
there were
480 total applications uh
administrations of this and it was
almost
uniformly effective in allaying the
naian vomiting the other thing that was
interesting was uh they seem to tolerate
very high doses compared to that that
would have been used in adults but that
um just highlights something that was
known say in the 19th century that uh
young children seem to be resistant to
the psychoactive effects of
cannabis um wow that's interesting it
sure is um explanatory a bit around how
we see um young children use THC
cannabis oil without um
you
know getting like really stoned you know
so many of of the the younger kids can
get relief from their symptoms without
the accompanying intoxication and I've
always wondered about that do we have
any explanation for why kids uh seem to
be able to to tolerate um that aspect of
it sure well the tongue and cheek
explanation would be that kids act like
they're stoned anyway
um but the more serious explanation
would probably have to do with the
density of CB1 receptors in the
brain and and what meaning that they
don't have them developed yet and so
they're not they're not taking it on
board as fast is is that the point right
so they're they're not as expressed as
say in in an older person an adolescent
or adult right on um so back to the idea
that um Dr mulam L were um using um a
large amount of Delta 8 isolate um which
you're right um you know we don't have
easy access to here right now um for
lots of reasons that we'll talk about
more later but this is normally when you
know you you've been on shaping fire
before to talk about other novel
cannabinoids and this is normally when I
say well you know if the isolate is good
does this canabo work more effectively
in a uh in a whole plant preparation
instead of an isolate but you've already
said that it's there's only Trace
Amounts of it um is there any um is
there any analysis to support that that
Delta 8's presence or not in such small
amounts in a whole plant preparation has
any meaning at all any any substanti of
impact uh the answer is probably not and
it was uh
addressed uh quite well by a study
that's Now 50 years old uh carneal and
Carini in Brazil back in
1973 actually did comparative studies in
man uh also in animals comparing Delta 8
and Delta 9
THC um and um you know these are very
carefully done studies that uh answer
some of those questions but
um because Delta 8 proved to be half as
effective as Delta 9 in causing rapid
heart rate Tac cardia um it also Delta 8
was 30% less effective in producing
impairment a Time
estimation um and it uh was had less
psychoactive value according to people's
uh subjective scores you know how they
rated their
psychoactivity so their conclusion was
because of uh the low
concentration of Delta 8 in natural
cannabis that it probably had very
little effect uh would be swamped by the
higher amounts of Delta 9 and I should
add at this time that we have no
indication that we could selectively
breed for higher T Delta a THC
concentrations um so you know I had
heard that before but earlier in the
show already you had mentioned that we
actually don't know how Delta 8 even
comes into being in the plant so um what
is the the early signs that were getting
this idea that it would be difficult or
unlikely that we could um selectively
breed for increased Delta 8
um well again because there seemingly
are no enzymes that would make it um and
uh there's been a lot of cannabis
breeding going on and nothing has
appeared that seems to have
significantly more Delta eight
concentration so we we just don't have a
path forward for
that all right and I you know it's
unclear to me that it would be worth the
expenditure of time money and effort
either oh sure well whether or not it
makes sense from a a market point of
view is definitely true but also a
different thing because you know when
you and I are here saying that um you
know there's no way to selectively breed
for increased delta8 that you know if I
was a breeder and hearing that that
sounds like a dare you know and um and
if there is some you know established uh
Botanical reason you know why we see a
you know a blockage in that path for
breeding I figured this would be a good
time to bring it
up sure um so um and I also think that
now is probably a good time to say we're
going to talk more about this later but
but I can imagine listeners asking the
question to themselves well then where
the hell does all this Delta 8 come from
and um and spoiler alert we're going to
tell you during the second set um that
it nowadays it is a almost entirely
synthesized from CBD can have a dial so
we'll answer that question question now
but we'll get into that more during the
second set so so Ethan if if U if Delta
8 is less potent than Delta 9 and the
high is not as delightful and the
medicinal benefit isn't as
substantial um it seems to me that there
is an obvious Market reason why such an
inferior canabo is being used in so many
states in place of Simply using
traditional Delta 9 cannabis
um what is that reason well first I I'm
not sure I'd use the word inferior um it
is inferior from the standpoint of
quality control um and really the issue
with delta8 is that it is
synthesized uh that the uh material
that's produced is not pure uh that
there can be all these byproducts about
which we know very little in terms of
their activity or safety and the
possibility of residual solvents so the
answer is because people make money
doing it and uh because of the these
interpretations of the law in some
instances that Delta 8 is
legal um people have been taking excess
CBD and turning it into Delta 8 um as a
way to use it and make money with it um
basically in some instances because
there have been 3% Delta 9 restrictions
on
concentration uh people have tried to
get around that by spiking things with
Delta a of synthetic origin um so it's a
market issue uh that is based on what
I'm going to say is a misconception of
the available law and and one way or
another we can parse out the law but
more importantly the the answer seems to
me to be just straight up prohibition
that that that if um we had uh federally
legalized you know cannabis that the the
the market for Delta 8 would
instantaneously disappear except for the
small group of cannabis patients who who
have uh unique issues that Delta 8 uh
can address like the um the the children
during uh chemotherapy that you
mentioned earlier and and I think that's
important to point out because um you
know we will be talking today about a
lot of the challenges to using Delta 8
in in the market as it presently you
know functions today but but these
questions are only um happening and
people who are uh incorporating Delta 8
into their products none of this would
be happening if it weren't for federal
um prohibition of the preferred sibling
Delta 9 would you agree with that uh yes
let me State this clearly the current
craze about Delta ATHC is a byproduct of
prohibition excellent it doesn't get any
clearer than that um all right so um so
that brings us to um wanting to
understand a bit about how we got here
and so um uh I was uh fortunate to uh
catch your uh webinar a couple weeks ago
um about uh the history of Delta 8 and
its uses and um you you've you've got
the the historical milestones for Delta
8 in a really nice like tight package
now so um I I think what I'd like to do
at this point um would just be like to
hand you the mic and just let you go for
a while and and please just teach us
about the historical Milestones to
delta8 that bring us to where we are now
sure well we have to go way back to the
fourth Century on what was then
Palestine um there was a skeleton that
was found in a cave in bemes uh which is
about midway between Tel Aviv and
Jerusalem um in this cave there was the
skeleton of what appeared to be a 14y
year old uh young woman who apparently
died in childbirth um in her pelvis was
an undelivered full-term
fetus uh next to her there was this
carbonized fragment of material that
when analyzed showed Delta ATHC now as I
mentioned previously that's more heat
stable than um Delta 9 uh so the fact
that it was there indicates that this
was psychoactive material that
apparently had been burned and the
um the analysis of the situation was
that this cannabis was burned in an
effort to Aid delivery of the the baby
uh which in this instance didn't work
however there's been thousands of years
of history of successful use of cannabis
for this purpose so that's the first
delta8 I know about then we've got to go
clear up to uh about
1942 there was an American scientist
named Roger Adams uh who did a lot of
work in analysis and synthesis related
to
canono um actually in 1940 he sort of
almost got the structure of
canaba uh so he had a bunch of this and
synthesized what he called tetrahydro
canabal from it but it wasn't pure there
were at least two
forms what he found out was when
administered to dogs this made them
wobbly on their feet what's called
Static Axia and then and earlier this
was a test for cannabis preparations as
to their
potency he took some of this material
actually 30 milligrams of what likely at
this point was Delta ATHC put it in
olive oil capsules and then tested these
on um convicts in New York 77 of them
now this is interesting because I think
people will see the similarities of
effects to Delta 9 so with the Delta 8
capsules um they got onset orally in 30
to 90 minutes it uh Peak somewhere
between 3 and 1 half to 5 hours and was
gone after 7 hours and the effects again
were quite analogous to Delta 9 they had
increased heart rate a little bit of
increased blood pressure faster
breathing their eyes got red um they got
dry mouth some got wobbly on their feet
um you know recognizing there was a
somewhat higher dose some got anxious
some were euphoric uh they talked a lot
it seemed a lower
inition uh they those who were familiar
with the term felt High uh there were
bursts of laughter and some
drowsiness um and then they did
experiments and showed that with
prolonged usage there was tolerance
these psychoactive
effects um now interestingly they made a
distinction in uh humans between inmates
and what they called high- ranking
individuals and industrialists who also
tried this but the effects were quite
the same uh so it may show you that
businessmen at a high level aren't that
different than
convicts but enough political commentary
um subsequently uh some of the same
material 15 milligrams of what was
likely Delta
ATC um was again used on convicts in uh
New York um this is part of What's
called the LaGuardia report that came
out in
1944 but they Ed this to test uh about
withdrawal from uh narcotics
specifically morphine or heroin um and
so they compared this 15 milligrams of
Delta
ATC uh to uh what was called mendi
solution which was just a a form of
morphine um anyway they found that uh
this helped with the withdrawal reduce
the symptoms and people were able to
leave the hospital after treatment uh
seemingly in better condition than those
who got no treatment or got the the
morphine
substitute um so they were able to eat
on and some actually gained weight
during withdrawal which is not what we
usually expect with
opas um after that we've got to go clear
up to the
1960s uh at this point uh professor
mulim and his colleagues were working
out all the structures of cannabis
components from
hashish um and so in 1963 they figured
out the absolute structure of canaba in'
64 uh Delta 9
THC uh in '
66 um they showed that um you could turn
canabidol into Delta
ATHC uh through a chemical reaction um
so two nasty things um heated together
with benzene and what's called row toine
sulfonic acid and they could make Delta
ATHC um that and similar schemes have
come down to us uh in the current time
uh as a way to make Delta ATC from
CBD and then there were some some more
experiments that were done um uh again
in ' 66 it was shown that you could find
some tiny amounts of Delta at in freshh
cannabis um the dean of American
cannabis studies in the 60s and early
70s with Leo
Hollister um he tested Delta
ATHC 20 and 40 milligram as compared to
20 milligrams of Delta 9 interestingly
they put this in chocolate cookies um
but the effects were qualitatively very
similar um Euphoria tranquil
difficulty thinking rapid thoughts
decreased memory the time frame he got
was onsetting 30 to 90 minutes early
peaking after 2 and a half to three
hours on with residual symptoms up to 5
hours um overall again there seemed to
be a lower
psychoactivity head-to-head perhaps
Delta 8 being about 63% of the potency
of Delta 99 as I calculated and that
might be in keeping with what people
have said
previously um I previously mentioned the
study of carneal and Carini in 1973 in
Brazil their findings were really quite
similar uh to the others um they uh
essentially thought it was uh about
30% uh less
psychoactive um and uh very careful
studies for the time um um so um
compared to what we're doing now uh
they're they're really valid
studies um and after that uh really not
much happened Beyond uh Abraham off and
mulam study in
1995 clear up until a few years ago when
uh suddenly Delta 8 appeared um in great
profusion uh as a way to get rid of
surplus CBD
right on well then um that's actually a
great setup that's where we start set to
so um thank you for that explanation of
those historical milestones and um let's
go ahead and take our break and then
when we come back we'll we'll pick up
right here you are listening to shaping
fire and my guest today is neurologist
and cannabis researcher Dr Ethan Russo
and you know without these advertisers
shaping fire would not happen so please
support them and let them know you heard
them on shaping
fire
there are so many seed banks nowadays
that you really have options in who to
choose not only that if you pick the
wrong seed bank you could be in for a
really sketchy ride and that's only one
of the reasons I recommend Gas Lamp
seeds to my friends and listeners who
are looking for a seed bank you probably
already know Gas Lamp seeds as hembra
genetics hembra recently changed their
name to Gas Lamp seeds Gas Lamp seeds is
not just another seed bank gas lamp is a
female operated Boutique cannabis
genetics provider that only sells
thoughtfully curated seeds from the top
names in cannabis breeding with over 60
breeders and over a thousand strains to
choose from you will certainly find
something you'll love Gas Lamp seeds has
something for everyone with over 650
feminized strains 300 regular varieties
and over 200 autof flowers to choose
from names you know you can trust like
compound genetics Humbolt Seed Company
night owl inhouse fast buds gnome
automatics and Ethos and we both know
that there are other seed banks who will
take your money but have no customer
service I invited Gas Lamp to advertise
on shaping fire after hearing so many
good stories about them from my friends
they have A+ customer service with
Lightning Fast Response times in most
cases holen and Caitlyn will get your
order out the same day you place it most
seed banks are simply not this organized
or interested in getting your seeds to
you so fast but Gas Lamp seeds cares you
even get free seeds with every order
Helen and Caitlyn get it they have been
in the Cannabis growing scene for over a
decade want some extra freebies use the
code shaping fire all one word at
checkout and they will give you an
additional set of gas lamp provided
freebies that's an extra $30 in free
seeds buy seeds from good folks who will
send you great seeds reliably every time
visit Gaslamp seeds.com today that's
Gaslamp
seeds fish poop brand fertilizer is an
allnatural fish poop concentrate with
nothing added real fish poop is
extraordinarily complex not only are you
adding the nitrogen phosphorus and
potassium your plants need to build mass
transport nutrients enhance flavor but
fish waste is also packed with
biological activity and micronutrients
when you add fish poop to your
irrigation water you are adding life
force probiotics and active microbes
these microorganisms include a wealth of
various bacteria and protozoa which
further enhance nutrient availability
for the plants because plants are
limited by the absence of any essential
micronutrient these Trace nutrients are
the difference between having a decent
garden and having a garden that makes
you feel really proud of your efforts
fish poop is a naturally complete
solution ution that fills in the cracks
in your fertilizer program to ensure you
offer your garden a broad base of
nutrients not all fish poop is created
equally most products with added fish
waste don't reveal their sources or lab
results fish poop brand fish poop
however generates their own fish waste
as a byproduct of their organic
aquaponic cannabis farm where they raise
ornamental koi and tilapia you are even
invited to tour their Farm in person or
on their YouTube channel to look for
yourself this sort of transparency is
wildly rare in the fertilizer Market the
folks behind fish poop are also lifelong
medical cannabis producers who have deep
Connections in the community donate more
product than they sell and support
cannabis prisoner veteran and patient
collectives and Charities to get your
bottle of pure fish poop go to fish
poop.com and to see their entire line of
cannabis products go to ounce ofh
hope.com that's fish poop brand and fish
poop businesses everywhere are striving
to reach people through advertising we
all know though that trying to reach a
cannabis audience with a quality message
is pretty difficult that's why many
people choose to advertise on the
shaping fire podcast advertising on this
show allows us time to talk about your
product service or brand in a way that
really lets people know what sets your
company apart from others bold people
who own company know that getting into
relationship with their customers is
essential and that is what we offer we
will explain your service or product
what sets it apart as desirable and help
our audience get in contact with you
it's pretty simple really advertising
does not have to be all whizbang smoke
and mirrors nowadays I find that people
prefer just to be spoken to calmly
accurately and with good intentions if
you want to make your own commercial
spot well you can do that too during
these pandemic days conventions and
cannabis events are pretty poorly
attended but podcast listening is
skyrocketing with a commercial on
shaping fire you'll reach your customers
in the privacy of their headphones right
now and will continue to reach new
listeners as they explore the shaping
fire back catalog of episodes again and
again for
years a spot on shaping fire costs less
than a printed postcard per person and
the shaping fire audience is full of
smart cannabis enthusiasts cultivators
and entrepreneurs who are always curious
to learn do yourself a solid and contact
us today for rates on podcast and
Instagram advertising email hotspot
shaping fire.com to find out more
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire I am your host Shango Los
and my guest today is neurologist and
canvas researcher Dr Ethan Russo so
before the break we were bringing us up
uh historically to um what is happening
now where most folks or nearly everyone
um who is incorporating uh Delta a THC
into their products is doing so from
Delta 8 um that has been synthesized
from CBD and a reminder that the reason
why they're not taking it directly from
the cannabis plant is because the
amounts are um so low so barely there in
Trace forms um that uh for both labor
and financial reasons trying to pull it
out of a great deal of uh plant material
just doesn't make sense um but because
you can synthesize uh CBD excuse me you
can synthesize delta8 THC from CBD um
and we had this huge glut of of CBD on
the market um just what 3 years ago now
that the the price of the the the CBD
raw bulk material the the bulk plant
material was so low that it made sense
to pull out uh cheap CBD out of these
hemp plants and then go to the lab and
synthesize it into Delta 8 THC which um
you know even though it's less potent um
uh you know there is a way to cause a
high and therefore is a way to make
money um so Ethan what I'd like you to
explain right now uh it's kind of like a
a two-part question um for a lot of us
who don't have lab experience the idea
of synthesizing Delta H THC from CBD is
kind of nothing but words and so if you
could um you know uh you know generally
explain what it means to do that in the
lab and kind of what that's like um so
we can picture that in our heads what it
is to synthesize something um and then
and then the second part which is part
of your answer is is that um the the
point of our concern about Delta 8 is
that so many contaminants come along
with it from the synthesis process which
then gets passed down to Consumer so
this is this is the Crux of the problem
and and I'd like you to explain the
synthesis and why there are
contaminants sure yeah I think that's an
important question so let's say that we
have a bunch of starting material uh so
this would be crystalline CBD that
originally came from the plant or even
could be be from a synthetic source so
first this would be dissolved in some
kind of organic solvent now they often
will use things like hexane which is uh
something you'd find in gasoline uh it's
not something you'd want to
ingest uh then
it's Heat Ed in the presence of an acid
and uh that closes a ring on kabid and
uh produces Delta
ATHC so that sounds fine except um then
you've got to get rid of the solvent um
presumably with some kind of drying or
evaporation technique but there always
could be residuals and uh you know
that's a source of toxicity but the real
problem here is this isn't a onetoone
proposition in other words you don't get
all all the CBD turned only
into uh Delta ATC rather there are all
these other things now we're going to
get into some fancy names here Delta 48
ISO THC 9 ethoxy hexa hydroc
canaban UM and even performing uh
getting new things that hadn't been
discovered before like ISO tetrahydro
canaba
furan um so these are things about which
we know little or nothing it may be that
some of these
substances are okay it may be that
they're not they are potentially toxic
some could be actually more psychoactive
than Delta 9
THC um and you know probably get into
some of other nases that have been found
in delta8 products but the bottom line
is
this
basically it is extremely unlikely that
any commercial product with delta8 in it
is going to only have that uh will have
these potentially toxic byproducts and
potentially toxic solvent
residues um so basically uh if you're
using these products it's a crapshoot as
to what's really in there and what uh
bad effects they might have either
acutely or particularly if taken on a
chronic basis in most cases uh product
manufacturers who are using Delta 8 um
they you know they they they get a test
done that's that's you know perhaps
needed for their state but one way or
another there's a testing test done at
some point of like what what the the
isolate is that they are they are
purchasing or making and it's done and
they're like oh you know it looks good
but isn't isn't the science that to find
any of these contaminants you actually
have to be using standards to actually
see them and and since there is all of
this you know chemical static in the the
isolate that is the resultant that that
many people may actually think they're
using an air quotes clean isolate of
Delta 8 but the the the the costs are so
preventative to to check for all of the
toxic items that that that that kind
of research is not being done on their
products uh very likely not so what you
said is quite right um so there is this
blip on a a screen uh you know whatever
kind of uh analytical test is being done
well that's going to remain unknown
unless you have a standard um a pure
chemical um that you've used in your
analysis uh that tells you what it is um
and for some of these compounds there
aren't any standards so um in the
analytical studies that have been done
they figure it out using Advanced uh
instrumentation um and comparison with
the literature but you know these are
just not uh necessarily available in
your friendly neighborhood
lab um you know I have struggled a bit
with this with the idea of delta8 being
um natural or a synthetic because
synthetic and natural both seem
to um be uh inexact words and and you
know I originally learned about uh Delta
8 as a synthetic something that is not
naturally occurring but the more I speak
with Scientists um they say what what
you have said which is there's there's
such a trace
amount uh that that it does occur in the
applant we're not exactly sure how it
occurs in the plant but but it's it's
there in Trace Amounts but to to to say
that Delta 8 is then natural seems to be
a bit of a misnomer because that's not
the delta8 that is used in uh the market
what's used for product
manufacturing is uh I dare say always
going to be Delta 8 that's been
synthesized from canabidol which is
synthetic because it's not naturally
occurring and so I just wanted to hear
whatever your thoughts were on this on
these messy use of synthetic versus
natural for uh in in in an
isolate right well you know to keep it
quite simple uh basically any consumer
product uh advertising itself as
containing Delta ATC is of synthetic
origin and subject to all the caveats
and warnings that we've uh already
discussed um and it gets worse from
there um you know some of these products
may contain Delta a CO acetate um
there's a whole problem with this group
of compounds the um
Esters um when these are
vaporized uh they can produce something
called ketenes which are toxic to the
lungs and have been uh associated with
um this uh problem with the lungs called
evali uh which is an acronym for
something very ominous uh called
ecigarette or vaping product use
Associated lung injury people may have
heard this term in relation to the
vitamin E acetate Scandal of a few years
ago where vitamin E acetate was put in
Vape pans as sort of a carrier uh it had
a consistency that was sort of like um
uh cannabis concentrate
um and it was put in vape pens but uh
number of people were hospitalized and
there were some deaths due to pulmonary
damage uh from this kind of compound and
the same thing could happen with any of
these uh
acetates that uh are sometimes seen as
toxic byproducts of Delta ATC production
so actually um Delta a thco acetate has
been demonstrated on a vape pen
something called Blue drain this is
showed shown by benowitz at all on an
article earlier this year and they
pointed out how uh this uh Delta a THC
acetate when subjected to heat produced
this ketene which again is the lung
damaging compound um so the same thing
potentially could happen with any uh
Delta 8 vape pen um if it had similar
contaminants right on so let's let's
tease out that Nuance a little bit
because I think that it is I think that
it's the Crux of this essentially the
entire episode um that that Delta 8 um
in a perfect world where it was
isolated properly in a lab
and then after the fact was cleaned up
to
remove
contaminants which is a very uh lengthy
and arduous process and takes you know
Advanced
skills that as that Delta 8 as a
medicine does have applications and does
cause you know a
60% Euphoria effect 60% of what what
Delta 9 does however that's not the
world we live in the world we live in is
that um folks without enough experience
are
are isolating Delta 8 not cleaning it up
afterwards maybe don't have the
experience to know everything that they
that that they need to be pulling out
don't have the budget or the lab to um
identify the toxic contaminants and
remove them and be and then this is the
Delta 8 that is is being dumped onto the
market that's being synthesized from CBD
from hemp from the last three years and
this is what the problem is so so it's
not
scientifically true Delta 8 the problem
is in the reality that people aren't
putting out pure Delta 8 and it's
actually got all this um these these
extra contaminants in
it uh yeah I mean uh
quite right I mean the way I'd put it
succinctly is Delta 8 THC the molecule
or compound is not the
problem the problem is how that delta8
TC is
produced um and again the toxic
byproducts and solvent
residues so uh again don't blame the
compound compounds all right but how
it's made and available to Consumers is
the problem and uh potentially a very
big one um there was a popular study
from 2021 that W that looked at this
case of of of Delta 8 from CBD being
sprayed on Delta 9 flour to make it more
potent and and and then I believe
subsequently they they were taking
products from the licensed Market where
there should not be Delta 8 and there
were all these products that had Delta 8
in it um kind of like uh to
fortify the the experience of the
regular Delta 9 so so it's like uh you
know a fortified vitamin or a fortified
alcohol or something it's like it's like
ah we we want to make it more strong and
so we're going to we're going to add
something extra and so people are adding
Delta 8 um and and not mentioning it on
the L a because it's in Most states it's
not supposed to be in their licensed
Market but they add delta8 so that their
product has what they think is an
improved experience can you um explain
what the downside would be for for
people to be buying products that have
got Delta 8 in it without their
knowledge uh well it's an unconscionable
practice and um uh I would condemn
anyone who engages in that kind of
activity um but beyond that uh again
it's a matter of uh not knowing what
you're getting the likelihood of
Overdose uh if in a vape pen the
possibilities of lung damage
um and you know it's been demonstrated
there've actually been studies that show
that uh use rates of delta8 products are
way higher in states that have
restrictive cannabis policies as opposed
to those that have Freer access to
Natural
cannabis uh
compounds um so um and again this stuff
is not uh without risks um there was a
study earlier this year Simon at all um
there's a reporting system at the Food
and Drug Administration for
nonprescription drugs it's called the
fairs uh system um and they've had a
massive increase in reports associated
with Delta 8 products um just to give a
rundown uh 33 deaths attributed to Delta
8 products um 49
hospitalizations 109 serious reports 41
nonserious and this one will surprise
people there were more respiratory
issues problems with the lungs that were
reported for Delta ATHC products than
any cannabis or hemp product M um so
that puts it in context so these things
are not without risk so this is quite in
contrast um to the claims uh that have
sometimes been made
um there was a a paper that was
published uh when it gotten past me if I
reviewed it but in 2022 Krueger and
Krueger public published a study it was
just an online survey of people using
Delta eight products um and you know
they reported um that um I don't know
how they made their comparisons it
wouldn't be scientific but they reported
delta8 was less intense uh produced
relaxation and euphoria that it relieved
pain but also uh was associated with
short-term memory
impairment um there was a comment from
one consumer that got in the title of
the paper and the quote was delta8 feels
like Delta 99's nicer young sibling um
and um that's just not borne out by the
figures um uh and you know the
conclusion of the article was quote
Delta ATC May provide much of the
experiential benefits of Delta 9 THC
with lesser adverse effects that's just
plain wrong um and never should have
been in a published scientific article
um and I I won't cast aspersions on the
publisher but I
could and I think that this adds a lot
to the confusion that we see amongst
consumers about Delta 8 um you know I
kind of came into the Delta 8
understanding being prejudiced against
Delta 8 I got to admit because I was
only ever seeing it in really low
quality unlicensed market products that
were very low priced in um uh states
where cannabis wasn't legal and let's be
clear off the top that that um the fact
that it's unlicensed doesn't actually
bother me um you know we talk a lot
about a lot about um individual patient
freedoms and to grow your own um on this
show but but what does get me is when a
product is of crappy uh um Quality
period whether it's in the Li Ed or in
the unlicensed market and so I would
when when I first started seeing Delta 8
it was in you know the these states and
and you know $10 Vape cartridges in
really you know bad packaging and you
could just tell like oh man somebody's
going to get really sick from this stuff
and then they did you know and and so um
certainly there are products in the
unlicensed Market that are are quality
but certainly that's that's not most of
them most of them are are of low quality
and and because there there are papers
um like the one you just referred to um
that product manufacturers can grasp on
grasp on to and say hey look here's a
study that says that you know it's safe
and good it creates enough confusion in
the market um where where people don't
aren't educated and so they buy what
they can afford and so these products
are are finding themselves more into uh
states that are are not legal and then
people who are lwi Income which is you
know such a drag um I also found it
interesting that um there's an ASN white
paper in 2021 pointing out that the
instructions for synthesizing Delta 8
are easily found on YouTube um but it's
it's it's not as simple as it's often
presented on YouTube most people don't
have the the skills to do it safely and
the study says it results in wildly un
ended consequences so are those
unintended consequences the same um uh
toxic components that we've already
referred to or or is it something even
further than that uh no that's it uh you
know basically they referred in that uh
white paper to acetic acid available in
your kitchen uh Translating that means
vinegar so there there would be ways of
making this with vinegar and heat um um
but again um you know I don't trust a
lab to do this
properly why would we have any inkling
that someone uh doing this in their as a
kitchen chemist would have better luck
in what they produce um no one should
ever try
this right on so um to to to wrap us up
here in set two um and and I know we're
putting a sharp point on this but I I
don't think that we can put too sharp of
a point on it you know a lot of people
say you know hey delta8 is in the plant
we've been using the plant for you know
thousands of years Delta 8 has a natural
or origin and therefore and natural
products are safe and therefore they say
that Delta 8 in in their products is
fine but but that's just not the right
way to think about it is it no no all
right so um let's wrap up here in uh set
three um we're going to start uh talking
about some of the unexpected attributes
of Delta 8 and you know some of the
interesting questions about uh deltra 8
and how to think about it that that just
haven't um fit into the show so far it's
going to be kind of a hodg podge of
interesting Delta eight topics I guess
so uh let's go ahead and take um our
second short break and be right back you
are listening to shaping fire and my
guest today is neurologist and cannabis
researcher Dr Ethan
Russo
[Music]
as cannabis regulations become more
demanding and consumers become more
educated it is increasingly important to
avoid the use of chemical pesticides
when cultivating cannabis beneficial
insects have been used for decades by
the greenhouse vegetable and ornamental
plant industry and today many cannabis
cultivators are moving from sprays and
chemicals to beneficial insects copert
has the beneficial insects mites and
nematodes microbials sticky cards and
air distribution units you need to
partner with nature to defend your
garden whether you manage Acres of
canopy or have a simple grow tent in
your home copert is ready to help answer
your questions and help you transition
away from chemical sprays towards clean
and natural
solutions since
1967 copert has assisted growers in
identifying pests and devising reliable
Solutions while providing healthy
insects and mites that will protect your
yield since the 1990s Cobert has been a
leader in cannabis Pest and Disease
Control worldwide and have highly
trained Consultants to assist you in
Canada and the United States from coast
to coast with their Global Network of
grower support copert can help visit
cooper.com choose your country and get
detailed information that's copert k p
peer
t.com for the most up-to-date cannabis
related biological control information
you can also check their Instagram at
Cobert Canada you know getting away from
pesticides is good for health and good
for business and copert is ready to help
visit ct.com
[Music]
today sometimes the topics I want to
share with you are far too brief for an
entire shaping Fire episode in those
instances I post them to Instagram I
invite you to follow my two Instagram
profiles and participate online the
shaping fire Instagram has follow-up
posts to shaping fire episodes growing
and processing best practices product
trials and of course gorgeous flower
photos the Shango Los Instagram follows
my travels on cannabis garden tours my
successes and failures in my own garden
insights and best practices from
personal grows everywhere and always
gorgeous flower photos on both profiles
the emphasis is on sharing what I've
learned in a way that you can replicate
it in your own garden your own hash lab
or for your own Canin apathic health so
I encourage you to follow @ shaping fire
and @ Shango and join our online
community on
Instagram the cannabis seed Market is
filled with big name and hype breeders
fighting to get your attention and
occasionally you discover a breeder who
is breeding because it is the only thing
they care to do and they would be doing
it even if they never made a dime that's
my friend Craig hardsaw who makes seeds
as magnetic genetics Craig comes from
five generations of farmers and is
earning his master's degree in
horiculture right now he's been growing
cannabis for 15 years and been breeding
for nine he hasn't sold many seeds
because he really isn't a sales guy but
I've personally been growing his seeds
for years and I know I can always rely
on his seeds to germinate Thrive and
smell and taste great I suggested to
Craig that he should probably sell some
seeds and asked if he had enough
stockpiled to bother much to my shock he
was sitting on five full menus in Cold
Storage that he produced in the last two
years and hadn't even tried to sell any
of them he was simply too busy breeding
well we his friends convinced him to
make his damn seeds available to the
people and now they are for the first
time anywhere you can now buy magnetic
genetic seeds at neptun Seedbank and on
strainly.io
Neptune Seedbank has just picked up
magnetic genetics for a trial to gauge
your interest they are carrying three
strains from his Mean Mug prominence and
tpon menus which are exclusive to
Neptune it's an easy way to score his
seeds you can pick up those menus plus
his hillbilly skunk and Candy breath
crosses and more on his profile page on
strainly.io
if you want very affordable seeds that
are exceptional quality with rare
tarpine profiles from a good guy go to
neptun Seedbank do.com or strainly.io
sometimes it is fun to buy the hype
thing from the brand you admire but when
you're ready to buy the stral love from
an obscure mad scientist you're ready
for magnetic genetics magnetic genetics.
org and on Instagram magnetic
genetics welcome back you are listening
to shaping fire I'm your host Shango and
my guest today is neurologist and
cannabis researcher Dr Ethan Russo so
here in the last set we're going to talk
mostly about um things that like didn't
really fit in the rest of the show and
there's some really interesting stuff uh
uh about Delta eight that we haven't
touched on yet and and the first thing I
want to uh talk about Ethan is that you
know we mentioned um early way back in
the first set that um that uh Delta 8
Works effectively as an antimimetic in
kids who are uh experiencing chemo
therapy meaning that it decreases their
nausea have we found anything else that
delta8 can do well I guess anything at
all because because Delta 9 may actually
be better than Delta 8 for this but have
we found anything that Delta 8 can do
that that naturally
occurring um Delta 9 THC and the the
other naturally occurring canabo don't
do better is there is there anything
unique that Delta 8 can do that the
other canabo can't
do uh yes and it would be its stability
to heat uh as demonstrated in the
ancient
sample and um I suppose there could be
some jurisdictions around the the world
where they had a law that specifically
cited Delta 9 THC and didn't site the
Delta 8 and it might be possible there
to use Delta 8
preferentially um but you know that's a
a legal Point not a medical point so
it's thermal stability is it's um main
selling point is the thermal stability
something that is actually a health
benefit or is that more a oh because
it's more thermally stable it makes it a
good choice for some particular
Pharmaceutical products that have got to
be heated it would be that kind of
situation or shelf life issues but um I
don't see this is being commercially
developed in any
capacity um meaning now or in the future
or both yeah uh because um to make a
Delta 8 prescription product it's going
to have to go through years of testing
and uh hundreds of millions of dollars
in expenditure to get it through Phase 1
to three clinical trial I don't see
anybody doing that mhm because the
promise of it doesn't seem to be J
justify that much time and resources
yeah two points one is it wouldn't be
worth the investment and two it's never
going to do what herbal cannabis in a
proper preparation can do MH so this
would be the place where I typically
invoke the Entourage
effect um go ahead why don't you go
ahead and invoke it for those who aren't
familiar with it um there's nothing that
pure THC whether Delta 9 or delta8 can
do that can't be done better by a
properly con
constituted um herbal cannabis
preparation um you know uh we really
benefit from having additional canabo
and terpenoids that reduce the side
effect profile of THC in either
form and it makes for a better more
tolerable and more effective medicine
excellent excellent we we always love to
support the whole plant medicine
thinking here on the show so you know uh
during shaping Fire episode 14 all the
way back five years ago with Dr Greg
German uh we discussed how synthetic
cannaboids can sometimes be used in the
lab as a tool so so not as something
that a human is actually going to ingest
for a medical reason but something that
can be used in the lab as a tool to do
you know one or other experiment or
process um would you explain briefly how
synthetic cannabinoids can be useful in
a lab setting and then also whether
you're aware of any useful tool that
Delta 8 has become in the
lab uh okay well you know there actually
been hundreds of synthetic cannabinoids
that have been used in the lab some of
these are extremely potent as compared
to Delta 9
THC um those can be useful in pointing
out path ways or the patterns of uh The
receptors in a given organ especially
the brain so they're just tools that are
used that way and they they're often
used in animal studies uh believe it or
not it's easier to acquire a lot of
these synthetics than it is to get
permission to use Delta 9 UM in such
experiments but we have to be very
careful um rats are not humans and in
particular uh there've been some
distinctions in the Affinity of uh Delta
8 for canabo receptors in certain
species of animals as compared to humans
um so um uh I hate to say this but you
can only learn so much from animal
studies um that's true um there are
distinct differences and uh any such
literature has to be read with that in
mind that um that's interesting but it
may not translate to human clinical
use um do you think that there are um
folks that are using Delta 8 as a tool
in the lab or or is that not necessarily
one of the synthetic cannabinoids that
that has use in a lab in that way um it
has been used I wouldn't say a great
deal um but again it uh might have to do
with things like uh its
stability as compared to Delta 9 right
on so um in uh some of the studies that
have uh grabbed um products from the
licensed Market um as well as our
general awareness of products in the
unlicensed Market we find that some
people will fail drug tests um because
they've had uh Delta 8 um with Delta 18
HC and and uh folks think that oh it's
got Delta 8 it doesn't have you know
real cannabis in it if you will these
people will say and so and so they think
it's safe to use but yet they still um
fail drug tests for you know their
trucking job or whatever so will you
just explain briefly why um a Delta 8 is
is is not safe for people who have to
take drug tests uh sure you know as we
said in the beginning the only
difference is where this double bond is
that makes a difference between Delta 8
and Delta 9 so in um analytical assays
for urine testing metabolites of THC
they're going to show up anyway so the
bottom line is if you're getting urine
testing for your job don't use Delta 8
Simple right on easy and to the Point um
you know a lot of people uh who are
looking to defend um uh Delta 8 um you
know as it's commercially made right now
as an Agricultural Product um you know
they they say listen it's an it's an
Agricultural Product like anything else
and and we should be allowed to use it
um but on your webinar the other day it
was mentioned why you know Delta 8
doesn't make sense to consider it an
Agricultural Product and and would you
repeat that
analysis uh sure sure you know uh it had
its first origin in a plant grown in the
ground presumably although um some
delta8 may be made from synthetic CBD
but once it gets into the lab and
subjected to these chemical
transmogrifications it's not natural
it's not an Agricultural Product it's a
synthetic product and one that
invariably is
contaminated right on so so is there a
is there a scientific threshold point
where um where a a molecule that started
out in a plant is now considered a
synthetic because I'm figuring that
somewhere along that chain of synthesis
um you know it's it's officially no
longer an Agricultural Product does that
threshold exist or is that um more um um
subjective uh anytime you've changed one
thing in something else that's uh no
longer
agricultural right on fair enough um
we've had you on shaping fire uh before
to talk about canabo hyperemesis
syndrome and um this is the likelihood
that that someone will be especially
sensitive to cannabis causing a whole
range of negative symptoms um have we
seen um cannabinoid hyperemesis Syndrome
from um being caused by D Delta 8
products yes in 2021 there was a case
report uh this is a woman who'd had
prior gastric surgery and came in with
nazine vomiting so she got a CAT scan to
make sure that nothing was wrong with
the surgery um and her nause and
vomiting wasn't responding to the usual
approaches and drugs that they used uh
it turned out she'd been using Delta a
THC gummies um they suspected she had
canabo hyperemesis syndrome and then
responded to drugs that seem to work
better there uh specifically haloperidol
which is a major
tranquilizer um and um capsus anointment
on the skin so canono hyperemesis
syndrome will be caused by
anything uh whether Delta 9 Delta 8 or
synthetic cannabinoids that are
stimulating the CB1 receptor the main
psychoactive
receptor uh for
canabo um so yes Delta 8 can be
associated with CHS right on thank you
so uh as we wrap up here at the end of
set three um I think I want to wrap up
by reading a couple of um um quotes from
uh the the SE hodala study from 2021 uh
We Believe In Unicorns and Delta 8 uh
from the Cannabis scientist
um and then and then and then I'm going
to ask you a question and and and we'll
we'll wrap up here so so here are a
couple quotes from from that paper um
the problem is not with Delta 8 but the
unregulated distribution of synthetic
contaminated
products at least Walter White was a
chemistry
teacher Delta 8 has become a money
printing
machine but when I show producers what
it is in their sample they don't stop
making it and they don't stop
Distributing it they just go to another
lab who not acknowledge the contaminants
found um this really points to oh so I'm
no longer quoting anymore this is my
voice now um this really points to the
the shyy nature of a particular um
section of the um unlicensed Market but
even some of the licensed Market because
we know Delta 8 has has snuck into state
level um legal markets
and and let's finish with this Ean you
know I know you're very passionate about
this um as a you know as a medical
doctor and also as a cannabis researcher
uh in search for the truth um for folks
that are making these um Delta 8 um
products that we know are all coming
from uh synthesis from CBD um you know
what message would you have for them um
uh uh in encouragement uh to perhaps
reconsider their
approach um again I would state that
there's nothing that Delta 8 does that
can't be done more safely and
effectively with a natural cannabis
product now that may not be available to
everyone but um you know I hope that uh
the laws will change and that we see
this Commerce and Delta 8 disappear
because to repeat what I said said
earlier uh Delta 8 craze is a byproduct
of
prohibition well said and and at the end
this problem um sits at the feet of our
legislators who are choosing to drag
their feet inste instead of taking um
real um legalization
action well thank you Ethan um it's
always a pleasure to have you on uh
shaping fire and um especially with such
a uh a nuanced topic as this um that is
just not getting enough attention I
appreciate you taking um your time and
your expertise and going uh through it
with us um so that we too as as cannabis
enthusiasts can understand the nuances
and you know use it in our own lives as
well as the the people who we care for
so thank
you thank you for the
opportunity so my friends um if you are
interested in uh learning more about Dr
Russo there's a few ways to do that that
um first and foremost I highly recommend
uh you check out um Ethan Russo's
library of uh work and research at Ethan
russ. org and then click on the library
tab um you can also find a link to this
um on the shaping fire.com website for
today's episode um you can also uh learn
about uh Ethan Russo's uh work bringing
uh cannabis into uh legal and healthful
cannabis products and and different um
projects at
k- science.com that's c d o- science.com
and then finally um if you have a
burning question or a comment that is
only going to be uh uh for Ethan Russo
um you can email him at Ethan Russo
comcast.net now be realistic you know um
Ethan for all these years uh he does his
best to get back with everybody but he
is you know still an active researcher
and he's he's flying around the world to
give um to give lectures so so it might
take him a while to get back with you so
be realistic but um I think he does a
pretty good job of of getting back with
everybody finally if you want to learn
more from Dr Russo um he has joined us
several times on shaping fire over the
last 5 years and perhaps one of these uh
will interest you um all the way back 5
years ago episode uh 22 on treating
traumatic brain injury with cannabis and
psilocybin mushrooms episodes 11 and 27
about his famous research papers on
canabo and terpenoids episode number 67
about treating migraines with mushrooms
and cannabis episode 80 on cannabis
hyperemesis syndrome episode 83 on
canaberal CBG and then um recently and
and very heartfully episode 100 3 um in
a memorial episode about the life's work
of uh the very respected Dr Rafael mulam
and of course on the there's the shaping
fire uh sessions a 10p part series on
the shaping fire YouTube channel you can
find more episodes of the shaping fire
podcast And subscribe to the show at
shaping fire.com and wherever you get
your podcasts if you enjoyed the show
we'd really appreciate it if you would
leave a positive review of the podcast
wherever you download your review will
help others find the show so they can
enjoy it too on the shaping fire website
you can also subscribe to the newsletter
for insights into the latest Cannabis
News exclusive videos and giveaways on
the shaping fire website you'll also
find transcripts of today's podcast as
well be sure to follow on Instagram for
all original content not found on the
podcast that's @ shaping fire and @
Shango on Instagram be sure to check out
shaping fire YouTube channel for
exclusive interviews farm tours and
cannabis lectures does your company want
to reach our national audience of
cannabis enthusiasts
email hotspot shaping fire.com to find
out how thanks for listening to shaping
fire I've been your host Shango
[Music]
Los