[Music]
when we like something it becomes a part
of us
when we like something we tend to defend
it and say it's a good thing
because it's us
anytime we identify with something as us
and start to defend it though it can
lead us down a bad path
it is important to stay philosophically
detached from ideas and people so we can
keep our minds flexible and willing to
say that we are wrong and adapt
if you want to learn about cannabis
health business and technique
efficiently and with good cheer i
encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter we'll send you new podcast
episodes as they come out delivered
right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week and
videos too don't rely on social media to
let you know when a new episode is
published sign up for the updates to
make sure you don't miss an episode
also we're giving away very cool prizes
to folks who are signed up to receive
the newsletter this month we will
randomly choose four newsletter
subscribers to receive three packs of
seeds from pride of the lion seeds in
mendocino
check out their instagram profile at
pride of the lion seeds and request
their new catalog of over 150
photoperiod and autoflower seed
varieties
there's nothing else you need to do to
win except receive the newsletter so go
to shapingfire.com to sign up for the
newsletter and be entered into this
month's and all future newsletter prize
drawings
you are listening to shaping fire and
i'm your host shango los
my guest today is dan jimmy more
commonly known in the underground as
full duplex
dan is founder and breeder at gnome
automatics formerly known as mandalorian
genetics an award-winning and
exceptionally well-respected line of
autoflower seeds
dan is also co-founder of autoflower.net
the center of the autoflower breeding
and cultivation universe since 2010.
dan and i are both well-known
evangelists of autoflower plants but
today we're going to focus on everything
about them that we found dif find
difficult and annoying welcome back to
shaping fire dan
shango thanks for having me back man i
really appreciate it you know it's kind
of funny that we're doing this
particular topic since you and i are
both known as
evangelists for autoflowers you know
we're both you know talking up
autoflowers all the time and here we are
gonna do a show where we're essentially
talking trash about autoflowers
exactly you know the uh the aspects of
what we
absolutely don't like about them you
know we have like you said we're both
evangelists for the autofire plant we've
seen a massive you know wave come across
the industry as they're progressing
forward but there's also a lot of things
about them that just get rather
frustrating yeah no doubt you know um
i've grown over
over 150 varieties like 158 varieties of
autoflower
and uh and i and i tell people they
should try them and i highly recommend
them for patients and for people with
space constraints um but my gosh um i
get frustrated just like everybody else
with some of the characteristics
so thank you for joining me today so we
can talk about all the things we hate
absolutely dude i think it's going to be
a great conversation for people to
realize you know that even though we
love them so much that you know like you
said we get frustrated we run into
problems and i think it's good to kind
of see both sides of that you know kind
of bring it both to light right on so
with that let's start on this list and
that's how we're going to handle this
show today we're just going to go
through
all of these different categories of
things that we find frustrating about
autoflowers and what's funny is that as
dan and i were getting ready for this
show and we were putting up a list
it was really shocking that the list was
so long you know like just just looking
at it really quick you know i can i
think there's like 15 or so here and
it's it's amazing that something that
has got so many downsides or challenges
would actually be something that we like
so much
so uh so let's let's start right at the
top dan so um since you're the breeder
um i will i'll let you start um with our
first one here about seed inconsistency
and um we're gonna talk about both about
the seating inconsistency in one pack
and also inconsistent seeds from breeder
to breeders so so why don't you go ahead
and get us started
sure thank you i appreciate you letting
me take off with this so let's just dive
right into it um the inconsistent seeds
in one pack
i remember coming over to
avimia events
back before we become so close friends
and you had made a comment that like you
know one of the things with autoflowers
is when you open up a tent pack of maybe
feminized or regular it's literally like
opening up a pack of pokemon cards you
have no idea what you're gonna get
and
that was a frustration point for me very
early on and i think it's partly why i
went down the rabbit hole so far was
because you know we're getting these
seeds in from europe they're being mass
produced in warehouses because the
majority like we've talked about in the
history of autoflowers so a lot of this
really started off in spain
and when you have such big crops being
produced into seed there's multiple
multiple parents from both sides whether
they're being reversed and making
feminized seed or they're being you know
traditionally bred male female there's
more than one pollen donor usually in a
room
and i think that's one of the biggest
things that leads to and i know it is
from experimentation myself the
inconsistency that we see in
a three pack to a 10 pack
you know yeah and you know it's it's
it's frustrating for most of us who have
spent
most of our growing time with photo
periods
you know you you might have a line of
something and there might be three or
four or five phenos within the line and
so if you're going to get your 8 or 10
or 12 pack you may see you know two or
three or four or all of these different
phenos but um
you know
a well-made seed run will will have
fewer phenos in it so that um
most everybody who's growing it is
getting an example plant that is closer
to the intention of the of the breeder
but my gosh when you get phenos in um in
autoflower packs
you know sometimes you're lucky to see
two of the same pheno in a pack just
because they've got so much variety and
that can be uh incredibly frustrating as
as a grower especially if you're growing
in small volume right if you are growing
uh you know just your five or six legal
plants in most states and and you and
your and you really like a particular
variety and you're growing it hoping to
get a few of that same plant
and
you
either you either don't get the target
fino that you wanted the one that's you
know you know on instagram the one that
looks incredible or like in your case
right um uh this year i grew a lot of
your stuff and and you know
most of your popular stuff is purple
but then there's like the purple on
purple which takes the great photos
right and so i grew wanting what i saw
in your photographs and and i was lucky
because i got that purple
and um and i'm assuming that that you
know that's because
i was running f4s of yours so so these
were
um
uh
these were seed this was a seed line
that was worked to a degree so there was
less variety of phenos
and that's why you know if if we find
somebody who's putting out unworked
lines of autoflowers sometimes they're
fun to see all the phenos but they're
you're just gonna get more variety
versus a more mature line that like you
tend to put out where your plants are
are are more the same i understand that
right is that right
yeah i mean that's that's the best way i
could have you know described it myself
you know i put the work in you know
we'll use anvil for example i would say
it's my most consistent cultivar that
i've ever put out
it's been
inbred to f8
the first feminization of that line was
f7 to f7 that was its first reversal and
even in the offspring of the first
reversal all the femme seeds
pretty much came out the same and and by
pretty much i'm not gonna say it was a
completely uniform grow or excuse me
uniform expression across every one of
the seeds that were sold but it was very
it was very close and that comes from
that consistent working
and developing that
narrowing down
your phenotypic you know your phenotypes
to pollinate
the pollen receivers in the room so if
that's either a feminization or a
regular you know male female pollination
run the idea is matching parents
and those matching parents that math and
i use that in air quotes has worked out
to me to produce something so stable
across any seed that cracks from anvil
and i i guess it's only fair to point
out that um you know even though we used
your you as an example and i've grown
your seeds and we're friends um that
there are plenty of breeders out there
that are working their lines you know
this is this is not a commercial for
gnome automatics right even though i
like growing your stuff um the point is
is that if you want to have less variety
in your seeds make sure that you buy
from a um from a seed producer who cares
about decreasing the phenos because
there are certainly people who
intentionally put out packs that are you
know great for hunting you know do your
own sift lots of variety um you know
these these these type of breeder packs
are great for their purpose but you know
if you're a home grower and you want to
grow the plant that's on that's on the
instagram that looks like the picture um
you're definitely going to want to get
something um that has been worked a lot
more it just depends on the kinds of
the kind of experience you're looking
for
100 you know there are several other
wonderful breeders out here in the in
the autoflower realm that put the work
in and actually do the testing and
produce these generational lines whether
it's just consistently feminizing them
for each generation or traditional you
know selection male female and then
feminizing them once they find a nice
you know group of seeds that are coming
out and expressing the same there are
several guys out there with that focus
and one other thing i'd like to touch on
about you mentioned just
slightly about like the home grower with
the inconsistency and you know a lot of
these states that are legal now they
have a very tight plant count some
people don't want to invest a lot of
money into a big setup you know they're
not going out and buying your 4x4 tents
and you're six and 750 or up to a
thousand watt leds or hids they're
dealing with a very small space
and if you've got inconsistencies in the
pack sure some of those might stay
within a height of a
you know say a two by two by four
size ten that they're growing in their
closet but then there could be a rogue
phenom in that pack that literally
pushes the light to the top of the tent
and they're gonna have a bad experience
with that you know it's going to turn
them off to
seeing all that's like well there's too
much variety how do i control this to
keep it
you know yielding successfully in my
environment yeah very true and also i
think it's important to point out too
that because
the um
the lineage of ruderalis in our scene i
mean while while it goes back you know
well over a decade it doesn't it the
ruderalis lines have not been bred
nearly as much as photo periods right
and so not only are you going to get a
lot of variety within a pack generally
speaking
if we look at the entire pool of seeds
but you're also going to get a lot of
variety from breeder to breeder
because
with photo periods
a newish breeder is generally going to
take something that is already popular
or reliable or hype
and they will you know they will they
will make that cross and so they're
starting with really reliable seeds that
have got a lot of breeding history and a
lot of stability in them to begin with
and then you know it's it's it's like
you know what they say
shoot in the side of a barn right it's
like really hard to miss when you are
when you're breeding things that are
already stable in and of themselves and
people have been you know
breeding them for years whereas there's
a whole bunch of wild still in these
root oralist lines
and
somebody who is a is a new new to
breeding
they very well may not uh have the
experience or the time um to get those
seeds up to snuff and so
you know you might you might find seeds
cheaper or they might be given to you by
a friend who's just starting out at you
know growing autoflowers or breeding
autoflowers
but uh you know most of the new stuff
the the wild isn't um bred out of it
like it is with with many of the photo
periods for most of the photo periods
that we have access to and so that means
that um
novice growers are really making novice
seeds whereas
with photos a novice breeder can make
really good seeds on accident right out
of the gate
and i agree with you 100 and we're
starting to see that
with the autoflower community too there
are a lot of you know people out there
who have done the work who've put in the
structure who have helped build up this
cultivar and sang its praises for years
and they're finally starting to make
their way in to being respected as an
autoflower breeder because
for a long time i mean we we and we've
talked about this you know autoflower
was a lot of times a joke of the you
know the cannabis industry
and we're seeing
some of these newer breeders coming up
and using stuff that's already been
built upon all the work and
brings me to the point that even though
they're doing that they're still getting
inconsistencies because they're not
taking like
two seeds from
one brand you know two cultivars from
one brand and using those
to the for their breeding project
they're usually taking something from
you know we'll say mephisto for example
or and then night out i'm just using
names just as placeholders here um and
then they throw them together and
they're not getting the result that they
look for because of that wild nature of
the root oralis everybody's breeding
style is still very relatively new the
angle of attack is very different and
structural wise of what people are
looking for and i think people still
don't quite understand the mechanics of
the auto flowering plant i think all of
that comes into the inconsistency that
we're seeing from breeders to breeders
um you see the quality stuff come out
from guys who have been working them
generationally and you start to see some
sketch stuff from somebody who's coming
up and they're trying to just force it
on the community and take hold of the
autoflower wave
yeah and i actually it's interesting
that you would mention mephisto and
night owl because i would say that those
two brands are at the top of
um
people
starting with those who are just
starting out wanting to make autoflower
seeds because they'll you know they'll
take they'll take a couple of mephistos
and and run them against each other or
they'll take a mephisto and and you know
pollinate it with something from daz or
you know something like that and um and
you'll see these crosses just because
they've got such great reputations and
the only reason i wasn't mentioning uh
your brand gnome automatics is because
honestly your stuff is sold out so fast
um until just recently you know you've
been making uh you know larger numbers
of packs now and so now they're more
available to people who want them but
you know your your your first runs like
sold out so quickly you're like oh yeah
those are already sold out and like oh
damn but um but yeah i think there's
i've seen so many crosses that are one
mephisto against another mephisto and
the person is trying to get um their
favorite qualities out of both and it
just seems to be a pretty common place
for people to start it does and and
again those like i said those were
complete placeholders i mean those are
two you know mephista has been around
forever dads and i have a fantastic
relationship i love that guy to death um
and it's you know it's no tack on either
one of them it's just an example because
like
you know then there are people out there
that are trying to build from the ground
up and and so you've got like a
multitude of angles of which we do see
the inconsistency from breeder to
breeder and you are correct you know i'm
trying i don't want this to be about a
commercial about gnome automatics even
though it would be amazing but you know
it's like i do i have been fortunate now
to figure out a few more things with
inside my plant counts to make more seed
for people because i've
you know adjusted my process and adapted
over the last couple years since things
started taking off it's like it was
pretty much i had to if i wanted to stay
with what i'm doing right now right on
so i think we've hit the seed
inconsistency part pretty uh pretty
sufficiently anything else you want to
say there before we move on to the next
topic
no i think that flowed very well dude
like you know we got some some depth in
there and give people a good uh i would
say a little closer than 10 000 foot of
view on why they see what they're seeing
all right let's talk about light
intensity so you know
we're all pretty much aware that when
you're germinating a uh seed you you
generally want to bring uh you know do
so
under a little weaker light than a you
know a high caliber 800 or 1000 watt
light you just want to give it that kind
of nursery experience but one of the
things that's really odd about
autoflowers is
they really don't like the intensity of
light until they are a bit older and
i have um
i have stunted my plants a variety of
times um because i i
germinated the seed
and and i put it into the tent with a
high intensity uh bios led light
and um
and it just didn't want to go it was
almost like um
uh the the bright light was too harsh
for the youthful nature of the plant and
instead of it sucking up the light and
you know growing swiftly it actually
seems to have slowed it and and i
suspect that that has been your
experience too
100 um i have seen high intensity
artists have a a love hate relationship
with light intensity and duration
at the early stages as you were
mentioning like they want a
weaker less intense light to allow them
to come up put their first set of leaves
up and start kind of moving along and
some people may jump the gun if they're
running new age led and dial it up a
little bit more or
bring it a little bit closer to the
plant and one thing i always suggest is
like let the plant to avoid this
stunting that's very frustrating because
i actually just did it this past run
again like two or two in a row um i'm
learning some you know i'm playing with
things but like
let that plant grow to the light because
when it first comes out and it starts
germinating if it needs more light it's
going to tell you it needs more light
it's going to do what i call the ninth
inning stretch it's going to give itself
that first set of leaves and then that
main stem is just going to get longer
and longer and longer and longer and if
you notice that elongation then you can
dial up that light intensity by you know
small increments so you don't inevitably
stunt that plant from trying to push
push push and the double-edged sword of
that is once they get to that more
mature state if you want to help which
is going to be our next topic yield you
need to make sure that intensity and
light our time is there
it's one of the reasons why i um i put
in the extra effort to buy a light that
actually has got an integrated dimmer i
love that dimmers have evolved for grow
lights
and so you know when i'm when i'm
starting my autoflowers out i mean i i
had to do it the wrong way first right i
i ruined two rounds of seeds before i
realized that my full power bios light
was just like kicking these these um
these seedlings asses they just couldn't
handle it and so
i um i turned down the dimmer
so it was um um you know to about half
power
and that that helped a lot and and so
i turned it up once the the the the
gosh i don't know the botany botanical
name but the the the young leaves you
know when they when they grow up tall
enough they're low and then they kind of
like shrivel up and go away and and we
we tend to talk about them at that point
as being like teenagers right that's
when i turn it up to full blast um
because if i turn it up too fast on
these small plants they're like nope
we're just gonna stay here at three
inches forever
yeah and that's one of the big things
that i've noticed too is like if you
turn that thing up too quick your
internal spacing becomes so stacked that
like it's putting all that energy there
it'll impact your side shoot growth so
any kind of side branching that could
have been there is going to be impacted
because like the nodes sit so closely
and
you have to you have to maintain
that balance between giving it enough to
get it started and then that that
preteen or teenager stage when okay the
plant sex we're starting like under a
jeweler's loop you can start to see
the the sex organs come out i mean we
could touch on the botanical terms of
that too but for for the conversation
like when you see start to see that
underneath a jeweler's loop
and that's when you can start to bring
up that intensity because if you bring
it up too soon like you said that
plant's gonna stay like three maybe four
inches tall and pretty much be pissed
off at you it's entire life and you're
gonna get frustrated you're going to you
know
think that you failed but we're here
trying to tell you that like this
frustration
hurts us all we all do it we've all done
it and i still do it to this day
and you know even with all this
all these complaints we've got we're
still both in love with autoflowers so
it's it's really
yeah totally it's it's really just about
um uh finding you know getting into
relationship with this new plant that
has got different characteristics than
we're used to with with photos so so so
our next topic is is probably the number
one thing that people uh complain about
when it comes to autoflower and and
that's yield and um it's funny you know
before uh before pandemic when i was
traveling to conventions and um
you know you know teaching about
autoflowers and kind of banging the
autoflower drum then you know the number
one
um you know question i got or from
people was you know yeah but can they
grow big because we love growing these
monster plants and and i love growing
monster plants too the whole monster
plant thing though really did take off
with um california's
medical plant count where suddenly every
single plant had to be a beast and that
really strengthened that large plant
culture and and they're beautiful and
i'm in no way dissing on large plants
but really large plants are not really
the end all when it comes to choosing a
plant because there are a lot of reasons
why the size per plant you may actually
want it to be smaller say for example
you are doing it in a tent or you're
doing it in a small closet kind of a
shoe box grow or if
you need to keep your plants short so
that your neighbors can't see them over
the fence or if you are a
a patient with poor mobility they're
like how the heck are you gonna harvest
a 10 12 foot plant when you know your
arthritis is so bad you can barely lift
your arms above your shoulders right and
so right
so so i guess i guess clearly i went
right into defensive nature about the
yield but yeah the problem is is that
the plants are small
and sometimes you you may only pull an
ounce off of a plant which you know if
you're used to pulling pounds pulling
off an ounce is going to be
it's going to feel very lackluster to
you
yeah it'll feel very unsatisfactory you
know i think
i agree with you big beautiful trees
like monster plants
are amazing you know what i mean like
i'll get on that train i've grown quite
a few big ones myself and it's fun to
watch but it is like you said it's a ton
of work um a lot of the people that you
and i deal with or medical patients i
try to you know ooze that
energy out when i'm you know talking to
other podcasts and i'm talking to other
people or behind the scenes and dms that
like you know patient-minded here um
you know it's hard for somebody to climb
up a ladder or hang trellis or trim all
that by themselves i mean i'm
fortunately still physically very you
know capable but like when i've got a
greenhouse that's got six
gigantic plants it takes me weeks to
harvest that alone and you know
i could see the deterrent of with
autoflowers being smaller and the yields
being less than that because that's what
we have seen for so long now that it
could turn people off to it but at the
same time in the mind you're still
getting an ounce at a minimum for most
of your autoflowers these days of your
own homegrown flower that you you
started from the seed you germinated and
you grew it um i would say you know more
or not traditional but more modern era
autoflowers aren't you know you can have
a few mistakes with them and still get
more than an ounce but i could see more
yield and discrepancy especially from
the big farm compared to like a home
grower you know homegrown is not going
to have the opportunity to grow seven to
eight to ten foot tall plants
yeah that's going to be pretty rare but
you know
even though we're talking about yield
and how it relates to size
um in my experience uh
the
the yield per inch of the plant is
actually quite good
um you know you might get a small plant
but the amount of flowers you get off
that small plant is going to be on par
with a photo period plant of that side
and has that beneath your experience as
well
yeah i mean i've noticed with
autoflowers the bud structure is indoor
let me caveat that first indoor a lot
tighter because a majority of people are
just really starting to grow autoflowers
indoors um and
with the you know the intense light
hours um you know 18 or more i always
recommend don't go anything lower than
16 or you're gonna impact your yield you
know
i have conversations on the regular in
different forms about like
what if we just 12 12 them was like it's
going to impact the yield
and even though this plant may be a foot
tall or something like that
the the flower is basically the entire
plant like the entire plant puts off
flowers in every direction uh especially
with side branching and things of that
nature
so
indoor my experience has been better
structure better yield yes
i think that also um
the autoflowers tend to grow their
individual flowers together
into what many people will describe as
either like a baseball bat stock or a or
a you know cola the size of your arm you
know people will talk about um it's it's
very common for a a you know
a
a petite autoflower plant that's going
to be under three feet to be also be
stocky you know it's it's fat it's got a
huge primary cola
and and so your your weight for space is
exactly where you would want it to be
and so when we when we talk you know and
complain about yield we're really not
talking about how much flour per inch
we're really only talking about the size
of the plant
and you know if you if you have got the
you know if you're in the kind of
situation um you know so instead of
growing one big plant grow three
auto flowers and you're going to get the
same yield but you know you're growing
three plants instead of one and so there
are ways around that um
you know if you're if you've got strict
plant counts and that is something that
you are
concerned with well then that's not the
best solution but a lot of people i know
who are growing for themselves and
growing autoflowers they're just growing
them on their deck and whether or not
there are five plants on their deck or
ten plants on their deck um doesn't
really matter to a lot of folks
yeah it doesn't you know and i mean i
see that up
a lot up here and i also agree with you
too like it's it comes back to that
space like it if you got three of them
in that tent
and you've given them an indoor 16 to 18
hours light or more during the day a lot
of people run 24 hours across those
three plants if you grew
you're going to get a great yield if you
compared to growing one large plant
inside
that single space area you know it's
kind of going to balance its way out i
mean sure you got a little bit more
plant care to take care of rather than
just focusing your energy on one plant
but i think it's kind of a wash between
the two
yeah
so so now that we've kind of established
that yeah the plants are smaller but the
yield for the smaller plant is on par
with a photo
um
let's uh finish off this set by talking
about terpene profiles so
oh boy
there's so much there's so much to say
why don't you get us started on this one
so i mean i'll come right out and say
like i there's it's very hard to find
the terpene profiles that people would
consider hype but
people consider hype two different
things it may be either like some kind
of cookies or it could be some kind of
unique uh specific terpene profile
whichever it is but like with rudder
alice this is one of those nasty things
that's we're still trying to find out
is the fact that we got a lot of earth
we get a lot of spice we get a lot of
um pining
pining there's a lot of um like incense
like nagchampa smell to them like
traditional early on terpenes before we
really started you know advancing the
way photoperiods are and we talked about
earlier that like the photopeering
breeding game has been going on way
longer than when the autoflower the
autoflower scene has really come forward
and we're working diligently on trying
to improve that i have expanded my realm
into
photo periods that are that have been
grown and selected into this area to try
to source in some of those new terpene
profiles so i can get the sweeter candy
smells and so i can get the the stuff
that appeals or the gas you know i i
gave you a tester this this summer
called methane and i finally found two
outliers that actually had a traditional
fuel smell i'm not gonna say like you
know straight up gasoline but there was
a fuel like diesely
like petrol smell to these plants and it
was shocking to me um and i worked with
those two
but the terpenes they do need a lot of
work
and i'll be the first to admit like i
there's some of the plants that i have
that they don't smell that great but the
smoke is fantastic so it's trying to
bridge all those gaps
so there's some serious work i believe
that needs to be done and it's
frustrating because it's it takes time
yeah
especially on that gas smell gas fuel
you know it's very popular right now but
also it's my favorite right i still go
for that i mean i i have yet to find
actually that's not true i was going to
say i i have yet to find a terpene i
don't like but that's actually not true
i'm not really a big fan of the burnt
rubber aspect that comes out in some
skunk lineages um
it was startling the first time i tasted
burnt rubber out of a plant i really
thought that i had done something
drastically wrong with this plant and
then i looked it up i'm like oh this is
this is actually a profile that's common
but anyway um other than that uh the gas
ones are are still pretty rare in auto
flowers uh so rare that you know after
about 150 some um varieties i've really
only found it in one plant and
and i must say that i haven't grown your
methane yet your methane is actually one
of them that i stunted with too bright
of lights already so i need to i need to
take another approach
with the methane um with my dimmer now
installed
but the
the humboldt seed company sour apple
that just came out this year
they were kind enough to send some seeds
my way and
that one has got an authentic uh gas in
it and it's actually paired with a green
apple so it actually makes for a pretty
interesting plant this kind of green
granny smith apple with um
with um with a fuel taste to it but
you know it
if you are
if you're going to autoflowers to
replicate the same
profiles that you're getting on your
photo period plants
the
lines are just not mature enough that
you are going to be satisfied when you
approach autoflowers
you it really will serve you to find out
what autoflowers have to say and how do
auto flowers like to express themselves
and then be happy with that and i'm not
saying that everything in auto flowers
is watered down but there are definitely
some terpene profiles that are more
successful in autoflowers than others
like we've already said
fuel is pretty hard um but um if if you
like like the the the um
you know grape uh jolly rancher kind of
sweetness of candy smells oh my gosh
you're going to you're going to love the
candies of possibilities in autoflowers
there's also good bubble gum in auto
flowers
certainly there is great you know pining
earthy incense kind of stuff that you've
already hit on
but when i first started experimenting
with autoflowers i wanted my autoflower
to taste like the similar parent in
photo periods and it's just not really
how it works out because
not only are you adding this
you know the ruderalis genetics which
you know naturally pretty much just
tastes like grass or hay it's not it's
not a wonderfully taste tasting plant on
its own
um but it is the relationship with the
terpenes that the breeder brings into
the storyline and then has to refine
over generations to get them out and it
doesn't mean it is it's a lesser plant
than going only photo it just means that
the breeding history of it is so young
that they've got a while to go and there
are a lot of really great tasting
autoflowers um
but
you know like like every summer i'll
grow
my my photo periods and my autos
and it's usually the autos that you know
have got better
terpene profiles because they're more
mature lines but here's the thing where
i live in the pacific northwest
none of those photoperiod plants can
really finish outdoors you know it's
pretty rare um for for those plants to
to get all of their you know eight to
nine and a half weeks to finish and so
the question is you know if if we're
going to grow it outdoors
are we more interested in in growing
photo periods that are not going to
fully mature and finish
or do i want to grow an autoflower that
will totally mature and finish and do so
conveniently in the beginning of
september instead of waiting for october
not finishing and dealing with mold of
the photo periods and you know that's
that's a pretty complex answer that most
people who just say
you know autoflowers suck compared to
photos it's like well you know there's a
lot of truth to what you're saying
friend but but like where do you live
what are your needs what's your health
what's your growing situation you really
have to weigh all these different
attributes
before
disposing of the idea of autoflowers
i just finished a great purple lemonade
and um you know it's it's one of the
best smelling most delightful to smoke
plants that that i've ever grown
and it's an autoflower and it it just
wails on so many of the mediocre photo
periods that i've grown
but you know it was still only three
foot
well right you know and i think i think
you hit the nail on the head right there
man you know with the with the growth
season that we have and the location
that we're at i struggled i've struggled
for three four years outdoor now to
finish some of these photo periods that
they look great they smell great but
there's just not enough time for that
maturity you know i've grown like
wedding cake and i've grown runts all
this from cuts and cherry uh cheerio g
and i've had you know the benefit of
being shared with
of all these different wonderful
smelling photo periods the problem is
they don't get to fully mature so i
don't get to enjoy that full mature
profile of that plant whereas with my
autos i've already got them down
dried and in jars while i'm still
struggling to fight the reigns and the
molds in the mildews so
so true you just described my life man
that is so satisfying to have the
autoflowers harvested dried and in jars
curing and already like sneaking buds
out to smoke
while the photoperiods are still outside
in the greenhouse dealing with the sub
50 degree knights wondering if they're
ever going to finish at all
well right once in yawns once we break
below 55 degrees you know photosynthesis
really likes to slow down so you're not
only adding in
the the combating of the mold and mildew
you're com you know you're dealing with
a long running strain to begin with that
runs in eight nine ten weeks maybe and
then you deal down with the actual
slowing of the metabolism of the plant
so you've you've compounded issues
whereas you know
autos are done you know it's done it's
ready to go you can smoke them while
you're trying to figure out how to
finish out your photo period crop
so let's see i've got something else i
want to suggest with the terpene
profiles of autos um
um
and and i can't say i know this to be
true but i but i have seen a lot of
circumstantial evidence on my side and i
would be curious or i would i would
hasten to say that
autoflowers may have a
difficult time holding
the same smell that they have while
they're flowering i would say that just
about all the autoflowers i have grown
you know we all expect the the flavors
of the terpenes to uh evolve in cure for
sure that's part of what we're trying to
do but with most autoflowers what i end
up taking out of the jar smells very
little like the plant did when it was
alive and that can be startling what do
you think
it's funny you know
i expected you to ask me if there was
going to be one more thing before we
moved on to another subject or something
and you literally stole the the thought
from my head
i have seen a lot of what i call loss of
translation it will be it'll grow great
i'll get a nice chemically smell or i'll
get a nice very pronounced um
like cotton candy smell you know or even
a very pronounced fuel smell and be like
oh man here it is finally
and then you do the slow dry you know i
do a 60 60 dry cure enviro
dry environment where it's 60 degrees
and 60 rh and try to let those things go
as low and slow as possible to maintain
the these terpene profiles and i don't
know if it is
the fact that the plant can't translate
it well enough or if they're still so
volatile in
the genetics since the early of the
breeding that they just they're gone by
the time they go through the the trying
process so is this could this open up
another way that we dry our autos
slightly different than the practices
we've been using our photo periods in i
don't know
but i have noticed that loss in
translation myself multiple times so i'm
like i'm so excited about what it's
outside and i've got three or four
females that are in a breeding program
like finally i've got a uh multiple that
are bringing this out and like
one out of the six may hold on to a
tenth of that smell
that i smelled on the plant and it's
frustrating
yeah this is very true i i share that
experience and and for me that's one of
the reasons why i don't hold on to
autoflowers as long as i would um my
photo periods i will either you know you
know as soon as they're ready to go i
will start to smoking them right away
start giving them to friends things like
that um or what i what i generally do
with most my autos is make hash because
that's that seems to stabilize it pretty
effectively but i don't know what's
going into the plant i i don't know if
it's um you know a volatile monoterpenes
that we're losing right away or maybe
there's something going on with the you
know the sugars in the plants that it
actually cures differently than a photo
period does and you know we have i don't
think there's any science on any of this
yet which just again speaks to the fact
that even though autoflowers have been
around you know 15 20 years that um
that with the modern autoflowers we're
still just getting to know them
right you know i think we're still
getting to know them i think it's still
a learning avenue and i think there's a
lot more that
you know comes across with throughout
with the root oralist genetics than what
we think
yeah yeah i agree with that
so um you want to you have anything else
to say about tripping profiles before we
uh before we wrap up this set
uh i think i'm good
you definitely grabbed that last thought
right out of the brain so i appreciate
you bringing that up right um so we're
going to go ahead and take a short break
and be right back you're listening to
shaping fire and my guest today is
cannabis breeder dan jimmy
[Music]
there are so many seed banks nowadays
that you really have options in who to
choose not only that if you pick the
wrong seed bank you could be in for a
really sketchy ride and that's only one
of the reasons i recommend hembra
genetics collection to my friends and
listeners who are looking for a seed
bank that's hembra spelled h-e-m-b-r-a
hembra is not just another seed bank
hembra is a woman-operated boutique
cannabis genetics provider that only
sells thoughtfully curated seeds from
the top names in cannabis breeding with
over 50 breeders and over 500 strains to
choose from you will certainly find
something you'll love
hembra genetics has something for
everyone with over 350 feminized strains
200 regular varieties and over a hundred
autoflowers to choose from names you
know you can trust like humboldt seed
company night owl cannerado in-house
genetics fast buds and gnome automatics
we both know that there are other seed
banks who will take your money but have
no customer service
i invited hembra to advertise on shaping
fire after hearing so many good stories
about them from my friends
they have a plus customer service with
lightning fast response times
in most cases helene and caitlin will
get your order out the same day you
place it and you'll usually receive your
seeds in just a few days
most seed banks are simply not this
organized or interested in getting your
seeds to you this fast but hembra cares
you even get free seeds with every order
helene and caitlyn get it they have been
in the cannabis growing scene for over a
decade
so save a few bucks by using this
discount code too use the code shaping
fire all one word at checkout to save
ten percent off your order
buy seeds from good folks who will get
you great seeds reliably every time
visit hemra genetics.com today that's
hembra genetics
[Music]
one of the reasons why no-till cannabis
growing is so valued by farmers is
because the mycelium networks in the
soil remain established from year to
year and we know these fungal networks
are essential because they are the
nutrient super highways that extend far
and wide in the substrate to feed your
plants
the trouble with growing in new living
soils or blended cocoa substrates is
that it takes most of the plant's life
just to create these mycelium highways
dinomyco endomycorrhizal fungi inoculant
reduces that time and gets your plant
eating a wider array of nutrients faster
and it's three times the concentration
of the other popular brand in the u.s at
900 propagules per gram of two fungal
species selected specifically for
cannabis cultivation
dynomica is the result of 30 years of
research and trials at the volcani
agriculture research institute in israel
it has also been vigorously trialled by
cannabis and food growers across the u.s
dynamico is now available at grow shops
and on amazon in the united states i
love using dynamico to both speed up the
growth of the mycelium networks in the
soil but also as a biostimulant to make
clone cuttings more virile you can see
side by side showing the comparative
growth on their instagram at dinomyco
if you demand reliable growing results
and appreciate the importance of an
active root zone in creating a thriving
plant i encourage you to check out
dynomico.com and use the store locator
to find out where you can get yours
that's dyno
dot com
shaping fire listeners can get ten
percent off any size of dynamico on
amazon or dynamico.com by using the
discount code shaping fire one word no
caps
whether you are starting with new beds
or pots or if you want to add some zing
to tired soil choose dinomico to
maximize your plant's potential
dynamyco endomycorrhizal inoculant
[Music]
businesses everywhere are striving to
reach people through advertising we all
know though that trying to reach a
cannabis audience with a quality message
is pretty difficult
that's why many people choose to
advertise on the shaping fire podcast
advertising on this show allows us time
to talk about your product service or
brand in a way that really lets people
know what sets your company apart from
others
bold people who own companies know that
getting into relationship with their
customers is essential and that is what
we offer
we will explain your service or product
what sets it apart as desirable and help
our audience get in contact with you
it's pretty simple really advertising
does not have to be all whiz-bang smoke
and mirrors
nowadays i find that people prefer just
to be spoken to calmly accurately and
with good intentions
if you want to make your own commercial
spot well you can do that too
during these pandemic days conventions
and cannabis events are pretty poorly
attended but podcast listening is
skyrocketing
with a commercial on shaping fire you'll
reach your customers in the privacy of
their headphones right now and will
continue to reach new listeners as they
explore the shaping fire back catalog of
episodes again and again for years
a spot on shaping fire costs less than a
printed postcard per person and the
shaping fire audience is full of smart
cannabis enthusiasts cultivators and
entrepreneurs who are always curious to
learn
do yourself a solid and contact us today
for rates on podcast and instagram
advertising
email hotspot at shapingfire.com
to find out more
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire i'm your host shango los
and my guest today is cannabis breeder
dan jimmy
so before the break we
hit the first uh
big challenges that we find with
autoflowers
seed inconsistency
light intensity
yield and terpene profiles and we're
going to start off second set with
probably the most
disappointing and argued about aspect of
autoflowers which is transplanting
and so um
i'll go ahead and get this one started
for a stand so um
autoflowers are very sensitive to shock
they do not like to have their roots
messed with um unlike other plants uh
where we can you know a photo period
specifically where we can you know pop
them up as we go from um you know the
germination tray into a one gallon or a
or a you know a party cup or something
and then up to a five and if you're
going to continue up you know you can do
that quite easily and
some folks will even say that it helps
the roots to um to mess with the bottoms
of them a little bit while while that is
a debatable thing you know some people
encourage people to actually touch the
roots which is just not something
that would be um recommended
with an autoflower because
when you touch the roots of autoflowers
it absolutely
causes them shock and
retards their growth and
you know you might change a plant that
would have been a three-foot plant into
not getting any more than you know 10
inches
because their their life cycle is so
short
that amount of
shock to the root system
will never really allow them to fully
recover
fast enough in time for them to really
express themselves through the flower
um
well what do you tell people about trans
um transplanting jim dan
i typically recommend not doing it um
can it be done yes does it
does transplanting
encourage and promote rapid root growth
into the new medium yes but again with
the mechanics of the autoflower like
grow that thing in the final pot and
i've seen
you know people
who can successfully transplant they've
done a good job at it they don't mess
with the roots much
but
my my primary recommendation is
don't transplant it you know started off
in a two a three gallon pot cloth pots
work the best they seem to help develop
the root system in a manner to where the
plant feeds better more frequently and
it'll fill those pots
um you know
there's a lot of controversy on it and
and i understand that and even in the
and that goes either if you're organic
or you're in fertigation or you're using
salts like any of the methods like the
only time that i think that you can
safely transplant
and not really do massive stress
translating to
the early triggering of flour on an
autoflower is deep or a culture you
start it in a smaller basket until the
tap root drops below the bar and a
smaller bucket until the tap root drops
into the water and then put it into the
final reservoir because typically those
people are starting them in rock
you know rockwool or rapid rooters and
it's surrounded by all the hydrotron and
stuff so you're really not shocking it
because those roots haven't really had
the you don't have the opportunity to
touch them like you do say in cocoa or
soil
or soilless medium i think the safest
transplant method i have ever seen with
autos is definitely going to be deep
water culture but i'll bring it back
just like if you do shock that root
system there it translates to lacquer
recovery for the
end result plant it's not going to be
able to be as vigorous as it was if
you're in there gorilla handing
that root ball like don't break up the
roots don't sit there and try to you
know make the roots a little bit looser
because chances are you're going to
cause
unwanted and unneeded stress to that
plant
so the only solution that i have found
for
i will use the term transplanting
loosely but a solution to not germinate
in the pot that i'm going to leave the
plant in
is actually by using
some sort of vessel
um to
germinate the seed in and then move that
vessel to the final pot and so i'll give
you a couple examples
now you know anybody who's been
listening to my show for any amount of
time knows that i'm not a fan of using
peat moss because it is a
um you know unrenewable resource when we
pull it out of the peat bogs that said
um i do still have those little pete
moss um expanding discs that that they
look like a like a half dollar like a
silver dollar kind of thing and then
when you get them wet um you know they
grow up to be like an inch and a half
tall
well you know back before
i kind of turned away from pete you know
i bought like a 200 pack of those so
they still have them floating around so
i use them to experiment with
and so what i found is i found success
with um
using one of those pete disks and for
the water i use compost tea
so it's got you know some living
nutrition that's in there
and then i will germinate my seed in
that peat um
that that that peat disc that it's now
expanded
and
the time by the time the first pair of
cottleden leaves have
shown themselves on the seedling
that is just about how long it takes for
the taproot to reach the bottom of that
little plug
and
i want to be moving it over to its final
pot at that moment
and so
while you are technically
um
you know re-potting it or transplanting
it you're never actually touching the
root zone at all you're really just
taking
one pot and then putting that pot into a
bigger pot
and i have found that to work and when
when these um when these peat discs are
are all used up the the the new strategy
that i'll be using is um
uh there are a lot of uh
of these small
hemp uh starter um
containers um they kind of look like um
like the bottom of an egg crate
and um what i'll do going into the
future is i will put soil into one of
these like little hemp cups if you will
and and start the seed in that
and use the same timing and let the
let the plant grow through
the the fine hemp bottom on on that cup
and so you you get the advantages that
you want um
from transplanting meaning that you can
start a whole bunch of seeds together
in a tray without having to you know
have that many full-size pots and then
you can select the plants that you want
to have continue on in their life cycle
but that is one hack that i have found
to kind of kind of get around
the inconvenience of not being able to
transplant what's what solutions have
you found to work around work around
this dan
um in the past what i'd like to do is
double layer if i need feel the need to
transplant or if i'm looking for you
know uh transplant shock resistance is
use two solo cups you cut the bottom out
of one solo cup you place that cup
inside of a solo cup that has its bottom
still intact fill that with your
starting mix or your organic soil or
your cocoa whatever your medium may be
and then germinate that seed in there
and then
you can allow it to go a little further
than what you do as far as like you know
before like the first true set can
really come out maybe even starting into
seeing the second set starting to
develop in the center of that plant and
then what you can do is literally remove
the outer cup you have an exposed root
ball already you don't have to pull the
plant from a cup and you can set that
cup
right down into your next pot
and you know i
see it is called a tiered method because
you know you have this you know slight
raised root ball above your main
domain pot but it's also caused a lot
less transplant shock
that i've
seen like it's been the easiest way to
move or it's been the easiest vessel to
allow a little bit more growth and move
that plant to another pot without the
massive transplant shock i like that
idea that that sleeve idea is a pretty
good idea you can
but the time that it will take for the
route to go
down alongside the inside of that first
solo cup gives you a lot more time to
play with whereas these small plugs that
i'm thinking about you know you really
only have a few days so so you need to
be on your game and you need to be
paying attention whereas um you know the
the height of a solo cup is is what you
know at least
three times the height
and so gives you a lot more time to um
to
you know respond like especially like if
you're not a full-time like grower
and and you've got to like go to work
and stuff well you know with the with
the smaller plugs when it's time to move
them to the big pots like
they're not going to wait for you you
must do it whereas i can imagine with
with your tiered sleeve method you know
you've got a lot more days to go with so
so the way i'm picturing it dan
your final pot will actually have the
white ring of the plastic party cup like
like on the surface of the soil
throughout the growing cycle well that
is that accurate
actually a little bit higher um because
what the the nice thing about this is it
allows you to give that taproot a bigger
vertical drop
and with that bigger vertical drop
you've got the soil that's already
around where the the main plant is
growing so that's going to have to be
watered through your watering methods
too but if you leave it a good you know
two and a half three inches above the
soil enough to where the the bottom cup
or excuse me the bottom container can
hold the cup stable and then have that
elevated room you're giving yourself
that drop
and so yeah i usually don't go
all the way down in because like in my
brain
those roots then have to come down out
of that cup and then you're losing that
top like potential three to four inches
of soil in that pot so
you kind of want to find the happy
medium between the two so where it can
take advantage of your entire the entire
soil volume in the destination container
you know dan i can imagine that there's
some people listening who would um you
know who there who are more visual
learners who would really like to see
this do you happen to have a photograph
of your tiered method on your personal
instagram that people could go hunt up
yeah i think i might and it may be
way back but what i can do is i do know
where i can go harvest the pictures
because it was a method that i was using
for a very long time on the autoflower
network to help people avoid transplant
shock and to grow bigger plants
six seven eight years ago
you know uh it was there's pictures of
it all on there i know there's gentlemen
that's still on the instagram today i
still see them running this method that
have you know trickled over from afn to
move you know into the social media
platform instagram but i definitely can
find some pictures for it and get it on
there like to update that in content
right on so if you're if you're
interested in seeing a picture of it um
dan will have that on his personal
instagram by the time this episode comes
out and so uh that's a full dupla full
duplex
underscore afn
all right all right so um
so that's pretty much the deal with
transplanting and you know um
once you are established in auto flowers
and and
you want to start developing methods
that you think might work for
transplanting i fully support it like we
like dan and i continue
saying we are still in the early the
very early days of autoflowers and so
developing new techniques are great but
from from dan and i's pretty vast
experience with autoflowers we have not
seen successful ways to
um touch the roots and and startle the
plant
and then and then still have the plant
going you know turning out nut well
but so we definitely don't recommend it
to anybody who's new to autoflowers but
hey you know
i've got an open mind i know dan does so
if you if you actually develop technique
for uh transplanting
by all means uh publish that up and and
share it with all of us eh
absolutely you know like i said i am
not against the transplant idea i
understand why folks do it if you are
new to auto flowers would i suggest it
no i wouldn't you know get to know the
mechanics of the plant and understand
what it could potentially do to your
future yield and harvest but if by all
means i mean if there's something that
you have found out um may it be cultivar
specific
or looking over the plant and
understanding that this method has
worked for you every single time i'd
love to hear it
right on which brings us to the topic of
stunting
and um you know
there are so many things that you can do
to your plant that would end up causing
it to be stunted i mean honestly some of
the varieties of autoflowers i have
worked with it's just like if you look
at it wrong it's gonna stunt and this is
a real pain in the ass because you know
photo periods they really do seem to be
you know quite resilient right out of
the gates
but autoflowers really do feel like they
are looking for an excuse to stunt
and and i guess for people who are
unfamiliar with this idea of stunting um
that's where the plant will will reach a
point at maybe um you know somewhere
between two and eight inches and it will
just stall and it'll just it'll it'll
continue maturing but it's not putting
on any more weight no more leaf mass it
will eventually
um flower too but you know you'll get
one
nug on it that is mature and it's it's
really a drag especially when you're
buying seeds
and you know most most of the quality
autoflower seeds are you know 15 or 18
per seed so you want to be damn
sure that you're not doing anything that
um that are causing uh of stun stunting
um
uh dan why don't you run down a quick
list of some of the things that you've
seen cause stunting on a plant
i mean first of all talk about i mean
real quick transplant right you know
transplanting will definitely cause um
stunting high light power height too far
too much intensity i know that's
bouncing back to an earlier subject but
the light intensity um will cause that
over watering if you over water it if
you're too you know excited about
growing it take your time remember that
you know this is a seedling and it
doesn't require as much water as you
think it does
underwatering if these roots run into
dry patches or the bottom of your pots
dry the sidewalls are dried it's only
got a core center that's maintained
moisture there's like a happy medium
that'll cause them to stun as well
temperatures cold temperatures can cause
them to stunt i haven't really seen an
issue with high temp
causing the stunt but i think that
grouping right there would would be
the biggest set of triggers that i've
seen regularly that caused stunting yep
i agree and your temperature is a good
one to point out too because you know
we're all always so excited to get
outdoors during the summer to get our
photos here our photo period seeds
popped and outside so that we can grow
the biggest plants possible for the
summer that we get
but you know since autoflowers are are
only going to
you know have a life cycle that's you
know 80 to well let's say 65 to 100 days
um you really don't have to rush going
outside with my photo periods where i
live i'm often really tempted to take
them outside in may
but in may you can still easily get
nights that are sub 50 degrees and a
photo period will handle that no sweat
especially if you take a moment to
harden them off but that is not true of
an autoflower if you put an autoflower
out in may where i live and we get a you
know a couple of those cold
nights without a really warm day after
it um that that's it the the the the
plant will will be startled and it will
never recover from it and um and i have
done this i did this a few years back to
30 seeds ouch
and um of of the 30 seeds that i had
outside only two of them continued on
and i ended up having to you know start
all over again
um
with with new seeds and that's an
expensive error
it is and it can be an expensive error
especially if you're buying purchasing
fems i mean you talked about about the
prices of seeds recently um or just a
moment ago and you know it's going to be
frustrating you out there and some
simple mistake like that of not being
cautionary
it could cost you
to restart everything again reboot the
entire run that you're planning to do so
just try to be i always suggest people
are like take a look at your hardiness
zones read an almanac take a look i mean
a lot of your extension offices in the
area are going to give you ground
temperatures and nighttime temperatures
and just kind of watch that and do your
planning for your you know your outdoor
crop based upon those things i mean i've
been using i mean my grandfather taught
me that eons ago it's like you know we
always had a farm farmer's almanac we
always had a moon phase calendar and you
know he always checked the university's
extension offices for ground
temperatures air temperatures and
everything before planting his his
garden vegetables so i think we should
take the same care and this to avoid
that typical environmental stressor
stressor also the the general rule of
thumb i uh suggest to people who are new
to autoflowers is um to germinate on
june 1st
because you know for the contiguous u.s
states there's there's pretty much
nowhere that is not going to be safe by
june 1st
and if you start a plant june 1st
and let's let's let's say on the on the
low side let's say you've got a 65 day
plant it'll grow all of june all of july
and you are harvesting um you know the
beginning of august so most of the u.s
has got um
drought then so it's going to be
fantastic for not causing mold in your
flowers
but like even a hundred day plant right
you know i talk a lot about the lion
claw cultivar on this show that i really
like
and so that's a hundred days and so you
know instead of the middle of august
it's going to be the middle of september
for that but that's still
um
drought season where i live and it's
still incredibly warm and it's it's
going to be the best warmth of the year
where i am for for finishing a
a plant in heat you know
and so
so feel free to just you know you can
you by all means you should be aware of
your almanac just to be more connected
with the world around you and they're
fun to look at but also if if you are a
patient or if you're a home grower who
just like just wants to get the cannabis
and you don't necessarily going to make
this like a full-time mental hobby for
yourself feel free to just germinate on
june 1st because i i can't think of
anywhere um and the continental us that
would have a have a hard time with that
one other thing i want to point out
before we move on from stunting is um
[Music]
you know we get into relationship with
these plants they growing things can be
emotional
a lot of us take a lot of pride and ego
out of these plants
do not beat up on yourself if you
get a plant and it stunts like you're
not a bad person you may not have even
done anything wrong um some plants
some autoflowers even when you treat
them perfectly they still stunt
and this has to do with the seed
inconsistency that we started the show
with some plants just stunt and it's a
drag but like take it easy on yourself
like this is this is part of this it
also you know adds some risk when you're
deciding to spend 18 on a seed too
because um you know out of out of you
know i would say there will be something
that's going to stunt out of most packs
from from that you can buy um
for auto flowers which is one of the
reasons why you know
going with more established breeders or
people who have got more worked lines
will be to your advantage
if if your money is tight and every seed
needs to be a home run um
but but i also really like growing new
seeds from new breeders so i know that
there's going to be some additional
stunted plants in there and you just
need to plan for it so so if you get a
plant that's stunted you know figure out
what you may have done wrong and use it
as a learning experience but don't throw
yourself under the bus about it because
it happens to all of us
it absolutely doesn't you know you bring
up something else too i did forget to
touch on something that's new to me and
we've had a conversation about it and
i've seen it personally
is if you have a cover crop in your pot
if you are an organic grower and you're
running a cover crop and say
you're not growing in like a traditional
bed you're growing in like 10 maybe 15
gallon pot indoor and you have a very
established root robust cover crop you
could potentially drown out the roots
development for the auto causing that
stunt whereas that root room that root
that taproot can't develop properly
because the cover crop has just consumed
the pot
i'm not i'm not too proud to say that's
me man we're talking about me i'm that
person um
so so that's that's what happened when i
grew your methanes right um uh i had i
had a light that was too intense and
then i didn't realize until after the
fact that my pot was totally root bound
not with the plant but with the with my
green mulch my cover crop if you will
um i i really love using dichondra pens
well the dichondra pens had been in that
pot since it was it was outdoor this
summer
and the repens had totally taken over
the pot and when i when it was stunted
and i took the soil out of the pot to
see what was going on the thing was like
wall-to-wall roots of the cover crop and
the plant never had a chance
well and i wasn't just you know we had
that conversation because i also had
that experience uh two seasons ago in my
huge culture bed
anything that i had successfully
transplanted into my google culture bed
which has a very dense cover crop of
two to three different species of clover
anything that i direct germinated into
that hugelkultur bed they didn't thrive
at all and it was across multiple
varieties and not just stuff from myself
but from fellow breeders and friends and
you know seeds that i have traded and
then anything that got transplanted into
that bed that already had a more robust
root ball
survived that stunning phase so we i
mean both of us it was the thing that we
both kind of had an aha moment about you
know and learning a whole new method of
what could potentially cause an autofire
stunt
right on
so the next topic we're going to talk
about is topping and i think that you
and i have had different experiences
around this one dan whereas um i d i do
not top my autoflowers i absolutely top
my photo periods uh when they're indoors
but um outdoors excuse me but but with
autoflowers um i don't top them because
um
they're
there i see their life um cycle to be
too short for me to mess with like
startling them at all
and when i have topped them i don't see
them
always
develop
larger
colas on the next set of of branches
like i do with photo periods and so
since i don't see that work reliably i
just don't top them at all because i
don't want to cause them stress in any
way how about you
i don't talk either uh my my personal my
personal preference is to let that plant
go
um the genetics will speak for
themselves your side branches especially
if you're growing outside you're having
more exposed light you're getting light
all the way around the plant rather than
just directly down on the plant
um and
i've never seen the need to top now i do
know that there are a lot of guys out
there that are very successful at
topping i've seen
several plants produce colas that are
just as big as what a main cola would
have been on you know the secondary and
third branches you know resulting from
the hormone shift of the topping
but i think you have to know the
cultivar as far as like is it known
to be able to handle the topping like i
think that's when it comes back to doing
the research and seeing what
people have done and successfully done
and repeated successfully rather than
just taking that photo period mentality
to the autoflower and just saying okay
work two nodes deep
and three nodes deep i'm gonna go ahead
and top this thing give myself you know
six side branchings or eight side
branches or however many you want
depending on where you top it um you
know i think that it's a frustrating
point because i know a lot of people
that are have grown photo periods and
want to get into autos and they find it
as a major deterrent because if they top
it and it's not one that's known to be
able to take top they have your
experience where it's just like a bunch
of little popcorn all the way around
this plant
yeah and i would go so far as to say
that the the the number of varieties
that you can top safely in autoflowers
is very low
i wouldn't say that oh you know some do
some don't you need to do your research
i would say that it is rare to find a
plant that can be
topped effectively
um i know that they exist because i see
them on instagram and friends of mine
have done it and i'm all like i'll be
damned like well actually in my head i'm
like man you got lucky but but
like i also have to be open to the
possibility that these are also very
skilled growers likely better than me
and they have got a soft touch
and the right variety and and and it
turned out really well for them so so i
guess this is kind of like the
transplanting things where um like yeah
sometimes you can get away with it um
but
if if you don't have seed dilute seeds
to lose or if you're new
highly don't recommend it and the reason
why it's in like the dislike category
for autoflowers is that i i like to top
everything i think that it's a good
strategy overall to control
size and to create more colas and so the
fact that we can't top autoflowers um
you know at least yet it is annoying to
me
it would not surprise me though that
over the years as autoflowers get more
um depth of of breeding and the genetics
get stronger towards what we want them
to do yeah i i it wouldn't surprise me
if that evolves
out of the genetics in the future
i would say so too i mean like you said
soft touch i think what it is are the
guys that have been growing them as long
as i have been growing them i mean
there's a few new growers out there who
have adapted quickly and everybody has a
different skill set but like
you know
i really think it's it comes back to a
soft touch if you're new to the
autoflower game
let it ride you know don't go
you know don't stress yourself out
by
trying to figure out how to do all these
new things while trying to grow a new
variety at the same time and topping is
one of those things i would definitely
say don't do it first once you
understand it
go for it but inevitably it's one thing
that i personally again don't do i see
it in my don't do not do list as well
right on
so the next topic we're going to talk
about is uh similar uh which is training
and um and and i'm pretty much a
training novice um i actually am only
really learning how to train now as i am
developing my scrogging skills indoors
um because you know pretty much my
entire life i've just grown outdoors
because i really do prefer growing under
the sun but with where i live now
um i i you know i decided i'd better
learn about growing indoors if i'm going
to be able to provide my own medicine
reliably and i'm a big fan of being a
self-sufficient cannabis patient
so so dan i'm just going to hand you the
mic and i'm going to say you know why
don't you address the training because i
know that you've done quite a bit
yeah um the training thing i think it's
a soft touch thing uh it's frustrating
too because it can you know lead back to
stunning you know and this this whole
set is kind of like
kind of turns back to that it's just
that touch of like
being able to manipulate the plant in a
manner that you can increase your yields
but at the same time having that gentle
touch
of the training and like manifolding um
because i don't like the word main
lining it sounds terrible um
manifolding and lst
and you know
both of those come back to actually
topping the plant to get those results
if you do feel the need of training i
think lst is going to be your safest bet
like after it's grown up and you've
actually seen sex or just previous to
seeing sex on these plants you know kind
of tie down that main head rather than
lopping it off
tie down that main head over to the left
gently so you don't break your main stem
and what that will do is it allows that
light exposure to come down and those
those under smaller branches will come
up and start to chase
that main top that you have pulled over
to the side of course just like any kind
of lst or slight train you know low
stress training um like that that head
will turn back up towards the light
that's what they do
just like when we do the super cropping
outside or we do the trellising on our
photo periods outside we bend those
heads down underneath that trellis to
expose those lower branches and allow
those lower branches to catch us big
heads to give us that even canopy so if
you do feel the need to train your
autoflowers and you want to learn about
it i i would say the best method you
know methodology to go with is an lst
rather than
straight like
cutting the head off of it pulling you
know splitting the main stem out to the
left and the right and then you know
watching it work out from there because
again it comes back to the potential
stunting and also comes back to
potentially hurting your yields and not
giving that plan enough recovery time to
actually build structure before it
flowers
right on
so our last topic for uh this second set
is nutrient timing and this is something
that
dan added to the agenda that i had not
really considered because he and i
approach
um
feeding the
autoflower slightly differently
i
start the plant in a pot that already
has its full
nutrition amendments um already in the
pot and so
all i add to auto flowers during the run
myself is just compost teas
and uh you know like
k f related sprays um but i do know that
there are people like dan who um will
sometimes amend um as you start the the
flower cycle
so so this is kind of your idea dan so
so why don't you explain um how why the
nutrient timing is is a little more
precarious with autoflowers
so and i'll caveat this with container
size now i typically i'm
not typically i am an organic grower in
the majority of what i do
and
during the breeding cycles i'm looking
i'm doing fetal hunting i'm sifting
through a lot of these seeds and i'm
using extremely small pots and i think
this relates a majority to the home
grower than anybody else
again that's getting into this they may
have one two gallon pots they have seen
some really nice stuff online they see
that they get big and smaller containers
and they go out they purchase them and
they want to do an organic run and they
buy
there are several brands out there
that offer pre-made you know soil or
soilless mediums that have
heavy nutritional value in them
most autoflowers can make it all the way
through
however i believe that there's also a
timing thing too just like if you're
using fertigation
back when i was growing completely with
salts and pro mix hp
as the plant would progress i would
alternate between a bloom
and not alternate excuse me i would meld
a
grow nutrient into a bloom nutrient and
then as that plant progressed into bloom
i'd phase out
the actual growth out of it to give an
even transition of like the maturity
stages of the plant going through so as
she was in veg she got more of a grow
dealt the nitrogen levels and things of
that nature once she became a teenager
you start giving it a little bit more
bloom food to feed that that that bloom
cycle that's coming into that plant and
as she's getting more into the sexually
mature side of going into flower it was
it's going to need more of that
phosphorus and potash and things of that
nature so you focus more on that when it
came back to feeding with salts
and to top talk about the top dressing i
do the same thing is when i noticed that
plant has
got out of its fed stage
and it's into it's it's pre-flower stage
where it's showing its pistols i know
that it's two weeks it's going to start
raging into its its sexual maturity of
the bloom cycle so it's going to
potentially need
that extra little boost that may not
totally be in that soil
so if you're doing a dry amendment top
dress you need time for the microbial
life to break down some of that some of
it could be you know available ready
with the top dress but there are a lot
of other things that need to have a
little bit of a breakdown phase and for
example just like when we make our own
homemade soils we take you know we'll
take a base we add some castings we add
some manures we have the perlite the
rice halls and we may add there's some
some dry amendments and one of the
things i do is let it sit for like two
weeks before i use it
let all that microbiology get up and
alive and ready to go before i introduce
my plants to it so if there's a if you
are an organic grower even if you're a
salt-based grower and you're using
smaller containers i believe that this
nutrient timing thing is huge that way
when you're in flower you're not
struggling and you then turn around you
over feed then you burn your plant or
you harm your yield or you come back to
another impactful site of disappointment
and you know i just want to make sure
that people keep it in mind that the
metabolism of these plants is very quick
and
those nutrient needs can shift on you
before you know it and just be mindful
of that
you know another thing that to point out
is that um
you know jeff lowenfels has talked a lot
about the low nutrient needs of of the
autoflower plant um unlike like super
hungry photo periods the ruderalis
aspect of the autoflower i really
think
causes it to need less food throughout
the the life cycle in fact i think that
when you over feed them i think that's
another quick way to get to stunting
right
especially if folks are using um
any kind of very
readily available nutrient like like a
liquid or something bottled you know
whether it's salts or not you know there
are there are very bio-available organic
foods as well that just like you know it
takes no effort for the for the
microbe life in the soil to
um
you know make it accessible to the plant
and so
it's it's kind of like force-feeding
food really really quickly and so um
don't
feel like you need to feed your
autoflower plants the same way that you
feed a hungry photo period
if you're if you're just experiencing
autoflowers for the first time
air on the under feeding instead of the
over feeding side
and it's also you know it kind of turns
that into an advantage because you you
really doesn't take as much nutrition to
grow an autoflower plant for me
i'm a big fan of the the kiss organics
uh nutrient pack for my autoflowers
and um you know i i will use that mixed
with my my nitrogen of choice which is
dehydrated pig's blood
and you know i'll make sure that my soil
is amended germinate that seed you know
water and other than composting i'm
pretty much done for its its life cycle
um but i do tend to be a little more
hands-off than a lot of folks who like
to you know feed and poke at the plant
right and i will second your opinion
what i use for my top dress is the kiss
organ it's nutrient pack no kidding
everything oh it's really good yeah yeah
yeah yeah like i keep i've got a big bag
i got a bucket of it in the garage like
it's one of the i mean i use it and then
if i'm outdoor i'll use um
down to earth all purpose and down to
earth by alive those are the three
things that i use for my top dress the
all-purpose has got a really broad
spectrum
of bioavail you know like different
biological availabilities and nutrient
aspects and then the biolive has got an
even more increased
microbiology in it and the combination
of the two seem to do really really well
outdoor for me
right on so anything else that you want
to add on nutrient timing before we go
to commercial here
no sir no i think
i appreciate you let me run with a mic
on that right on so we're going to take
a short break and be right back you are
listening to shaping fire and my guest
today is cannabis breeder dan jimmy and
without these advertisers shaping fire
would not happen so please support them
and let them know that you heard them on
shaping fire
[Music]
for 20 years humboldt seed company has
been family owned and providing reliable
high yielding seeds originating in
northern california while the current
trend is to slap one super male into a
line of hyped strains humboldt seed
company continues to breed with
precision and care by doing large sifts
and back crosses to emphasize the
absolute best traits that a line has to
offer this kind of breeding takes time
talent and space to work
no matter what kind of aroma you are
particularly into humboldt seed will
likely have something you'll love if you
love fruit you can choose from banana
mango apricot papaya blueberry blood
orange melon and lemons across their
various strains they have all gas glue
and classic sour diesel lines as well of
course there are the heritage california
strains like og kush jack hair and
headband and their award-winning
blueberry muffin is one that delights
just about everybody's palette
especially when concentrated
humboldt seed company is proud to bring
to market the infamous freak show
cultivar 2 which has a great thc high
but looks so much like a fern that some
folks can't even identify it as cannabis
it's a plant that really needs to be
seen to be believed
if you're looking for well-balanced cbd
seeds humboldt seed company can turn you
on to cbd strains that actually have
flavor like the dill and pepper terpenes
of willy g's lebanese land race
whether you are looking for regular
feminized or autoflowers humboldt seed
company has the gear to make this your
best growing cycle ever
visit
humboldtseedcompany.com today to check
out their line of vigorous genetics
download their catalog and find out
where you can pick them up you can also
check out their instagram at the
humboldt seed company to check out their
gorgeous flowers and the extraordinary
freak show plant
humboldt seed company let them know
shango sent ya
[Music]
cannabis folks are innovators and
problem solvers and we like to make
money have you developed a tool
technique or plant that you want to
protect and monetize
you'll likely want legal representation
that is experienced accessible and
shares your values
plant and planet law represents a wide
variety of clients who choose to respect
the environment while pursuing their
business goals
have you invented a machine or gizmo
that you're bringing to market did you
discover a breakthrough environmentally
friendly pesticide or fertilizer
formulation that you're about to start
selling
have you bred a canvas plant with
attributes not found anywhere else
attorney dale hunt and his plant and
planet team have established genetic
patents in over 30 countries
working to help entrepreneurs scientists
throughout the life sciences plant and
planet represents environmentally
positive clients in cannabis and other
botanicals fungi water purification
clean energy emulsions and medical
applications
plant and planet helps people protect
what they've created
if you are an early stage company with
an established idea and are in the
process of fundraising often the
investors require intellectual property
protections happen at the same time
plant and planet can be your sole
representation or they can integrate
with your existing legal team and plug
in their specialties
plant and planet is made of scientist
lawyers with a real passion for cannabis
inventions and the environment they have
the scientific and legal depth to help
you establish patent protections for
your great idea
you don't have to go it alone friendly
qualified and honorable legal
representation is available to you
contact plant and planet law today to
start the conversation
email info at plant and planet.com
that's plant and planet law our clients
make the planet better
[Music]
after you've caught up on the latest
shaping fire episodes do you sometimes
wish there was more cannabis education
available to learn well we got you
shaping fire has a fabulous youtube
channel with content not found on the
podcast when i attend conventions to
speak or moderate panels i always record
them and bring the content home for you
to watch the shango los youtube channel
has world-class speakers including zoe
sigmund's lecture understanding your
endocannabinoid system kevin jodrey of
wonderland nursery talking about
breeding cannabis for the best terpene
profile frenchy cannolis lost art of the
hashishin presentation nicholas mahmoud
on regenerative and polyculture cannabis
growing dr sunil agrawal on the history
of cannabis medicine around the world
eric vlovsky and josh rutherford on
solventless extraction and jeff lonefels
on the soil food web there are several
presentations from dr ethan russo on
terpenes and the endocannabinoid system
too while there be sure to check out the
three ten part shaping fire sessions
series one with kevin jodrey one with dr
ethan russo and one with jeff lowenfels
and even my own presentations on how to
approach finding your dream job in
cannabis and why we choose cannabis
business even though the risks are so
high as of today there's over 200 videos
that you can check out for free so go to
youtube.com forward slash shangolos or
click on the link in the newsletter
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire i'm your host shango lo so
my guest today is canvas breeder dan
jimmy so the big finish set three let us
focus on
starting with fluffiness of flowers and
you know that's interesting because
autoflowers have got a reputation of
being fluffier but i really think it's
important to talk about
not only the fact that they are fluffier
but also whether or not you're growing
them indoors or outdoors right
correct
yeah so so i guess we should handle
these individually so so i'll do the
outdoor part and you do the indoor part
so so when you're growing outdoor plants
there's something even though the sun
is
more intense than your light in in your
your grow tent or your grow room
um
the relationship between the light and
you know in the plant is different than
the sun and the plant and auto flowers
just about everywhere will grow
fluffier outdoors
and you know the
the the flowers will look larger
than their actual weight
and you kind of have to choose in to
embrace that because um
because it's what you're gonna get and
you know they they smell good they taste
good they look impressive um
but they are going to be fluffier which
where i live in the pacific northwest
where it's especially humid is actually
an advantage because if you've got a fan
going
uh you're less likely to get any kind of
a a mold rot situation
or a flower rot situation because
they're constantly getting um
um you know dried out in the core of the
flower the downside of it is if somebody
is looking for those tight california
style photo period nugs
this will be this will have a different
um
different bag appeal
than uh photoshop or photoshop a photo
period will have
what do you see with them indoors dan
i see
um
them as a
very tighter flower the intensity of the
light and i believe the length of the
light hours that we're giving them
causes a different in the more a
difference in the morphology of the
actual flower itself i see tighter buds
i see better
structural wise presenting that bag
appeal that we're all so used to
just a complete morphology shift than
being grown outdoors
and you know i really do
prefer my autoflowers how they come out
how they look being grown indoors
i'm a big fan of sun grown and i think
that the terpene profiles outdoors are a
bit wider because the the spectrum of
light is a lot wider
but now that i have grown autoflowers
both outdoors and indoors i really do
prefer
the indoor finished product more as far
as like bag appeal goes it's they're
they just look sexier
and um
and i think i i'm unfamiliar with the
study but i've heard people refer to a
study around cannabis that suggests that
sun grown plants actually produce more
um
more leaf leaf weight and so it's going
to be more challenging to trim one grown
outdoors as well what are your thoughts
i agree
outdoor seems to have like you said that
that fluffierness to it than it does
indoor
um
and i think
traditionally root or alice in its its
makeup is leafier anyway but i have seen
that increase when it's out underneath
the sun
and that's what and i've seen again like
i've seen it indoor and i've seen it
outdoor but i see it more so
outdoor
um
and it does
make it a little bit more difficult to
give it that um
that mendo style like cut where it's
like trimmed down and like a brazilian
cut like a better turf you know what i
mean yeah like i prefer a little leafier
cut i like to have the sugar leaf there
i think it adds to the flour but
like it does present a little bit more
of a challenge when it comes down to
streaming when i caught you uh talking
at the um
the um
camp root oralis autoflower cup event
you also were talking about the calyx to
leaf ratio why don't you tell us a
little bit about that
so i think that is a negative side
effect of
the regrouse um not a bad thing you know
what i mean but it is unfortunately part
of i've touched on it slightly through
this episode
of something about the genetic marker of
the day neutral coming across it kind of
like likes to hang out together
um you know i was growing um
i see it as a brutal a ruderal trait
and my example for that is i've had the
recent pleasure of talking with nick
from greensource gardens about his
pickleberry and what i saw with
pinkleberry
and pickleberry had that mechanic of
a higher leaf ratio to the flower ratio
on a specific phenotype that i was
looking at it triggered very early into
flower we're talking like at the equinox
and
i had a hunch that if i added an
heirloom that i could see higher
autoflowering results in the f1
and that higher leaf ratio you know the
leaf to calyx ratio that higher ratio
just some seems to be there with root or
alice it's frustrating and
i'm working to try to select that out of
what i'm doing
because i guess seems to be the biggest
complaint from farms to home growers is
like okay so we got a lot of trim
more so than we did bud weight because
of the fluffiness we were talking about
because most farms traditionally grow
them outside there's not a lot of farms
that are growing autoflowers in massive
warehouses yet
right
you know that that
the leaf is so intense on some of these
varieties of autoflowers that instead of
using scissors i want to i want to use
like um like the like the razor clippers
like they use on your neck when you get
a haircut you know like absolutely oh my
gosh it's just so thick with um
thick with with the leaf rate the leaves
the other thing that a lot of the um
cultivars will have that um are are
showing a lot of their root oralis
aspects visually because because you
know it's true some look like rudy's and
some don't and i tend to go towards the
ones that don't look like ruderalis
because because they've got better bag
appeal
but a lot of them also um
the
the leaves all down the flower
especially on the main um stem
will look like they're pointed up and
and i don't mean when the leaves are
praying right we all know how on a on a
bright sunny day
when the plant is really happy it it it
looks like it's reaching up to the sun
and the leaves can kind of like get this
gentle cur
crease in them and and you know
we generally refer to that as as praying
what i mean is that the
the
the the leaf and the flower matter will
grow
at an upwards angle
and it's always reminiscent to me of the
throne uh the iron throne on game of
thrones um how how it they look sharp
and they look like they're going up
and um it's very it's very dramatic now
the smoke is great and the terpene
profile is great but that look
looks like there's something wrong with
the plant to me
having come from photo periods it just
it looks janky right it looks like it
looks like there's something wrong with
this plant
and it does everything we want it to do
except for
look as expected and so
you know i've smoked a lot of great
stuff that does that but it is
definitely not my preference and and
something that i i generally don't grow
a second time
right and like earlier on it like this
is that's a besides the the straight up
pointing and you know how we were
talking about how like you know you may
have a few of them indoors and they may
not be like larger plants but they grow
real super dense inside another issue
that makes them look real janky is like
once you get done say you got a nice big
fat baseball bat cola or a couple big
fat baseball bat colas and you got it
down it's dried and you're going through
you're trying to trim it up to get it
into the jars and get it separated and
you start separating that flour from the
the um
the main stem you start this when you
pull that flour out you'll notice like
the part of the bud that was resting
against the actual main stem
is kind of off-colored
and it's a lighter usually a lighter
green like if you're growing a purple
plant you'll see like reds and like like
almost under development deep inside
there because of the way that everything
with that leaf and the way that that
structure's grown is compacted inside
there that light can't get in there to
mature that part of the
part of the flower and that's another
aspect like the outside looks great
terpenes look fantastic and you start
bucking those things down and
into jars you're like okay this looks
looks a little off but it's completely
fine
yeah but it makes you suspicious it does
every single time
every single time it makes you
suspicious you know and um
if you if we had the better
the note spacing that we have like with
photo periods to wear like you have a
bud you have some stretch you have a bud
you have some stretch once they get into
flower those bud sets tend to alternate
up the flower and don't typically grow
together most modern day photo periods
anyway
but ruderalis or in autoflowers they
still tend to do that without that
offset to kind of give that flower its
ability to fully develop in it again it
just kind of looks off it's completely
fine but visually to an untrained eye
like
i don't know if i want anything from
that
yeah it's funny because that is the same
attribute that gives people the big
colas that they refer to as like
baseball bats or your arm right so some
some people are all like oh look it's
one big bud this is awesome and then and
then other people will be like oh
there's no internal spacing and it's all
grown together
and and there's janky stuff going on
along the stem which it's still great
smokeable flower but um it looks like
it's immature
exactly it looks immature but it
inevitably is not
the the actual definition of mids
actually
pretty much
i mean you know down to the point yeah
yeah so all right so the next thing that
we're going to talk about is um soil
germination and
you know one of the challenges with
autoflowers is the the that we don't
want to transplant them right and so as
autoflowers have become more popular um
it is the common suggestion that you
just go ahead and germinate the
seed
in the in the soil of the pot where it's
going to finish and so um
while we do have you know a fix for this
when i first started growing autoflowers
is it was a super drag because um
it it is more challenging to germinate
in soil than it is in
paper towel or or you know some people
hang and put it in paper towel and then
hang the bag on the wall so it's got a
uh orientation to go up but um
you know it
it's so easy for the soil to dry out
it's so easy for if you're outdoors some
varmint to come and eat that seed
um it's it's a real hassle and and
unless you've got a good solution for it
um
it can be a real a real drag so but you
know dan and i and and and probably a
lot of other autoflower people came to
the same solution
separately and we didn't realize that we
did the same thing until we were
preparing for this show so so dan why
don't you go ahead and explain the the
solution that we like for germinating in
the soil
so germinating in the soil one of the
things that i really really like to do
is maintain the moisture kept above
you know
you know maintain the moisture on the
surface level above that seed and i do a
couple things to do that one of them is
i put a little tiny like nine ounce
party cup dome over the central location
of where that seed has been planted a
clear one a clear party club not a red
one correct yes thank you yes a clear
like
you're at the high school dance punch
cup that's the best way i could describe
it you put that clear cup over it and
then you still have uh if you're growing
in like a two or three gallon pot and
trying to germinate in that you still
have a large surface area of exposed
soil to wind circulation in your room
and
soil wicks so if that soil is dry even
though you have that party cup over top
of that
that soil will dry out around that cup
and then tend to leech that moisture
from underneath that cup because you
can't put the cup down to the depth of
where it's going to protect the seed you
know three to six inches so what i also
do is i layer rice halls around that cup
so now you've got the seed protected by
a
micro humidity dome
with the clear cup and then you avoid
the moisture wicking and maintain a
level
uh moist soil with the rice halls as a
mulch so the rice halls protect the
large exposed area the clear cup covers
your seed and usually within three to
four days that seed will pop its head
right up out of there and to touch on
your you know not only do we have to
deal with varmints and drying out we
also have to deal with like certain
types of insects and said soil too
especially if you're growing in large
beds or if you're growing outdoors and
you're growing in a garden you got to
worry about what i like to call like the
roly-polies you know they will come
through and they will eat
your seedling slugs if you don't have i
mean especially if you're growing in an
organic matter
area
slugs absolutely love dead decaying
plant matter and those slugs also like
live plants too and i have come out many
mornings
to missing tops off of these new
seedlings that have come up in like my
hugu culture beds or even in the pots
that i have around there because the
slugs have found them and had a snack
yeah i have lived that hell myself do
you do you put uh holes in the top of
your uh plastic dome
i do not um i keep that dome on there
until they break up and they're turning
true to the light once they turn true to
the light meaning the head is completely
pointed up its catalans are open the
first set's starting to develop i then
work the rice halls in around the base
of that main stem and then let it
proceed with my my watering schedule
right on so so i guess that's slightly
different with me i i put holes in the
top of the cup so that there is a little
bit of airflow it's definitely
restricted airflow so that though i
don't lose my moisture inside
but i
also just want to make sure that it
doesn't get too hot under the cup and or
the humidity spikes too much so so you
know um you know try it yourself and and
see what you prefer um also um you know
there are lots of things that you can do
to creatively not have to buy more
plastic right certainly
the clear
party cups work um i'm very lucky
because of where i live there is a
walnut tree on the property and um the
the prior occupants had um
taken all of these one liter clear soda
bottles and cut them in half
and put them on the branches of the
walnut tree to protect the young walnuts
from the squirrels who love them
and so i'm not really
harvesting that walnut tree and so
you know every spring the winter winds
blow these
these one liter plastic bottles um out
of the tree and so i'll just go and i'll
i will harvest the plastic off the
ground and so what it essentially is is
a is a one liter clear plastic bottle
and cut in half and so that you can use
the top and you can use the bottom as
domes
for
the plant and so
using the top of the bottle there's
already an air hole maybe a little
bigger than i would want but it works
fine
and then the bottom i poke a few holes
in as well and so the reason why i'm
telling you this is not that i expect
that you have a walnut tree at your
house
but that if you look around through your
recycling and other places that you use
plastic in your life um chances are
you're going to be able to find some
plastic at your house or your
neighborhood that
you can upcycle into protecting your
autoflower seedlings
absolutely upcycling is always a good
thing right on
so uh so yeah soil germination is a pain
in the ass until you get your recipe
down and once you get your recipe down
um the the soil germination just it
becomes a non-issue but when i was
starting out you know um it took me it
took me two rounds to realize that i had
a problem and then and then a third
third round to solve it so there's that
um so so the last thing that we're gonna
hit on here um is is the making of
autoflowers and i'm mostly gonna let dan
to speak to this since he's the he's the
breeder here today um but i want i want
to point out that you know i am not a
breeder um at best i am a pollen chucker
but i do enjoy taking pollen off of a
male plant and putting it on a female
plant and you know suddenly oh boom
something something that's across of the
two plants that i like
well when i started getting turned on to
autoflowers i was like oh
well i want to make some of my favorite
photo periods autoflowers i'll just i'll
just you know
you know put an autoflower and a photo
period together
and
and that's when i realized oh they're
not all going to be autoflowers i'm
introducing a new trait
that is not usually what i'm doing when
i'm just you know
pollen chucking with photo periods which
are like so easy to make seeds so dan i
recognize that this is not a an
autoflower breeding episode but if you
would just give us a nice sketch of what
the steps are
to
breed an autoflower
to a a photo period so folks can kind of
get a picture of what that looks like
and if that is something that tantalizes
them well then they can start doing
their homework but for most folks um
they'll just have it in their head and
they'll they'll realize that oh
autoflowers are a different animal so
take it away
absolutely and thank you and i'll keep
it at like a 10 000 foot level that
you know like you said people can choose
whether they want to be tantalized by
this or if they want to just you know
leave it to the rest of us to figure out
um
like you said and we'll start with that
photo period to photo period is
very simple when you put a male to a
female and i'm going to talk on i'm not
going to go into feminization we're
going to say
pollen donor and recipient you take a
pollen donor for your photo period
you're going to pass it to the female
on your photo period the resulting
children are going to be photoperiod
now with that said there is going to be
a mix of genetic expression in that
first offspring
that's how the gene code matches up you
may find some nice stuff you may have to
do another generation
autoflower to autoflower if you use a
pollen donor an autoflower and you cross
it to a female autoflower a hundred
percent of those offspring will be
autoflower you're gonna get again
different kinds of phenotypical
expressions across that first lot but
you're gonna have true autoflowering day
neutral
results when it comes to making
your favorite photo
exhibit autoflowering traits
there's a little bit more work involved
because you're then dealing with those
varying traits that you're seeing
express in the resultant offspring or
the f1 of the photoperiod cross auto and
that doesn't matter if it goes male
photo to female auto or male auto to
female photo
you have to search through that gene
pool looking for genetic markers and
traits of the ruderalis parent that you
introduced to the photoperiod
so that builds upon you having to search
through that set of seeds
and then moving to the next generation
using a male and a female from that
first set of seeds to make the f2
at the f2 your numbers are going to
typically increase in your autoflowering
expression because the day neutral trait
is recessive and you have to bring it
out in dominance and to bring it out in
dominance you have to work the fellow
generations to bring it out by f3 you've
got a really good autoflowering day
neutral trait that's going on in there
and then you can kind of pheno hunt a
little bit because you're going to have
a nice mix of like fast flowering photo
periods you're going to have what
some people call super autos which is a
terrible term
um and it's basically an autoflower or a
photo period that's stuck it has some of
the day neutral trait it can
it grows up it matures it sexes and then
it gets to the stage where i call
optimal pollenization it looks like 80s
hairspray styles like straight sticking
out and then it needs 12 12 to finish
its life cycle that's still not a proper
true autoflowering
plant that we know them as today
so that f3 generation you're going to
see a conglomerate of that and by f3 you
could probably find
you know representations of your
photoperiod parent
that you want to progress forward with
the autoflowering trait so by f4 you're
kind of honing in a little bit more and
by f5 pretty much everything that you're
spitting out of the inbred line
is autoflowering
right on that's great so this brings up
another aspect that is
not pleasurable when it comes to
autoflowers which is
you know so so often during this um
breeding process we take clones and and
autoflowers do not clone properly
because if you think about it when you
clone a plant your clones are still
actually the age of the mother plant
even though they're like these new cute
young looking plants they are actually a
plant that has the age of the mother
and and since auto flowers um
you know they've got such a short life
cycle if you take a clone it is probably
going to
um immediately flower
because it's on the same flowering
schedule as the mother plant that you
took it from
now the reason why i bring this up at
this point is because
taking clones is a way to
intentionally
um
i don't know bank genetics while you are
going through
the autoflower bree or the the the
photoperiod breeding process but dan
please tell us about how inconvenient it
is when you're trying to breed
autoflowers that you can't clone it's a
royal pain in the ass
and i'll give you an example i have been
chasing something for probably nine
years
and i see it out of one line i never get
a matching parent
it's either the male or the female
so
not having that clone i can't hold on to
it until i either find the matching male
or i find another female that comes up
and i can do a reversal on to kind of
lock in this specific trait that i'm
looking for it has been elusive to me
for almost a decade now and it's
frustrating and
i keep trying for it i'm not going to
give up for it um
but it's it makes the process
complicated and
not having that clone also keep you know
the
the seed to seed identical
ability is pretty much gone until you
work all these generations to get the
homozygous expression to where pretty
much all the seeds look the same
you know with the clone
okay i can back cross i can forward
cross again i can reverse to that
you know you have so many different
options whereas in with the autoflower
world
you don't have the ability to hold on to
that precious clone that you've been
hunting through and you sifted for to
find
and
it's frustrating but to me i appreciate
the challenge you know it makes me work
harder to get to the ending result that
i want
right on i like that you uh gave it that
nice spin at the end there
so it doesn't just seem to be like a
[__] only
no it's not a [__] only it's
frustrating as hell i mean that's that's
the straight and you know narrow of it
but i also like to turn that into the
motivation keeps me driving keeps me
doing what i'm doing because i know
eventually it'll show up but makes you
want to work for it it's probably one of
the reasons why there's so many phenos
in autoflower seeds still too because
isolating these phenos without the
ability to clone is is so much more
difficult
it is and that's something as simple as
doing like an s1 what a lot of guys do
it's like they found this amazing
female through a sift
and they clone her out you know they got
a bunch of seeds they take clones at the
mature at a mature state label them all
and then flower out all these other ones
and then okay we can chuck these other
five or six but we like these two
and you know i just don't have the
ability to do that and you know the
ability to have that sitting
around and like okay now i really want
to lock it in and i want to get seeds
out to the public i could turn around
take a clone from one of the other
clones flower it out reverse it and then
pollinate that same mother locking in
that trait trying to make those seeds a
prime example of what that clone only
would be
yeah there you go
so anyway so that brings us to the end
dan of all of the things that we dislike
about autoflowers uh thank you so much
for uh joining me well actually more
than just joining me you helped me
design and put this show together so
you've been you've been involved from
the very beginning so i appreciate your
partnership in uh in making these lists
of of of challenges of autoflowers and
then going through them with me today to
you know so that we can we can air them
out publicly so people can be aware of
them and and also the ones that we've
got some kinds of fixes for i'm glad
that we were able to provide those as
well and we all know that as auto
flowers evolve um we're gonna see more
and more of these uh unsavory attributes
get under our control so thanks so much
dude
and thank you man and no thank you for
giving me the opportunity to sit down
and create this list and help build this
show so we could get like
proper representation of like yeah we're
frustrated but here's some fixes and
this is what we do and how we handle
those fixes and i think it's a very
valuable tool and some information for
people who are either just getting
started or who have been growing them
and are looking for answers and to see
that even though i'm you know we're
evangelistic about it like i still get
frustrated on a regular basis and
sometimes open my door and just go
start again
right on cool well thank you very much
so um if you dear listener um enjoy
listening and learning from dan jimmy as
much as i do i recommend that you go
ahead and you follow him on instagram
where you'll be continually entertained
with more of his tips and tricks and
beautiful flower photos um to do that um
you can either just easily go to the
shaping fire episode page for this
episode and um and all the links are
there but you can also go to his
instagram
at gnome that's g-n-o-m-e
underscore
automatics so that's gnome underscore
automatics um that is uh his seed
company providing autoflower genetics um
you can also check out his individual
personal instagram
at full duplex
underscore afn so that's full duplex
underscore afn
also this is not dan's first time on
shaping fire he was so kind to join us
back on episode 73
to go through a history of autoflowers
so if you are
you know just getting into autoflowers
and falling in love with them
i recommend that you check out uh that
history of autoflowers covering the last
12 years or so of autoflowers what most
of us are kind of calling modern
autoflowers now
because there's a lot of interesting
history and understanding in that
and then um i also since i am active
with growing and evangelizing
autoflowers you can see a lot of
autoflower photographs and information
on on my two instagrams the ones for
shaping fire the show that you're
listening to right now at uh shaping
fire and also my personal one at shango
los you can find more episodes of the
shaping fire podcast and subscribe to
the show at shapingfire.com and wherever
you get your podcasts if you enjoyed the
show we'd really appreciate it if you
would leave a positive review of the
podcast wherever you download your
review will help others find the show so
they can enjoy it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the newsletter for insights
into the latest cannabis news exclusive
videos and giveaways on the shaping fire
website you also find transcripts of
today's podcast as well
be sure to follow on instagram for all
original content not found on the
podcast that's at shaping fire and at
shango lose on instagram be sure to
check out shaping fire youtube channel
for exclusive interviews farm tours and
cannabis lectures
does your company want to reach our
national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hotspot
shippingfire.com to find out how thanks
for listening to shaping fire i've been
your host shango los
[Music]
you