[Music]
I'm not a big fan of gatekeeping
knowledge if you want to learn a skill
people shouldn't try to keep the
education from you gatekeeping happens a
lot in cannabis nowadays it was less
common before when we were all just
criminals together now that there are
some Legal Financial opportunities in
cannabis some folks have decided that
cannabis can now be a win-lose sport
instead of including everybody and I'm
not down with that
if you have ever considered introducing
a male and female cannabis plant to each
other to watch seeds be made and have
your own pile of seeds to Fino hunt you
should absolutely do that breeding is
not hard at all in fact it is so easy it
happens on accident all the time don't
let people tell you it is too hard or
that you shouldn't do it
now that said you don't become an elite
breeder without years of work studying
and looking at thousands of plants but
that isn't what you wanted to do right
you just wanted to make some seeds make
seeds save seeds share seeds with
friends and especially patients open
pollinate and preserve land races and
share those too
I firmly believe in cannabis patient
self-sufficiency and the plant wants you
to make crosses even bad ones so this
episode is for you it's just some
breeding Basics but it's really all you
need to get going and after you enjoy it
there are plenty of sources of advanced
breeding best practices to refine your
skills later but get started now and
have fun with it
if you want to learn about cannabis
Health cultivation and technique
efficiently and with good cheer I
encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter we'll send you new podcast
episodes as they come out delivered
right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week and
videos too don't rely on social media to
let you know when a new episode is
published sign up for the updates to
make sure you don't miss an episode also
we're giving away very cool prizes to
folks who are signed up to receive the
newsletter there's nothing else you need
to do to win except receive that
newsletter so go to shapingfire.com to
sign up for the newsletter and be
entered into this month's and all future
newsletter prize drawings
you are listening to shaping fire and
I'm your host Shango Los
my guest today is Brandon Potter Brandon
is co-founder of Michael fight Solutions
a group of regeneratively minded crop
advisors providing Professional Services
to cannabis and food agriculture he is
also on the Cannabis breeding team at
New Breed seed in Oregon Brandon earned
a Masters of Science in biology
concentrating on both fungal endophytes
and fungal pathogens at University of
Wisconsin
during today's episode we are talking
about breeding your first cannabis
plants making your first cross this
episode will be a great primer for
anyone considering making cannabis seeds
for the first time and others who are
just simply curious about the process
if you are especially curious about
breeding cannabis be sure to check out
episode 92 with Caleb inspecta and Ryan
Lee kamira about breeding S1 seeds then
episode 71 with Daniel Morford on pollen
collection and episode 64 on female only
breeding with Ryan Lee Chimera and then
all the way back to episode 24 to hear
Mean Gene from Mendocino discuss
cannabis breeding on the episode
entitled The Keeper plants on today's
episode though set one will focus on
common motivations folks have to breed
cannabis seeds some of the clear
opportunities there are for seed makers
and choosing whether to breed indoors or
Outdoors the second set looks at
choosing plants to cross sifting for
parents and ensuring pollination occurs
and then we wrap up the show in set
three talking about the best time to
harvest your seeds curing and storing
your new beans welcome to shaping fire
Brandon
hello Shango it's really great to be
here awesome thanks for taking the time
to join me you know um I have been
trying to put together this show for a
while but you know it really takes
um um a particular kind of person to to
do like an introductory show on breeding
you know so many of the people in the
scene who I'm friends with
um uh they may be Advanced breeders but
they don't necessarily have
um the bringing it down to the basics
for new folks level uh or or really all
that much teaching experience and so
um when I got turned on to you just you
know a few weeks ago uh I mean you you
were kind enough to send me auto flower
seeds that I grew this summer and that
and that was great but like I I knew you
just as a as a seed guy right but um
when I had the opportunity to see your
um your interviews after the auto a
flower cup I'm all like oh wow this guy
really can explain what he does and
that's when I looked you up and I found
out like you had a you had a masters and
you had been a great graduate assistant
and you had been teaching you know
biology and I'm like oh that you know
this is the guy that I'm looking for and
then and then you know we we connected
and you were exactly the guy who I
thought you were so anyway I appreciate
you bringing your skills to us so that
um you know people who are tuning into
the show to get like a like a an easy
better understanding of how to start off
growing your first uh not just growing
but breeding your first cannabis variety
that that this will be a good solution
for them so so thank you for all of that
thank you for all the compliments and
yeah I really hope I can help some
people today maybe avoid some pitfalls
and wasted time that I definitely got
into when I first started making seeds
and it is so time consuming right it's
so it's such a drag to to put in all
that time and effort and like patience
and then get all the way to the end and
find out that like something you just
screwed something up or something wasn't
right and and then having to start over
so
um you know I I've only uh bred uh one
time myself and it was for very
particular reason it was what like six
seven years ago and at the when CBD
stuff was uh first starting to become uh
more readily available uh and the seeds
at the time you know you'd buy you know
CBD seeds in a pack and they didn't all
breed they didn't all grow with CBD in
them you know there it would be it was
more like there are some CBD seeds in
this pack so so you couldn't just like
you know grow them all find your females
clone them and then have a field of CBD
because not all of those female plan
it's had CBD in them and and working
with the patients here on Vashon Island
I I could I couldn't just give out seeds
to people that that they were going to
have to grow and then get tested before
they knew that it even had CBD in it
that's not like setting them up for
Success right and so my first project
was to make CBD seeds that were 18 to 1
but that every single female was going
to show that CBD profile and so so you
know I did that and gave away a bunch
and then much to my surprise sold a
bunch and and that was awesome what was
your motivation for starting to breed
cannabis
um okay well before I just want to say I
can totally relate to that problem back
in 2013 and I was this the first CBD
seat I could get was from sohum seeds it
was Harla zoo and you know the pack just
said most plants will be CBD dominant it
was really frustrating for me at the
time because I like CBD crew was
releasing one-to-one seeds so I knew
that one of their parents had to be a a
CBD dominant true breeding line and they
just weren't releasing it so I
appreciate your work doing that
um
but uh the the first seed that I ever
made and I wouldn't you know this wasn't
really breeding uh it was just making
seed to have more seed uh and it was the
first strain I ever grew which was
Twilight from Dutch Passion and I just
made seed with it
um I've actually never I never grew any
of the seed I made because I didn't like
the strain so that's one uh one Pitfall
to avoid don't make seed if you die
actually that's really funny to put in
all that effort and then go like I'm not
happy with this I'm gonna move on yeah
yeah I mean at the time it was like I
concurrently made the seed with the
first grow of it so it didn't really
waste any time for me but it was effort
that
um you know if I knew that I didn't
agree with the strain so much I wouldn't
have done
so um you know it's interesting because
like people grow for a lot of different
reasons right I mean of course there's
just fun right there's cannabis
enthusiasts who just you know freaking
love the plant and they want to do and
try everything and
um and then there's people who are like
more in it for the science right they're
like bot but you know botany-minded and
they're all like I must I must
um I must know all plants intimately
um then there are some people who do it
in service to patients which was kind of
like where I was coming at it from is
that I needed this for patience
um and then there's uh I think most
people fall into one of the last two
categories which is to get something
that they uniquely love
um or because they need to make some
money right and
um and uh I think that's uh you know I
think people generally fall into to
those categories when you decided that
you wanted to dive in and you know
really study it take your take your you
know you know botany and and soil and uh
biology backgrounds and really dive into
cannabis
um you know what were what did you want
to create with that what was your goal
um and the reason why I'm asking you I
know that I know the show isn't like
about you but um but what I'm hoping is
is that um the people who are listening
to the show who are thinking about
getting into this or are considering it
maybe kind of giving them a little
encouragement
sure
um so I I sort of always had an interest
in cannabis I didn't know that I would
be in the industry necessarily but
um it was a goal and you even I lived in
the east coast usually in you know not
friendly States uh
so I was growing Black Market but back
in like the early 2000s and all that
while I was going through formal school
for biology and then I worked for the
forest service for a little bit and then
I went back to grad school for uh Plant
Pathology
focused on fungal pathogens and all of
that was kind of with back in the month
you know in the back of my mind well
this could be used for focusing on like
a natural resource career with the
forest service or uh Park service or I
could also do cannabis with this and
especially nowadays if you're young and
you have access to a lot of schools have
cannabis specific programs now or
classes uh and even schools in
unfriendly states are able to work with
hemp and do really cool uh you know
genomic uh Cutting Edge technology type
stuff with it so if I were just getting
into it I might uh have focused more on
that in my education
um but yeah I always wanted to work with
cannabis I was always interested in
breeding I I didn't really take many
formal breeding classes I really learned
on the job since I've worked with a
cannabis breeder and you know I had a
background genetics and biology but uh
practical plant breeding is a much
different thing than I had in my head at
the time
um
yes it's it's just much more directed
than you know I I think evolutionarily a
lot and uh Evolution still applies of
course to plant breeding and artificial
selection but the numbers and how to
achieve something on a human time scale
are a lot different is opportunities
right because uh you know you and I both
got into breeding originally because we
both saw the opportunity and the need uh
for to to to have a pack of seeds that
CBD was expressed in every one of those
seeds and so that's what you know
originally got you and I to start but
there's so many you know opportunities
right now
um as somebody who's very involved with
the the Cannabis breeding scene what are
the some of the opportunities like the
niches
um that that are just dying to be filled
right now
so there are a couple that I see
um so some of the first things
Beyond just making seeds for preserving
and growing in the future the first
breeding programs that I also started on
my own were uh CBD programs where I was
trying to get CBD dominant plants as
well and then I was also eventually
trying to put CBD into Autoflower plants
so the Autoflower generally was a
missing Niche that I saw maybe 10 years
ago and that's being filled but there's
still a huge deficit in the quality and
variety of Autoflower plants so that's
still a really big open Niche a lot of
people are moving into it there's a lot
of new Growers that are just growing
autoflowers
um and there are some great Autoflower
genetics but you know people have only
been working on autoflowers for the last
20 years intensely maybe 30 40 years
total as far as smokable flower goes and
they've been working on Photo periods
for thousands so there's a lot that can
be moved into Autoflower to improve
those still just as THC cultivars also
um smokable hemp is turning out to be a
smaller Market than maybe I thought it
was going to be a few years ago but
there's also a lot of potential and a
missing Market there so I don't know how
big of a market but there is a lack of
good smokable Autoflower hemp there's
increasing amounts of good smokable uh
photo period hemp but that's still uh
you know
far below THC photo periods better
Elites the other big Market that's going
to be a little harder for small-scale
Growers to compete with is the minor
cannabinoid Market yeah so especially
you know CBD THC are relatively easy to
The Inheritance patterns of them they
kind of function as one co-dominant gene
where you cross a THC that I'm going to
plant a CBD dominant plant they come out
intermediate you inbreed that generation
and it's going to segregate one to two
to one where one uh 25 will be THC
dominant 50 will be intermediate 25 will
be CBD dominant uh so that's a
relatively easy uh test or um Gene to
breed with for a home breeder you still
have to get that tested you can bioassay
it I guess and if you're not getting
high off a plant it's probably a pure
CBD plant uh but what's that what's that
term you just used bioassay
is that just like is that like kind of
like a
um like a cute phrase for smoking it
exactly right I've not heard that that's
funny all right sorry go ahead
yeah I I actually heard that in
reference to
um I think it was Andrew Weil and Gary
linkoff who was the Audubon mushroom
field guy author uh they found some Jim
nopalist spectabilis in Central Park in
New York and they reported it as active
following a bioassay I mean they just
ate it and helped everyone went well yes
yeah
so I'm sorry I I interrupted you you're
explaining how some of the novel
cannabinoids uh are are a target-rich
environment but
um but uh that's not just for everybody
because of the analytics that are
necessary
yeah it's going to be hard to compete
with some of the bigger players with um
you know like you're like your neighbors
at Oregon CBD seeds right like right
they've got a whole
scientific setup there now for like
intense analytical breeding that's it's
hard for a normal Joe to compete with
that
yeah exactly especially at numbers to
create a a plant that is not just that
cannabinoid but is a worthy agronomic
plant to grow uh
so
yeah that's that's where I see the major
uh Market
taxes right now yeah I totally agree
with you on both of those and and you
know if I was getting into breeding
right now I would intentionally try to
stay away from uh the kinds of stuff
that um
um like the big companies with Deep
Pockets and scientific teams were
working on because you know long and
short of it is that unless it's your
passion
um all those companies are gonna get
that stuff done first and um you know
you don't really it's it's really hard
to compete with folks like that
um whereas uh you know and anybody can
for example I agree with you the
autoflowers are continuing to be more
and more
um predominant for home Growers and
patients and uh and competing with um
with light depth and so I think there's
a lot of opportunities in autoflowers
and also for uh atypical terpenes for
example like Menthol right like sure
there's some plants that have got
Menthol but
um you know there's there's not a lot
and there are a lot of other flavor Pro
terpene profiles
um that are as Fringe as Menthol that
that people can find and and and just
run with and um I think that is
something that uh is more about uh uh
you know having a decent sized sift and
putting the time to smell it and then
and then focusing like you can you can
get to that with with backyard or or
bedroom breeding a lot easier then
you're going to be able to create a
freaking thcv dominant strain
and then in some ways even though those
are
inherited in complex multi-genetic
fashion uh something like a terpene
profile there is a limit to the
scalability simply because one is some
of these large firms can't smell every
plant and can't take care of every plant
in a way that really gives you a good
idea of what the terpene uh profile or
the the aroma profile is going to be at
the end of The Cure so even if they have
all the genomic data and they know
exactly what base pairs are in that
plant we don't really have the phenotype
data of what genes are associated with
different terpene profiles so that's an
area where home Growers are still very
competitive uh something like disease
resistance can also even though it's
very complex and for known genes the big
players are going to have an advantage
if you have a plant that you observe to
be resistant you know that's something
you can observe
at home even if it's a you know complex
trait
yeah that's a really interesting point
um these these companies that are doing
uh huge huge huge grows of thousands of
plants
um they are totally not going to have
the staff and the labor to be able to go
and sniff all the plants to find out you
know what they have that's special and
um that really uh does create a stronger
position for the home Growers
um another another opportunity that I
think there is is for short flowering
plants and and I mean short flowering
photos that are under like let's say 52
days
um because as we know when when those of
us in
um well let's just say those of us who
are not in California right
um we we buy these seeds and we get
California seeds and and you know if
you're going to grow them indoors that's
one thing because you can pretend
California in your bedroom but if you're
going to grow outdoors
um California seeds don't just Thrive or
they don't Thrive just anywhere because
most of us have got
um you know other
other kinds of weather I mean I mean I'm
an extreme example here on Vashon Island
where
um you know our our plants start
flowering around August 15th so an eight
weeker is going to be like October 15th
and like I'm two and a half to three
weeks into my rain season at that point
like there's no chance I'm going to
finish anything from California in
western Washington and so
um so I look for very short things like
the uh like there's a bunch of under 55
Day stuff from Humboldt Seed Company
where you know they may just barely be
that where I live versus California but
um but there's no doubt that they're
short and that's a great opportunity too
I mean if somebody could if somebody
could get a reliable great terpene
profile 45-dayer
um I think it'd be a huge breakthrough
yeah I agree and that there's um you
know increasingly I'm seeing people
selling
what they call fast photos which are a
photo period crossed with an Autoflower
uh so they will be they'll function as
photo periods you can eventually you can
take clones but that auto is either
speeds up its flowering time and or it
triggers earlier from uh diminished
light so it has a
longer critical night period than a pure
photo period I actually haven't come
across those yet I want to come across
that myself the idea to have a um a a a
fast flower that I can clone is very
attractive to me
yeah I think that humbled seed company
uh has some like that
um I'm gonna have to I'm gonna have to
start using that keyword so um all right
so we we you know we've we've kind of
established like a whole bunch of
different reasons that people breed and
what some of the opportunities are
um let's um let's talk a bit about uh
space and materials
um because there's a lot of different
ways to do this and anybody who tells
you that there's only one way to breed
um they're just kind of full of
themselves because there's lots of way
to do this
um would you go ahead and uh just kind
of like uh describe and compare
um what your thoughts are about breeding
indoors versus breeding Outdoors
is going to depend on what your final
goals are to some extent and what your
situation is you can do either uh if
you're
goal is to produce a plant that's being
grown Outdoors then there are benefits
to Growing outdoors and you can also
grow outdoors and indoors where you're
breeding a cycle outdoors and then
breeding indoors over the winter or some
combination like this
um
of course indoors is more accessible to
more people but again it depends on what
your final goals are and there's there's
different ways you can tweak your
breeding scheme and methodology to
buffer against some of the negatives for
either situation so
um
yes both can be done I I don't know that
there's an inherent benefit it just
depends on what your end goals are to
what degree do you think it's important
to breed in the same environment where
the seeds are going to be grown
I think it's fairly significant
especially for outdoor varieties
um like I'll give an example where
we have worked with some autoflowers
that are bred in Oregon where the
they're grown outdoors in the summer
usually when during the dry period so
like July to late August and the weather
during that period is usually 80s to 100
during the day lately and then it still
drops to you know 40 to 60 at night so
you get this cool night period well
those same Autos when they were grown in
the midwest ended up really short and
one of the things we kind of theorize is
that they're responding to
basically heat units so because it's
still hot in the night in the midwest
their metabolism is sort of still
running and they're Aging in a way but
they're not actively elongating and
growing in the same way that they do uh
in Oregon
so there's definitely environmental
effects that can have like unforeseen or
significant consequences on how the
plant reacts
depending on where you're growing it of
course for indoor breeders those are you
know the differences are going to be
minor well there still will be some to
between
and among different indoor grow setups
but it's going to be a much more
significant effect when you take an
indoor outdoor or vice versa
that's an interesting idea about the the
hot nights I think you may have just
solved something that happened to me
earlier this summer I was running a
specialty Autoflower indoors which I
normally just run them Outdoors but I
was doing it indoors and it it was a uh
it was like a really squat plant it
didn't stunt but it stopped at about 18
inches and it was Heavy I mean it was
heavy for 18 inches but I didn't
understand why it didn't
um get the height that I was expecting
and other people did well it was it was
indoors and it was hot in this this
spring here and my my nights were hot
and I bet you that
um those those additional heat units
um kept them surprisingly small because
it was so hot in the evening so I I had
never heard of that analysis before so
it could be something you know not
necessarily how I described it like
there there is a technique called
temperature diff in greenhouses where
they uh affect the height of greenhouse
plants by raising the temperature in the
morning for a certain period of time and
plants will react physiologically to
things like that so
um it could be either or both of those
things and I've seen similarly I've seen
a plant a not a flower that was bred
outdoors in Oregon or in greenhouses and
uh it was grown indoors under 24 hours
of light it ended up about a foot tall
like branched like six branches and each
branch had about a two liter nug on it
just to the soil it does not look like
normally you know it's a four or five
foot plant with normal size Buds and
structure so
they definitely are reacting differently
so let's talk about the advantages in
space between indoor and outdoor so
indoors is of course great there's lots
of great reasons for it for for privacy
and control of your environment and
maybe your breeding for indoor plants
because that's what you want to provide
to people
but also outdoor is great because you've
got you know if you if you don't live in
the city you may well have uh unlimited
space and so you can do a more
significant
um you know run with with you know to
produce more seeds at one time I was
talking to to Dan Jimmy
um at um at gnome automatics and he's
all like when he wants to bring
something to Market he's looking to
produce 30
000 seeds of it and I'm like holy crap
that's a that's a lot of um that's a lot
of moms and a lot of processing those of
those seeds and so
um
you know depending on what your
particular needs are as the Breeders
that's really going to influence whether
or not you choose to grow indoor or
outdoor it's it's it's not just one
variable it's probably you know eight or
ten or twelve variables that you have to
decide which is right for you yes
totally and that's a lot of these
questions we have to start with where
your goal is are you just reading for
yourself or home are you trying to
produce commercial quantities things
like that and that will change uh you
know how you approach the project to
begin with
what do you think about
um you know a lot more people are
breaking up indoor space into subspaces
by using grow tents versus just you know
using an entire room like a grow room
they might take their garage and put you
know you know four or six you know tents
in there and treat them as individual
spaces I I think that's a pretty novel
approach to to turn one room into six
rooms
and they're doing this for breeding yeah
they're doing this for breeding okay so
I think it's valid as long as you meet a
certain uh pollen control
threshold so
especially cannabis pollen it's wind
pollinated it moves around really easily
so
I've seen people doing this where
they're filtering usually through a Merv
filter I think anything rated above a
nine will work for pollen but probably
an 11 to 13 is better and then they'll
have them under positive pressure
blowing in clean filtered air the
problem is if you have a bunch you know
right next to each other you also want
to be filtering the outlet air with the
same filter or higher and then
with grow tents they're usually sewn
together so if you have
any holes in that tent pollen will be
escaping out of those holes you can you
know tape them up or I've seen heat
sealed tents where there aren't any
holes in the seals
um
but it anytime you open that tent as
well you're going to be exposing the
rest of the tents to pollen so there are
there are ways to manage that uh you can
build tents where there's irrigation
into the tents and you once the pollen
starts to drop you close the tent you
never open it until it's harvested so
that's one way to prevent pollen
contamination uh another way you know
that's for producing pretty much
uh commercial quantity seed Lots though
if you're devoting a whole tent to it if
you're just breeding you can do pollen
bags or an individual
uh Branch pollination probably with just
as much control over pollen
contamination uh and you know if you're
not opening the tents that's different
you have a situation where they're
completely sealed that's the ideal
situation but if if you have grow tents
and there's these you know pinholes all
over the seams and things like that well
that might still work broadly but you're
going to have a certain amount of pollen
contamination from one to the other
especially if you're opening and going
Ten to Ten and you can minimize that
with spraying water and things like that
but cannabis pollen is is very movable
yeah I think that's a good point and and
I and I think for most folks uh you know
that they're they're probably going to
start with their their 110 and their one
project and then after they have success
and they give some seeds away to
patients and they sell some uh you know
to you know friends or online or
something uh and they were like oh hell
I think I wanna I think I want to do
this some more well you know okay so so
maybe now you you get a couple more
tents but you're gonna spend some of
that money you made to get some like
really nice tents right so I've had a
bunch of really mediocre to crappy tense
and then I and then I you know gorilla
sent me a tent and I'm like oh crap this
is
um this is a whole different level than
the other tents I've been using and you
know if I was doing this I'm certainly
you know not pushing you know saying
that people need to use gorilla tens I'm
just saying that there are different uh
grades of tense and and as as somebody
decides to take this more seriously if
they choose to they will probably
upgrade their gear to be on par with
their level of Interest yes I would say
that's valid if you're producing a tent
full of seed though that's a lot of seed
like you said 30 000 uh seeds for a
commercial lot uh from Dan that's you
know you could do that in a 10 by 10
area with
I you know I'm used to producing seed
Outdoors but probably a thousand
uh maybe 1500 watts
could easily produce that much seed
yeah I agree with you on that
um but if you're you know if you're if
you've gotten to the point that there's
one well I I I'm pretty sure that uh one
tent can grow to be five tenths pretty
fast when somebody's got the bug
um so you you said that most of the time
that you are breeding um it's outdoors
um let's talk a little bit about uh
doing that responsibly
um uh I have I have no idea what process
you use but but the main thing I want to
hit on is uh folks that just let their
pollen go like into the air wild
um especially if they are in uh
neighborhoods right
um it's it's been very challenging here
on Vashon Island we you know we we did
an education campaign here
um and uh we're not running into it as
much as we did say in like 2015 but in
2013 14 15 times
um we had people that were just putting
a male plant with some female plants in
their yard and you know our whole island
is only like 14 miles long and
um you know with enough people letting
pollen you know go on the island all all
sorts of cross-contamination was
happening and I you know patient Gardens
got ruined by being seated because they
didn't know that their neighbor at the
end of the block was letting pollen just
like just like the raw dogging it out
into the out into the air and so you
know I definitely discourage people from
just letting like males go
um but you know you're doing this at a
professional level
um uh you know are you is that how you
guys do it with the pollen or or I
imagine that you have more pollen
control even Outdoors
um where you're where you're applying it
in a more controlled way I don't know
though and and and so I'll leave that up
to you to explain there are pollen
isolation distances for like commercial
seed production if you're going to do an
outdoor uh production of seed which I'm
talking like many many acres of seed
production uh otherwise you know all the
breeding that we do and what I would do
outdoors is
the plants are bagged
so usually we do all female breeding and
so we're partially reversing plants to
self them and those plants are bagged
before any pollen is dropped so they
never release pollen openly it's just
onto themselves inside the bag and
similarly if we're doing say a
production we will have it in a pollen
isolation like I described earlier with
a
um
filtered Inlet and outlet and then once
they start producing pollen they don't
get opened again so we're not we're not
just releasing pollen and if you're
doing something like a backyard and this
is another thing like you really need to
know what your goals are why is someone
leaving a male out there just you know
continuously poly pollinating his female
or their female
um you know how many seeds are they
trying to produce you don't need much
pollen to produce a lot of seed so if
you're going to do a select pollination
in your backyard I would have that mail
in a closet or in some you know you can
do it in a little Greenhouse something
like that and
personally when I have a single male at
home like this and it's not bagged I
remove all of the any uh forming male
flowers before they drop pollen
until the female is ready to receive
pollen and then I'll let the males
develop collect that pollen or pair them
in the closet bring the female inside
let them you know uh
have sex with each other and then I kill
the male immediately so stop doing
something like that or a more controlled
pollination if you're trying to get a
big lot of seed then I if you can try to
bring the females to the male in an
enclosed space and you can let them hang
out for a couple days even in the dark
just to get pollinated and then kill the
male or you could do it a couple times
you know bring them in at night and just
shake that mail all over them take them
out again
um
and you could keep the mail for a couple
weeks do that and then kill the male
whenever it's done yeah I like that idea
and and I think the moral of the story
is is a is like you know there there's
no way in one show that we are going to
be able to cover all variables everyone
might consider for making their first
they're making their first cross what
we're trying to get across is that there
are a lot of ways to do this and make
sure you do your homework and try not to
be irresponsible with your pollen I
think that's kind of like the generally
the point yeah totally and if you're
just letting your mail out there
pollinate everything you're also only
doing you're limiting yourself to one
pollination uh project a year as well
yeah that's true because your entire
property is going to be covered with
that one pollen yeah that makes a lot of
sense yeah at least well that's alive
yeah yeah right on all right cool well
let's go ahead and take our first short
break when we come back we're gonna talk
a little bit about
um this new vocabulary people are using
about bio intelligent seeds so you are
listening to shaping fire and my guest
today is crop advisor Brandon Potter
there are so many seed banks nowadays
that you really have options and who to
choose not only that if you pick the
wrong seed bank you could be in for a
really sketchy ride and that's only one
of the reasons I recommend hembra
genetics collection to my friends and
listeners who are looking for a seed
bank that's hembra spelled h-e-m-b-r-a
hembra is not just another seed bank
hembra is a woman operated Boutique
cannabis genetics provider that only
sells thoughtfully curated seeds from
the top names in cannabis breeding with
over 50 breeders and over 500 strains to
choose from you will certainly find
something you'll love
hembra genetics has something for
everyone with over 350 feminized strains
200 irregular varieties and over 100
autoflowers to choose from names you
know you can trust like Humboldt Seed
Company Night Owl canorado in-house
genetics fast Buds and gnome automatics
we both know that there are other seed
banks who will take your money but have
no customer service I invited hembra to
advertise on shaping fire after hearing
so many good stories about them from my
friends they have a Plus customer
service with Lightning Fast Response
times
in most cases Helene and Caitlin will
get your order out the same day you
place it and you'll usually receive your
seeds in just a few days
most seed banks are simply not this
organized or interested in getting your
seeds to you this fast but hembra cares
you even get free seeds with every order
Helene and Caitlin get it they have been
in the Cannabis growing scene for over a
decade
so save a few bucks by using this
discount code too use the code shaping
fire all one word at checkout to save 10
percent off your order
buy seeds from good folks who will get
you great seeds reliably every time
visit
hembrogenetics.com today That's hembra
genetics
[Music]
as cannabis regulations become more
demanding and consumers become more
educated it is increasingly important to
avoid the use of chemical pesticides
when cultivating cannabis beneficial
insects have been used for decades by
the greenhouse vegetable and ornamental
plant industry and today many cannabis
cultivators are moving from sprays and
chemicals to beneficial insects
covert has the beneficial insects mites
and nematodes microbials sticky cards
and air distribution units you need to
partner with nature to defend your
garden
whether you manage Acres of canopy or
have a simple grow tent in your home
corporate is ready to help answer your
questions and help you transition away
from chemical sprays towards clean and
natural solutions
since 1967 corporate has assisted
growers in identifying pests and
devising reliable Solutions while
providing healthy insects and mites that
will protect your yield
since the 1990s covert has been a leader
in cannabis Pest and Disease Control
worldwide and have highly trained
Consultants to assist you in Canada and
the United States from coast to coast
with their Global Network of grower
support covert can help visit copper.com
choose your country and get detailed
information that's covert
k-o-p-p-e-r-t.com
for the most up-to-date cannabis related
biological control information you can
also check their Instagram at covert
Canada
you know getting away from pesticides is
good for health and good for business
and culprit is ready to help visit
covert.com today
[Music]
one of the reasons why no-till cannabis
growing is so valued by Farmers is
because the mycelium networks in the
soil remain established from year to
year and we know these fungal networks
are essential because they are the
nutrient super highways that extend far
and wide in the substrate to feed your
plants the trouble with growing in New
Living soils or Blended cocoa substrates
is that it takes most of the plant's
life just to create these mycelium
highways
dynomico endomycorrhizal fungi inoculant
reduces that time and gets your plant
eating a wider array of nutrients faster
and it's three times the concentration
of the other popular brand in the U.S at
900 propagules per gram of two fungal
species selected specifically for
cannabis cultivation dynomica is the
result of 30 years of research and
trials at the volcani agriculture
Research Institute in Israel it has also
been vigorously trialed by cannabis and
food Growers across the U.S
dynamico is now available at Grow shops
and on Amazon in the United States I
love using dynamico to both speed up the
growth of the mycelium networks in the
soil but also as a biostimulant to make
clone cuttings more viral you can see
side by side showing the comparative
growth on their Instagram at dynomico if
you demand reliable growing results and
appreciate the importance of an active
root Zone in creating a thriving plant I
encourage you to check out dynamico.com
and use the store locator to find out
where you can get yours that's
d-y-n-o-m-y-c-o.com
shaping fire listeners can get 10 off
any size of dynamico on Amazon or
dynamico.com by using the discount code
shapingfire one word no caps whether you
are starting with new beds or pots or if
you want to add some Zing to tired soil
choose dynamico to maximize your plant's
potential
dynamico endomycorrhizal inoculant
welcome back you are listening to
shapingfire I'm your host shangolosa and
my guest today is crop advisor Brandon
Potter
so before the break we were talking
about uh you know some of the things to
consider uh when deciding whether or not
you were going to breed indoors or
outdoors and um while people can
certainly breed in any kind of a
substrate there is this interesting
discussion that's been going on the last
few years about bio-intelligent seeds
and the idea with bio-intelligent seeds
is that they are grown in soil and seeds
that are grown in soil have got a
different biological makeup and they
know what to do when they are presented
uh soil again and you know at the
beginning when I first heard that I'm
like that's a really cool idea as being
a living soil guy like I am I said but I
really don't know what the what the
reasons would for that would be like
like a seeds a seed but then last
episode when we were talking with Jeff
lowenfels about endophytic bacteria well
this is where the whole case for
bio-intelligence seeds I think starts
because the idea that there is
endophytic bacteria which if you haven't
listened to that show yet is bacteria
that spends some apart of it of some
part of its life cycle in the cannabis
plant it's interesting to find out that
the these these these endophantic
bacteria will
come up through the roots into the plant
and enter a newly forming seed and there
is
um oh I forget what it's called but it's
it's another type of bacteria which
means that it is bacteria from the
neighboring environment that lands on
the flower and so and gets folded into
the seeds
um from the branch and so these seeds
are going to be all packed up with the
bacteria that it that the seeds going to
need wherever it goes which makes it a
more reliable and people are using this
term bio-intelligent seed and I'm very
attracted to that
um what are your thoughts on on uh seeds
that are grown in living soil versus
more inert mediums like cocoa or
something
so I definitely agree and am intrigued
by the interactions that are going on
with the Environmental
organisms and the seed and how they can
pass from the environment to the seed
and back I am more familiar with fungal
interactions in that way because fungi
also form endophytic relationships
within a plant body including some
within the seed but I am learning more
about the bacterial Cycles the
rhizophagy and things like this and
there are also of course bacteria within
the plant body of the of the seed so
it's in the embryo of the seed there's
also you know a plethora of things on
the seed coat
um so one of the previous practices are
is often to be like oh bigger plants or
your seeds and hydrogen peroxide or
bleach water and I I would really only
do that if you think there is a pathogen
on the seed coat so there's definitely
going to be differences in the
population that are colonizing seeds
that are grown in organic substrates and
and living soil and things like this
compared to cocoa or more sterile media
they're still you know I say sterile
media nothing is sterile there's
definitely organisms in there as well
their population is going to be
different than a different media
different types of organisms maybe
species as well as total population
density you know I haven't seen specific
numbers on this but in general I would
assume or expect that living soil is
going to have higher diversity and more
likely to have beneficial organisms but
not necessarily you could also you know
pathogens and latent pathogens can also
get into the seed even botrytus can form
an endophytic infection in a cannabis
plant potentially and not show symptoms
and even get into the seed or the plant
the mother plant may have cannabis on
the buds and there will be botrytis on
the seed coat mostly but some of the
seeds may also be internally effect
infected and that's going to be cultivar
and path if are specific on whether or
not that's happening but
um so my point is that yes there's going
to be a lot of potential beneficial
relationships that we can exploit and
how you produce the seed will affect
that
um but it's also a pathogen risk that
these organisms are in there so one
thing to say about at least for uh
endophytic fungi of the aerial parts of
the plant so this is the parts of the
plant that are going to be producing the
seed and will potentially
uh
provide the inocula to colonize the seed
those fungi are usually uh acquired
horizontally from the environment so
it's not just your soil it's where
you're growing the plant if you're
growing that plant under a canopy of a
certain tree you're gonna you might
you're going to expose it to a different
uh
potential
population of endophytes than if you
grow it indoors or under a different
species of canopy tree something like
that so there
it's hard to predict which one's going
to be most beneficial because this is
all so new we don't really know how to
manipulate it in that secondary way from
environmental manipulation to help
inoculate the seed with the proper
microorganisms we are gaining some
knowledge of oh this is my microorganism
is beneficial and we can inoculate the
plant perhaps while it's growing the
seed or the seed
post-harvest
to help it get that organism associated
with it uh
you know they there's a lot Unknown
about it in general the bigger the
diversity the more diverse uh
the population of microbes are the more
resilient more likely you will have
beneficial symbionts in there with it
uh yes right it's not guaranteed yeah
right on a very very very good point and
you know this whole idea of
um of of bacteria and uh fungus that is
that is on board a seed you know this is
this is brand new science and it is
really strange to consider the idea that
uh different seeds from the same mother
plant will have different
um you know endophytic bacteria in it
because of where it is on the plant and
then when that those seeds are
germinated
um that is a um that bacteria expresses
itself differently in different ways in
the different plants so
um I'm going to use the word Fino even
though it's not appropriate but but
people will understand what I mean we're
always talking about different phenos in
one seed run
and and what we're realizing now is like
yeah there are those different
um variety Expressions within the seed
run but now it's even more complex
because each seed is going to have
onboarded different endophytic bacteria
depending on where it was in the plant
and us trying to figure out how
influential that is that opens up a
whole bunch of new doors you mentioning
making seeds Under The Canopy of a
particular plant
um you know or a tree or something we
may find out that the the the fungus
that's you know being dropped from these
plants in its own pollen that's in the
air might also be influencing our
cannabis plants and that's just like a
whole new Brave New World
yeah and and the ways some of these
organisms are inherited by the plant are
some of them are passed from the parent
to the seed and that's vertical
transmission some of them are acquired
from the environment during the plant's
life cycle which would be horizontal
transmission as some plants are more
prone to acquiring
um their endophytic partners and some
lean towards systemic vertical
transmission of them so something like a
there's a lot of grass endophytes that
are past apparent to offspring and I'm
really not sure where cannabis lies
along that Continuum if you can uh you
know if you take a variety and it has a
certain microbi biome associated with
its internal seed you grow that a couple
times is it keeping that through
generations this is something I'm
unclear of for cannabis and it might be
you know maybe some of the organisms are
kept and some of them are lost so
there's definitely a lot of work to do I
there's a potential here too for a
scientist if they can figure out a
stably inherited uh you know microbe
that they can sell to breeders or seed
producers to improve their their
existing varieties that's uh you know
definitely a marketable product for
someone if that's possible yeah that's a
really interesting idea
in fact they actually do that for
grasses there are endophyte inoculated
grasses usually fungal endophytes
um because grass and the fights often
have a toxin that is poisonous to
livestock so they've developed these
endophytes that are symbiones with the
grass they help reduce insect herbivory
but they don't poison the last livestock
right on all right so let's uh let's uh
cycle ourselves back um off the theory
and back on to checking these boxes for
the the new Growers so so so you know
the the the new breeder rather so the
breeder knows why they want to grow and
they've got an idea of of what they want
to breed and they've figured out whether
or not they're going to do it indoor and
outdoor and how they're going to control
their pollen and
um and so now they're actually like
choosing their plants right and and the
actual characteristics now
um you know
for for an advanced breeder who are who
are going to go
um many generations this can get
confusing very quickly
but what I'm going to ask you is that if
if we're just talking about the first
time somebody is making a cross and so
they are going to be looking for a male
that they like and they are looking for
um a female or potential potentially a
group of females that they like
um to just get this what I'll call F1
um what are some of the plant
characteristics that you recommend that
a first-time breeder look at when
considering they're males and females
so again you're gonna have to start with
whatever the breeding goal is uh and you
might have certain goals that are you
know required checks that you have to
mark off and some other that are
negotiable and there might be traits
that come up in your program as you move
along that you you know re-prioritize
that list
um but in in general for
small scale Growers
um
one of the okay so the first decision
you have to make is are you doing
regular seeds or feminized seeds if you
um
are doing regular seeds I actually
generally advise against choosing a
single male to choose a single male
properly you would want to create a
bunch of test crosses with a bunch of
different males and pick pick the mail
that actually passes on the genes that
you want which is uh quite a bit of work
you that's
how a large-scale breeder might do it
but for a home breeder that's a lot of
work that's uh I think might be better
spent moving forward in Generations as
either a half sib population where
you're selecting the female that you can
get a good read on the characteristics
from and you're using a group of males
um
or you could do uh you know
most traditionally people do pedigree
breeding where they're picking one male
to one female and the risk with that is
if you pick the wrong mail you send your
line down the wrong road if you're
buffering that with a group of males and
you're picking based on characteristics
you know are present in a female it's
going to take longer but uh long term
you might be more likely to
reach a product without having to go
back and start again
um but so for characteristics that I
would look for in either a male or
female one you want to have whatever
characteristics you're breeding for
should be present in both if possible or
you're planning on working more
generations to get it
standardized but General Vigor you know
uh
disease resistance things like that
on top of you know most people will be
selecting for a terpene structure resin
potency things things like that will be
in most people's selection list
um
so in your example when you have uh
multiple males
um in that example you're gonna have
multiple males and multiple females are
you trying to hit one female with
multiple males and then you're gonna
you're gonna sift and search the seeds
that that one female uh uh puts out I've
never I've not heard this uh multiple
males uh approach unless people were
trying to uh like do an open pollination
and
um you know preserve preserve a line
that might be lost or something
[Music]
um so I I like to work on a population
basis uh especially for early
generations of lines before I start
inbreeding uh
but
so basically why I I lean against single
males you
let's see how should I explain this
um
okay so when you do a selfing you're
increasing the homozygosity to the Next
Generation by 50 percent
if you do a full save mating so a male
to a female or one female to a separate
female you're increasing it by 25
and then it goes down half if you're
doing a half the meeting where you're
picking uh one select female mother
plant out of a population of males that
pollinated it so it's the slowest form
of breeding in that respect
but you're moving the line forward in a
more General way whereas if you're doing
the the more specific inbreeding types
of breeding that are more traditional
say fulsive is most traditional
um for cannabis or cell thing is a lot
more common now you're moving it towards
homozygosity a lot faster but to screen
the amount of lines to get the
exceptional plants will be more
difficult you have to plant larger
populations you're more likely to take a
step down an inbred line that isn't the
good step
so it's not that multiple males is
better than doing it that way but for a
home breeder a small scale breeder
that's the technique I would lean
towards more of like an open pollinated
variety uh
production method rather than inbreeding
when you inbreed you're generally
producing parent lines to make hybrids
out of and and that is going to be much
more difficult for a home breeder to
produce exceptional hybrids than you
know someone with a really large
operation
so I know that some people resist going
about their breeding projects because
they don't believe that they have got
like a lot of room
um for large sifts I mean we all
idealize large sips and and in a in in a
perfect world where you've got lots of
time labor and space that's awesome
um but you know when when a when a new
breeder says to me oh I would really
like to cross this and this but you know
I don't really have all that much
um all that much room for a lot of
plants or you know or I usually just say
just do it dude or person you know just
just just go ahead and do it and get
your first one done you don't have to
you know you can always get better as as
new projects come about for you and then
and then after your original cross if
you're going to start inbreeding well
then they then you can fine tune it
there
you talk about a lot of these different
variables that we want to control for
but but
am I right that that controlling for all
these variables is really about getting
more and more sophisticated and if
you've got you know your male line that
you like and your female line that you
like just get them in the same damn like
space and let nature do its thing like
you don't have to overthink this
yeah absolutely and this is this comes
back to what your goals are if you just
want to make say you want to make seed
to have seed defino hunt for the rest of
your life you could do that in one grow
and if you have two lines that you like
you know smash them together you have
seed and you can either move forward
generational with that seed or just
final hunt that seed forever and for
that you know especially if someone just
wants oh I just want a bunch of dank
seed and have it forever you could get
two Elite female clones that you know
you like put them together and other
people would start a seed company for
that and that's very easy if you have
access to those original genetics to do
but if you have two lines that you like
you know absolutely don't don't
put barriers up for yourself
um
it just just get it done make the seeds
and see what you end up with
there's a lot of different directions
you could take that as well if you if
you are an indoor grower and you have
those plants uh on hold you can do back
cross breeding type things if you're
selecting for certain traits in one of
the parents or you can inbreed or you
can just grow that seed for it so we we
now are talking about being in a
situation where we have we have chosen
our um you know either one or now I'm
liking your case for multiple males and
you've got your one or multiple females
depending on what your goals are and
what your
um you know how much space you have
um what do you do about the the pollen
from dropping from the mail when the
female is ready for it right because
um you know since you're going to be
bringing together two different
varieties
um you know it's entirely likely that
the male is going to be ready at a
different time as the female and I've
not run into this since I've I've only
done this once um I just I just put them
next to each other and I got lucky
um would you speak to this idea of of
having the pollen drop at the right time
um and and you'll probably end up tying
this back into the show to um your idea
for just just maybe bagging some of the
branches to collect it and put it on
later but just kind of speak to this
idea to the male and female being ready
at different times
which unfortunately happens with humans
too
[Laughter]
so I hopefully you have some background
on how long your plants are going to
flower or something like that generally
I would start the male first because
even if it's ready first it'll produce
pollen for a certain you know window of
time and you can get your female ready
in that time or you can save the pollen
generally females you know people like
to hold the pollen off of them until
they're you know if you have an eight
week flower maybe week three so that it
has enough uh stigmas to produce a good
seed yield if you pollinate earlier than
that it'll be fine you just might get a
lower seed yield your seeds might be
bigger
um you could also have the female and
male together the whole time and it will
eventually produce new flowers that's
fine as well you just have some
different seed ages
um
so as far as the best way to pollinate
uh you know
if you can get your mail dropping
flowers at the great right time or a
little bit before that and you hold your
mail in a separate area until you want
to pollinate that is ideal
um if you have to save pollen I
personally try to avoid saving pollen
it's it's always been hit or miss for me
but you can get the pollen collected
remove any flower material from there
and save it with desiccant in uh
the freezer and that should last
theoretically a long time I have never
pushed it because saving pollen has
always not worked out well for me it
always uh gets better seed production
when it's fresh
um
similarly like uh
feminized uh pollen producers especially
sometimes have trouble dropping the
pollen out of the anthers so you can
collect the entire flowers dry the
flowers and then kind of grind them up
and the pollen will fall out and then
apply that by hand that works
all right I it's always preferable that
the pollen just drops and it's less work
and everything works out all right
but usually I would just uh
get rid of the mail as soon as you
pollinate unless you're leaving it in a
tent or something like that and letting
it go until Harvest
yeah I agree with you about saving
pollen uh I have found that most the
time when I've done that
um it gets it gets moist in rots or it
starts to Clump on the female flower
when I go to apply it so
um you know this is you know in
retrospect this is pretty cheesy but um
when I when I did my cross I literally
wrapped the mail into the the female
plants
um and put them on a um
uh on on my deck in a uh in a tent and
just uh you know let them let them do it
and naturally and I got lucky because I
didn't have to save it um but you know
there's a lot of people who save pollen
successfully and there are certainly
ways to do it
um but you know since we're talking
about somebody doing this for their
first time
um we want to try to continually keep
this as as simple as possible
um where in the in the process do you
normally add the pollen to the female
print and when I say process I mean like
where in the in the flowering cycle do
you want to
um um you know encourage the pollen uh
immediately as soon as you start to see
pistols or do do you want to wait until
the flowers are are more mature uh so
generally I would wait until the flowers
are a little more mature however it
depending on your situation if there is
potential for say pollen contamination
you you might want to get that pollen
all over the branch or plant that you're
making so that if there is a few pollen
grains from a you know fiber hemp grow a
couple miles away blowing around there
you've already fully pollinated with
your plant uh with your preferred pollen
source to limit a potential
contamination otherwise I would wait
until there's a little more flour and
you get better seed yields right on so
um how do you know that you have
effectively pollinated your plants a lot
of first-time uh breeders you know
they'll they'll either you know add the
pollen themselves or put them near each
other and they're hoping for it and then
and then because you know they don't
have a lot of experience they're all
like did it did it do it you know so
what are what are the first visual signs
that the plant has
um accepted the pollen successfully yeah
sometimes it can be hard to tell
um and generally the first things that
you'll see is that the pistols kind of
start to turn brown this can also just
happen by touching them so if you
touched them it might just turn brown
because you touched them but it's it's
it kind of becomes distinctive once you
get an eye for it it's like a certain
way that the the pistol shrivels back
and then pretty soon within a week maybe
you can see uh of you'll start to
develop into a seed through the bract at
what point like will will they start to
see seeds form like I know that we'll
talk more about how long to let the
seeds to run and mature during the down
the line in this conversation but when
will they start seeing the the green uh
very young seeds start to form it's a
little bit plant dependent depending how
like uh the structure of their brachial
that's surrounding what's going to
become the seed but as as soon as a week
I can see them sometimes and they
usually appear white at first and the
pistols still are attached uh you kind
of can see them poking out sometimes
um you know you hit on feminized seeds
uh briefly and I want to go back to that
for one moment so you know this show is
not about uh you know breeding or you
know making feminized seeds and their
importance we've done that on other
shows but but I would just like you to
speak to the idea of of the first time
breeder considering whether or not they
want to make feminized seeds just walk
us through like you know what those
considerations might be for the first
time breeder yeah so there's definitely
positives and negatives the the first
positive for a growing female only like
a female only breeding project is that
you're getting a read on both sides of
whatever cross you're going to make so
you can make more effective selections
uh the the major drawback to feminine
seed especially for home producers is
that it's less reliable and that some
some plants don't reverse as well and
you're more likely to have a pollen
failure you can have a nicking failure
where like you know especially you
mentioned earlier about getting the male
flowers at the right time as the female
is ready you know if you have a short
flowering indica and you're trying to
cross that to a long flowering tropical
variety
you might want to have the short
flowering variety be the pollen donor or
you're going to have to flour that long
flowering variety far before the short
flouring variety because you could you
know you could trigger a tropical
variety and it doesn't produce pollen
for another eight weeks meanwhile the
other plant's done
um
so with feminized seed you're more
likely to get of pollen failure like I
mentioned where either you're going to
have to put extra work into collecting
the flour and helping that pollen Escape
or it just doesn't produce very viable
pollen and you get lower seed yields so
and you don't want to be if you're
having a long-term breeding project if
you're having pollination issues from
the beginning that's a red flag so some
varieties are going to be better as
regular varieties for for breeding
because of that for home breeders
um or seed seed producers but as far as
functionality like you know
feminized seed isn't genetically
modified or anything like that as far as
I'm aware there is no functional
difference in the plants that are grown
from it you can breed female
feminized seed to regular seed you can
breed feminized seed only for
Generations that's fine so
yeah those those are the major drawback
I see about feminine seed is pollen
production and
you have to understand at least some
about the technology of how to reverse a
plant which is pretty accessible
nowadays all right
um so let's go ahead and take our second
uh short break when we come back we're
going to talk about uh judging when to
uh collect the seeds and harvest them
handling them and and and prepping them
for whatever you're going to do next
um you are listening to shaping fire and
my guest today is crop advisor Brandon
Potter
[Music]
once you've discovered the benefits of
using cannabis it's a very small step to
start making your own Edibles gummies
lotions tinctures and concentrated oils
at home
magical butter has been helping cannabis
consumers become self-sufficient for
over a decade with the easy to use
magical butter countertop Botanical
extractor you can create high quality
cannabis products to your exact
specifications at a fraction of the cost
of store-bought edibles
I talk a lot on this show about the
importance of Home growing so you don't
have to rely on others to feel healthy
well the magical butter machine can
Empower your personal health by putting
you in control of how you use cannabis
in your daily life
I've been making my own Butters and oils
on the stove for years and I much prefer
the ease of using the magical butter
machine I just set it and walk away with
the Simple Touch of a button the magical
butter machine grinds Heats stirs and
Steeps your herbal extract all at the
correct time interval and temperature
for the perfect infusion every time as a
result you achieve your desired infusion
easily safely and consistently check out
the magical butter Instagram to see the
machine in action and don't feel like
you have to go It Alone there is a huge
community on Facebook called magical
butter users United sharing recipes and
best practices so you can learn at your
own pace from others who are already
doing it successfully now is the time to
get your own magical butter machine and
save money while enjoying cannabis use
the discount code shaping fire one word
no caps to get 10 off visit
magicalbutter.com today
[Music]
one of the challenges with buying
Autoflower seeds is that often you'll
have as many different phenos as you
will have seeds in a pack that can be
fun sure but so many varieties in one
pack is a sign of an immature seed line
that hasn't been worked enough
I prefer my auto flowers to be worked
enough that each Fino in the pack really
captures the aspects that the breeder
was intending
this is why I recommend gnome automatics
to my friends and listeners who grow
automatic flowering cannabis seeds
gnome automatic seeds are not just
crossed and released they are
painstakingly sifted again and again
tested at a wide range of conditions and
taken to a level of maturity that each
plant will be recognizable by its traits
traits that were hard earned so that you
can have your best growth cycle ever
gnome automatics became a trusted and
loved brand in cannabis over the last 10
years as Mandalorian genetics and
recently changed their name to gnome
automatics
the only thing that has changed is the
name founder Dan Jimmy continues to pour
His passion of breeding cannabis into
every variety he releases for you to
grow
check out the gnome automatics Instagram
at gnome underscore automatics to see
the impressive plants folks are growing
you can score gnome automatic seeds in
feminized or regular at your favorite
seed provider listed in the vendors
section of their website Farms
interested in bulk seeds of more than a
thousand should reach out through the
website too
while on the website be sure to check
out the gnome automatic shirts and other
merch section
if you want reliable seeds hand built
from effort expert selection and
experience choose gnome automatics
[Music]
for decades Americans have enjoyed
cannabis flowers and joints and bongs
and bowls and now with the normalization
of cannabis use increasing across the
country we have the opportunity to enjoy
smoking cannabis luxuries that simply
were not attainable before
North Coast hand rolls blunts cannons
rosin infused donuts and canagars
available in the state of Michigan
North Coast focuses on Flavor over
everything else instead of growing their
own flower North Coast goes out into the
cultivation community and creates
relationships with the best Growers
working with the best new cannabis
varieties available surely heavy THC is
a factor but North Coast focuses on
Aroma complex terpene profiles and taste
that continues throughout the entire
smoking experience the North Coast team
curates flowers like others curate art
they seek out the best talent build
relationships helps them take their
product to the highest levels and then
buys their well-cured flowers in order
to hand roll them just for you I really
like their hand blown glass tips
and North Coast has branched out Beyond
canigars into rosin solventless thca
diamonds and exceptional hash rosin
carts for on-the-go cannabis
connoisseurs too
North Coast provides you with attainable
luxury offering you an Ultra Premium
smoking experience at a price that seems
reasonable and repeatable
to find out more about North Coastline
of cannabis products visit their
Instagram at
northcoast.rolling that's North
coast.rolling and when in Michigan ask
for North Coast at your favorite Shop
North Coast
welcome back you are listening to
shapingfire I'm your host shangolos and
my guest today is crop advisor Brandon
Potter so here we are at the big finish
so um now we've got plants that have got
seeds in them we have successfully uh
pollinated and we are uh so grateful to
have reached this point with the plant
um you know Chances Are by the time
somebody is at this point they have
already grown cannabis before so they
know how to successfully grow and
harvest cannabis in your experience are
there any other particular care
instructions that are different than
growing a regular plant when you're
growing for seed
um uh I'm thinking like you know
different uh you know different
nutrients that you would normally use or
different or different light or I don't
know anything is there anything
different when a seed is being grown for
excuse me when a plant is being grown
for seed than when we're just uh growing
it for smokable usable flower
um so generally I would give it more of
a veg nutrient type profile through its
entire life than if I were smoking for
flour and I wouldn't do any type of
flushing or anything like that you want
the plant to kind of finesse on its own
not because it's being starved of any
nutrients
um other than that it's it's pretty
similar to Growing for flour around so
for a lot of folks you know the the the
trying to figure out when to harvest is
one of the more challenging aspects
because
um for many people if they're doing
photos
um you know people a lot of people are
just looking for uh the you know a 20
percent ish ish of trichomes that have
gone Amber and of course you know when
you're when you're a more
experienced uh cultivator you will know
how to recognize swollen flowers and the
color changes and you know the change in
the pistols and all these extra things
but really
um the first rule of thumb that that
most novice cultivators go with is the
is the 20
Amber trichomes unless it's an
Autoflower which which don't really
Amber up the same way
um what do you look for when deciding
when to
um to harvest the seeds because you know
we've all gotten seeds that didn't look
like they had finished maturing and uh
you know for for many seed varieties
we're looking for you know a darkened
seed potentially with you know striping
on it depending on what kind of a plant
it is but uh but we've all bought seed
packs that that looks like the seeds
were not mature and we're like keeping
our fingers crossed uh when we that they
that they germinate so so what do you
look for what in considerations when
you're judging when to when to pull the
plant down
so basically it I base it on time from
when I know pollination occurred as well
as I usually dig out a couple seeds and
squeeze them see how full they are how
mature they are uh of course they're
sacrificing those seeds
um but it should also be noted that a
lot of seed the color of seed and the
striping on seed is really variety
dependent the of course if you have a
seed that's supposed to be brown and
it's tiger striped and it's it's white
then it's probably immature uh but you
know like the variety freak show has
notoriously
light colored seeds that are kind of
misshapen
but that's all they ever do even if you
let them go forever but generally I you
want to be able to squeeze a seed and
have it you know be resistant full of an
embryo when you squeeze it you'll see a
now dead or dying embryo pop out of it
uh you should be able to see like the
completely formed Little Radical and
things like that
um and it should it should start to be
getting a hard seed coat it wants the
you know you do do a few tests like that
when the majority of seeds are like that
uh you're probably good to go it doesn't
hurt to let it go over I've heard people
claim you know it's you can get over
mature seed I really don't think that's
a thing
um
the especially if you're cleaning your
seed at the end of it you might get a
lighter seed and things like that that
will blow off
when you're cleaning it
um you said that uh one of the
um one of the things you use to judge
when to pull the seeds you said you know
days from uh pollination so
um like dig into that a little bit more
if you would uh do you are you looking
for a particular number of days or a
certain number of days in relationship
to how long the bloom cycle is supposed
to be for this particular female like
give us a little more on that
usually I use the same time frame
regardless of the variety and I haven't
I haven't produced seeds on any you know
16 week varieties so I can't say it's
necessarily true for that but I think
that it would still apply and that there
would even if you pollinate based on
this time frame there would be a mature
seed sitting in there for you know 10
weeks or whatever but uh
so
I would say two weeks is the absolute
minimum to get viable seed if you're
trying to do something really fast
uh preferably you wanna
let it go at least four weeks and six
weeks is better so if I can let
something go at least six weeks and then
start looking at it sometimes it'll be
just completely finished uh at four
weeks and you don't really need that
extra two weeks but
um I I don't think it hurts to let it go
over unless you have something like but
right it's happening and that'll start
infecting and eating your seeds there's
really no harm in letting it over mature
let me push on this a little bit so you
said um you know six weeks two two is
minimum six would be Optimum now uh if
if we are going to pollinate our our
plant you know a week or two into the
flowering cycle that kind of lines up
with an eight-week plant which is you
know give or take that's it's a pretty
common uh Bloom cycle so it could be
unless you're doing a specialty plant or
something that has an especially long
flowering cycle that
um you might want to pull those seeds
just simply when the flowers are done is
is that
um am I is that oversimplified
you're saying that
you you might be pulling them earlier
than six weeks everybody no no I'm
suggesting that if if you if you're if
your plan is going to start to flower
and then you pollinate it at like you
know somewhere between week one and two
of the flowering process and then you
said you know you want a minimum of two
weeks for pro but more like six weeks to
put forward to allow for this all the
seeds to mature when you add those two
weeks and the six weeks you're at eight
weeks which is like one of the most
common Bloom cycles for cannabis plants
so it's it's sounding sounding like uh
in in many or if not most cases
um it's not really a different time to
pull the seeds as it is just when you
would pull the flowers normally
yeah completely so it's it'd be very
convenient you know if you have like a
under branch that you pollinated but you
still want the flour from that plant you
can usually just Harvest them at the
same time if I do pollinate something
especially if it's later in the cycle of
something that I know I'm going to cut
down for flour then I'll pick a lower
branch and you can kind of leave that
lower Branch alive and let the seeds
mature a couple weeks longer say you
have an eight week flour you pollinate
it week four or five then you want to
let it go beyond where you would flower
or harvest for a flower
yeah I you know the one time I did this
I intentionally just let it go until
um uh
until I was a good two weeks beyond the
when I would have flowered it because I
was so concerned about
um
the seeds not fully maturing and
ripening and I would have gone through
all this you know effort for nothing
um and then so so this this eight week
plan I was looking to harvest it at week
um and then I was surprised it actually
just started dropping the seeds onto the
ground and I'm all like oh well I would
say that that's probably like the most
sure sign I'm going to get but it's
possible I was misreading that sign what
what stage are we at when the plant is
actually literally dropping seeds into
the pot or on the ground
and I mean that's you know it depends
what
varieties you're working with that's in
you know kind of atavistic trait where
it's ancestrally wild cannabis plants
will shatter and drop their seeds a lot
more readily than the domesticated
varieties uh so if you have a plant like
that yeah you want to harvest it before
it drops its seed if it's dropping its
seed they're definitely ready that's
really the only that and say if you're
outdoors and it's getting rained on I've
seen uh seed germinating in colas before
um
so
you want to avoid those kind of
negatives to letting it go too long but
otherwise there's not a harm to that and
if you you know if you collected had a
plastic piece of plastic under the plant
collected those seeds they'd be fine
right on so so all right so so we're in
this situation the the seeds are
dropping from the plant
um if if some are dropping chances are
your vast majority of them are mature
and ready to rock
um uh do you have any best practices for
harvesting a seeded plant that is you
know dropping seeds because uh you know
certainly we want to we want to be more
gentle with this plant because we don't
want to be dropping the seeds all over
all over the room so
um you know I just cut it and put it in
a bag like right then and there so
there's as little motion as possible
um what do you do that's that's exactly
what I would do if it's a big area of
seed production I'd lay down plastic
before I start cutting plants down and
then collect uh the Fallen seed as well
um but yeah there's if it's just one
plant I just put the bag under it cut it
right into the bag
Would You Walk us through the the next
steps of um take us from where we're at
now to
um to having clean seeds so what just
walk us through I know there's a lot of
different ways that people do it and we
are talking about somebody who is a
first-time breeder so they're they're
not going to have all the sexy gear that
we see you know professional breeders
have so just walk us through like the
Baseline of what they're gonna do
so what I would do first is uh just
drive the plant material usually at
ambient temperature you don't want to
use heat if you have a dehumidifier you
want to keep the humidity low
once the plant is kind of crispy that's
when I would thresh it it's a lot easier
to thresh plants that are just like
crunchy if you're trying to save the
flour from the seeded Bud that it
generally I don't I usually just throw
it away because it gets really beat up
and isn't the best quality but you could
you could absolutely save it especially
for something like cooking
um but regardless I would get it crispy
and then you just basically shuck it
right off the branch get real rough take
those flowers and grind them between
your hand you don't have to be too
careful at this point the seeds should
be relatively resilient if you're
crushing them by grinding them in your
hand then they probably were dead
already
so do that until it's kind of like a
consistent powder seed plant mixture and
then you can start to separate that
material so I I always use I always
recommend using gloves at this point
because anytime I'm touching the seeds I
really want to limit my human oils onto
the seeds for the reasons we mentioned
earlier about the vital biology that's
on the outside of the seeds you know a
lot of people handle their seeds like
like they are like a little impervious
suitcases but um you know I go a little
more gentle than that um what are your
thoughts
I definitely touch seed without gloves
during that that process I wear gloves
because grinding plant material in
between your hands is not doesn't feel
good uh but I'm you know I've never
thought about it how the oil affects the
seed coat microbiome I'm sure it has
some effect I don't know what it would
be yeah I didn't actually think about it
at all until uh last episode with Jeff
lowenfels when he was explaining the the
bacteria on the inside and outside of
the seed that are carried with it where
the seed is going the the um the
research of uh I think the the
scientist's name was James White I
believe it was anyway
um it's totally changed my relationship
with uh with with the you know handling
the seeds
um so so now that you've kind of like
pulverized the flowers in your hands and
a bunch of seeds are like just like
raining out of it for you hopefully
um you still have got all of this
um plant material mixed in with the
seeds
um you know if you're just producing a
little bit just going at it on a on a on
a flat surface with a credit card might
be tedious but it would work uh is there
um is there a nice best practice you
like for removing the plant material
from the seeds for home scale I do one
of a couple things I will
grind the plant material through a
screen sometimes to get it really fine
uh when you okay so when you thresh the
plant you have just this pile of whole
plant material you can kind of shake it
in a tub and the seed will sink to the
bottom and at that point you might want
to just pick the plant material off the
top and get rid of some of the bigger
stuff but then I'll grind it through
like a
spaghetti strainer screen and make all
that plant material more fine and
usually the seed sits on top of that
screen so that's like the first
sift of plant material I throw away
everything that ground through the
screen
then I pour that seed into like a
dishwashing tub
and I kind of shake it around and I've
seen people do this a few different ways
and you can also buy or build machines
that use vacuum cleaners to air clean
that are more precise but just for the
home grower just a dishwasher tub shake
it around move it to one corner and then
I blow into the
tub kind of in the direction of the
seeds and all the light seed and plant
material will fly away you have to be a
little bit careful you're going to lose
some good seed pretty much any air
cleaner is going to remove a little bit
of good seed but the idea is that you're
removing you know
95 of the trash and you're leaving
yourself with viable seed so now we're
sorting seeds
um what are you looking for for seeds
that you are going to reject once you
have like a in it depends on what size
lot you're doing and what are you saving
are you just saving them for breeding
then I might you know have a lower
standard for defects and things like
that but if you're going to give it to
people I'd clean them more precisely but
generally you can light colored seed is
usually pretty obvious and if you pick
up a seed it just crunches in your hand
it wasn't filled with anything you just
toss those away
sometimes those Will Survive air
cleaning and they'll still be in the
batch especially if they still have
plant material attached to them they
might be have been a little heavier and
survived that you know if you know your
seed variety well you'll get a look at
what a a good mature healthy seed looks
like and you'll be able to kind of
calibrate and look for the ones that
don't look correct so if you have a seed
variety that usually has Tiger stripes
and you have one that's light and tan uh
you know I would toss that
um but it's surprising though because
some some seed especially uh you know if
you do cell thing or you say you're
trying to do a quick breeding cycle and
you only let it go two weeks the seed
might look green still and look immature
but it'll still have 70 germination
which could be enough if all you're
doing is breeding with it I haven't seen
any of those seeds yet that's a that's a
strange thing yeah probably because
they're not released that way right
they're just they're part of a breeding
program yeah absolutely yeah
um you know I I you know I don't really
know when people talk about curing their
seeds
um I don't usually know what they mean
but we do know that a a fresh seed taken
right off the plant
um
given a little bit of time to dry will
then germinate better in a couple weeks
than it does on the day that you take it
from the plant but I actually don't know
a whole lot about that would you speak
to this idea of curing seeds and letting
them dry and to increase germination
rates
so that when you go to them they're
they're actually ready to do their job
yeah so I think it's two things one is
is drying it down to a moisture lever
level where it will be shelf stable uh
for a certain amount of time and that's
down to five percent moisture is uh
preferred anything under 10 and in cold
treatment is also going to stay alive
for years
um there's also another aspect to you
know curing or aging your seed a little
bit and it's probably a post Harvest
maturation just physiologically that
embryo is still doing things after the
Harvest and it's not quite ready to
germinate yet if you plant you know a
week after cleaning seed or something
like that you might get 50 germination
if you wait two to three weeks that'll
go up to 90. so there's something
happening and I think it's beyond just
because the moisture content probably
won't change that long in that amount of
time so my guess is that's mostly some
physiological process within the seed
and uh let's finish up with storing so
now you've put in all this effort and
you've got your first run of seeds and
you're so freaking stoked and you're
gonna you're gonna share them with your
friends and you can't wait to grow it
and smoke it
um but you got some other stuff you got
to do first and so um so you're gonna
need to store it for a while
um what are your best practices for um
for storing seed before I get to that
there's just one more thing
I forgot to mention I have heard some
people talk about uh you know some seeds
need to of other species need to what's
called vernalize or they go through a
cold period in the winter before they're
able to germinate I have heard some
people report and I don't have a
specific experience with this
um but they say that they get better
germination if they put their seed in
not just wait the those two or three
weeks before trying to plant it but they
put it in a refrigerator or a freezer
for that period of time
um
I'm not sure if they've compared that
just to waiting and I'm kind of curious
to try that sometime but usually when
we're waiting the seed is in a cold
Vault so basically all our seeds is
getting that treatment anyway
um but yeah so when your seed is when
your seed is dried down to a good
percentage which should be under 10
preferably under eight or so percent
moisture
um
you can put it in either a freezer or a
refrigerator I usually keep my stuff in
a refrigerator freezer should be okay as
long as the moisture level is low and
that's probably best for long term uh
storage the problem with either a
refrigerator or a freezer usually arises
from when you're taking the seed in and
out so you want to have it in an
airtight container maybe with a little
desiccant
um
and put it in the freezer refrigerator
when you take the seed out to access
that session whenever you're ready to
grow it you want to let it acclimate to
whatever the room temperature is before
you open it because like if you take
that say you have it in a little plastic
container you take that out of the
freezer it's going to be instantly
covered with with moisture and if you
open that before the seed reaches before
it all equalizes in temperature the same
thing will happen to the seed and that's
what will limit the viability over time
more than more than temperature more
than the air exposure it's going to be
moisture that is a dangerous seed uh so
we've now we've got them cured and we've
got them stored and we know that we want
to bring it back to temperature before
we open the the container especially if
we're only going to take out some of the
seeds we don't want to reclose the
container with all that condensation
that it suddenly pulled out of the air
because you you'd risk either mold or
heck maybe even potentially accidental
germination eh
yeah if you're taking out a little pack
and you're going to plant all the seed
then you know you don't have to wait but
if it's like a stored seed that you're
taking a little aliquot out of you don't
want to damage the seed that goes back
into storage aliquot there's my word for
the day I haven't heard that in a long
time
um all right great so um so before
before we wrap up and I let you go
Brandon is there is there anything else
that um you know you've done this
process so many times and and now you're
doing it uh professionally is there is
there anything else looking back on this
show where you're all like you're like
actually there's one more thing that the
um that the new breeder is going to want
to know is there is there anything that
jumps out into your brain right away
that uh that we may not have covered
that we want to go back and and
punctuate before before we wrap up
it there might be a couple points if
someone to ask me advice as a new grower
the first thing I would say is know your
germplasm that you're working with and
what is available before you start
designing your program uh don't just
cross things because you like the name
or whatever and also expect things to
react differently than you think they're
going to when you cross them
when you say know your germplasm break
that out a little bit what exactly do
you mean
know the two lines that you're working
with and have grown them and things like
that I I yes I would say have grown them
and have some at least have seen the
flower people in canvas especially will
attach to names and have these I was
guilty of this where you you get these
ideas you fantasize about a plant uh
based on its description or something
and then it's not what it is when you
get it or you have the plant and you
fantasize about a cross because oh these
will this plant and this plant would
make a really good intermediate but then
you cross them and the intermediate
doesn't exist it's totally different so
you need to be flexible and just uh work
with what you have and not you know the
fantasy of what you have yeah I actually
have been running into a problem with
that myself I have this fantasy of
Crossing um Sour Diesel to jet fuel OG
um because I like both of those very
much
um but you know having grown Sour Diesel
a couple times it is uh so
likely to both
throw male flowers and express itself
with intersex flowers
um that I just I'm just not willing to
you know breed with it and cause all
these potential problems down the line
and I didn't realize that until I you
know started growing the sour diesel
that we have today and realizing that
that most of the folks who are
you know working with sour diesel are
expecting male flowers and intersex
flowers and and I'm like well I guess I
probably won't go down that path because
I I did my research on the germplasm yes
it's also surprising I have some things
that are prone to intersex that when you
cross them none of the plants in the
cross will be intersexed maybe if I took
it another generation it would start
causing problems but if you're just so I
don't want to discourage people either
if you're just trying to make an F1 you
know and one of them is intersex it
might solve the problem and
alternatively I've had plants that were
you know never produced in male flower I
crossed them all of the seeds are
intersexed
and neither of the parents seemingly one
of the parents was deep chunk which I'm
not aware of intersex problems with deep
chunk and the other was a clone
lesperado so I don't know the background
of esperado but the Clone itself you
know never had had a problem but every
almost every single seed is just almost
50 50. right on
um right on so do you have anything else
to add before we before we wrap up
um lastly the the other the last like uh
kind of point that I try to
impose on newer Growers is uh you know
consider working with higher populations
even if you have a small uh space so
this might be breaking plant count
numbers for a lot of people and this is
why I would prefer say uh if you're
going to regulate Gardens do it on Space
rather than plant house because I can
you can fit
a hundred plants or more in a two by
four if you have them stunted in little
uh trays something like that and if
you're not selecting especially when
you're making cross initial crosses and
you're introducing jeans where you're
just selecting for one major Gene but
you want to keep the gene pool uh broad
like if I'm doing a photo autocross and
I'm not trying to select specific
phenotypes yet I'll do those original
Generations as populations in small
tents so you're still hitting a large
selection numbers and I still will make
especially selections against plants
that get diseased and things like that
but you're in a very small space that's
probably not something that's going to
happen with the first time rear but that
sounds like it might be a really good
set too because as soon as you do this
once and you have success you're
suddenly going to want to do way bigger
sifts so you have more options I'm
guessing well cool well Brandon thank
you so much for coming on shapingfire
and sharing your experience I
appreciated a great deal I really
appreciate the invitation thank you for
having me so if you want to follow along
uh with Brandon there are three
different places that you can
um you can be in contact with him if you
wish the first I definitely recommend
following his uh personal Instagram at
growinghire
um he I mean first of all there's a lot
of great plant photos but the commentary
that Brandon offers on on this or that
project that he's working on is engaging
in educational so that's a good thing
second I'm a big fan of the company that
Brandon has started uh with a couple of
his friends Michael fight Solutions uh
which focuses on uh crop advising with a
regenerative and mycology mindset for uh
for agriculture and and their Instagram
is at micro fights Solutions and if
mycophyte is a is new vocabulary for you
that's
m-y-c-o-p-h-y-t-e microphic might go
fight to Solutions and then and then you
can find out more about their actual
consulting services and what they can
offer at michaelfight.com
you can find more episodes of the
shaping fire podcast And subscribe to
the show at shapingfire.com and wherever
you get your podcasts if you enjoyed the
show we'd really appreciate it if you
would leave a positive review of the
podcast wherever you download your
review will help others find the show so
they can enjoy it too on the shapingfire
website you can also subscribe to the
newsletter for insights into the latest
Cannabis News exclusive videos and
giveaways on the shaping fire website
you also find transcripts of today's
podcast as well be sure to follow on
Instagram for all original content not
found on the podcast that's at
shapingfire and at shangolos on
Instagram be sure to check out
shapingfire YouTube channel for
exclusive interviews farm tours and
cannabis lectures does your company want
to reach our national audience of
cannabis enthusiasts email hotspot
shapingfire.com to find out how thanks
for listening to shapingfire I've been
your host shangolos
foreign