[Music]
it was late 2015 when I first watched
overly excited and inexperienced new
cannabis executives totally fail at
Interstate brand licensing they were an
Oregon company seeking to expand their
brand into Washington I was the lead
negotiator on the Washington side of the
deal the deal as it appeared on paper
was really more of a franchise agreement
than it was a brand licensing deal and I
saw it as packed with red flags it
included some attributes that were
downright fraud to get around the state
ownership laws here in Washington and
then another part of the deal would have
cost my clients their license because of
how they were intending to move the
money around now these were not bad
people these were folks who just didn't
know enough about business to do it the
right way and they were very driven to
find a creative solution in the morass
of regulation luckily for us another
cannabis business was publicly
reprimanded for trying to set up the
same kind of licensing deal our suitors
wanted to set up with us and everyone
realized that my cautious read of the
situation was spot on and everybody
involved walked away from that deal this
is wildly common some of the stories
I've heard from California and Nevada
recently have similar blatantly
fraudulent and unenforceable traits
today's show is intended to give you
context on the differences between
licensing and franchising how to choose
partners and how to think correctly
through your opportunities in cannabis
if you want to learn about cannabis
health business and technique
efficiently and with good cheer I
encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter will send you new podcast
episodes as they come out delivered
right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week and
videos too don't rely on social media to
let you know when a new episode is
published sign up for the updates to
make sure you don't miss an episode
also we're giving away very cool prizes
to folks who are signed up to receive
the newsletter congratulations to
Sebring Ophelia Erin and Nate who all
won organic soil nutrients from green
bicycles yesterday just for being
subscribed to the newsletter there's
nothing else you need to do to win
except to receive the newsletter so go
to shaping fire comm and sign up for the
newsletter
and be entered into this month and all
future newsletter prize drawings you are
listening to shaping fire and I'm your
host Shango Lowe's my guest today is
Chris crane Chris crane is a 20 year
veteran of the cannabis industry first
starting out in advocacy before moving
over to business consulting from 2000 at
2005 he was associate director of normal
and then became executive director of
students for sensible drug policy in
June of this year he was elected to a
third term on the board of directors of
the National cannabis Industry
Association he's now president and
co-founder of forefront a leading
investment in operations firm chris has
clients and speaks at cannabis
conventions all around the world he is
highly sought after by companies scaling
their cannabis operations and he also
happens to be a really nice guy today
we're gonna talk about Interstate brand
licensing I also want to note that we
experienced some technical difficulties
while recording this episode while Chris
and I were both in professional studios
we were still talking via the internet
and some days packets just don't travel
well you'll hear some pops during the
first set but they do settle down as the
show goes on and eventually kind of go
away so it'll be alright and we
appreciate you hanging with us welcome
to the show Chris hey thanks for having
me right on so let's get it let's start
by getting everybody on the same page
right cuz everybody thinks they've got
an idea about what's going on with
licensing and franchising and and
everyone's expansion to other states but
for a lot of people they don't
necessarily understand why this is such
a pressing thing so certainly we're
seeing some brands break out as clear
leaders in their origination state the
state that they are from that they built
their first business in but most of
these companies are eyeing expansion
into other states to explain this to
folks would you explain why expansion
beyond one state is so attractive to
these companies and perhaps even
necessary in the cannabis market that
we're looking at right now yeah I mean I
think like any business you you're gonna
want to expand your business one
successful so if your operational one
state and you're doing well in one state
you're gonna want to expand elsewhere I
think that the big difference between
the cannabis industry and other
businesses is that you know if you're
successful in in a state let's choose
microbrews for example let's say you set
up a success
microbrewery in colorado you gain good
market share Colorado you start seeing
some popularity you know online for your
products in some neighboring states say
California and Arizona you want to start
expanding to those states you would
simply increase your production capacity
at your called your ball your
cultivation in this case your your your
brewing facility in Colorado and you
would start shipping product into
California and Arizona that's simply not
possible in the cannabis industry
because it's still federally illegal and
because of its state-by-state nature of
the industry so if you have a product
that's gaining popularity and you want
to expand your market share expand your
market you have to go to another state
and you have to get another license in
that other state which may not be the
easiest thing in the world to do in most
states they have very competitive
application processes where you're gonna
be competing against lots of other
operators from around the country as
well as some homegrown folks and you
know and a lot of those states there
just aren't licenses available many
states have a limit on the number of
licenses they grant all of those at once
and then they're not able beyond that it
so the only way to get into those other
states would be either to acquire a
license in another state to basically
buy somebody else's business or to
license your brand to a license holder
in another state so say you have a brand
somebody wins a production license in a
different state you want to get in there
there's no brands if there's no licenses
available you don't have the capital or
don't want to buy that license you could
find willing partner in another state
and license that brand to them so
essentially licensing your intellectual
property your your SOPs your way of your
methods of production and your brand and
it would then start producing and
selling your brand and use some sort of
licensing fee or royalty agreement back
you back to the main company one other
thing I would just want to point out in
terms of why people are looking to do
this is you know this is a this is a
growing industry and it's very hard to
be a successful business just operating
in one state and so it makes sense you
would want to go state to state to state
and when we look at what's happening for
example in the public markets where in
Canada a lot of these US companies are
going getting listed there's a big
appetite for
multi-state operators there's much less
of an appetite in terms of getting
publicly listed in getting investment
into your company if you're a single
state operator and so that's also been a
big motivation I think over the last
year for folks to get into multiple
states because it provides them with
better access to capital which in a
federally illegal industry with no
access to traditional institutional
lending is particularly attractive yeah
I think you're right the big role that
access to capital plays because you know
in the in the earlier some five to five
years ago there are a lot of folks who
were planning on on doing it on their
own right and then they realized that
the only way they were going to get
access to capital is from people who
wanted them to hit a grand slam so it
was no longer really people just doing a
solid job in their state of origination
suddenly if people wanted to you know
get get capital they needed to have as
part of their pitch with their national
expansion was so-so in it along that
thought Chris you know do you think that
there's going to be much future for
companies that choose to stay in one
state and don't expand into other states
I think there will be yeah but I think
it's gonna get it's gonna get
progressively harder to do that so I
think the O's that will you know survive
as a solo state operator are largely
going to be you know those folks who
have a really solid sort of craft brand
in particular you know I think there's a
there's a place for craft production so
you know the highest quality flour the
highest quality products where you know
you you have you would have a hard time
doing that as a much larger scale
operator I think those folks will you
know will find a way survive and
ultimately you know the the walls of
Interstate Commerce are going to come
down on and when that happens they'll be
an ability for some of those those
single state operators to expand all of
a sudden your state doesn't really
matter as much you know if you're
getting if you're getting orders from
your just across the border which you
know some of these Northeast states
might be you know a 45-minute drive away
you know that's no longer a relevant
factor you can sell into another state
once multi-state car interstate commerce
opens up and I think to the the other
potential Avenue for for the solo op
and we're starting to see this now is
frankly is to be acquired themselves so
they you know if you can bill really
solid brand in one state whether it's a
prop brand or as a great cultivator or
the great retail brand as some of these
you know larger multi-state
consolidators and multi-state operators
to start looking to acquire assets and
and grow their their license portfolio
those who have done a really nice job of
operating a single store or a single
operation within one state are going to
be you know nice attractive targets to
these multi-state consolidators so you
know as you know as we all know you only
really need to worry about this you know
the difficulty in spanning to another
state if you're actually a license
holder in your particular state you know
corollary companies like making bonds or
being a tax accountant firm or all these
are the things that that you don't have
to hold a license for you all's can just
expand like you traditionally would off
you go but if it's folks who I actually
have got a state license where you are
either a producer of the flower you know
a processor of it in some way transport
or a retailer and what I'm curious is
from your experience are you finding
that particular niches of that that set
of market is finding an easier time of
expanding than others
you know not really frankly it it
depends on the state because new states
have very different caps on the number
of licenses and ways to expand so for
example you know to get a cultivation
license in Nevada is fairly easy or was
very easy in the application process and
would be relatively easy to acquire
because they granted 180 cultivation
licenses for a state of about 4 million
people compared to say in Illinois where
there are 19 cultivation / production
licenses for a state of 13 million
people you know those licenses much much
more difficult to acquire or to even win
in the first place
so it has less to do with which part of
the vertical urine right cultivation
production dispensary as opposed to what
states are looking to expand into what
the availability of licenses
are in those states either from a from a
Lexus application standpoint or an
acquisition standpoint all right so like
a guy like you who is working in in many
of the states for your own group
forefront ventures and are also probably
assisting some other people in other
states where forefront ventures is not
working themselves where have you seen
to be the hardest states to move into so
far and for what reason
well they've mostly been states in the
eastern half of the US and that's
primarily it's a combination of factors
but number one is the is the limit on
the number of licenses so in a lot of
these states in the eastern half of the
country there's a really small number of
overall licenses so the applications for
these licenses are incredibly
competitive and you even if you put
together you know in some states I would
say if you put together in an A+ team
with an A+ quality application and like
an A+ lobbying effort you might have a
10 to 15 percent chance of winning you
know if you if you if you can't put all
that together you may have not you may
as well not even bother applying I would
look at states like Florida New York for
example states that fit that New Jersey
some has been similar although we think
New Jersey's about to open up to more
licenses later on this year and into
next year as they expand their medical
program and Spanish recreational you
know even a state like Illinois where
there's again there's 13 or sorry
there's 13 million people and 19
cultivator producer licenses right
that's a very difficult state to get
into so by and large it's the states in
the northeast during the eastern half of
the country with the limited licenses
very challenging application processes
and fairly strict regulatory environment
so you know not only do you have to be
able to win a license or acquire a
license you have to be able to navigate
what's generally stricter regulatory
environments than you then you get in
many of the western states so clearly
there are savvy business people in every
state but as we've seen you know there's
a certain amount of I don't know
corporate memory creep of how to do
Canada's business specifically that
comes along with normalization and that
has generally been you know coming from
the west coast
across the country as more states first
adopt medical and then move their way
towards rec do you find that there is
that then along with setting up these
licensing arrangements going east that
there's not only a lot of just you know
simple negotiating the licenses but
there's bringing these these otherwise
competent entrepreneurs up to speed
going east just so they understand the
the new moving parts in this industry
that hasn't existed before can you I'm
sorry can you repeat the question there
the point I'm trying to bring out here
is that that that there are good
business people everywhere right but
they may not necessarily know cannabis
business specifically in every state are
you finding that as as as cannabis is
moving into these new states that yeah
you need to reach out you need to find
partners you need to to negotiate what
you want to do with the license but at
the same time you also have to teach
cannabis business because it's different
and unique to other types of business
yeah I think that's right when you look
at some of the more successful operators
in particularly in these more
challenging states what you typically
see and I would say successful in terms
of both winning the license and then
operating licenses what you typically
see is a combination of your business
experience and cannabis experience and
frankly you know local political
experience as well I mean these these
licenses are somewhat political in terms
of how they're granted even if states
like to say they're not so you know and
they tend to give to friends to locals
to a degree as well sometimes implicitly
sometimes explicit so you know that it's
the combination of having a really good
local Oh
good local business people who might
have good political connections or good
real estate connections who partner up
with folks who have really good
experience from outside of that state
that can help demonstrate competency in
cannabis and that that combination tends
to do fairly well it is a bit harder
or the business people who've never done
in cannabis to figure out how to do this
on their own without you know a
significant dose of education and of his
business and likewise I think for folks
who started in cannabis particularly in
you know the more sort of great markets
in California in prior to the last year
or so when real regulations came into
place a lot of those folks had a really
hard time navigating these much more
complex regulatory environments in the
eastern half of the country so I think
that combination is proven to be
relatively successful and frankly fairly
necessary for both sides of the equation
right on that makes a lot of sense
so we're gonna take our first short
break a little early and try to get rid
of that pop in the recording so so blah
stay with us you are listening to
shaping fire and my guest today is Chris
Crane co-founder of forefront ventures
as a business owner you are incredibly
busy in reality you are responsible for
everything your company does you've got
so many responsibilities every single
day that often you just don't have the
time to really dig into your marketing
as deeply as you'd like you know there's
more that you could do to reach out to
new customers and encourage loyalty and
the customers you do have but you
certainly don't have the time for it and
you're not really ready to hire someone
full-time for that role either for you I
recommend blunt branding at blunt
branding Kirsten Nelson and her team are
focused on improving your bottom line
you know most marketing firms are
excited to make your logo packaging and
website very pretty but they leave
responsibility for improving your bottom
line up to you they don't want that kind
of responsibility but that's pretty much
the most important part of marketing
right Kirsten and her team will help you
engage new customers funnel them to your
point of sale whether it be online or
storefront and keep them coming back to
you and telling their friends now if you
happen to be a new cannabis company or
an established company moving from
medical to adult use in your state
Kirsten especially can help you not only
is she well-versed in marketing and
finance but she totally gets cannabis
whole plant medicine terpenes heritage
farmers and the particular needs of
startups check out what she did recently
for moon time medicinals in Humboldt
County
at moon time medicinals calm Kirsten and
her team put together a whole brand
package for them built their website and
wrote their sales materials no doubt
this is a paid commercial spot but that
does not mean that they bought my
opinion I've worked with blunt branding
on four projects now for various clients
and every single time they have done
more than they've promised and over
delivered on results I love how they
generate new revenue and focus on that
as the goal instead of just making you a
pretty logo similarly every single
friend I've referred them to has come
back to thank me that just doesn't
happen every day grab a pen and paper
because the website address is coming if
you want someone to implement marketing
programs that feed your bottom line give
blunt branding a call they will share
proven techniques to increase your
audience and generate sales while using
cutting-edge technology solutions in the
background that make all of this easy
automatic and trackable go to shaping
fire com forward slash blunt branding to
find out more you can also click on the
link in our newsletter Blount branding
marketing that makes you money did you
know that shaping fire has a fabulous
YouTube channel with content not found
on the podcast when I attend conventions
or speak or moderate panels I always
record them and bring the content home
for you to watch the Shango loss youtube
channel it has world-class speakers
including kevin Jodrey of wonderland
nursery talking about breeding cannabis
for the best terpene profile nicholas
Mahmood on regenerative and polyculture
cannabis growing dr. Sunil a girl on the
history of cannabis medicine around the
world Ben Cassidy of true terpenes on
using terpenes for health in your
everyday life Reggie Godinho of steep
hill on the cannabis genome and Jeff
Lowen Fell's on the soil food web
there are several presentations from dr.
Ethan Russo on terpenes and the
endocannabinoid system and even my own
presentation on how to approach finding
your dream job in cannabis and why we
choose canvas business even though the
risks are so high as of today there are
over 100 videos that you can check out
for absolutely free go to youtube.com
forward slash Shango 'lose or click on
the link in this week's newsletter
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire I'm your host Shengo Louis
and our guest this week is Chris Crane
founder of forefront ventures so during
the first set we talked a lot about why
a company would be looking to expand
beyond their origination state for all
sorts of good reasons from spreading the
risk around to accessing more capital
and also just to be able to be an
established national brand but one of
the things that gets people in a bad
position constantly is a confusion
between licensing and franchising and
that's what we're gonna talk about
primarily today here in the second set
so Chris you know now that we've
established the why let's focus on the
heart and that's the difference between
licensing and franchising people often
Lee mistakenly think that they're
synonymous but they are certainly not
and they're really not even
interchangeable for cannabis what's the
primary differences between licensing
and franchising sure so it's a good
question and you're right people really
do often get this one wrong and they use
the words interchangeably but they're
quite different you know the main thing
to get across is I don't think there is
any franchising in cannabis right now I
know there are some groups that have
looked at doing it but I don't think
anybody's actually running at a
traditional franchise the two to back up
the main difference between licensing
and franchising is licensing is
essentially you are giving somebody the
right to use your brand and potentially
your intellectual property some
operating protocols your methods of
production and then they have the right
to use that and they pay you some fee to
do that franchising agreements are much
more broad so they give you the ability
to to essentially sell all of those
things write your name of your your
brand and your your SOPs your protocols
write your methodology but you also have
a much greater degree of control over
your franchisee so in a franchise
agreement you can tell your franchisor
you must offer these sales on these days
your store must look exactly this way
you must buy your products from these
vendors or you must buy these products
from us specifically franchisor can tell
you where you can locate and where you
can't locate in fact they can tell you
where you have to locate so if you go
and buy a Dunkin Donuts for example you
have no freedom over what that Dunkin
Donuts looks like over where you buy
your products over where you buy your
doughnut making materials and and what
not or is in a licensing agreement it's
very difficult to get into that level of
detail and so licensees have a bit more
freedom than a franchisee would have
license sores also have to jump through
sniffing utley fewer hoops than
franchisors would have to go through so
in order to be a franchisor you have to
put you come up with what's called a
franchise disclosure agreement or
franchise disclosure document and FDD
that there are very specific guidelines
that govern what what go into an FDD
there's a ton of disclosures about the
owners of the company any business that
you've done anybody that you've offered
franchises to I mean it's a it's it's a
few hundred pages of background
information information about the
business
there are rules around how you how you
franchise so you have to give that
document to somebody you then can't
contact them for something like a week
let's make sure they have time to review
it right if you do then they can get out
of their franchise agreement and so it's
a it's a real process and then in about
half the states are over half the states
you have to file with the state court or
franchise board to be recognized as a
franchisor in that state in order to
offer a franchise none of those are
necessary for licensing agreements a
licensing agreement you know any good
corporate attorney can put together a
license agreement for you you negotiate
that with the attorney on the other side
you all agree to what parameters you're
going to operate under but you won't as
the license or have the same degree of
control over your licensee that you
would as a franchisee work over their
franchisee let's tease out where that
threshold is right because while while
in a licensed relationship you can't
call out everything as specifically as
in a franchise relationship certainly
there are some things that you can
control for example I would think the
the deployment of the brand and what the
looks like essentially the the brand
usage book that probably stays
consistent since that's part of what's
being licensed that's right but but
where does that where does that end so
does it does it end as soon as you start
talking about the operations of the
company or is it only particular parts
of the operation so there's not really a
clear line and this is where I mean I
should I should disclaim all this by
saying I'm not an attorney and today
thinking about if you're really thinking
about your becoming a franchisor or a
licensed or or a franchisee or licensee
you need to seek out a good corporate
attorney and if you're on the franchisee
side of things definitely seek out a
franchise attorney or specific attorneys
that handle these kind of things and I'm
not one of those so we'll talk about
this at the high level but my
understanding is there's not a very it's
not a concrete line between what you
know what would constitute a franchisee
versus a license but generally you're
right it's things like you can say you
have the right to use the brand the
brand has to say consistent right you
can't just change the logo or or do
something that's going to be detrimental
to that to 2d2 the overall brand and
you'd have to set out certain guidelines
as to you know this is what we expect
out of the brand this is what it looks
and feels like you you can and you can
you can't dictate how they run their
business so again you can't say in a
licensing agreement you have to buy all
of your products from me right you have
to you have to buy these products from
these vendors and you have to buy this
particular type of floor board for your
store this particular type of display
case for your store you can you can do a
little bit of that as long as as long as
what you're what you're contracting
around is to protect the integrity of
the brand but you can't tell them they
have to do this they have to do that the
fees are also to also tend to be a
little bit different in a licensing
agreement you can have all different
kinds of fees so somebody could pay you
you know a flat fee per month to license
your brand and your in your operations
protocols it could pay you a royalty on
sales there's a lot of different ways to
do it with a franchise agreement it's
much more standard
you typically pay a
upfront fee as your upfront franchise
fee and then there's an ongoing percent
sales back to the franchisor some which
your ongoing franchise fees some which
are joint marketing fees and so usually
the franchisor will do marketing for you
all of their franchises in in an area so
for example again if you go back to what
Dunkin Donuts having lived in Boston for
the last four years it's a good one to
use for me since you can't throw a rock
without hitting a Dunkin Donuts and the
Boston area but you know there's so
there's a there's there's hundreds of
Dunkin Donuts in the Boston area for
example they don't each go out and do
their own advertising the corporate
retinue the corporate franchise or
Dunkin Donuts does all of the
advertising for all franchises in Boston
so they'll run the advertising on Boston
radio on Boston TV on you know online
and and and that's to the benefit of the
choices they don't have to then go out
and spend that money themselves but it's
also why it's important for the
franchisor to make sure that if somebody
walks into you know one Dunkin donut so
then they walk into another Dunkin
Donuts your half mile down the road that
all of the products are the same the
displays are the same the look and feel
is the same right it's the exact same
experience that's much harder to dictate
through a licensing agreement than it is
through a franchising agreement all
right that makes sense so let's dig a
little deeper into that because I
thought I had an idea of what the
threshold was and then and then and then
I realize I don't because I thought that
we were gonna say that
the the threshold for a license is that
your licensing the brand and that when
you're doing a franchise relationship
it's it's more operational based and the
how-to but I and this last answer you
said that the licensees will license
both the brand and the SOPs the standard
operating procedures how how the the
company can run internally so so this
tell this suggests to me that perhaps
the threshold between a franchise and a
license may be perhaps on the
enforcement of this of the operating
procedures because from my understanding
with a franchise they can send people
from the home office to the franchised
location and run them through a bunch of
of questions to make sure that
everything is running as it's supposed
to in the operating procedures from the
home office and I and and and I believe
that with licensees that actually breaks
the law and you can't actually and do
that that kind of enforcement so so we
hit that a little bit if you would yeah
my understanding is that that's right
and again this is where the liens give
it a little bit blurry but it's which
what is clear is as a franchisor
absolutely you can send folks from Home
Office in so you look if you're not
doing all this we have the right and we
have the right to take your store away
and take another franchise or from
another store and give it to them you
know if you're not if you're not
maintaining the integrity of our of our
brand in our stores that that not the
case with a licensing agreement or
you're gonna have to go through a number
of steps to your not claim contract
infringement and then and there has to
be steps to remedy that infringement
within the contract that you would you
would take as a French as a license or
towards your licensee give them the
opportunity to cure that so you're
dealing much will sort of standard
contract law rather than what you
haven't a franchisor and a franchise
agreement where the franchisor is have a
great deal of power but you're right the
licensing is not necessarily just around
a brand it is often around the operating
protocols specifically so you know let's
say for example somebody develops a
better way to create cannabis infused
patches right to a but kind of like a
whatever marries medicinals or Magana
molecular right who do that we do a you
know yeah the transdermal transdermal
exactly yeah trained several so let's
say somebody comes up with a really good
way to come up to do and thermal patches
and they have their own brand say in
Illinois right and then somebody from
Arkansas comes is I'd really like to use
that but you know what your brand in
Illinois isn't you know it's it's known
in Illinois but like nobody here in
Arkansas knows your brand I don't put a
whole lot of value in the brand itself
because you know nobody knows it here
and I can put that out in the shelves
and they're not gonna know that from the
other transdermal patch but your
methodology is great and I really
interested in that and I want to build
my own brand around it
you could license the technology so
let's say you've created some kind of
machine that creates this transdermal
patch and then standard operating
procedures or standard operating
protocols for how you operate that
machinery you could license that machine
and those operating procedures but say
you know you can write you can just
white label it put your own brand on it
you don't have to run our you know you
don't have to have our brand but you
have to use the Machine you know you
were licensing you the ability to use
this machine so you don't own the
machine we own it
we're licensing you to use it and we're
licensing you the intellectual property
that goes along with how to operate it
but that would also fall under the
category of the licensing agreement so
it doesn't have to include demand
whereas with the franchisee it's
everything it's the brand it's the
operations it's the SOPs it's the look
and feel it's who you buy stuff from
it's how much you pay for it it's all of
it right so if you're if you're a if
you're a franchisor again we'll go back
to the Dunkin Donuts example you let's
say you won't you own a Dunkin Donuts
and you know some vendor hits you up and
it's like hey I can sell you the same
flour that you're buying from dunkey for
half the price and it's gonna you know
it's gonna save you you know ten cents
on every you know $0.50 doughnut that
you create or that your that you cook
you don't have the right to do that as a
franchisee or if you do that that's a
clear violation of your franchise
agreement and you could you could
potentially lose your store for that
that that kind of enforcement comes much
more difficult in a licensing agreement
right on so I've got one more question I
want to keep I want to keep banging at
this license versus franchising at the
threshold points so so you mentioned
that there's a gray area right and the
funny thing about gray area and business
people including myself is on one hand
you want to get rid of these gray areas
because these gray areas create risk
right and we're all trying to decrease
the amount of risk that surrounds our
business investment of time and capital
but at the same time I also know that as
a business person I've done most of my
best deals in the gray areas of
arbitrage kind of like you know finding
loopholes and and exploiting them to my
benefit so it's like a great you know
gray areas good or bad who is the
arbiter of the gray area
I'm guessing it's some some federal
group who when push came to shove if a
decision was to be made whether or not
something was licensed or franchise
there's got to be somebody who plays the
umpire to that so who does it eventually
fall to so it is there's if there is a
federal agency and and in off top my
head I'm not recalling the name of the
agency it's got federal offense
franchise form so there's a federal
agency that looks as it looked at this
Oda my understanding is this is actually
mostly done at the state level so most
states will license franchises through
their their their either their franchise
board or or corporate board and then
even states that don't you don't have to
register as a franchise or
they still have oversight over
franchisors because you still have to go
through the FDD disclosure process and
there's a long process you have to go
through in order to be a franchisor nor
sell franchises so you could get in
trouble at either the state or the
federal level and there's a there's
actually a no it's a category of law but
there's a there's a term called
accidental franchise which which which
is what gets people in trouble if they
are essentially acting as a franchisor
without having gone through the full
franchise process they can get fined as
an accidental franchisee their licensing
agreements can all be basically
nullified at that point they can get
massive fines they can lose a lot of
business so you know very important if
you're looking to get into licensing or
any kind of licensing agreement that you
consult with a good corporate attorney
or even a franchise attorney to make
sure you're not running afoul of
accidental franchise laws and that
generally comes down to the level of
control that you're giving your
licensees
so again if you're if you're just saying
look you have the right to use our brand
you don't have the right to do anything
that would besmirched our brand or bring
down our brand value and if you're going
to you know if you're looking for some
if you're trying to use our method ology
we really need you to stick to those
SOPs because you can gunk up our
machines if you don't do it this way
right all that's going to be fine but if
you start saying you have to buy certain
things from certain
people at certain times you have to do
things certain ways you have to offer
certain sales in certain days and we're
gonna do joint marketing for you and all
of our other licensees well now you're
starting to look like a franchisor and
that's the kinda stuff that get you in
trouble the other thing too is which a
lot because a lot of people don't
recognize the difference between
franchise and licensing is just don't
use the word franchise I've had a lot of
people who've had like oh yeah I've got
this great brand and we're gonna go and
we're gonna franchise the brand well
have you talked to a franchise attorney
about it well no well what do you plan
to do well we're gonna license this and
real essence that ok great
don't use the word franchise you are
licensed or you're not a franchisor like
that's like the number one thing they
get somebody in trouble for accidental
franchises they use the word franchise
because they just don't know the
difference and they don't get the
distinction so you really want to make
sure that you work with a good corporate
lawyer who really understands franchise
law and accidental franchise so that
your contracts are set up the right way
your marketing materials are set up the
right way your licensing agreements are
set up the right way so you don't
accidentally run afoul of these these
quote-unquote accidental franchise laws
right on now that we understand all of
that we're gonna go to our second
commercial break and we come back for
set three we're gonna talk about how
actually to implement one of these
licensing agreements and some pitfalls
to watch out for we're gonna take a
short break and we'll be right back
you're listening to shaping fire and my
guest today is Chris Crane co-founder of
forefront ventures as a listener of
shaping fire you already understand the
importance of living soil when growing
cannabis when you have active microbe
communities in your substrate you go way
beyond simply fertilizing with nitrogen
phosphorus and potassium having active
microorganisms in your substrate
supports vigorous plant growth
throughout the plants root zone making
for higher yields and thriving flowers
mammoth pee is the first organically
derived microbial inoculant that focuses
on your plants nutrient cycling
processes to release soil phosphorus and
other micronutrients from they're bound
forms making them more available to the
plant increased levels of phosphorous
will also keep internode shorter and
focus your plants energy on bud
production not only that but the
microbes act as a defense shield for the
plants rhizosphere
by out competing potentially harmful
pathogenic microbes
pretty cool right mammoth he not only
unlocks the nutrients in your soil but
it also helps protect your plant from
disease mammoth Peas beneficial bacteria
act like micro bio reactors continually
producing enzymes that release nutrients
mammoths Pia was developed at a u.s.
university has been extensively tested
by Colorado growers and independent
laboratories mammoth pea is proven to
increase growth and enhance blooming one
of the great things about supplementing
with microorganisms is that they won't
compete with whatever fertilizer program
you're already running simply dose on
top of your fertilizer schedule for
increased benefits to learn more and to
find out where you can buy mammoth pee
near you check out their website at
www.att.com/biz industry people
everywhere are looking for the purest
terpenes without adulterants the problem
with most terpene providers is that
they're not sourced naturally and
instead are made as a byproduct of
refining petroleum and that's so sketchy
the terpenes sold by true terpenes are
entirely different they are certified
organic non-gmo and food grade that
means that they are extracted from real
plant sources there are no solvents of
any kind they are distilled only with
steam that's right only steam in fact
terpenes from true turbines are so pure
that you can eat them not only that but
you can stack them with better results -
what I mean is
other companies terpenes have got a few
percent of impurities and when you stack
those terpenes to make your blend you're
adding a variety of impurities that
degrade your final product true terpenes
also have strain-specific terpenes for a
wide range of cannabis strains like
Durbin poison sunset sherbet and ran
daddy purple true terpenes has robust
and supportive customer service so your
questions will get answered fast and
efficiently if you shop for turps before
you know how rare that is so whether you
want to cup your hands to smell some
betta carry off lean to call them down
after getting too high or if you want to
dab some pining so your lungs feel
fabulous
your mind feels liberated true terpenes
will provide you with a truly natural
experience if you are a cannabis product
developer these are the Terps you want
to add to your oil or edible or capsule
or whatever true terpenes are simply the
best your money can buy don't try and
make a premium product with substandard
terms choose true terpenes for a
top-shelf experience go to shaping fire
calm board / true terpenes to find out
more or click on the link in this week's
newsletter welcome back you're listening
to shaping fire I'm your host Shango
Lowe's and our guest this week is Chris
Crane co-founder of forefront ventures
so during the first set we talked about
why folks are wanting to license and
expand in other states and during set-to
we really dug deeply into licensing and
franchising so we got a really good idea
of what it means to license your brand
how to go about doing that and how to
not get tripped up by agreements that
are actually franchising which we cannot
yet do it now in cannabis so with that I
now want to understand how we would
reach out to parties in our new host
target state if we want to expand so
let's say that we are either in say for
example Washington which is totally
broke so a lot of the companies here are
looking to expand into new states to
hopefully have a greener future and then
and then of course in California like
everybody wants to expand nationally
because everybody is aggressive as hell
so so let's say that we have got our
company and we're ready to move to
another state Chris how do we find good
reliable folks in the target state that
we want to move into to work with so by
and large there aren't that many license
holders in most of these states rights
in most states there are caps on the
overall number of licenses and
oftentimes the states list the winners
so you can usually go on to the state's
health department or a new department
website and get a list of all the
licensees in those states you can not
often then go on to their corporate
commission website and find their
corporate foundation documents which I
usually have some sort of contact
information or you know oftentimes they
may even have a website you can contact
them that way
so it's not that difficult by and large
to find out who the licensees are in and
by licensees I mean people who hold
state licenses in these new states and
those are gonna be your your targets to
license your brand and you need to go to
somebody who has a production license
the cultivation license a dispensary
Lysa's depending on what it is that
you're looking to license so if you're
not gonna go into one of these states
and win a license yourself or acquire a
license yourself it's not that difficult
to find out who holds those state
licenses and then figure out a way to
reach out to them when you're vetting
folks in the target state because let's
say they're you know there could be a
few hundred or more of these people that
you're that you're targeting what do you
look at as a first level vetting of who
you might want to go to first I think
much like with just about anything you
want it you want to feel comfortable
with the management team so you want to
find out you know who the owners are who
the managers are you want to do some
diligence on them there's background
checks ask for references make sure you
feel comfortable with the management
team themselves and then and then it
really depends on what it is you're
looking to license so you know if you're
a retailer for example and you're
looking to license your retail brand
you're gonna want to see you know where
are they do they fit the you know do
they fit the the types of areas that
you'd like to locate your retail stores
so if you're you know if you're the type
of company that you know you want your
stores on Main streets and high
populated areas there you're probably
aren't going to be as interested in
somebody who has a more rural or
suburban location you know if you are a
product manufacturer you want to make
sure that the the the license holder has
a good operating capacity you know if
you're a cultivator and you're trying to
learn since cultivation methodology
right - they have a good cultivation
facility that would fit the types of
operations per recalls that we're gonna
be licensing or is this just a you know
is this a bad fit from a you know from
from a location standpoint you also want
to think about distribution particularly
when you're looking at larger states so
in Illinois where I currently live there
are a number of producers that are we
call downstate right in the southern
part of Illinois that's logistical
challenging
to get their products into the Chicago
market on a regular basis because
they're not allowed to warehouse their
products in Chicago so anytime they want
to make a shipment or they got a drive
you know five six hours to you know to
Chicago to drop things off and so you
might want to look for somebody who has
a cultivation or production facility
that's closer to the the you know the
the more dense markets or it's not going
to be as difficult so all these will be
factored in but it really does depend on
you know what segment of the market
you're looking at and what your ultimate
goals are I can imagine that when
setting up a licensing agreement that
you know when going through the
negotiation process and and putting
numbers and compensation into the
document it's probably relatively common
for the licensee and the license or to
have different perceived values of the
brand where where the the the parent
company thinks that their brand is worth
so worth a whole hell of a lot and the
licensee is all like man you're not in
our state what have you seen about that
where where they have got different
values for the brand yeah that's been
really interesting and and this
something we saw play out a lot more a
few years ago particularly these East
Coast states were really just starting
to come online knew you had brands like
Dixie or o.penvape for example which at
that time we're probably the two biggest
brands on the west coast who had you
know big market share in Colorado and
California in particular and then people
were winning licenses in places like
Massachusetts or Illinois or Nevada
Arizona and these companies were coming
in and they were marketing themselves as
the best brand in the industry household
names and what we found was a disconnect
between the the brand owners and the
potential licensees in that the brand of
owners often really valued the brand
itself thinking like hey we've gotten
all this market share in Colorado all
this market share in California people
love our brand or brands a household
name right you the brand itself comes
with a nice premium right you should pay
up for the right to use that brand
because it's such a good established
brand and what a lot of the folks in
these newer states
looking at it's going well yeah people
know Dixie in Colorado in California but
if I were to go out and hold most
cannabis consumers and most patients in
in Illinois or Massachusetts or
Connecticut most of them probably won't
know what Dixie is so what I'm more
interested in as the potential licensee
is your operating protocols like I want
to do marijuana infused beverages or I
want to do vape pen cartridges but you
know I don't really know how to do it
and I know that that trying to do it on
my own I'm gonna make a whole bunch of
mistakes I'm gonna have to learn and
that's gonna impact my you know my sales
in the market I'm willing to pay a
licensing agreement to use your SOPs and
your operating protocols and your
equipment and you know and and and not
have to reinvent the wheel but you know
I don't really care as much about
whether my products are called Dixie or
like right you know create something new
on my own that's new to the market and
it's actually I think why reason why a
lot of those early licensing agreements
didn't work is because there was a real
disconnect over the value of the brand
itself versus value of the operations
protocols I would think to that that
there would have to be some some really
intense thinking by a brand who was
being asked to license their SOPs
without the brand right because
potentially they could be creating a a
competitor in their own market who are
making quality products just like them
but then not using their name yeah I
think that you know that that would be a
real concern I think that's why a lot of
these early agreements didn't get done
now we're seeing more of them get done I
think we've seen more movement on both
sides towards towards consensus of what
these brands are worth but you're right
now by and large you're not so much
concern that you're creating a
competitor within your own market
because by and large right with the with
the nature of this being state-by-state
you're going to markets where you're not
already there and trying to license that
technology and I said that brand but for
the owners of the companies you're the
value to them is really in the brand
they want to get that brand out there so
if you're a Dixie or you're an
Incredibles or you're an opener you know
one of these are wanna brands right you
want to get that brand out there in
these other states and your best way to
do that is through a licensing agreement
that gets challenging when the person
the other side's going yeah I want you
know I want
I want the the expertise I want the
protocols but I don't really care about
your brand and I kind of want to develop
my own brand and so you have to then you
know stop and think is it is it worth it
for me to help create a competitor even
though reality is I'm getting I'm
getting a cut of their sales right like
the licensing agreements not free so if
I create if I help create someone who
becomes a really good competitor I'm
still benefiting from it but I'm
probably not benefiting in the way that
I would if it were my brand that were
being promoted because that then helps
me expand that brand into other parts of
the country it helps boost my brand port
my brand profile may have boost my
valuation is a company because I could
point to my brand being all these
different states so it's a it's it's a
real challenge and I could see from the
standpoint of a license or why it might
be on starter for many of them to just
say I'm gonna let me know license get
technology and you can do whatever brand
you want with it now that in and of
itself I think is a business model but
if you're starting from the point of
having a really well established brand
in a more in a more mature market you're
probably going to want to make sure that
that brand is being promulgated around
the country and you're not just no
seating competitors with the know-how
you've learned through your years of
trial and error one of the things that I
talk with my clients about a lot is
what's gonna happen to the market after
Interstate Commerce is allowed because a
lot of these you know not necessarily
robust companies and individual states
are just gonna get crushed from
competitiveness primarily from
California but you know there'll be
artists and brands in individual states
that stay you know strong and can hold
off the onslaught from places where it's
nicer to grow and maybe they've got more
in-state talent but I would think that
once interstate commerce is is something
that we can do that it will also impact
the likelihood of licenses and that that
whole ecosystem will change how do you
see Interstate Commerce impacting the
licensing market well it's a great
question so interstate commerce will and
will change things pretty dramatically
although I think interstate commerce is
gonna take a while to roll out so even
when it happens I don't think it's
something that happens you know
overnight
I think the state-by-state nature of
this probably stays in play for a
while as interstate commerce is opening
up but that you know that said I agree
with you I think companies that are
spending new tens of millions of dollars
building out new hundreds of thousands
of square feet of cultivation space in
the eastern half of the country you
might find themselves in some real
trouble when interstate commerce does
does open up I think interstate commerce
you're right I think is largely going to
be out west in terms of where the
cultivation is gonna happen you know the
atmospheric conditions in the eastern
half of the country are really tough for
cultivation much more humid you much
bigger temperature swings and so for all
those reasons I think you're gonna be
seeing a large-scale greenhouses in in
places like you know the Central Valley
of California and Arizona and Nevada
Colorado even high deserts with with
with your temperature spring swings and
and you'll see outdoor in you know many
in in in other places other parts of
California in particular you know as
it's a bit of an aside you know when we
talk about what we do at forefront and
you know we're very focused in the
eastern half of the country we do some
cultivation but it's very targeted and
we're not doing a really massive scale
cultivation because ultimately I think
when that when that comes this
commoditized is right I mean the prices
the wholesale prices are going to fall
you know bulk you fall through the floor
once you can grow in a massive scale
because ultimately like it's still a
plant and particularly if you're talking
about growing for extraction where you
don't really care as much about the
quality of the buds you just care about
volume right I mean the prices are gonna
come way way way down so when we look at
you know when we look at where we're
interested in playing the market we're
not really interested in large scale
cultivation they're gonna be a few
really big winners in that market but
there's gonna be a lot more losers
it's not you know we just say it's kind
of like likening and playing the end of
alcohol prohibition by buying a Hopf
farm right well you know if you want to
if you wanna you know you want to want
to do really well in the alcohol
industry you're the beer industry oh you
don't want to be a farmer you know and
hop farm so you wanna own brands you
want to own distribution right so you
want you want to own the the the
distributors you want to own the popular
brands you want to own those
distribution points but the hop farmers
are the victims it's the least
well part of the of the equation and I
think the same ultimately is gonna be
this is gonna be there for cannabis
which makes the brand side right come to
me back to your original question makes
the brand sites so much more important
because ultimately the feedstock that
goes into that brand is gonna be really
cheap and other than your really
high-end artisan cultivators like the
absolute best to the best right the
prices for raw material the prices for
raw flour is really gonna drop but
brands tend to hold their value quite a
bit better of course the value of those
brands will come down as well so in
different kinds of infused products
brands so edibles and fate pens and
everything else right those will hold
their value a bit more than the raw
material and the flowers themselves and
so I think establishing a really good
brand now that can go state to state to
state to state and establishes you and
establishes a a following for that brand
and in multiple states across the
country is gonna be particularly
valuable when the rails come down and
interstate commerce because those brands
are gonna then be able to buy their
product a lot cheaper to create their
product a lot cheaper and a ship
elsewhere around the country a lot
cheaper while the ball the value of
their brands well it will come down some
will hold this value a lot better than
the then the raw flowers right now
getting into that licensing game and
making sure that you're doing everything
you can to maximize the exposure of your
brand I think is really important
because you're gonna want to have those
distribution channels right if you're
Brent your brands become important but
being able to distribute those through
the distribution channels in the
industry also becomes incredibly
important the way that you get into
those distribution channels today if
your product manufacturer largely is to
license your brand to do manufacturers
in other states and eventually you know
if you do really well maybe you end up
acquiring those those companies that
you've licensed your brand's to down the
road or you pump way more product
through those license stores down the
road and increase your you know increase
your revenue that way I definitely think
that the big-time players are very aware
of this too and also the next level up
right because you know I'm at
conventions and at dinner and talking
with these guys
who are invested in highly scaling oil
folk right and they're like yeah you
know like we do our product
manufacturing and we are aggressively
licensing but we're not really all that
invested into the production of the
flowers to the materials to go into the
oil because they're all waiting for
international commerce well for the u.s.
to get involved with international
commerce because it's already occurring
we're just not playing in it
because everyone's waiting to like you
know you know what it's going to be like
to have all of this flower grown in
Mexico on inexpensive land with less
expensive labor they you know and they
certainly will have the the intellectual
property and talent to do the
extractions and then just shift the
finished product here or where people
will plug it into their actual products
I mean you talk about that to somebody
who hasn't really thought that through
in their single state business model and
you can just see their face go pale
whereas other hardcore players say for
example in California like they're
already planning on that happening
within the next 15 years and they're
they already know what they're gonna do
when that happens and I and I think that
that I think that that is shocking to
people who haven't considered it yeah
it's a great point I mean the
international piece of this is something
that's largely off the radar in the
United States but it shouldn't be
because it's you know it's already going
on you've got licenses for for large
scale cultivation and oil production in
Colombia which by the way is where most
of the the cut flower industry gets
their flowers from in the US if you go
into you know you buy it like yes yeah
yeah yeah interesting you go to your
supermarket you buy a bouquet of flowers
I mean chances are those are those
record in Colombia that most of the cut
flower industry has moved down there
over the last decade or so you know if
you're buying greenhouse produced
cucumbers or tomatoes or peppers in the
United States chances are those are
produced somewhere in Mexico it's
possible they're produced in southern
Arizona but most of that was produced in
Mexico and you're starting to see the
rest of the world catch on to this I
think the you know the idea that the
large-scale cannabis is going to be
grown in a warehouses in you know Ohio
is just silly I also think that when we
look at what's go
in the international scene you've got
Canadian companies that are building out
you know a million and a half square
feet of greenhouse space to you know
supposedly supply the global market in
you know places like Ontario and I just
I can't imagine that in the medium term
they're gonna be able to compete with
places like Mexico or Columbia or
Macedonia or Bulgaria or North Africa
right all places that are big
agricultural regions outside of cannabis
right I mean you think about know who's
gonna supply Europe well Kanna doesn't
make a whole lot of sense
Germany certainly doesn't make sense
right you got people investing in
massive green horses houses in Denmark
what's cold that it's it's gray in
Denmark it's cold it's gray in Canada
and the cost of living and cost of
expenses are really really high you look
at what I know I would look at like
where is all the tobacco in Europe grown
it's grown from Albania to Macedonia and
Bulgarian to Turkey it's like when you
you know when you get when you pack a
camels and it says fine Turkish tobacco
and most that's actually grown in
Macedonia Bulgaria
there's not even grow some it's still
grown in terms just Turkish health of
ours it's Turkish cultivars that's
exactly right but it's all grown in that
Bay it's the tobacco belt of Europe and
South Eastern Europe right like that's
where cannabis will grow more
efficiently the cost of living a
standard cost the production cost the
labor there is substantially cheaper
than anywhere in northern Europe
the same is gonna go for North America
and there's a reason why we don't do
large-scale commercial agriculture for
just about anything in Canada other than
trees right because it's it's expensive
and it's not a great climate for it and
so I think you know that to think that
like these Canadian companies are gonna
wind up being the suppliers for the
world I I think is kind of silly and you
know similarly if you're focused on you
know building a really large-scale
large-scale infrastructure for
cultivation and in most states in the
United States it's gonna be a tough sell
when first when interstate commerce
opens up but then also when
international commerce opens up new
again outside of I think there will be
some winners that come that can do this
on a large scale in certain places in
California in certain places in in
Arizona Nevada where you can build go to
conferences scale where they happen the
conditions are right for it but even
there I'll give you an anecdote from the
from from the the greenhouse producing
industry the the largest contiguous
greenhouse in North America I believe
still is actually in Wilcox Arizona it
was a company called euro fresh they
were the largest producers of greenhouse
cucumbers tomatoes and peppers in North
America mostly shipping into the
northern states in Canada and the winter
months well they were pretty much put
out of business by a very large scale
greenhouse setup in southern Mexico
right they just couldn't compete on
price with massive scale greenhouse
production coming out of southern Mexico
because cost of labor is so much cheaper
down there then is even in southern
Arizona where the atmospheric condition
is actually really good for greenhouse
production ironically the owner of that
greenhouse in some Mexico happens to be
the son of a former governor in the
state of Arizona that greenhouse put
like I said put out a business the
largest greenhouse producer of tomatoes
cucumbers and peppers in North America
in Arizona and the owner then went and
got one of those satellite greenhouses
not the largest one but the satellite
one of one of this company's large
larger satellite greenhouses in
snowflake Arizona and is now converted
that to being a cannabis house and is
now the largest a largest producer of
cannabis in the state of Arizona well
yeah the the the venture capital reacts
right it certainly does let me ask you
this for those of us who don't have the
same comparison scale as you have you
said a very large greenhouse and I think
Wilcox Arizona versus another bigger
greenhouse in southern Mexico how many
acres would you say each of those
greenhouses were just to give folks in
scale oh gosh general general idea I
mean it was like a few square miles
oh yeah like there Matt like we saw
satellite footage of the one in Wilcock
and you could see like a there was I
think a nine hole golf course on their
property and that was like it was like
1/10 of the whole property it's massive
massive you can see from sattell me if
you look at the satellite footage if you
if you if you you can actually put it in
I think if you put in euro fresh Wilcox
Arizona on on Google Earth or Google
Maps you can see it on there and it's I
mean it's it's huge right not cool well
thank you for going down
that international rabbit hole with me
I'm gonna circle us all the way back to
we are talking about the two sides of
licensing agreements and negotiating the
contract I would think that when the
licensee goes to implement the contract
that they have set up with the license
sore that that they will often implement
it incorrectly right either either
because you know they've not done it
before or because they want to make
their own changes have you seen you know
will poor implementations of license
contracts I have and that's where things
get tricky to actually take you back to
my earliest days and the industry side
of things here back when I was with a
company called can be which was it was
an offshoot of Harborside Health Center
is a consulting business and actually we
were we were way ahead of our time that
can be we were actually in the process
of getting a to be a the first cannabis
franchisor we were gonna franchise a
couple of dispensary brands including
Harborside back then before the company
went under but so that's actually where
I learned a lot about what you have to
do for franchising but you know
Harborside Health Center in Oakland one
of the one of the you know the best
known names and biggest dispensaries in
the country opened into their first
satellite location in San Jose and they
did it initially through a licensing
agreement in this was something that we
help them with it can be and the
consulting side of things was to help
get that new store up and running and so
they licensed the Harborside brand and
some of the protocols to Harborside San
Jose and so the owner was that the owner
Harborside San Jose was a different
owner than the owners of Harborside
Oakland the original store and that that
owner I won't name names frankly it's
been about a decade only remember the
name at this point but decided that you
know he wanted to do different things
without with with the way Harborside was
being run and so you know early on you
saw some all signs like he wanted
everybody wearing you know polo shirts
with the Harborside brand on them and
you know part of what part no part of at
least in Steve DeAngelo and the harbor
site owners minds who a part of what
made her besides such a great experience
was allowing their employees to express
their individuality so they didn't have
you know dress codes outside of you know
you can't wear something
it's inappropriate to work but they
wanted people to be able to express
their individuality to be able to relate
better to people who came them into the
stores and you know now you've got this
licensee you saying we want everybody in
a polo shirt
Harborside logo but it's just once it's
one small example there were a lot of
other things like that where the license
oh I think I can do better by doing XY
and Z and it caused some real
consternation amongst the original
Harborside owners who felt like well
this is not our brand you know this
isn't it's not even necessarily that
what they're doing is wrong but this
isn't our brand and we're really
concerned about the way that this brand
is being implemented because we want to
maintain the integrity of the Harborside
pram something that we put our blood
sweat and tears into and you know
ultimately it was a it was a little bit
of an ugly fight to to get control of
that and back and and I can't go into
the or I won't go into the details of
what happened because there was you know
there was a little bit of ugliness there
but you know by and large in the end he
Harborside owners were able to take that
back and they ended up you know they
they ended up I don't know whether it
was a buyout or exactly how it was
structured but basically took it took
that control of that San Jose store and
operated it as a company owned the store
you know so essentially a real satellite
Harbor side rather than a licensed
harbor side because they just felt that
through a licensing agreement like this
they weren't gonna be able to maintain
the integrity of their brand as well as
they could if they were operating
themselves or they could if they were
franchising it but that you know that
really wasn't an option at that point
right on that makes a lot of sense so
I've got one more question for you and
you know you have given a lot of ever in
how you want to go about establishing
your license but how also not how to
screw it up and so I'm sure that when
you when you are you know at conventions
like I am and you're overhearing people
talking about their their their efforts
to license and and sometimes you hear
something cringe and you know you hear
something that makes you cringe and
we've heard a lot of those things today
but what is one good piece of advice
that you can offer people who are
seeking to license their brand outside
their origination state that they may
not be thinking about and you hope to
god they do think about oh I mean I
think the two big thing
and we've hit on on both of these at
various points but I mean the two bigs
that jump out at me is number one have a
really good corporate attorney with
experience in franchise law even if
you're just doing licensing to make sure
you're not running afoul of accent on
franchise laws as I mentioned but you'll
make sure things are papered up really
really really well if you want to be
able to protect your brand you have to
have a good contract that you can that
you can rely on to you know as much as
it's you know I'm not a litigious person
you've got to have a good attorney from
the very beginning to help you set this
thing off right to help you structure it
the right way to help you write your
contracts the right way having that
having that having an having an attorney
there is absolutely critical and then
the second thing is make sure you're
really comfortable with the people that
you are licensing to so do as much
diligence as you possibly can on the
principles and the managers of the
company that you're licensing to you
know really dig deep into who they are
talk about you know talk about their
their past business experience ask for
references as to talk to people that
they've worked with in the past asked if
they've done licensing agreements and
how those have gone in the past but you
don't you know don't just rush into a
deal because you really want to be in a
state and you found somebody who's
willing to pay you the money because
ultimately if you wind up in bed with
the wrong person it can be really
painful in a really expensive process so
you really really want to do your
diligence well you really want to feel
comfortable because ultimately you're
entrusting your brand or your protocols
to this person and this company
potentially for you know for a decade or
more and you want to make sure that
they're gonna do right by it that
they're not gonna bring you know
disrepute to your brand which ultimately
will reflect negatively on you because
when it comes down to it the consumer
doesn't know if they're buying a brand
in one state versus another state the
consumer doesn't know whether that was
licensed or whether that was produced by
the same company that produced it in the
first state and so if somebody does
something wrong with your brand and and
and and and you bring some sorta
disrepute to your brand that reflects on
your brand all around the country and
you can deal with some of that through
litigation you could deal with some of
that through contracts if you have to
but the whole point is to not get there
in the first place not have to do that
kind of damage control and the best way
you can do that is to make sure that
you're really really comfortable with
whoever you're
gonna be working with and thinking about
licensing your brand or your protocols -
I think you really hit on the point
solidly when you say you know remember
that this is a long term relationship
because you know I think it's good
advice for folks when they're looking at
somebody to date and to being a
long-term relationship with you know
choose somebody who fights in a way that
you feel reasonable right because like
if you date somebody who fights fair or
fights dirty you very well could end up
with a really ugly breakup but if you if
you if you get in a relationship with
somebody who is at least respectful
enough that you can fight fairly if you
do break up chances are it won't
necessarily be ugly and it surprises me
sometimes when I meet these folks who
are aggressively licensing you know
they're working on three or four or five
state deals at the same time and you
know I understand their priority that
they want to quick and get them done so
they can move on they've got a busy day
but at the same time this is a serious
relationship and and I always recommend
that you know you you go to the state
you meet with them try to you know try
to have more than dinner you know try to
do something with them because you can
learn a lot by about the communication
of the other management team by how they
speak to their spouse or the rental car
that they choose to drive or how they
handle who's paying the check really
simple things like that we can all pick
up on oh all right I see how they would
be under stress because this is how they
are in their normal life and and I think
a lot of people figure out well you know
we're all papered up everything I'm
protected legally let's just move
forward and I tell them you know you
really need to get some more face time
with these folks because you really are
getting into a relationship with them
yeah I mean if you're you know if you're
at the point where you're having to
enforce legal agreements right you're
already at a really painful point so the
whole point is to not get there and
frankly you can have really good
contracts and really good legal
agreements and if you have an
unscrupulous person the other side it
could be really painful and really
expensive even if you ultimately wind up
winning right I mean I say once you get
to the point where you're in a lawsuit
or you're in arbitration with somebody
the only winner is there or the attorney
yeah right for everybody else involved
it's really painful it's really
challenging
usually wind up settling where you know
nobody's really happy with the way
things came out I think your advice to
spend time with them and see how they
interact with things is really good if
anything you can do to get somebody
under stress but then to see how they
respond to stress before you get into
that relationship with them that kind of
business relationship with them and I
think that goes for licensing it goes
for partnerships right jayvees any of
these things are really important
because it's easy to get along somebody
when everything's going fine when you're
talking about all the money you're gonna
make together and the deal you're gonna
do together and no everything's great
and he'll stress it and that's when you
see people's true colors and on that
note you know I actually think one of
the one of the better ways and this set
this this is gonna sound up it may sound
a bit odd but one of the better ways to
see how somebody deals with stress in
particularly stress in an adversarial
relationship is actually through a a
tough contract negotiation it's through
the negotiation for the licensing
agreement itself so that's something I
think you don't necessarily in a rush
because this is the one time when you
are actually adversarial so you go from
you know you meet somebody you talk
about we should do some business
together right everything's rosy
everybody's happy everybody loves the
idea right it's not adversarial at all
you're really happy together
that's you know that's kind of like the
you know the honeymoon dating phase and
then then you got to get things papered
up and then you start bringing lawyers
in and then there's provisions of
contrast that they they're they're not
gonna like this provisions you're not
gonna like there's push and pull it is
inherently an adversarial relationship
and I've always found this to be a
little bit odd because you go from
everything's great to all sudden we're
on opposite sides and we're each pushing
for what's in our own interests as
opposed to the other person's interests
and then as soon as that's done you're
in the boat together and everything's
good again right and you're on the same
team again and so it's this weird
interim time when you're negotiating a
contract when if you you know if you do
make it a real negotiation you get a
window into how somebody's gonna respond
in an adversarial stressful relationship
and I've actually had situations where
I've been in contract negotiations with
somebody and ultimately said you know
what what not interested into his deal
like the the dollars and cents are there
the you know the the anything else lines
up but but you guys are a-holes
yeah but
but it's been a nightmare to deal with
in all this and what's gonna happen when
we have a disagreement over the business
right if this is a nightmare
that's gonna be even worse and so I
think you can learn a lot from
contracting about how some was gonna
respond and if you get a bad feeling
about like I just don't like the way
these guys are handling that you should
probably walk away from that deal that's
awesome Chris thank you so much for
taking the time to be on the show and
sharing your vast experience in this
this deeply going topic area really
appreciate your time and you sharing
what you know with all of us absolutely
thank you for having me on if you want
to connect with Chris Crane directly you
can reach him at the fore front Ventures
website that's four front ventures
dot-com and the four in the front of
front it's the number four so it's the
number four front ventures calm and if
you want to check out their newly
rolling out retail brand called mission
you can check that out at their website
mission can calm that's mission see am
calm you can find more episodes of the
shaping fire podcast and subscribe to
the show at shaping fire calm and on
Apple iTunes stitcher and Google Play if
you enjoyed the show we'd really
appreciate it if you'd leave a positive
review of the podcast wherever you
download your review will help others
find the show so they can enjoy it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the weekly newsletter for
insights into the latest cannabis news
and product reviews on the shaping fire
website you will also find transcripts
of today's podcast as well for
information on me and where I'll be
speaking you can check out Shango lows
Calm your company want to reach our
national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hotspot at shaping
feiyr.com
to find out how thanks for listening to
shaping fire I've been your host Shango
lows
[Music]