[Music]
for pretty much everybody in cannabis
except seed makers male Canada's plans
are a scourge for breeders male cannabis
plants are joyful thing and essential to
the advancement of cannabis genetics and
the creation of regular seed but for
nearly all hobby medical and commercial
growers though males are a pain in the
ass if you find a male in your garden
too late
he will pollinate your entire crop and
decrease its potency and ease of smoking
because the flowers will all be full of
seeds feminized seeds play an important
role in cannabis nowadays feminized
means that just about every seed will
produce a female plant for home growers
it means less room wasted on plants that
will eventually show that they are male
and for commercial growers it means less
risk of pollen in their fields if you
want to learn about cannabis health
business and technique efficiently and
with good cheer I encourage you to
subscribe to our newsletter will send
you new podcast episodes as they come
out deliver right to your inbox along
with commentary on a couple of most
important news items from the week and
videos - don't rely on social media to
let you know when a new episode is
published sign up for the updates - make
sure you don't miss an episode
also we're giving away very cool prizes
to folks who are signed up to receive
the newsletter there's nothing else you
need to do to win except receive that
newsletter so go to shaping fire calm to
sign up for the newsletter and be
entered into this month's and all future
newsletter prize drawings you are
listening to shaping fire and I'm your
host Shango lows today my guest is caleb
inspector from CSI humble caleb and his
family have lived in Humboldt County for
over a hundred years for the last 40
years
three generations of his family have
cultivated extraordinary sensimilla
cannabis in Humboldt Mendocino in
Trinity counties caleb reaches way back
and works with significant strains
recreating them in new and interesting
ways today we're gonna talk with him
about modern feminized seeds
welcome to the show Caleb good to be
here right on man
so let's start by getting a little
better understanding of the tech the
terminology we're gonna use today
because you know when most people are
talking about the kinds of seeds were
going to talk about today a lot of
people just use the words feminized but
you know the more I study it and the
more I listen to people
who actually breed feminized seeds more
of them use the term selfed and and you
know then people are talking about s1
seeds their first generation of Femmes
and and on your seed packets they say s1
so would you kind of get us all in the
same page by talking about the
difference in terminology between
feminized seeds and selfed seeds and
what that all means
well basically selfed
only refers to s ones which is a plant
cross to itself feminized seeds is
generally it encompasses selfed as well
but it also covers all the feminized
hybrids when you know say for example
you reverse one female and you cross it
to you know x y&amp;z female those are all
feminized you know hybrids hmm you you
don't refer to the hybrids as selfed or
you know s ones obviously you you only
refer to the the individual you know
plant that was soft on to itself as
solved
I see so so you know I cross for a self
seed would be for example chem dog by
chem dog versus versus chem dog versus
whatever else you're gonna cross it with
yep all right so I see so so so s1 sir
selfs are actually a subset of this
bigger tent that is feminized seeds all
right go ahead and you know to add to
that feminized seeds got a bad rep early
on because the the selfed while they
might be the closest best example of a
particular plant you know just crossing
it to itself there's a lot of inbreeding
going on in that and so anywhere from 40
to 60% of those seeds generally I just
say 50% are going to be inbred and just
kind of throw away plants whereas with
the hybrids you
you get the same hybrid vigor from a
feminized hybrid as you do from a normal
hybrid so you know people kind of
misconstrued the whole self thing with
feminized seeds in general when that
wasn't even a fact right on cool so I
want to talk more about the the early
days of feminized and the bad reputation
but before we leave S ones and selfed
seeds when when you when you self a seed
or when you self a plant you're doing
that too you know one expression of one
Fino of that line will will the seeds
produced by selfing a plant give you
snapshots of all the fee nosed available
in that line or where they all be that
exact Fino of the plant yourself in oh
you will rarely get the exact plant it's
basically going to encompass all the
genetics contained in the DNA of that
plant and depending on how stable that
plant is it can be you know fairly tight
to extremely broad a lot of people think
they're gonna get an exact replica of
the mother and that's not true at all
you're gonna get everything from the
absolute worst inbred genetic that that
DNA contains you know in the recessive
traits to the absolute best which often
times in s ones you find stuff that's
way better than the mother plant that
was soft in the first place
Wow right on so so what I'm gathering
from that is that you know when you buy
a packet s ones that's really a pack for
somebody who is planning on you know
digging breeding or looking for fee
knows it's not necessarily you know a
stabilized pack that somebody would buy
because they want they want they want to
know what they're gonna get right with s
ones you really don't know what you're
gonna get if you if you're gonna buy a
pack of seven or ten seeds you may have
you know seven or ten different
expressions of the line absolutely yes
oh right on okay good alright so then
let's let's
back to the bad reputation that
feminised seeds have had for a long time
so so because I work so much with
patients you know I realized early on
how useful feminized seeds can be for
patients because you know they're it's
so sad to see a patient pop ten seeds
and you know you know if you're gonna
pop a hundred or more seeds you you were
probably gonna generally see fifty fifty
male and female but at such a small
number above ten you could get any ratio
statistically and an occasional you'll
you'll find a you know a patty or you
know ten seeds and you'll get like six
or seven males and four you know a
breeder that would be fun but for for a
patient they're like oh my God all my
resources and all this soil and all this
space I just used for you know these six
or seven males that I'm gonna call and
so when I realize that oh my god we
could just get these people into
feminized seeds and all 10 will be
females I'm like hell yeah like I'm want
this but but as I told people I was
getting into this you know folks were
like oh man feminized seeds like suck
and they don't have the vigor and they
Herm on me and all all this kind of
stuff and and but then if you ask him if
you like really kind of drill down you
find out that either a they haven't
tried a feminized seed in years or be
like they heard it from their bro you
know and so you know give us a little
context if you will about you know the
how feminized seeds have gotten better
you know since they started showing up
in the scene and and what your thoughts
are on today's femme seeds versus the
the stuff that where people are
originally popping I think a lot of
people were really focused on just the S
ones early on and so they had a lot of
those recessive inbred genetics coming
out and so when you popped your films
you ended up with you know like I said
about 50% just weak inbred plants well
when folks started realizing wait you
need to you know make you know hybrids
of it then you you get this you know
that vigor back and then of course the
herm thing
it's definitely valid I mean
unfortunately you know in today's you
know a cannabis landscape most of the
popular stuff is a result of no
selection and you know just you know
hermaphrodite a plant onto hermaphrodite
a plant you know and so on and so on and
so you definitely you know will get a
certain percentage of hermaphrodites in
feminized seeds but that also depends on
their environment
you know in indoors it's it's gonna be
higher
you know outdoors you know most of the
times it's gonna be non-existent you
know unless you really really stress
something out or the genetics that you
know the FEM feminine were really prone
to hermaphroditic so what's the variable
between indoor and outdoor that causes
the the her mning more indoors you know
I don't know I honestly you know I mean
indoors where we're putting such extreme
stress on a plant you know taking it out
out of its natural environment you know
exposing it to this that the other a lot
of times you know light leaks you know I
mean not everybody has just you know
light tight rooms so something as simple
as that you know easy to you know stress
something out and I would also think
that you know since so much of this
reputation is built on forum posts you
know when you're indoors you are
stressing a plant you know like an
Olympian you know it's ahead it's
healthy and thriving but it is under
stress even at its best right at the the
best-run room and you know the majority
of people are not running you know like
put together rooms
and so so just about everybody is taking
a plant that is already stressed and
then and then stressing it out more by
you know changing their inputs or you
know their power goes out or whatever
whatever and so so you've got that that
added challenge indoors as well
yeah and you know honestly I I've always
I've always thought that the roots are
kind of the core to you know whether a
plant will hermaphrodite or not and
indoors you're most people are generally
using smaller pots you know three
gallons five gallons whatever you know
compared to you know outdoors where
you're using 20 100 200 gallon oars and
when you keep the roots happy you know
the whole plant is happy I think that's
true with everything right yeah you know
so indoors you know you got the small
root balls it's easy to just you know
tilt them one way or the other to make
them unhappy I mean too dry too wet too
much nutrient too little nutrient you
know anything like that you know too
cold too hot it goes on and on but any
of those extremes you know are going to
you know change change that plants you
know yeah how its gonna express itself
because you know you piss off you piss
off that raizo sphere and suddenly it's
sending all these different messages off
the plant yeah yeah so so the other
thing too you mentioned is like you know
a lot of people are just looking to well
alright I guess that's not fair I was
gonna say a lot of people are just
looking to make money and seeds and
that's certainly true but there's
there's also people who are in it who
are just cookies right and and and and
they don't really have maybe the space
or the experience to do the kind of sips
that you do I mean we we all see like
the the way people put out seeds right
now where they're like okay I got I got
one mail and I'm gonna hit it to the ten
hot strains in my area and I'm just
gonna rush that stuff out and you know
that stuff you know has not been sifted
properly
and probably not even tested right
they're just running them out the door
while it's hot and and so to that degree
I think that what you're saying probably
applies to FEM seeds the same way it
applies to reg seeds where hey men
there's good Femmes on the market and
there's you know sketchy Femmes on the
market so no your frickin breeder oh
absolutely absolutely no not only no
your breeder but no your genetics you
know because I mean you can you can give
a dozen different breeders the same
exact cut and they're gonna be playing
with the same exact you know potential
that same variability that same you know
you know possibility of everything that
comes out of that cuts gonna be a
hermaphrodite mm-hmm you know and that's
that's where the bad reputation comes
from and really ruins your run yeah so
um so you mentioned a little bit earlier
about how the you know the the Femmes
have got the same vigor as as a reg
version of it is and you know I often
hear people kind of get confused who
don't know a lot about the breeding side
because they get them kind of confused
with autos right because with with autos
which I'm also a fan of you you get
these you know you get whatever the
let's take like a and Auto Girl Scout
cookies for example all right so so
people go alright well that's not really
like Girl Scout cookies anymore that's
actually a new keema var that's Girl
Scout cookies crossed with a ruderalis
plant from Siberia right and so you you
are definitely taking a step away from
the original phenotypical package of any
particular kima var but if I you know
the way I understand it that is not the
case with Femmes because you're not you
know you know you you you will either
get the the full package of an S one of
that one plant or if you're gonna
hybridize it to another one you're gonna
get
you know the essentially clean fie nose
of of those two plants together but
isn't a third plant added to the mix
like in autos which is bringing in all
these like kind of wild Rudy genetics
from Russia and so so so Femmes really
should be just like you would expect the
the Reg version to be yeah so so let's
let's get to the heart of that you know
that query because most people don't
understand where Femmes come from period
right and and that's where a lot of the
confusion comes from so would you kind
of go through how feminized seeds are
made you know people you know you ask a
lot of people and they'll give you one
of two answers he'll either say oh don't
you like dump colloidal silver on them
and then the other folks you know
referred to Matt riots FEM spray right
and so so this is the part of it that
I'm least familiar with as well so will
you kind of just talk about the the
various ways of getting to feminized
seeds well basically I've always used
STS so silver thiosulfate and you know
what a lot of people don't realize this
might be a little bit of a tangent but
what a lot of people don't realize is
it's not that easy I mean I've got
buddies who have tried to reverse you
know 20 30 plants and have never had a
successful reversal where they got seeds
you know let alone even pollen from
their reverse plants why n why is that I
mean what's the failure point you know
if I knew I'd share I mean I'm good
buddies with with Matt riot and I mean
you know we we chat about this same
topic quite often and you know it's not
unusual for me to have a failed reversal
run it's not unusual for him you know to
have a failed one and I mean I've used
his spray eyeball generally I've always
used my spray
but I've you know tried his spray and
I've also tried my other buddy hyb his
hypertext spray and it's really variable
on what works when it works and you know
how well it works
yeah and it's it's not an exact science
that's true that's for sure
right on so do you do you think that you
know and I know I know that I'm asking
you to guess here cuz you already said
you don't know for sure but do you think
that do you think that it probably has
more to do with how a particular plants
genetics accepts it or do you think it's
about method and people are just not
doing it right
it definitely has a lot to do with the
individual plants certain people
absolutely it's got to be method because
you know if you can't reverse you know
20-plus plants there's something going
on that's not quite right and their
method I'd imagine but you know I've
successfully done you know plenty of
reversals and sometimes you get tons
upon tons of seeds blah blah blah and
other times you get no pollen and
sometimes you get loads of pollen and
almost no seed so you know it's just
like huh I don't get this but you know I
don't claim to be an expert but I'm I'm
in a very active student right on right
on it
and in artisan as well so I'm gonna ask
I'm gonna want to go more into the STS
but before we like go past it will you
address the colloidal silver thing is
this just an outmoded method okay so I'm
more uh I'm fairly busy let's put it
that way and with chloral silver that
reversal method you essentially have to
spray and spray and spray I think you
have to spray every day and honestly
that just doesn't work with
you know my style or my workload and so
I need something where you know I only
have to spray it you know one time maybe
twice and I'm good so that's you know
why I go with the STS and you know
lately I've just been spraying the one
time you know when I trigger that
reversal plant if I was using colloidal
I'd have to spray every single day that
plant and that's a lot of spring
yeah for sure it was so what do you
think about its reliability so let's say
that you know we've got a home grower
who wants to make you know some reversed
there wants to reverse their plant but
they only have four plants they need to
worry about and spraying everyday is
easy you know do do does it have the
same quality of results or likelihood of
success as using STS if you've got that
time if you've got that time I know
plenty of people who have you know had
good success with that you know it's a
lot of you know hobbyist type work yeah
you know you got a oftentimes you you
got to kind of make it yourself
right basically just from raw silver and
yeah I've never entertained that much
time right on fair enough so um so what
I'd like to do right now is would you
take us through step by step you know
you don't you don't have to you be
overly elaborate but but um you know
would you walk us through what you're
doing with the STS spray that causes the
feminized seeds if you could just break
it down into steps so that people who
really want to picture it in their head
what what did it looks like or maybe
they're actually looking for actionable
information because they want to go and
try this would just break it out for us
would you
I'll do my best all right thank you
basically you're spraying some form of
silver on your plants whether it's
colloidal silver or silver thiosulfate
and you spray it
your target female and the silver acts
as a ethylene inhibitor and the ethylene
is what you know makes your plant female
so by inhibiting the ethylene production
you are essentially changing the hormone
balance I guess in the plant to exhibit
you know a male and you know if if all
goes well with your spray and your
timing and everything then your your
mail your reversed female male plant
will uh will give you pollen roughly in
four to six weeks from the time you
first spray so this this plant that we
just sprayed with the STS our goal with
that plant is just to get male flowers
to be produced and then we will collect
that pollen and then hit that to a
second plant we're not so the idea isn't
necessarily that oh we want the plant to
have both male and female flowers and
then self pollinate no we're taught
we're talking about we want to force
this female plant to make pollen so we
can take her and hit something else oh
yeah right although although some people
do do individual branch spraying on a
plant and then they can take it'll only
reverse the one branch and and it'll
pollinate you know you can pollinate the
rest of the plant that hasn't been spray
yeah that's the only way I've ever seen
it actually and so the idea of doing a
whole plant and collecting a pollen
sounds like could be a hell of a lot
easier they have been going branch by
branch I mean me personally when I do my
reversals I'm I'm generally reversing
four to eight plants that are they
generally finish out at about three to
five feet tall
and you know two to three feet around so
I'm I'm reversing some pretty big plants
but I'm also pollinate and you know
good-sized rooms as well so I need a lot
of a lot of pollen and a lot of people
don't know but you do not get even
remotely close to as much pollen from a
reverse plant as you do a regular male
plant so that's why you need the you
definitely need them because like
normally a male pollen a male plant
giving off pone there's a hell of a lot
of pollen in there and so that's why you
have to do multiple so so if you're
going to be doing four or six of these
are you are you doing your best to make
sure that these females are either you
know from the same Fino of seed or are
you taking one primary mother making
clones of her so they are all the same
fee no and then and then reversing that
the majority of plants I reverse are all
just heirloom cuts you know so yeah
they're they're all all the same
cuttings and one other thing I do is I
stagger him because in early on I I had
plenty of failed runs and when I'm
trying to reverse in pollinate a room
and half the time it was because the
reversal plant either dropped pollen too
early and missed the window or it
dropped pollen too late and missed the
window and I'd get you know a 10% seated
room which that doesn't really help me
or anybody yeah you know and so nowadays
what I do is is I'll pollinate I'll
reverse I'll reverse a female you know a
week or two in advance of flowering the
rest of the room out then all then I'll
do a you know a couple more at the
trigger date and then you know and I'll
also use different different different
STS products different STS
concentrations that cetera etc so so
you're trying a variety so that
somewhere in the mean of this somewhere
in the middle every
we'll get the particular combination it
needs since everybody's so finicky yeah
it's just a you know trying trying to
circumvent failure yeah yeah better your
odds a little bit
so so clearly if these reversed plants
produce less pollen and everybody in the
room is more finicky this of course
increases the value of each bit of
pollen and you know storing pollen can
really be a [ __ ] and it goes bad so
easily do you find you know it in your
process are you collecting the pone and
saving it or are you all like you know
oh no I'm just gonna put you all in the
same room and and it's gonna happen live
without any saving of the pollen I
always do it alive I've I would love to
you know have faith and saving it but
just like you said you know I don't have
trust
for saving the pollen so it it would it
would be pretty miserable to be like I
got this room and you know throw a ton
of pollen out there and you get 17 seeds
you know yeah totally and and where I
was going with that is that it was do
you have a a pollen storage technique
that you trust and I'm thinking the
answer's no I've never even bothered to
store pollen yeah right on right on so I
should I should but you know it just is
one of the things that I haven't gotten
into right on and like you said earlier
like it's something that you can do with
all that extra time you've got right all
right cool well with that let's uh let's
go ahead and take our first commercial
break you were listening to shaping fire
and my guest today is Caleb Inspectah
from CSI humble as a listener of shaping
fire you already understand the
importance of living soil when growing
cannabis when you have active microbe
communities in your substrate you go way
beyond simply fertilizing with nitrogen
phosphorus and potassium having active
microorganisms in your substrate
supports vigorous plant growth
throughout the plants root zone making
for higher yields and thriving flowers
mammoth pee is the first organically
derived microbial inoculant that focuses
on your plants nutrient cycling
processes to release soil phosphorus and
other micronutrients from they're bound
forms making them more available to the
plant increased levels of phosphorus
will also keep internode shorter and
focus your plants energy on bud
production not only that but the
microbes act as a defense shield for the
plants rhizosphere by out competing
potentially harmful pathogenic microbes
pretty cool right
mammoth pee not only unlocks the
nutrients in your soil but it also helps
protect your plant from disease mammoth
Peas beneficial bacteria act like
microbial reactors continually producing
enzymes that release nutrients mammoths
pee was developed at a u.s. university
has been extensively tested by Colorado
growers and independent laboratories
mammoth pee is proven to increase growth
and enhance blooming one of the great
things about supplementing with
microorganisms is that they won't
compete with whatever fertilizer program
you're already running simply dose on
top of your fertilizer schedule for
increased benefits to learn more and to
find out where you can buy namma pee
near you check out their website at
www.opm.gov/tribalprograms differ from
ornamental crops can be the start of a
world of hurt erik Branstad and his team
at greenhouse advisory group have the
experience and technical know-how to
help you avoid these pitfalls Erik
Branstad has been helping cannabis
growers find locations design build and
equip their greenhouses for over a
decade first starting in Northern
California but expanding over the last
five years to helping clients throughout
the world he has an impeccable
reputation for both depth of knowledge
and kindness and communication you can
hear Erik explain some of the challenges
facing
Animus greenhouses and how to overcome
them in episode number 41 of the shaping
fire podcast no matter where I go in the
country good people with smart
backgrounds still are making the mistake
of building without knowing cannabis and
it causes them to burn through capital
and time fast everyone has their own
failure point for some it is improper
ventilation planning for others it is
surface temperatures of the building or
the plants leaves or both some folks
that build their greenhouse from scratch
make really basic errors like placement
of the greenhouse on the property or not
understanding the natural environment
where the greenhouse sits
some have even built a decent greenhouse
but are inefficient in their deployment
of light deprivation techniques and
never really hit their target yields
it's great when you learn from your
mistakes but it's even better when you
learn from the mistakes of others when
you bring on greenhouse advisory group
you will learn from the mistakes of
their many clients and you'll take
advantage of the best practices
developed by Eric Branstad over his
years of working with clients just like
you from location development to
choosing a builder and tricking out your
new greenhouse or retrofitting or
rescuing your failing greenhouse Eric
will help you through it
visit greenhouse advisory group com to
learn more and connect with Eric and his
team that's green house advisory group
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire I'm your host Shango Louis
and our guest this week is caleb
Inspectah from CSI Humboldt
so during the first set we talked a lot
generally about feminized seeds and what
they are and what they aren't but during
the second set Caleb I want to talk more
about your particular approach to to you
know building feminized seeds you know
the great interview that you did with
Kevin Joe tree at wonderland nursery
during the Wunderland seed series you
know Kevin definitely made the
suggestion that you do significant seed
sifts right you are you are very active
in popping a lot of seeds and you put a
lot of thought into your choices which
you know I wish would I wish that a lot
more people are doing that but I would
you know to give people an idea
of you know how to sift and what a sift
looks like would you just kind of walk
us through what you typically do when
you're when you're hunting for the
keepers so generally from every reversal
I'll usually sprout anywhere from 200 to
500 seeds and a lot of them are you know
just feminized hybrids
I'll also you know run out the S ones as
well best ones I usually do separate and
those are usually in hundred Lots or two
hundred Lots but for the feminized ones
I just like to you know get a good idea
of everything that's contained in you
know in the seeds I sell and you know
just see how things combine and usually
you know the the funnest part is you
know watching them all grow selecting
selecting out you know you hurt your
favorite your terpenes and you know all
your favorite plants out of them and
then of course at the end you know you
gotta go through and sample and figure
out really which ones you know make it
from your your favorite growing plants
to your favorite smoking plants it's
it's it's a big process so when you are
so like let's talk about like what your
call points are right so so you the
first call probably happens naturally
the ones that just straight up don't
germinate you're like okay those those
aren't those genetics are not gonna be
part of it and then I'm assuming that
you probably do another call just for
you know mediocre plants that aren't
really thriving right and but but when
do you start what's your first call for
plants that are not obviously failing
right the ones that failed they're out
of the mix but but but how soon do you
start saying that plant doesn't look or
isn't expressing self in a way that I
want to keep you you know and and this
this is something that a lot of people
do I think for one
I usually have a pretty high gem right
so I usually have between 98 and 99
percent germ so I'm not having a big
call as far as you know just you know
seeds that don't sprout and I rarely
kill a plant I I like to see every
single plant you know go start to finish
no matter how small of a rut it is you
know no matter how weak it looks cuz
honestly some of the best plants I've
ever come across have been these little
weak runty just you know weirdo plants
now are they gonna be great for breeding
probably not
you know usually you're not gonna
forward them but I still like to give
them a chance and see what they have
I've seen tons of breeders who you know
think that you know they can call it the
seedling stage or think they can call
you know in early veg and they're making
their decisions they're mostly making
their decisions on structure and you
know vigor which you know for certain
things that's great but you know for a
final finished product that has nothing
to do with that you know what I mean
yeah totally and and there could totally
be something in one of these runts let's
say that it's a runt but you're like oh
my gosh it's got this terpene profile
that's out of the world if you would
have culled it early you wouldn't have
smelled that and and now you know to
look for it elsewhere in the sift but
also you know if it's an attribute that
you particularly think is badass maybe
you're like okay I'm gonna I'm gonna
take that plant and do something with it
to maybe help it not express as a runt
but also keep that terpene or whatever
variable right right exactly so you know
to grow out that many plants that's a
lot of freaking space so are you do you
run them in one gallons or you know or
shorter
oh no no III predominantly just use
you know raised beds so my beds are four
foot by four foot by about one foot deep
and I'll generally run anywhere from 16
plants in a bed 281 plants I mean it
that's really close yeah yeah I mean I
just did a little last year I did a run
where I had either 72 or 81 chem dog
hybrids in every single bed and I mean I
had probably less than a 10% drown out I
mean most everything in those beds you
know finished up just perfectly fine
didn't get drowned out and I got a you
know sizable sample of each one to you
know make my assessments and judgments
on so when you run them that close are
you doing a lot of D leafing or are you
leaving them just as the seed intended
so you can actually find the ones that
are leafy ER and Leslie fiour um it
definitely varies but I will I have no
problems kind of a taking off the the
fan leaves you know I don't like
overdoing it but I won't you know let
them overlap and just completely you
know over overload a bed with leaves so
definitely a lot of cleanup on the
underneath and also uh I don't know if
this is the right part to throw this in
but I always make sure about you know
two weeks in the flower I your two to
two and a half weeks let's put it that
way I'll clean up all the lowers I won't
clean them up early just because I want
to see what type of firm expressions the
plants put on and you won't see that
until two to three weeks into flower so
you know I leave all that undergrowth on
them and until that time and then I
clean them all up and I check every
single plant and you'll be able to see
you know any any herm troubles and a lot
of times you know
you know these plants will have maybe
like one ball here or you know just a
couple balls per plant mm-hmm
most of them generally aren't you know
don't have any and then very few are
really bad hers I usually see a a really
bad herm indoors
maybe one or two per hundred plants you
know and when they are her me like that
indoors you know obviously you are
checking them constantly right because
this is this is what you do but are they
a threat to the rest of your crop no not
generally I mean basically I'm not
checking them constantly at all I check
them in that window of two to two and a
half weeks into flower and that's gonna
be the window
where they will be visible they'll be
expressing but they won't be dropping
pollen and sabotaging your room and so
as long as you check your plants at that
time you know it doesn't matter if
you're doing rag seeds if you're doing
feminized seeds you know hell it doesn't
even matter if you're doing clones from
the dispensary or whatever I mean you
know it should be you know a
prerequisite that you check your plants
in that window you know and make sure
you know otherwise you get what you get
so so alright so so you're you're doing
this sift of a few hundred plants and
you are looking for the particular
traits that you want for that run so you
know and I know you grow a lot of
different types of plants for four
different expressions and and honestly
how you express your craft - right
they're not your you you have a pretty
wide variety the kinds of seeds that
that you like to make so so let's say
that so you've gone through the sift are
you trying to find you know your two
favorites that you think will have
create the best seeds among those two or
are or are you gonna do this cycle
several times and cross and re-cross so
that you
can pull out multiple traits that you
want like do you have to commit to two
at this point or or are you actually
going to commit to you know four to six
and then work with those and bring those
down to your final you know pair that
you're going to bring to the market
honestly um I I make selections but I
rarely end up keeping them for very long
just because I grow so much so so many
different things out and I always just
just you know for me personally I always
save the mother stock versus any hybrids
so most of the time the hybrids even if
they're just absolutely amazing you know
they end up going by the wayside just to
make sure my mother stock is you know
happy and healthy and has plenty of room
the the predominant sifting I do for
keepers is in the s1 stock where that
that's actually gonna be the second
phase of my company because I don't
remake any of any of these hybrids in
general I'm and I'm only making I'm only
reversing them and making the seeds so I
have s1 stock to go through and refine
the s wands you know into you know
exactly the direction I want to go and
and so the second phase of my company is
going to be to make all these s2 lines
and then from there you know I think
I'll go to s/3 s/3 might be the limit I
think that's where you're just gonna get
too much inbreeding past that but you'll
be able to have you know as we're fine
as you need for like future hybrids
you're like so it's like you're it's
that so by going to s2 and s3 you're
essentially making a very stable library
Abul seed stock
that you can put on ice and no if you if
you want to call on that you know that
genetic line again in you know six or
ten or twelve years that you've got it
encapsulated from this work absolutely
but also that that stock say say I have
ten different things that are in that s2
s3 form well I can start making true
feminised F ones you know because each
when each line is you know just rock
salt and stable then you you combine
those together and you're gonna have
something completely different than you
know that original f1 where it's just
you know say a amend Oh purple times of
purple Arkell you know if you work both
those lines you know for multiple
generations on their own and then you
know create stable on both sides and
they cross them together it's gonna
create something way different than just
that original mother times mother you
know yeah talking about that that s1
variability you know I can imagine that
a hobby grower who wants to get you know
a bunch of plants that are similar you
know alright phenotypically different
but reliable you know they wouldn't want
an s-1 because there's so much noise in
the in the line but I would think that
as you know for those of us who are
canvas plant nerds right who just love
to see all her expressions right that
that that that packing popping s ones
even though it'll be losers in there you
know a lot of them I think that that
would be really fun just for the joy of
like getting all these what the [ __ ]
plants like oh my god what is this oh
yeah oh yeah no I I love s once s ones
are I don't think there's a single s one
line I've run yet that hasn't just been
a pleasure you know well that's a that's
a good recommendation so so so while
we're talking about all the the weird
the weirdness of it and and the things
that are in the the hidden recesses of
these genetic lines you know you know
you
you and I are both fans of feminized
seeds and yet sometimes you know some of
the these ultra purists will say that
they're they're not down with feminized
seeds because they're they're unnatural
and and and anything that comes from
stressing or forcing the plant is is you
know an abomination right they may be
useful but it's not what nature intended
and I just like to hear what your
thoughts are on the the potential
unnaturalness of feminized seeds I'd
like to ask these same people have they
ever seen landraces grown out and have
they ever seen a land race that isn't a
hardcore hermaphrodite most land races
that come from source whether it's
Afghanistan Pakistan Thailand Colombia
wherever you know there are huge
populations of hermaphrodites so you can
almost guarantee that you're gonna your
little land race seeds you're getting
are gonna be part feminized and part
regular and everything in between
you know so and you know one thing a lot
of people don't even realize is there's
tons of male hermaphrodites and most
most breeders most anyone it seems
doesn't really realize that and males
can produce seeds themselves when
they're hermaphrodites
and what happens when a male produces
its own seed is you get a portion that
are pure male you get a portion that are
hermaphrodites and you get a portion
that are pure females and that's a whole
nother topic I like I like your response
though they're like for the people who
think that that all of this all than all
the noise in the seed is unnatural like
you want really messy go to actual
nature exactly you know nature is as
messy as it gets thank you and you're
welcome yeah
right on so so you know one of the
things that that you know attracted and
to me to your seeds when I was first
getting turned on to you and your work
was that you you're you foraging your
own path right there you you choose good
genetics to start with and then you have
a vision of what you're looking for and
you go for it and so you don't
necessarily I mean certainly you you
work with a lot of you know hot sexy
named stuff right that's true but but
you don't really seem to care first
about what is popular you are you are
following your art and your craft based
on what is exciting you personally next
and so I'm curious what you'd look for
when you are looking for starter
genetics that tells you that this might
be good for a feminized seed breeding
run I mean honestly most everything up
up until you know up until recently
anyway that you know I've worked with
for the feminized is just all old
heirloom stock that I've held you know
for years and the people before me have
held for years I mean you got you know
Arkell I mean I've had that cut for
we're getting close to 20 years with it
you know a snow I've had that cut for 20
years you know you know the chem dog
I've had that for going on 15 years and
you know that makes dates back all the
way to you know 1991 the triangle cush
you know it dates back to the early 90s
as well you know so I'm just working
with stuff that I've held for a long
long time minimum a decade oftentimes
you know multiple decades and you know
things that have been around you know
you know for the long stretch I haven't
I haven't really worked with anything
that is you know just popular for its
own thing if I've worked with stuff
that's pocket
it's just you know it's just stood the
test of time that's all that is is the
reason why you're not necessarily
working with the the the hot trending
stuff right now simply because you like
the older genetics that are you know
they're they're they're more referent
more refined than a land race but
they've been worked a little bit to be
stable without being boring I I think
it's just a little bit of a personal
issue with me too though where I am I
know the history of the genetics and
I've watched how genetics have have
moved over the last you know thirty
years and then I also know you know the
history of the genetics you know going
back further and so everything that's
really come out in the last 10-15 years
I mean I have pretty much all the
building blocks or most of the building
blocks that created all these things I
mean you know your Girl Scout cookies
you know it's it's just an OG Kush
crossed with yeah probably not d'oeuvre
you know yeah but you know I mean a
perfect example is when we ran out the
triangle cush s warms there were green
phenotypes of essentially cookies in
those plants so basically all cookies is
is an expression of of that green og
cush triangle cush plant crossed with a
certain dumb and a purple strain and
honestly the only plant that I've really
ever seen that does the certain purple
ink that you know the the common form
cut of cookies does it's it's deep chunk
you know yeah I mean so the these these
guys I mean cookies was founded in
Mendocino County and the guys who are
responsible for it yay cookie
Shango they they they aren't you know
the most honest individuals when it
comes to genetics and history so I mean
but you know weed nerds like myself you
know obviously care a little bit more
about that stuff yeah well because
you're not you're not worried primarily
for marketing and IP or intellectual
property right you actually want to get
to the truth of the matter it's a it's a
different goal exactly exactly
while we're while we're talking about
you know strain histories and stuff and
and how you like to use local heirlooms
you know I read a lot of and listen to a
lot of your other interviews to prepare
for our interview today and do I
remember correctly that the that the
Humboldt snow that you use is a is a
purple cush team of are okay so the
humble snow is a kind of a tricky one
that I'm still working on tracking down
the the full story on it for one we do
know it came out of Eugene back in the
mid 90s there were there were stories I
heard you know around humble talking
about blah blah blah but then I know a
handful of cats who actually brought it
down from Eugene in like 95 96 something
like that and I got the cut in I think
99 well there's a story up in Eugene how
it was just a selection of for way but
you know some of the some of some of my
boys have been talking to the cats kind
of involved up there with that and some
of those who are really in the know seem
to think or seem you know that they
claim that it actually came to Eugene
from Florida so basically worse
still backtracking that one mm-hmm you
know and I almost wonder if it's not
just one of those old hash plants that
were popular in the early 90s out of
Florida because hash plant you know it
had a heyday back back in the early you
know late late 80s early 90s in Florida
so I'm just wondering if you know and
and you know I never I never pretend
like humble or where I'm from is the
source of you know everything wonderful
I think there's so many hot pockets
everywhere you know
III I'm a fan of you know whatever koala
genetics and where they came from you
know I'm I'm not blind to you know oh
you know we're the best right on right
now and that's also you know and I'm
gonna make a judgement but I also would
guess that that's one of the reasons why
you know you tend to be you know one of
the more polite and play nice with
everybody breeders out there because you
want to have relationships with these
other pockets around the country and you
don't get access to other people's
networks by being an [ __ ] right right
sure yeah so so um the reason why we
asked about the Humboldt snow as it was
was to as an example was because you
you've done a lot of crosses with the
Humboldt snow and so and I also know
that you are a hell a twosie with what
you're gonna cross with so what was it
about the expressions of Humboldt snow
that you saw that made you want to make
it a major player you know in your lines
for a couple years and the reason why
I'm asking to kind of inform your answer
is there are people who are listening
who are gonna want to you want to do
this right and so so they they may model
their decision-making process a cut on
how you thought through the challenge as
well so so kind of tell us a little bit
about how you decided to choose that
particular keema bar you know honestly
um it probably has to do with I've just
had it for so long I mean when I got it
back in 1999 we actually traded a the
this this cat
are pretty much well this cut called
Uriah
it was it was a it was inherited cut
from my dad and we traded Uriah for the
snow and the very first time I ran the
snow out it only ended up being like I
don't know six inches tall or something
and it produced produced four grams but
it was the widest stuff I'd ever seen at
the time I mean it was and we actually
got in a snow cap and it looked like a
little snow capped mountain you know but
you know anyways the the last time I
grew it like a full light of it I think
I did like two and three-quarter pounds
from a bed
so it's yields are definitely you know
have potential over that four gram
initial but I I just really learned how
to grow it really well back in the early
2000s and just grown that cut taught me
a lot I grew a lot of it indoors and
then I grew a lot more of it outdoors
and it was just you know a really solid
you know quality plant um high potency
you know great bag bag appeal um just a
hashey kind of a old school a little bit
of pine a little bit of you know this
and that but a little bit of pepper I
think but uh just just kind of an
old-school you know solid plant when one
of the things that that's interesting
that that you pulled out because I
thought you were just gonna go for you
know typical variables like you know I
liked the terpene profile in the
structure in the yield you know just
your basic stuff but you went right to I
had a relationship with that plant yeah
and I'm like oh wow that's a different
idea you're like you're like I know her
I know how to grow her I can do a
successful run with her and also you
know she's she's very resinous right and
and then and then and then you
eventually is also a good yield or - I
like that idea - because that
a really different kind of growing than
what we're seeing commercially right now
where people are just hitting lines with
with their male of the day right yeah
then again you know very few people are
sitting on mothers you know cuts from 15
years ago either
so yeah it's one of the advantages you
have you know not only living where you
live in the Emerald triangle but also
having a lineage like you do where you
know multiple generations of your family
have been growing therefore for ages
that's a that's a pretty good network
for for attracting genetics your way oh
yeah oh yeah and you know honestly you
know I got I got into the whole you know
internet forums and everything you know
in the early 2000s and that you know
really you know helped to create access
to you know a lot of really high-quality
you know fellow growers and breeders and
aficionados of just cannabis in general
yeah right I mean bless the internet
even for all the things that it annoys
us today the everybody being able to get
into contact with each other and connect
and share genetics photos and you know
education god it mean it was it changed
everything right right yeah right so all
right cool well let's go ahead and take
our second commercial break when we come
back I want to talk to you about the
naming of your your strains because
you're here names you're the names you
choose our grades so you are listening
to shaping fire we're gonna take a short
break my guest today is Caleb Inspectah
from CSI humble did you know that
shaping fire has a fabulous YouTube
channel with content not found on the
podcast when I attend conventions or
speak or moderate panels I always record
them and bring the content home for you
to watch the Shango Losey youtube
channel has world-class speakers
including kevin Jodrey of wonderland
nursery talking about breeding cannabis
for the best terpene profile nicholas
Mamun on regenerative and polyculture
cannabis growing dr. Sunil Agarwal on
the history of cannabis medicine around
the world
Ben Cassidy of true terpenes on using
terpenes for health in your everyday
life
Reggie Godinho of steep hill on the
cannabis genome and Jeff Lowen Fell's on
the soil food web
there are several presentations from dr.
Ethan Russo on terpenes and the
endocannabinoid system and even my own
presentation on how to approach finding
your dream job in cannabis and why we
choose cannabis business even though the
risks are so high as of today there are
over 100 videos that you can check out
for absolutely free go to youtube.com
forward slash Shango 'lose or click on
the link in this week's newsletter
now that the health benefits of terpenes
have become well known in the cannabis
industry people everywhere are looking
for the purest terpenes and custom
terpene blends true terpenes isolated
terpenes and terpenoids are tested to
the most demanding worldwide safety and
stability standards terpenes from true
terpenes our third-party tested non-gmo
and food grade their triple distilled
making them the purest terpenes
available in the world with over a
thousand terpene isolates strain
profiles and Terp flavors you can be
sure that true terpenes will have the
perfect aromatics for your manufacturing
goals true terpenes also offers custom
blending so that you can match your
company's marquee strains across all
your product categories while you can
certainly simply just order terpenes and
go right to manufacturing true terpenes
also offers a wealth of manufacturing
insight best practices and a willingness
to help you break new ground with your
product formulations true terpenes has
robust and supportive customer service
too so your questions will get answered
fast and efficiently if you shop for
Terps before you know how rare that is
if you are a cannabis product developer
these are the Terps that you want to add
to your oil or edible or capsule or
beverage true terpenes are simply the
best your money can buy don't try and
make a premium product with substandard
Terps choose true terpenes for a
top-shelf experience go to shaping
feiyr.com ford slash true terpenes to
find out more or click on the link in
this week's newsletter welcome back you
are listening to shaping fire I'm your
host Shango Louis and our guest this
week is Caleb Inspectah from CSI
Humboldt so Caleb you know one of the
things I enjoy about your packs is is
the
the names that you choose and you know a
lot of people in the modern more
commercial market are just taking names
that have nothing to do with the lineage
right they're just you know they'll
they'll make a and they'll cross it to B
instead of the the final name being a B
they're like it's called L now and
you're like all right well I can tell
nothing about the that about the the
strain based on the name and you know
I've always thought that's one of the
cool things is that it's it's like a
it's like a verbal puzzle right it's
like okay what what in this name
conjures other you know other Kim parts
like you know the word they'll you know
blue or dream right you know like you
can you know in the in the early blue
dream cross days like you could tell
where it came from and and and there is
a certain artistry in naming those
things because you know very often the
the strain names don't naturally fit
together easy they're they're pretty
unrelated and so you have to kind of
come up with a poetic ways to put those
together and I think that's great
and a lot of the scene is moving away
from it and and so many of your kiemce
of our names are so playful I think that
you must enjoy doing that like what's
your story on how you name your strains
oh I gotta give credit where you know
credits do I mean
my name's early on yeah they were okay
but they weren't nothing special but
when I started doing name games on
Instagram I I would you know I'll have a
thousand people chime and in you know
with just to name one single strain and
you get so much just you know so many
options and just all kinds of clever
names I mean that's the Instagram
community is is where all all of my best
names come from and by having by having
contests it allows people to you know
participate and you know
uh III think it's win-win for me when
win for them and you know everybody who
will you know ends up win and you know
the the contest you know gets the very
first fries you know free seeds of
whatever they may and and it's also as
somebody who loves to read those threads
now it's it's just fun to read
you know like three hundred people's
ideas even if they're not going to be
fellow one you know it's it's usually a
whole bunch of fun and a lot of laughs
oh yeah no it's great and you know the
way I do it is you know I'll break it
down
I'll I'll write out you know my 20
favorites out of the out of the you know
the thousand or whatever and then you
know I'll have the it was written down
and I always you know have whoever
suggested it you know at that time you
know and sometimes I'll go back and I'm
like you know even if I'm not having a
competition I'll go back home you know I
still love this name ooh I could use it
for this so I hit that person up and I'm
like hey you know I'm gonna use your
name for this you want three packs of
this and you know I haven't had anybody
yeah the answer is always yes
you know yeah so yeah I mean it's it's
it's it's a lot of fun for everybody
it's a lot of fun for me and you know
and it also you know really takes a lot
of you know weight off of you to come up
and be like ooh brilliant so like so
they for some of your some of your
strains I'm just gonna pick three that I
particularly like on your stuff that you
put out for for this summer so like so
one of my favorite named is the
mozzarella right and and that and that's
you UK cheese and chem dog 91 and and
it's like like how much fun is that
right that like that's cool and then and
then a girl's best friend is also I
thought pretty creative so that's Girl
Scout cookies and chem dog 91 and
there's so much poetry in that girl's
best friend it's her dog Girl Scout
cookie and is I just feels you know it
feels good right it does it does I like
it and then and then one that I'm
excited to grow this summer I've always
wanted to grow the Big Sur holy weed and
and
and have never had access to the
genetics but then you put out sacred
snow which is the Big Sur holy weed
cross with the Humboldt snow and so I
don't know what she's like yet but it's
it's it's not only cool to be able to
play with something that's part Big Sur
holy weed but I like the fact that you
chose a name that that really focused on
the the holy weeds sacred snow kind of
Baha you know vibe where it came from
oh absolutely and you know that's one of
the things you know I really appreciate
when people go for because not a whole
lot of people you know get like the Big
Sur holy weed hybrids they it's not
popular people most people don't care
but every time I run out a Big Sur holy
weed hybrid they're the [ __ ] best
excuse my language they're the best
plants in the room you know I mean it
produces some of the nicest plants it
doesn't matter the hybrid the the sacred
snow they were amazing the chem dog you
know Times big star holy weed I don't
even think I've even released those ones
yet but those things were beasts you
know it's just it's one of those things
though that it's some of the most
impressive plants and just you know
gorgeous overall plants and yet you know
something popular is just gonna outsell
it you know a thousand to one for sure I
mean like you you really have to come
across some of the the lineage stories
right written in a magazine about Big
Sur holy weed or like like I didn't even
get turned on to it from cannabis I got
turned on to it by you listening to an
interview with a poet from the Big Sur
region talking about it and I'm like my
god I'm learning about a you know a new
strain from a poet at a college and so I
went back track tonight and I found out
about it but because it's not a trending
thing you're right it's gonna get out
sold all the time but but clearly you've
got a depth of experience and you're
excited about it and which just makes me
more excited to grow it the summer I'm
actually concerned though because you
know I think it's gonna go longer than
the first or second week of October and
which means that it's gonna have to be
in a in a tent where I live in on Vashon
Island in Washington because we get the
rains here and everything I've heard
about it is that she's tall she's a big
plant and she's just a big plant she's
just gonna crush my you know you know my
7 8 foot ceilings on like I know on a
basic tent so I'm gonna have to figure
out something special for her for this
year yeah yeah I mean there's a plant
and plant for every place she'll be a
big one
yeah well that's well that's one of the
reasons why I've been so hot on Otto
flowers recently not only do I like them
because you know I'm always selecting
for patients right helping them like get
their their home grows up but also you
don't have to worry about them growing
into the lights I've never personally
played with Otto flowers but my buddy
hyb he he's been breeding Otto flowers
for I don't know 15 or 20 years and I'm
actually a gonna be a cell on his Otto
flower seeds on my Humboldt CSI site
here pretty soon but I I definitely see
the value and I'll never hate on an auto
flower because you know hey justjust
like we said you know a time and a place
for all all the plants yeah yeah
absolutely well if we're gonna if we're
gonna do that let's let's hit on your
your Australian bastard so so it's it's
funny it actually where was I recently
that it came up oh that's right it was
at the regenerative agriculture
conference that Joshua Rutherford Dutch
blooms took across the country I was in
Michigan and they put up wait a minute
no that's not where it was sorry it was
it was just a couple weeks ago it was
Jeff Lowen fells the pic the picture
that you put on Instagram of the
Australian bastard
he's got in his in his slides too as an
example of the wide-ranging variety that
the cannabis plant has that we haven't
even accessed yet oh I liked he stopped
by at the Emerald cup and sat down for a
good probably half hour just amazed at
that Australian bastard he was like wow
so yeah well he remains excited about it
he's a good intelligent fellow that's
for damn sure
yeah I think I think that between this
summer and next summer it's going to be
the the real coming to prominence of
Auto flowers I mean certainly the
quality of the seeds have gotten a lot
better recently but also you know Jeff
Lowen fellows has got his book on Auto
flowers coming out in October and and
and and I you know I personally got
turned on to him so I have done like a
whole year of auto flower content like
you know I mean I I'm interviewing well
it just had Jeff here on Vashon Island
to do an auto flower presentation and
then I'm doing an auto flower panel at a
cultivation classic in Portland but you
know I'm all like well if this is what
everybody's gonna want to learn about
let's try to get them good information
to start instead of have to untie all
the rumor that usually comes with
something new right right right right
all right so let's circle back around to
names so I wanted to get your thoughts
on this and so you know there's a lot of
people usually kind of green rushar new
business types who advocate for the for
the simplifying of stray names they
they're all like you know you need to
know too much history to know these
names and unpack them and you know I
understand how people new to seeds and
breeding and purchasing canvas they want
to simplify it so that they can kind of
dumb it down so they can sell the most
of the most people but I personally
think that feels like some culture
vulture [ __ ] because you know I think
one of the beautiful things about
cannabis culture is the creation
these names whether or not you're making
them at your home or you're getting them
from like wonderful crowd crowd crowd
sourcing you know on Instagram I think
that's a really important aspect that we
need to aggressively preserve in our
culture what do you think oh I I agree I
mean there's definitely pros and cons to
the whole name game you know I mean the
names have definitely gotten a little
out of hand but then on the flip side I
mean you you you you really can't just
keep calling something you know
especially generation after generation
after generation blank times blank times
link times like times Leigh if you use
just the original strain names that's
gonna end up you know getting a little
long so yeah you need original you know
unique names to describe and define and
I like how you put it you know where a
lot of these names don't have anything
to do with you know the plants they're
trying to describe I think that's almost
imperative that the name has something
to do with the genetics it comes from
yeah I mean personally I think I think
so I think it helps everybody involved
the the consumer the breeder and and
certainly it's a you know it's just a
valuable thing of our scene right it's
another way for us to express ourselves
and and certainly there you know some
names can get us in trouble like you
know you know like gorilla glue and Girl
Scout cookies specifically I mean it's
dumb that that stuff ended up getting
litigated but but you know all of us in
this scene you need to be aware of that
and then you know even even you have got
some strain names that you know will
probably never become popularized in
magazines simply because it's called
coked-out Girl Scout right you know I
mean I might when I thought you know the
so that's Girl Scout cookies and
Humboldt snow when I first saw that I
just started howling right because it
it's funny it's an inside joke but but
you know you're not gonna hear coked-out
Girl Scout in any crossover magazine
and and and just just for the record
just for the record I don't use any
drugs whatsoever except for cannabis
maybe an Advil once in a great while but
that's it right I guess I guess that's
good to clarify III just like the name
and you know that that name itself is a
perfect example because there's a lot of
people are like oh that's terrible you
named it that I'm like you know what
have a little bit of sense of humor and
don't take it so serious and it's
alright
and know it's not gonna be on the
magazine it's not gonna be on the
dispensary shelf girl's best friend that
was named so it can end up on the
dispensary shelf coked-out Girl Scout
okay that's just for fun right there
yeah right on and you know and in and
even though it's you know it's a it's a
bold pile it still actually fits the
cross right Girl Scout cookies and
Humboldt snow it's it fits it does so
rhinos all right cool well I think
that's pride enough on naming I love
that that whole topic though so all
right so next question as far as you
know a lot of people say that you should
not breed with a feminized see a mother
from a feminized seed what are your
thoughts on that complete I'll shut
those people down every single time I'm
like if you breed with a Sour Diesel a
chem dog and OG Kush and X a Y or Z
you're already breeding with a feminized
seed so if you want to breed with
anything popular and I'm including Girl
Scout cookies cherry pie is this that
the other
everything that stems from any of those
if you're gonna sit on that high horse
and be like oh you can't do that I'm
like yeah well you can't do that so
we're you what are you breeding with and
and and and I already already hit the
whole land race thing where you don't
know what exactly those seeds are that
you're you're you're growing so yeah all
right all right I'll get good so just
just a couple more things before we wrap
up here you know for for folks who
our longtime multi-generational growers
probably everywhere but I've run into it
most in the Emerald triangle area you
know it said sometimes bye-bye
longtime growers that certain strains
that they've got are kept close and not
shared and I was just curious as
somebody who did not grow up in Humboldt
I can only guess why those are not
shared and so you know something you
know they they don't want it to get in
the hands and be belittled by pollen
chuckers maybe or maybe it's like a
family secret special sauce for their
for their seeds like but but you live
there and you grew up and you probably
have some of these so so what what are
you locals what's the motivation that
locals have to hold cuts close and not
share them well it's easy economics
I mean supply and demand if the supply
is small you know I mean you know you're
gonna fetch it you know a high dollar so
it's it's essentially always been about
the money on that tip that's the only
reason really to hoard anything you know
I mean when everybody has it a perfect
example is say a purple Arkell when I
first got purple Arkell back around 2001
2002 not a whole lot of people had it
you know and the people who had it were
you know if you were you know you have
that trust and everything they'd be like
you know here have a cut but don't go
giving it out so you know a bunch of
people you know fast forward you know
four or five years from there you know
it essentially or it eventually got out
and you know about popular tons of
people had it and you know then the
price started dropping on it and a lot
of people you know aren't really quality
growers they don't really have a love
for their craft and they're just trying
to pump out something with the name and
not giving two shits you know and so
you know they watered down for everybody
else and eventually you know but you
know if if you hold something tight and
you keep it tight you know there that
demand is never gonna add you know yeah
and you can put it out itself you can do
crosses with it and and so you know it
may not be the level of popular that
something gets to be when everybody's
growing it for a little while but you
essentially have got you know a monopoly
on that and on that intellectual
property if you will and it's something
and you know I would say that we're
probably in that arc right now with
Kappa laters Mac won right we're we're
you know at the beginning people lost
their freakin minds and and you know it
was you know barely available and just
through like whispers and friends around
you know that we're near where you live
and then like the first flowers you know
we're like wildly overpriced in the
market but now we've got to the point
now much later that that you know a lot
lots of people have got the cut gotten
the cut one way or another probably by
by breaking caps rules around it right
yeah exactly and and now every you know
everybody's hitting it with their you
know hitting it with everything and so
you know we are probably on the far side
of that arc which is why you know even
probably cap himself you know he's moved
on to his his next project and his
crosses with it right but it's
interesting though that to watch that
that arc from nobody's got it and it's a
rumor and then there's just pictures and
then and then it becomes kind of
available at an insane price and then it
kind of gets washed out you you know you
bring up a perfect example to so I get
asked you know from time to time you
know just friends that friends of mine
are like we got to hold this tight you
know we can't let it get out you know
blah blah blah blah when people get it
you know then it won't be worth nothing
I'm like why are we worried about that I
mean you know I'm working on ten
projects that are probably going to be
better than that
you know in a year or two you know and
so you know I think it's it's fear-based
you know people get stuck with you know
thinking oh they only have one little
thing of value and they got to hold that
tight I'm like man I got so many things
of value I don't even care right it's a
the people acting on a scarcity
mentality right yeah and honestly that's
how I feel about popping my seeds like I
have lots of respect for people who
collect seeds I get it it's a it's a
it's a thing and I'm not really a seed
collector I like to get my hands on good
seeds and then I grow them you know
that's the point yeah and you know you
know certainly you know people who are
breeding they want to sit on stock for
you know they're building their palette
of colors for a future breeding program
right but but but since that's not my
shtick I just like to grow plants I'm
all like well hell I'm gonna well like
even your seats you know that are there
sitting in front of me I'm looking
forward to popping all this stuff this
summer and and because you know what
you're gonna you're gonna put more stuff
in the market next year you know yeah
and so you know so long as there are
people like you who are doing the work
of selecting and sifting so I don't have
to I don't have to do that myself and
there's certainly no question that that
you're gonna keep on you know putting
out quality things so so there's no
reason to have that scarcity mentality
if you got seeds pop them and grow them
oh absolutely my boy is a underrated and
Garth cultivator they got this new rap
album coming out this weekend they have
a track on there called grow your own
it's my absolute favorite track on the
whole album if you like rap you know
it's cool if you don't is that the one
that you posted
snippets of on your Instagram yeah yeah
it's a good track and actually the
videos pretty fun too it's it's got its
it's stylish ously done and it's all in
the freaking redwoods yeah yeah yeah I
was actually just out yesterday with a
big Schmo and Garth cultivator
underrated Eddie lip was even in there
oh wow shoot shoot in their latest video
and I mean that grow your own track they
you know release that yet but it's on
the album I mean that is my favorite
track of album because that's that's
that's what I like to see I like to see
people just grow in their own you know I
mean and you know that's that's the
whole you know message of that of that
track I think they teamed up with Mendo
dope on that track too so you know yeah
well we're big fans here every but you
know liberating the plant
everybody becoming a gardener you know
it's like Eliot you know there's a lot
of truth to it you know like there's no
reason why everybody shouldn't have a
few plants in their yard every summer
it's super easy to grow the sunshine is
free it gives you an emotional
connection to the plant
you know nothing tastes as good and as
emotionally as awesome as the stuff that
you drew yourself versus the you know
the stuff that you're gonna pick up at a
dispensary and and that doesn't mean
that it's gonna hurt the cannabis market
either because like you know I grow my
patient grow and then I also go to the
store it's both it's like tomatoes right
I grow tomatoes in every store I grow
tomatoes every summer but you also know
I'm buying them at the store - oh yeah
oh and and that's that's that's a
perfect one too though that's the whole
reason people ask a lot on Instagram
like what's the point of you know
growing or working with this Australian
bastard cannabis and just - you
mentioned earlier you said you know
you're Australian bastard cannabis it's
not mine
the kid who sourced it you know painted
forests farms painted forests organics
that is his and I'm just working with
him
just to clarify that fair enough yeah
but but the Australia bastard cannabis
it is something that people will not
recognize as cannabis so you can grow it
in your backyard you can grow it you
know now the way it is right now it's
unrefined yeah it's it's like the
ruderalis that created the you know Auto
flowers before it got
and you know bread for quality so it is
in its bare-bones building blocks and
we're given people the opportunity to
breed it themselves or to you know work
from the starting point of quality
hybrids to breed it so when you say that
it's not recognizable clearly the plant
itself visually does not look like
cannabis it looks like a fern or
something it's weird but but but you've
had the flower I'm assuming at this
point when you do the do the flowers
look like cannabis leaves do this
alright so so when you if you got a bag
of it you'd be like okay this is weed
even though the plant does not look like
it yeah yeah everybody recognizes weed
or cannabis by its leaf you know yeah I
mean if it doesn't have that canvass
leaf whether it's indica leaf or sativa
leaf it does not look like cannabis you
can walk by a fully flower adapt plant
of Australia bastard
and be like oh that kind of looks like
yeah you don't have the leaf yeah it
looks like a shrub you know it's a
really strange plant so right on well on
that on that fun note let's wrap it up
so Caleb it's been a real joy to talk to
you to be able to chat with you about
this and to you know really you know
break down feminized seeds for people to
kind of get everybody on the same page
and also to be able to enjoy a whole
bunch your stories from being down in
the trenches and doing this for so long
so though so thanks for sharing some of
your valuable time with us so that we
could get to know you know you and
feminists i feminized seeds better it's
been a pleasure right on thank you
brother so if you want to find out more
about CSI humble and Caleb there's a
couple different ways that you can do
that I definitely recommend that you
follow his Instagram it is enjoyable and
educational at the same time so so his
Instagram is CSI underscore Humboldt and
don't get confused there is another old
CSI Humboldt Instagram profile that
comes up but you don't want the one with
hardly any followers his is the one that
he keeps updated is is you know two
hundred thousand followers or more and
you
follow that because you'll be able to
watch the progress of this Australian
bastard plant as well which you can see
pictures of there now if you want to get
yourself get your hands on some of
Caleb's seeds you want to go through his
distribution website and that's you flip
the name around that's at Humboldt CSI
so he you know he breeds as CSI Humboldt
but the distributor is called Humboldt
CSI so that's at Humble CSI comm and
that's got not only his feminized lines
but also his reg lines and probably
eventually the Australian bastard lines
and and your buddy hives Auto flowers
are going to be there soon so so so
definitely check out Humboldt CSI comm
and the last thing is actually how I got
turned on to Caleb which is a great
interview that Kevin Joe jury did with
him at the Wunderland nursery seed
series back I don't know maybe two years
ago it was actually the first thing that
shapingg fire sponsored the first event
that we sponsored so that was pretty
cool and you can find links to all that
stuff on the shaping fire comm website
so check that all out you can find more
episodes of the shaping fire podcast and
subscribe to the show at shaping fire
calm and on Apple iTunes stitcher and
Google Play if you enjoyed the show we'd
really appreciate it if you'd leave a
positive review of the podcast wherever
you download your review will help
others find the show so they can enjoy
it too on the shaping fire website you
can also subscribe to the weekly
newsletter for insights into the latest
cannabis news and product reviews on the
shaping fire website you will also find
transcripts of today's podcast as well
for information on me and where I'll be
speaking you can check out Shango lows
calm your company want to reach our
national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hotspot at shaping
fire calm to find out how thanks for
listening to shaping fire I've been your
host Shango Lowe's
[Music]