[Music]
trimming is a constant companion of the
cannabis community since the earliest
days of commercial cannabis growers have
been trimming their cannabis flowers to
increase their bag appeal and clean up
the flavor profile from being overly
green tasting trimming styles change
depend on where you live and what your
final use of the flowers will be one
thing for sure though trimming is very
time intensive and it's hard on your
hands and usually your back and butt -
it is true though that it is a necessary
step in producing fine cannabis and both
home growers and commercial growers need
to get the job done one way or another
you are listening to the shaping fire
podcast and I am your host Shango Lowe's
my guest today is Kristen Baldwin
director of operations of Green Mountain
hardest they are a mobile trimming
company that sends out teams of between
one and fifteen or so people to trim
home grows and large-scale commercial
growth - today we'll talk about the
different styles of trimming their
favorite scissors to use and get a
better understanding of their business
plan and how they make money in this
area that many in cannabis consider a
difficult necessity welcome to the show
Kristen hey Shango great to be here so
glad you could make the time to join us
so you know the canvas market is
exploding of course as licensees and
patients and even just everyday citizens
are beginning to grow what are the kinds
of clients that you find calling you for
trimming services you know it's
interesting we see clients all the way
from large scale commercial growers who
have several locations in which we trim
with teams of you know 15 to 20 trimmers
several days a week two personal growers
in their homes who have just a few
plants so really it's a it's a huge
range it's probably you know probably
feels like two different departments
because of the demands of your of your
big commercial growers the the
expediency and the regularity and and
how after once the contract is set up
its kind of plug and play versus your
you know your personal trimming services
where you know you might just be at
somebody's
house for a day or two and and so you
kinda have to create that relationship
anew with that person way differently
than the commercial clients for sure and
you know to that effect we make sure
that the people we send to our personal
and grow clients are our supervisors
there are our best trimmers they're our
fastest and and also they're in a
position to sort of educate in the home
as the client wants us to or doesn't
want us to they may want to sit with the
trimmer they may not it's really up to
them how involved in the process they
are and how closely they work with the
team yeah I can imagine that I can
imagine that there's a lot more customer
service actually it's probably really
weird to to be in some people's homes
right I mean that's a that's awfully
intimate and if they're growing maybe
sometimes they're a little sketchy about
having people in their homes and then
heck you know if their patients some
patients are you know they're living in
some rough situations sometimes I can
imagine that's a very colorful
environment for your team yeah you know
what we find is that it's really just
great people who generally are either
caregivers for them for their own needs
or caregivers for a friend or family or
a group of patients and they're they're
genuine kind individuals who just really
need a service sometimes especially with
the older folks it's just that they're
not able to manage it themselves you
know with some folks it's that they're
new it it just depends on the situation
some folks are just not able to
physically take care of the plants
themselves so there's some times that we
go do harvesting and gardening we can
move clones around it's really you know
a fit to your need kind of service
especially in that circumstance and
really even all the way up to the
commercial grower it it multiplies out
in the same way we use the same formula
regardless of where we are I can
actually imagine I mean I'm a patient at
all but my my hands still work fine and
I can do my own trimming but I hate
shrimping right and so and so you know
if if if you were in my state I think I
would just call because my time is
spent you know recording a podcast or
calling an advertiser instead of
spending my time trimming and so I think
that you know it makes I would expect
that you have a lot of people who
certainly can but it's just not how they
prefer to spend their time that's
exactly it and and also I mean that's
even true in the commercial spaces it's
not that they couldn't hire and manage
that staff it's that they prefer not to
that they have enough on their hands
just managing growing the plants and
it's a completely different skill set I
mean that's the other thing it just
because you know how to grow doesn't
mean you know how to manicure and and
interestingly we find some of the best
trimmers come from industries like
cosmetology school graduates for example
make excellent marijuana trimmers as you
can imagine and they're they're the
fastest that we've seen and the most
deft with the smaller smaller work which
you know some of it can be quite
meticulous yeah that makes a lot of
sense do you charge by weight or time we
charge per person per hour mm-hmm so
based on the size of the team that we
send you and the number of supervisors
versus trimmers that calculates an
hourly rate we don't charge any
administrative fees or anything weird on
top of that and you know on a daily
basis that gets observed by the grower
whether that's a personal grower or a
huge commercial grow they see the same
tablet that says this is how long we
were here this is who was here this is
how much a costume so it we try and keep
it as you know transparent and without
much room for error
I find that doing it by weight it just
kind of lends it to a to a lot of
variants and ways that things can go
askew yeah well then then you have to
change the price for dry or wet and how
dry is yeah yeah a lot of malarkey well
yeah I'm sure that I'm not the only one
listening to you who's curious about a
ballpark figure for what this would cost
and I also figure that you probably got
a wide range of pricing from like you
know your bulk commercial clients to
somebody you know who's a personal
so let's say that somebody has just got
you know here's your simple legal six
person grow and they've got you know
very you know moderately sized plant
let's say everything's like a medium
right so so what would I expect to it to
cost for to have one or two of your
people come and trim out my my six
plants you know I think that it would
really be just a few hundred dollars I
mean it would be a day of work for one
or two people and you know if it's six
really really productive plants like a
big big fat indica versus sativa that's
gonna have a lot fewer smaller buds that
are further apart that would make a
difference in how many hours it would
take but generally we wouldn't book more
than a day all of our personal grow
clients I've never really seen it go
over more than two days unless the
objective is for us to come and cut the
plants down on one day and do the
harvesting and D fanning and then let it
dry and come back and do the trimming on
another day which is you know quite
often how it goes so it could be two
days but it might only be four to six
hours of work on each day yeah I get
that I get that and and for me to think
okay my my six plants go from being cut
and hung which I would do to being you
know nice and in jars done for a few
hundred bucks I'd be like in you know
okay I'd be like that let's do what yeah
totally so you know there's a lot of
variety and trimming styles you know
like like you know if you're if you're
trimming for bag appeal it's gonna be a
lot tighter you know where I live in out
here on Vashon Island
you know people leave their flowers
really shaggy because they're like look
at all those trichomes on there you know
I'd rather have those on my flower than
you know in the trim which you know
you'd normally go somewhere else
what sort of client intake do you
perform to make sure that your team is
providing trimming that matches the
clients expectations right so so every
time we get a new client there's an
intake they go through that sort of
talks about do you twit trim your stuff
what do you trim dry
I are is this just us prepping a large
amount of cannabis to go into a trim
machine which is one job you know that
we do for really really big clients is
this are you gonna make some sort of
extract out of this are you
extracting in some way are you making
hash are you what are you doing you know
that's that's the the endgame sort of
can dictate the trim in some cases and
then all the way down to I want a loose
leafy trim maybe for something like a
caviar roll where you want to take all
your excess keef and and re-roll those
buds in it so you the leaves are
something for it to stick to we have
some clients who are absolutely you know
because their medical clients are on a
such a tight budget they want to make
sure there's not even any little tiny
crow's feet or anything left on the buds
that's extra stem because that's a lot
of time what the client is looking for
you know the end user so as the kind of
intermediary our big deal is you we will
do it exactly how you want why we have
the supervisors there who can interface
directly with the client and and get
really specific information on what the
team is supposed to do and then also
over time you know because a lot of
places we go back over and over they'll
develop a rapport and then it becomes
you know almost fluid as a new member of
the team comes on to really get them up
to speed on that particular style for
that place fairly quickly right on that
makes a lot of sense let's let's dive in
the one aspect of that a little more
specific so so let's say that you've got
three clients one's gonna make
everything into bagged hash one person
is going to process it you know in a in
a you know a BHO tower or something and
the third person is going to you know
just just roll it up and smoke it so so
how would you trim differently for those
three clients okay so for someone who's
making you know doing a Pho extract that
maybe they may be wanting
a very heavy trim product and that may
be all they're using to make their BHO
they may be then separating out the bud
or they may be doing what's called a nug
run which would be that extraction using
the buds as well so that would be the
point of clarification there would
obviously be are you you know is your
main product goal for the for the hash
going to be the trim or the trim plus
the bud what do you you know which thing
do you want and then and then if they
really want the everything together the
Phoenix tears then then it would just be
shucking essentially getting it off of
the stem and ready for you know
processing and that would probably
happen wet and and you wouldn't do much
more to it after that but for somebody
who's gonna you know smoke the buds
themselves then typically we would do
something more of a Dee fan first in the
harvest flip and then and then trim it
down dry because you can get a much
finer trim on a dry product it's I think
you know it's it's a more time consuming
manicure but ultimately you're getting a
lot more flavor that's solely from the
bud and your you'll lose that kind of
hay taste or smell a lot more quickly if
you trim it that way I remember the
first time I was involved with a grow
for a large co2 run and it was the first
time I had done shucking right and you
know up to that point I had always just
trimmed for personal smoke right but
then you know I'm was watching guy was
being mentored and kind of learning how
to do this and I and I saw these folks
just like you know shuck it right off
off the branch and it drops into the bin
and I'm like no effing way you know
you're all like you're like somewhere in
between is is that disrespectful to the
flower
oh my god this is gonna be the easiest
trim ever right exactly right and you're
never really sure which thing is true
when you're doing that process
especially if you're working for
somebody else right yeah absolutely and
you know I mean it's a big
responsibility to get take somebody's
hard work over several weeks and and
then you know take it from that state to
a usable end product and that's really
the intermediary that the trimmer
performs in a lot of cases especially if
it's not going through an extraction
process you know if if the trimmer
mangles the buds they mangle the buds
and that's that's it if they're squashed
they're squashed and it's not like you
can suddenly you know replace them it's
like oh sorry no there's no like little
like bike tire pump that you can stick
back into it and sort of like oops
you know once you've squished it it's
it's over and and I think that that's
why it's such an intense process also
these guys are working in under extreme
scrutiny and that's the other thing to
keep in mind on the commercial level is
that we'll have a team of ten people
they'll have you know three or four
cameras on them at all times everything
has to be meticulously weighed and
accounted for because of the systems
here that are extremely rigorous in
managing this whole market both on the
medical and retail side so you know it's
it's a lot of responsibility and and we
don't take that lightly nor does anyone
really in the whole chain of process
that's involved with this on a
commercial level you have to take it
really seriously right on we're gonna
take our first short break and be right
back you are listening to shaping fire
and my guest today is Kristen Baldwin of
Green Mountain harvest if you like
podcasts like shaping fire chances are
that you will like audiobooks to pretty
much audiobooks are like podcasts except
with less stuttering better production
quality and more targeted topics yeah I
know
I make audiobooks sound better than a
podcast and you know maybe they are but
I get you I like podcast too I like to
learn from
while talking to me while I'm doing
something else like you know driving or
cleaning my house or making dinner or
even being at work whatever here's the
thing audible.com has an offer I want to
tell you about right now they are
offering a trial of their audiobook
service for absolutely free you can go
to shaping feiyr.com forward slash
audible and you will get a free
audiobook straight up you can listen to
it on your mobile device on your
computer or you can download it and
listen to it you know pretty much
anywhere it's really simple you know of
course they really want you to subscribe
to their service forever and enjoy more
and more audiobooks but as cannabis
users you also know how this goes the
first one is free they're gonna hate
I've said that but it's pretty great
you know I listened recently to smoke
signals by Martin Lee from Project CBD
org Martin's book is a classic of
cannabis advocacy he explains the
history of cannabis in America THC and
CBD cannabis science and why cannabis
policy in America has gotten so jacked
you know if you consider yourself a
cannabis person this book really is a
must
talking cannabis we all sound radical
just because we're talking about weed
but if you learn the history and science
of cannabis suddenly you become smart
and trustworthy to people the book was
really incredible and there's no doubt
that Martin Lee is the real deal you can
get the book for free just for doing the
trial you know if you don't want to
listen to a can of book that's cool too
there's everything else there's sci-fi
and history biography hell you can even
listen to a book about card counting in
blackjack whatever it's all pretty read
so here's the deal your first book is
free it's easy to sign up it's easy to
quit but they do do a pretty good job
making you want to stay every month just
check it out go to shaping feiyr.com
forward slash audible to find out more
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire I'm your host Shango Lowe's
and our guest this week is Kristen
Baldwin director of operations at Green
harvest so in the first set we talked a
lot about kind of the idea of of the
trimming business and the kinds of
people who hire you and and actually how
damn necessary it is in the new legal
market and and it's funny because you
know a lot of people have trimmed before
and so a lot of people have got their
preferred method and their preferred
scissors and so I'm like totally curious
you know in online grower forms it seems
like everybody has their own favorite
scissors I myself like small
spring-loaded scissors with a curved tip
so you know so I can like get on in
there in the flower yeah but my growing
mentor he prefers tiny scissors without
a spring but with really big hand
openings do you find that that your team
like everybody likes their own style or
is there a particular style that seems
to really come out as being you know
universally best by professionals sure
yes so we I think in the early days of
Green Mountain harvest so that was it
like six years ago
they did experiment with several
different styles of shears and what
we've settled on and really we provide
all of the tools through a supervisor
kit that they carry in the field we use
the Hydrofarm curved blade shear and we
chose that one because for a few reasons
one it's super affordable we think it's
a really good price point the curved
blade kind of like you said is really
what we think creates the the tightest
tightest trim and also it's it's the
easiest on your wrist we find because
you're not curving your hand as often
the blade is curved so you can have a
straighter arm and allow the curve of
the blade and then the twist of the
plant rather than arcing your your wrist
at a funny angle and you know that that
makes me think about OSHA standards and
just generate worker health you know
you're in this odd position because your
company is the state level but obviously
cannabis is still illegal federally you
know what kind of best practices have
you put together for you know creating
an environment
that is you know ergonomically healthy
for your Yammer's even though they've
spent their entire day using their hands
and probably sitting down which is
probably two of the worst things that
you could be doing yeah for sure so
actually you know we really really made
a point of keeping safety as a main
priority for our team and so to that
effect you know we at when they are
hired they're given a set of exercises
for their wrists and their backs we also
have a system in place where our
trimmers can sit or stand and they can
go back and forth so unless there's some
really heavy space constraints that
would disallow somebody from being able
to get up and and and choose to sit or
stand we encourage people to really take
both of those options and and you know
surprisingly though OSHA is a federal
organization they have been great
working with me directly over my years
in this industry regardless of the
context and really you know come and
educated us and had open dialogue with
with the industry so yeah we're in a
funny place there's no there's no doubt
about that but you know our main goal is
to create an environment for our
trimmers that's healthy so that also
involves not just an ergonomics
situation but some other things as well
and to that effect it it it we have some
some other things masks if there's any
kind of mold or mildew present we use a
food grade brown butcher paper on the
tables so that each environment is
sterile our trimmers all use a new set
of gloves after each break so they are
able to have you know left the building
and come back and clean your do you know
do you have a daily team that's pretty
much full-time or is it pretty much all
part-timers
who are on call so all of our people are
part-time they are employees with us
which allows them to be covered under
our workman's comp which is a huge key
in this industry really trying to you
know put as many of those standards of
normal working conditions in place for
people even though again we're in that
funny gray area but generally the
trimmers work between 25 and 35 hours a
week you know December is certainly
slower we joke that we think that the
trimmers get less work because the
growers plan not to have to harvest
right around Christmas because why would
they want to you know right and that's
fine you know we can plan for that but
like I'm looking at our January schedule
and it's it's totally insane I think
everyone who didn't harvest in December
is harvesting in January and then we
also sort of lovingly call October hemp
Tober here in Colorado because all the
big outdoor farms that's a big big time
for them so that can be really fun and
exciting little trips for the trimmers
out to these really cool outdoor big big
you know really really nice farms that's
one of the funny things about outdoor
isn't it you know the idea of harvest I
mean obviously there's lots of indoor in
the country and and there's certainly
way more harvesting taking place as I as
far as around the calendar but in volume
you know harvest suddenly you're needed
everywhere do you have you know a
seasonal spike where you need to over
hire just for harvest season and then
you get back down to a more basic crew
for the rest of the year you know we we
actually don't follow that kind of
hiring practice once you're an employee
with us you're an employee and we do our
best to provide you hours consistently
you know and so for us it really is a
balance of demanding excellence from our
team so that the people that do stay
with us are the best ones and then and
then making sure that those people have
work and and it's a delicate balance I
you know I do handle
a lot of the hiring and firing and all
the stuff in between and I do find that
you know I do want to be able to provide
work for people immediately when I hire
them
but I do have to caution them that this
is a business where there are lulls and
so we give our employees the opportunity
to sort of create their own schedules in
the sense that they're they have some
some big flexibility there which to that
effect if they need to have another
part-time job to supplement this we
understand that that's part of the deal
you know on that note is it hard to find
skilled trimmers you know to fill all
the ranks because so many people say
they've got experience and then that you
know maybe they're too slow or
distracted or sloppy or drunk or
whatever yeah so all those things have
happened and you know that's part of why
we have this supervisor in the field for
each group of 12 trimmers that allows us
to sort of regardless of what your
resume says really watch what you do in
that first 30-day probation period and
then if if we can't get you up to speed
in that first 30 days then then
typically that'll be it for people who
just can't cut the mustard and and
sometimes you know the other the other
side of the equation is true people find
out that they really can't or don't
enjoy the repetitive nature of the of
the job and and so we do have people who
will do it for a couple of weeks and
then say yeah I don't want to do this
but for people that want to put their
headphones on and you know listen to an
awesome podcast like this one and and
and trim some plants and be with some
great people it's a it's a great job
the other cool thing is that we can hire
people with some disabilities so that's
pretty neat because you know it's like
you have a walker hey man if you can get
into the facility and we'll make sure
you can then you can sit down and trim
and that's good for people who are
retired we have a lot of folks that just
turn with us one or two days a week you
know and have their own grows and and
and just loved it and had been with us
for years and years we have other people
who are you know fast young people
directly from the industry in the last
few years who just are amazing and and
and and so so so so fast so that's
that's the other side of the workforce
is people who've just been trained
commercially in the last few years but
we don't hire anyone directly who
doesn't have some sort of trimming
experience I'm if you don't have any
trimming experience then we have a
trimmer training school sort of program
you can can choose to go through you
know I've met some folks who are on the
autistic spectrum and it's amazing how
appropriate trimming is for a lot of the
folks oh yeah I've got the hyper focused
ability and they can work for long
periods of time you just like you know
you you allow them to wear their
headphones and let I don't you need done
and boom and you're like damn it was
done fast and efficiently and in good
cheer and you know it's really great
it's amazing the kinds of people you
know who are able to work in our
industry who had not necessarily had the
opportunity before can can folks get
high on the job no no no yeah there's
really strict regulations in place
around use anywhere within 500 feet of a
commercial facility whether it's a grow
or a store or an extraction facility you
can't use the product or even bring
personal product into that facility so
technically when you go into a
dispensary you're not supposed to even
have any cannabis already on you and
technically if they see that they have
to ask you to leave and and if one of
our trimmers is observed using cannabis
within 500 feet of a facility we have to
fire them that day because they can lose
their light their badge essentially to
work in the industry for just that I can
imagine that for a lot of trimmers
that's a that's a deal breaker right
they're like listen if I'm going to be
trim in 30 hours a week I want to be
high
or it's oh no no good no good for me
right well you know what you do at home
is your business what time of day you do
that is also your business what you do
when you leave the facility is your
business but what you do while you have
to be at the facility that's the key so
you know on a 15-minute break where
you're not allowed to leave you can go
outside and stretch but you know it's 15
minutes you can't leave the facility
you can't smoke weed and and that you
know I feel like there's ways that
people could probably get around that if
their dosage requires like a morning use
they could maybe supplement with an
edible or something else I mean no one
is suggesting that especially for a
medical patient they don't do what they
need to do but you can't be using the
product on the job that's the main thing
and that's you know true just across the
board and and I think that that's the
one of the big differences between you
know what what people think we do in
this industry and what we do is that
there really isn't a lot of use in in
the actual manifestation of the industry
itself that's sort of a completely
separate thing at this point and I think
the more the more commercial and
commodity based if he comes it's going
to continue in that direction
I remember when everybody was working in
medical and it was much less regulated
and and loose you know everybody would
get high at the beginning of you know
just about every business meeting and ER
and because that's how cannabis culture
was you know I I found that frustrating
a lot of time because even though I got
to try some amazing you know flowers and
oils from that people would bring to the
meetings at the same time so many of the
folks would not remember the key points
of the meeting or what they or what they
committed to do and then I would have to
send follow-up emails to remind them
what they agreed to so even though even
though I enjoy the social aspects of it
I do see as as cannabis businesses are
getting more serious the less people who
are doing it you know cooked its yeah I
mean it's sort of like you know I guess
the three-martini lunch would be the
closest
equation you know and and even if you're
in the beer industry you're not testing
beers at 9 a.m. every day like you just
you can't do it it's just like in any
industry where there's this quality to
it where there's some sort of you know
state of alteration that's going to
occur I think that you know in this
industry the reality is you're trying to
mitigate that weird gray area that weird
federal state gray Aryan so I think this
is one of the ways that they've done
that and then the other side of it is
exactly what you're talking about
professionally at 10:00 a.m. you know
would it be appropriate to pop a bottle
of wine maybe on a special day but
probably not you know probably not if
you want to get a lot done so what
people need to do to take care of
themselves medically again is another
thing but I would say recreational use
in a meeting is really bad especially
because you could have 10 different
people who respond to that particular
strain super differently so that could
be one that's really like makes you
really focused but it may not work that
way for this whole group of people that
you know now you have to make decisions
with yeah in there oh yeah that makes
sense so we're gonna take another short
break and be right back you are
listening to shaping fire and my guest
today is Kristen Baldwin of Green
Mountain harvest businesses everywhere
are constantly striving to reach out to
people through advertising we all know
though that trying to reach a cannabis
audience with a quality message is
pretty difficult that's why many people
choose to advertise on the shaping fire
podcast advertising on this show allows
us time to talk about your product
service or brand in a way that really
lets people know what sets your company
apart from others bold people who own
companies know that getting in a
relationship with their customers is
essential that is what we offer we will
explain your service or product and what
sets it apart as desirable and help our
audience get in contact with you it's
pretty simple really
advertising does not have
to be all whiz-bang smoke and mirrors
nowadays I find that people prefer just
to be spoken to calmly accurately and
with good intentions if you want to make
your own commercial spot you can do that
too because the podcast is young but
growing in an exceptionally fast rate if
you become an advertiser on the shaping
fire podcast now you are going to pay a
fraction of the cost will be asking for
in just a few months and yet everyone
listening both now and to the back
catalog of interviews later will hear
about your company again and again for
years it's a great deal for you pay a
small amount now because the show is new
but take advantage of the huge listening
audience we will have forever do
yourself a solid and contact us today
for rates on podcast and newsletter
advertising email hotspot at shaping
fire calm to find out more
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire I'm your host Shango losan
our guest this week is Kristen Baldwin
director of operations at Green Mountain
harvest so before the break we were
talking about a lot of the specifics on
not only running a business but working
the best possible customer service with
either the commercial growers or with
personal growers and you know during the
break I was thinking about it and it
made me wonder about employee theft
because you know you know in a big
commercial environment you know maybe
you can do something on the slide that
the cameras don't see and if you're
something you know if you're in a real
informal situation in somebody's home
you know I can imagine you know being
able to abscond with some there you know
what's what's your experience with
employee theft you know is that much of
an issue yeah so you know we really
really really just sort of impale with
every ounce of our strength into our
employees how dumb it would be to try so
we don't typically have a lot of problem
with that that being said you know
people try all kinds of crazy things
like like there was an incident in one
of the very first dispensaries that I
worked in where the employee he was in
on their trim team and what he would do
would be to put like several gloves over
his glove and then he would successively
put a but in each glove and stick it in
his pocket as he was trimming but you
know I don't think that he really
understood that his adidas like running
pants were very much showing the outline
of these like what looked like golf
balls in his pockets and so you know I
noticed this and it I couldn't figure
out what was going on because he
definitely didn't have golf balls in his
pocket when he came to work so that was
one of those situations where you know I
think it seemed like a good plan at the
outset but in in execution particularly
with the number of cameras that he was
visible on I just did not go well for
him yeah I can imagine that you know and
what I find is you know there's so much
cannabis just around in the industry
it's kind of a really dumb play to steal
from work you know it really is so easy
you know everybody's got it in the
industry so why would you then go and
risk your job to steal it right but
here's a funny thing like you know even
at the beginning there was a whole point
of contention around well what do you do
with the little buds that fall on the
floor
riot Legos floor weed that just kind of
like in the early days that was just
sort of going out the door I was floor
weed you know but even that in the long
term had to be accounted for and there
had to be standards of operation put in
place to say no you have to actually
take that back and weigh it and say this
is how much we wasted and and account
for it and then destroy it
you can't just sweep it up and stick it
in a jar and take it home so so let's
let's flip that dynamic around instead
instead of the
the trimmer stealing like how let's talk
about arbitrage like what is yeah what
if you get like a you know somebody
who's got a personal grow and in lieu of
paying you for some or all of it they
want to give you your trim or give you
their item for you to then like resell
to you know a BHO person or something
does is that is that a is that legal be
is that something that you ever come
across
right so no that's not legal you know
the only intermediary we would be in
that process would be if we're brought
in to trim and then they're separating
those things out and they send it with a
licensed courier from their operation or
another to take that to an operator we
can't we can't have the product at any
point that's the the nature of the
difference in our licensing doesn't
allow us to to have it to move it to
grow it to sell it nothing like that
because that requires a much different
license than what we have we're an
ancillary vendor so we don't we don't
have you know a middleman on the deal we
can yeah we all that stuff is RFID tags
so essentially we don't own or move any
RFID tag product so so let's let's talk
about licenses in a different way so up
to this point we've been talking about
either having a a license to do a
cannabis business or an individual
person having their badge which allows
them to work in the industry but learns
but you know I have not come across
actually I mean you're the only one
actually you're the first trim company
that I've come across which is why I was
so curious to have you on the show and
you know I've been I've been all over
the country talking to people at this
point and so I think that you know the
days of trimming businesses have have
now have now arrived and yeah and
there's you're going to be having a lot
more competition soon so so are you
looking to other states to license your
intellectual property and you know
not a franchise right because we all
understand that friends yeah isn't legal
but but you know are you looking to
expand the Green Mountain harvest name
into other states we are absolutely yeah
we have business opportunities now
available in any state where its medical
or retail or somewhere in between we are
available to create business
opportunities for you know people who
want to do this there and when the owner
Susan Tchaikovsky started this six years
ago she really saw a need for this an
industry and no one else was doing it
and she had to go to the state and say
this is what I want to do and they said
wow that's a really good idea we hadn't
even thought about that you know it
wouldn't hadn't even crossed anybody's
mind that this was a really valuable and
necessary piece of the puzzle to make
all this work so we have lots of
different services available to that and
we sometimes just go and we'll train
teams of trimmers for people that
already have an existing operation and
and want to have an on-site team so
we've sent people to other states and
we'll send you know again some of our
supervisors and Susan the owner will go
and they stay for a few days or a week
or two and they get everybody up to
speed that's one option the other option
is to actually you know become a partner
a Green Mountain harvest partner and and
and carry that name into another state
and in that case then you know you get a
huge amount of our intellectual property
and our standard practices and how we
how we operate in that gray area
successfully which is which is kind of
part of the key for sure let's let's
circle back to your you mentioning Susan
going to the state to try to get the
blessing for this kind of a business
model because that is a really important
entrepreneurial point and a lot of
people are like oh now that cannabis is
legal I'm just gonna start a business
and I don't have to be an activist
but but right I think that all
entrepreneurs in cannabis have to remain
activists I mean not only to make sure
that your your local government doesn't
pass some kind of moratorium that's
gonna suddenly you know tie your hands
but what Susan did you know Susan had to
come up not only with the business idea
but then she had to lobby for it with
regulators so that there was a license
allowance for it and I think that's a
that's extra credit to Susan for
stepping up and following that and I
think that's a good lesson for everybody
that you know you might have a
groundbreaking idea and you're gonna
have to sell it to your regulators
absolutely I mean yeah it's all about
being part of the movement overall and
so you may have a great idea and you may
be really scared about you know coming
out of a gray market or a black market
with that idea but unless you stand up
and unless you become part of the
movement and say this is what I'm doing
and this is why it's important then you
know you don't move us all forward as a
whole and and that's really what she did
was say not only do I want to have you
know provide a safe way to handle the
product for this particular point in its
process but also what does a business
model look like that really supports its
employees as if this were any other
industry you have to have workman's comp
you have to make people employees and
not have them work as contract labor
which is so often what people are more
apt to do because it's easier for the
employer but it provides the employee no
protection they're not an employee
they're just they're not they have no
protection so Susan really did say I
want to do this but I want to do this
right and what does this look like and
got amazing certifications put in in
place for our company that sort of stay
we are the most compliant and this is
how that looks and and that's why I was
excited to come and work with her after
years of doing other things in the
industry for sure and and I think that
it really helps the end
three as a whole when people like Susan
provide that leadership because then the
regulators can point and say look here's
a good actor who's doing it the right
way who is doing the things that that
cause us to feel more safe as regulators
and then I know hopefully eventually
some of those regulations can be a
little loosened so that they don't cost
as much for companies to comply but
fright now you know we've got this
strange dance between entrepreneurs and
regulators of you know what can the
entrepreneurs get away with versus the
regulator's wanting to you know regulate
or and/or ban everything because they're
afraid of risk absolutely and that's and
and that's why people have to be really
vocal and they have to get out there and
you know even to the point of for
children who are using cannabis patches
in schools that was a big big hurdle
that we had to overcome here in Colorado
helping people understand that this is a
medicine and that these kids are using
it they're not getting high at school a
kid in a wheelchair whose can move their
arms solely because they've started
using these patches isn't getting high
they're having a better quality of life
so so even something as you know simple
as that takes a huge group of people and
a lot of effort and a lot of people
coming forward so you know what I would
say to anyone in those states that where
it's still kind of gray is don't don't
stay in the dark just get out there and
be vocal and and get and and get ready
to sort of be part of something special
because you know the amazing other side
of this is that after you've been in a
state where it's gone recreational and
you've supported the the medical market
and you've seen you know what's happened
here in Colorado some of the outcomes
with people getting out of jail and all
the cool stuff that happens on the side
with the medical research and the kids
getting better and the seizures going
away it's it's just it's worth coming
out of the dark
and you know like Susan is going to
Pennsylvania for example where you know
to speak at a conference that's all just
for doctors who were you know just just
getting the doctors on board as crucial
so you know there's there's work to be
done in every state and and and and what
I say is just be brave and go do it
thanks for being on the show today
Kristin thank you it's my pleasure how
exciting thank you for doing such good
work and getting this information out
there
Kristin Baldwin is director of
operations of Green Mountain harvest you
can find out more at Green Mountain
harvest comm you can find more episodes
of the shaping fire podcast and
subscribe to the show at shaping
feiyr.com
and on Apple iTunes stitcher and Google
Play if you enjoyed the show we'd really
appreciate it if you'd leave a positive
review of the podcast wherever you
download your review will help others
find the show so they can enjoy it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the weekly newsletter for
insights into the latest cannabis news
and product reviews on the shaping fire
web site you will also find transcripts
of today's podcast as well
for information on me--and where i'll be
speaking you can check out Shango lows
calm as your company want to reach our
national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hot spot at shaping
feiyr.com
to find out how thanks for listening to
shaping fire i've been your host Shango
lows
[Music]
you