[Music]
breathing is at the heart of what it
means to be a living human we don't
usually think about it much because
breathing is an autonomic function and
happens without us even really thinking
about it at all
similarly when we inhale cannabis we
spend a lot more time choosing our
favorite strain and smoking or vaping
device than we do thinking about the
role our lungs play in this process
because cannabis is a bronchial dilator
many who use cannabis think that means
that cannabis cannot injure or impact
our lungs and that's simply not true
it's wishful thinking for us to think
that whatever we inhale will be fine so
long as it's cannabis the reality is far
more complex than that
inhaling cannabis can help lungs in many
ways for sure but there's also methods
that negatively impact the lungs as well
not only that if you are talking on a
budget there are definitely ways to
smoke that are more effective at getting
you high with less flour or oil common
myths about cannabis and the lungs are
easily spread while hanging out with
friends smoking bowls or even easier
over the internet but that does not make
them true there are proven and
well-established health insights about
breathing that can improve your use of
cannabis whether it be for health or fun
if you want to learn about cannabis
health business and technique
efficiently and with good cheer I
encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter will send you new podcast
episodes as they come out delivered
right into your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the weekend
videos too don't rely on social media to
let you know when the new episode is
published sign up for the updates to
make sure you don't miss an episode also
starting this month we will be giving
away very cool prizes to folks who are
signed up to receive the newsletter
there's nothing else you need to do to
win except sign up and receive the
newsletter for April I'm really stoked
that we are giving away several newly
released air vape x vaporizers from air
vape usa.com i'll be talking about those
more later in the show but for now go to
shaping feiyr.com to sign up for the
newsletter and be entered into all
future newsletter prize drawings you are
listening to shaping fire and I'm your
host Shango 'lose my guest this week is
Robert Wittman for over 30 years Robert
Wittman has guided clients and students
in the use of movement breath and sound
as a tool for personal growth and
efficient body mechanic
he co-developed the Wellsprings
practitioner program with Emily Conrad
founder of continuum movement and
co-taught with her for 18 years he was
on the faculty of continuum movement
until 2014 and has made many
contributions to Continuum's practices
particularly in the sciences
incorporating respiratory physiology
neuroanatomy and cellular biology Robert
has been a faculty member and head of
the departments of anatomy and
physiology and movement education at the
desert Institute of the healing arts
massage school he teaches the Buteyko
breathing technique helping people with
a variety of disorders and is also an
organizing member registered educator
and trainer of the Buteyko breathing
educators association robert has
advanced certifications in the Duggan
French approach and somatic pattern
recognition and a graduate certification
as a breathing behavior analyst he's
also a specialist in breathing and the
use of feo genic psychoactive substances
he founded his practice personal
practice the breathable body in 2003 and
regularly leads classes and workshops
worldwide
welcome to the show Robert well thank
you good morning to you so before we get
into the mechanics of breathing I want
to set the tone correctly for this show
because you know it's important for
folks to get that you are very
integrative and holistic in your
practice and you know I've already
described your practice in the
introduction but would you set the
context for us by explaining how
cannabis inhalation can increase our
awareness of breathing and the body as a
whole
towards the general betterment of
everybody who talks cannabis yeah one of
the things that I played with and
discovered for myself as well as for my
clients is that cannabis increases body
awareness when I say body awareness is
our ability to be able to sense what is
going on inside of our bodies sort of
like an animal does you know it is
operating from their senses and when we
operate from our senses we're more in
touch with how breathing is actually
moving inside of our organism and by
able then being able to sense that and
feel into how our lungs open how our
body spreads out when we breathe in and
how it comes back into its normal shape
when we breed out we'd be able to then
have better access to using our breath
to soothe our nervous system and to let
the cannabis in its Bronco dilating
effects open up our Airways and so I
like that particular piece of the
awareness that gets included in smoking
cannabis or taking it in other forms and
so that when we learn that about
ourselves even when we are not using
cannabis we're able to implement what
we've learned just throughout the day to
help soothe our nervous system and any
kind of breathing disorders that we may
have that cannabis can support so I know
we're going to be talking a lot about
the relationship between
cannabis breathing and anxiety today can
you break out just a little bit how
breathing is interacts with the nervous
system and so the mechanism by way it
even has the ability to soothe us well
when we relax when we're you know if
cannabis can have any effect of relaxing
you you tend to breathe from a deeper
place with inside of your body it's more
down in the lower belly your diaphragm
and it's more active in breathing which
sets the tone for the nervous system to
recognize that we're not on fight or
flight that it's a time for the body to
be in a more parasympathetic moment of
relaxation when we're anxious we tend to
breathe up high in our chest which is a
much smaller space and so that's sending
a message to our nervous system that
we're in something is threatening us and
so that we're in fight or flight and
when we're in fight-or-flight we're
bringing way too fast and usually in the
case of people who are anxious and not
moving quickly fight-or-flight there's a
mismatch and so there's a lot of
adrenaline running through the system
but we're not moving so the body gets
anxious thinks what's happening where's
the threat and what am I supposed to do
about it right in this particular moment
so the mind gets really active in that
regard if we were really in
fight-or-flight and running for a life
there would be no mind involved so if
cannabis has this ability to if it can
for you soften and their surface soften
the nervous system soften your breathing
relax the body so that you're breathing
more
your diaphragm and more with ease and at
a slower pace that's the biggest issue
too is breathing at a slower pace when
we're really anxious or for having an
asthma attack will tend to breathe 20 to
30 times per minute normal breathing
rate is about 12 to 14 times maybe even
8 to 12 breathing breaths per minute and
when we're really in Paris of authority
sympathetic mode and really relaxed
we're breathing around six breaths per
minute and so that's the dets the
learning that we're looking for is to
how to establish both the pace and the
rhythm of breathing and also the volume
we're breathing less per minute than we
are that in freedom we're in
fight-or-flight and that's a big issue
right there which we can talk about in a
few more minutes why that's so important
that's really interesting and you know
even though I I didn't just toke the
fact that you and I are talking about
breathing is increasing the awareness of
my breath which which now I'm doing it
with more awareness and I notice it's
slowing down and you know I'm excited
because we're doing the recording but
I've just calmed myself down just by
listening to you talk about healthy
breathing so so you know awareness is
everything so so let's talk about now
the actual mechanics right we all take
breathing for for granted but but there
are right ways and wrong ways to do it
and and and our body actually has to do
several things for us to successfully
breathe thank goodness that it's on
autopilot so so so we can unpack this
later on when we're talking about some
of the challenges would you explain the
mechanics of inhalation inhalation thank
you that's a really clear question well
when we breathe in the inhalation the
diaphragm is descending that's that
that's the major breathing muscle that
is right down at the lower ribs and when
the diaphragm moves properly and lowers
down towards your pelvis it's increasing
the size of your lungs it's stretching
the bottom of the lungs that's the first
stage the second stage is the ribs on
the side if you had your hands on the
side of your ribs they
we'll start to elevate and that begins
to take the lungs you know with its
opening up the lungs to be wider in a
really full and big breath when you need
a lot more air then the front of the
chest will move which will increase the
dimension of the lung front to back so
the function of that is to change the
internal pressure of the lungs so when
the lungs are fully closed and we're at
the end of the exhale the pressure
inside the lung is less than the
pressure outside in the atmosphere which
is surprising but it's true and so when
the lungs begin to open up at the pull
of the diaphragm and the ribs the
pressure outside to the body is greater
than the pressure inside this little
space is expanding and so what happens
automatically is air is drawn into the
lungs it's almost like you say we don't
even have to think about it but because
of the pressure changes in physics it
wants to move from a higher pressure
gradient to a lower pressure gradient so
lung the air is coming into the lungs to
equalize the pressure both outside and
inside and so our lungs fill
automatically which is what happened
when we're sleeping we're not thinking
about it which is one of the amazing
things about breathing that it's both
under our control and it happens
automatically that's probably a really
healthy failsafe for our human that as
as we exhale there's like an automatic
bounce back to inhaling again that that
makes evolutionary sense to me
yeah well there is like people who faint
you know a lot of people have
experiences like getting up to speak say
or being on a radio show where they get
anxious and start to breathe too fast
and they begin to hyperventilate and
they get dizzy and they pass out well
that's the failsafe right there you
can't kill yourself by breathing too
much you'll end up fainting and the
mechanism of fainting of course is that
when you're fainted your body will go
back to breeding at a rate that has
actually commensurate for what the body
needs and so you're back coming back to
normal that way right on that makes
sense yeah so as somebody with lifelong
asthma
I've always thought that inhaling
cannabis would be bad for the lungs
because of the resin collecting on the
lungs cilia inside and gooping those up
and also I always expected the throat
and the lung to be irritated from the
heat but you know I got laughed at I had
a lot of social media threads about that
belief and so I I read more and more
about it and it does seem that I'm wrong
and the more studies that I read about
you know tobacco inhalation marijuana
inhalation you know whether it's dabbing
or joints they all seem to suggest that
overall inhaling cannabis is good for
the lungs how can that be so why isn't
inhaling cannabis smoke coating our
lungs with additional resin and making
things worse well one of the things you
have to speak about first is is how much
even is smoke at one time how much
you're taking in what kind of volume and
what kind of heat it's at so in terms of
asthma there are strains and that are
bronchodilators is many this actually
I'm in my own reading too there are six
ways that cannabis actually helps helps
the lungs but if you have to be careful
about how much you smoke and how much
how much heat is in the smoke because
when you know there's too much heat in
the smoke your coughing which is
actually a reaction to kind of push out
what got in there that doesn't need to
be in there so we're looking at other
effects of it in terms of microdose in
cannabis we're looking at
anti-inflammatories antibacterial
bronchial dilation and anti somatic and
it's an allergy sick it helps with the
pain so if the the Bronco dilating
effect is the most important because
with asthma that's what happens when
you're starting to have an asthma attack
the smooth muscle in the Airways is
contracting in a way that doesn't allow
the air to be released so cannabis
offers that effect where it's the smooth
muscle and it relaxes it to let the
airflow begin again so I think in terms
of what you're talking about in terms of
the resins it just really depends on how
much you smoke there's
to the readings and most of the studies
have been done with cannabis or about
small doses yeah that makes sense
so so that's interesting that that
really there's a threshold point where
the the regularity of smoking cannabis
switches over from being necessarily
healthy for the lungs to actually being
potentially detrimental and and of
course you know I'm sure that everybody
like me is wondering how do we know
where that point is and I'm assuming
that it's different for every person but
do we really only know where our
threshold is when we reach it and we
start experiencing negative side effects
from too much smoke inhalation yeah
that's my experience my experience is
the fact that the smoke and the resin so
let's talk about mucus so the lungs have
this ability to make mucus and so you
could you know you start to expect your
rate you start to notice that you have a
little bit more mucus and it you're
coughing up so why is that mucus being
produced in the first place it's being
produced to protect the lungs something
is irritating the lungs beyond what they
normally need and the body's making more
mucus to cover it up and to help it move
out because the mucus is meant to either
be swallowed or coughed up so my
experience is when I start to feel like
I've got more mucus in my body I know
that I'm smoking too much and that I'm
putting too many irritants into my lungs
that actually makes a lot of sense to
because you know people in cannabis you
know often will joke about you know the
the mucus or feeling chunky after you
know after a big session and and and I
myself you know when I go to full
weekend you know cannabis events that
are more party than convention like like
emerald cup down in Sonoma County at the
end of Emerald cup by the time I'm
driving home you know I feel like I feel
like there's been a warzone in my lungs
or something you know they feel they
feel sore and tired and and and in and
that is from you know successive joints
with friends and colleagues at the event
because you know certainly my usage goes
up at something like that so that makes
sense um you know you know you
excuse me for happening but you said
something really important there it's
like the sore and then overused you know
there's a that we're so see what's the
word I want to use here you know so
unaware is the best word I can come up
with at the moment about how our lungs
are really taking care of us I mean they
are the most essential thing we do yes
we could talk about our heart being very
essential but the way the heart runs of
course is that it has to receive the
oxygen that the lungs bring in so it's a
rule of three go three minutes without
breath three days without water three
weeks without food it is the most
essential process that our body goes
through and we take it for granted most
of the time so that when our lungs are
feeling sore and feeling tired it's a
time that we can say to ourselves you
know you know your lungs you our lungs
they've been taking care of us for a
really long time here how about I slowed
down relax let my body breathe in a
quiet way let me take care of my lungs
for a while right on so before we go to
the break and in our second set we're
gonna talk a lot about vaporizers and
the difference between that and smoke
but I want to hit one more moment on
different warning signs or at least like
little yellow flags that people can look
for you mentioned mucus which I'm sure
is maybe even the most prevalent one but
but when somebody is you know new to
cannabis and they don't have the
experience of years and years of it like
like many folks do you know what what
things can they look for to let them
know that they may be reaching their
outside threshold of inhalation and so
maybe need to start considering you know
tinctures and other other less inhale a
inhaled cannabis well it's interesting
about what the other thing that drives
the other thing that drugs breathing is
the ratio between carbon dioxide and
oxygen in that system and most of the
time we think about the top oxygen is
the nutrient and carbon dioxide is the
waste gas and actually the truth of that
is that carbon dioxide regulates the
distribution of oxygen in our bodies so
when I talked about hyperventilating the
reason we
is because the carbon dioxide levels get
so low before blowing it out all the
time that the oxygen distributions in
the brain slows down and we faint so
it's the same thing with smoking too
much cannabis your if you especially if
your exhaling be exhales you're
disrupting the blood gases in your body
so you can start to get headaches you
can start to get tingling in your hands
and feet you can start to feel your
blood pressure rise your heart rate
increase and those are signs that
perhaps you're exhaling too much and so
and it may be exhaling a lot through
your mouth so you could think about
exhaling through your nose but those
would be some of the signs that your
you're overdoing dehydration would be
another one so those are some of the
sons because you're disrupting the blood
gases wow that's that's really
interesting so so based on that would it
be a safe to say rule of thumb that
taking more smaller hits is going to be
better for our lungs than taking monster
bravado hits yes and you know it's also
changed we used to think we had to hold
the air they smoke in our lungs and
that's that's been proven inaccurate now
we don't need to do that holding up her
breath which does cause the breathing
rate to get disturbed now we can breathe
in small small amounts let it come in
and then put it right out as well as
taking it into your mouth first and then
let me get cool there and then going
into the lungs rather than taking it
right into the lung so yes smaller hits
are much more preferable than really big
hits I'm glad you brought up that that
myth because you know there's a lot of
people I mean even even I I believed
that for you know 20-some years that
that you take the hit and I want to hold
it as long as I can because I'm thinking
that it's it's soaking into my lungs and
I want all the cannabinoids to soak into
my lungs and then and then if I could I
just want to you know exhale clear
because I've got it all now you know and
and and I know that that's wrong but I
don't know why that's wrong what what is
wrong with that understanding of how the
cannabinoids are taken in in the lungs
that I don't have to hold my breath yeah
so the one thing is the fact of what
happens to the breathing rate and the
the rhythm of the breath gets disrupted
by holding your breath in that that
pattern can carry over into real life
but it's also keeping the smoke in the
lungs too long that's where the that's
where the damage can be done by the
smoke is having it be circulating inside
the lungs for too long a length of time
it just needs to come in absorb what it
needs to absorb and and release it I see
so the the fallacy in the thinking is
that an infinite amount of cannabinoids
can be absorbed through the lungs and
any particular breath when the reality
is is that if you just take a you know a
small to medium sized hit breathe it in
the the capacity for the lungs to intake
cannabinoids is going to be hit its
limits and then you exhale and that's
great but if you take a bigger hit and
you hold it for longer you're actually
causing damage without actually any
increase to benefit because your lungs
can fill themselves up with all the you
know cannabinoids that a can take in
just with a simple small hit yes yes a
couple of things one is that a red blood
cells line up singularly as they travel
through the lungs and it takes
three-quarters of a second for a red
blood cell to pick up the oxygen and
whatever else it's gonna pick up from
alone so it's on its way in
three-quarters of a second the other
piece of so you can imagine that the
parades going it's the blood stream is
very available to pick up what's ever in
there the other piece of that is that if
you start holding your holding your
breath with little air in there you're
over stretching like a rubber band
that's getting used too much in its
stretched position and so eventually
it's a possibility if you're smoking and
holding it for a long period of time you
could be done doing damage to the
elasticity of the lungs wow that's
really interesting all right cool so
after the break we're gonna start
talking about vaporizers so we're gonna
take that short break and be right back
you're listening to shaping fire and my
guest today is breathing specialist
Robert Lippmann join me at the upcoming
can med event in Los Angeles for a
gathering of the top minds in cannabis
medicine field experts will present
their latest findings and best practice
in treating a variety of conditions with
cannabis including epilepsy pain
traumatic brain injury cancer autism and
more laboratory professionals will share
their revolutionary technologies in
cannabinoid and turpenoid extraction
delivery methods and quality and safety
testing can med 2018 is October 22nd
through 24th at the Luskin Conference
Center at UCLA and while the final
speakers list is still coming together
the speakers who are already announced
give you plenty of reasons to get your
ticket today prepare yourself to learn
from 54 thought-leader presentations
focused on furthering the convergence of
medical cannabis research treatment and
product development speakers include the
father of cannabis research Raphael Mis
ulam Michael door chief medical
consultant for the Israeli Ministry of
Health will be there to the list of
esteemed speakers participating is long
and includes shaping fire guests
cannabis neuroscientist dr. Ethan
Rousseau and Kevin McKiernan of
medicinal genomics you can view all the
speakers at kin med events calm this
year's kin med features a special
education track on the application of
blockchain technology in the cannabis
market including cannabis banking seed
the sale tracking sequencing the
cannabis genome ICO financing and more
if you are a medical care provider be
sure to arrive a date early to
participate in the pre-conference CME
course find out more about that at kin
med events comm that's c-a-n-n-a me D
events calm 95% of attendees said kin
med 2017 met or exceeded their
expectations that's a serious vote of
confidence that can med 2018 will be
well worth your time and resources
shaping fire listeners can save 20% off
the ticket price priced by purchasing
before June 21st and using the discount
code Shango so don't delay visit kin med
events comm today to reserve your seat
and find out more because I often
mention that I have asthma on shaping
fire I get emails from folks asking me
what vaporizers I recommend now
certainly there's a wide range of
interesting vapes on the market but
since this episode is all about
breathing today I'm going to take a
moment
tell you about the two vapes and one
filter that I use pretty much every day
the most luxurious vaporizer I have is
the vape exhale it's considered a
desktop vaporizer but it's also easy to
travel with in a padded case it plugs
into the wall and because of that it
gets up to temperature very fast not
only is that great for just not waiting
around but it packs enough power to give
a really solid satisfactory dab hit the
vape exhale can use either flower or DAB
oil for flower you grind up the material
and drop it in a basket and you place
that basket in the base for dab oil you
place your dab in a borosilicate or
quartz tube and then you drop that into
the base because it's a wall plugged
home appliance you'll get hits of flower
and dab unlike any of you've ever had
before
especially from a vaporizer in fact I
sold my email after my first month
having a vape exhale I just knew I was
never gonna use it again so I let the
folks at vape exhaled know ahead of time
that I was gonna mention their device on
the show today and they sent up a
discount code for you to receive 10% off
just type in shaping fire as one word at
checkout and you know 10% off actually
matters when buying a serious device
like this so make sure to use it
the website is vape exhale the EON the
front of exhale is drop so it's just
vape exhale calm and you know even in a
padded travel case though sometimes the
vape exhale is bigger than I want
sometimes when I'm like hiking or going
to a show or whatever I need something
for my pocket for that I use my air vape
X this is the latest model from air vape
usa.com
you know I had their last version too
and I liked it but the new X version is
really just fabulous it's more refined
than the last version and clearly is
more user friendly the air vape also
gets up to temp very fast for vaping on
the go and I like it that you can set
the temperature that you want it to hit
and also that it vibrates when it's
ready to vape in case like I get
distracted by chatting or something you
know it's all I hey you know ready to
smoke that's especially great because
you can vape both flour and oil in these
you just slide the little concentrates
cup for oil and slide that in and you're
good to go I also dig the travel case
that comes with it it's super sleek and
discreet and more
importantly it protects my air vape ex
from getting beaten up or damaged in my
pocket or luggage this is the same
vaporizer you heard about in the
introduction to the show today air vape
has given us a few of these to give away
to people on our email list so if you
listen to the show but you're not on the
email list make sure to subscribe for
your chance to win one of these vapes
this month you'll also hear more about
air vape a bit later on the show because
they bought a commercial spot today now
I know you could be thinking that I'm
recommending the air of eight because
they sponsor the show but let me say
this I have five different travel
vaporizers at home but the other four
all stay at home when I go to
conventions or to the beach it's the air
vape that I grab to take it's as simple
as that
the last product I want to mention is
the filter 420 comm filter for pre-rolls
because of my asthma I really got to be
careful with pre-rolls ever since
finding the filter 420 I've been able to
enjoy pre-rolls a whole lot more when
you attach the recycled plastic filter
on the end of the joint it filters out
the tar and gives a much nicer tastier
smoking experience it is astonishing and
actually kind of gross to see all the
tar that builds up in one of these
filters and I'm glad it isn't going into
my lungs and it certainly doesn't impede
my high at all
that's filter 420 comm again not a paid
ad so there you are
for today's episode on breathing I
recommend the vape exhale desktop vape
the air vape X pocket vape and the
filter 420 pre-roll filter check them
out your lungs will be happy you did
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire I'm your host Shango lohse
and our guest this week is breathing
specialist Robert Lippmann of the
breathable body so before the break we
were talking a lot about combustion
basics you know how to breathe in smoke
what's going on and and why we enjoy it
so much with cannabis and before we talk
vaporizers I want to talk about what it
was essentially the old-school vaporizer
right if we were using a bong and we
didn't want it to hurt as much we added
ice man and for me that's that's a good
part of college so so were we kidding
ourselves that that adding ice to the
bong what made it easier on our lungs
or did it just make it feel easier
because it makes the that makes the
experience of the smoke a little less
harsh well is there a difference between
feeling and and the truth of that
experience it is all based on feeling
and it does cool the smoke I mean how
many times have you burned your throat
and it's and when you're burning your
throat it's the same Airways that are
inside the lungs and so anything that
helps cool it down so that there's not
that burn that has to be rehabilitated
by the throat and the lungs it's going
to be advantageous right on so so all of
you who put ice in your bongs thumbs up
and for those of you who live near the
snow your snow bongs are still good to
go as well right so think of the thing
about it for using it for for asthma and
learning how to use your breath properly
with the smoke it's you know you got to
stay somewhat conscious this is true so
is so while we're still talking about
asthma you know um you know people who
listen to this show regularly know that
I'm a big fan of vaporizers I mean I
love smoking you know joints and bongs
as well when but but for daily use I'm
really much more about the vaporizer
because because it makes my whole life a
little bit better and the vaporizers
that are out now are infinitely better
than the ones that we had just a few
years ago but you know since you are
looking at this as more of a you know a
science and dr. lead direction how much
truth is there actually to the idea that
vaporizers are healthier for people
generally but especially for people with
breathing issues like asthmatics and CP
of COPD and things like that well you
certainly don't get any of the tars and
any of any of the burn from the paper
and it is a it is definitely a cooler
smoke you're not even going up over you
know 170 180 degrees well when you're
combusting through a pipe or through
paper you can be up to a thousand degree
temperature so there's quite a bit of
difference right there alone as well as
like I said with especially with papers
you're getting a little league
particulate sore in the papers
vaporizers you don't get any of that you
don't get any ash you're just getting
the vapor and the vapor is carrying at
your
carrying the THC certainly
experientially it's much nicer to the
point that when when I turn people on to
my my luxurious vape Xcel water pipe
vaporizer at first they're not even
certain if they got a hit because
because they're expecting the the
irritation and the and the choking and
all of that and and and and and and what
they normally just say is oh that tastes
good which is of course a great response
but then by the time they've had their
second or third hit and they they've
gotten used to the idea that they exhale
and it's more of a of a light tasty
vapor than it is smoke you know people
start to get into it at that point
so what's going on differently in the
body is it just simply that the body is
not clenching because I'm not smoking in
all those extra tars and particulates
that you mentioned
yes it's very true I like the way you
say that because the lungs are very
responsive to atmosphere and so if
there's things in the atmosphere like
Tarzan - they are going to contract to
make sure that they do not absorb those
things and so with vaporize invisibie
it's not going on alert the body's not
going on alerts around um so the other
go ahead yeah the other piece that I was
going to say about it is that you know
when you're vaporizing and you you don't
think there's much smoke coming out you
kind of have to wait to see what the
effects are yeah that's actually a good
point you know historically I would
judge how you know how high I was going
to get based on my exhale like so you
know somebody has a big exhale and it's
a big cloud of smoke and everybody in
the smoking circle goes oh you know
because that person's in for a fun ride
but with with a vaporizer
I really have to judge it in how much I
pack into the vaporizer because there's
there's not that visual cue anymore and
and certainly when I was learning how it
first using how to use a vaporizer I
would you know hat you know both over
and under pack until I learned
you know how to use this new tool that
makes sense mm-hmm and remember too that
we're talking about this from additional
use from you know started this
conversation around asthma and about
body awareness so slowing it down
cooling the tempers down gives a chance
for the consciousness and the awareness
to actually pay attention to the process
without the happy to be so reactive so
there's an engagement you breathe in
breathe out you're kind of sitting with
what how's this how's this acting in my
body and what kind of medicinal effects
is it having right now especially if I'm
using it at a time that my lungs are
contracting and having a bit of an
asthmatic attack I want to feel that
instantaneous dilation that's possible
and for folks who don't have asthma or
COPD I would think that this would be a
winning strategy for them as well simply
because you know for a lot of people if
you take you know a monster hit and it
has a lot of particulate smoke in it and
you start coughing you know perhaps your
adrenals kick off a little bit maybe you
get a little anxious maybe you do get
that soreness of a lung going forward so
even if you're just toking for fun using
a vaporizer may be to your benefit just
because it's an easier experience yeah
and one of the things that's speaking to
about chalking excuse me
choking and coughing again when we go
back to what we said earlier in the day
about breathing from the diaphragm
everyday from the chest coughing and
choking are all energies that come up
word and it doesn't take the body long
to get pattered into a different
breathing mat and so if you call from
choke for a little bit you'll probably
notice right away the next couple of
breaths you're up in your chest so then
you have to be conscious about bringing
your breathing back down to the lower
part of the body so if you're brave
vaporizing easily and taking small hits
on it you can kind of stay with that
experiences you've been begin to deepen
into your breathing so so this next
question I I don't know if you're gonna
have an answer for this Robert it's it's
definitely non-sequitur and I haven't
seen any Studies on it but I'm gonna ask
you anyway because you've already
surprised me a couple times um so you
know when some people when they first
start vaporizing they say that the
is different than when they're smoking
joints and and you know after doing a
lot of both and having a lot it using a
lot of different kinds of vaporizers I
have to agree with that to a certain
extent certainly I can get just as high
from a vaporizer as I can from a joint
but somehow the the tenor of it is
different it's it's a little it's a
little cleaner it's a little less
violent but but I don't really know why
it's that there's a difference I suspect
it's because there are attributes to the
experience of the high that people feel
after smoking a joint that that they
don't feel after a vaporizer so I don't
know if that was a very well worded
question but if you understand where I'm
going what are your thoughts well I do I
do understand you going that's my
experience as well but I'm really about
engagement and participation with an
experience and I find that I can be more
I do notice that I'd you know it is a
different kind of hi I would said I
don't feel as high but I'm not sure
that's exactly accurate but I do feel
like I'm not engaged my body is not
engaged with having to filter out the
negative attributes of smoking so I can
stay more connected to the experience
that's my best answer for that and
that's the part that I like I like it
being engaged with the process that I'm
participating in and I like being
engaged with my awareness that I stay
present in my body and in my experience
I don't like getting so far out that I
have to manage too many different
experiences at one time being kind
clearing my throat all those different
pieces I think the body what we're not
aware of is that the body is on alert in
some way that takes us out of me and we
need enjoyment of the experience I like
that answer good I'm glad I asked
thank you so um you know a lot of these
folks who are listening a lot of folks
that listen to the show work with COPD
patients like I do and a lot of folks
talk about COPD patients but I have a
feeling that people don't really get
what's up with that condition as much as
they do with asthma so will you just
describe what COPD is and just so for
everyone's understanding well it stands
first of all first of all the initials
stand for chronic obstructive pulmonary
disease so something's happening in the
Airways so obstruction so over time from
asthmatics that's what usually develops
from it's a crime it's an order of the
allergies asthma COPD emphysema where
the Airways are so occluded or tightened
and twisted that it's hard to get the
air move air in and out as well as
what's beginning to happen is that the
little air sacs in the lungs there's 300
million of those little air sacs that
get move air back and forth I just like
this little statistic if you cut them
open and later side by side it's like at
the surface the area of a tennis court
to move air back and forth so those
little alveoli start to distend and they
lose their elasticity and the blood
vessels that are picking up oxygen
around those alveoli start to separate a
little bit so the movement of air and
oxygen is that is hindered we can't get
as much oxygen we're not as saturated as
much so the where we go with this with
COPD it is really important that
breathing rhythms and breathing volumes
and the balancing of the blood gases
that are available all right they're
optimal so even if we're getting less
oxygen than normal we are able to move
it to ourselves that's the issue it's
not just that what we can take in what's
in our blood but how does it get from
our blood into our cells where does the
most good making the energy that runs
our body so COPD is a very debilitating
energy-wise we bodies don't have enough
energy to operate fully unless they get
something mental oxygen or learn how to
breathe really in the most effective way
to minimize the reduction of not moving
that's too many negatives of not moving
the oxygen from the blood to the cells
but maximizing that potential so I run
into patients all the time asking me
about
cannabis as a bronchial dilator and they
want to vape it but when I originally
started hearing this from people I
thought that was crazy right because
with COPD why would you want to inhale
anything and then I went ahead and I
started looking at the studies and and
and and there's there seem to be a mix
some - some suggest that you want to
inhale cannabis vapor so that you are
directly applying it to the lungs for
the bronchial dilation and general
relaxation effects but then but then
some talk about the potential use of
oral tinctures - which would be more
systemic and and and not targeted
towards the lungs so so what are your
thoughts about the the benefits of
taking a cannabis tincture and their
ability to bronchial dilator the lungs
without actually inhaling the vapor for
this is for more severe COPD folks who
are looking for relief yeah I'm a big
fan of the tinctures I can say a couple
two things that I'm thinking about right
now it depends what's going on COPD wise
whether there's something some kind of
obstruction that's going on in the lungs
themselves or whether it's in the
Airways going towards the lungs so we
have to kind of take a look at what's
going on at this more if the damage is
more systemic in the lungs and I like
teachers and so a lot of the studies
that have been done are tinctures are a
good way to go that is the oldest form
of taking cannabis even in Egypt in
ancient times they used tinctures in
India and China when you're thinking
about bronchial dilating for asthma for
COPD it would be more effective to do
that when you are having a moment when
you really are bronchial constricted the
VAP we'll get to it much sooner if
you're just trying to keep the Airways
open and relaxed then pinches will do
the job but if you want if you're having
an attack and really can't catch your
breath and there's a you're not able to
move any air the teachers are too slow
so you need to bathe in that particular
time I get it so so taking a tincture is
more of a
and and and vaping is more like crisis
management exactly that makes a lot of
sense so so before we go to our second
commercial I want to create this
opportunity because when I met with you
you went through this wonderful little
breathing exercise and I think that
everybody would would appreciate having
this experience so so we're talking
about asthma we're talking about COPD
we're talking about taking too big of
hits and we're talking about crisis
management and and all of these can be
answered by creating a soothing
breathing pattern and and and this
example is is you teach this on your on
your youtube channel as well so if if
people hear this you know once in your
car with the podcast and you want to
hear a longer version of it you can you
can get that on the breathable body
website and on this YouTube page but but
would you this is this is a short thing
it's only about 90 seconds but but
Robert would you go ahead and do the
soothing breathing pattern exercise for
folks and then and then after
everybody's all chill we'll go to
commercial okay have a little time for a
little backstory on this yeah yeah go
right ahead
okay so we've been talking about in
those breathing a little bit so let me
just say a couple of things that nose
breathing is the way the body uses air
most effectively you breathe through
your mouth as often as you eat through
your nose as always like to say in class
and that you pace yourself you can
breathe through your nose
almost all the time why is that is
because it's the best utilization of
carbon dioxide the body retains more to
help the oxygen move when you breathe
through your mouth you give up way too
much covered outside as I said in
hyperventilating and we've seen this
experience when somebody's about to
faint and they breathe in through a
paper bag that breathing back their own
carbon dioxide and they reduce the
ability to faint they lose the they
won't think let's put it that way so
this exercise is designed when you're
feeling anxious or when you're feeling
like you're breathing too fast in 81
seconds I don't bring the body back to a
little slower breathing rate as well as
to maximize the use of your carbon
dioxide to help oxygen get distributed
more quickly which will bring the system
back into relaxing so I'm going to do
this in a
1981 second exercise and it's up to the
count of six and then back from the
count of six so you'll understand when I
do it if you're having an asthma attack
you would do it up to the count of ten
and then come back from ten so sit
comfortably I'm going to say it this way
I'm going to tell you to breathe in I'm
gonna tell you to breathe out and I'm
gonna tell you to suspend your breathing
so I'm having you breathe in to the rate
of two seconds out for the rate of three
seconds and then we'll be holding
periodically moving from two seconds up
to six seconds and back again so don't
over breathe
don't try to breathe harder be in a
relaxed place just let the air come in
as naturally as it can in this
particular time or whatever your
breathing rate is and rhythm is let it
be that don't overdo it all right here
we go
so when I say ready take a breath in
take a breath out and suspend your
breathing one two take a breath in take
a breath out let's just spend one two
three breath in take a breath out
suspend one two three four breathe in
breathe out suspend
one two three four five breathe in
breathe out suspend one two three four
five six breathe in breathe out suspend
one two three four five breathe in
breathe out suspend one two three four
breathe in breathe out
so spend one two three breathe in
breathe out suspend one two breathe in
breathe out everybody nice and relaxed
oh yeah Robert I am really calm
I am very chill now
yeah so this feeling that I have right
now is why I wanted to include it in
today's show because when we did this in
person it actually makes me feel like
I'm gently high and it's just working
with my body's natural rhythms and not
only is this great for folks with asthma
and COPD and related you know blockage
type things but but also as more and
more people are experimenting with
cannabis and and people introduce
themselves to dabbing and and cannabis
is getting stronger sometimes we can
feel anxious when we're using cannabis
and so this this breathing exercise you
know so far it has been a hundred
percent effective in me when I get a
little off my game and get anxious when
I'm talking this brings me right back to
where I want to be and for something
like that to be so effective and only
take a minute and a half of
concentration I would call that some
pretty powerful tech it is what's
happening with the feeling of is you
know all that breath holding in between
is increasing the co2 which is really
allowing the body to flood with oxygen
and so that's what you're feeling when
you feel a little high you're getting so
much more oxygen to your brain and once
the brain has more oxygen it's as well
okay we can chill no there's nothing
there's no threat going lower we're
fully fed we're nourished fantastic so
let's go ahead I'm so calm now let's go
ahead and then and take our our second
break and we'll be right back you're
listening to shaping fire and my guest
today is breathing specialist Robert
linman
while I certainly still enjoy smoking
joints I moved over to using vaporizers
about three years ago the high was a
little different than burning the flower
and in the end I decided I preferred it
for daily use especially because I have
asthma more importantly though I could
taste my flower so much more it's hard
to express to you how significantly
different cannabis with a good terpene
profile tastes when vaped instead of
burned I have brought my vape with me to
visit growers and they are astonished by
the clarity of taste and they say they
feel like they're tasting their flower
for the very first time the air vape
vaporizer from air vape usa.com
is a great device to use on the go or at
home when you pick it up and feel
satisfying like a medical device
it isn't flimsy like many vape Tsar I
like how the flower is inserted in the
top instead of the bottom so travels are
shorter path to my mouth with the
cannabis at the top I get a hit that
feels more substantial even though I'm
just inhaling vapor and not full-bodied
smoke since I used this vape for flower
hash and concentrates I really like that
that digital control for the temperature
is right there on the front three clicks
of the button and it fires up to the
temperature I specify really quickly and
discreetly you know vape concentrates
are a milder experience than dabbing but
you still get the potency in your hit
also the taste is great
as would be expected with a low temp tab
I love that this vape gives quick little
vibrations when it gets to the right
temperature that way if I'm chatting or
distracted while it's heating up it lets
me know when it's ready if you are ready
for a nice pocket-sized vaporizer
consider the air vape the new air vape
ex has just come out and it's gorgeous
and includes many updates you can find
more about the air vape vaporizer at air
vape usa.com if you own a cannabis
company you know that finding good
business partners vendors and allies is
an essential part of your role and
building your business in a new industry
like cannabis doesn't always make that
easy Kanna Khan is coming to Boston in
Detroit this summer and the halls will
be filled with every kind of ally you
need for a cannabis company technology
horticulture packaging marketing legal
human resources and media everything you
need for your business will be there and
your customers will be there too because
canna con is a premier
business and networking event with
nationally recognized speakers and the
opportunity to have serious
conversations with your business peers
and investors reserving yourself a boot
that can akan can unlock a lot of doors
for you not only do you get to network
with all the people who pass your booth
but it is not uncommon for kin akan
vendors to do a million dollars in
business during the event Canha con
seattle ii event in february sold out
well in advance so reserve your booths
now for detroit June 1st and second and
Boston July 27th and 28th attendee
tickets are still available for both
events whether you reserved a booth or
attend just for a day do not miss the
opportunity to become a serious player
in your market visit canikin org for
tickets booth reservations and more
information that's Kanak on.org
welcome back you're listening to shaping
fire I'm your host Shengo Louis and our
guest this week is breathing specialist
Robert Wittman of the breathable body so
I gotta tell you that was one of the
calmest breaks I have ever had in fact I
needed to do a couple jumping jacks to
get my head back in the game for this
last section so during this last section
we're gonna talk a bit about dabbing and
then a bit about a ceremonial plant
medicine so that'll be fun
um but let's let's talk we'll talk a
little bit about what we know so far
about breathing and dabbing because
because you know most of these studies
around the impacts that dabbing has on
the human just haven't been done yet
there's a lot of opportunity there but
they just haven't been done yet so so
let's start with something really basic
so the heat coming off of dab rigs is
extraordinarily hot especially if
someone's using a torch and if they hit
it at full temp you know you know Robert
is is is dabbing especially abusive to
the lungs compared to other types of
inhalation of cannabis yeah it feels
that way to me I mean it's the burn if
we're doing again I go back to the
burning issue the burning issue is is
going to cause the the lungs in the
airways to to scar so over time the
repetitive tearing apart of the
epithelial lining rebuilding the
epithelial lining tear it down
rebuilding it
it's gonna count do you know the bodies
are very adaptable in terms of
strengthening what it needs to
strengthen and it will just solidify
some of those more malleable teachers
that are meant to be malleable and so
you know over time period that's a
stiffening of the Airways not what's
meant to happen yeah that doesn't that
doesn't sound good
certainly it doesn't feel good is it is
an odd part of cannabis culture right
now and and you know and I should say
upfront that I dab you know I'll using
butane torches when I'm out but really I
prefer dabbing at home on my on my vape
XL device but you know I dab so I'm into
concentrates but what I'm not into is
that burning feeling and and you know it
seems to me that that it so it's an odd
aspect of our cannabis culture that the
burning and even sometimes people
Keeling over from the from the amount of
you know things that they inhaled
calling husband that keeled over there's
a certain amount of you know here onus
to having that big hot dab and III think
that we're gonna we're gonna evolve away
from that as a scene and and for me the
the sooner the better
how about the inhalation of terpenes
though you know smoking a joint is one
thing because there's only so many
terpenes to inhale in the joint but with
a concentrate you know those are could
theoretically reach a level of terpene
toxicity you know and I and I have yet
to see any Studies on this so so it's
it's mostly just opinion but like what's
your hunch as somebody who does this all
day every day what do you think that the
studies are gonna look like when when
they're eventually completed
I do think there'll be toxicity I think
you think of it the terpenes is
aromatherapy you know and you're doing
this from aromatherapy you're always
looking for the light of the light smell
and you know you're gonna eventually
become more immune to the terpenes and
stuff the body's going to develop a a
protection device so there won't be as
effective what's my edge yeah that makes
sense and you know it also makes me
concerned about the
these custom sauces that people are
putting into vape pens I mean anybody
listens to the note and into the show
knows that I'm a big fan of whole plant
medicine anyway but some of these you
know these custom terpene sauces people
are making they are being blended based
on taste more than they're being blended
based on science and it concerns me that
some of these especially tasty carts
that are jam-packed with aftermarket
terpenes that don't come you know that
are not in the original makeup of the
plant the percentage of them are so high
so they taste good I'm just concerned
about their long-term effects of the
lungs and I know that that could make me
sound like a like a negative Nelly or
whatever but you know as somebody who
works with patients every day this is
this is where my head's at
no you're answering your own question I
mean it's an artificial stimulation it
says it can't human body doesn't like
that kind of stuff just doesn't right on
so um so so let's let's up the scales
right so so when someone takes a huge
dab they are inhaling heavy amounts of
you know THC and other cannabinoids
intense terpenes and I've seen plenty of
videos and you know people even joke
about this online and memes where
someone takes a huge hit and keels over
right there their eyes are rolling back
a little bit maybe they shake and they
fall over and you know in some circles
their friends laughs and you know that's
that's just it's part of our scene here
but but why right like what is happening
with the delivery of that hit to the
lungs that somehow shuts their human
down how come it doesn't happen to other
people you know doing entertainment
sighs dabs of several grams for a video
it only seems to happen to some people
sometimes when they take a monster hit
do you have any suggestions about what
might be going on at the the
mechanization level you know all each
each one of us is sensitive in a
different way and so some people can
tolerate pain some people can tolerate
loud noises and some people can so it
depends on a person's nervous system the
shutdown is an overload
the nervous isms but I can't handle it
so I gotta shut down it's too much it's
too much stimulus way too fast for this
particular nervous system and so it
shuts down well that would make sense
why it's different for for every people
and and probably even why it's probably
also related to tolerance too if it you
know over time you can probably handle
more dab inhalation than you would a
normal eyes but you know I'm thinking
back to this the second set you know
it's actually a you know well said that
if people are gonna dab because I'm
gonna continue to dab even though I know
what we're talking about but but what I
have found is that micro dabbing is the
way to go because just like we were
talking earlier about the the very clear
reasons why it makes physiological sense
to take more smaller hits because you
are you'll be gentler on the lungs plus
honestly you're preserving your your
cannabis as well because you're not
wasting it on the exhale but but taking
more like a higher number of micro dabs
so you're taking more of a smaller
inhalation really seems to be the way to
go if if you're gonna if people are
going to continue with concentrates
which they're you know it's just getting
more popular not less well when we come
back to the topic of the show which was
asthma and COPD so you had kind of have
to evaluate when the micro death does
its job for you for that particular
person that particular reason if you're
using it for other things like the party
and have a good time that's a different
story
but otherwise the studies that have been
done show about 200 micrograms of THC is
all you need for the bronco for the
lungs to begin to expand so it's
overkill in terms of that regard so yeah
i think i think i think of it in terms
of alpha me that we're experimenting in
both ends from micro dosing to dabbing
to try to come to some middle middle
ground that says this is what's really
best for the body is we now it's
becoming you know so pervasive it's
legal almost everywhere
we didn't have that opportunities like
when we're in a candy store now trying
to figure out what the what's the best
candy to use yeah right and we want we
want to experiment with all the candy
without suddenly getting obese or having
a sugar fit right yeah totally so yeah
interesting a lot of us are learning in
the mix especially those of us in the
industry who are developing these
products at the same time as we're
learning how to use these products I
remember the early days of dabbing you
know the same people who are dabbing
were the ones who were doing the you
know that were the first extractors and
so they were their own guinea pigs which
I see a lot in this industry meaning
heck i I I experiment myself with new
techniques and I'm like well was that a
pleasant experience you know did did
this CVG tincture work to help with my
back pain or not and and it's it's
interesting how many of us in the
industry are our own guinea pigs well I
think the word you use there was
pleasure of all was this pleasurable or
not that's not something that we really
is a culture of value is what's
pleasurable and I think that's one of
the things that we can do with cannabis
especially in micro dosing or you know
being gentle with ourselves is to really
find out is it giving us the results
that we want and does it feel pleasure
well to me well I don't know once a
thing that feels pleasurable whatever
what's the thing that's gonna burn me
well the the pleasure principle there is
something that is a great transition for
our last topic because you know one of
the things that I've enjoyed hearing you
speak and and and watching your your
videos is that you know you really blend
science ceremonial plant medicine and
experienced based spirituality together
when you're teaching people you know not
only how to take care of their body with
breath but also people who are
interested in you know ceremonial plant
medicine as part of that health
experience so you know tell us a little
bit if you would why smoking cannabis
can be so spiritual with the right set
and setting
well I friend of mine kind of introduced
me to this idea about speaking to the
plant itself to Santa Maria
Jane however you want to call her and
recognizing that she's an ally that
she's a teacher and in that teaching she
will go through many stages when you
ingest cherry and it's the first rush of
her and then there's a long period of
her enlivening you in some kind of
spiritual body way and then the peace
that comes afterwards where you begin to
come down from it and you feel your
tiredness and your end of your journey
so you're thinking of it as a journey as
a time period of in ingesting an ally
who is on board to wake up some part of
your consciousness for me it's mostly
body consciousness but I also like when
I am moving my body Howard enlightens my
psyche and my spiritual consciousness so
being conscious that it is an allied
that's the big best way I can say it in
so many plants like other plants or
master teachers but cannabis has its own
its own textures and personality so you
know really engaging with the
personality of the plant that you're
ingesting allows it to enhance what
you're wanting to bring forward in that
particular moment and different strains
will do different things so there again
comes back to the engagement and being
intelligent about what am I using this
for and what do I hope to get out of it
and let me use the plant in a way that
will support that one of the things that
I find interesting is that you know we
have an ability to look at our
inhalation of the cannabis plant in very
specific analytical techniques now
because we've got we've got laboratories
and microscopes and things like that
whereas if you look back 10 or 20,000
years you know early humans who were
carrying this plant around with seeds
around with them from from encampment to
an encampment and selectively
hybridizing just based on on what seeds
they took with them they didn't know the
analytics like we do but they knew
something moving and important was going
on where where during the first set you
were talking about how the the
inhalation of cannabis makes us more
aware of our body and
expands our connectedness to the world
around us and for us you know we can we
can actually explain that what's going
on in the brain you know and and and
what parts are being stimulated and we
can look at it with an MRI but
anthropological egh looking back that
far it was much more filled with with
mystery and myth and storytelling and
you know engaging with you know gods and
angels you know what you know how
whatever whatever the religion of that
part of the world was right um do you
think that there is still a place for
that kind of experienced based
spirituality in a modern world where
everything is so data and analytics
heavy yeah I absolutely do I think that
one of the things that cultures have
been doing since the beginning of time
is altering consciousness and that's
what you're doing when you're ingesting
your ear and just in cannabis here
you're inviting an alternative
consciousness for perception what do I
not see in normal consciousness that I
can see when I ingest cannabis that can
inform how I live in my normal world
more in touch with my feeling part of my
reality than my thinking part of the
reality and what magic shows up not like
magic as you know something that's just
a game but the magic of the mystery it's
like wow I'm tuning in to something that
I've never turned into before so people
are doing ceremonial cannabis evenings
now where that is the focus what what
can I bring forward that I normally
don't talk about that I normally don't
see then I need to process to help me
feel more multi-dimensional we are
living in a multi-dimensional reality
and that's what the fear of it in the
government is this thing they don't want
us to feel what else might out should be
out be out there that feels more human
than not well may we all tune in and get
more attention to the natural world and
our own bodies thanks for you thanks so
much for being on this show Robert your
your perspective is very unique and I
appreciate it and I'm
that you were willing to join us thank
you it has been a pleasure to be here
and I enjoyed the conversation but it's
immensely you can connect with Robert
Lippmann through his website at the
breathable body calm and there there's a
link there but also you know make sure
you check out his YouTube page you can
just search Robert linen and it'll come
right up because the videos there give
you know some more exercises some more
just general explanation of breathing
and and if you tend to get your nasal
passages tend to be clogged up because
it because you toke so often there's a
really great exercise there for opening
those up nearly instantaneously you can
find more episodes of the shaping fire
podcast and subscribe to the show at
shaping fire calm and on Apple iTunes
stitcher and Google Play if you enjoyed
the show we'd really appreciate it if
you'd leave a positive review of the
podcast wherever you download your
review will help others find the show so
they can enjoy it too on the shaping
fire website you can also subscribe to
the weekly newsletter for insights into
the latest cannabis news and product
reviews on the shaping fire website you
will also find transcripts of today's
podcast as well for information on me
and where I'll be speaking you can check
out Shango lows calm your company want
to reach our national audience of
cannabis enthusiasts email hotspot at
shaping fire calm to find out how thanks
for listening to shaping fire i've been
your host Shango lows
[Music]