[Music]
one thing that the New Year means for
most of us is an opportunity to renew
and relaunch it's the time to make plans
real make smart decisions and reach for
things that may seem unattainable if
you've been wanting to try something new
in your cultivation recipe now might be
a great time to give it a try for those
of you following along on the shaping
fire Instagram account you know that I'm
experimenting with my first sea of green
style grow in a 4x4 tent in the shaping
fire offices now I got inspired watching
Caleb from CSI humble run sea of green
for many years and finally found the
time myself so far so great stop by the
shaping fire Instagram to check it out
for yourself while talking about
Instagram though I want to make sure
that you know how sketchy it has gotten
for cannabis businesses on Instagram if
you haven't already noticed Instagram is
intentionally pushing cannabis
businesses off the platform to support
their new Teen safety program up until
now cannabis accounts were primarily
flagged by folks in the community
reporting each other now though insta is
using keywords and image recognition to
automatically flag cannabis plants and
words like cannabis and cultivation and
clone causing creators to be
shadowbanned or deleted automatically
often with no way to appeal
Instagram very truly does not want us
there and yet Instagram is where we all
connect with each other as a Canabis
Community it doesn't seem right and it
is going to knock many cannabis
businesses and podcasts out of existence
there is talk of moving to Twitter or
blue sky or threads or Noster but none
of these have the participation of a
significant percentage of our cannabis
Community nothing beats Instagram in
that Guard we're all here when we all
leave Instagram the community will be
splintered as we go different places so
if you are interested in continuing to
follow your favorite cannabis content
creators or businesses be sure to
connect with them in a secondary way
that is more direct something like
signing up for their newsletter in fact
I encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter too the shaping fire IG could
be gone any day we send you new podcast
episodes as they come out delivered
right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week and
videos too don't rely on social media to
let you know when a new episode is
published sign up for the updates to
make sure you don't miss an episode and
since we moved the newsletter off our
own servers to generic servers our
successful delivery rate has spiked and
participation with the newsletter is at
an all-time high 44% of subscribers not
only read it but click on the links too
also we're giving away very cool prizes
to folks who are signed up to receive
the newsletter this month's sponsor is
TP Wizards plant magic Homestead and
five lucky winners will receive the
three crosses of his grape cream cake
seedline and be sure to check out their
Instagram accounts at plantor magore
Homestead uncore and of course tore
wizard to see what else they are up to
so go to the shaping fire.com and sign
up for the newsletter and be entered
into this month's and all future
newsletter prize
drawings today's episode begins year
nine of shaping fire podcasts we've been
doing this for you since
2016 thanks to the folks that sent the
Christmas tips that was appreciated if
you like what we do and want to put
something in the tip jar you can always
venmo us at
Shango you are listening to shaping fire
and I am your host Shango Los happy New
Year welcome to episode
119 today Eric Branstad returns to
shaping fire to talk about small green
houses for home cultivation Eric has
been a greenhouse and farming adviser
for over 30 years now he started out in
the northern Carol California Heritage
Market helping cultivators optimize
their green houses learn light
deprivation techniques and avoid many of
the common errors that impact cannabis
crops his reach widened with the
adoption of proposition 2115 Medical in
California which started Eric working
across the state both selling
commercial-sized green houses as as well
as offering top tier Consulting since
normalization began creeping across the
country Eric has become one of the most
respected names in cannabis and a
thought leader in cannabis green houses
he helps multi-state operators and
smaller family businesses across the
country and he works with indoor
cultivators too Eric has been on shaping
fire as a guest before on shaping Fire
episode 41 Eric was here to talk about
cannabis Greenhouse rescues when the
worst scenario happens and you got to
save your crop specialy of Erics and
again gosh all the way back 100 episodes
and8 years ago to shaping fire number 13
titled maximizing yield with light
deprivation techniques both great
episodes today we'll be discussing green
houses for home cultivation while our
insights today are applicable to most
green houses that are 20x 20 and smaller
we are especially focused on the green
or white Greenhouse kits that are sold
on Amazon and elsewhere that are used by
f all over the world and are an easy
Greenhouse solution if you've never seen
one of these green horiculture plastic
green houses or if you want one
specifically that I use uh there's a
direct link on the shaping fire.com page
for this episode easy peasy so during
the first set we will discuss the
advantages of using a greenhouse no
matter where you are in the country
recommended sizes for your needs
placement on the property anchoring
venting flooring and bracing of your
Greenhouse during the second set we will
look at dealing with heat and cold
issues of green houses and how to keep
your growing parameters dialed in as
well as pests from insects and rodents
up to deer and we finished the episode
looking to upgrade your small home
greenhouse with light dep adding lights
heating coils for the soil and how to
properly store the plastic over winter
all in all a jam-packed episode of
useful ideas for the home cultivator hey
Eric welcome back to shaping fire hey
Shango thanks for having me so glad to
have you back so um let's get right into
it you know the biggest question
probably at the top is is why bother
with green houses because we can talk a
lot about the details of green houses
but for many people they're like you
know I don't really want the money and
the expense I'm just fine growing
Outdoors it worked for me and it worked
for my py and like this is the way like
it goes and um you know when I used my
first Greenhouse I was really caught off
guard by how much better my plants
thrived so um you make this pitch to
people all the time about why they
should upgrade to a greenhouse so so why
don't you start us off with
that sure I mean you know most people
when they grow cannabis you know have
trouble especially in the fall you know
towards harvest season or harvest time
let's say you know the weather can start
to turn bad it starts to get colder it
starts to you know possibly even a rain
um and then you know throughout the
growing cycle depending on where you are
there can be a reason for green houses I
mean people in New York deal with rain
throughout the summer um you know we're
pretty lucky here in California through
a lot of the Cannabis growing where
Outdoors has been uh pretty pretty easy
for the most part except for you know
some of the years we've had some some
late or early rains that you know cause
problems but generally speaking um the
green houses provide a benefit of
protecting the plants it's a great way
to hide your plants if you don't want
the neighbors to see anything it also
provides a great great structure to be
able to pull a light dep cover over if
you want to do the light dep technique
as well so there's a bunch of reasons to
use a greenhouse for cannabis it can be
a little bit of a double-edged sword
using a greenhouse in the summertime but
as you noticed out on the islands where
you are in Washington it became a great
benefit rather than just going straight
Outdoors so um I think that you know
with cannabis being the Michael Jordan
or the super plant that it is compared
to all other plants um it just seems to
do really well in green houses I think
that's really well put it it really just
gives us options you know it it it gives
you an opportunity to um you know boost
your warmth if that's what you need to
cut down on your wind if that's what you
need to make it more discreet if that's
what you need it just it just makes
options and um and and really these
these kinds of green houses that we're
focusing on today you know you you you
you started in you know NorCal doing all
the all the gorilla and kind of like OG
hidden stuff and then grew into medical
and then now you're Consulting at least
all over the country if not all over the
world on these big you know
multi-million dollar shticks but but
what we're talking about today are these
these small $200 green houses which if
you get them on sale like this time of
year now like December for the following
year you can get things that'll be like
$350 in May for like 200 bucks and um
that that buys you a lot of options
comes the
summer for sure I mean my business and
previously when I was in you know
selling green houses I definitely was
shooting for the big stuff but we did
spend a lot of time and even when I
started out with the greenhouse company
um in 2006 and 7 uh we we were carrying
smaller green houses I mean granted they
were automated and expensive and way
more expensive than any would want to
spend even now um but we were really
hyperfocused on you know the home grower
and the medical grower and so we had a
10x10 and a 20 by 20 later on we created
a hoop house that was um 16 by 12 it so
it was still kind of big but at the same
time you know our our our thoughts were
always with the homeg grower um outside
of you know targeting the the commercial
Growers which was really you know what
the business had to do but um you know
the hom grower was really where where it
all starts and and um you know with the
medical side of things we had a lot of
hom Growers early in the day and then
with the new legalization in various
States you know hom growing is still
allowed in most cases and so it never
really went away but um you know I think
that it it's a great opportunity for
people to give it a try with you know
especially these more affordable options
that are out there now yeah absolutely
so so let's let's talk about um the
footprint so there are um you know you
can buy these green green houses U lots
of places um a lot of people buy them on
Amazon um but you can also buy them at
um you know different types of
agricultural stores if you're not not
into Amazon but I mean I have to mention
Amazon because so many people write to
me saying I just picked one up on Amazon
and right so I'm I'm guessing that if
90% of the people who are writing to me
asking questions about or buying them on
Amazon that that is is kind of the
default for most people um for better
for worse um uh I have bought maybe five
or six different brands on the website
um and and while um none of them are
particularly sponsoring shaping fire
right now um uh I just want to clue
folks in that I have liked the quick
tent brand qu UI c t NT for their new
upgraded stuff but but really I I have
not gotten a bad brand yet um so so you
know take a look and and and see which
ones on sale and which one looks good to
you but specifically let's talk about uh
Footprints Eric um the the the ones that
seem to be predominant are you know 15
by7 um uh 10x 10 20 by1 and there's a
lot of 25 by10 all of a sudden um um I'm
not sure why there's so many of the
different um sellers are using the same
footprint but it it wouldn't surprise me
if they were all buying their their
framework from the same company in China
and then they're all just you know
rebranding what they put on this
skeleton um what are your thoughts in
trying to you know figure out the size
that you want I it wouldn't surprise me
if most people just go for I'm going to
get the biggest um that I have got room
for in on my property right um but but
some people are like myself I needed to
make get one that I knew would be two
rows wide at least cuz I I I wanted to
be able to walk down the middle and and
have plants on either side when you were
selling these uh green houses not the
cheap ones I'm talking about what you
were selling was much nicer but it had a
similar footprint um what kind of um
guidance did you give people when they
were trying to determine what size they
wanted you know that's a great question
because everybody is a little different
than what they expect or what they want
and so with the green houses that I was
dealing with you know sometimes it came
down to price people had a budget and
this is all I could really spend so
we're going to okay we're going to get
what we can get out of this budget
basically um other times people just
felt like hey this is and and people
have a you know um a thought in their
minds I guess of what is safe to them
and what is not maybe or what is
reasonable let's say and what is maybe
out of reason to an extent and so you
know a lot of people would call with hey
this is the size that seems reasonable
to me and so a lot of times with the you
know they're not terribly bigger Hoops
than the ones you're talking about but
they are um bigger in width and height
and so the most common size Greenhouse
that we sold back then especially in the
early days was a 16x 48 or a 20x 48 and
I'm not 100% sure why but the majority
of customers that would call would
always stick with this 48t long
Greenhouse um and you know that wasn't
because that's the size of their
backyard that just seems to be the
reasonable size in everybody's Minds at
the time and so when you look at the
green houses that you're talking about
and the backyard setting or the homeg
grower setting it really comes down to
that like what fits in somebody's
backyard maybe without being too much of
an isore maybe it fits in the backyard
and it still leaves room for the animals
and the kids to play you know maybe it's
something that isn't going to look too
big to the neighbors and cause them to
call and complain or something like that
so I mean there's a a plenty of reasons
of you know why people pick these differ
Siz green houses and I think the one
that you picked or the company that
you're you know talking about has really
you know found um The Sweet Spot let's
say because a lot of the hobby green
houses that have been on the market and
currently on the market you know are
typically square or
rectangle um they're usually the clear
polycarbonate that um is you know
similar to Glass and it's transparent Y
and a lot of
them are kind of difficult to put
together some of them are fairly flimsy
in some regards and so it's really hard
to find the right hobby greenhouse and
that's why you haven't seen a lot of the
Hobbies be very popular um until this
one came along and so you know kind of
like you're saying there's been a a lot
of people liking and buying this
greenhouse off of Amazon or similar to
it and it's just because it seems to fit
that reasonable aspect of shipping
putting together longevity and then you
know the sizes they have seem to be
reasonable with where people want to
stick those in the backyard or at the
home grow yeah all all true and um four
years five years ago now there was a big
upgrade in the industry they used to be
all that like really cheap kind of like
white really bendy aluminum kind of
metal that like you get one bad storm
and they would mess up and then all of a
sudden at once all of the companies
tended to said upgraded and they all
moved to galvanized steel and um that
seems to be when they took off cuz
suddenly they were they were one step
closer to kind of like the adult green
houses that you're that you're more
familiar with right like suddenly
they're like oh if you get a little bit
if you get a little bit of weather
you're going to be okay and um and so
people started going with them um well I
I think that's really important to note
because a lot of the green houses and
even the greenhouse that I've put
together over the years that are you
know a little bit more you know a little
bit more commercial grade I guess you
could say I don't know but it doesn't
take much for a wind to pick up a
greenhouse and move it whether it's the
hobby ones or even the bigger uh more
commercial ones and so weather and and
you know wind and things can really put
a hammering on a greenhouse and so I
think with the amount of little you know
green houses like yours that took sale
in a windstorm and blew off the property
or maybe got damaged from some severe
rains you know was enough you know
complaints or notes to the company for
them to go oh you know here's what we
need to do and then they made that
change but I think
collectively um you know they had to
have enough people complain or have
problems with them for them to see that
change needed um but it doesn't take
much I mean honestly um you know I think
sometimes you can see the writing on the
wall and people just want to try out the
flimsy stuff first and see how far it
gets them let's talk about height some
because um most of these these um
consumer backyard green houses top out
at 6.6 feet and of course this does not
set one up for Monster California's
outdoor sized plants um and so we have
to you know be aware of that and um
probably um you know topping your plants
at least once and and getting you know
getting good at that but um it's
frustrating because with these these
hobby green houses um they have the um
they have
the what's the word like the curved roof
right and so you really only get the 6.6
Apex at the middle of the roof and so if
you put your walking space along the
middle you've got the head space but
then your plants are going to be topping
out at like six or 5 and 1/2 ft and so
so there's an argument you be made to
like put the plants in the middle and
walk yourself around the side but then
when you're in the middle it makes it
when they're in the middle it makes it
harder to tend to every side of the
plant because you've got them doubled up
in the middle um what kind of um you
know uh advice or thoughts might you
have about you know an abbreviated
height Greenhouse that cuts off at 66
versus to you know somebody who's got a
commercial greenhouse and they can go as
as tall as they
want well I mean I think that we need to
look at it as you know there could be
worse problems in the world than too big
of plants and not being able to get
around sometimes and so I would say that
maybe that could be a good thing even
though can be tedious and a little bit
annoying or whatever like I mean um but
to your point you know I always advocate
of trying to put plants in the middle or
to towards the center if we can you know
when you when you look at winter time
growing and I know we're kind of focused
more on the summertime but there is the
season extension and things like that
when you start to have your plants
closer to the walls of the greenhouse
they are closer to the cold basically
and so being away from the walls gives
you a chance to keep things warmer for
free basically but um at the end of the
day I think like what you're talking
about topping and training is really
important unfortunately a lot of States
you know and if I talk about California
in particular the hom Growers are only
allowed to grow six plants legally and
so of course you want those six plants
to be as big as possible but you know if
you really dig dig in or look back and
maybe there's nothing to look back at um
literature wise or podcast wise but when
I look back or think back I start to
think about some of the growers in
between you know really before the 215
days and into the 215 days there was
some Growers up in the Humble County um
a friend of mine Joey Burger the humbal
local one of the unique things what they
used to do is they used to start their
plants outside you know and this could
be done in a greenhouse too but they
would actually lay chicken wire on the
ground over these plants and I mean they
could grow a six PB plant and it would
never be taller than 3 feet just because
of the way that they trellised it down
with this chicken wire and did this
crazy ground technique and so there's
only a few people I've heard over the
years that are recognized that method or
seen it or heard about it or anything
like that um but it's amazing what you
can do with some of these plants I mean
some people have seen how there's
Growers and you know artists that'll do
bonsai to these plants and these crazy
root systems that come out of these nice
um features that they create with the
pots and and the bedding but you know
the cannabis plant can do incredible
things and so it's surprising of how
much trellising and bending and keeping
a plant spread out low to the ground um
that's possible POS so I would say that
you know on the on the easy side yeah
topping them um but secondly you know
how far can you spread your plants and
how much can you bend them and bring
them around and it does take a lot of I
wouldn't say a lot of but it takes some
extra work and and tending to to do some
of this stuff but it isn't out of the
question to be able to train your plants
to grow low and still stack on uh good
weight I know from when you've been on
shaping fire before and we've talked
about large scale green houses that you
put a lot of Blood Sweat and Tears into
studying the placement of big green
houses on the property and studying
microclimates and then um you know
lovingly encouraging the owners to put
the greenhouse the smart place instead
of necessarily the convenient place and
um you know when it comes to Backyard
green houses I would say the same is
true
and yet you have even more pressure like
oh but that's where the garage goes or
oh that's where the dog run is or oh
that's where the that's where every
summer we put up the pool or you know
whatever um there are lots of Demands on
you know somebody's backyard now
assuming that they have options instead
of just it's the only place in the yard
for it um can you give us some like um
you know thumbnail suggestions from
where we might want to place the
greenhouse on the
property sure I mean you know back in
the day one of the things that we'd look
to is that you know when whenever people
call for and and and this technolog is
changing over time I think there's apps
and more things now on our phones to to
sort this stuff out than ever but you
know originally when a solar person
would come out to give you an estimate
for solar on your house they would have
this device handheld device that would
basically tell them where the sun was
and the Shadows are for the 12 hours of
the day and so they would come out with
this handheld device stand in a few
spots and look and see where the
trajectory of the sun and the shade is
going to be and they would say ah this
is the sunniest spot on your property
this is where you want your solar panels
so we kind of started adopting that same
idea with you know where do I put my
Greenhouse we want to put it in the
sunniest spot possible and so we would
use you know some of the same techniques
um now you know like I said with the
apps and
and um other things that we might use as
far as instruments or tools we can still
do the same thing and maybe do it a
little bit more affordable or a little
easier uh but I would say that one of
the things that I like to look to is
that to make sure that the fall Sun or
the the late Summer Sun um is really
Intense or um really good so what I mean
by that is that you know I I I lived in
uh 5 Acres of pasture land you know for
20 years and so Sun really wasn't that
big of a problem but recently I moved 20
minutes up the road and I'm in the
forest and it's literally barely get it
gets any sun here and so it's not the
great greatest place for growing
cannabis but I did find a really sunny
spot and I thought I'd give it a whirl
this year and put out just three plants
I didn't even use a greenhouse because I
just wanted to test out this new spot
after we cleared some trees and so while
the spot was really sunny throughout the
summer and the plants grew fairly tall
as we started getting into the fall the
sun started changing um and basically I
got a lot of shade when I needed a lot
of sun for the ripening and the flow
production and so that's where it
suffered the most and I would say that
you know a lot of plants will veg and
grow pretty well even in a little bit of
shade or some shade in the afternoon
mixed shade let's say uh but when you
start to have the seasons change and
that's Sun becomes diminished during the
flowering time that's where you're going
to be the most bummed and so I wouldn't
I I would what I would recommend is
trying to make sure that that Sunny Spot
you pick is sunny all the way through
the finish and so if you happen to be in
the forest and you say oh this is a
Sunny Spot that might be true but is it
going to stay sunny the entire time and
if it's not I would find a place or cut
a tree or do something to make sure that
you get that late uh Summer Sun for the
flower development and the rening that
is so true especially if you live a
place that isn't as gifted with uh
cultivation weather as California right
like up here in Washington my uh my son
disappears um there in September and so
um um my first couple years here I was
positioned where the sun was in July
because I was all excited to bring the
plants Outdoors um but by um by you know
third week of September it it was
cutting across the sky differently and
we already have such a hard time
finishing plants where I live that you
really need to put that tent where where
you're going to get the most bang for
your buck in September and you know
other places October too but we can't we
can't grow in October here where I live
at all so right yeah so um all right so
um let's talk about now that we have
figured out where they're going to be in
our property let's talk about anchoring
them down um I think that a lot of
people just all like well it's a big
Greenhouse it's not going to fly away
and yes yes it's going to fly away if
you don't tie it down um I I I I don't
know what professionals use but all I've
done is I I I've picked up a really nice
um tent what do you call those tent
stakes and um I wrap a uh industrial
size zip uh zip tie around the bottom uh
metal bar and and then I create a loop
with it and then put the um I put the
steak through it and I do you know on my
20 foot by 10 I will I'll put like you
know six of those on each side holding
it really down and you know occasionally
during the summer I might I might lose a
zip tie but not um not all the time um
what do what what do adults use
[Laughter]
like well I think there's a hand handful
of things that people do to secure their
green houses and I think all of them
could be looked at as a good good or
correct way to do it but um you know
sometimes things resonate with one
person better than or one idea resonates
with somebody better than the other idea
and so I think the bigger fancy um
stronger tent Stakes like you're talking
about are a great option um the other
thing that I've used is concrete stakes
and you know concrete stakes are you
know basically heavy metal bars with a
pointy end on it and they also have
holes drilled into it and so for me was
a lot of the green houses that we did
some of them we did as you know as Dem
uh as booths for trade shows and lounges
and you know there was other people that
wanted to do a similar Greenhouse but
they knew they were going to move it so
they didn't want to augur the holes and
cement them in like you're supposed to
like the plan say and so when some of
the green houses maybe have a baseboard
at the bottom it could be a small 2x4 or
something like that around the base
perimeter of the greenhouse um even if
there's not one but the tent the
concrete stakes uh work really well
because you can get them in a 8 in 12 in
24 in 36 in concrete steak so you can
really drive them down pretty good and
if you have it right up next to the
greenhouse you can use those holes that
are pre-drilled into that concrete stake
close to the top once it's all the way
tapped in and run some wire through it
run a zip tie through it or or even take
a screw and screw it right into the
baseboard and it it stays pretty well
attached and so concrete stakes have
been popular rebar cut up into various
lengths and section has been popular
kind of doing the similar thing there's
other people that have taken rebar and
bent it in half so it makes make kind of
like a horseshoe or a a u-shape so
you're basically driving it into the
ground maybe straddling something of the
greenhouse maybe a bottom um sideboard
or Lin or something that maybe you can
attach to and and do that with um
another thing that people have done is
similar to what you maybe see when
people put up those you know party tents
or circus type tents for um get
togethers and things is where they uh
actually throw the strap over you know a
ratchet strap over the entire greenhouse
and attach it to something that's fixed
into the ground and in some cases
there's been places where we've put
things up that we're not allowed to
drive staks into the ground so we fill
up um a bucket with um cement so you'll
take a 5 Gall bucket dump a cement bag
into it and fill it with water and you
basically have this hardened cement
bucket for a lack of better words and
some people will even put a fancy hook
maybe inside that concrete so then it
dries you actually have something to
hook to that concrete inside the bucket
and so people will put the buckets
around the perimeter of the greenhouse
throw these straps over the the
greenhouse and then attach them to these
buckets and so it's not to be ratcheted
down so tight that it's actually pulling
your Greenhouse down but it avoids it
from being able to take off or lift off
listening to you uh uh kind of uh name
off all these different solutions I just
felt so proud of of Stoner Ingenuity you
know like like you take these plus all
the ones that we're not even going to
mention like people are always figuring
stuff and new in novel ways in our scene
oh for sure I think you know you could
take whatever we just explained and and
hybridize it or do it a little bit
differently with the same parts and then
you and I learn something totally it
does it it doesn't surprise me that
we've already mentioned Joey Berger as
as an Innovative cannabis person because
he's always he's always posting about oh
I'm trying this new thing you know and I
I really appreciate people who are you
know thought leaders like that right
yeah necessity is the mother of
invention and when you're you know when
you've smoked a couple it really can go
you can really go out there with it yeah
all right so let's talk about um uh the
skin when the plastic is is put on um
the the only and and biggest issue that
I have run into with um a season of
plastic is when there is rain um it is
often um it often creates uh like div
it's in the plastic where uh water will
collect now people who have got more
professional green houses will
immediately say oh it's not it's you
know it's not pulled tight enough you
have to you know you have to have like
channel locks on either side of the
greenhouse to to Really you know lock
that in but the this these these green
houses are are much too small for that I
forget what those things are called that
little the little wiggle wire what's
that y that's what it's called wiggle is
it called Wiggle wire all great um so
it's like the these green houses are
just too small for that and like you
know you could but you'd probably double
the price of the greenhouse by adding
wiggle wire minimum so so so really what
we're talking about is um ways to
support the roof differently and this
year was the first year that I tried
just simply to run rope back and forth
between the ribs that would create um
addition
support in between the ribs and it
worked out it worked out okay I
definitely took it all apart and I'm
going to try it again next year with
with a a um a thinner rope wrapped more
times but is is there anything at the
professional level that you recommend to
people to to help fill in those gaps
between the ribs so that the water
doesn't create like little
buckets yeah I mean that happens even on
big green houses or or you know
traditional green houses
or commercial gray whatever but I mean
it it does come down to sometimes the
way these things are manufactured and
how the plastic goes on and you know
nine times out of 10 not everything's
100% ideal but it's close enough and you
know I do suggest to make sure that when
people do put their Plastics on they try
to do it on a sunny day you know it's
good to pull out the plastic and maybe
lay it on top of the greenhouse or on
the ground right next to the greenhouse
and let it get hot and that way it a lot
of times as as most people know when
things are warm they're a little bit
more pliable or malleable and and when
things are cold they're a little bit
more stiff and harder to deal with and
and most if not all Greenhouse Plastics
are the same way and so it's good to lay
it out let it get warm and really try to
stretch it on as tight as possible so
that when it does cool down that
contraction you know is what creates
that tighter um fit so to to basically
hold things on a little bit better It's
Tricky I've seen people use you know the
the really sticky fancy velcro from Home
Depot to try to rig things up um you
know using LA or PVC in conjunction with
the ropes like you talked about to
create peins and things that go between
each rib to try to create the rigidity
you know
rigid um or create make the the
structure more rigid so it doesn't
always help the plastic but sometimes
when you're messing around with things
like you're talking about you know you
go in and you do something and maybe it
works pretty good and a lot of times we
have this aha moment going well if I was
to do this again I'd do it this way and
it sounds like that's kind of where you
are with your you know possibili that's
exactly where I am the the the first
year I did this I tried packing tape and
that was great but it broke over the
course of the year just from the weather
and then and then this year was rope um
but but I need I need to come up with a
different pattern so that it gets more
coverage yeah no and and you know in
some cases you know if you thumb through
some of the greenhouse cataloges you
know I mean there's the catalogs that
get sent to you in the mail there's the
online ones you know like Greenhouse
mega store for instance U there's some
others out there on the East Coast like
Griffin greenhouse and I would say that
you know sometimes when you're going
through these catalogs and these online
things you run into new things that you
know could be applicable to a homeg grow
greenhouse and so they do sell a lot of
do-it-yourself parts for creating um
backyard and maybe hom grow or
do-it-yourself green houses but at the
same time there are certain parts and
things that we run into that could be
useful in whatever Greenhouse you're
using or you know the one that you're
talking about in particular and so you
know sometimes there's stuff out there
that's been around for a long time we we
just haven't noticed it because we're
flipping through the pages so fast
looking for something else and so
surprisingly enough that I mean there's
even a place here in Grass Valley called
Peaceful Valley Farm Supply that ships a
lot of stuff and over the years they've
had Greenhouse Parts too so it's just a
matter of kind of looking around and and
you know really trying to engage in what
you're what you're doing for your
plastic and seeing if any of these other
things might fit or work or or help in
any ways but I would say that generally
speaking getting greenhouse plastic
tight so that it doesn't hold water is
pretty common for everybody in the hoop
house and and Greenhouse game because um
you know weather Mother Nature is pretty
powerful and she typically always wins
in one way or the other and so I would
say that it it it's kind of a
ongoing uh situation to be worked on
yeah I I agree uh it's it's hard a lot
of these uh a lot of these at the green
houses at this grade the plastic is just
held on with velcro hoops and so they
can slide all over the the galvanized
steel um so anything that that we can do
to to
um anchor them to the ground is going to
be a win so the last the last thing I
want to talk about is actually the
ground um on this topic before we go to
the first break and that is whether or
not to put flooring and you know I've
really been torn on this over the years
on one hand um I have uh liked leaving
my greenhouses just bare dirt um because
you know I'm a grower of the soil food
web mindedness and and the idea of
having the floor be natural um and there
so that there are uh you know voluntary
pest predators that are growing there
naturally and and um you know the water
has somewhere to soak down into it just
seems like it makes sense to me
however you know if we've got un uneven
ground where there are all these like
little divots that you can twist your
ankle in or if you live like where I
live where we've got a lot of uh
varmints you know you've suddenly got
them um growing um uh like little holes
underneath your pot so they can drink
the water during the drought of the
summer right um uh it's it really goes
both ways about whether just to leave
the ground um natural with grass or
whether or not it makes sense to put
down a couple pieces of plywood how do
you weigh in on
this yeah that's that's a good question
I mean for the hom grower I think that
you know it's it's really up to you know
what their perspective is on all this
stuff and you brought up a lot of good
points I mean there there's definitely
beneficials and there's definitely some
things that aren't beneficial that could
show up in some cases and so I would say
that if it's just plain dirt without
grass it's good to put something down
down because when you're irrigating or
if some rains come or whatever that that
dirt does get wet and it tracks up mud
and next thing you know you're starting
to get stuff everywhere and it becomes
quite messy I've even had people on you
know just plain dirt put down the ground
cover that's been recommended over the
years and when that stuff gets wet from
irrigating or leaving a hose on or just
dribbling around when you're moving from
place to place with a hose the mud will
start to seep through the ground cover
even so it's I think the idea of having
the grass is pretty cool um you know
people can be fearful of the pest
because the grass can be a nice little
habitat for things that you maybe don't
want um when it comes to the rodents the
rodents are definitely a little bit of a
problem and so putting down some wire
mesh underneath maybe could help keep
the rodents from coming up and getting
through um you know the plywood isn't a
bad idea some people are a little bit
iffy plywood or wood in general because
there's the chance you know in the
regulated market what we learned is that
you know wood and cardboard and a lot of
these things can have this aspergillis
and maybe even cause some post Harvest
molds but a lot of that is a whole
another podcast to deal with but um at
the same time um wood can get moldy just
by nature in general and so that can be
a little bit of a thing for people if
you use pressure treated wood it has
chemicals in it and some cases some of
those chemicals could um bioaccumulate
in your cannabis and so it's really um
kind of tricky I know that you know
another popular solution people like to
go find those plastic pallets I mean I
don't know if they're plastic or
polycarbonate or what they're really
made of but the pallets that um are not
made of wood they can be fairly
expensive sometimes you can find people
tossing those and use those um um you
know at the end of the day I think that
um anything re reasonable would work and
so a pallet could be used but that's
wood also a regular wooden pallet but
there's people that will paint those
with a low vo paint maybe even um a hemp
deck stain for that matter um there's
also you know just putting some gravel
down isn't a bad idea over the dirt in
some cases so I mean a little bit of
gravel goes long ways um you know if you
do use the ground cover I would you know
recommend putting something underneath
it maybe even some straw before you cap
it with the ground cover just so you
don't have the mud that comes through um
but you know when using the containers
that you're using some of the containers
can take up a lot of space as well and
so those cover the ground when people
are doing these beds or rais beds a lot
of times they will even use bark around
the beds as a mulch layer and and you
know bark is pretty pretty safe in most
regards for the fact that um the weeds
don't like to grow through it as easy it
doesn't get muddy and some of the bark
doesn't seem to have the same moldy
effects um or negative effects that you
know wood does like plywood or things a
lot of times the mulch from wood chips
can have a lot of beneficial qualities
to it with um you know the fun fungi
growing into it and having that
mycelial mat growing and it keeps the
weeds from growing through and and uh it
makes for a nice uh cooler atmosphere it
doesn't get too hot like some of the
other things do I would just be on the
cautious side and knowing that you know
maybe if someone was to use certain
Ground Covers like black you know black
can get really hot in the summertime and
it can heat up the greenhouse more than
you want it to and maybe have adverse
reactions to the environment in the
greenhouse just because it stores and
collects so much energy you know it
could be a benefit to some people though
that are in places maybe like the
islands or areas where it stays fairly
cooler and they're trying to get some of
that free heat into the greenhouse and
warm some things up um on the other side
of that would be using you know
something that's a lighter color a white
ground cover it's kind of the other side
of that is why over the years we've
recommended people use a tan grow bag
versus a black grow bag um and that's
because they just get way more hot than
a you know black gets way more hot than
a tan grow bag but again that can be a
benefit in some areas I just went to a
farm recently that
um does put down the black this time of
the year because it is colder and
they're trying to get as much free
energy as they can and so they do switch
the colors up for their Fall Run um but
you know and and the other part of that
is that you know if you're going to be
using your Greenhouse in the winter time
or the summertime so you really kind of
want to be strategic if it's only the
summertime then you might be able to get
away with you know just a lot less or a
thinner layer of something and uh and if
you're going through the winter then I
would recommend probably going into some
type of a gravel base to start with you
might cap the gravel with the ground
cover you know a pallet or wood or
something else but the gravel is really
helpful in the winter time to keep from
sinking into the
mud wow uh all right so first of all I
love having you on the show Eric because
you have such a depth of experience as
as you gave that elaborate answer I was
going through every one of the
situations and and it brought to mind
two things number one how you always
teach that there's no right way to do it
there's the best way to do it for where
you are in the country what your weather
is like what your growing goals and what
your budget is right and and so you gave
us a bunch of options depending on what
our goals are and I dig that and also
listening hearing you go through the
list I can almost see you go like oh man
that guy did this and we had to fix it
and this guy did this and we had to fix
it and like you're really kind of going
through a greatest hits of problems and
solutions that you've had to deal with
with different
clients it it yeah I mean unfortunately
maybe fortunately for me unfortunately
for some of the Growers that I've showed
up you know a lot of the work that I've
done is to help people in the kind of a
rescue situation or showing up to work
on one thing and I see another problem
going on and and and it it just you know
it's been a lot of years of being able
to see what works and what doesn't work
and
it's not to say like you're saying you
know there's not one thing that is
better than the other it just every Farm
is different there's not one Canabis
farm that is exactly the same and that's
even here in California I mean every
Greenhouse I go to has a different way
of setting it up or doing it or heating
it or the flooring for it you know so I
mean and it's the same way across the
country um and you know the bigger the
fancier the greenhouse the less similar
it is to any other greenhouse and then
when you get to the very basic simple
you know home jobs you get to actually
see a lot of cool stuff but in cannabis
and in growing in general whether you're
doing vegetables or cannabis but it
seems like with cannabis especially
there's always you know two steps
forward and one step back um and that's
not necessarily a bad thing but it's
really you know not something that is a
perfect situation all the time yeah
especially when you're burning money so
yeah right so um all right cool well
we're going to go ahead and take take a
short break and be right back you are
listening to shaping fire and my guest
today is OG Greenhouse consultant Eric
Branstad now without these advertisers
shaping fire would not happen so please
support them and let them know that you
heard them on shaping
fire this message is for folks who grow
cannabis I'm talking to Hom Growers
patients and Commercial Growers too I'm
probably talking to you when you plan
out your next growing cycle be sure to
check out Humbolt CSI seeds at Hult
csi.com Caleb inspecta and his family
have lived in Humbolt county for over a
100 years for the last 40 years three
generations of his family have
cultivated extraordinary sensia cannabis
in Humble mesino and Trinity counties
because of his lineage and the
hard-earned experience that comes from
growing up smoking and sifting large
populations of cannabis plants in
Northern California the seeds you'll cop
from CSI will be winning genetics based
on longtime Heavy Hitters and updated
and rifted to bring out new and exotic
traits and better yields go ahead and
ask around Caleb also known as inspecta
and pirates of the Emerald Triangle is a
breeders breeder he reaches way back and
works with significant strains
recreating them in new and interesting
ways that you'll love as a toker and a
grower as well as offering you some
surprises that will Delight serious seed
Traders and cultivators humble CSI goes
a further step and selfs all these chem
of ours so you know all the seeds will
be female these are not experimental
feminized seeds humbold CSI releases
some of the best female seeds available
anywhere and it will show in your garden
folks grew quite a bit of CSI humble
Genex last year here on Vashon Island
and everyone was pleased the patients
had beautiful female plans and didn't
have to call half of their Garden as
males the folks growing for the fun of
getting high grew colorful flowers with
exceptional bag appeal and great High
and breeders had seven out of seven
females in a pack which gave them a lot
of phenotypic choices take a moment
right now and visit humbled csi.com
you'll find an up-to-date menu of both
feminized and regular lines along with
photos and descriptions that's humble
csi.com
revenue is tight for cannabis businesses
right now there is no question about it
and when Revenue tightens businesses
need to spend Smarter on Advertising
instead of throwing obscene money at
Hanging your company's logo from the
rafters at your next convention perhaps
consider placing commercials on shaping
fire and if you are a very small
business there is simply no better bang
for your buck than commercials on
shaping fire especially if your products
are for regeneratively minded
cultivators advertising on this show
allows us time to talk about your
product service or brand in a way that
really lets people know what sets your
company apart apart from the others bold
people who own companies know that
getting into relationship with their
customers is essential that is what we
offer we will explain your service or
product what sets it apart as desirable
and help our audience get in contact
with you it's pretty simple really
advertising does not have to be all
whizbang smok and mirrors nowadays I
find that people prefer just to be
spoken to calmly accurately and with
good intentions if you want to make your
own commercial spot you can do that too
with a commercial on shaping fire you'll
reach your customers in the privacy of
their headphones right now and will
continue to reach new listeners as they
explore the shaping fire back catalog of
episodes again and again for years a
spot on shaping fire costs less than a
postcard per person and the shaping fire
audience is full of smart cannabis
enthusiasts cultivators and
entrepreneurs who are always curious to
learn and right now in the New Year We
are booking the few open SP we have for
the rest of
2024 I'd love for you to be one of our
new
advertisers do yourself a solid and
contact us today for rates on podcast
and Instagram advertising email hotspot
shaping fire.com to find out
more one of the challenges with buying
Autoflower seeds is that often you'll
have as many different fenos as you will
have seeds in a pack that can be fun
sure but so many varieties in one pack
is a sign of an an immature seed line
that hasn't been worked enough I prefer
my autof flowers to be worked enough
that each pheno in the pack really
captures the aspects that the breeder
was
intending this is why I recommend gnome
automatics to my friends and listeners
who grow automatic flowering cannabis
seeds gnome automatic seeds are not just
crossed and released they are
painstakingly sifted again and again
tested in a wide range of conditions and
taken to a level of maturity that each
plant will be recognizable by
traits traits that were hard-earned so
that you can have your best grow cycle
ever over the last 10 years gnome
automatics founder Dan Jimmy has become
a trusted breeder and he continues to
pour His passion of breeding cannabis
into every variety he releases for you
to grow check out the gnome automatics
Instagram
_ automatics to see the impressive
plants folks are growing you can score
gnome automatic seeds in feminized or
regular at your favorite seed provider
listed in the vendor section of their
website commercial cannabis Farms across
the country love growing gnome
automatics because of their consistency
from seed to seed short grow times THC
percentages and colorful bag appeal
Farms interested in bulk seeds of more
than a thousand should reach out through
gnome automatics.com
while on the website be sure to check
out the gnome automatic shirts and other
merch section too if you want reliable
seeds handbuilt from effort expert
selection and experience choose gnome
automatics welcome back you are
listening to shaping fire I am your host
Shango Los and my guest today is
greenhouse consultant Eric Branstad so
during the first set we we figured out
where our Greenhouse is going to be on
the property and we got it all set up
let's start talking about how to deal
with some of the common challenges that
are involved with having a greenhouse
and let's start with heat um uh you talk
uh regularly about the difficulties of
abating heat in our greenhouse and um
this is something that we attract right
because we want the warmth and we want
the heat uh because the plants want it
but we also don't want to cook the
plants or make them too thirsty or dry
out our pots and so we're trying to get
um you know we're just trying to hit the
this sweet spot so um I'm assuming that
our number one um helper Ally for G for
keeping our heat low is going to be fans
but um but I know that you have got a
bunch of strategies so so so why don't I
just kind of hand you the mic and say
what are the things that we should be
thinking about um for abating the heat
when we're setting up our small you know
20 by 10 foot
Greenhouse sure I mean you know
primarily the greenhouse itself
hopefully has some ventilation and I
know the one that you're talking about
actually does with the big door in the
front and then down the side it has all
these windows that roll up or
open and so similarly to other greenh
houses or well let's back up here a lot
of the other hobby green houses also did
not have or not equipped with enough
ventilation so a lot of times they have
a just a little Louver that opens by
hand and
maybe there's one on the roof or
whatever and so historically speaking
most of the hobby green houses that have
been on the market turn into little
storage sheds in the summertime and then
they don't get used in the winter
because people are happy with storing
stuff in them and it's because they get
incredibly hot and the other thing
people forget is that you know green
houses were invented for the winter or
when it's really shitty out not when
it's you know a perfect hot sunny day
but when cannabis came along we all you
know grow the best time to grow is when
it's hot summer and the sun's out and so
boom we put these green houses out there
that are not really for that time of the
year and we have all these problems or
heat build up and so you know like I
said the vents are really crucial um you
know looking at these Greenhouse covers
is also um an important factor and so
the clear the cover or the the
polycarbonate the more exposure to the
plants that we have and so one of the
things that people talk about is you
know the word heat but we're not just
talking about the air temp we're talking
about the heat that is associated to the
plant and so there's two different um
things that I look at in the greenhouse
and so one might be the air temp
obviously but the other is going to be
the plant temperature itself and and you
know we look at that by simply even
using a handheld laser thermometer where
you point and the little laser comes out
and it you point it to where you want
and it tells the temperature of these
surfaces and so it's really handy to
take one of those devices and aim it at
the flower of your plant or even a leaf
and you can actually see that the plant
temp is typically different than the air
temperature and so um monitoring that
really helps a lot more than just
looking at the air temp because in some
cases if you have enough ventilation and
maybe a good greenhouse cover um that
isn't totally clear like glass you might
see that there could be reduction in
leaf surface or plant temp compared to
the air temp and if that's the case
you're on the right track or things will
probably be okay but if it's the
opposite where the greenhouse is warm
inside and the plant temp is actually
warmer than the than the air temp you're
bound to run into problems with powdery
milw mold you know Bettis type mold and
things like that it's just it's it's not
going to end well um so what we try to
look at is that you know like you
brought up fan hands are definitely a
popular thing to move some air around
but if it's still sealed up and there's
not enough fresh air coming in um it's
it the fans are just going to move that
air around and so the one thing that I
always like to tell people and and the
phrase that I like to you know live by a
little bit is that if you trap air it
will heat up and so the key for a
greenhouse in the summertime especially
a homeg grower and even you know maybe a
commercial grower that has not such a
fancy setup you know kind of a basic
coup house is that uh we want to not
trap that air so that it heats up and
how do we do that is we try to take away
this greenhouse effect and so it's okay
to have the greenhouse but it's not
always okay to have the greenhouse
effect where it's getting warmer and
warmer inside all the time um we can
break that by opening up the greenhouse
and avoiding trapping all that air and
so you know on a greenhouse like the one
you've showed pictures of you know in a
place that maybe gets really hot I would
say that the benefit would be to put
doors at both ends of that type of a
greenhouse and that way it really slows
down the ability for that a to be
trapped and so when we have these
openings let's say we just have one door
the windows are open you still might
have a little bit of solar gain it might
not have the same amount of solar gain
if everything was sealed up uh but you
know it still has a little bit of solar
gain it's a little bit warmer inside
than it is outside but if we put that
other door at the other end you know we
might might have now alleviated the
ability for it to act like a total
greenhouse and we're going to actually
see the same temperatures inside the
greenhouse as we do
outside and so some people might say
well it's 100 outside that's okay if
it's 100 inside the greenhouse we know
that we've avoided the solar gain we're
not going to get it cooler by any means
but the goal is to not let it get more
hot inside than it is outside and so if
we've um if we've gotten to that point
then we start monitoring the leaf
surface or the flower temperature of the
plant with our little laser thermometer
and what we're going to start to notice
is that you know maybe those
temperatures are similar to each other
or in fact maybe a little bit lower and
so we're definitely on the right track
and this is where some circulation fans
might actually help a little bit because
now once we've avoided the solar gain we
move a little air across the plants and
it might be in a racetrack pattern it
might just be one fan at one end blowing
across this small Greenhouse so that it
creates a slight Breeze or mimics a
slight breeze and what ends up happening
is the plants actually become a little
bit cooler than what they originally
were and so when I have leaves kind of
dancing in the circulation of the of the
fans we can see a 3 to 5 degree
temperature difference than we would if
the plants weren't experiencing any air
movement and so you know plants and
people are similar in the sense that
plants have all this water moving
through their system just like we have
blood and our blood's like I don't know
70 or 90% water anyway and so we have
this circulation going on right between
ourselves and plants with this water
moving through everything and so you
know on a hot day if you go and stand in
front of a fan it'll have a cooling
effect on our body because our sweat you
know our perspiration basically is
starting to get cooled off and
eventually we might even stop perspiring
even though we're still out in you know
the hot weather this fan is created a
littleit bit of relief for us and and so
plants are the same way and so a plant
doesn't perspire like a person does it
transpires right and so as the plant is
transpiring and we start to blow some
air across it it will eventually start
to cool down a little bit and that
transpiration process doesn't go away
but it uh slows down quite a bit and
anybody that's had a plant that is
transpiring it's hard to see because
it's not like sweat on our forehead you
can't just see it dripping down but what
we see is we see condensation forming on
the roof of the greenhouse and trying to
drip back down onto our plants and so
condensation typically is a result of
plant transpiration and so if we try to
work on getting our plant temps in check
we'll be able to avoid that condensation
that everybody is trying to avoid or get
rid of and and not deal with and that
you know kind of coincides with the
light depth technique when you put your
plants in a light dep You Know cover
them in this bubble with the blackout
cover um there's no air coming in or out
a lot of times especially traditional
ways of growing and if your plant temps
or or your plant temps are up when you
go to seal it up you're instantly going
to see this condensation form and so
people that are able to keep their plant
temps down compared to the air temp and
that's why I'm saying there's not a
perfect number that we're looking for
we're just looking for plant temp to be
lower than the air temp you typically
don't see that condensation form
throughout the day and you don't see it
show up as much when you pull your light
depth cover and so another thing that
helps with that is the greenhouse cover
itself and you know knowing that you
have that green cover on your
Greenhouse it does provide a little bit
of diffusion it has the reinforcing
strings that go through there that makes
that cover you know more durable than it
would be if it was just a plain piece of
plastic um does provide some diffusion
and so basically the diffusion is also
maybe another way of looking at shading
you know or or um another aspect of
diffusion is scattering infrared and so
infrared is what brings the Heat and so
we're basically trying to disrupt the
infrared but we're still trying to get
as much light as possible um and to the
plant and so a lot of times with the
clear like glass covers you don't have
that protection they actually can
magnify the light at times and it'll
make the plant temp even warmer than it
should be or warmer than you want it to
be be just because that's how these
Plastics work and so um originally when
I first started selling green houses
that's what we originally thought we
want the clearest cover possible like
glass because outdoor plants are in the
full sun you know when we're growing
with lights indoors back in the day
before LEDs and all this people wanted
as many lights as possible and they
wanted them turned up as high as
possible and so we automatically thought
the same thing for going into our
Greenhouse but what we learned is the
sun is intense um you know it's the most
intense light bulb we have around and so
um a lot of times the overexposure to
plants can be too much throughout the
growing cycle and so having the right
Greenhouse cover and I believe the green
one that you you know in that picture um
is a great option for doing that and
then I know that the upgraded version is
a white and I've you know seen a white
um I forget the product name of it but
it's a white you can't see through it
and almost didn't think it was a
greenhouse cover it's a sunm they have a
bunch of different versions and this
white one actually does let light
through and it worked incredibly well in
Arizona so I'm assuming that the white
upgraded version that they have offering
for your Greenhouse uh would be suitable
in some of these areas like Arizona New
Mexico and even California where it can
be extremely hot sometimes where that
white will actually
diffuse um and calm down that infrared
or that heat that's being brought onto
the plants but still provide enough
light for a great growing cycle so in
some cases somebody might just use the
openness of the greenhouse for
ventilation to take away the greenhouse
effect on top of that they might use the
greenhouse cover to make sure that that
you know helps or works even better and
then the other thing would be adding
that circulation fan now somebody might
want to do all of these things into one
aspect of a greenhouse to have the most
you know support or protection and then
in some areas of the country one of
those things might do the
job um as far as the one one more
question about the fans before we go on
to cold so it's from what you just said
it sounds like a uh positive strategy
would be a for example a box fan set up
as an intake at one end of the uh
Greenhouse and I've got I've got mine
hung just simply with zel velcro not
velcro zip tie um to the rib and then at
the other end you have um a an an
exhalation end and so it creates this
the comes one in in one end and it's
being pulled out the exhaust end at the
other side and then maybe um for the
leaf temperature maybe a couple
oscillating fans in the middle so I've
got an intake on one end an exhaust on
the other end and then a couple of
exhaust fans in the middle just kind of
like moving the air around on the inside
is is that kind of what you were
describing yeah I I yes yes and no and
the reason that I say the no part of it
is is because here's a couple things and
I'm not necessarily directing this
towards your setup but this is kind of a
generalized um um aspect or or outlook
on this topic is that people can put too
many fans and what ends up happening
let's just say in the idea of fans at
both ends like sometimes people will
have fans you know at both ends pointing
inwards and we have only air coming in
and no air coming out so it's almost
like this positive pressure idea and
what ends up happening is the air comes
in at a high volume but it has nowhere
to go and so inevitably it heats up and
it becomes hot inside and so like what
you're talking about with a more
negative pressure idea you have a fan
bringing the air in and maybe there's a
fan at the other end helping it shuttle
its way out one of the things that can
happen though is that some fans and and
and this could be even using the same
exact fans not all Motors and
manufacturers are perfect and so there
can be flaws in some of these ideas or
setups and so what I mean by that is
that you could have more air coming in
than you have coming out and so in some
cases what I've seen in even commercial
the big fancy green houses is that they
have so much air coming in that it
actually heats up before it's able to
travel out and in and in some cases what
I've seen is there's too many
circulation fans on the inside so what
that what that does is it draws more air
into the greenhouse than it would just
using the exhaust fan so the exhaust
fans are designed to bring in this air
and shoot it out the other side but if
you have circulation fans inside that
are bringing in more air it's almost
like if you were trying to you know put
a hose in your mouth and drink all the
water you know you you you can't it's
you you end up having water blowing out
your mouth and your cheeks are full and
it doesn't work and so the same kind of
I don't know if that makes sense but the
same kind of thing happens with the fans
is that you're the circulation and maybe
the exhaust draw in more than the exit
exit fan can handle and so you're
basically having air that's sitting
around in the greenhouse waiting for its
chance to escape and in the time it's
heated up and so we want to make sure
and in some cases maybe that's the idea
for some Farms is just to have that
exhaust fan at one end that's blowing
the air out but what it's doing is it's
it's uh capturing Air at the other end
and naturally bringing it through the
canopy and out the other side and so I
would just say that you know more air
movement isn't always better just
because we're in these structures and
there has to be a way you know an even
in and an even out for all that air and
if we kind of go in between that with
too many maybe circulation fans or other
things in some of these setups we could
cause the opposite reaction and so it's
always just good to be mindful and one
thing that I always say to people is
that it's easier to add more fans if you
think that you need more if you buy a
bunch of fans and all of a sudden you're
like well maybe I didn't need this fan
or or this is too many fans I listen to
the podcast and now I realize I've got
too many fans it's really easier to go
to the store and buy another fan and add
one than it is to sit around with a
bunch of fans and go okay now they're
going on Facebook Marketplace or the
next garage sale or or whatever and so
um you know starting out with a little
bit and adding more is the best way to
go right on so let's talk about about
too much cool too much cold not enough
heat now for most of us this isn't
something that we're going to experience
during our the main part of our growing
season it's probably something that is
happening towards the end uh certainly
there are people who are going to have
cold nights that they need to insulate
from uh in in the country but but for
most people it seems to be the end of
flowering when they're trying to squeeze
out another week or two but the E the
nights are have dropped below or near 50
and so they're just trying to keep their
their plants awake and the soil awake
um at the same time we don't want to
close up the greenhouse totally because
this is also mold time of year and we
don't want them to to the plants that
are molding to get other plants also
molding so um what suggestions do you
make for um preserving that air exchange
so that you can keep the fresh air
coming in um without
um making the plants too cold there at
the end of the
season yeah that that's definitely a
tricky or a slippery slope in some cases
depending on where you are it's
different for everybody um one of the
things that I would also look at you
know going into those times years is is
how I'm irrigating my water schedule you
know I might actually start to cut back
on the water a little bit as I know it's
starting to cool down cuz the plants
aren't going to use as much water as
they start to cool down if they're
starting to finish it's not a bad idea
you know even though maybe there's the
idea of flushing um that doesn't go away
but it uses less water less amounts of
water in order to do that
um you
know bringing in cold air isn't the
worst thing in the world but it takes a
little bit of work in these
do-it-yourself greenh houses because you
know we try to put things on a timer or
something like that but a lot of times
you know we're we're the sensor you know
us as humans are the main sensor and we
go hey it feels warm oh hey it feels
cold we should do this and so again it I
think it's really important to have that
infrared thermometer so you can point
and shoot and see what your plant temps
are especially your buds and so I would
say that you know as you're getting
closer to the finishing of the plants
knowing what those flower temperatures
are and making sure they don't get too
hot in the daytime um and then that
temperature swing in the night gets too
crazy where they get terribly cold and
so you know what ends up happening
sometimes is it's almost like a air
conditioning condenser you know it
starts to get that you know um on a hot
day that pipe starts to get Frost built
up on it you know plants are kind of a
condenser in the same regard they don't
necessarily get Frost and freeze around
them or whatever but they get hot and
cold and when they get hot and cold they
expire moisture um or not in some cases
and so being being able to monitor um
where the shift or where that change is
and kind of knowing cuz here's the thing
you don't necessarily have to carry this
thing around all the time and monitor
things it's not a bad idea it's not hard
to do but eventually you start to get a
little bit of a a Groove going you know
you kind of get that Jedi mindset with
the plants and going okay I know what's
going to happen on a day like today so I
need to be prepared and maybe close the
greenhouse up a little earlier than I
normally would and that goes for the
opening of the greenhouse maybe I need
to actually open the greenhouse a little
bit more um on these days and so really
understanding and looking ahead at the
weather patterns and then realizing what
the cause and effect is with some of
that weather on those plants in that
greenhouse and really you know the temp
and humidity you know um sensors are
great you know even the basic pool ones
that you know you hang outside and you
don't have to hook it up to any
electricity at all are really good for
telling us the temp and the humidity of
things and then we look at the plant
temp with the laser and we go oh aha
this is where I'm at so you know if
things get warmer or colder this could
be what happens and so in some cases it
might be just turning off the fan or it
might be just turning on the fan or it
might be closing the greenhouse like I
said earlier opening it up but I would
say that it's best to always do one
little thing at a time rather than
several things because it's really easy
for us to get caught up in how we feel
also and how we feel isn't how the
plants feel and so you know when we're
walking around in socks and shoes and
hats and gloves and pants and all these
things what we're feeling isn't really
how the plants feel there's not an
Apples to Apples situation going on and
so I always kind of laugh when people go
into a growroom or a greenhouse and go
oh it's really hot in here oh it's
really this or that and that's true it
is but are the plants experiencing that
same you know feeling or reaction action
that you're getting out of the room um a
lot of times it's not and so that's why
I say like monitor what the plants is
really doing soil temp is really
important the substrate Temp and knowing
what that is and being able to make sure
that you're not using freezing cold
water towards the end of that cycle and
and shocking The Roots even more for the
development of things it might just be
that we need to heat up the water when
we irrigate at that time of the year and
maybe Nothing Else Matters uh but again
you have to monitor all that stuff so
that you can really process everything
to help make that decision of what
direction you're going to go again just
because we read that some guy does it on
the internet does not mean that it makes
it appropriate for where we live and our
goals and and and how our gear is set up
so always always good to interpret these
things for
ourselves Instagram has not helped the
commercial farmer one bit I feel like
all I've seen is people go I saw this
online and I'm like well that wasn't in
your state your town and your climate or
any of these things and so you know
Instagram or social media is a great
place to see you know a lot of times
people are only showing the good stuff
you know for the most part but at the
same time there's more to it than the
picture that we're seeing there's
usually more to it than even some of the
statements that we read about some of
these techniques and while they're
important to learn and and to know about
people are really quick to apply or jump
you know knee-jerk reaction to hey this
is what I want to do or hey this is
where we want to go this direction or
whatever and in the commercial setting
at scale it's taken people down the
wrong road and so luckily with the homeg
Growers I think that there's a little
bit more of a you know a little bit more
forgiveness here but still it's it's
money out of our pocket when we're
trying to grow and do these things
whether we're at scale or we're at home
and so um you know like I said The more
things that we can kind of Monitor and
keep an eye on the better we have
chances of making the right pivot at the
right time uh but again you know I would
take what you learn on social media
sometimes especially when it's just a
picture and a quick statement with a
grain of salt because there's way more
to those stories than um what's being
told totally all right so the last area
I want to Ping on here before we wrap up
set two is um is insect pests because
we're you know once you have a
greenhouse you kind of have you're kind
of a host for a war right we we've got
all of the naturally occurring
beneficial insects that are just in
nature and if we've got a grassy floor
certainly they are in um the greenhouse
and we've got a bunch of plants so they
are attracting uh beneficial um
Predators as well and then if we are um
you know choosing to also do order
benefit IAL insects online from somebody
like you know natural enemies or
something we're adding those to it and
so now we've got um whatever pest
pressure that we have in the natural
environment plus all the good guys in
the natural environment and anything
that we've added and now they're all
within um you know these walls and it's
like a cage match so um what has your
experience been as far as um pest
pressure being worse in a
greenhouse and also Pest
Solutions being potentially easier in a
greenhouse I mean how how does this play
out differently in a greenhouse and what
are your
recommendations well it's it's funny
like you brought up a couple funny
points of the yeah I mean it's it can be
an ongoing battle and it's definitely
something to be noteworthy of and so I
would say that you know one of the best
environments for green for a pest is in
a greenhouse I mean pest will really
take off in a greenhouse just because
it's the warmer spot than anywhere else
on the property a lot of times and so
it's another reason that well let me say
this too is that a lot of people come
from the idea of controlled environment
agriculture or controlled environment
period they just say that word all the
time oh a greenhouse is a little more
controlled environment and we hear that
term a lot and so to be honest I mean
even some of the most sophisticated
greenh houses out there state-of-the-art
are really hard to control um on one
hand it's just because some of the Bell
there's too many bells and whistles and
some in some cases there's not enough
Talent or people that know how to dial
all this stuff in I mean cannabis has
taken green houses further than any you
know a greenh hous is ever gone and so
are there people out there that know how
to dial these things in and make them
work right right there's far and few
between it's really difficult out there
and so it's really better if people you
know look at things at a more practical
aspect but that's a different story um
with with my way of looking at things I
want to create support and so instead of
controlled environment I want to have a
supportive environment and so a lot of
the stuff that we talked about is
already in that alignment of supporting
things you know naturally how can we um
help the plants and benefit um growing
them easier and and without all these
problems and and without all these bells
and whistles so that's why I always say
you know use the word support as much as
possible and so when it comes to um the
green houses and this pest issue that
comes up it definitely really can be an
issue because I've been to a lot of
green houses that do get really hot and
have you know adverse effects and the
pests really proliferate and do well in
some of these green houses and
especially these hot zones and so the
first order of business would be you
know knowing where your plants come from
so I mean if you're starting them from
seed at your own house that's great you
have a lot more control over it than
than um if you were maybe bringing in
clones from somewhere else if you are
bringing in clones from somewhere else
you really need to make sure that
they're clean and how do you do that
well you can take the jeweler's Loop the
microscopes and really look the plants
over from the leaves and the underside
and things like that to determine if
there's anything on them or wrong with
them um and then the other thing would
be to you know work on a a program of
keeping them clean maybe if you did buy
clones and they're not clean then that
program of of dipping them before you
plant them or making sure that you're
using some type of Pest Management right
off the bat so that you know you don't
wait until the they they uh become you
know more infested so get trying to nip
it in the butt is soon as possible is
really the key and that goes for the mom
plants if you're making your own cuting
off your own moms you want to make sure
that your moms are as clean as possible
so that you start out as clean as
possible and then as you go into the
greenhouse yeah like you said if you
have a grass floor or wearing these
green houses with these open doors and
sidewalls and things like that sure bugs
can fly come flying in I hear that a lot
of times when I've talked over the years
about opening the door or rolling up a
sidewall in a greenhouse it's like well
the bugs can come in and and that's
definitely true they can I mean from
what we've learned and seen over the
years the bugs really you know try to
find the weakest plant in in the in the
population and so you know plants that
are not as healthy as other plants
typically will get the bugs first some
people will even say oh you know I grow
these three different cultivars in my
Greenhouse but they only want to go to
the you know the gelato or something
they they like the turps of the gelato
more than like the OG or the The Lemon
Cherry gelato or something whatever you
know and so that might seem like the
case but it's not totally the case most
of the time it has to do with and and
again plants can seem and look really
healthy but when they have this bug
infestation that's the first sign that
there is something wrong with the health
of the plant and why aren't they going
to the other plants well the other
plants are a little bit stronger and
more resistant to those bugs and they
found that this strain or this
particular plant in the greenhouse is
weaker than the rest and that maybe is
because of the N nutritional demands and
the way that the substrate and things
were made up maybe we mixed up a pot and
it it was the last of our bag of soil in
our amendments and we kind of just
didn't give that last little plant
everything that everybody else got and
so we now know that it's getting all the
bugs because it just didn't meet the
health demands of the nutrition and
everything that it was put put up
against um the other thing is that
inside the green houses we always want
to start scouting in the corners because
the corners are typically warmer than
the center of the greenhouse when the
sun comes up in the morning it's usually
directed to one end of the greenhouse or
side and then as the sun goes down the
same thing and so uh typically you
always want to look on the outskirts or
the ends of the green houses for the
first
infestations um and and that will tell
you a lot as well and so again we're
trying to avoid an infestation and so
the program that you set up from the
early time is really important to have
and the the main part of that program I
would say is scouting um I know that a
lot of people's first line of defense is
just hey I just spray my plants every
couple days no matter if I have bugs or
not and you know that method is okay but
it it's not the best for the plants and
the expressions of the flowers and it
can be hard on the plants to spray them
all the time with even Organic
pesticides they don't love it but they
also don't necessarily hate it a
tremendous amount but if we're trying to
grow quality
medicine and trying to keep the plant
moving forward every time we spray the
plants with those oils it is a little
bit of a setback uh for the plant itself
and so scouting with the jeweler's Loop
and just really being able to identify
where the pests are how bad it is maybe
gives you the ability to spot spray
rather than entirely covering um every
plant and soaking everything down and so
identifying uh the hot spots or where
these things are which pests they are
and knowing the life cycle of these
pests there are times where we don't
spray enough maybe we're spraying every
seven days or something like that maybe
that's just the idea that someone has
hey I spray every seven days well in
between that time how many eggs have
hatched and how many aphids even maybe
have proliferated in that amount of time
um it can be quite a bit and so you're
actually just kicking the can down the
road and so I I think that you brought
up a good company natural enemies and
copert they really have a lot of cool
stuff as far as pocket guides and
Jewelers loops and books on these pests
and and you know posters that you can
hang in your garage or in your growroom
that help you know kind of keep you on
your toes for all this pest stuff and so
um if you're not scouting and using a
Jeweler's Loop and taking off leaves and
looking at the underside of them quite
often um I would say that you know when
an infestation does pick up I wouldn't
be surprised because you can actually
find this stuff um pretty easy before
things start to get out of hand and so
going in and you know de leafing the
plants a little bit before you spray so
that you get rid of some of those pests
and I would say that when you de Leaf
your plants you always want to have a
plastic garbage bag or a some type of a
garbage bag with you so you're not just
throwing those leaves on the ground I
know that it's been common practice even
for me and I've seen it in the
commercial level where when they go de
Leaf Everybody Just DE Leafs as fast as
they can and all the the leaves are
hitting the floor and on the pots and
then we come back later and we you know
maybe sweep it all up or rake it all up
and then throw it into the garbage bag
and what happens is the pests start to
move around quite a bit and you're not
actually getting rid of them and so by
De leafing the plants that maybe have
some bugs on them we're getting rid of
quite a few bugs because that's where
they reside as the underside of the leav
so you can imagine yourself throwing
away hundreds of pests by Just DE
leafing and then going in and doing that
the spray that needs to be done and some
of the products I like to use is aagard
which is an aid duratin I'm not a as
much of a fan of the AA Max as I am the
aagard um but the aid duratin um another
product that I like to use is called
suffoil X and there's a similar product
to suffoil X called trch they're both
80% mineral oil one's more expensive
than the other I happen to just think
and notice that suff oil X seems to be a
a a better product at the end of the day
but if you need to save a couple bucks
and go with the trch that's okay and I
would say that mixing the trch and the
aagard together can be a powerful combo
in fighting spider mites and uh aphids
um when it comes to things like thrips
like I was saying earlier understanding
the life cycle is really important
because the thrips also um have one of
the stages of life down in the soil or
the substrate and so we can spray all
the thrips we want but if we don't treat
the soil they're never going to go away
and so getting uh nematodes like the
steinera faler if I said that right
sorry if I botched it um is a good
nematode to put into the soil to help
get rid of thrips or even maybe avoid
getting some of those thrips um in the
long run and so you know being a homeg
grower sometimes people don't want to
know all these different ins and outs
and details and things but unfortunately
it's a really important aspect to to
learn and to understand and once you get
the hang of it and read about it a
little bit and know the common pests
that you have and what to do about them
it isn't that hard to deal with but
again um if you don't know things can
creep up and by the time they creep up
and start to do their thing it could be
way later in flower too and that's just
a tough time to have to spray and to
begin battling pests and so the more we
can do the moms the clones and while
they're in veg and even the earliest um
weeks of flowering will help ensure that
we have a great finish to the to the end
of the cycle damn that's so well put so
many everybody's interested in um crisis
management for their pests when really
the easy solution is on the prevention
side so it doesn't happen in the first
place so um all right so let's go ahead
and take our second commercial and be
right back um you are listening to
shaping fire and my guest today is OG
Greenhouse consultant Eric
Branstad fish poop brand fertilizer is
an allnatural fish poop concentrate with
nothing added real fish poop is
extraordinarily complex not only are you
adding the nitrogen phosphorus and
pottassium your plants need to build
mass transport nutrients and enhance
flavor but fish waste is also packed
with biological activity and
micronutrients when you add fish poop to
your irrigation water you are adding
life force probiotics and active
microbes these microorganisms include a
wealth of various bacteria and protozoa
which further enhance nutrient
availability for the plants because
plants are limited by the absence of any
essential micronutrient these Trace
nutrients are the difference between
having a decent garden and having a
garden that makes you feel really proud
of your efforts fish poop is a naturally
complete solution that fills in the
cracks in your fertilizer program to
ensure you offer your garden a broad
base of nutrients not all fish poop is
created equally most products with added
fish waste don't reveal their sources or
lab results fish poop brand fish poop
however generates their own fish waste
as a byproduct of their organic
aquaponic cannabis farm where they raise
ornamental koi and tilapia you are even
invited to tour their Farm in person or
on their YouTube channel to look for
yourself this sort of transparency is
wildly rare in the fertilizer Market the
folks behind fish poop are also lifelong
medical cannabis producers who have deep
Connections in the community donate more
product than they sell and support
cannabis prisoner veteran and patient
collectives and Charities to get your
bottle of pure fish poop go to fish
poop.com and to see their entire line of
cannabis products go to ounce ofh
hope.com that's fish poop brand fish
poop sometimes the topics I want to
share with you are far too brief for an
entire shaping Fire episode in those
instances I post them to Instagram I
invite you to follow my two Instagram
profiles and participate online the
shaping fire Instagram has follow-up
posts to shaping fire episodes growing
and processing best practices product
trials and of course gorgeous flower
photos the Shango Los Instagram follows
my travels on cannabis garden tours my
successes and failures in my own garden
insights and best practices from
personal grows everywhere and always
gorgeous flower photos on both profiles
the emphasis is on sharing what I've
learned in a way that you can replicate
it in your own garden your own hash lab
or for your own canopic health so I
encourage you to follow @ shaping fire
and @ Shango Los and join join our
online community on
Instagram after you've caught up on the
latest shaping FL episodes do you
sometimes wish there was more cannabis
education available to learn well we got
you shaping fire has a fabulous YouTube
channel with content not found on the
podcast when I attend conventions to
speak or moderate panels I always record
them and bring the content home for you
to watch the Shango Los YouTube channel
has world class speakers including Zoe
sigman's lecture understanding your
endoc canabo system Kevin jodry of
wonder Nursery talking about breeding
cannabis for the best turpine profile
Frenchie canoli's Lost Art of the
hashian presentation Nicholas mmud on
regenerative and polyculture cannabis
growing Dr seil agrawal on the history
of cannabis medicine Around the World
Eric voski and Josh Rutherford on
solventless extraction and Jeff
lowenfels on the soil food web there are
several presentations from Dr Ethan
Russo on Turpin and the endoc canabo
system too while there be sure to check
out the three 10p part shaping fire
session series one with Kevin jodrey one
with Dr Ethan Russo and one with Jeff
lowenfels and even my own presentations
on how to approach finding your dream
job in cannabis and why we choose
cannabis business even though the risks
are so high as of today there's over 200
videos that you can check out for free
so go to
youtube.com/ Shango or click on the link
in the
newsletter welcome back you are
listening to shaping fire I am your host
Shango Los and my guest today is OG
Greenhouse consultant Eric BR stad so
here's our big finish uh during the
first set we figured out where we were
going to put the greenhouse and how we
were going to put the greenhouse during
set two we figured out how the hell
we're going to deal with heat and cold
and pests and here in set three we're
going to talk a little bit about
tricking out our greenhouse and proper
care so um Eric you know you've been on
this show before and um we have talked
at length about um light deprivation
light dep and um I should probably know
the episode number but but for anybody
who wants to listen to that episode you
can look for it on um I'll put the link
on the on the page for this episode but
why don't you explain just just real
quick what light de is for folks who are
not familiar with it for their home
greenhouse and they can go to that
episode if they want to learn more yeah
sure I mean cannabis is a photo period
plant and what we mean by that is that
it uses these light cycles in order to
grow or to flower and so most people are
familiar with indoor growing and the
fact that 18 hours of light makes the
plants veg or grow and then when you cut
that light back to just 12 hours of
light they will start to produce the
flowers and so when we want to do that
same technique outside we can't turn on
and off the Sun but we can put a tarp
over the greenhouse that makes it uh
that puts that Greenhouse in the dark so
basically we are using um a green
Greenhouse with light depth curtains or
tarps that create that photo period so
we have full control of when they've
flower and when they veg um using the
sunlight uh that is great dude you know
what I just realized I just looked up
while you were saying that the episode
that you were on talking about Le light
de uh you and I are recording
episode9 right now we did that episode
episode 13 holy mackerel that was a bit
13 wow that was 8 years ago wow wow well
it's still a good one it's just still a
good one so so yeah thank you for that
definition and um dear listener if you
want to hear a really good hour and a
half about how to do this in detail go
on back to episode 13 and uh listen to
Eric and I as
youngans all right so so so that's
that's a quick little plug for light dep
because if if if you are trying to be
self-sufficient um with your cannabis
and and you want to be able to maybe get
in two cycles during your summer light
dep is a great way to do it yeah so that
gives light dep a short shrift but
that's it we're moving on so uh so um
one of the things that I personally
really enjoyed was um adding some Wii
environmental um uh um gauges to the
tent outside and it just as close enough
to the house Wi-Fi to pick it up which
means that it can then throw it to my
phone so I can be anywhere in the world
and know what's going on in my
Greenhouse um because you know mostly I
grow food here and um you know food and
cannabis are all very temperature and
moisture dependent and and if I'm if I
can set my alarms and and they can like
bring me bring me on in um to you know
to tell me that I need to check on on
the greenhouse um gr granted at the at
the homeg grower level um Outdoors
there's not usually a lot of integration
of these sorts of products but um my
gosh they're really helpful if you
bother to you know spend a little coin
and get
them totally I mean it's not out of the
question and there's a lot more out
there than there used to be I mean um
there's there's little companies that
people barely know exist that have you
know some of this technology going on
and so getting a couple sensors in the
greenhouse that can be hooked up to your
phone just to know what's going on
sometimes and you know the pivotal parts
of the Year might be in the spring and
the fall when the seasons are starting
to change and you really want to know
what's going on so that you can prepare
uh to make some changes or prepare to go
home and do something about this and so
you know while it's like you were saying
it's not 100% needed and it's not going
to always do everything that maybe an
automated Greenhouse is going to do it
does give you an edge and having that
slight Edge is always you know a step
forward in the right
direction to be able to you know rescue
your own crop or enhance the quality of
that crop you know the a lot of times um
with the way the weather is these days
things can change pretty quick and it
might be where you're away from home and
you need someone to go back and close it
up because all of a sudden it got cold I
mean we've had crazy weather where it's
sunny one day and the next day all of a
sudden we get a snowstorm or something
you know and nobody knows and sees this
stuff coming even though we look at the
weather and you know the weatherman says
it's going to be great they're not
always right and so it's really good to
be able to notice some of these things
and and stay ahead of the curve a little
bit um another thing that can be you
know cool and important to have is that
you know some of these things can be
hooked up to even a selenoid that turns
on and off your irrigation so there
might be just a simple hey I want to be
able to turn on and off my water when
I'm gone from home and that's not out of
the question because you know a lot of
the Landscaping stuff that we use
nowadays for our homes um can be
outfitted to do that and so you know
Rainbird is a common company or term
that have all sorts of
landscaping uh devices that can be
remote or you know controlled just you
know right at your house type of thing
with with a couple buttons or um even a
timer on on there that you know allows
you to be able to control when stuff
gets water or maybe when a fan turns on
or not um you know simply hooking stuff
up to a timer because you know when you
want something to come on or turn off uh
can be an important way to do things but
it never hurts to you know if you can
throw in a little technology in there
and and see if it helps you um I like
your point too about you know you only
need to go into this as far as you need
to um I grow different types of plants
right I've got my I've got my my food
plants which are mostly ungreen housed
but the but the ones that are greenh
housed I just need something really
simple to know what the temperature and
the humidity is and I've got like just a
simple like little goie smart
temperature thing right it cost me like
25 bucks nothing to it but like but with
my cannabis I'm I take that very much
Ser more serious for obvious reasons
right um I I want I want to know you
know uh I want to know you know heat and
humidity and vapor and like all this
more detailed stuff and I want to be
able to look at uh charts and graphs of
it and so for my cannabis uh Greenhouse
well I like I've upload I've upgraded to
like a pulse system right and so so now
I've got all the details plus as you
were saying I haven't gone so far as to
like connect it to my drip irrigation
which would be dope but like whenever I
want to I could like expand my pulse
meter um into controlling all of my
stuff you know and and it's great you
can just take these steps one at a time
from season to season depending on what
you can
afford I agree like I said earlier and
you're kind of hitting that same nail on
the head is that you start out simple
and with what you can afford and what
seems reasonable and always have that
ability to expand and the expanding can
be adding another light adding another
fan or adding something to that control
system which might be okay I've been
reading and collecting all this data now
I'm going to add something where I can
turn it on and off myself or something
like that so I mean there are especially
with that pulse and um a couple other
systems the ability to phase this so
phase one's simple phase two might be um
getting you know once you get your feet
wet in the growing season you want to
you know you can take more on we have
more bandwidth even for stuff and so um
I always try to like I said recommend
starting out slow do what you can within
your own bandwidth and then after that
season look at what the upgrades might
look like yep all right so we were
talking about upgrades and upgrades
around Tech um let's talk about adding
lights to extend the growing season now
I think that adding lights to um an
indoor space is an obvious thing and to
to a greenhouse is generally a good idea
though I'm not a big fan of of uh the
light pollution that comes from people
who run their lights all night but you
know that's a personal thing um but um I
have more concern conc ER when we're
talking about these small hobby green
houses of hanging lights in them
primarily for two reasons number one
lights are heavy and the the internal
frames of these green houses even the
galvanized steel ones they they wiggle
and I I'm kind of not so sure about that
and then second the lights themselves
can generate heat and potentially um
melt the plastic just because again
we're not working with a lot of space
here so um you know I I I have seen
people do it I've seen them do it well
um it takes their height from like 66 to
more like 510 which is light I space I
wouldn't really want to give up but what
are your thoughts on adding lights to to
you know a greenhouse that's this
small yeah it can be tricky all those
things that you said are definitely
noteworthy and each you know Hobby House
is a little different and so you can't
just you know I mean I we can imagine
we're going to hang lights and something
and then we put it up and we run into
some of these you know it's one step
backwards type of thing yeah yeah and so
um you know I've seen where people have
taken and and basically taken a 4x4 post
and and augured or put that into the
ground it at Four Corners or even just
one at both ends and they actually run
um a cable or a pole of some kind and
they actually hang the lights from that
so it's not attached to the
greenhouse um this came came up years
ago because when they started doing
proposition 64 in California and rolling
out the ordinances for how people could
grow they were kind of weird with the
hoop houses they you know you either
were a permitted greenhouse and uh
commercially growing or you know because
an egg you can grow with a non-exempt or
you know a non-permitted greenhouse and
so um cannabis Farmers wanted to have
that same opportunity but the ordinances
were hey you got to have a permit or or
nothing and what they did is they said
well if you okay if you want to have a
exempt Greenhouse that isn't permitted
it can't have any electricity or
lighting fastened to it fans or any of
that so then what people started doing
was rigging up with you know 4x4 posts
and internal framing so that they could
hang their fans and hang their lights
but it wasn't attached to the greenhouse
yeah yeah to totally outside the spirit
of the rules but exactly how we cannbis
people interpret rules exactly we find a
way and you know when you go to Home
Depot these days and so when we're
talking about lights you know a deeper
dive would be what kind of light what
color what intensity and all these other
things and so the short side of that or
the easier way to look at it might be
that hey I'm just trying to veg my
plants a little longer or hey I'm trying
to you know flower them sooner or
whatever the case is and so you know you
can get away with fairly low powered
lights in order to keep a plant in one
stage or another it doesn't necessarily
mean that they're going to grow bigger
and faster and produce bigger buds but
it's definitely going to help keep the
cycle that you're
intending um streamlined for a certain
amount of time and that's where the
lights could come in handy and so you
might say you know and people have done
this even on the commercial side where
they go to Home Depot and they sell the
decorative
uh uh outdoor patio lights so it's
basically like a long extension cord
with some light bulbs hanging on it and
most people would put that in their
patio or their backyard for um you know
barbecuing and and hanging out and
making more of an Ambiance or whatever
and so these same you know 40ft string
of lights that they have in a box at
Home Depot can be strung up inside these
green houses maybe even without any
framing because they're fairly can be
lightweight now I'm not saying that
they're light enough for all these
frames but they're lighter than hanging
an LED or a HPS light that you might go
get at the grow store right
right totally and um and also they're
they run a lot less hot too correct they
do run a lot less hot and so something
like those string lights can be a great
way to say okay I'm going to bring my
plants out whatever time of the year and
I want to encourage this veg cycle and
and I don't want them to trigger into
flowering by accident or the opposite
might be that you know you want them to
trigger into flowering and you're just
you know not getting enough sunlight in
some cases or whatever that case may be
you know this supplemental light is
exactly what it is it's supplementing
some light in order to keep those plants
um in the stage that you're intending um
without trying to rely on them for
ultimately all the growth and production
that's required yeah right on um there's
one more topic I want to uh mention here
we don't need to discuss it but I just
want to throw this in out there for the
the the one person who needs it um if
you happen to live in a place with a
very short cultivation season like where
I am in Washington state um you can also
consider something that I learned from
an OG uh Black Market grower in uh Port
Townsen if you're listening man I would
love to see you again um he made raised
beds
and he put in heaters in the soil
because one of the problems that we run
into is that after the evenings start to
get under 50 the the containers go to
sleep right all of your all your micro
life falls asleep from from the
consistent cold and so that tells the
roots we're done and so the plants
finish up and start to mold but he would
keep um he he would trick out his tents
with the lights and then he would also
put them in warmed beds and like he was
growing outdoors and harvesting like
first week in January and stuff and like
in Washington that's ridiculous he said
that he was able to um go until the snow
started to be too heavy on his on his um
hoop and then he had to be done so so if
you happen to be in one of those places
where um the the season is cold and you
are in containers there's an idea for
you 100% I was going to bring that up
earlier and I kind of just moved through
things and forgot but that the radiant
heat is really important for production
going into those colder months or parts
of the areas of the country um anytime
that you have your substrate start to go
below even 60 like you're saying
everything starts to hibernate and slows
down progress and so we want our soil
temps to be 69 to
70 and so that also means we don't want
to use freezing cold water to irrigate
with when we do go irrigate so I'm not
advocating hot water but I am advocating
you know something that's temperate and
not straight out of the ground at you
know 40 or 50 so if you can get your
water closer to 70 it doesn't have to be
hot because hot water will actually
start to grow bad things and cause
problems as well but we want to avoid
the freezing cold and the other thing
that people have done is they've you
know maybe wrapped their beds or even
their grow pots in some type of
insulation the the the most most low
cost effective might be straw mulch even
that they wrap around them there's other
people that you know you're familiar
with hash makers they'll wrap their
washing machine with that um myar
looking bubble wrap stuff that is
insulate of and it can get wet it
doesn't fall apart you know and so that
kind of stuff chopped up and wrapped
around your pots or your beds in
conjunction with the idea of adding some
heat and so there are some radiant heat
ideas and companies out there um you and
I always throw these selfless plugs
we're not connected to any of these
companies usually but we plug them
anyway um there's a company I think in
the midwest called radiant Tech and it's
you know radiant TEC at the end radiant
Tech has a lot of do-it-yourself um
supplies for creating a um a radiant
heating system and then there's another
company that's more commercial but I
think they do have some hobby kits now
and they're good people called biotherm
in California and biotherm also provides
radiant heat systems for commercial
green houses but again I think they have
something on the hobby side uh but if
you're considering extending the seasons
if you're considering growing in the
winter or if you're growing in a place
like where you guys have the short
really short
Seasons some of these things could be
beneficial if not all of them at least
one of them and the and that would be
not irrigating with the freezing cold
water don't pull it up from your well
and put it right on the plants yeah
exactly you're not going to want to
bathe in that so neither are they right
on all right so the last topic I want us
to touch on Eric um you have told me so
many times to make sure that I put to
get put away my Greenhouse skin properly
because they are expensive and if I
don't clean it before I put it away it's
going to get crappy over the winter and
then I did not listen to you and I
screwed up all my stuff and so I had to
replace the Plastics and next year so um
uh going forward I now listen to you and
I make sure I I wash down the greenhouse
let it dry and fold it up before you
know before the weather gets too bad but
I I I can imagine that there is some
like General upkeep that should probably
be done on these Greenhouse skins over
the year like I don't know if there's a
plastic conditioner or anything and then
they should be put away correctly so
will you give us your little your little
best thoughts on taking care hair of the
greenhouse and how to properly put it
away for the season sure I mean there a
little soap and water goes a long ways I
mean I think if you were to look online
of somebody like Greenhouse mega store
or Griffin greenhouse and maybe even a
company that in Santa Barbara called
total Energy Group total Energy Group
sells a lot of um whitewash materials so
that you can you know add um you know a
lot of green houses in the winter time
that are commercial that might be glass
I'm sorry in the
summertime that don't have a automated
shade cloth or something like that um
will spray a whitewash type of a paint
on the glass and so it basically calms
down the sun's intensity because it
takes away some of that transparency and
then it washes off in the winter time or
when it rains and so companies like that
might sell a conditioner of some kind
but I would say that you know in a lot
of areas of cannabis growing I've gone
out and seen that you know there is
um quite a bit of particulate that
settles on these greenhouse frames
whether it's dust or environmental stuff
pine needles or whatever it's not out of
the question to go out there once a week
once a month and just hose the
greenhouse down with a hose so that you
get some of that particulate off and
then when it comes to wintertime like
you were saying is taking it completely
off and it not only protects the skin it
protects the frame because as you were
saying earlier if we get a tremendous
amount of rain it can build up into the
greenhouse in these little pockets and
saggy spots if it snows that snow load
will take down the greenhouse frame and
so will the rain if it gets enough water
trapped on top of it in weird places and
so by taking the greenhouse cover off
we're avoiding the frame collapsing or
bending or creating any stress on it and
then it's also going to make that cover
last a lot longer one of the things or
mistakes people do is they'll just fold
it up and stick it in the garage and
what ends up happening is for some
reason I don't know what it is but mice
just seem to be attracted to plastic and
weird things like this and they bore a
hole in the side of it when it's folded
up and then when you go unfolded it's
like a piece of Swiss cheese um and so
you know having that piece of plastic
rolled up and maybe put into a cardboard
box simply is enough um i' for some
reason the mice don't always bore
through them they can uh but for some
reason they tend to leave stuff alone um
if you can get a black and yellow tote
and fit it inside of that that might
even be a better solution for really
keeping anything out and bugs and and
rodents that that way um I would never
recommend using any kind of rodent um
killer or spray or anything because a
lot of the products or chemicals in
those products um Can Be bioaccumulated
by cannabis and cause a test fail and so
um trying to keep the like I said soap
and water letting it dry folding it up
putting it in a box or a black and
yellow tote of some kind and stick it in
the garage maybe um somewhere up high or
or um easy to keep away from the kids
and the animals and things like that and
your Greenhouse cover is going to last
way longer than probably even the
manufacturer specifications
state right on now that's the kind of
experience I was looking for you know
the idea of throwing it in a black and
yellow tote is so obvious and I missed
it I've actually run into the the the
rat problems that you've got with them
eating through it and so mine are
actually suspended from rope from the
ceiling okay and U but I actually like
your idea of putting it in the black and
white a lot better cuz well it doesn't
look as weird um but also it it won't go
through all the temperature changes as
the the the ambient air in the
garage yeah so that's good so all right
cool well Eric let's wrap up man um
thank you so much for joining me again
on shaping fighter you know I have
always enjoyed your professionalism and
your depth of knowledge but I also
really enjoy because you're a good
conversationalist and you're just fun to
hang out with and so I'm I'm glad we got
an opportunity to hang out for a couple
hours today with everybody hanging out
with us so we could just like you know
chat and hang yeah no it's always good
chatting with you and I miss hanging
with you we're going to have to get you
out of we're going to have to dust you
off and get you out here to want
something one of these these days so we
can hang out again but it's got to be
the right thing so when that comes up
I'll be calling you yeah the the man I I
miss because it used to be like it at
the very least you and I saw each other
at Emerald cup and and and like you know
I don't I don't want to uh dis Emerald
cup cuz I know you're still heavy there
as a judge but Emerald cup has changed
you know and and it just doesn't bring
all the people that it used to and and I
I miss that old family it's changed a
lot and it yeah I miss a lot of that too
it's it's definitely not the same and
there's some other events out there that
are kind of like that but um yeah it's
it's all changed and the events are all
different but one of these days
something's going to you know happen and
we're going to be like hey we'll be at
that see you there yeah I mean the
Wonderland days were great too for
meeting up I mean I missed the
Wonderland days and you know some of
those spring kickoffs and things that
Kevin used to throw up there um you know
people just don't want to travel like
they used to
especially um you know a lot of The
Growers I think the most popular event
or one of the more popular NorCal events
nowaday that just happen is the ego
Clash I've never been but uh it seems to
be you know the new community event yeah
I agree I do think that um the these
these uh specialty very small ultra high
quality events is where it is right now
I'd love to see The Return of a big
event but it would have to take a very
particular promoter to pull it off so
that it doesn't get usurped as much by
the the commodity advertising and turn
it into what everything else is but um
totally I would definitely support such
an event if it happened right on man
well it's always good catching up with
you yeah good catching up with you man
um so let's let's plug some of your some
of your stuff so my dear listening
friend um if you are interested in
hiring um Eric Branstad to consult for
you on your Greenhouse whatever its size
um by all means you should reach out to
him cuz he does that full-time all over
the country and he's great at it so um
for that kind of information you can go
to his website at
Greenhouse
advisory
group.com and get all that information
and reach out to Eric through there um
if you are interested in following uh
him on the media socials um you've got
two options the first one is the um the
the Instagram for the business which is
ghore Advisory Group un nope nope nope
sorry let me try that again ghore
Advisory unor Group that's the business
Instagram and the one that I would
recommend Everybody follow because it's
a good time and Eric really kind of like
you can get to know Eric as a person
through it is his personal IG which is
LightCore
deore Greenhouse so those two are on IG
and then his uh website you can find
more episodes of the shaping fire
podcast And subscribe to the show at
shaping fire.com and wherever you get
your podcasts if you enjoyed the show
we'd really appreciate it if you would
leave a positive review of the podcast
wherever you download your review will
help others find the show so they can
enjoy it too on the shaping fire website
you can also subscribe to the newsletter
for sites into the latest Cannabis News
exclusive videos and giveaways on the
shaping fire website you'll also find
transcripts of today's podcast as well
be sure to follow on Instagram for all
original content not found on the
podcast that's @ shaping fire and @
Shango on Instagram be sure to check out
shaping fire YouTube channel for
exclusive interviews farm tours and
cannabis lectures does your company want
to reach our national audience of
cannabis enthusiasts email hotspot
shaping fire.com to find out how thanks
for listening to shaping fire I've been
your host Shango Los
[Music]